Alibis, secret codes, tricks, deals,
the mysterious organization
of men in black.
Conan's target finally appears.
It smells of a serious crime.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult.
No case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene
One Billion Robbery by
the Black Organization
Thanks for waiting, Conan...
Was the money for
detective services deposited?
Aye! Plenty! Too much that
it filled up the entireibook
All right! Let's eat lunch out
some place and go home, then!
It's been awhile since I've had
drink from day time...
Dad. We're talking about lunch!
I'll go get this savings book
changed for a new one...
epeless drunkard...
he:counter-is... Let's see... Wow.!!
What a beautyl
-- -~
Mlbb
Ye, Yes!
Would you exchange this
pass book for a new one please?
I'm ven serry, sir. Please get
yourself a number over there,
then please have a seat and wait your turn.
Yes, we.should all wait
I'll be nght back. I've got:to get
a liluinipel, a 1iuliiouet .
Miss!
Oh, Conan
What's wrong? You seem to be
ceneerned and:leeking @t the cleck...
so I was hoping that it would
be lunch time soon.
I'll see you later, then, Conan.
Is she somebod ou know onan?
Uh-huh, her name is Masami Hirota and
she is a new employee
who just came here a while ago.
He usually much kinder...
Aaaagh . 1" S.She s gone
She's not here...
h no...
For some time yet, so I'll wait.outside.
Okay, be careful of cars.
T's-the«parking lot of .the bank...
I wander what that sound was...
They're robbing the armored
cash transport truck of the bank!!
There are two robbers...
One is armed with a shotgun
d the other with a gun...
Re he other security guards...
dead?!
I can't tell from here...
Cenan?
What are you doing:in a place like this?
We're oin home!
Help"! It's a robbery!!
What's with that car?!
It's an cash transport armored car robbery!
What!
Ran:.please call the police
Hey, Conan
Get an ambulance too, because there
seems to be some people who are hurt!
Ran, notify the bank first! I'll go check
on the people who are hurt!
Okay!
Talk about high speed
It:s as if we're having a car race!!
I can barely keep up with them!
Great! A railway crossing!
All n ht.éthen!
What the .?!!
He's going to run the crossing?!
I'm not letting them get away!!?
They got away!
What?! One billion yen was stolen?!
Yeah: all the cash-that was
suppesed to be delivered
from the main bank to
all the branches were stolen.
One billien, eh...
Conan, you're sure of the license
plate number you just gave me?
Yes. I'm sure!
There are two of them armed
nth a shotgun and a gun, eh...
Well, fortunately, the security guard
wasnit seriously hurt
The armored truck stopped. so we
were getting ready to unload the cash.
That's when we were suddenly
tacked by the robbers.
Mr. Koyama?! Mr. Murata?!
Hey! Driver!! Is somebody there?!
Since I got no response from the driver
! dhought they were killed and
had no choice but to open the door.
Strange... I'm sure that back then I...
After hearingathe gun and
the window crack,
Il ran right over to the entrance: of
he parking lot and looked in...
At that time. they were already
Ioading the cash out of the ruck.
He shouldn't have had
any time to call the driver!
You understand too, don't you?
I really had no other choice...
Excuse me, sir.
You sure are lucky, sir.
Huh?... Why am I lucky?
Because, The window of
the armored truck is smoked
so that you canit see anything
from thesoutside, right?
Yeah...
The bullet that was fired through that
smeked window, and yet it didn'tihit you.
Besides, the bullet hit the coin bag,
so it didnit bounce back at you.
You had to either be real lucky,
or had planned
where to place theacoin bag and
where-to hide beforehand, right?
Don't be ridiculous
This is still just a possible deduction...
But...
Ms. Hirota!" Where were you
at a time like this?!
I'm sorry, I changed shifts
and went out to lunch...
Talk about the young girls nowadays...
Just-what time do you think it is?!
Is your watch broken or something?
There is one other ossibility...
Inspecter Megure!
What's up, Detective.Takagi?
There was a report that what looked
to be the runaway van was found.
What?! Where?
By the rive bed of the Teimutsu River.
Beside the TR railway bridge!
Okay. let's head eff. right away.
Come with me teo, Mr. Mourn:.
Sure! Ran, you take:Conan
and go on home!
Okay!
Let's get geing then.!Conan... Cenan?!
Ugh, he's gone again!
So, what's the stery, Tome?
Oh. Inspector Megure...
I just took a quick look=but-the
fingerprints have been wiped off clean
What other clues are left?
Well, as for pretty large sized clues,
there are 5 cases in the bed of the truck.
There are no fingerprints on them either...
Hey, bring me the stuff
we found "a while ago!
This was thrown out
on the driver's seat.
H. thanks... Take a look at this...
These are...
A mask-and gloves...
VV, Adllliuylil 111 piewy suie
we can't expect any prints on them either...
Oh, sowyou're here too, eh, boy
Hello. Mr. Tome!
Hey! I thaugfit I field you to go
on home with Ran!?
H. there s something on
Be inside of the mask...
On the inside of the mask?
What's this pink colored soil?
This pink.celer is...~ but, why:.
Okay. then! I'm berrowing this for a while!
Ustias'l thought...
You don't "ow me! What do you think
A If, ,_lr\__., . o, -r\_ ,.\_(\»,-¢_,,_¢ A A,
YOU I QGUITIY WILIT LI 11ijpouitarinil ciue >
That's enough, kid!!
So, the case started off as
an-ordinary case of robbery...
Hewever... This is no
ordinary case of robbery.
1t didn't take me long to prove
that my hunch was right. .!
What?! The robber
the other day was killed?!
Yeah a former racer, Jiro Kaizuka
was found shot to death in bed.
I see... No wonder
they earned it out so fast...
How did they figure out
that he was the robber?
A- memo.ofithe blueprint of the bank.
The schedule of the armered
cash transport truck.
As well as a map of the get away
route were found in his roem
Furthermore... Anoether persen was killed
astinight with same gun.he had...
What?!
Securit. guard, Kishii!
Which means that Mr Ki
was also a member of the group...
I'm sure he was an aceemplice
He liked gambling and seemed
o have a lot of debts
He probably played
the role of being frightened
into opening the rear of
the armored truck from the inside
The rear door of an armored truck cannot
e opened unless from the inside
Does that mean that the two were
maybe killed by the other robber?
Probably...: because the meney
that was stolen is gone.
The other robber prebably killed
he two to take all the-money .
It seems that Inspecter Megure is also
going to check in on things on that line...
But, I'm sure that its - nly a matter
of time before they are caught...
at do yeu mean...
What do you mean...?
Pink colored lipstick was feund
in Kaizuka's room...
Lipstick?
It matched the color that was found
on the mask that the robbers left behind...
Mereover...
It also matched the color that bank teller
Ms. Masami Hirota is using, right?
C Conan
One of the her colleagues testified that
it matched the color of lipstick she is using
She left-the bank saying
she was going out lunch
so I'm sure she went to
the back door and joined them
But, why would a bank employee
do somethingdike-that?
Il don't know., but 'she has
already quit the bank
She handed in a resignation: this morning.
What?!
She started working fer this bank
only half a year ago
What do you meanv
She just snuck into the bank to cheek
things out before committing the crime...
It's more natural if you think of it that way.
Well, I guess that how:it.is...
I'm sure... I'm sure that is the way
things took place on the whole .
But there is s ill one question left...
I wonder if she would-really
ake her lipstiek.rub off...
After all, she spentia half a year
to check the bank out...
esides, the lipstick on
the mask-was situated too low,
that the chin would be there and
1 ot the lips And above all...
it would've smelled of make-up
if she wore the mask.
But there was no such smell on it...
If someon jschemedythis all and
Is trying to frame her up~as the robber
Oh ne!
Conan, where are you going?
Let him be, let him be...
Hello, this is Inspector Megure
"The Police Department
Hello. this is Inspector Megure
Oh. Mr. Moun...
Ms. Masami Hirota's address?
Werve already cheeked her place out.
Yes. I kn w. but...
I have semething kd-like to confirm...
Here it is!
It's this teem!
If my deductnen us right,
asami's in danger
wondaer It...
if there's same clue somewhere...
The outlet is blocked off
y the leg of the desk...
aybe it's deliberately blocked off...
Could it be that...
mm?... What's this...
This is a key to a coin locker...?!
This us probably where
e stolen money is hidden
D...Don't go, Ms. Masami Hirota...
If you go: you'll be killed...
I'm sor
Wait!
Ere's nobody here...
There she is!!
It's Masamnh!
Okay, kil use this transmitter and
my. . suspenders...
Stick on - please...
o fer it!
All right!
Okay, she's started off!
I won<t let you get away!
There's no doubt that she
Is\sbeing used by someone!
Whoron earth is pulling
the strings behind her...
Where are yeu?! Come out here!!
Goed work.
Masami Hirota... Rather
Akemi Miyano!
May I ask you a question?
Why did you kill those two?
Fuh... That's the way we do things.
Now, hand over the cash.
Itss ot here. I have it in another place.
Whatrd
efere ) giv it to you, get my sister!
Bring my sister here!
You promised, didn't you!
That when this job is over, you'll let
me and my sister out of this organization!
There's no deal h
ecause she's an indispensable
brain to the organization.
Your sister, unlike you, is a
necessity to the organization!
Which means that yeu didn't intend to...
Come on, this is your last chance.
Tell us where the money Is
Don't be silly.
If you kill me, the whereabouts
of the cash will be unknewn forever.
You re the one who's being silly...
We already knew that you have
the key to the coin leeker...
I told you; that this was your last chance...
Gun fire!
That way!
Masami!!
Get a hold of yourself, Masami!
Onan...
Hew did you know I was .herer*.
I stuck a transmitter onto your car...
because I was sure hat
you were coming to see the people
who were pulling the strings
from behinds he scene...
If I only explained everything
0 you back then...
ho are you...
Edegawa... rather...
hinichi Kudo a detective
Kudo Shinichi
So. you're him...
I've heard rumers abeut you
The two men that I hired were killed...
nd me too, by the organization...
rganization...
It's a large, mysterious organization...
The enly thing that one who is
on he bottem of the line.knows,
as that the color of 'this
rgani -ation is black
Yes...The people of the organization
favor wearing that color...
Black clothes as black as a crow...
May I ask you to
O me a last favor
This 1s the real key
The one they teok s fake
It's for the coin lee -er at he
east exit of Beika. Station...
Please... before they realize
what's geing on,
I don't ever want o be used by them again.
I'm counting on you ..«
Little Detective...
Hello, I'd like to speak to Inspector
Megure of the 1st Division.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
KRsuo Ono
Katsup-Ono
Masatomo Sudo
. P it Yoy )
vradaluliiiv ouuv
vidddlulniv ouuvu
Junichi lioka
umichi hoka
Junichr Miyashita
Tdshlk: (hone
SCRIPTS+«BY
KGZUIIJTI Knuth:
Junichr Miyashita
Yuichi Hioure
Masamoto Sudo
Haruo Oogawara
Ahi1o Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
Yukihiro Shibutani
OF PHO
Takashi Nomura
Hnronobu Honkos:
Takamsa Ogawa
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
Ken]: Kodama
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenj1 kodama
TMS - Kyokuichi Corporation
in association with
Yomiuri Telecastine Corporation
Gosho-A~aa ulkkan
Since the only fingerprints found
on the gun were hers
it was concluded that she committed
suicide thinking she could not get away.
The one billion yen that was robbed
was safely recovered
And it looked to be that
the case was closed
But, no, it's not over at all!
Ill never forgive these guys...
I'll nab then for sure with these very hands
f mine. Definitely... and certainly...