Daitohma! Daitohma!
I've come to Daitohma Station. but nobody
has seen the man with the black hat...
What now?
Their pugpose is to make .counterfeit-bills...
Maybe I should start off by
skiing at a real estate agency...
A warehouse?
Haven't you rented out a warehouse
that is ilncenspicuous
in the suburbs and won't be suspected
no matter what IS dene there to anyone?
We haven't rente
any warehouses out.recently...
t could've been many years in 'he past...
Ghads, you're getting in the way of business.
Take your friends and go home!
Riends
They're your friends, aren't they, sonny?
Y You guys?!
Do you think you can fool-usyg
every lime-with the same triéldv
You really have a talentrof
running out on us, don't you!
How'd yeu know I was here...
We came after you because Ail told us to!
She said that you were geing to leave) us
behind and pursue the man by, yeurself!
Right!
What is it?
Isw$ there a novelist who lives near here?
A novelist?
What do you mean?
After brother disappeared
he calledrus once at home,
What!
Why didn'. you tell us sooner?!
Although grandmother was
he one whe toe the call I...
Shers lard of hearing and
besides brother taled so fast.
That she:co 1dr understand what he said!...
All' she ce Td make out was>his words,
I'm with a lot of people like Sosek.
He's with ..- people like Soseki...
Soseki
Did you tell the police about this?
Of course! But: they couldmt find anybody
Iike that no"matter 'how lard they searched
So. they said that maybe grandma made
a mistake, orthat it was a can «call...
But, wasn't your brother a fan of Soseki?
If so, here's nothing
to worry about. is there?
Ut... Grandma said brother's voice
was trembling and cut off half wa...
I see . He somehow made
the call while they weren't around,
Come to think of it, a man who
Iooks like Soseki does live near here!
He's the owner of the bookstere on the corner...
his niekname is "One-thousand yen."
T, That's it!!
Please.!
Please what?!
Takews there.
Oo + I'd advise you net to
Not to his place, ne. ¢
You've gotta be kidding!
Counterfeit my foot!!
I'm serry!
Stop playing jokes on adults!
Get out of here!
A thousand yen, they say!
I'm-not that cheap. \
Why isn't Soseki-Natsuméeél
OI LIne. 1. VUuuv yenaoitil!?
H he scared me...
That's why I told you not to come.
What's with that man, anyway.
He sure smells fishy
No, he probably has nothing
to do with the incident.
I checked the warehouse of the beokstore but,
there was no printer for
printing out counterfeit bills:
:alking about printers, he newspaper agency
in front of the station was installing one...
A newspaper agency?
Seenthesbuilding next.to the police box
The-agency is:on:the 3rd floor.
We:-handled-that-building:2 years ago too.
What were the people in there like?
A lady who is always wearing a broad brimmed
hat is the president of that small agency.
But. they re.printing out information magazines
on this tewn... not counterfeit 5 bills...
Fhey couldn't possibly do
something like that here.
Se. that:sithe stogy. I;don't.know what
this is about, but it's already night time.
Quit playingidetective.already
and head on home. you guys!
Could that... newspapenragency be .
B.But, it doesn't have anything &
o with Sos ki, dees it .
Rinse one's mouth with\stone and sleep
with one's pillow in the water
This 1Isha~famous ancient event
that Seseki took his name from...
it means eccentric.
Hy WE [1110€ UUl 111UULllS Will] Tul
water and use stones for pillows, right?
But, to use it reversely,
you'd have to'be quite eccentric...
To make counterfeit bills,
-- 9
IA LAOS aQily, ¥WYallL
the subunrbs_and_avoidithe-eyes-of-others
Lyzolitual
in'a-bustling station
right beside a pelice_.box!
It may at first glance leek-to be
the action of one*whosis.eceentric
But, -there is no better way-than to use
this advantageousllecatieneto'.blind-the police
Toshiya's brother probably
wanted-to-relay this message
hi" I mea. s that brother is...
If it's as "have deduced,
he's probably inside that newspaper agency
That why I've been telling you.
His brother's been kidnapped and
Is making counterfeit bills in there!!
You've been watching
too many gang movies. kid!"
It's really true!
Please believe us!
Why would they believe kids talking like that.
Hey. you guys4den't move
from there, no matter what!!
You got me, right! Don't move!?
C Conan?!
The more he tells us not to move...
The more yow, eel like moving, right...
What?! Counterfeit bills?! ~
Is that true, Shinichi?!
Although I have no proof y
'E's very likely...
And. please befcareful when yeu raid the place.
They may-:threaten the hestages
oO save themselves
oman dressed in black...
Come ts think of it
there was that one...
No, Genta.
Conan said not to move. remember?
Shut up! I've got to find some kind of
proof or the police won't believe me!
Theresstnebedyahere...
There are no counterfeits anywhere...
Maybe Conan made a mistake?
II types of ink...
They were trying it out...
P.Please forgive me, boss.
- - - ay
mLnoudnt 1 lida OU 110OL LOUSC LildlEpelausce
it wasgjust a prototype with- no watermark!
1.1t looked so real that
I just couldn't help myself...
Phooey. I'll let you use-it
until you get sick of it .in time.
Something-we. better than
this half done. Soseki Natsume,
A 10.000 yen bill with Yukichi Fukuzawa on it
I hope you bought the ink that I specified 3&
Y.,Yeah. I bought all there was lefth*O
I tried all kinds, but this is
he best for watermark...
H.Hey!! Somebody's in the room next door!!
K.Kids, five kids!!
1, Toshwya'l!
vviiat Lice...
You stay quiet?
So, he came all this way ta look
or his brother. How cute
They went inside the newspaper agency?!
All five of them sayin
they'll come again after they find proof...
Darn!
Hey...
Those idiots!!
There is a chance...
hey couldsbe...
they could be in the same organization
as the men in black!
So, we still don't know where she is , eh
Sorry.iwe're trying the best we can, though
I still can't believe it.
It's hard to believe she'd
appear from there...
Phooey, if his corpse wasn't there,
just means that he wasn't killed...
We've got to look for her fast
and bnng her here.
We can't afford her talking to
anybody about us.
Of course I don't care if
you get him dead or alive.
They went inside the newspaper agency?!
All five of them sayin
they'll come again after they find proof...
Darn!
Those idiots!!
Heyrcould-be...
The Youth Detective Squad
made it into the site
where counterfeit
ills were being made...
The woman with thé 'black hat and the gun
pointed at the children await their entry...
Is: she really connected to
the men in black in some way?
Or... will Conan run up the stairs
to reveal the truth behind it all!
He runs to save his friends. as well as
to gain his true identity as Shiniehi Kudo back!
Darn, Genta and them
After I told them not to move
from the police box!
Genta, let's ge back already...
If somebody comes, we'll be seolded.
Quiet. If you wanna go home. why
don't you go home alone, Ayumi!
It seems like everybody is still safe. Okay,
I'll have to get everybody out of here now
That's it for your detective game, kid...
Heys look at this!
A lot of:10:000 yen:bill§!!
Wow!
God knows hew many eel bowls
bh can eat with that much money.
But, there's semething strange
abeut these 10,000 yen bills...
ultichi Fukuzawa's left eye [IS not drawn in
s Ii e the darma doll...
We're drawing in both eyes
when our wish is granted.
And when that 10.000 yen bill is perfected.
WwW. Who are you guys?
How's about a touching
reunion of the two brothers?
T Toshiyah'O
rother!!
Brother aaaagh!!
Troshiyal!
H.Hey cut it out. you guys!
T.That8 right, I'll contact Conan...
What do"you think you'reldaing?!
L.Let her go!!
Shut up! You don't seem to
know what this is, do you?!
D.Don't\ ourdare touch the children! g¢.
F you do, I won't cooperate
with»you anymore. -
Don't worry, I'll save
your little 'brother for last.
ny uial dirt witli Liegiicdud vdliiu. 11d
AAyumul
H.Hey, what're you going to dos!
I'm going to make you speed your wor sup.
If they dier@ne after the other,
maybe you'll want to work harder?
Help, Conan!!
Conan? Oh... if it's that boy with glasses
that was loitering around the stairs,
he's already deadtg
C.Conan's dead?!
No way...
It's a lie!h)here is only one wa.
In and out of this building!
When can you kill-himy.4
The surveillance camera was
watching all of you all this time.
The outside stairway is also(@Quarded...
You didn't know, did. ou?
1 had Inuyama come all the way
arourrdPto this entrance
rom the emergency exit so that
you guys wouldn't be able to run-away.
Just them the boy with the glasses
came air-mg.- so I killed him.
Hey, come on, don't cry...
ou"ll re just fine...
I'll let you go to him right away.
Ye. bye, young lady...
W. Who is it?! e
Same as the Darima dell, you say?
What a joke
Yukiehi Fukuzawarss eye is not
drawn in because the sculptor
at was carving him got hurt...
What?
See. the man over there with the white
beard and his hand:wrapped up...
He's the real sculptor. isn=t he?
You panicked and made
Toshiya's brother take his place
because, the sculpter get
hurt just before completion
After seeing his talent fer art at the exhibition,
you lured him eut and-confined him here
The ink beside the printer, and the container
with magnetic steel powder inside it.
Seeing that you've got all these prepared
I'llObet you're going to put it
0 through a machine next?
You plan to pass it through
the counterfeit detection machine,
and use these counterfeits that are
difficult to detect even by appearance
through the change machines of banks,
game centers, and pachinko parlors,
to ¢c ange them in large amounts.
By the time your deed is made pu lic.
You 'plan to be.some place far awa.
Isn't that right, lady in the black hat?
WwW. Who?
Who aresyou.
Onan Edogawa
detective
Cc.Conan'!!
It,it can't be. lnuyama got rid'-of you a!
Oh, so this dog of a man is called Inuyama?
I'm sorry, but I put him to
sleep with an anesthetic gun.
A. Anesthetic gun?
Oh, yes, yes. The gun I threw at
you awhile ago was Inuyama's gun.
I kicked it right at you.
EK Kicked it?
Yeah, with this Super Kick shoe.
A... ala... fa...
WwW. Wow!!
You're fantastic, Al.
This 1s the first-time: I've
ever seen a r,real gun
ell, at.any rate, I'm glad...
Brother!!
Toshiya!!
So; now guess the case is closed.
Im glad!
The Youth Detecti e Squad's great victory!I
Is anything the matter?!
Thanks for coming.
The case has been solved!
This issthheascounterfeitswhich is evidence.
And that's Toshiyars brother.
The one w. 0 was kidnapped.
Hello...
They were telling the truth...
Leave it to the Youth Detective Squad»
and cases are selved in a jiffy
Right, Conan'?
Yeah
Being reckless ike his, we'll
need mere than nine lives...
20 minutes#later. Inspector Megure arrived.
They were all taken away
Nd Toshiyvars brother was set frees"...
And...
What a goef, to be arrested
over such a measly crime.
You may as well spit it all out at the station.
Abeut the big organization that is
oulling the strings behind the scenes...
anization .
Don't play dumb with me! You also had code
«names like "Gin" and Vodka", didn't you?
Gin Vodka?... I'm sorry.
But I quit drinking quite some time ago
Hey, hey, just what: are
you talking about, Conan?
These people are notorious for making
- -- r€~ ~~ vf ~~ "n - ~ oe ~~
counernieit Dis dail go uy uiesiidaine oliver mrox
A - -~y - -
MALTTOUUYT! OIC O TIATU Up a VIL VY pPlasliv sulycly,
Il would never fergetdhe face of this woman} boss.
But, this time you'll have to sew ) for kidnapping,
possession of dangerous weapons.
a Jui vu...
spending some time in jail this time!
My. I'm not the one who fired the gun!
It's that:girl with the brown hair over there.
What?!
What a dangerous thing to do?!
But... because...
I'm sorry, I shouldn't have scolded"yeul .
So, she's a girl after all...
Hey. don't cry.
Your house is near here, isn't it?
Ghads, why me?
I'm thrown off finding out that
hese people dressed in black
and why do I have to baby-sit
a crying girl moreover. walk her heme...
Hey. you can go heme alone
from here can't you?
See you temorrow. then
at school!
PTX4869...
Do you know what it is?
It'srthe name of the medicine
yeu were given...
WwW. What're you talking abeut? I've never
been given such a strange.medicine...
Oh. I'm sure-that the name of
he medicine us not wrong...
because I'm the one who made it
by order of the organizatien.
O.organization? Made it?
A child like you could never...
I drank it just like you did.
Through the accidental effects of the
self-destructive program-ofat "e c 1is,
everything from bane structure. muscles.
Internal organs, body hair,
all but the nervous system. regress
to that of the childhood years.
It sure ls a mys deal peison.
1 H.Haibara, don't tell me you're...
It's not Haibaraf...
It's Sherry.
Thisiis my code name.
vvell... 7 surprised
Shinichi Kudo?
Hen you're a member of
the organization of the men in black...
You've got no time to be surprised,
Iow peke detective
What?!
Idn't tell you that I liv
Beika 2-22 now...
next door to your real hous
You know where it is, don't you?
T.itcouldn't.-be...
Doctor Agasars house?!
Ey. Doc?! Hey?!
Answer the phene!!
OO use
No matter how much yeu call
ou'll get a busy signal
The phone is off the heek,
he can't pick it up.
Why, because he is
o lenger of this world...
Why you...
O HC
- - Wk -~ 3
PR Bx =x,
Pb wu gy NR TE yg 2 - -
BLVEHNT TE == LTA
wl%= BRET
ER EF
NAY T= TTY
ZS HR S/= FE
FE EA
80a il ET ==
RE-cRiE T= =--4&
Fl oR =
or NR -H C_wag I -_- ox Taye SC
-- & _ . ire ee. YN
- -g Te <> -3
- SUSE Er CRS TE
FEXEXE- BEB EX TEBE TL
94. = R mam
Pansy :9
ys a \
- - fr ~
MALT d= dS SS
HFT BOL TL &-ITTAHAICT
I - fed _ ~~ vy -—
HoZZXllJ LL BN Ve WINALL C
AAS ILL EA LL ~The PED oo al -2 CC
A-TAA- TI 47-3
- - ER
SXF TH
RIT SA
KR TFIERPT
a Bs tl ted) -e ee. mee CP a CO Cn TS EEO og wn. wa I enn - Senn
) =waY - so 7
My Destiry
HES I 7
ATVEE WU LUC OWUA YY
BEET
> Jrik
I PIC 4
Fork
NES La-&
Ws fa-&
I §-YIC