What?!
Professor Hirota was killed?!
Agent
hat's ridiculous...
agent
He was fine till just awhile ago...
You came here just as Mrs. Hirota was going out
didn't you, Mr. Hosoya?
Oh. yes.
My daughter is geing to
apply for Nanyo University.
So I came to have Professor Hirota
write out a recemmendation for her.
But, 'he Prefessor was so drunk.
I decided to leave for today.
Is it true that the was drinking?
From evening
Mr Monoka!
According {& the message in the answer phone.
you were also supposed
to meet Professor Hirota...
Yeah!
0 play chess
she Professor and I pla- chess together!
He asked me to come over andiplay tonight tool!
See, chess pieces are
scattered all over the floor!
We used to always play in this room!
Phoned twice because we
didn't decide what time to start
but the answer phone was set.
I came ts check out what was happening
because he wouldn't answer the phone
despite having called me from his side!
¥ You came here tonight?
Yeah!
I came around 21.30...
Although the front door was open,
nobody answered the door bell.
So, I thought he had forgotten
about the game and went to sleep
1 went into the house.
But, when I knocked on the door
of the study, nobody answered
and on top of that, the door was locked
So, I gave up and left!
1 SCC...
And Mr. Agasa arrived an hour later,
realized that something was wrong,
broke the door open and found the corpse?
Yeah, that's right.
By the way,
Wil. OTNTURUTAd. YOU Late 1iunn
after we got here. right?
Aven't asked you what you
came here for yet?
the act is, I am working as a model.
I'm suppesed be deing an article
Ra magazine entitled.
"The Un xpected Plain Face of a Model"
ihteek a picture of me
dressed in woman's clothes
during a university festival.
Tegether with Professor Hirota,
and I came to get the floppy with
the data of the picture from him...
He saved the data of the picture in a floppy?
Yes...
my husband used to input all the pictures
that he liked into the computer...
He net only saved pietures
He also saved the entrance exams of universities
the grades this s wden
and even saved the process and results of
th » chess game that he played with Mr. Morioka.
Ale 4
1 OCC
So, the killer stole all @f those floppies
after killing Professor Hirota
Which means that the criminal
killed to get a hold of them
Your:daugther's going to be applying
for Nanye Universit , isn't she'?
If you got a held of the floppies
with the entrance exams in them
she would definitely get in, wouldn't she?
NNO,
it never even crossed my mind.
Somebody else could've been here
besides us, right?
Moreover, the Professor was
also using the computer at the university.
The Professgghimself
could've taken all the floppi~S to the university!
S possible...
He never writes anything on the label so.
He may've taken all*the floppies
Besides,
this room was loeked frem
the inside, wasn't it?
Moreover,
wasn't the key to this room found here
under the notebeek that was on the floor?
Officer.
OOo matter how you look at it...
Exactly
All the possible places of entry
were locked and «he only possible space
if any was between the door and the floor,
which only a key would slide through...
If 2 rubber band or a fishing, string, were used,
it may've been possible to kill Professor Hirota,
ake the fishing string away,
Iock the door from the outside
and from the space beneath the door,
move the key to the center of the room...
It would be close to impossible
to slide the key nicely under the notebook -
What bothers me is
why despite all the books that
were scattered around the room
wasdhere only the notebook
in question on the floor
whieh was lined in a row
from the door to the phone?
The tape of.the answering
phone is a bit out of shape but...
this couldn't have possibly been used
to push the key under the notebook...
Conan Edogawa?
Remember, the boy in glasses
that I told you about last time.
You alse said that you went
to somebody's house at Beika Town?
Oh, you mean Shinichi Kudo
Right!
He's the boy of the Detective Office there!
E seems a bit different...
He's unusually co 1 headed
nd very matuse fer a child...
How about you, Akemi,
are you all nght?
Ll heard that you were in
et water or something
Don't worn
I'm deing fine.
I'm mere worried about you, Shiho!
Cut out making poison, and 98
fimd yourself a over er two.
I'm really okay!
I'm really okay,
okay
Impossible
To lock the door from the outside,
and slide the key to the center of the room.
Much less to slide it under the netebeok.
It would be impossible
even if the tape of the answer
hone were to be used...
Although there are many strange points,
f he late Professor Hirota was drunk,
it's not all that strange
if he fell together with the bookshelf.
D hit the back of his head...
Besides,
it's too dangerous to stay here any longer,
as well as useless=
orget it, Shinichi...
orget this case...
It's checkmate.
Heckmate 70
urry let's get out of here from the back doer...
Held it.
Don't you care to know
the truth of this case?
Ke I said...
No matter how you look at it.
Thisus_no accident.
It's hemicide!
After the killer murdered Professor Hirota,
he used a trick and lecked this
room up from-the inside
to make it loek like-an.accident.
I'll show yeu what the truth is,
tarting right this minute...
I'll show you that there is no case
that can't be solved in his world!!
In order to get the floppy disc
that had the data of the poison,
made by code name Sherry, alias, As Haibara,
from her older sister's-teacher,
from her older sisters teacher,
Masami Hirota
University Professor
Professor Hirota, T Nanyo University,
we headed off to his house.
Masami Hirota
University rofessor
However
The Professor was found killed inside a room
where the deer and/the windows were 0 ked.
The cause of his death,
was a vielent blow on the back of the
head wih a decorative object upon falling.
Whis is carefully schemed
behind loeked doors!!!
Kazuhiro Hosoya (43)
Insuranee Company agent
The three suspects are Mr. Hosoya.
Who came around 20:00,
Kazuhiro Hosoya (43)
Insurance Company agent
In exchange to Mrs. Hirota going out!
Kazuhiro Hosoya (43)
Insurance Com an a ent
>? OS
in exchange to Mrs. Hirota going out!
Michio Morioka (48)
Vetennarian
Vetennanan
EX EX (48)
Mr Morioka who came to
play chess around 21:00!
Michio Morioka (48)
Veterinarian
HE EX 48)
Michio Morioka (48)
Veterinarian
= 1 =< (48)
Akira Shirekura 25)
[MIC-ma
And, Mr. Shirakura who came
after he incident had occurred!!!
Akira Shirekura (25)
Model
Akira Shirokura (25)
The questions are
the key that is under the notebook
in a straight line from the telephone,
and the slightly bent out of shape
cassette tape of the.answer phone!
How on earth. did! the killer
commit the murder... . ?
Orget it, Shinichi...
orget this case...
It's checkmate.
Che kmate™?!
This is it!!
Now 11 the mem ase out en the board!?
It's an-accident, an accident!!
Professor Hirota was drunk,
fell down together with the bookshelf,
hit the back of his head violently and died!!
Judging from the circumstances at the scene
it sure can be looked at in that way
but there are 2 or 3 points that bother me...
I don't give a darn!
The room was locked,
I and moreover, the key was under the
notebook among scattered books. right'?
If there were a killer,
how did that person lock the door?
That's why we're trying to figure that out...
I'm sorry,
but I have some matters to attend tomorrow.
So if you will excuse me...
I'll be on my way toe.
I'm leaving too.
Hey, wait...
Everybody, wait up!!
Oh, uh...l just...
H Hey, what are you using
my veice suddenly fer...
I've figured if out.
How the trick of the-locked door
murder was carried ou.,
as wellsas who the killer is.
WwW What?!
H. Hey, Shinichi
Never mind just move your
mouth in keeping with my veice.
Ghads,
Iike I've been telling you...
No matter how you look at it...
No, no,
that's why amateurs are no geed...
Nn amateur...
and just who do you think you are...
The ream was indeed locked fram the inside!
Ne matter how you look at it
it looks to be an accident...
But, this trick of a locked reom
can be carried out perfectly
by using the cassette tape of
the answer phone and the chess piece!
Assette tape
chess piece
A. Are you sure, Shinichi?
Hey, stop glancing at me.
Act mere eonfident like a detective, will you...
Proof speaks mere than words,
show us. will you?
The trick that ou have imagined,
right here before us all.
Aye! Definitely.
I'll have Conan help me and
replay how it was done.
D.Do yeu know what you're deing?
Yeah trust me.
It'll werk 100% 1
I Officer,
do you happen to have a cellular on you?
Yeah. I have.one.
Lend me that glove too!
Officer Yokomizo,
I've brought the cassette tape!
It is the same as the one
used in the telephone here.
Why?
Asked fer no sueh thing...
Huh, 'but,just a while ago this boy here...
Oh well, never mind, no big thing!
May I have the tape; officer?
First. pull out the tape to a certain length...
Agh, hey!
Set.the cassette into the phone.
Of course the tape is left sticking out.
Next, straighten:the tape that is
sticking out, and pull it straight...
Go out of the door.
And pull the tape threugh the ring of the key.
Then leave that key outside the door,
take the remaining tape
and go back togthe place where
he notebook was on the floor...
Next place three pawns that are of
the same height in the shape of a triangle,
then hook the edge of the tape-that is left.
Onto the pawn that is closest to the phone,
andyplace+the notebook on it...
What a joke.
You may be trying to knock the pawn over
with the force of the tape being pulled,
but that's jTSi a paper plan.
The stand of the pawn is quite stable,
so the key will hook on to
the pawn before it falls,
and come out from under the notebeok...
It's the opposite!
I'm geing to turn the pawn
upside down after this!
Even if the head of the pawn is round,
so long as the cover of
the notebook is firm like this,
can be placed on...
You just wait and see.
I'll do it for you right now.
First, the door is locked from the outside.
Then, the key is placed on the floor
d a phone call us made...
The answer phone goes off,
and the tape is wound .."...
The key is pulled in under
the space of the door,
and moves under the notebook
that is placed in the center of the room.
It will eventually bump into the pawn,
which will then lose its balance
and he key
will go under the notebook.
It. It went in!!
See.
So. if you keep on meving the answer phone.
The tape is wound. and
he evidence vanishes .
Well? Did 1t werk?
Oh, it-was fantastic, Shiniehi.
Oh, no,
well; it's just as I thought
And. if the pawn is place at
a corner of the notebeok.
It would make it mere difficult for -
the pawn to roll under the neteboeek
Well. even if it did, it weuldn't
Iook very unnatural.
Whieh means that the one
who called and left 10 messages in the answer
phene in order to use the trick...
IS you,
Mr. Akira Shirakura!!
Then, are you the one who killed my husband?!
W. Wait...
The tape was twisted here and there,
and that serves as evidence
that the tape was used fer the trick!
Isythat right?
Just a minute, please!!
I admit that the triek just now is really superb!
But, why do») I turn out to be
he one who set it up?
All 1 did was put a lot of messages
in the answering machine
In the first place, if I were the one who did it,
I wouldn't ceme all the way back here.
You came back to get semething, didn't you'?
Yes...
You came to get he tape of the answer phene
because it had your fingerprints
Il over the place...
When I teek a leok at the tape awhile ago,
I could tell in one glance.
There were the fingernprints,.of
somebody all over the tape
And I could also tell that
his was an unprepared, impulsive murder.
You prebably met
Professer Hirota tonight
and got into an argument
You then, impulsively hit iim on the head:
Fortunately, this trick crossed your mind,
and you were able to think up
a locked door murder
which looked to be an accident.
But, since the murder wasn't
planned ahead you didn't have gloves
And you couldn't help getting
your fingerprints on the tape.
Therefore, you decided to be
the first to discover the corpse.
And.after your made Mrs: Hirota
confirm thatethe door was locked
you were waiting for atime
when you could switch tapes.
However, we found the corp @ first,
and the police arrived sooner han expected.
SO having no chidice, yew came here
Iike you said mm he tape!
You went out of the way to
Ieave your name on the tape.
So that in case you couldn't get the tape,.back,
it would make it more difficult
to see through the trick.
If there are many blank recordings,
whether you like it or not,
attention would focus on
the tape with your fingerprints on.
Youscan go ahead and check
Mr. Shirakura If you like.
He's beund to have Professor Hiretass
floppies on him somewhere.
After all, he couldn't have possibl. cheeked
the centents of the large batch
of floppies he took in sueh a short time
Then. can we start by searching your house
Mr. ShirakuraO?
They're in the dashbeard of my car
that is parked in front of this house.
All the floppies are there...
The one with the data of
e pictures is there too
Pictures?
Didn't I tell you awhilerago
that I'm supposed be deingea celumn
In a magazine entitled,
The Unexpected Plain Faee of a Medel "
and that & teek a& picture of me
dressed in woman's clothes
during a university fes ival,
ogether witiWProfessor Hirota...
but, what he had sent me
was a message that said,
There is Nething Better Than
This Plain Face of Yours."
and a picture of my face
in the past...
Your face in the past?
I had plastic surgery
when I became a model...
I changed my name teo.
I thought it was just the picture.
My face wasn't all that clear
because of the make-up and wig.
And since I was in woman's
clothes. thought it'd be funny...
I naturally couldn't give the~editor
a picture of the face of the past...
So, I came to ask the Professor
to lend me the picture .
Oh, I forgot which floppy it was that
had he picture of you
dressed in woman's clothes!
If it's the picture I sent to you,
I can get it now.
I can send it to
the editor If you liker
I got enraged at his words...
and when I snapped back e myself...
Hirota was om the floer before me.
The rest 1s as he had explained.
Verything is right to the smallest detail...
Okay, please come to the station with us, then.
Hey!
Yes, sir!
Mr. Shirakura...
Maybe it's nene of my business...
But- I think that Professer Hirota
sent you the picture of your past
because he wanted you
to have more confidence
in yourself as well as be true to yourself.
1 would've hiked to
hear those words directly
from Professor Hirota
Too bad...
Well, that was a fantastic deduction!!!
Thanks to you, the case was solved,
Mr. Agasa.
Oh, no, well.
And I would like to have the floppy
at I came to get right away...
We'll have to check out
the evidence at the station first...
So he says! What now?
Can't help it
I guess we:ll get out of here-fer now...
Okay.
Then, we'll be heading heme.
Take care!
Hey, come on, you teo!
Why?
Why didn't you
sav my sister?
Your sister
You still haven't realized?
Masami Hirota is
an alias that my sister took
from Professor Hirota's name!!
D Dent tell me
that Masamwiirota of -
one billion bank robbery is your...
Don't go
Masami Hirota
If you go,
you will be murdered
Thank you.
I'm sorry,
Conan.
Who IS the mastermind?
Where are you?
Ceme out!!
Good jeb.
Masami Hirota
Akemi Miyano.
It's a shot!!
Masamil!
Ar") you okay?!
Masami!
It is a big-organization
that is wrapped irr mystery.
I. a low rank member. know only one thing
that the color 1 the organization is black...
Black
Members of the organization like to wear...
Iack clothes like a crow...
Take this:
Iease
before they notice
I'm counting on you.
Uttle detective
0, she was your older sister...
That's right!
Hey...
With your pewer of deduction...
yeu could've easil seen through
what my sister was up to!!
Then why
hy didn't you...
Why it
Her trembling..crying voice,
brought 'backs memories
of a painful and-"sad case
that Ijhad almost forgotten.
That was
prebably the first time she
howed her real self to me...
We - =m i11TC
Ar BF 3 -_=
0) uur
BLVENT =~ (TUT)
Pp =u
- aE BE Ink +e 1
x =EHBSeE
IW ERA
7) "HP
BE ink 7
- - IT RES Oo - = -
Als TE
BE 35
- § -  . -r -
FESS TRS JF Neil Vw.
Ft =H -
AEST xx Do
HE TS
-_- as = TD - -TASA Ye-m- - - - ~-
- a - -ap-
AY So FT
- re - amy
ASS IA
-- - = Te CT lar. - -— _- u
So, 4
it ---
TILA
- - Fr "wv &«& on « ».
Iy - I I __Yp- be co ~ . ren pe,
ITN dd oe, SO PV FIEao- Zr Se A
[8% 1 - hme
- ye 090909am NN, SAe- En
\-"~. SSL
SETME
ITSL
== FT
IIS hd ee ON Va EERO Ar Clee A
-- 2 TOT,
- - - - .
5 lll Ts WW Cdl PN LO - - ad 3
Iab-t
WW se fa-&
A week later,
the floppy was sent to us from the police,
SO we decided take a look at
in on thefjcomputer right away
It's a wonder it made it through
the investigatien of the police.
All the floppies of the organization are»
plain t xt files
unless a password is entered.
They would never BB suspected.
How us it 1
Will! it came bu r
And the«data that is in here
is-not only of the poison
The real name, address and
code name of the persen
who was werking @m the poison
before lswas plaeed
in my position is.supposed to be in here 00.
The name of the person who invested in
this research should also be in here
I see
If*we do it right. we might be
able to expose them
seems like the old man
alled Hirota dropped dead...
Yeah.
It saved us the trouble of killing him ourselves.
we still don't know the whereabouts
of the woman who got away...
They're checking to see
if somebody within
the organization helped her escape.
And now,
the places the they may hide
have all been gotten rid of.
I'm sure she'll come oution her own soon.
I heard that the floppy with information
on the peisen was forfeited by the police.
That's nothing to worry about.
That floppy is a bit rigged.
WwW. What's happening?
What is this?!
- @mputer virus,
Night Baron!
What?!
The fleppy has beensprogrammed
Se that if fits booted uprwith a computer
other than the organizations.
A virus eats the data.
How careless.of me.
Then all the data is .
Fveyihing... has vanished 'No
Evensthe.computer program
- a - - -
1 sOCCIIIS Lidl we ITC yoingyriooeanmanylingyg /
around each other for a long time,
Conan Edegawa
What's this?
This is a»7.62mm
full metal jacket
Indiscriminate Murder Threat at the Stadium
Part I