Alibis, secret. codes, tricks, deals,
the mysterious organization of men in black.
UTBTIEA[ IPO. TITTLE
as 4 episo
Toda. 1s a 2-hour special program,
of many mysteries being solved.
We.also get very close to
meeting Gin and Vodka
UMBTR AND JTELVET
UTE will broadcast this specna
He sees through the ene and only truth
UTB TEAL] 77T EL FXFT
UTE will broadcast this speci
as 4 epr
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult.
Veonll
HO LAdSC IS €I1L UlisLIveu wilicell
Oetective Conan comes to the scene.
I went to an amusement park
with my childhood fnend Ran.
When I happened to witness a suspicious
dealing being carried out by a man in black.
Absorbed in watching the event,
I did not realize that another man
in black was sneaking up behind me.
1 was knocked down,
and forced'to drink poison.
When I regained consciousness
I realized that my bed. had
shrunk to that of a child's.
If they find out that Shinichi Kudo is alive,
danger will fall"upon the people around me.
Through DocterAgasa's advice,
I decide to hide my true identity.
When Ran asked me for my name.
I instantly replied, 'Conan Edogawa.
In order to gather information
on the men in black.
I decide to free-load at Ran's house,
because I find out that
her Father is a detective.
The Mysterious New Student
Teitan School
Hey, did you hear, did you hear?
A new student's comingltoClass toda. /§
No kidding?
We haven't had a n w student.
Since Conan came have we?
I wonder what kind, of person is ceming?
I hope she's cute
0. no, whether itibe »girl or boy
the main thing isrpersonality! .
Hey Conan?
What kind of person do you
think will come. Conan?
Wonder
Maybe a reticent bookworm type?
You think it's going to be a bey, then...?
Ayumi, you didn't get to see
the st "dent in the teachers' room?
But got the name
It was Haibara
Haibara?
Rig ht-H-Haibara! q
An unusual name!
Not as unusual as Conan's though...
Leave me alene
Heresthey come.
Oh, it's a girl! Wow!!
She's...
Cute! Whoopee!
Sit down everyone!
Yes!!
What's the big deal... over a girl...
Hi, everyone,
this is Ms. An Haibara who will
be studying with us starting teday!
Let's all welcome her to our class!
Yes!!
Hew energeticyyou all are.
Where shall we seatsyou Ms.iHaibara...
Mrs. Kobayashi!
Over here, the seat next to me ls open
Here.
Yeah...
What's with her... She's so stuck up!
Essure is cool...
She's robabl. nervous!
All right, everyeme. Class ime!
Yes!!
S. Haibara...
Let's: go heme together! Okay?
Let her be! That stuek up chick!
Where do you live?
You moved here, didn't you?
Don't be hesitant, we-ll walk you heme!
Beika 2-22...
Hat's where I live...
What is it?
Oh no, nothing
Strange, Beika 2-22 is my address.
But, there are no condos or
artments nearby
I wonder if there was
residence called Héibara...
Hey! What's the matter?
Nuns you ma
for that stuck up chick?
No way. No darn way!
Youth Detective Squad?
Ou're members?
Yeah
We work da. , in andrday~out solving
difficult cases by request of our clients!
Why don't you jein us too, Ail
Is Conan a member too?
Yeah+.he's something like my henchman!
The requests all go into
Genta's shoe case!
35354 a
The requests are to be put in here!
We haven't told the teachers
bout it theugh
They alread now bout it...
We get loads of mails from guys
who have unsolved mysteries everyday.
Here's nothing inside...
There usual area let of mail
in here but I guess net today...
u never have mail in there...
A Tr - rm ;
Play soccer at the pa k!
Let's, lets!
Good ideal
y wait for
Hey, wait-for me
A request!!
Ally
It says that they'li*be.waiting
for us in grade} class A
Then, let's go!
To grade 1, class A!
Come with us 00, Al, quick!
What, disappeared from home?!
My brother suddenly disappeared.
Don't tell me he's been kidnapped?
Wait 2 minu e
There was a similarmcase once before
h, come to think of it...
Dent tell me-that-the brether of yours is a cat?
No!!
My brether.who.is 10 years older than me!!
He disappeared a we k ago at sundown,
saying he was wing to dro)
by at his friendrs house.
And he never came back since!!
The police set out to search for him too,
couldn't find him...
I thought that
maybe you guys could help me...
Have you received any. threat calls
Calls? Nope nething) like that.
Maybe he just ran away from heme?
He would never sun away frem heme!
Ecause: because...
Me and my brother, we get along really well.
But, your brother may-have had
his reasons
Let's to over to his house!
We'll talk later
Thank you!
Okay!
The Youth Detective Squad are on our way!
Let's o, All!
He, it's that house where
th xpelice car is parked.
Wen a police car
This is a standard police car...
But, it's been modified nicely like a police car.
Oh, is that right?
Which one's the radio?
See, it's the one by the passenger's seat.
I wonder if
11 can ask for eels over rice with that?
I'dalike a pizza.
Ey: what did yeu guys core here for..." 88
All right, if something comes up,
Iease contact therstation
Thank you.
Hank you.
My, Toshiya... Are they your friends?
Hello!
Eme on in
'Toshiya. would you In e-me
to-serve you something?=
Oh, please don't bother
because we'll be leaving right away
h. is that right...
Il be in the kitchen, then...
Mm Sorry.
Mem's preoccupied about brether right now.
I know, let's hurry to your brother's room.
Yeah.
Wow, t's so neat andrclean.
Are we going toilook for clues here?
Exactly!
This is!
Take a leok at this!
Super premium priced air shoes!
- Don't you guys get semething wrong?
Don't mess around too much!
But, now we know that Toshiya's brother was
knowledgeable of famous brand products.
Was your brother that ind of person?
Onder... I dost knew: but Uncle gav
him these as a gift from the United States.
I getvOne too...
Now we know that he wasn't.
Right!
Hey, Conan, we're getting
nowhere standing here
See, sO ma. be he.ran
away {rem home after all.
that can't be...
See, this wallet is your brother's, isn't it?
Yep!
If heis.going to run away frem.heme,
he'd at least ta ee his wallet: wouldn't he?
So then, where is.he ....?
He either get into an accident
or get mi ed up in same incident.
Oh no! What's with this piéture?!)
There are many strange pictures under-the bed!
Wow, talk about the pits!
Who drew t 1s pict
1ICaSsSo...
Ow! Yes! That's a copy o
Picasso's "Crying Woman!"
Gogh, Monet; Gauguin... . Utrillo...
They all look genuine!
Brother drew all of these!
He was in the art club of his high scheel,
and was good at copying
ther peoples=paintings...
Hey, don't tell me he's been +1dnapped
and being forced to draw pictures.
Possible if the masterpieces are copied
and exchanged for the reabenes...
0, that's not possible either...
His sketches are indeed good but he needs
a bit-mere practice as to color'and touch.
It's net goodenough to be counterfeit yet .
Amd this is not a kidnapping fer ransem either.
Because if it were so,
it would be easier to kidnap yeu
than to kidnap your brother
who is in high school.
What bothers me, is this painting.
I've seen him somewhere before
Soseki Natsume...
Yes! Bretlver was a great fan of Soseki!
He-liked that painting se much that he even
entered it in the community exhibition.
But, everybed. was complaining about it
because was a copy of his picture...
@nly one weird weman praised it...
A weird woman'?
Yeah she was wearing a broad-brimmed
hat and dressed in black from head te toe.
When was that?!
When did youfsee that weman?!
About 10 days ago.
Were there any men dressed
in blaek besides her?!
Here were two...
on't tell me that
What's the matter, Conan?
It couldn't be that
MN -sosass
Hey», fake me to a place near here
that your brother is likely to go!!
His wallet, and his train pass
are in his drawer.
Ven his bicycle is at the front door.
It's highly probable that your brother
was called out near here and kidnapped!!
I see, so if we search the vicinity
aybe we'll find some clue...
Come on, hurry!
Hey wait, Conan'!
Onan!
A week ago at sundown
I wonder I don't think she came
because I was at the sheep all the time,
but. don't remember seeing a weman
dressed f@blaek
Ithough I'm.sure she'll standout,...
We've gone to all the place
he may been called out to
Iike coffee shops, game centers,
department stores and back alleys
There is nobody who?saw himrthat day .
Nor did anyone see*theweman in black...
hat am I getting;all worked up for...
I'm sure the police already checked
Il the places he eould be...
e have too little to go on
Isn-t_.there anything Anything else...
Conan, would you mind%f I step by
at the convenience store?
MM thirsty
Wow, it's so coel!!
Thank you very much.
Hello, there. It'll be 430 yen, please.
Thank yeu very much.
A "Seven Mild".
Your change is 770 yen.
Thank you very much .
What's the matter, Conan?
ne pouygiilt util, VINE PpdUnR Of LligdicelLies
with @ thousand yen bill... Strange.
Maybe he didn't h ve llcose change?
If he had a thousand yen» he could've
bought it at the vending machine outside.
He didn't have §@ go through.the trouble
of waiting @8 the .check out counter.
Maybe the cigarette he wanted was sold out?
Will you show me the 1.00 £en bi
that the man just gave you?
Never mind, just let me see it!
Agh. Hey!!
There's no watermark!
Aybe he's...
What's with you an ay .¢!
Conan?! What's wrong?
Callithe police. This 1s counterfeit .
Hey. wait!
Agh, wait Conan!
Wait up!
Hey, Conan, What's the matter
What is it about the-countesfeit that y u were
talking about ? the convenience storex
That'man... bought cigarettesw
with a. 1000 yen, right?
He did so, although there was a vending
machine right outside the store
and went out of his way to line up 1
at the counter.
In other words, he usedva: thousand yen
that the machine wouldn't accept!
A counterfeit that the human eye
is likely to overlook!!
But, that has nething to do
with brother disappearing. does it"?!
It has everytRimg to do with I him?
You remember. dent you?
The portrait of a certain person
at your brether had drawn...
oseki Natsume...
Come to think of it. the thousand yen bill
has the face of Soseki Natsume omit...
Then, then, brothers...
Maybe somebody s
through his talent. for art,
and has im confined some place,
fercing him to make counterfeits.
We can't be sure if that man-s invelved or net,
but maybe they're the guys who shrunk
my body... Those men in black...
Runk your bedy...
I'm only joking! Joking!
I was just teasing you guys!
What a fix... I can't get them involved
iW such &@ dangerous case either...
HI lose sight ef'tilé man if I don't hurry
All nght then!
1 use this. then
Conan!
Hey you over there!!
You dropped something!
HIS 1S YyOUIl 1. UUU yCllll. Isl tL IL.
Conan!
See! He dropped his meney
So, came after him to give it bac <to him!
OQoao
t*s*n0 un...
tss+no fun
But. what're you going to.do
out looking his brother.
S gettingrlate too...
We've no choice but to come
ack and continue tomorrow...
You guys go on ahead to Toshiya's
house and pick up your bags!
I've got to stop'by some place first.
Wiha + Come back right awa. . ekay.
Okay. see you!
Okay, then... I caught him!
That man took the 1,000 yen
with the transmitter on it!!
I have to do now, is to pursue
im with these glasses...
Ail, hurry or we'll leave you behind!
He,just-may take me to where they
the men in black are!!
Oh, the station.
A stand?!
No...
Yeah... That man wearing
a black hat came here!
He bought a cansof 110 yen
coffee with a theusand yen.
H me, just as 1 theught __.
He wasnetéfriendly, and besides=&
there was a'strange-seal stuck on. the bill.
He*was a weirdo.
And, do yo knew which way he went?
. After-he bought-thé-can of
e was using-the phone-over there
He placed Icose.changeion-the phone up...
and was talking on the phone
until he used it all up
aybe for about 10 minutes...
Did he by any chance ask you to give him
the change in 100 yens and 10 yens?
I'mixed.500 yen'and-gave-him-89Ofyen...
The change that he got at
the convenience stere is 770 yen.
One 500 yen coin and two 100 yen coins,
one 50 yen coin and two 10 yen coins
If the 890 yen change that
he received at the stand is added.
The money that he can use to
make the phone call would be
five 100 yen coins and eleven 10 yen coins.
That is, 610 yen all together.
F he had mere lease change
on him. it be mere than that...
He used"more than 610 yen for a call
approximately 10'minutes long?
Was he making a long distance call?
Den't tell me he went somewhere far away
te the place where his
Iephone partner is waiting...
No, .if he call from ublic phone
to.a cellular phone
it would cost 10 yen per 9 secends...
here is still that pessibility
Hey, kid? are you an acquaintance
of 'the man wearing the black hat?
Es, sort of...
Oh, great. Please give this to him.
50 yen?
He was in such a rush that
he forgot to take this 50 yen change
from the ticket vending machine.
Which ticket vending machine was it?
The one for the Tohto Line, over there.
Do you know which.button he res ed?!
I don't know...
He put in one 500 yen*cein, and
I sauna-lot of loese change came out.
But. was more concernedrof
the rubbish at his feet tha
I didn't notice anything else...
Thank you! I'll go after him! Bye!!
Eah...
He probably get mere than
three coins as change
If he insertedeS5S00ayen,
and got change that included a 50 yen coin
and three more. theastatiemwould be
500 yen minus 320 yen, the answer is
2 one 100 yen coin, one 50 yen coin and
three 10 yen coins. making a total of 5 coins.
A change of 180 yenrwould come out.
It's Daitohma Statien!!!
PR - ==]
A BE ~~ 3 T= om ==
JLT AL == I.-
dd mT» ow = - 7
OD: 33
of - V Se oul - "a
Hens only a=
DP us~
BL VA NT = - 13 TL
Ins';
BELT
BESAEAX TR RE
a pe -y - gg- - I LT Se- - A - -
SHNTeve=a WY JR AY
x ERE
VE ERA
Mold SNVIPRN = JI DD - SC
yy "EY
-» eo
-y cer 8 Es -_- Sc
NN BE
- = = -_- - -
"E/E BA JID - 2
mR B-oTR. oex~> DOD
Ag =F X73 ==
Sg%... TT SJ
Lo - Xv
=EERE3E
'Hs.
RAF -
APc=E_ 5
SASF TTD BOL SL\BEAITAICT
ICES JIL Je. I Ae" FR ae ate lL rd TFC
- NO ems ny, J ENS
7 °S J SL
{ I __ Q I '44 Li
IIXAS I ee CD TE EEO mn CC AS ae 7
--— TN - -y
FS EEC, dB CT -
<< A Li TL
an I 557
ht SE ==
an 3852
- - Jrikt
Iab-t