Org Beach/Les Angeles/San Diego
1 - 4 oe - LJ - Co - » - O O *
ac /Los Angeles/San Diego
acn/Los Angeles/San Diego
We » Pr -echy
CIVLUD AI é 11 WIT
! eng Beacbhbal s/ -v» Diego Bo
Why you...
What did you do to him?!
Will you be in trouble If he
isn't around, after all?
That phone...
The super kick shoe...
The are air-thin s that the Docter
made-for-you, aren't they?
With the cooperation of the Dector
you can be playing your rele
astyouth detective with that bedy of yours
In other words.
Docter Agasa is the life line
or the present Shinichi Kudo...
Is that-why you killedhhimr.!
Well. I wonder?
If it bothers yeu why don't you go
over to his house and see for yourself... «
Doc. please be
Maybe the men in black
re still inside...
Nothing seems to be
different from the usual...
It doesn't seem like the men in black...
e here...
Dec!
Doctor Agasa'?
Huh? I theught I heard Shinichi's voice?
Shinichi, what is it...
0 you need anything...
D,Dec .
So, \ ourre okay?
Okay . What's up...
Oh. I'm really sorry, truly I am!!
- - AS
I°VE LJEEII IlllU VVLJIRIIIH
with the computer recently,
that I guess the telephone line was busy!
Mshome 3.
Oh, welcome baek, Ail
How was schoel?
Was quite fun...
She deceived me!!
#Well, you can't blame her for the fact
that you didn't know my address.
How should I knew
never sent anything to your house.
I even brought the New.Year's
greeting card over in persen.
Never mind that. Who on earth is she?
Didn't-she tell yeu'?
That she us a member
of the black organizatien,
drank the same poison as you
nd became small...
Strance
She told me she'd tell you herself,
so not to say anything to yeu...
WwW Wait, Doc.
Oh, I thought up the name
Ail Haibara with her.
We took it from the name
of a woman detective!
The 'Hal of her name meaning "gray" in
Japanese, was taken from Cordilia Gray...
Ail" was taken from,/the "I" in Vioshosky.
1 advised her that the
Japanese character for love "Ar"
YWoOullu Ue LuLler Lali 11 Ml
of the character for sadness, but...
Why is a weman involved with
the men in black living in your house!
He rescued me
in the rain outside your house where I had collapsed
Dr. Agasa found me
In front of my heuse?
Did you know?
The organization had sent investigators
to your house about twice.
Out of the people who drank that poison,
only your death wasn't verified.
1. the inventor of the peison, naturally
ame along on the investigation
But, the house was dusty
and there didn't seem to
be anyone living, there,
so the first time, we left right away
We went on our second
investigatien a month later...
It was dus. as usual
and it didn't seem different
from what. we saw before...
I was starting to think
that you had died after all.
1 got goose bumps hen I saw
the strange thing in your clothes drawer.
Your childhood clothes hat was
in the drawer a month ago was gone.
Whole lot of it too
During -theJstage of animal experiment,
only one mouse regressed
to childhood without=dying,
s@ it 'was easy to establish
the following hypothesis.
The possibili. that Shinichi K do was
given APTX4869,
and regressed, becoming) a child!!
Then the guys of the organization
know of my having became a child...
Thank me...
I rewrote "Confirmed deadgionyyour data.
I decided to let you live because
you're very interesting research material
If 1 report you to the organization,
the chances of yeu being killed
before getting to me are.greater...
Well, if they find out that the one
who rewrote your data is me
the one who betrayed them, they may
start getting suspicious again but
BB. Betra. ed?!
1-5.
One of the reasons why I gave that
peisen that was still in the testing stage,
to a human on my own aecerd,
was beeause I was getting sick of them. but,
the real reason, was my older sister...
Ider sister?
He was killed...
She was killed by the hands of
the men of the organizatien.
No matter hew much I asked them
they wouldn't tell me why hey killed her...
And. I went against them saying
that I was going to pestpone my research:
until they gave me a formal explanation...
Naturally, since I went against the organization
they confined me to a certain room in the lab
1 was to wait until the higher ups
decided what to do with me.
Thinking that I may as well drink the poison
if I was going to Be killed anyway,
§ drank the APT X4869 that 1 had hidden on me.
Fortunately. the pois 1 tee in
ap attempt te ll myself
transformed my body to that of a child's
and freed me from
the handcuffs that were on me.
And, I escaped from the tiny dust shu &
Having no place to go,
the only person I could
think efsgoimg to was
hinichi Kude...
onl \ ou
I figured-since-we~wereni'n¢the*same boat.
You'd be-able-te-understand-my predicament
You've get to be kidding!!
Just how am I supposed to
understand somebody whe
made peison to kill people?!
H.,Hey, Shinichi...
Do you know what you did!
Are you aware of just how many people died
because of the peisen you invented
I couldn't help it
I hadvno intention of making peison...
What?!
Well, come now,
she left the erganizatien already.
Since she's the one who made the poison,
she ceuld'come 'up with 'an antidete
without difficulty too, right?
The data for the poisen is all in the research lab.
I couldn't pessiblk remember
Sue massive amount of data!
Tell me where that researeh lab is then!!
O use...
Look at the evening paper 3 days ago.
This is about the mysterious fire
that burned down. the pharmaceutical cempany!
So. there would be nothing left
even if wejgo there!
W, what?
The organization get mid of it fearing
At this rate, everysfacility that I was
involved in wouldebe closed down...
Which means that these guys are after you...
Yes, they're probably going
berserk looking for me...
Without even knowing that
I've transformed this way
But, if they keep using
this peisen €& ill poeple,
there is no guarantee that people who
will regress-like us will eventually appear.
The organ: atien who has
a pieture 6 my childhood ays
will definitely find me
What will you do?
Will you chase me out of here
because I pose a threat to all of you?
High school detective,
Shinichi Kudo...
What will you do?
Will you chase me out of here
because I pose a threat to all of you?
Igh schoel detective, Shinichi Kude...
s... 1 made the poison
am-an accemplice to murder.
The organi -atien is also after me.
1 am an.extremely dangerous
€rson to have amund...
Theregis no reason why you
should keep me near you.
If they find out about you,
it'll be a matter of time before
they find out about me.
I hate to impose on Doc,
but I'll have you stay here as a grade
schooler whether you Ike it or not.
It's more bothersome to have
you hanging around outside.
H my, how nice of you...
How about the safety of your parents?
No need for worry,
they are also members of the organization
I was told.they died of an accident
oon after I was born...
hich means your family is...
Me and my older sister who
I didn't get to see too often
Unlike me. who was studying in the US
roug or ers 0 e organiza ion,
My si ter was, constantly under surveillance
because she was living in Japan...
until my sister started
working for the organization,
in an attempt to set me
ree of them, she was...
geing to an ordinary school. 1 .
Wad esdinary fiends,
Come to think of it. several
years before:-she was killed...
She sent me 2 or 3 floppies
with. pictures of whensshe went on a trip...
1 looked through them at the research lab
and sent it back to her right away but...
the floppy that I» lad aha data of
the poisen in. get lest after that.
I looked all over for it but couldn't find it.
I see
So the floppy with the data of
the peisen may be mixed up
ameng the floppies that you
sent back to your sister.
So, if we search the place
here your sister used to live...
No use!
The condo that my sister was living in
was gotten rid of by the organizatien
ight after her death,
not everything was cleared out...
But, she said that the person
who put the pictures into the. floppies,
was the professer that went
n the tnp together with her...
so, maybe...
Youtdon't know who that professer is?
Asami Hirota of Nanyo University...
Asami Hirota
But, I don't knew where he lives...
All we have todo is ask at the universi...
All right!
Let's get with it right away!
Uh, hello, could you look up the phone
number to Nanyo University, please?
What?
The floppy with the picture of the trip in it?
Who are you?!
Oh, well you see I'm...
What's yeur sister's name?
Kemi...
Akemi Miyano
Oh, an acquaintance of Akemi!
If.it's the floppies with the pictures
of the trip that I went with them,
If it's the floppies with the pictures
of the trip that I wentawith them.
Masami Hirota
University Professe
she gave.them baek to me!
Masami Hirota
University Professor
A strange floppy seems to have
been mixed up'amongsthem, though
Masami Hirota
University Professor
A strange floppy seems 0 have
been mixed up'amongsthem, though...
A strange floppy?
No deubt about it!
That's' the one!!!
Is it all right for us to go and
piek up hat floppy from now?
Yes, I don't mind.
I'm expecting a few guests soon.
But if you:don't mind coming after them...
Then, we'll be there in 3 hours
What. ouire 'own: to
stay over at Dr. Agasa's?!
What-on earth are you doingr
Dinner's ready fand we've been
waiting-for-you to come home, Conan!
Dr. Agasa says that he made an interesting
game and wants me to play it with him!
I'll be home by tomorrow morning.
I'm sorry. Ran!
Hey, Wait!
You're sure good at acting like a child.
Yeah... but, I'm net as geod as you
who can fake crying like a baby...
It's 150 kilometers to Shizuoka...
I wonder if we can get there in 3 hours
Hey, Doc.,
be on your guard with that chick.
That chick, you mean AI?
Yeah, although shes saying
she fledMrom the organization,
she's not telling us her real name or age,
and even if we ask her
what the orgamzation us after.
She insists on net knowing a thing...
What she said a while ago,
could be a lie to lure us into a trap.
She doesn't look that way, though...
And. anether thing that
bethers me is, Masami Hireta...
I've heard this name'semewhere before.
Good evening.
Oh, Mr. Agasa.
Oshiko Hirota (53)
Professer Hirota's wife
My husband told me about:you.
Toshiko Hirota (53)
Professer Hirota's wife
Please come in.
Have your guests already left?
Yes, it seems that my husband s
student were here just before you...
Dear?
wean
Strange,
I wonder what hers deing inside,
with t '3 door leaked?
It won't open
Do you have a spare -ey to this roem?!
No, I haven't...
Then. help me break this door open, Doc!!
What?!
Quick!
Here goes!
One mere time!
H.Hey .
Heave-ho!.
Heave-ho!
An accident...
you say?
Yes...
we canitibe 1004 sure yet bu...
it isivery likely to be an accident
we can't be 1006 sure yet but...
it s very likely to be an accident.
Inspector Yokomizo
Shizuoka Prefectural Police
Officer Yokomizo!!
The cause of death seems
o have been this object #.
It may have hit him when he fell...
Just as I thought...
He fell?
In other words
Mr. Masami Hirota wanted to take
something that was on the bookshelf,
and placed his foot on the shelf.
He lost his balance and fell, beekshelf and all.
Then, he bumped the back of his head onto that
object that had already fallen to the floor
and it killed him As proof of that
The door of this room, and the windows located
above the door were all locked securely!
Besides,
the only key there is to this.room,
was scattered over the floor with the books
under the notebook...
Professor Hirota, locked the door himself,
and died because of
the accident, right after that?
No matter how you look at 1
He could've been killed by someone.
It was just made to look likeran accident.
You're the boy
that's staying with Mr. Moun, right...
Oh, yes. That's right.
He's the son of a relative of mine.
See, look at this phone,
it's toppled on the floor, right?
That's because
the phone.book fell togetherwith the bookshelf
\ Then, why is the reeeiver not off the heo «.
Although the phone is upside down
and it is camouflaged with the book on top of. it.
Semeene has deliberately
essed this room up
1, Then, s this homicide...
Wait.
If so, this weuld be
a murder behind leckedadoors!!
Locked doors?!
Murder behind .
Right
the doors were all locked,
and the key to this room was found here!
Then who?
Who killed my husband?!
Please calm down, Mrs. Hirota.
Were there any suspi€ious people
who came to see him,tenight?
RT wT
TT€'D6€IIID LU lldVE lldU Q U! '4
guests including Mr. Agasa.
An acquaintance of mine teld me
that she had mistakenly given
Professor Hirota her floppy,
I came to get it back.
So, I'm sure that it is beside that computer
All the floppies are gone.
A wholesbu ~h of-them.
At this rate, maybe all the data
in this computer ls also erased
WwW. What's with that girl?
S,She's also the child of my relative.
H Hey. Al. Den't touch!
At any rate, Bhave nothing
fo do with this murder!
No, one would be stupid enough to bring children
ong when thinking of committing murder, righ
That's true...
Listen<llittle lady
I don't want you touching anything in this room!
Go to the room next» deer and
wait there quietly with yeur Grandpa!
Understand?
I'm still 52. too young
to be called grandpa, den't y Tahink...
Hey,
don't tell me they took the fleppies?
Very likely.
Because the lest record of
the data of the poison,
as well as the record of the parcel that
I sent back to my sister about the same time.
Are all left behind at the organization.
I see
So, they could ve predieted that
since you fledifrem the organization,
you would stop by here
to come get the data...
The organization came+here to look fer the data,
and shuck in here,
but was seen by Professer
Hirota, so they killed him
Not bad.
No, let's not jump to conclusiens 00 fast!
First, let's ask about the people
who came here tenight.
We'll think about everything else later!!
You were at a community meeting?
together with a neighbor of mine,
- pp em ee a
HON LU. UV 0 £0.UVU, 101 ee mould...
Which means that you
haven't met the guests who,
came to see your husband tonight?
No, all except the first persen who, came.
Who came just when I was ready to leave
My husband said it was: one of his students.
I think he said the
person's mame was Hosoya
Okay!
Bring that persen called Hosoya who
is a student of Prefesser Hirota,
and was here tonight!
Yes, sir!
Do you know the names of
the other people who came here?
I wonder...
1 have no idea, exeept fer Dr. Agasa who
called just before I was ready to leave...
Although, my husband did say
2-3 of his students were coming
Which means that we have no cheice but to
check on all of his students who were here...
Hey, blin ing on this phone here.
This IS an answer phene. isn't it?
We could find something out
if we listen to this, right?
Yeah
13 messag
13 message
Thirteen...
There sure are a lot of messages.
Ello...this 1s Shirokura...
Professor Hirota?
The promise was for tonight? ~
Who is this 'Mr. Shirokura?
I've met Mr. Shirokura before.
E's still .a young man...
Strange.
Hy is.the tape cut off here and there...
his 1s Morioka...
Hat time
I supposed...to go there... t
Who is he?
Know Mr Morioka. too.
He is my husband's first student and...
comes over a lot...
Do you have the address and phone
number of Mr. Shirekura and Mr Monoka?
Uh, I'm Shirokura...
What's the matter?
Akira Shirokura(25)
Model
What's all this commotion about...
Akira Shire ura:(25)
Model
Did something happen here?
Akira Shirokura (25)
Medel
Model
Professor Hirota has been murdered
by someone.
What 4!
Elle, ht s Shirokura
I've got other matters to attend to tomorrow,
so I'll head on over there now.
You placed 10 messages in here
and Mr. Morioka placed 2...
Mr. Shirokura, you sure left a lot of
messages on the answer phone, didn't you?
Ike I'm telling you...
I came here directl
because he wouldn't answer,
no matter how many times I called!
Oh. all right
But, why did something
Iike this happen to him...
This is the 13th, and last message...
Uh, this is black... . life.
I'd like to come over to explain
ur new... Insurance plan...
What time should... over...?
I will call... again... later...
Nn Insurance agent...
Altheu PR the voice is a bit
is wa, Ttalking is...
his velee IS
odka...
Sigh... Now
H.Hey
hen this case involves
hese guys, after all
No he possibility of them having
donefanything have decreased...
If they had came here to get he floppy,
they wouldn't have done
something as stupid as to leave
their voices on tape at the scene of a crime.
It would be a cinch for them to pick up the floppy
without even creating such
a locked-in-room situation...
They left the message on
the answer phone so that,
in case Professer Hirota was heme,
it would ease-his suspicion of them,
and make it easier fer them
to carry out"their purpose.
I'll bet they're all panie « now.
Because they can't come get the floppy.
If so, then they'll be here seen
Yeah...
we were right to move
your Velkswagen elsewhere.
They may be somewhere near here already.
It hid I
Ex EP =
& = age BE) We w _ VD
Bo -R
BL SH T-F-ET=0
daa» TE
& BR =F
BAT 55 <02 BE vr Ad
=m, vc 00m) BBL. Tol
fififif
fx] *%
-< = FT Xess
XL T=
- = ~~ cops)
=_, 59
ATT m= TT
VAT = Jo /72/
- .t --r3 . wn CSL
Hol. La UX val BEI 1, C
So ZET 7D EBB OL TL GATRAITT
» ms TUN Y gm _ a
SEE E
AX TAX. Hd
=lSIEB TE
VITA
2 TY PoE 08
- aC MT eel AES Tries
HIT ZXZT PRiBoe T&T
___ Jd
Elm-C
WW sz fa-&=