Alibis, seeret codes, tricks, deals,
the mysterious organization
of men in black.
Today's,stage is a jam pac ed stadium.
Fear closes in on the cheers
of the audience.
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene
Indiscriminate Murder Threat
at the Stadium Part I
Hey. donst you think that the! dancing
Iion looks like Inspector Megure?
Huh?
Just what de you think)
you're doing. Takagi!
Very true!
See! It does, doesn't it!
It also looks like Genta!
Ow dare you!
See, you look just like it!
WwW you...
Hold it!!
Hey, we'd better hurry,
r the game w.ill"start!
Yeah, I know!
Let's go, Mitsuhiko!
Okay
Hey, Ran, one mere serving!
What? Anether servings
This is your sixth serving!
What's the big deal.
After all it's New Year's Day.
T me drink all I like .
You're always drinking
Il you Ii e anyway...
Oh, and where is the little one?
Conan went to wateh a soecer game.
He said it's the Emperor Cup Finals.
What's the fun of geing out to watch
a soccer game on New Year's Day...
What better way is there to
spend New Year's Day than
to watch Yoko on TV
while drinking sake.
Here goes!
Treat me. Treat me.
Stone, paper, scissors squad!
What's this program about?
A special New Year's program, maybe?
And besides. I den't think Yoko's coming
on today until the Afterneon Drama Special.
What?!
She's net coming on until this afternoon?!
Oh, what a bummer .
I guess lsll take a sneeze, so
ake me up when the drama starts
ey- Dad! You'll catch a cold...
New Year's Da.
National Stadium
Who's the one that just seared?
What's his name?
Hide of the Spirits!
Hide struck afleading ab Naoki°s centering! ,
Just as expected of Hide!
Yes! If it were not (or his wound,
he would have surely been chosen
as one of the players on thermlapan team!
Talking about the Japan team...
It's too bad they couldn't win
the World Cup
To think that they couldn't win
even one game Is so vexing!
Iwender why all the adults were
so excited about it too?
Dad said that t's ike a dream
that Japan got to pla.!
It seems to be a super fantastic match...
u idiots
The World Cup is one of the-world's
greatest events in which
natiens: all over the werld,
compete with their entire heart and seul!
It's no wonder that:the Japanese
are making a big thing of it!
I'm vexed that
Japan couldn't win.one game...
it only goes to showithe walls
of the world are not easy to break!
How can you be so reserved?
R= ~y » ¥
PpLiiou re ane ole wii 1IVOORCU Lie 111UsSlt
vexed after we finished watching TV!
Exactly, exactly!
You were having a fit on
the table of Dr. Agasa's home!
1.1 couldn't help it.
DeCauscepdlilLicipaltniyggiin ue vvoria ow.up
was my dream since I was a kid!
What are you talking about Conan
ince you were a kid
ou're still a kid, Conan
When on earth did you
begin watching seccer, anywa. ?
Ell, that us, you see
h? What's so funny. Haibara
Mr=renown detective, you turn into¥a mere
child when it comes to soccer, den't you
eave me alone...
Didn't you come here to watch the game?
I just came here because-you all did...
Fe -_- =, \ & \
111IEY RIHTUW Wildl 1 UsCU "Lu 1OUR TIRE
when I was a child-you know.
If I were to be seen on the TV screen...
they'll find me on the spot. If that
happens wouldn't it put you into a fix too?
That's why I wasn't really
Pp lo ceming. but . .
Hey...
here Thiswway, it wouldn't matter
If you're were to be seen en camera, night?
FOLgctLr about Lier or now. dalid
Iet's watch the game, 'he game!
Soecer games are best seen live!
H... I'll bet it hasn't even cro
your mind that you are already deeply
involved in a secret project thatour
organization has been working on
ince half a century ago...
Switch from camera 2 to camera 1...
Camera 1 den't miss the goal scene!
Camera 4 what are you deing?
Mr. Kaneko...
Hat is it, at 'a busy time like this...
Will you please take this call
The call? Is it for me?
He's been repeatedly saying that
you'd regret it if you don't take the call
hoots, what a~nuisance...
s this is Directer Kaneko...
10. who are yeu .
Ml say this only once so listen close
00 = t(. = ogg*v 1° 2, G Q o
LUURN al LIT DUUY 1 LIT HHTUNiL 1uvy wiv
Is leaning out against the railing,
right up ahead to the right
side of the bleachers.
What?
Hey, camera 13\is open how, isn't it?
Will you zoom the bleachers to the right???
H .yes sir...
Hey, camera 13!
Ery composed
People watching:sueh an interesting
game would normally react like that...
Go, go Hide!
Hang my there!
Right there, Rames!
Doesn't your heart ever skip a beat
or don't you ever get excited?
Donjt you have such emotions?
I wonder, maybe if you look around
VCCI vwlililClll youTcarliic 10
class the first day.
It would normally be embarrassing
to study among kids
ut you didn't:seem to mind at all...
ost naturally...
You were here...
I remained compesed because
ou were in that class...
You, who are in the same
redicament as I...
eah, I see them, 5 kids...
The bey on the left edge
wearing the blue cap?
What about that
can. I ask you onexquest
What
How old are you anyway?
4 years old
What?
I'm-just kidding...7-I'm-actually...
What is it?
What's the matter?
The ball suddenly bounced and .
Conan?!
Ah, hey!
There are two heles in the ball...
Dent tell me that
You shouldn't be in here!
Ut. I dropped my cap!
Your cap?
If so, it should be left somewhere
this rubber court
Here it is! This 1s:it...!
Here you go, sonny .
He cap that you dropped...
H,Hey, sonny, just what
do you think yeu're doing?!
He) What's your problem. sonny'?!
This is... 2762 millimeter bullet...
full metal jacket...
It's a gun! A gun! Semebedy in this
stadium fired a gun, Inspector Megure!
And, where is the victim whe was shot?
Nebody was shot, just a soccer ball was
eccer ball
I did as I was told by the man who
called and was looking at the ball
that rolled right below the boy in the
front row wearing a blue cap with monitor.
Then. the ball sT™denly bounced
and the air leaked out of the ball...
I'm sure the ball was shot by a gun!
But, maybe it was a prank where
Nn air gun was used...
most likely a Tocaref...
Huh? C.Conan?
The Youth Detective.Squad ai our service!
Ome off it, yeu guys...
ou guys were here too, eh...
It's her, right? The child with the Blue
Pp that you were leeking at...
Y.Yeah . right...
Which means that you guys
were watching the whole thing too?
The ball suddenly bounc
d air leaked! out of it .
So. I went dewn 'into the fiel'?
Right away and found this...
» A bullet that pierced through
the rubber court!
What?.
7.62 millimeter bull
ussian made, eh...
A Russian gun that can be loaded
with this bullet would be one that
is frequently smuggled via China into
Japan, mest probably a Tocaref...
It is extremely deadly and has
a:high capability of killing its target
Gun fire was net heard, so the
killer probably used a sileficer...
W Why are you so knowledgeable...
of course Pops told me: all of this...
Ghads... What's with him teaching
kid semething like this
The game's off! ff!
Stop the game right this minute and
evacuate the spectators
as well as the players!
Yes, sir!
N.No!
The man who called said if we do
anything funny like stop the game or let
the spectators go.he'd sheot
indiscriminately throughout the stadium. .!!
What?!
And, what does the criminal want?
He says to have 50,000,000 yen put
into a bag and ready by half-time.
As to where to take it, he said
he'd call back later .
Did he demand that of you people?
S, to Nichwun TV
Could it be semeone who has
grudge: against Nichiun TV...
r, could it be a terrorist...
Do you have any idea as
to the voice of the man?
T, The thing is, his voice is muffled
nd hard to make out...
He probably had a cloth over the
receiver or was wearing a mask
And, didgyou get
the 50.000.000 yen eady
es...it's on its way here...
Okay! Scatter plain clothes officers
through the audience!
Our chance is when the criminal calls!
The mement he calls, nab everyone
who is using the phone!!
Yes, sir!!
It's dangerous here, you folks go on home.
Hey, is that kid wearing the blue cap a girl?
Y how rude
Can't you tell by lookingyatiher?
Strange . he man who called said,
the boy in the blue cap to the
treme left of all the 5 kids .
Please wait; Inspector Megureb!
It's not a good idea to nab the
criminal just like that!
What do yeu mean?
The ball was right below
us, which means
thatthe criminal shot from
nearby us, right?
Yeah... He shot from a range
that is not difficult to shoot from.
Besides, it'll be no laughing matter
he missed
If the criminal isthearby, why did
he mista -eher for a boy?
Looking at her clothes anybody
an see that shes a girl...
Maybe he couldn't see her skirt
because ef the wall, or something .
If the wall locked! his view,
it would mean that
he was at the back stand
ight opposite us
In other words, the person who told us
about the gun going off over the phone,
and the person who actually fired
re different people...
There are at least more than
two people involved. right?
Hey Inform all the officers by radio.
And tell them not to move
until I order them to!!
Y.Yes sir!
What are they geing to do?
Can they find the criminals with
what little clues there are?
From this stadium that helds 56.000 fans...
How?
To all ofiicers scattered
ameng the audience!
There are mere than two criminals!
And. one of them is most likely
armed with a Toearef!
Donst do anything; even if you
see somebody suspicio!
Just keep on watch until further orders!
We can't be sure what the crimin
willido to save. their companiens'
Listen, don't you ever let them
suspect that you're officers!
2 ¢ Z 2 Q
TCrRVYECLY LaicTiul alliluUu TACIT UL youull
entire:efforts into nabbing the criminals!
The next time the.criminalem
when he calls to designate where
to pick up the ransom he demanded!
Check each and every
person in this stadium
who us using the phone at that time!
H; and check. also for binoculars...
I'said before just awhile ago, didn't 1?
That the criminal was watehing us from
the back stand night. opposite us .
He could see that there wereY 'of us.
As well as that there was one kid
wea ing a blue cap, from so far away.
He couldn't have possibly seen
that the ball was night below
that kid with his bare eyes...
Besides the cellular phone, the
criminal probably has binoculars, or
Opera glasses!
A teleseope!
A mobile video camera!
A camera with zoom lenses
should also be checked
T.True
There is a high probability that one
of the criminals have something
that will help him: view
quite a distance away.
Please keep.that in mind
I,Inspector! The phone!
I wonder if it's frem the criminal?!
Tay calm
Okay, the phone is inging!
It could be theycriminal!
All of you go and check en anybo
who is using the phone in this stadium,
and inform me of his location!
If it's from the criminal,
try to do everything you can
to prelong the cenversation, understand?!
Yes: Sir...
Hello. hello. this as Kaneko, the directer...
Hello hello?
Why didn't you answer
the phone right away?
Don't tell me you contacted the police?
N.No way just had some problems
picking up the phone...
It's from the criminal... find him!
Well, never mind. Is the meney ready?
Yeah
ut the money at the exit of gate 18...
Place it there dunng the less time of the
first half of the game... Den't geef...
Hey. wait! Hello?/Helle?
me nutty up.
How abeut it, did eu find him?
This ls sector "E" .~... An 'elderly man
was using the phone till just a while ago...
this is sector "K.!" There is one
person ere on the phone,
but he 1s still using it so
dent think he's the criminal...
He may be contacting the
others In his group!
Keep your eyes en him!
Hey. Takagi! How about your side?!
The ones who were on the phe
at that time, are the 8 people here...
Were you also watching the aisles
and dressing reams of this building?
Fficers were also watch
over the restrooms,
but nobody was on the phene...
And, of course nebody left.
He stadium either...
I had the cameras-that were open,
check the audience too
but it seems that only these
people were using the phone
There seems téube-no mistake that
ne of the criminals: is among the eight...
But. Inspector! I wender if the criminal is
ally going to come get the money
Well, I don't think hell come just like that...
Don't take your eyes off
the eight in question!
Weill have to nab them all befere
they realize that we are here!!
Hmm? Huh? Where's my wireless radio?
Oh, this?
Oh, yes that's-it.
Here youfgo!
H: thank you, Conan...
all of yeu cheeking
thegbuilding gather at gate 18
I'll be right over teo!
Hey... What didt¥ou set up on
that wireless radio?
I'll be right over too!
What did you set up
that wireless radio?
Yeah... a wire tap!
I want to at leas {be aware of
hat the polieegis doing...
aincidentaliyl do you know where Genta
and theTothers are:
they.ran off delighte
when I told them that
they could came hack in with
their ticket stubs
This is Genta! Genta here!
Did you find any suspicious
Iooking guy? Over!
Mitsuhiko Here!
No, no one suspicious. Over!
Ayumi! How re you doing'!
Pe... nothing's happening here .
Yes, this is Ayumi.
What do you mean. this 1s Ayumi!! Just
what do. ou think you guysyare doings?!
The criminal is armed with a: gun
you knew!
Let me and the pelice handle the criminals
and you kids hurry on out of here...
No way!!
You're, a kid teo, aren't you
We want to help arrest the criminals teo!
We-re all members of the Youth
2 Detective Squad, arenrhswe?
Il right
Don't you-dare move on your own-'even
- - p- y
HH you 1d SOIMNMevoUuyvoUusSpiCilOUuSRLICI]. ¢0
Contact me, understand?
Okay!
Hey may-come in quite handy
ure. q1t wouilditl It uawll Of
iminals to suspect children *.
at's true, but...
it's already loss .tim
It's time to put the bag withthe cash -
at gate number. 18
Sato here. he bag is still intact
Tamiya here. Nobody is approaching
the bag yet.
H, He's came, Inspector!
A man wearing sunglasses, dressed in
a gra. ceat and wearing a white maskd...
The man just picked the bag up!
Is thereyanybody else around?
0, he's alone
ay... ab mm...
The gun! Look for the gun!!
Its not here!
Talk! Where 15,it?! Where's the gun!
On't ouch...
y - - -_ ~ vy ox B r- ~~ ~~ -\
L211 LL LOUULT11T11lYy pParutnicgy
I'll shoot at the audience!
Get away from him!!
Artner...
So the police were sneeping
roundafter all...
Hey, what's this all about?
Mr. Kaneko of Niehiuri TV?!
Well, that's .
Taking me lightly, eh... I guess one
person'll have to die to set:an.example...
H. Hey. «hold itl!
We're in@fix...!
E're in a fix...
Well, I wonder who I should kill?
I've gotta whole load of targets
0 choose from
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Ksuo Ono
Katsuo Ono
cree
Masatomo Sudo
Junichi loka
Junichi lioka
Kanji Kashiwabara
'fin 'f\~ F'! Iffi,
ARdZUllidri ROUCIII
Junichi Miyashita
Masamoto Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
0 OAR]
Yukiiiro Shibutam
TURITITTO Jdliitoulialil
DIRECTORS or PHOTOGRA 'Fly.
- a * Pr Pu -
IFdRdMII INOIINIUT Ad
Hironobu Horikosi
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Terumitsu Okada
EDITOR™
Ken]: Xodama
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Kenji kodama
PRODUCED BY.
TMS -Kvokuichi Corporation
In association wit
Yomiuri: Telecastine Cor oration
Ayumi! Ayumi!
Ayumi, which one. is the criminal?
He's the one!
You're under arrest!!
H.Hey you guys!
You're not getting away!
You wen't get away!
Ve finally figured it out, mister...
You're the one who blackmailed
mica tv, rig ILL.
Indiscriminate Murder Threat
at the Stadium Part ii