We the members of he Youth
Detective Squad
went to watch the Emperor's
Cup game finals
A bullet is-fired into a soecer ball right
before the very eyes of the five children
Just then, the director-of Nichiun TV
receives a threatening phone call,
while .they are broadcasting the game.
The blaekmailer says,
Gets 50.000,000 yen ready
If you cancel the game or let
anybody out of the stadium,
I'll fire and kill indiscriminately.
The criminal demands ransom holding
everyone in the stadium hostage
A bag with the cash that is demanded
Is placed in the specified spot,
and he officers charge at once
to nab the criminal...!
indiscriminate Murder Threat
at the Stadium" Part ll
H.He's come, Inspector!
He's a man wearing sunglasses, »
dressed in as gray coat and a white mask...
The man just picked up the bag.
Is there anyone else aroundr
No, he's alone...
Okay... Nab him!!
The gun! Look for the gun!!
1.1t's nowhere!
TAIL VVC, INL IL ¥ViilEie 5 Wie yun...
Don't touch...
Don't touch my-partner!
I'll shoot at the audience!
Get away from him!!
Partner...
So the police were sneeping
oundeO*after all
Hey. - what's this all about?
Mr. Kaneko of Nichiun TV?!
Well hat's
,, Taking.me lightly, eh... I guess one "oe
person"ll have to die to set. anexample...
H.Hey, hold it!
Kugh...! We're sure in a fix...!
Well I wonder who I should kill?
I've.gotta whole load of targets
to choose from...
D.Don't, net that!
We'll do as you demand, so...
W We'll pull-out too!
We don't want any vietims!
All right, I'll give you a chance
make up fer what you did...
Make up?
Yeah! I'm going to have
Nichiuru TV who went out and
called the police give us
additional ransom...
it'll'be 10 billion yen!
Get 10 billion yen befere the game ends
and place it at the same exit of gate 18.
If it's net ready by that time.
I'm. killing somebody in the audience!
T.Ten billion?!
Hat's outrageous
What's this?... Are you saying
that you can't pay my share?
So, there's only one mere of them left?!
Hey, is there anyene among the eight that
we markedia while ago using the phone?
No. Inspector, everyone here is
absorbed in the game.
Likewise, here seems to be
no such person here either!
There is no one who seems to be
on the phone here either. Inspector!
It can't be «! Where on earth
is he calling frem?!
No use. no use... No matter
how mueh you strain your eyes,
you officers would never be
Ie tO see me...
What?!
Oh, and will you order the officers
who are scattered
among the audience to
ave right this minute
I hope you understand that I'm holding
6 thousand people hostage...
You knowswhat will happen =
if you-go against.me
I'll order all of the offi
to leave right away...
Ome off it...
I can see night through: you.
The man who us smoking a cigarette
sitting to the left side
the aisle on the very top stairs...
the woman who isthidingrher face with
a newspaper sitting in-the second row
from the bottom in.the center of
e stand right up ahead...
The two men-leaning against 'the railing
mot the front row. diagonally in front of her .
They're all officers: aren't they?
The fat man.beside the goal*to
the right of the bleachers right up front...
Hey, Genie,- mitsuhikoyAyumu.
You guys are by the back
stand, arenst] you?
Yeah...
Don't you see semeene looking. -
through binoculars or semething?
There are...many... they seem to
be looking at the faces of the players
who are leaving the field during half time.
Idiot, he's looking towards
the stands. net:the field. ™
Furthermere, he: Yusing a phone too!
Ameng the 56,000 people here, there
could only be one person deing both!!
Oh, there's a weird guy looking
around the stadium!
Whereas that go , Ayumi?!
In the center of the back stand
on the very top stairs!
But, it looks like he's listening to music,
ot talking on the phone .
Music?
Because he 1s'wearing an earphone...
Something strange 1s attached
in the middle of the cord.
What a funny looking earphone.
) see, he had an earphone
microphone attached to his cellular.
That's why the officers overlooked him!!
Ayumi! I'll beiright overmso don't yous
dare 'take your eyes off him! 2
He's the one!!
Ayumi! Ayumi!
Genta. Mitsuhiko.
Ayumi, which one's he criminal?!
Him!
The hat, the coat>*he sure
does lleok suspicious.
Yeah, he sure looks like a criminal!
Right!
What?
You're under arrest!
H,Hey, you guys!
I won't let you get away!
Both of you, get off of him!!
I'll out him to sleep right
@ Officer Takag:!
Ghads, if you 'retan officer,
dress like an officer, will you!
Thatss right!
I can't help it. because
my wireless broke on me...
What?! Your wireless broke?!
Only mine wasn't-deing too
thinking that using a cellular
phone might confuse, .everybody
I was keeping contaet-with the
Inspector with an earphonexmicrophene.
And, where's the partner of the criminal?
He seems to have left the stadium from
the main gate with the cash because...
the criminal threatened us saying,
I'll kill someone from he audience
if yourgo after him
Is he the only-one who left the stadium?
Yeah, he's the only one: Nobody else left.
Which means that the bad guys?
Are still here in this stadium!
We've still. get a chance of capturing him!
But, what-a greedy criminal to~
demand deuble the first amount
I don't think h
after money this time?
Because it's impossible to get
10 billion yen ready in 45 minutes...
Hen. why... . ?
The criminal'is*planning to sheot
somebedy to-begin with
He'll do so at the time the end
f the game whistle IS blown...!
Officer Takagi, howaifar has
the game be played, already?
It's exactly 15 minutes after
the 2nd half of the game has started.
Which means there is only 30
minutes to go till the end of the game...
Put 10 billion yen in the bag and
put it at the number 18 gate!
If you can't get it ready in time,
I'm killing one of the audience.
I'm sure you're aware that I'm
olding 56.000 people hostage...
Inspector! Inspector Megure,
we've lost track of the car of
the criminal whe fled with the cash!
What?
I'm serry. we were threatened
not to pursue the car,
so were trying to be inconspicuous...
We got the license plate
mber, though...
ut, it turned out to be a stolen car...
We've get no choice but to nab the one
what's still within this stadium, then...
You mean there are-no 0t
The criminal said things like "my partner
and "my share, in his conversation...
Which means that it is highly probable
at there are only two of them...
Furthermore, he remarked on the position
of all the officers throughout the stadium...
I'm sure that is he still hiding
omewhere in this stadium...
But. how should we find him?
After alb, e fiucers have all withdrawn
from the stands by demand of the criminal.
That's what I'm trying to figure out now...
Why don't you cheek through the video?
When you got the phone call,
a video that was not in use
was scanning he audience, right?
If so, a shot of the criminal
ay be on the video...
A strange man looking
through the stadium with binoculars
while talking on the phene...
see Can we see
that video night away
Yes...
Inspector! »
There seems to be
+3 NO such suspicious person
in the stands up front.-or the'back stand!
It can't be?!
Id you check the press tha
came intofthe stadium?
If the cameras are equipped with zoom
Ienses, they can see quite a distance!
I was watching over the stands
where the camera men were %
b t there were no
suspicious looking persons!
Besides, if there was somebody on the
phehe looking through the view finder
of a camera and talking on the
phene as well, he would attract attention.
Right . Hmm .
Idiculeus
as well as leek areund
the stadium at the same) time
How could) he do 'it« with ut
anyone noticing him
1. Inspector
1 got together a little over
billiengyen fer new...
It's impessible to get together
ameunt like 10 billion
ve got no choice... We'll ju
use newspaper or something
to fill up whatever is missing and wait
0 see what the;cnminal will do...
h, Inspector...
Hmm. What is it Officer Takagi?
Maybe the criminal's .not after
money this time
What?
It's obvious to anybody that no matter
how you run around the banks,
it would be impossible to gather 10
billion yen in a matter of 45 minutes
Therefore, all the criminal wants is the
50,000,000 yen that.he first demanded...
Y don't-tell me
That the criminal was
planning to shoot semebody
as soon as the game
ded to begin with
N No. why?!
Ma. be something happened
at Niehiuri TV recently, that
meone held a grudge against...
No, No, I can't recall any such thing...
Hey. mister... Was; the voice of the criminal
« that led you all of the same person?
Y.,Yeah#the voices of all three
calls were muffled,
but I think they were of the same man...
Which means that the person:who called
and the persen who shot the ball
are two different people,
so the man who came to get the money
is the one who shot the ball. right?
Yeah . .The other guy's voice
was heard from the phone
that the guy whoscame to get
e cash was holding. so...
But, the guy who came to get the cash
- -g - I - - . - - - Pru p- - Jp- - Ty ~~ 3 So -
IQ tL Inave a gull OI 1iirny. 11a jic.
I wonder why?
- He gave his gun to his partner
Okay, check all the videos between the
35 minutes * 10 minutes past the first half
of the game when the ball was shot, to loss
time when he came to-get the cash again!
Find the guy in the audience that the man
who came to get the cash had contact with!
He's the criminal that's left in the stadium!!!
Yes, sir!
37 minutes past the 2nd half of the game,
Ramos's volley shot makes goal!!
The score is"a turn over of 2.1%
with the Big's in the lead!!
There he is, Inspector!
That guy is on the video!
And, did he give something to someone?
0... He was just walking along the aisle.
Ah. he s-out of vision:of:the monitor...
Don't give up!! We still have time.
As long as there's a.
Possibility keep searching!!
It is very unlikely that he is on the video...
- Mereover, it's not definite whether
he actually gave the gun to anyone...
ut, this is the only way we have left
to look for the criminal
This is the only method we: have left!
It's almost loss time...
shut up, I know.
There's not much time left!!
Where IS he'?! Where, where'?!
Where is he?!
Please... ~Please, the time...
Iease step
Cool it...
e can trcontrol time, can we
If we tryasto.centrol it by force.
E'll have to pay the toll...
What're you talking about...
Oh, that was clese!
It's already the 3rd time!
This is no time to be getting
excited watching the game!
No, that's not it
We were else leeking fer the suspicieus
person that you were also leaking far!
That suspicieus man always
disappears from scene!
Disappears?
See, the minute he ts seen
to the edge at left
the camera moves and
goes off scene
This is camera 13, isn't it?
Hew unlucky...
al 4 «4A
Come to think of it, even a while ago...
1 get tt...
So, that's what it was!!
Inspector, it's loss time.
It can't be helped. Put a camouflage bag
at gate number 18, and watch it...
The rest:of you,
charge into the stands as soon as
he game ends' Hurry!
Here's Conan?
I've finally figured it out, mister.
You're the one who threatened
Nichiun TV. night...
It weuldn't look strange even
if you were to be looking
hrough the audience with the camera
And you wouldn't look suspicieus
even if you were to be
talking into the microphone that
Is attached to your earphene...
Besides, nobody would imagine
that a camera man
from the same TV station is
threatening his colleague
Good'werk, kid...
I saw the video that you shot, mister
The partner of the criminal entered
the scene 4 times
but all four times...
he framed out right away...
And that's when I figured it out.
Tha dittwasnst that he was
coineidentally not in the video,
buy that: his,partner 'had deliberately set
t up to be so, in order to protect him
And, he position of the oflicers
that the criminal had pointed out
ere all in the center stand...
Tihe only camera that can take these shots
IS the one that is situated
y thetbackstand!
You're the only one who meets
Il the requirements »to do so...
What are you going to do
Will you turn:yourself in? Well, mister...
1 have no choice, I'll do that
Shoots!!
Is what lad actually like to say,
t, I can't do that...
I've got my reasons, you see
Beretta... That's not a Tocaref»...
Yeah, my partner's gun is.in one of
the trash cans inside the stadium...
The Baretta and Tocaref are all guns
we get together for the bank
robbery a year ago .
The plan that we schemed and
invested all the money
we saved up fer 3 years for,
s perfect .
On the day we were to carry out the
robbery, a stupid event of some
show biz talent serving as one day
branch manager was being held...
Nd it got crowded...
My woman who was expecting that
money, drowned herself in alcohel
d committed suicide...
Thanks to the stupid event that
Nichiuri TV had-put-on!
Ee... ou vurpcodlliie
a camera man for Nichiun TV
so that you could take,revenge
But, what do you plan to do?
F you sheet me new, I'm sure
semeone will notice. right?
Phooey, nobody will realize a thing...
Look, the eyes of the audience!
E gluedsto the game
With the cheer of the crowd and
this silencer attached gun,
ot a sound will be heard...
Nobody has even noticed that you're
dawn here in the field, either...
+Ism sheeting, you the instant
he game ends
he cheers"I] tun Intorscreams
and there will be panic...
I'm going to flee in the midst
of the commetien and
nd inferm the papers that...
) killed a kid because-Nichiuri TV
refused to pay ransom!
What the...?!
Jhe game is over! Theiscore is™2-111
Big Osaka has wen
the Emperor's Cup game's
The man of the match, of course
IS Ramesfiivero
who showed great offensive
sas well as defensive play!
The defensive iron w ll play that
he displayed towards
the endfof »
the game was fantastic!
Ramos!
Nice clear!
The criminal was arrested by he officers
who charged in at the end of the game...
30 minutes later His partner who was-feund
at his apartment was also arrested.
The Emperor's Cup Game ended as if
othing had happened. at all...
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Mi -hihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
KJtsSuo Ono
Masatomo Sudo
Junichi lLioka
Junichi lioka
SCRIPTS BY
hanji kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Yuichi Hisure
oshih1 noue
fasamoto Sudo
Haruo Oocawara
Atsushi Aono
Takashi Hyodo
Yukihiro Shibutani
Yukihiro Shibutam
DIRECT
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Hm 'k0sl
Takahisa Ogawa
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
- ) [0
Itsu
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
Keni hodama
PRODUCED BY.
TMS -Kvokuichi Corporation
In association wit
Yomiuri Telecastinc Corporation
Shoots... I wanted to have
a closer look at the game .
The criminal was arrested before
we realized what was happening .
He Youth Detec we Squad didn't do
anything werth neticing teda.
Not really, the Inspecter was saying that
you helped out in the arrest
of the criminal too.
Really?!
Yiouyre really semething Shinichi.
To be able to
track down the criminal with
ittle of a clue
Yiousre becoming an.even more
attractive.research matenal fer me...
Heh=I:don.t. €° V*5w 84 years, eld
granny telling me that
n<le-m.actually... . 18 years old,
gperfect match for you...
Aybe...
Call the police, Pops!
Ran. I'll be right there
Ran!!!
Ran .... run fort...
ThéMagic;Lovers=Murd Case
Next Conan's Hint.
Handle name