Inspiration flashes
piercing through to the truth.
Once he gets going
nothing can stop him.
In today's episode, a car explodes.
The adult
world is a bit complicated
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the
IQ of an adult
no ase is left unsolved when Detective
Conan comes to the scene
+A AA
The Car Explosion Case" Part I
¥A AA
Thanks for waiting...
What're you looking at so intently?
I was just remembering the past.
The past?
You may not know,
but in the past, in every bank,
there was a space
open for the general public.
They had a.bulletin board
with messages such as
Looking for nice home for kitten,"
or whatevers
I once put up a
please hire tutor message
on the board too...
Oh, were'you tutoring, Pops?
Really?
I didn't know at all!
Well,
I didn't have money, but I married
your mother while I was still a student so...
I had no choice &
but to part-time to make a living.
You and Mom
had quite a tough time, I see!
But, the one who really had a tough time
must've been the one
who was taught by Pops.
You can say that again.
Fuh fuh, fuh...
What're you talking about?
I was a pretty good tutor.
As proof of that,
the student I taught for 3 years,
entered the
Iaw department of Jonan University!
That's right!
She used to
Iive in Beikacho!!
Huh?
Follow me!
I'll introduce you to her
Megumi!
Oh, Megumi...
H-Hey wait, what do you mean?
She's a woman??
Hey hey...
How nostalgic...
I've never been in this
part of Beikacho very much,
but it hasn't changed much.
Are you sure you
haven't seen\that person for a long time?
Yeah!!
Her name is Megumi Tanaka,
andiher father is a lawyer.
He used to let me
drink beer after lessons.
That's why
he lasted for:3 years...
What's with that car?
Hey! Hey!
Watch out, Conan.
What's with that car anyway...
Speeding like that
on such a narrow road...
Her house is right around
that tobacco shop!
Maybe the person called Megumi
has gotten married long ago,
and doesn't
Iive there anymore?
Could be
but there's also a possibility
that shes still single!
Dad!
I hopeyyou're not
thinking of anything, funny...
Come off it. &
What can I do
with you kids along with me...
Hmm?
Oh, it's her!
Megumi!!
Mr. Moun?!
You've really grown to be an adult,
haven't you?!
Wait, Mr. Mount!
Huh?
All right!
Okay, okay...
Hiromi...
Megumi!
My little sister...
Hiromi is inside!
What?!
Hiromi is!
There it is!
A fire extinguisher!
Give it to me!
Il handle this
H-Hiromu...
Aaaag
Megumi!
Beikacho Hospital
FETE Tbe
I'm sure you are in shock
because it isliight after the accident, but
May I ask. ou a few questions?
Your name is Mrs. Sakihara,
Is that right?
is that right?
Megumi Sakihara
Yes...that's right...
The person who died
in the car that exploded is...
Ms. Hiromi Tanaka,
your younger sister.
your younger sister?
Hiromi Tanaka
Yes, that's right...
An explosive
was riggedson to the car
Explosives?!
Just as I thought...
Yeah!!
It seems that the explosive was
rigged onto the underside
of the car together with
an ignition device.
It was probably rigged so that when the
tires turned, an explosion would occur.
Yes,
I also remember that the car exploded
soon after she reversed.
O-Oh...
Ms. Sakihara,
I know how you feel,
but let me ask a few more questions.
That house you came out of,
IS your parentssshouse, isn't it?
Yes...
My parents died of a car accident
6 months ago
What?!
You mean your father?
Yes, that's right.
My sister's been living
there alone ever since...
Was that car your sister's?
it was mine
Yours?
Whaty!
That's the car that I drove all the way here
from my residence in West Tama today.
My sister's car
was at an auto shop for a safety check,
so I parked my car In the
empty garage.
Since I'm not good at backing up
my sister was getting the car out for me,
so I could head on home.
My sister...
she offered to
back it out for me...
Which means
that you were the one who was
actually supposed to be driving that car?!
Y-Yes...
Then the killer
mistakenly kille 1 our younger sister?!
I don't know!
I don't know
what on earth is going on...
Uuuugh...
Megumi!
Megumi,
about what time did you leave
your residence in West Tama?
A little before... 2:00 in the afternoon.
Did you notice anything
abnormal about the car back then?
What time did you
arrive at your parents' house?
I think It was around...2:30.
The explosion occurred at 3:00 sharp!
If so.
Then it is most likely that the
explosive was rigged to the car
during the
30 minutes period...
Do you have any idea
as to who it may be?
Huhry.
Do you know if an, one
may have a grudge on you?
No...only...
Only?
About a week ago...
I was being watched by
a man at a supermarket near my house.
Huh?!
A 'stranger...?
Yes...
I pretended not to notice,
but I felt
quite uncomfortable...
Do you remember
that man's face
He had a
very characteristic face...
We'll get an officer
who is good at drawing portraits,
so we'd like your cooperation.
Megumi.
It didn't even occur to me that
I'd be meeting you again like this...
I knew that you had become
a famous detective Mr. Mour.
I boast to my friends that
you used to be my tutor.
I see, I see...
I will surely track down the killer
who did such a terrible thing to Hiromi!
Please do that, Mr. Mourn.
Aye!!
Leave it to me!
What a surprise
that she used to be a student of yours.
You also knew her
younger sister too didn't you?
Yes...
She was still in
Jr. High School back then
and used to always
serve us cake and tea...
Unlike her older sister Megumi
who was quiet and easy-going,
Hiromi used to joke a lot,
had many friends,
was outgoing
and was very cheerful...
They don't seem to have changed
much to this day.
After Megumi graduated from college,
she went to work
for a securities company.
She stayed there
only for a short while and got married.
She has no children, but seems to be living
a peaceful life as a housewife.
Hiromi, on the contrary,
after graduating froma two-year college,
worked as a free part-timer,
and even after
reaching the age of 30,
still seemed to be living
a carefree life...
It seems the investigation on Hiromi's
oing to take some time...
Inspector Megure,
The portrait\is done.
Oh, thank you.
Let me see too!
Huh?
He's...
Doesn't he look like that man?!
Remember the driver who overtook us
on our way to Megumi's house...
Hmm?!
Although ,he was wearing sunglasses
his hair st. le andschin
Iook exactly the same!
Come to think of it...
He looks just like that man!!
About what time did you see him?
About 10 minutes
before we got to Megumi's house.
At the alley about 500
meters before"reaching her house.
Which means, he could've been fleeing
after setting up the explosive...
Do you remember the model
and license number of the car?
Uh...
It was a red RV,
with a Shinjuku license number
All right!
Let's search for it immediately.
Excuse me,
how is Megumi...
My wife...?
How is she?
Excuse me...
but are you Mr. Kazuo Sakihara?
Yes...!
Azuo Sakihara
I got a call from the police
azuo Sakihara
Saying that my wife
had a bombing accident...
Azuo Sakihara
Saying that my wife
had a bombing accident .
And how is she?!
Please don't worry,
she's fine.
Huh?!
But, your wife's
younger sister passed away.
H-Hiromi?!
Oh, I mean...
Why her?!
An explosive
was rigged to your wife's car
but Hiromi was
driving the car in her place.
Mr. Sakihara,
have you ever seen
anyone like this before?
It seems you have.
N-No, never.
Hmm...
Excuse me!
He sure is acting strange.
Inspector Megure!
Hmm?
Investigation at the scene of the
explosion has been completed.
Hmm...
How was the portrait?
Hmm, here it is.
Ir Mouri and the others seem {to have
séen'him near the scene of the explosion.
That's reliable evidence!
Huh?
This man...
- What's-up, Officer; Takagi?
Uh, well,
I thoughtdl saw him among the papers
of the case that Officer Sato is handling
What?!
You mean the one
who was killed in Shinjuku?
Yes,
I only took a glimpse
but he looks a lot
Iike the victimes husband
All right!
Check on that portrait right away
and contact Officer Sato!
Yes, sir!
Or BLD
, ToT 1]
Yes...they do look alike.
I've met the man himself,
so I think there us
no mistake about it
He's the husband of the woman who was
stabbed to death on her way back after
shopping at a
convenience store at night....!
Hiromasa Takahashi
I 03% RE
His name is
Hiromasa Takahashi,
Hiromasa Takahashi
LL U5 8&8
age 33,
Hiromasa Takahashi
LL O35 8&8
I U3 88.
An employee at a
chemicals company.
Hiromasa Takahashi
TL, TS
And over here is his wife,
theivictimO Mrs. Sachiko Takahashi.
Age 27
We're investigating as
random murder
But, she was covered by a
very expensive insurance policy.
Her husband who is in
debt was also a suspect. However,
he had a perfect alibi.
Hmm, I see...
Is Takahashi's car a red RV
with edShinjuku license plate number'?
Yes!
Exactly...
What?!
Now, it is quite definite that the
man we saw was Takahashi.
And if he works
for a chemicals company,
he could easily get a hold of
explosives too...
A random murder case
and a bombing incident,
Iooks to be two very different cases
but I wonder If there is a any connection?
Although there are no names that
correlate in both cases
But, too many things fit in
for this to be a coincidence...
Another deduction could be...
Officer Takagi
Huh?
You've got a cool looking
badge there!
Please exchange it with mine.
Oh no, Conan,
this is not a badge.
Please exchange it
please exchange it.
Conan!
Hey!
Don't you understand
that you can't exchange it!
Huh!
Exchange?!
I've figured it out Inspector!
This is an exchange murder!
Exchange murder?
Huh?
Yes!
If so
both incidents connect!
Do you mean that.
An agreement of an
exchange murder was made between
Kazuo Sakihara and
Hiromasa Takahashi.
First, Sakihara kills
Takahashi's wife. Sachiko.
Next, Takahashi tried to kill
Sakiharass wife, Megumi
When Sakihara saw the sketch of
Takahashi at the hospital,
he looked out rightly shocked.
That's because he knew that
Mr. Takahashi was the killer!
But, why did
Mr. Sakihara want to kill his wife?
That can be imagined! from his remark
when he found out that the one who died
was his wife's younger sister.
H-Hiromi?!
He's remark
sounded obviousl more intimate
than just a
brother-in-law relationship with her!
All right!
Let's investigate the case with all
what was pointed out just now!
Yes, sir!!
Mr Takahashi?
You seem to be in a rush,
are you going anywhere...
Rats!!
Freeze!
You're arrested on
charges of assault and battery!
Crud!
There is a bomb in the bag.
What?!
We did it,
Officer Takagi!
Indeed
A few days later
After Sakihara saw the sketch,
HA bd BL
A few days later
he informed Takahashi to run for it
But, that"in turn,
was a breakthrough for us.
Sakihara, after hearing that Takahashi had
admitted the crime, also resigned
and confessed that
he had killed Takahashi's wife.
He seems to have talked Takahashi into
committing an exchange murder
when they happened
to see each other at a bar.
They never met after that first meeting,
and all arrangements were done by phone.
Tiheyilsed~the pay phone,
so that no proof would be left.
Sakihara had a phone exclusively
for himself in his study upstairs
He seems to have made sure
to take all calls with this phone
That's why Megumi didnat realize
what was going on...
And, what was Sakihara's motive?
Just as you-had deduced,
Sakihara had an
Intimate relationship with
with Megumi's
youngerssister, Hiromi
Sakihara seems to have thought up killing
Megumi, in order to come up with cash
for opening a boutique that Hiromi
said she wanted to start.
Because if Megumi dies,
allsthe money-that
he inherits from her,
andsthe money for the
insurance that she is covered by...
would become his...
How cruel!
Poor Megumi...
Does Megumi know about this?
Yeah...
althoughdit seems
she couldn't make herself believe it at first.
All she could do
after finding it to be true was cry...
It's understandable,
because although she
wasn't involved in the crime at all,
she was back stabbed
by her own younger sister...
I'll go and look in on her
in a few days.
That's a good idea.
So, the case has been
solved and is closed.
Help her out
as an old friend will you
Yes, sure thing.
I'll see you later, then, Ran.
Goodbye, Inspector Megure.
I wonder if
evenything has really been solved...
I have a feeling...
a feeling that something is
being overlooked...
few days later
Dad!
Few days later
You promised to meet Megumi
at 1:00 didn't you! .
Look!
We're an hour early!
Let's go have some coffee!
Huh?
Isn't this the supermarket where Megumi
mentioned she saw Takahashi...
Conan.
Hurry, come.
Okay
Huh?
Dad.
Isn't.that Megumir!
What?!
Megumi?
Hey, Megumi!
Hey!
She's gone...
Conan?!
She reversed out of a
parking space so narrow...
Didnt she mentioned
Since I'm not good at backing up
my sister was getting the car out for me,
so I could head on home.
My sister
she offered to
back it out for me...
But, what I saw, doesn't look like a
person who has trouble backing up the car.
Then why did Megumi
asked Hiromi for substitution?
Because of that,
the explosion killed Hiromi.
Can this really be
an unlucky coincidence?
If she already knew
the wholevplot...
This case isn't
solved, yet!!
GoshoAoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
Masatomo Sudo
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashrwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki IToue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masamoto Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro shibutani
DIRECTORS.OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikosi
Takahisa @cawa
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS - Kyokuichi Corporation
in association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoywnma Shogakukan
All Rights Reserved
Are you saying that Megumi has
something to do with this case?
The Megumi you know is the
Megumi in her high school days,
Megumi could've changed
after becoming an adult.
She hasn't changed!
She's what she
used to be before!!
You want to believe so,
don't you, Pops.
But, actually she's already.
The Car Explosion Case Part Ii
Z£< 2° It. ts A
HE EERE TOE