Inspiration flashes piercing
through to the truth.
Once he gets going, nothing can stop him.
Today's episode has the smallest cast ever.
Stay right there for a sudden
reversal of circumstances.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with
the IQ of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when Detective
Conan comes to the scene.
A car that is rigged with an explosive
explodes at the parental home
of Megumi Sakihara, a person who Pops
used to tutor in his school days.
The victim who passes away in the incident
turns out;to be Megumi's younger sister,
Hiromi, who was reversing the car out of
the garage for Megumi
because she was supposedly not
good at it.
The suspect turns up to be a man named
Hiromasa Trakahashi.
He agrees to carrying out an exchange
murder with Megumi's husband
Kazuo Sakihara. However, he inadvertently
ills Hiromi instead of Megumi.
Both men confess to their crime,
and it looks at first glance
that the case has
een solved. However...
She's easily reversing that big car out
of that super narrow parking lot...
This case haspnot yet ended!!
The Car Explosion Case" Part ll
ConanOwhat's up?!
Hey! Is anything wrong?
Oh, it's nothing.
I think Megumi came here.to buy:.us
some cake or something.
Let's hurry and go to Megumi's house!
Ghads, what's with that kid anyway?
It's too early to tell Pops about this...
I've got to get more corroborative proof...
I, uh...l just don't know what to say .
Thank you very much I'm fine, so please
don't worry yourself over me.
O,Oh...
Please have some tea before it gets cold.
Thank you.
I'll have some too.
How about some cake, Conan
Huh. Oh, okay!
May I goat athe restroom first?
Over there. .!
Sakihara had a phone exclusively
for himself upstairs and
took all his calls with that phone.
What's that...
That's the remains of masking tape
being peeled off!
Just as I thought...
So, "it" was set up there after all.
I'll bet you're relieved that Megumi looked
way better than you thoughtishe would, TN
right, Dad.
Yeah! I'll guess she'll dookay.
I've got some place to stop by
when we get to Beika Station,
so you can both leave me and go home.
All right, but remember, don't be too late.
Here's a window...
I see... If it's from that window.
I see... If it's from that window...
Just as I thought...!
Okay! I've got the overall picture!
Now, all I need is proof!
I'm back!
Pops!
Something bothers me about the case.
What...
Because, remember Megumi
reversed her car out of
the narrow parking space of the
supermarket today, right?
Then why did She have her younger sister
back her car out for her
when the incident happened...?
Besides on the wall near the telephone of
the upstairs study of Megumi's house,
it looked like masking tape was peeled off.
That means that something was
stuck on there, right?
Masking tape?...
Did you know that there was a window
way inside the garage
where the incident occurred, Pops?
It seems that the window cracked from the
impact of the explosion and
a wooden board was placed over it.
But, with a window like that over there,
it's good because you can get
a good view of the car
from inside the house .
What are you trying to get at...?
Are you insinuating that Megumi has
something to do with thi'case'?!
I don't know... But.
Don't be ridiculous!
I know her best because she used to
be my student!!
You knew her as a high school student,
right, Pops?
Megumi could've changed
after growing up
Don't you dare get cheeky with me!!
She hasn't changed a bit!! She's the way
she always used to be!!
You want to believe so, don't you, Pops.
What?!
But, actually she's already...
Shut up and go on upstairs!!
I'm going to go take a bath.
Ghads! How dare that brat
talk to me like that!
A secret window?
Yes, Hiromi and I call it that.
KES DE
Megumi during High School
2 LEW
FIFE OD=
It seems that Dad actually wanted to use
his as a door, though...
When I was little and getting into
things in the garage,
I would always be
SCO e€ rom ere...
Police Station
The record of the testimonies of
Sakihara and Takahashi?
Police Station
The record of the testimonies of
Sakihara and Takahashi?
Yes. I'd like to take a quick look, and
eview the results...
Dideianything new.come up.in later
Investigations?
Hmm...According to one
of Hiromi's friends. .the late" Hiromi seems to
have taken two boyfriends away from
Megumi, in her younger days.
Well, I guess you could say that she
was very carefree...
It seems that Hiromi was only fooling
around for the fun of it...
But, it seems that-when Megumi
decided to marry Sakihara,
although jokinglyashe warnedsHiromi
saying thatOif she did"it again,
she would make her pay for it...
Pops'll probably come up with some sort of
circumstantial evidence in his investigation.
But, when it comes to concrete evidence...
I see! Maybe!!
Inspector about what I asked you over
the phone a while ago...
Yeah. I confirmed with Takahashi,
but the only time he saw her face was
at that supermarket.
That's the first and last
time he ever appeared before Megumi!
And, how was Takahashi
dressed at that time?
Uh he was wearing a
jacket and sunglasses.
Just as I thought!
Mr. Mouri, what are you up to anyway?
Thank you very much, Inspector.
Goodbye.
H,Hey, Mr. Moun?!
Okay! So, now I've got proof!!
Huh? What do you mean?!
Hey, Dad?!
He hung up.
What's the matter, Ran?
Dad's in Akihabara now, and says he's
going to Megumi's house from now.
He said that he is the only one who can
persuade her...l wonder what he means?
Ran, let's go to Megumi's house too!
Ghadsnn."
Why'd you guys have to come too...
I'm sorry, but I was really concerned
over your call so...
Sorry to keep you waiting
Thank you very much.
And, what is it you wanted to
talk to me about?
I... I came here today to
you to turn yourself in.
H,Hey , Dad
After finding out that your husband and
your younger sister were having an affair,
as an exchange murder was being planned
between your husband and Takahashi,
you decided to use all this,
to kill your younger sister that
you haveralways hated,
and send your husband to jail
on charges of murder, isn't that right?
D...Dad! What a thing to say!
Two months ago, you bought a wire-tap and
automatic recorder at a shop in Akihabara.
You asked the sales person to give you the
details on how to use the machines
These are the same modular-type wire tap
and automatic recorder that youfbought!
I didn't want to do it, but when I went
to the restroom a while ago,
I checked out the upstairs study.
You..rigged a wire-tap to your
husband's study and
bugged his conversations with Takahashi.
The remains of masking tape
being peeled off from the wall is proof.
You were probably planning to listen to the
conversation between
your husband and
your younger sister at first, weren't you?
But, along the way, you found out something
awesomely terrible.
That is, your husband had agreed to an
exchange murder with a complete stranger
and that he had already killed
the wife of that man...
The time came when it was your turn to be
killed by that man Takahashi.
You found out that he was planning to ng your
car with an explosive,
but was undecided because if he does
so in front of your house
your husband Kazuo, may turn up
as a suspect to
Therefore, you deliberately
tell your husband
that you are driving over to Hiromi's,
because her car just happens to
be at the service station for a safety check,
and the garage is open yyy.
Your husband, then goes out
to a pay phone
and tells Takahashi all that you told him
Although you didn't listen
to their phone conversation,
almost positive that Takahashi was going
to carry out his murder plan,
you went over to Hiromi's...
And; afte telling Hiromi that," ou were not
good at reversing,
And, after telling Hiromi that you were not
Megumi's Residence
good at reversing,
you made her back the car out of
the garage for you.
Just as you had expected,
your younger sister died.
But, at that time, just one thing that you
ildn't expect happened...
I happened to come and see you!!
You were surprised and...
wait, Mr Mount!
Okay!
You wanted her to back out right away
because you didn't want me
to see through your plan.
I did buy the wire-tap as you say.
I set it up behind the desk after suspecting
my husband of having an affair
with someone.
But, I thought it over right away
and immediately disposed of it...
Therefore, I didn't actually use it!
Did you know that the person he was having
an affair with was your younger sister?...
I didn't know at all.
Let's presume, this is just¥a'presumption
now, that I did act as you had deduced,
what 'charges am I guilty for?
Takahashi is the one who rigged
the explosive onto the car,
and the person who made him
Mo it, is my husband.
All 1 did, if anything is make my younger
sister get into a car
that was maybe rigged
with an explosive.
I'm not an accomplice in a crime, nor did
urge anyone to commit murder'forme.
Isn't that right, Mr. Moun?
Just as expected of a student in the law
department, and a daughter of a lawyer.
Just as you say...
If all you did was get your younger
sister to ride the car,
you wouldn't be found guilty of anything.
Why then...
However!
In the case that you made your
sister get in the car despite knowing that
an explosive was rigged to the car, or if
the possibility that you knew,was very high.
You will be charged with homicide!
You mentioned back then that.
You had to look for something and went
into the closet alone.
Then, you were watching the
garage from the window!!
And, just as expected, Takahashi
came into the garage
to set the explosive onto the car
After you confirmed all that, you asked
your sister to back the car out!!
In other words, there was a very high
possibility that the explosive was
being rigged to the car, and still
made your sister ride it!!
Do you have any proof that I was watching
the garage through the closet?
If you do, please show it to me right now
Right this minutel!
You've got proof, Pops.
Remember! The sketch)of the man that
Megumi said she saw,
that was drawn by police officer Honjo.
Megumi, where did you say
you saw his face?
A. At the supermarket near my house.
Huh? Strange. The officer mentioned
that Takahashi was
wearing a jacket and sunglasses
back then.
But, wh 1s the man in the sketch not
wearing sunglasses?
Megumi, isn't it true that you didn't even
notice Takahashi was
watching you at the supermarket?
You found out only after you
Iistened to the conversation between
Kazuo and Takahashi
that you tapped, right?
Then where did she see his face?
From the closet!!
She saw him from the secret
window of the closet!
Megumi... you were watching Takahashi's
face from the closet of your parental home!
The face of Takahashi who was
setting up the explosive!
H...How can you be so sure?...
That day, Takahashi who didn't want
anybody to notice him,
was wearing sunglasses until
he entered the garage.
Of course, he were his sunglasses
when coming out too.
However! There was just one time
he had to take off his sunglasses!
It was when he was setting the explosive
onto the car!
Because nobody would even dream of
doing a dangerous job
Iike setting up an explosive
onto a car while wearing sunglasses.
In other words, this sketch of Takahashi
without his sunglasses is proof that
you witnessed Takahashi rigging the
explosive to the car in the garage!!
Just as you say,
I...happened to hear them...
E...was planning to kill me and use the
insurance money that I was covered with
together with the inheritance money
my parents left for me
to open a new boutique
that Hiromi was to own...
Ah. .l remember the good old days...
I was really... happy in those days.
I kept hoping that I could go back to those
ood old days all this time...
But...
15years ago.
There was something very important that
I was supposed to have taught you...
Something more important than studying...
But, maybe I can't really teach you much
since I'm separated with my wife
and all now.
True!
But, it's never too lat
Repent for the crime that
you have committed and
study all over again.
This time: the study of life!
Will you watch over me... then again?
Sure! By all means!
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
ACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SGRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masamoto Sudo
Hirotosh: Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
DIRECT
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS.OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi: Nomura
Hironobu Horikosi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRE TOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS - Kyokuichi Corporation
in association with
Yomiuri Telecastine Cor oration
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Anyama Shogakukan
YTV TMS-K
All Rights Reserved
It's a good thing that the case
was solved, but...
This case must've reall come
as a shock to Pops.
Yes, the Mouri Detective Agency...
What?Yoko...
Agh! A concert? Of course I'll go.
If for you,
I'll go and cheer for you or tutor.
I'll do
anything you wish! Yes!
I guess we've got nothing to worry about...
Really! It takes Pops no time at all to get
back on his feet.
It bothers me! I met him somewhere, but
can't remember where...
n MO disc...
What's this?
I don't remember buying this
The old»man who disappeared!
The man wearing sunglasses!
Something... Something smells fishy!!
The Old Man Disappears