Inspiration flashes piercing
through to the truth.
Once he gets going,
nothing can stop him.
Today is about a strange passenger
on the bus.
The incident unfolds into something
beyond imagination
He seesgthrough the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the
IQ of an adult,
no casONeft unsolved when Detective
Conan comes to the scene.
Run!
H,Hey!
Ran, hurry, quick!
Wait bus, wait!
I'm getting on!
Whew...we made it...
I'm pooped. Ugh!
It's because you tn to buy
everything at once.
Talk for yourself...Look at all the outlet
brand .goods you bought too.
Gee, I really wanted this.
Oh...l see. I'm happy for you.
I'm sorry I put you through all this.
Goodnight...
gh, not fair...
Let me know when it's time to get off.
The Old Man Disappears
A Are you all right?
Es...l thought they finally got me...
This jabbed me In the stomach...
[I'm sorry...
Hmm. ? Aren't you Mr. Mouri's daughter?
Y.Yes...
h...you are... :
I'm Shitara, Jukichi Shitara.
Jukichi Shitara
S Led es
I :'s' not surprising that you don't remember
e. though...Ha, ha, ha...
JukichigShitara
3 S00)
It's not surprising that you don't:remember
e. though... Ha, ha ha
Mr. Shitara...?
It's written like this...
Oh...It's a nice name.
I am Ran Mourn...
Today is quite humid, isn't it...?
Ce. because it's raining, I guess.
This is how my name is written.
Oh, thank you so much...
Oh, not at all...
I was on my way to visit your father...
Is it a request for an investigation?
Yes...
Only, it's not the kind of work that can be
discussed over the phone...
Oh..._.
By the way, is the muromachi Hospital still
far from here?
Huh? Oh, you mean the bus stop.
It's the fourth station from here...
I'm going to ride way passed there,
would you like me to let you know
when it's time for you to get off?
Oh, thank you so much for your kindness.
No problem...
Ran... Ran...
It's time to get up
Come on, get up
We're almost there.
Ull...URAy... TE&dlll...
I'm the one who asked you to wake me, and
I'm waking you up instead!
Is it Muromachi Hospital yet?
Wesrve passed that station long time ago!
What?!
Did the old man get off all right?
The old man...Uh
His name was Mr. Shitara...
Who's that?
The\man that was sitting next to me!
How should I know.
I didn't see such an 'old man.
That's because you were asleep, -Sonoko.
Don't ask me, then.
Maybe you were dreaming or something...
Reaming...
I wonder if it was a dream...
Ran!
Uh, did an old man get off
at Muromachi Stationp?
An old man who was wearing a
cap and was holding an umbrella...
I wonder...because I lot of passengers get
on and off at that bus stop...
I see...
So, we're home, home at last...
Well, do you want to stop by and grab
something to eat?
Hello?
It still bothers me...
What does?! \
Taxi!
Huh?!
Keep me company
H,Hey, Ran!
? 000 o O a0 00
POWEIT ¢ 500 Soo
No RT
n= Br
Andmlfjust what-"db you intend to do now?
We're going to ask around.
Why are you so concerned
ver that old man.
Something bothers me about that old man!
I'm sure I met him some place, but I can't
remember...and besides...
I was just on my way to visit your father...
It seems he wanted{to ask Dad for an
Investigation.
How about over there, then?
Beika Newspaper Agency?
Beyond that
r. Jukicni shitara...
He doesn't seem to be here.
He's not here?!
{ No, his name is not listed among the
out-patient list or the in-patient.
Oh I see...
How strange, though... ..He said he was
going to the hospital, right?That old man.
I think so...lwonder if he just came to see
somebody who is hospitalized here...
No, I don't think so.
The name Mr. Shitara'is not
on the list of visitors either...
You're being over anxious.
If he wants to see your dad, I'm sure
he'll call in tomorrow...
I guess so...
It's got to be.
If not, the old man never existed
in the first place.
Oh, so you don't believe me after all!
An old man disappeared?
That's all I can think of.
Sonoko thinks it's just my imagination,
but something bothers me...
I wonden'if« ou could ask Inspector Megure
o look for the old man...
guess not...
Of course not! You're probably just
imagining things or were dreaming
I wonder if it was a dream after all...
An MO disc...?
What's this?
I wonder what it is...? ll don't remember
uying anything like this...
It could be that old man's.
But... Why... .??
Agasa Residence
BB DDFs TL
Hmm...No good.
I can't open the file without a password.
H, is that right...
Here you go.
Top secret, don't take off premises...
Co fir
1Eg AZ
Well, its understandahle., but...
Can't you somehow figure out the password
nd open the file, Doc...
Hmm...it'll take some time...But,
aren't you bin a rush?
Is\m thinking of visiting the company of the
bus that I rode this afternoon from now.
E might be able to get some more clues.
Okay. I'll contact you when
I get to open the file.
Okay!
Thank you!
Uzuki Residence
Yes, yes...
Oh, is that night. Thank you very much
Everything's-okay. The company told me that
the bus is still running its course.
Okay let's go!
Wait up, will you!
Why in the name of earth do I have;to get
involved in this?"
Because. .Conan said that
you should be with me
to compensate for my vague memory...
So, it's you after all.
Please help me, Sonoko.
Ghads! I just took a shower
and was feeling refreshed...
What's with that car...
Hey, Conan! Looks straight ahead!
It's dangerous.
Ran, that car...
There's nothing. Now, look ahead.
Like I said this afternoon,
I don't remember a thing
bout the old man...
Something may be left where
the old man was sitting.
True!
Hey! This isn't the same bus.
That bus was not functioning too well, so
it's under maintenance now
Let's go! Ran!!
It must've been, about you girls?
What?
Well, I was asked where a girl named Mouri
who was on the bus, got off...
NO! What does that mean? Creepy...
What kind of person was
the one who asked you that?
What kind of person... well,
he was wearing a coat and sunglasses...
Oh no!
Oh, no!
1, That person...
Do you know him?
But, why...?
Let's hurry, Ran!
The old man who disappeared!
A top secret MO...
The man who is wearing sunglasses...
Something...Something smells fishy!!
Please wait here.
Wait, mister!
Hey, hey, you can't come in!
I'm sorry, I forgot something on the bus!
Over there, Conan!
H,Hey...
No doubt about it. It's here.
I sat here, and the old man sat next to me.
Do you remember anything else?
Hat's right! His name...
IS Name...
Right, he wrote his name on
the window back then,
because the window was
cloudy Like this, with his fingers...
But, it's gone already...
It wasn't a dream after all.
What's going on...? I have no idea
what is going on...
Hello...
Huh?!You figured out the password!!
Yeah ..and about the contents of the disc...
This is double accounting...
Double accounting?!
You know the company Beika
Construction Company, don't you? O
It's something that was taken out of their
accounting department.
It has a dummy account book, and an
account book that corresponds to that
which shows all the bribes given to
politicians and all...1
The names of all the corrupted assembly
men that had transactions dealing with
the general assembly, meeting of
stockholders are also listed.
I see...
The old man was sought after because
he had the double account book on him
Y,Yes. . But I thought
they finally got to me...
The man wearing sunglasses was not
after me, but rather, after the old man
Yep. That's why the old man who realized
that he was being tailed,
put this MO into your purse
Yes, and also because he knew that I was
Kogoro Mouri's daughter...
We've got=to find the old man!
Find him...But,
we have no idea where he is
after he got off the bus
The newspaper agency!
He went to thexnewspaper agency after
Ieaving the double account book with me!
I see!
Try and remember...
The man who was wearing
sunglasses asked
the bus driver about
you and Sonoko, right?
Which means he found out that the old man
didn't have the double account book!!
That's why he was looking for Ran who
was sitting next to him on the bus!!
Yes, in other words...
The old man was captured by the man
wearing sunglasses?!
Ran, call Pops and Inspector Megure!
Agh! Where are you going?
I'm going to loo 'around the area
that the old man got off!!
I'll 'go too.
No!!
Since they are after you, stay at the bus
company, wait here!
O Okay...!
Excuse me, may I use your phone?
Go ahead.
Uh... . my telephone card
Will you hold this for me?
Okay.
No, that's not it, Dad...
Are you listening to me?!
Donst sleep on me!
Yes, I'm listening, I'm listening.
8 dye /
fleas
Ghads, how can he be like
that at a time like this!
Well, is he coming right away?
I can't get through to him at all...!
I'm calling Inspector Megure!
It's pretty good for something
that was bought at the outlet.
OO Oh, no,...
Yes, that's right I'm at the Heian Bus
Company right now.
B, Bad news!
The other girl's been kidnapped!!
Shinichi, it's me,
Shinichi, it's me
What's up, Doc?
Ran just called saying that
Sonoko's been kidnapped!!
What?!
The kidnapper's car seems to have gone
to the left after leaving the bus company!!
Left, which means the other way!!
Driver, please make a U-turn!!
Hey, you're late...
Sorry, it took me some time to get to her...
Strange...! We shonld have overtook the
kidnapper's car by now!!
On one side of this road is
the fence of factory...
Which means they made a left
turn somewhere!!
Driver, please turn right, over there!!
Does this road lead out somewhere?
No, beyond here is a warehouse area,
Nd It's a dead end...
Using this road as a
short-cut, wouldn't do any good,
because you'd have to go all the
way around anyway!
Which means that Sonoko is
omewhere nearby...
Beika Construction Company, eh...
Wait a sec...The one who's going to be
in trouble when the double accounting book
IS publicized is not only the Beika
onstruction Company.
All the companies that had been behind the
curtain dealings are involved...
Doc!! Is there a place called Ryujin
Economics Research Lab
in the list of the MO?
1259.0
473,64
8.253
vvall...
15.614
rourna iL, Srinicrll.
A lot of money is involved here...
Thanks: Doc. Aa
Stupid, she's not the one!
What?! You mean the other one?!
You goofed it
1.I'm sorry, boss...
She had the purse with her so
I thought she was the one...
Go again and get her!!
O,Okay, boss...
Don't goof it this time now!
Yeah, okay
What're we going to do with them?
Without the disc, we don't
need them anymore!
Get rnd of them
WwW. What the... .?!
WwW. What is thispkid doing henner.
Conan Edogawa...!! detective....!!
You brat!
The two men turned out to be bad men
who had dealings behind
the curtains with
Beika Construction Company
And, Mr. Jukichi Shitara
who and been an executive
of the Beika Construction Company
for a long time,
after pondering decided to take the double
accounting book out of the company .
Sonoko!
Ran...
Ran!
Aaaaaghn, I was so scared...
I'm glad, I'm so glad that you're okay,
Sonoko...
The following day,
Beika Construction
Company was searched by the police...
thanks to the courage of one old man who
reported the crime...
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
ACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi lioka
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masamoto Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR.
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS.OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikosi
Takahisa Ogawa
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS - Kyokuichi Corporation
in association with
Yomiuri Telecastine Cor oration
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Acyama Shogakukan
YTV TMS-K
All Rights Reserved
I still think I've seen that old man
somewhere...
You still can't remember, Ran?
Uh-huh...
That old man was an executive of the Beika
Construction Company:
so*maybe you saw
him in the papers or on television? -
Hi there! Upstairs people,
Here's your sandwich with coffee and
orange juice
TL RILA
Thanki cum,»-
I wonder if I'm making a mistake after all?
No, No...
You're not making a mistake...
uh, fuh, fuh...
Gramps!
Mr. Jukichi Shitara was a patron of
the coffee shop
that is located below the
Mourn Detective Agency...
What's the matter, Ran?
I have a feeling I saw that person...
with the glasses somewhere.
What?!
Where...
Where did you see him, Ran?!
Ran!!
(AIR)
(mu #R)
5 Sonoko's Dangerous Summer
(FR)