Inspiration flashes piercing through to
the truth once he gets going.
Nothing can stop him.
This episode features Sonoko
in her natural state.
Danger, romance & fate awaits.
The one & only truth is
brought into the light.
He looks like a child but he's got
the brains of an adult.
His name is... Detective Conan
FA NA
SONOKO'S DANGEROUS SUMMER PART I
Perfect!
Sonoko. what in the world
are you taking?!
It's a.close up of your rear as you §
fixedwyourabathing suit.
A real close up! It's an eyeful!
Why did you take a shot like that?
It's obvious, isn't it!
When (Shinichi gets back.
I'm going to show it to him!
What?
I'm sure he'll be thrilled!
You're nuts! Shinichi would NOT be
pleased by those pictures!!
Conan... you agree with me don't you?
Uh... sure!
Hah!! What does a kid know?
Good grief.
I wish I werefback to normal.
Sonoko. what's wrong with you! You've
been acting so mean lately!
Don't mind me». I'm just jealous...
Eh. but .why... was it something I did?
Do you know whyy
Do you know why we came here to
IZU for these 2 nights & 3 days...
To. look for guys, as always, that:'s
your motive, isn't"it, Sonoko?
That's right! And this time. I've got
my girl next-door act perfect!!
What do you mean?
Whenever we travel, we always stay at
my family's vacation*home
some fancy hotel!
Oh woe... the likes of
her is beyond my reach
To relieve the fears of suchemen,
"deliberately 'picked
this rundown inn for us this trip!
Oh... is that what this is all about
What a waste of energy...
And still... And-still...
Sonoko...
In the train coming over here...
and last night, at the fireworks display
site near the inn...
and even here on the beach today.
All the guys that have come up to us.
Every one of them... were after Ran!
You're the one!
I don't think that's true
Oh never Mind" forget it!
I took some candid shots ofég
you in your underwear.
I'll just show those to Shinichi too!
Hey. you can't be serious...
Sonoko. wait!
I'll never forgive you if you do that!
I was just kidding, I didn't take
those pictures!
Sonoko, you little...
Good grief... she was I ing.
Hey ladies...
are you free?
How about having lunch with me?
Of course, it'll be my treat!
Adahiko:Michiwaki
Yes! We'll be happy to...
I'll bet you're after Ran too,
Go ahead, take her!
She's at her prime!
Sonoko!
But don't try anything funny!
She's already got a boyfriend!
No, the one I was asking out...
was you...
Me 2:1
You're kidding!
Isn't that great Sonoko!
How exciting
Id n't believe it! Who'd pick
noko, no one... no way!!
Something's fishy here... there's got
to be a catch somewhere!
But there's no sense worrying
about it...
Shall we go?
Sure
I'll just stay here with Conan for
a while longer!
On, so you're a student at Beika
Universit I!
Ran's father graduated from there!
Yes, that's right
I don't understand, she's always
Iooking for guys but
When she's with
one, she's so uptight...
So what brings you here to 1zu?
I'm just getting over breaking up
with my girlfriend...
she shattered my heart... I felt so
Iost & was looking at the ocean...
then I saw an angel!
If my instincts are correct, you're
going to turn out to be my savior...
Your... savior...
Here's your beer!
Un, thanks...
un, thanks .
Sir, don't drop your cigarette ashes
on the floor, please!
Makoto Kyogoku
It makes cleaning up harder!
Sure thing...
What a rude waiter...
Hey, haven't we seen that waiter
somewhere before?
Of course we have, his father owns
the inn we're staying at!
I heard he comes back during the
summer break to help out
How do you know all this?
He was staring at us, from the doorway
so I asked someone working at the inn!
Then I wonder why he's working here?
It's probably under the same
anagement...
the Kawara Inn where we're staying...
So. you're staying at the Kawara Inn?
Yes, that's right.
That's close to the hotel I'm staying at!
How about it then?
Why don't we all have dinner tonight
at that fancy restaurant on the beach...
I'll picks Ou up in my car!
Really?! Are you sure?
On one condition. you bring your camera!
Why's that?
I just heard from one of the locals,
something happened on the beach close
to the restaurant
Like what?
Let's see... it was almost a year ago
to this date .
A young girl with long brown hair
was murdered.
She'd been stabbed in
the abdomen...
Murdered?!
Yes it seems she was attacked while
on her way to that restaurant but
there were no witnesses and the case is
till being investigated.!
A year's gone by, the customers have
forgotten the incident
and business at
the restaurant is booming, but...
There's one problem. the girl seems
to have taken a liking to the restaurant,
she still appears there
She what?!
Photos taken in the restaurant show
her grotesque figure!!
Yipes...
Geez
What baloney...
That's why I wanted to test the rumor
and see if such a picture'd turn out!
What do you think?
I still have about 10 shots left...
No way! Don't you dare take your camera!!
But if we showed it to Shinichi, he
could probably figure it out...
Besides. I'm going to show hill the
other pictures
I told you about that are in this camera...
Listen to me!!
What good will it do to show him pictures
of someone unidentifiable!
With his.deductive 'powers' I'm sure -heill
be able to figure out who it is-in a snap.
Good grief!
Deductive powers?
This girl's boyfriend is a mystery buff!
Oh really...
by the way, what kind of photos
are you talking about?
Wait until you hear
Sonoko!
Here's your order!
FriedPnoodles!
Customers are lining up so
please eat fast!
Zs 74
zs 7 .
What is it with that guy. Does he
have a grudge against us or something?
Shoji Terabayashi
SIEYL L&D LL
THEROL L&D UL
Let's not go to that restaurant,
it's just too spooky...
Don't worry! It's just a rumor.
Besides, a whole year's gone
by since it happened!
If she did appear there as a ghost. I'm
sure she's grown tired of the place by now...
Hey. did you hear?
They found another.in the woods
along the railroad tracks!
Another what?
A body! Another girl with long brown
hair's been murdered!!
I'm going to have a look!
Conan, don't go!
Conan!
Good grief, he's so curious...
She's been stabbed in the abdomen.
Detective Yokomizo
Shizuoka Police
Just like the victim last year
Detective Yokomizo
Shizuoka Police
Yes... this victim also seems
to be a tourist...
by the way, what's the
estimated time of death?
Let's see, sometime between
8 and 9 last night...
about the time the fireworks
display ended
Isn't that about the time we passed
here last night?
Yes. I think:so
That's scary...
Don't be silly, no one would attack
you Sonoko
Bot look! I have brown hair too!
Can you guarantee I won't be the
next victim!
I don't want to die in a place like this.
I haven't done any of the
things I want to yet...
Sonoko...
Don't worry... I'll protect you
while we're here in Izu!
By the way, I think it'll be best to
eat dinner at a different restaurant
Yes. you're right
And no cameras either!
I agree! I'll pick you up at 7,
wait forame in front of the inn!
We'll be there
That man... I'm sure he was at the
beachside concession...
I'll seefyou later then
wAliight!: We'lllbe 'looking¥forward to tonight!
Let's change and go back
v Ho]
Why if it isn't Ran and Sonoko!
I didn't know you were in*lzu.
Yes, we came to do some swimming
So Detective Mouri is with ou too?
No. only the 3 of us came this trip
Hello
So you're guarding these 2 ladies.
Stay on your toes
Yes sir!
And you two be careful too!
There's been a terrible crime.
Yes, we'll be careful
I'll be going then!
Give Mr. Mouri my regards.
I will!
He hasn't changed at all, he's still
energetic but somehow unreliable...
if your father were here Ran. he'd
solve the crime in no time.
Detective Yokomizu's much more reliable
than old man Kogoro. trust me...
Oh no, it's starting to rain!
I wish he'd come soon...
Patience, don't be so anxious!
Heroes always arrive late!
Stop that! You're embarrassing me
What'd he put this uabrella here?
Does he mean we can use it...?
Maybe he has a crush on you Sonoko
What?!
Why Sonoko. Arenst you the popular one!
For goodness sakes? he's so gloomy!
You're right, after all Sonoko.
You have Michiwaki!
Ran stop, you're enbarrassing me...
Oh no! I forgot my wallet!
Wait for me, I'll be right back
Ran, what's the matter?
That guy wearing the glasses... I'm
sure I've seen him somewhere before
Yes. probably in this hotel
No, not here
Somewhere else...
Are you sure?
Where? Where did you see him before?
Think, Ran!
Ran!!
Sonoko. what's keeping you?
Don't tell me you're changing
your clothes... eh?
Sonoko! What happened?
A man attacked me, he ran out
through the window!
What?!
Rats! He got away...
I was so scared!
Why would someone attack you?
On't know...
when I opened the door to this room,
that man was going through our things,
I was going to scream but he grabbed me!
Going through their things?
He probably wanted to steal our
undenear! The pervert!
What did he look like? You saw his
face. didn't you?
I didn't have a chance!
Besides, the room was dark and I was so
scared, I nearly fainted...
But Sonoko...
how'd you know it was a man...
While we were struggling.
I bit him!
Right on his hairy upper arm!
Wow, nice going...
What's going on? What are you
doing in the dark?
Mr. -Michiwaki...
I had engine trouble on the way so I
ran over, sorry I'm late *
But. how'd you know this was our room?
You weren't waiting at the entrance so
I asked the clerk
His shirt's wet...
and his pants are splattered with dirt
he couldn't be...
Michiwaki, can you take your shirt off?
What?!
I want to see your upper arm
Conan!
I don't know what's going on but
Is there something on my arm?
Nothing?! There's no sign of
Sonoko's bite...
Satisfied now?
Uh huh...
Is something wrong here... folks?
He's bandagedmy?!
What happened to your arm?
Oh this... a guest got drunk and bit me
the other night
When was that! Answer me!
I don't think he's the one... the man
who attacked me was pretty hairy...
You were attacked?
Yes! A man came in through that window
and was searching our bags
Sonoko just happened to come bac #to
{the room and she was attacked!!
But it seems he got away emptyhanded
because Conan and I arrived!!
It was probably just a thief or
something... it happened once before
It happened before...
why didn't you warn us?!
D... didn't I tell you to sec
the storm shutters...
Besides, it's quite late and look
how you're dressed
your belly button s showing,
you should thin Fhow you dress
What?
You've just asking for trouble...
Besides, you don't even look
good in that
How dare you! This is my favorite outfit!!
Don't worry. You look good in anything.
Whether it's"a, kimono or a bathing suit!
What do you think you're doing?!
I'm moving you into another room...
we have another room available
But if you prefer to spend the night
in a room a stranger broke into.
Well that'll be fine with me...
And I suggest you forget about going out
tonight and have dinner in our dining room...
your assailant may be waiting out
there for you...
Yipes!
What do you think Ran?
Let's have dinner here...
Hey, the food here is pretty good
If we'd known before. we should've
had dinner here last night
If you had made reservations,
we could've prepared
an even fancier seafood dinner for you...
of course.
It would be on the house...
but in exchange.
We'd appreciate you didn't go telling
people a thief runs around our inn...
Alright. alright. I won't tell anyone!
That there's a knife wielding underwear
thief in this place!! Happy?!
He had a knife?!
What?!
That's right! Some light seeped in
through the crack in the door and
I caught<a glimpse of it...
the blade of the knife flashed!
Don't tell me it's the same guy
who killed that girl they found
in woods near the railroad tracks
this afternoon...
Last year, a girl with long brown ,
hair was also found
stabbed in the abdomen here in Izu,
Is it the same man?
But if it is. Why's he after Sonoko?
Because she has brown hair?
That's ridiculous!!
Wait a minute...the guy.who attacked
Sonoko was going through the luggage!
What could have been in those bags that
had anything to do with the murder...
A camera! Could there be a picture
in it of the crime?!
Sonoko! Did the man who attacked
Nou 'take-your camera?"
It was still in my bag!
But the back of the camera was open...
Then did he get the film?
It-wasn'tin there in the first place!
I took all 36 shots.
So this aftesnoon.l.brought-it to be
developed so we could look
at them during dinner tonight...
See! They've been developed!
Well then..May I have a look?
Go ahead
wait a ainute!!
Oh no!!!
Don't worry! I took your
pictures out, I have them
Sonoko you sneak!
You had me scared!
Do you know these people? You sure
took a lot of pictures of couples...
She took those before she met you,
she was in a very foul mood.
She took those while making fun of them!
That's strange... nothing looks out
of the ordinary and
the victim's not
in any of them either...
Besides... although we passed the spot
where it happened last night.
Sonoko didn't take any pictures there...
So why did the killer think she took a
picture that might incriminate him?
I don't undererstand...
Something she said at the beach
concession bothers me though...
With his deductive powers, he'll be able to
figure out who-it is in a snap
If the killer was at the concession then
But... would that comment make him
misunderstand?
Hey ladies... you said you were leaving
tomorrow afternoon. didn't you?
Yes...
Alright then, shall we go to that
haunted restaurant in the daytime?
What?!
Yes, let's go! It's not scary
In the daytime!
Alright, but no camera!
Vies I know!
It might be my imagination but it
feels like somebody is watching us...
and the guy in the glasses Ran says
she saw somewhere bothers me too...
then there's the man who attacked Sonoko,
was he really just some
mall time thief...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTOR OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hi 'onobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaoa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogdkukan
II Rights Reserved
The sidebrake's disengaged!
Sonoko wake up! Sonoko!
It's that guy again!!
Oh no!! Sonoko's in danger!!
SONOKO'S DANGEROUS
SUMMER PART II
(248)