Inspiration flashes
piercing through to the truth
Once he gets going,
nothing can stop him.
Summer vacation's just started,
what kind
of boyfriend will Sonoko catch?
The one and only truth is
brought into the light.
He looks like a child
but he's got the IQ of an adult.
His name is...
Detective Conan
The three of us
went to Izu to do ome swimming,
went to Izu to do some swimming,
Ran and=*I¥sare witness to a
strange summer event!
Can you believe it!
Sonoko gets herself a boyfriend,
his name is Masahiko Michiwaki!!
But,
while she's in seventh heaven
waiting for him to
pick her up for their dinner date,
someone attacks her!!
Is it my imagination
or are we being watched...?
What bothers me is that
man with the glasses, which Ran saw.
And the man
who attacked Sonoko.
Is he really...
just an burgular?
SONOKO'S DANGEROUS SUMMER PART 2
There it is!
What a lovely restaurant!
But it doesn't seem that popular...
Maybe:we*tgotihere toorearly?.
Hmmmmm
Are you sure you
aren't coming Sonoko?
Go on!
I couldn't
sleep last night,
thinking about that
man ;kept me awake.
I'll rest in here.
Oh alright'. Abut-what a waste...
There're drinks In this
cooler box, so help yourself.
Thank you so much!
We'll see you later Sonoko.
Have a nice time.
After your nap and
if you're feelin Yup to it,
join us in the restaurant.
I will.
I'm so sleepy...
The seafood here is delicious...
I'm so disappointed.
I wanted Sonoko to try it.
I wonder if she'll be OK...
sleeping inside a hot car...
Don't worry
I turned the air conditioner on...
Wow, look at this!
Is this for 1 person?
Yep!
Therews'quantit «
and price is low!
That's the secret to
this restaurant's success!
Oh brother,
a full course meal for lunch...
Didn't I tell you
the food was great?
You were right!
It was delicious!
I'm completely stuffed...
Thank you very much!!
I feel bad for Sonoko though.
Huh?
You're from the inn...
Do you come here often too?
No, this is my first time...
By the way,
where's your
brown haired friend?
I haven't see her anywhere...
You mean Sonoko,
she didn't
get enough sleep last night,
so she's resting
in the car parked outside
Look!
Eh?!
Isn't that your car, Masahiko?
Why's it moving?!
Oh no!
There's a cliff up ahead!
Please come again...
Hey, where you think
you're going, pay your bill!!
Those are lock opening tools!
The sidebrake's disengaged!
Wake up Sonoko! Sonoko!
Eerah!
Rats! I can't put
full strength in while I'm running!
Oh no!
We're almost there!
Conan, get away from the car!
Whoa!
Hah!!
Hmm?
Ran...
Sonoko!
Grab hold of me!
Huh?
Are you guys alright!
Yes.
Just barely!?
That was close!
Boy I'm glad you're safe!
Hey you!!
Why didn't you put
the sidebrakes on?
Don't be ridiculous!
I had them on!
If they weren't on,
the car'd have
fallen off the cliff a long time ago!
Someone released the sidebrakes!
What?!
Someone broke into the car
using lock picking tools!
Someone who wantedsSonoko dead!
I see...
So someone broke into the car
while Sonoko was asleep inside
and released the sidebrake.
Causing the car
to drive down this gentle grade
and fall over
the cliff, is that right...
Here's the diver's report.
The sidebrakes of the car
in the water were disengaged!
And we
found this lying on the road.
These are lock picking tools!
Is this a professional hit?!
It's been wiped clean of prints!
Did you find anything else?
No...
the only other thing we found
was a puddle of water that
Ieaked out of the cooler box where
the car was
parked in the parking lot.
Sonoko.,
did you see anyone
suspicious lurking around the car?
I wouldn't know...
I didn't
sleep much last night
so I was
fast asleep in the car...
ever since arriving in Izu,
we're bein followed
for some unknown reason...
one person
following us is over there.
Would you mind
identifying yourself?
I work at the inn
the girls are staying at
I came here today
to have some tea.
- The inn's not busy during the
afternoon and I had some free time.
He's not the one!
When the car started moving,
he was already
in the restaurant with us!
If he had broken into the car
released the sidebrake
and then come into the restaurant,
we would have seen him walk in...
The waiter told me
the backdoor is
always kept locked...
We first noticed him
when he came out of the restroom but
there's no window
Ieading out from inside the toilet!
And of course,
Masahiko's in the clear too!
He was having
Iunch with us at the time
and he never left the table.
Which means
the most likely suspect
is the man following us!
Who is he anyway
well take all your
statement down at the station!
So please get!into the car!
Did you say can!
L..uh...
Don't feel like
riding a car just yet...
It scares me...
Then
why don't you and I
walk to the police station?
It's not far from here,
the view's nice,
it'll refresh you,
what do you say?
Yes I'd like that!
Wait just a minute!
What if she's attacked again?
Sonoko does have
brown hair, you know!
It's possible her assailant
is also the murder suspect!
You have nothing to worry about!
No one would be fool enough
to attack her in broad day light.
But there's
always the possibility 1!
Don't worry, Detective!
Masahiko will be with me...
and so will Ran!
Argh~ alright then,
but don't stop off anywhere,
come straight to the station!!
Es, Sir.
Icant believe it,
the attack at the inn last night
and then he car incident today
what's with you anyway...
Sonoko... are you sure
you don't know what's going on?
No, I have no idea...
Maybe it's because
you're so charming?
Yes...why is he after her...?
if he wanted to kill her,
why didn't he do it
when he broke into the car?
He didn't have to go «.
Through all that trouble
car go,over the cliff...
We planned on leaving Izu
as soon as we had lunch
so we put
all our bags in the car,
they've all gone up
in flames now
Rats!
Why is all of this happening!!
All you lost was your luggage.
I lost my car too.
Yes, you're right...
just because
you got involved with me,
I guess }
I brought you bad luck.
No, I don't think of it that way,
I'm not so unluc « ,
you lost all your memorable photos,
you can't replace
those once they're gone.
All tha s left
Is that 1 picture now...
You mean...
You know,
the one I'm going
to show to Shinichi
I have it on me at all times,
you have nothing to worry about!
Eh?!
You still have! it?
Get rid of it,
you're making me mad!
That's it, it's that picture!!
He wants to
get rid of that picture!!
That's why he had to send
the car over the cliff, to get rid of
both Sonoko and her luggage!!
But I don't understand.
Why does he think Sonoko took
an incriminating picture of him. 7?
There wasn't a single
unusual photo in the bunch...
did I overlook somethi g?
It's him again!
I think we're being followed.
What?!
Is it the killer?
Can you run?
Uh, sure...
Alright then,
here we go!
What the?!
Let's go too!
You're putting her into
more danger going into the woods!
No! This is more thrilling!!
Right?
Oh yes.
Let's split up and lose that guy!
That's strange
if he's Sonoko's attacker,
«Why's he still afteriner.
All the pictures were burned...!!
A train...?
Hey, that's right,
this is .the woods
where they found the body yesterday...!!
When we passed
this place the other night,
I'm sure a train went by...
What is this ?
I'm missing something here....!
Rats...! I lost them...
the situation's turning bad...!
Give it up, you...!!
If you thought we'd keep
running, you made a big mistake!!
Oh...hey...
Ouch!!
It's your fault for wearing
sandals when you run in the woods!
Sandals...?
It was you wasn't it...
You attacked
Sonaka last night at the inn
and then today you
sent the car over the cliff! 2
Hold on there!! That's...
No use lying...!!
Your hairy arms are proof enough!
Let's have a look...!!
There should be bite marks
where Sonoko bit you last night!
What?! It can't be...no bite marks!!
Maybe on the other arm!!!
I don't get it,
there're no marks on this arm either...!!
What's going on!?
Who are you anyway?!
Well, actually...
I'm a detective with the Chiba
Prefecture Police Department...
You're just showing me the cover,
I'm not stupid enough
to fall for that trick...!!
My father was once a
police officer, you can't fool me
When an officer has to
identify him or herself,
they must display the "Koukyuyoushi
Daiitchou" face of their police identification!
Shoji Terabayashi at your service...
Oh my 2!
It's the real thing
I've been following a
suspect in a certain case...
A suspect...?
Ran!
When you wear sandals,
you don't usually wear socks, do you?
No not really
Oh no!
Sonoko's in danger!!
Ouch...
I stepped on a branch...
I guess
wearing sandals in the
woods wasn't such a good idea...
Are you alright. .?
Eeth marks...!
Why are you so surprised...?
Uh.. um...
There's nothing
to be so surprised about,
is there?
After all...
this is the bite mark
you gave me last night...
es... so that's it...
So that's it
Ss. so that's it
Sonoko didn't
bite an arm last night,
she bit his calf...!
It was so dark
she couldn't make it out...!!
He thought Sonoko
took his picture because
the sparks
the train's pantograph produces,
Iit his back
at the time of the murder,
when Sonoko
passed by holding a camera
he jumped
to the wrong conclusion...!
He thought
there'd be a shot of him with the victim!
That's right
and I remember his saying...
Don't worry,
you look good in anything,
whether it's a
kimono or a bathing suit!
The only time she wore a kimono
was to the fireworks
shown 2 nights ago. .!!
We only met him yesterday,
how could he know
what she looks like in a kimono...!
Rats!
Why didn't I.
Why didn't I
figure it out sooner!!
What are you doing!!
Give me that picture...!
The picture you were going to
have some detective look at!
You probably thought
you took a picture of a couple dating
but I was
in the midst of committing murder...!
Just like now...!!
F-Four...?
He killed four girls...?
If he was responsible
for the murder the other night.
Then she's probably the fourth. .!
For some reason, he
Kills only girls with brown hair!
I've had him
marked for a long time
I got him on a
stolen vehicle charge once,
but there wasn't enough proof
on the murder charge...!
I came to Izu because I heard there
had been a similar murder before
and there he was...!
But I got here too late.
He'd already killed...!
I don't understand though...!
He was in the
restaurant the whole time,
why'd the car
start moving on its own?
It was the ice...!
He had a cooler box...!
He took a
wedge shaped piece of ice out,
put it under the left front tire
so it wouldn't move...!
Then,
pretended to talk
to Sonoko who was inside
and released the sidebrake...!
Then
he left some
Iock picking tools on the ground!
To divert the investigation... .!!
I see...
that's why he left 2 spaces
open when he parked,
so there'd be no cars obstructing
his car's path when it moved...!
On top of that,
the melted ice would
just appear to be
water that leaked
out of the cooler box!
But why...?!
Why does he kill only
girls with brown hair...!!
I told you, didn't I?
A girl jilted me in a cruel way....!
That's why,
that's the reason,
whenever I see flirty girls like you,
I get so mad...!!
Girls with brown hair
remind me of her,
how she ruined my life!!
Look over there,
isn't that Sonoko?!
What?!
Oh no!!
I don't get it!!
Why're all the guys
that make a play for me so weird!
I hate you God!!
Wha...?!
Are you alright?
I'm fine...
but, how about you. ?
Oh, this?
Now I remember!!
Eh?!
I knew I'd seen that guy
with the glasses before,
it was at the tournament!!
Euh?
He's captain of the
Haido High School Karate Club!
He's the Kick Attack King!!
Makoto Kyogoku
Wow.
You're a very reckless lady...
You're just lucky I had some free time
and just happened to be close by...
Free time...
do you mean you were
following me all this time...?
That's right,
I was following you!
Until I lost sight of you
in the woods...
I knew you might think
I was a stalker.
Before he met you,
he'd been flirting
with a few other girls,
it got me worried...
Why did you worry about me...?
You don't even know me...
You didn't notice me
but I'd seen you once before,
at a karate tournament.
You were cheering like mad
for your friend...
I never dreamed
you'd reserve a room in our inn.
I suggest you stop
wearing
outfits that look like lingerie,
it arouses
the guys more than neccessary...!
Of course!
You're free to ignore my advice
and pass it off
as just another casual remark
made by
one of your many suitors...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Mich Biko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
CRIPTS BY.
Kan 1 Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutanr
DIRECTORS YOF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaca
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
IMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyanfay/ "Shogdkukan
II Rights Reserved
What?!
Teitan High School
Makoto's gone
abroad to study?
Teitan High School
But why...?
You and he were getting
along so well since then, weren't you?
He said
there is no one strong left in Japan
so he went off to train abroad...
3 days later.
Ran!
Let's go see the baseball
team's practice game'])
The other team's ace
is a freshman,
I hear he's so cute
and just so adorable!
Good grief,
I thought you were
going to wait for Makoto to return...
That was then
This is now...!!
I knew it...
There's a key in the water
A window...!?
It's impossible, no one could
get in and out through there!!
What trick did the killer use
to lock this room?
Next episode.
Case of the Key
Underwater in a Locked Room"
Next Conanrsghint!