Inspiration flashes.
Piercing through to the truth.
Once he gets going, nothing can stop him.
In today's episode,
the mysterious key is the key
A surprise behind locked doors.
The one and onM truth is brought into light
He looks like a child but he's got the
brains of an adult.
His name is... Detective Conan.
I'm sure it was around here
Did you say Hikari Soh?
Yeah. it's an rundown old apartment
building that looks like it'll fall any minute
Hey... I think,
this might be it
Maison Hikarl...
I... don't believe it...
CASE OF THE KEY UNDERWATER
IN A LOCKED ROOM
Oh I'm so sorry.
I had this place rebuilt this Spring
into a condominium
Mitsue Souda (73)
Landlord of Maison Hikarl
I had this place rebunlt this Spring
into a condominium
Gee... I didn't know that,
what a shock
It's a lot different from the
apartment you stayed In
when you were a student, isn't it?
It sure is, like night and day
As a matter of fact, you left here
after only 6 months
to get away from
your nagging landlord didn't you.
Un, I. don't remember. Ahahaha...
Hey, ma'am, do you live here all alone?
That's right. My children have moved away.
But my grandson fives on Him floor.
Here you go, eat up/eat up...
Wow, looks delicious
You're not so Ioneh then
No I'm not... Makoto is studing construction
at Jyonan Universitx
but lately he's been so depressed.
I asked why but he won't tell me.
So I thought a famous private detective like
you would be able to get him to talk...
Is that why you called me?
He said he'd drop by around 8...
I think I'll go check on him
Only he and I live on the fourth floor.
I'm only renting out
the rooms on the 1st to 3rd floors.
That's Odd
He might be sleeping...
Do you think we should go in without
his permission?
It's alright, he's my grandson
Makoto, are you in?
Good grief, what a mess
What is this...
Excuse me
Is that what I think it is.
No. it's just crayon...
Oh no!!
Even over here
Monument in the water...
What in the world is this
How awful...
Makoto'?!
There's a key in the water...
Makoto'fl "
Ma koto'?
Makoto!!
What's wrong?!
Makoto?! Wake up!
Makoto'?!
Makoto?!
Gash on the inside of his
Ieft wrist...
No hesitation cuts
Hurry, call an ambulance...
No it's too late.
That's ridiculous! oh, I know,
call Kido!
Ki'do?
He's a medical.studen't'. He lives
on the 3rd floor.
He and Makoto are friends!
But your grandson is already...
Just get him!
HI -0 et him!
Mr. Kido! Mr. Kido!
Mr. Kid0!?
Mr. Kido"?
Mr. Kido...!
How smell
Oh he's only in a drunken sleep.
Just look atqthis place
Un? Who're you ?
Mr. Kido! Something's happened to
Makoto! Come quick!
LE'hU
Makoto!!
The deceased is Makoto Souda.
22 years old.
He was a senior at Jyonan University,
majoring in construction in the
engineering department.
Cause of death IS assumed to
be loss of blood due to the severed
artery of the upper arm
Hmm... judging from rigor mortis of
the neck region,
it looks like he's
been dead for 2-3 hours
Which puts the time of death bet-ween
6 and 7 PM, is that correct? fl
Inspector, this is clearly a suicide
A suicide?
Yes. Please follow me!
Lboki'atlath is!
And what is this 7
A model the deceased made.
Notice there's a key in the lake.
It's the key to this apartment,
It's a specially made key so duplication
is impossible
And there are only 2 spares,
his grandmother has one and the other is
kept by the management company
When you got here, the door was...
It was locked. Which means the apartment
was completely'? sealed off.
I see, so that's why you concluded
it was suicide...
You're wrong!
He would never commit suicide!
When I brought him juice this evening,
he said he wanted to eat
pumpkin for dinner...
What time was that?
Just about 5. I went out right after that...
he was killed while I was gone...
What kind of juice was it?
It's my own blend to prevent
summer heat fatigue.
It has some honey, garlic, banana in it
And anyway. he showed no signs of
wanting to kill himself.
Besides, he had no reason to...
was troubled
In what way...
in? 13 (22)
flax? Egfi4$
He said the design he was wanking on
for his graduation project
Yoshihiko Kido (24)
Jyonan University Medical Student
wasn't coming along.
I knew it!
Maybe that's why he was so depressed
And judging from the red crayon scratches
on the wall and the mess in the room,
he must have been in a
very unstable state of mind...
Excuse me, Inspector
What/is this white thing attached
to-the;key
You're right...What could it be...
What are you doing. you fool
I think this is toilet paper
Tbilbt paper?
Yes. Tissue and other kinds of paper
won't disintergrate so easily when wet.
I'll bet someone out the toilet paper really
thin then rolled it to make string
but why would they put it on a key?
Well... he could be rather
strange at times...
It was probably just due to curiosity!
At any rate, this place was
completely locked...
No it wasn't
What?!
Over there... the ventilation
duct's open
You dummy, do you think some one can
get in and out through that tiny space?
Take a look. The duct's onlyfabout
15 centimeters wide
All the other keys are accounted for,
this was definitely a locked room
But I still think it "8 strange
to be a suicide
It was pitch dark? you-couldn't cut the
artery with such precision could you?
Pitch dark?
Where the fights 0 when you
came in here?
H yes but the bathroom...
The light m the bathroom was also
off . I turned it on and then went in...
It's still light outside at 6-7 PM
which is the estimated time of death
but there're no windows in the bathroom.
Without the light on, you wouldn't be
able to see past your hands
The killer may have inadvertently turned
the lights off when he was done...
If this was murder, could the crayon
markings on the wall be to cover the crime?
The question is this key.
How was the killer able to leave the
key here in the Water.
There are 2 more mysteries.
Why did the killer mark not only the wall
but also the edge of the (filler
and the lock on the front door with crayon...
and that ventilation duct,
it was open from the start, I doubt
the killer would have overlooked it.
Wait a minute, that's not the only
place that was open
I've got it!
Inspector. I've solved the case!
Forget what I said before,
this is a murder!
Just follow me!
The key to solving this case is...
Is that mailbox!
First, the killer...
threaded some string under the bridge,
pulls it to the front door.
Passes it through the mailbox,
goes outside & locks the door...!
And then, puts the key on one end of
the string, when the other thread is pulled.
The key moves toward the model,
and when it passes under the
bridge, the paper string breaks
and the key falls into the water...!
What do you think?
That solves the mystery of the locked room!
Yes, I see! Brilliant deduction, Mourl!
That's it...! I've got it!!
Uh, sir. I don't understand
This entrance and the living room are
at a right angle. Isn't that right?
Huh? What about it?
If you pulled the thread
from outside the door.
The thread would rub against the pillar at
the corner and leave a mark. wouldn't it?
It's not here...
I wanted them to see the killer deliberately
colored the edge of the pillar
that this trick had nothing
to do with thread .
Now for this...
That's it! I've got it
The killer locked the door
through] the mailbox rigging it...
the marks are... not here
That's it! The ventilation duct!
The killer used the trick I explained
but wuth the ventilation duct
Umm. . theoretically, it I's-possible
No. it's impossible
See. there's a dog in the house
on the other side
that is a wonderful watchdog, he won't
Iet anyone except his master get close
Isn't that right, Kido?
Yes It always barks at me too.
This place is in plain view of that yard.
If someone was doing
something suspicious.
That dog would bark like crazy and
everybody'd look outside.
I guess I missed on this one too
it must've been suicide after all,
Inspecto'rc'.
No, it is murder! And the killer.
The victim's wound shows no hesitation cut.
The gash is perfectly straight and deep
The only ones capable of such precision,
would be a doctor or a medical student
ut what trick did he use . ?.
The buglight'?
Wait a minute The sweater in the
entrance! The crayon markings all
over the apartment! And...
That's it!
That's why that duct was left
open just so much,
making this place an
almost sealed room!
Now to prove it...!
There has to be something.
There has to be...
Hmm, what's this?
Wha'tjs-tms' émem.
The smell's coming from here...
I wonder)! /
There it is!
Excuse me, Ma'am!
Yes?
Is that the cup you brought
the juice in?
Why yes it is... how unusual
he washed it...
I knew it now I have the proof
Thank you for all your cooperation.
That's all for today.
I've got 'it'!
I figured out the trick the killer used.
What?!
Are;you sure, Conan?!
Yup, I'll demonstrate. Ma'am,
may-J-borrow your key?
You dummy, how would you know...
Here kid, you need the key, right?
Take it.
Thank you
Wait here for a while
Hey», what in the world are you doing?!
Never mind. just watch.
And now ma'am.
When Igggqnbutithe'door, I Want you to
turn all the lights off
Alright...
OK? I'm going to start, everyone
watch quietly
Humph. how "Coo \
Something fell...
A beetle
A male beetle
What!
The key...
A buglight!
How did it go?
Conan.
I see, so this is how the killer did
it... but why did the beetle-come here?
The smell 1)
It was lured here because the top of
monument was coated
with the scent of something it liked
And what about the sweater
on the threshold?
The killer put it there so the
beetle would be able to walk easily
Beetles have a hard time walking on
Wb'dd "flooring.and tile!
This hallway and the living room
are carpetted...
The conditions were ideal for the killer.
Good work Conan.
Hey? Where did you get the
beetle you used?
Oh, I just took one of them Mr.
Kido is raising in his room
I didn't ask permission.
Sorry Mr. Kido, I let one get away!
Oh, uh, forget it
By the way. Mr. Kido... were you here in
this apartmen'utonight
before I went tofget you?
Eh? No, I didn't come here
Reall; ? Are you sure?
Of course I'm sure!
Why're you asking that...
Then why does your handkerchief smell
ike the juice Mrs. Mltsue made?
Em?) "
Mrs. Mitsue brought the Juice to
him at about 5 this evemng
Mr. Kido...after Makoto drank the
juice, you washed the cup, didn't you?
And the juice that dripped to the floor
you wiped it up with your handkerchief,
didn't you
hy did he do it...
The reason is...
The male beetle might be lured by
the juice being its smell is stronger
that the female beetle's scent.
So it might climb something other
than the monument!
You coated the monument wit'hsthe .
Female's scent, didn't fiou.
Kido, you didn't...
Let me see your handkerchief
boy. I
I was so relieved I shut him up
I forgot to get rid of the handkerchief.
All because I got drunk celebrating
and fell asleep
Why did you do it...?
About a year ago, he come to me
with a proposition
that I stole some sleeping
pills from the university's hospital.
We sold them.
But recently, he told me he wanted to quit.
I was a 'raid he'd tell you about it and
I'd get arrested
Why you...
I'm sure Makoto regretted what he did and
was prepared to be punished...
This comes late, the crime
has been committed
but a life is a burden
heavier than you could ever imagine
Delve on that burden
while you're in prison
you'll have a lot of time to think
about It. .'I
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODU ERS
M'lc'hlh'lko Suwa
Masalfito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatbmo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Jumchl Iloka
CRIPTS BY.
Kan]! Kashlwabara
K'azunarl Kouchn
Junlchl Mayashlta
YUIChl Hloure
Toshlkl lnoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatfimo Sudo
Hnrotoshl Takatanl
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushl Aono
Aklo Kawamura
Takashl Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yuklhlro Shlbutam
filRECTOR'S'OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takash'l Nomura
Hiron'obu Ho Jkosh:
Takahlsa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshl Kobayashl
EDITOR.
Terumltsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
KEN]! Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In 3550613 tron With
Yomlun Telecasting Corpora tron
(5th Am; ama Shogakukan
II Rights Reserved
I feel so sorry for Mrs. Mitsue.
You can't replace her gran
but why don't the two of you visit
her from time to time
Conan you were so sharp tonight.
I was amazed.
Uh that's because I always get to
see the famous Mr. Mouri in action...
Like they say. "Learn by watching,
Without being taught!
You owe it all to me, you're learning the
trade without you even realizing it!!
I wish YOU would learn a little
more of trade...
Get the real killer"?
Find them! Find both Sato and Takagm
First. I'll start checking out the pub the
victim stopped off before the crlme
It can't be.
Is this the room?!
Tihaitfliierson lives in'th'is condominium
too, doesn't he?
Was)
(me)
DETECTIVE LOV TSTQRYS'ZLPART {It
(may