Inspiration flashes. piercing through
to the truth,
Once he gets going. nothing can stop him.
In today's episode, a lot of police
officers make their appearance,
the Junior Detective League
prove to be an asset
The one &only truth is brought
into the light,
he looks like a child but he's got the
brains of an adult.
His name is... Detective Conan
YA AA
TA AA
DETECTIVE LOVE STORY 2 / PART I
FA AA
There's no doubt about it,
she's beginning to suspect your
true identity .
It's no use trying to keep it
hidden from her any longer...
You'll only end up hurting her...
Wh... why are you telling me this...
You mean you can read how a criminal
thinks but you can't read
the heart of a woman?
The heart of a woman?
I'm in love with you...
I have been since the moment we met...
You didn't know that. did you...
Masked Yaiba?
Cut, cut!
That won't do Conan!
You've got to look more surprised!
This is the climatic scene where the
female spy who betrayedss
the underworld confesses her
Iove for Masked Yaiba!'w
Good grief. .isn't this supposed to be
a school play?
Then let's do a normal story.
Like Momotaro or Issunboshi
I can't direct something that
Iacks reality like those stories!
Masked. Yaiba is just as bad...
Don't complain, I'm not happy as the
Potato Giant but I'm sticking it out!
He's right!
After all. we snuck in this abandoned
building to create an air of suspense!
Then let's do a police story!
You know what I mean, don't you?
Where the criminal escapes into
an abandoned building
& a shoot-out takes place...
Hold it!!
Stop!
Put your hands up &don't make a move!!
Detective Sato...
Ayumi!
Don't cone near me!!
Ayumi!?
Don't come near
Conan!!
Let me go!
No let me go!
Let me go!!
Sorry little girl, I must
have scared you...
I'm really sorry!!
Ayumi?!
Conan...
Where is he?
I think he's out on the roof
Let's go!
Ho, hold it...
Gee. whizz!!
Detective Sato!
Oh Detective Takagi
Detective Sato
Takagi! Go around &
come in from below!
Right away!
Hey. what happened?
What! A prisoner escaped!
Yes that's right!
We were taking him to headquarters,
there was an accident involving
a car & a motorcycle.
The suspect was sitting next to me but my
attention went to the accident &
when I turned back.
He was gone!!
He was a very quiet man, I never
thought he'd try to escape...
You blew it!
You let him escape,
you won't get off the hook
by just filling a report you know
Boy do I know it!!
18:43... escaped suspect is
apprehended... . there...
Oh no , the chain on the handcuffs cut
Oh bother... you're nothing but trouble...
Now then, get up!
I don't believe it...
The key! The key! The key!
Where's the key!
No. no, it's not here!
Good grief, I bet I dropped it
somewhere...
I shouldn't have been So rough...
1. I'm Innocent.
I'm innocent!!
I didn't kill her. Detective!!
Hey... did you hear some kind of noise
from upstairs?
It must be your imagination.
The place is locked up tight
Come on, let's get this job done!
Detective Sato. where are you?
Detective Sato...
Strange...
Isn't this an art museum?
Then why aren't there any
paintings...
You're.right'...
There're probably changing displays!
Listen here! It's very dangerous
didnst-! tell yo ids to.go home!
Takagi...
Detective Sato?
Takagi! Over here!
Where are you?
Detective Sato...
Detective Sato?
In here! Here!
What are you doing in there?
This is the men's room.
And what happened to the suspect?
Uh,well... I did manage to
recapture him. but .
I sort of made a mistake...
Wh. what in the world did you do?!
Isn't it normal procedure to
handcufPthe suspect, hands?
I didn't want him to get away again so
I inadvertently handcuffed myself to him!
Where's the key?
I think I lost it
if the other detectives hear about
this, I'd die of eabarrasseent
so could you please go get the spare &
not tell anyone?
I wouldn't be able to get in & out
unnoticed
the entire station is in an uproar because
of this escaped prisoner
I see... is that any way to talk
to a senior officer
besides, this entire situation occurred
when you took your eyes off the prisoner
& allowed him to get away, right?
Y. yes... you are correct
Alright, get going Takag
Yes ma: am
I didn't do it...
I didn't kill her!
Don't know what happened but
when I woke in the morning,
Miss Muranishi was dead!
That's all he's been saying
It's the truth!
Please believe me!
Listen to me Mr. Higashida...
The deceased is Masami Muranishi, she
Iived in the same condominum building
as you & she just happened
to be your boss
Victim
Masami Muranishi
The crime was committed
in her bathroom
Victim
Masami Muranishi
When her body was found, you were on
her bed, you were stone drunk asleep!!
The front door was locked & chained
from the inside.
The apartment was completely locked!
Besides. your fingerprints were on
the doorlock & chain
& even on the
video cord we found around her neck
On top of that, you always argued
with her about work.
The night of the murder you told a friend
you were "Going to tell her off"
then you rushed out to go home,
isn't that so!
You were drunk. you went to her apartment
& killed her in the heat of the argument,
isn't that how it happened?
You locked the door so
she couldn't run away...
and after you killed her. you were so
drunk. you fell asleep on her bed,
isn't that right?
But I don't remember anything...
That's because you were drunk
out of your mind...
Yes it's true, I hated her for
finding fault with even job I did!!
But I didn't hate her enough to kill her!
Then why'd you try to escape?
Th... there's some place I have to be
And where's that?
I have a daughter in Chicago...
my wife took her when we got divorced.
My daughter sent me a wedding invitation.
And for the past 17 years.
I thought she hated me...
that's why I have to go. I have to!!
It's the truth! Go to my apartment.
You'll find the letter & the ticket!
B. but what can I do...
That man's not a bad man
You know 'he let me gox& when he
put me down. he said he was sorry!
If he was a bad man, he wouldn't do that!!
But listen...
What time is the flight tomorrow?
It... leaves Narita at 12:30...
D. Detective Sato?
Takagi? I want you to listen very carefully
to what I'm about to say to you
What?! You can't contact Takagi & Sato?!
Police Station
What?! You can't contact ,akagi & Sato?!
0... I've been trying to rais
them on the cellular...
Something may have happened to them
while they were pursuing the suspect...
Find them!!
They should still be in that area!»
Hey Shiratori! We're going along too!!
Yessir!!
Wheat. get the real killer by
noon tomorrow?
D. do you mean me?
Yes that's right. I'll keep an eye
on this guy for you until then...
Wbesides. I'm not roin: an where for awhile
Alright then. I'll go get the key.
Let's take him down to headquarters
first then we both can go...
No! If someone sees you at headquarters
getting the key,
the boss"ll put you through the ringer,
while you-ire writing the report,
the plane"ll take off & it'll be too late!
Now listen, we're still in pursuit
of the escaped prisoner!
That's what we have to make it look
Iike. in the meantime,
you will work alone &
find the real killer!
That's our only alternative!
If the suspect is found not guilt
before he is delivered to
the Public Prosecutor's Office,
the police department has the right to set
him free at their discretion!
B:.but...
The time limit is tomorrow morning
about 10 when this-art museum opens!
Because as»soon as someone comes In
here. they're sure to call the police.
I'll believe you until then. is that
OK with you?
1. I really appreciate that!
B, but I don't know if I can do it
all by myself...
Why you aren't alone. Those kids
Iook anxious to help!
Hehehe...
You got me? The time limit is
97) TCENERR MYO RNRCN!
You have until then to capture the
real killer & prove this man's innocence!
Don't worry, you can do it
Have faith in Yourself...
Hey, what're you doing?
We're going!
No, wait a minute...ll know Detective Sato's
in tight with Inspector Megure,
she only said
those things to encourage me...
His mood's been going up &down
Iike a seesaw...
Weird
Hey! What're you doing up there?!
Eh? Us?
Didn't you see the sign down there?!
It said no trespassing!!
It was an emergency
That's right! We were chasing a criminal!
Criminal. oh sure!
You're not the police!
Uh. I may not look it. but I'm with
the Metropolitan Police Department...
Of course if anyone finds out a detective is
here with an escaped murder suspect,
our efforts will have been for nothing.
Nor er or IS Oma el oO
his daughter's wedding,
you have to work on your own
& In secret
Oh. uh sorry about that, we were
just playing cops & robbers...
Good grief...
You think he'll be OK...
Eh? What?
That detective didn't seem too reliable...
You're so right! He seems so kind &
somewhat clumsy,
the kind you just can't help worrying about!
But he's really quite dependable
when he puts his mind to it...
Oh great...
Besides, that kid's with him...
I hat Kid
That kid wearing the glasses...
somehow, that kid gives me hope...
That's the 5th one...
I wonder what happened
I told you! They're looking for the
killer. Detective Sato &me!
Detective Takagi, you look like a hoodlum
It can't be helped, I doing some
top secret investigating...
Anyway, we've got to go to that pub first
That's where we'll start
because Mr. Higashida said
he stopped off there just before the murder
Yes... he was totally plastered
he said 'I'm going to tell that woman
off once & for all today.
But I never dreamed he'd kill her...
Was he alone when he left?
Mr. Kitagawa who was drinking
with him took him home.
There, that's him.
He & Mr. Higashida work
for the same coapany
So he's the same Kitagawa who first
discovered the body...
He discovered the body!
Yes...when Higashida & Miss Muranishi
didn't show up for work the next mooing,
he had the landlord.use the master key
to unlock the door,
that's how he found the body.
I'm leaving the money on the table
Thank you!
Oh, uh...Mr. Kitagawa!
Om with the police!
I have a few questions for you...
I already told the police everything.
I'm in a state of shock.
My friend killed our boss...
Please leave me alone...
Of course...
He's right, he's already been
questioned by the police...
so has the pub's owner
probably several times...
That's right! Miss Muranishi was a
Tokyo!Spirits fan &
Mr Higashida was anti-Spirits!
Really...
You there!
What're you'think you're doing?!
I'm terribly sorry
we'll be going now
Oh. I've got to call home!
My mom"ll be worried
Me too
Me too!
Good grief. I'll never be able 'to.get the real
8B ODE THY
What?!
ET NE TI
ou wan me O pre en you're a
spending the night here?
No. I don't mind.
If Detective Takagi
Is with you I'm not worried...
Tomorrow's Sunday, the big day!
I'll just tell your parents you're
all coming with me to tomorrow's event
Event? What event?
Tomorrow's the day myginvention
will serve our town!
I call it [Tropical Rainbow], when
iteblows, it glows like a rainbow
When you're done with what you're
doing, come have a look!
Sure thing.
DidpDoctor Agasa say he'd do it?
Yes. he was pretty excited about a
fireworks 'display
they're holding in Haido tomorrow
Fireworks?... I didn't hear anything
about that.
Never mind that. next we go to the
victim's apartment. right?
Eh?... Uh, right
The police again?
The officers who came in the
afternoon just left...
Yes. well there's something they
forgot to check
Who're those kids?
This is a social studies project!
We're experiencing police work & then
reporting to the class!
Oh I know. you're studying jobs &
the people doing them!
I'll return the key to you later then .
Yes, I'd appreciate it
oh, hey!
F you touch things your...
» Don't worry, look!
While you were buying your hat, we
bought these gloves
Conan told us to!
I see...
Good grief where in the world
IS the suspect & Detectives Sato & Takagt!
It seems we lost contact with them
when they entered an/abandoned building
in pursuit of the escaped prisoner...
Don't you find that strange?
It's not like Detective Sato to not call
in for so long...
You don't think...
They could be lying dead, killed
by their prisoner .
Nooo!!
How awful...
Why you, how dare you kill
my valuable subordinates!
Eh?! Detective Sato?!
What?! The suspect has
Detective Sato?!
Miss Miwa's being kept hostage!
0... Am I coming down with a
I'm sorry, this is all my fault...
Forget it, it we made a false arrest.
We'd have to apologize to you...
Besides... this isn't for you
Hun?
I just didn't want your daughter to
go through what I did
I lost my father when I was little
it broke my heart...
Come on kids. let's go home...
we're not going to come up with
anything no matter how hard we look
the guys from the crime lab
were already here.
There isn't a single piece of
trash on the floor...
There are 4 things out of place...
The first us, the color of the mattress,
the sheets. the pillow &
the curtain beside the bed...
everything from the kitchenware. to
the dishes,
down to the interior is in beige,
why then is only the bed &
curtain in gray...
I-suppose-ités-justdcéncidence
But there were beige sheets &
curtains in the closet!
And the lady who ran the pub told us
Miss Muranishi just loved beige!
And she also told us MisslMuranishi
Iiked the Spirits & cactus!
She also said Mr Higashida knew a lot
about video equipment & hated baths!
And that when he got drunk he would
always fall asleep and couldn't wake up.
That's why he was late for work a lot!
I don't think she told the investigators
that when they questioned her
when people are being questioned
by the police.
They are afraid that if they mention
something unrelated to the crime
they'll be reprimanded.
But the tension sometimes makes them
talk anyway.
She may not have appeared like it but
I think she was scared
S, scared...
The second thing is,
why was this calendar taken off
the wall next to the bed...
See, this is this year's To « 0 Spirits
calendar, it was in the closet.
It matches the spot on the wall perfectly
She probably took it down because the
team's not doing so good lately.
But look!
Her whole schedule until December
IS written In
Why. you're right...
The third thing is. there'rerslight
traces the furniture's been moved
The men from the crime lab
mentioned that«too,
they said she'd probably
rearranged the room
But don't you think it's strange
she wouldn't notice she'd crushed
something this valuable When she
moved:the chest?
They're just matches
Open it up
Huh. There's*a piece of paper inside
why, this is?!
It's her.marriage registration!
She was going to be married! But the
groomss name hasn't been filled in.
His seal is on it though...
The fourth thing is, the cactus
On the day of the murder, it had been
raining heavily since morning...
Would a cactus lover such as herself
Ieave the pots outside?
Which means someone besides the victim
moved things around for
some unknown reason
Yes. here it is!
This is the gold dolphin cactus the pub
owner gave her on the day sherwas killed!
But the thorns have been bent. poor thing...
So what does that have to do
with anything
e suspecC r. 1gas I a was
found sleeping on the bed
in this room sprawled out like
it was his home.
His fingerprints were found not only
on the video cord,
which was the murdrer weapon.
But also on the door lock
& even the chainlock...
No. it can't be...
You don't mean. this room?!
Shall we go check it out?
His apartment's in this condominium
too, isn't it?
Yes, let's go
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatdomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
CRIPTS BY
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisd Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
OGosho Aoyanta /'Shogdkukan
Il Rights Reserved
The time... we don't have much time left
Eh?!
Hurry, get in!
We're going to the real killer's home!
N. now of all things...
I'm sure they said bomb...
There's no time! Hurn! Hurry!!
5432,1..1
5432,1...1
DETECTIVE I VE STORY2 PART Ii
"NW in: EEC:
8.9 AA
(Bz)