Inspiration flashes.
Piercing through to the truth.
Once he gets going. nothing can stop him
The stage for today's case is
the Loop Line.
There is no end of the line for
either the train or the case
The one & onl truth is brought
into the light.
He looks like a child but he's got the
brains of an adult.
His name is... Detective Conan.
THE LOOP LINE OF SILENCE
2nd Street station
We missed the train, didn't we...
Uh huh...
Hey...
Wait for goodness sake...
Good 'grief.
The ole guy's=aslostycause...g \
We just finished a job, at least let
me have a beer
Oh big deal the job was delivering
some papers the client forgot,
that's all
on top of that, since
it's Sunday, n one was in the office
ahh... that hits the spot, delicious!
The train sure is empty,
isn't it Conan
h huh...
Probably because it's a Sunday night.
This IS the business district.
'Masuretit's usualydbusy-on-workdays
hew... boy today sure wore me out...
Sorry, it's all my fault...
You really are a klutz. Kiyomi who started
a year before you was a fast learner.
By the way, Kiyomi sure rushed home, I
wonder what she had to do...
Seiji Kurata (26)
She probably had a date. After all,
Sunday's a day off.
Sizuka Kawai (24)
And if it weren't for someone I know, we
wouldn't have had to work today either...
I'm really sorry I promise to make
It up to you soon...
Yukiko-Mori (20)
That's what you always say...
Now now. don't be so hard on her.
Yukiko didn't do it on purpose
There you go again.
Spoiling the newcomer...
that's why I always look
Iike the meanfone...
You know that not true...
OK, calm down you two...
Huh: &«
The train will be pulling into track #2
momentarily,
please wait behind the yellow line
Oh... I'm going to go buy some juice
Come back . the train's coming
Don't worry. Get on without me
Good. grief...
Conan, come on Hurry.
Alright.
I wonder if Yukiko got on OK
That girl's so irresponsible sometimes
1 Let's go take a look
Pretend we don't know him
What're you doing Yukiko
Oh Seiji, I made it just in time.
I spilled some.
Clumsy...
You know Yukiko...
Isn't that? Kiyomi?!
IL 10...
She left hours ago, what's she doing here...
She's fast asleep.
You mean she's been sitting here and
rode the train for a whole lap?
She must've been exhausted...
Hey Kiyomi, wake up! Kiyomi!
Hey!
Huh?
What was that?
Excuse me...
There's no pulse she's dead.
Excuse me, are you her friends?
Yes, we're...
Who are you?
Who? me?
I am Kogoro Mouri, private investigator.
You mean Kogoro Mouri... the famous...
That's right, in the flesh...
Wow!
It looks like something pricked her earlobe
And her ear's a little black, .like
it's been pressed back...
Excuse me, sir, her ears...
You keep quiet!
The color of the ears... it looks
Iike a reaction to pois n
This may be a murder
A murder 7!
Ran, get the conductor and
call the police too!
What is this mark?
Everyone, please stand back.
I don't want anyone in here until the police
arrive! That means you too...
Kiyomi...
Please don't touch the body.
Oh I'm sorry
Inspector Megure...
I took down the names and addresses of
all the passengers we let off
The estimated time of death is
approximately 6:30 PM
Yes, I see
The body was discovered past 7:30 PM.
It takes 1 hour and10 minutes for this
wa + scovered past 7:30 P
Ioop line to complete 1 lap so...
So I guess there's no mistake, she
died in the train...
Which means the victim died shortly
after boarding the train.
The train completed 1 lap and
came back to this station...
MM... and the cause of deal
It appears she was pricked on the
earlobe with a pin
Iike object coated with a fast acting poison.
There are no other wounds or
signs of a struggle.
This is the victim's shoulder bag...
What are you doing...
Sorry...
Uh, sir. Wasn't that left open?
Oh just be quiet...
Huh? Just a second
what you're saying is,
there's a possibility the killer took some
thing out of victim's bag
Inspector, her wallet's here. Nothing
seems to have been taken out
we'll let her 3 friends confirm the
contents... they may notice something.
Hmm.
Detective Takagi
there's more over there.
Eh... you're right.
Thanks, Conan.
I'd like you to confirm these items
where's your other friend?
It seems the shock of it is
hitting her only now...
I don't blame her.
I'll let you two take care of the
indentification here.
Conan!
Come on, let's wait over there.
Neo 0
How are you feeling?
I'm fine, thank you.
I don't remember what Kiyomi
always carried with her.
But Seiji might know.
He:d been asking her for a date for the
Iongest time and he gave her a lot of presents
Presents?
Were you dating the victim?
No, she kept turning me down.
I see, that means you had a good
motive, revenge.
I'd never...! Shizuka, how could
you say such a thing?!
Now, now...
Usually we get along very well...
But becausegof what happened today...
So, after work, you all went for dinner but
Kiyomi alone left for home.
Yes, that's right.
Do you usually wor {on Sundays?
Our job is advertising design. But
I made a mistake yesterday
so we had to give up our Sunday to finish up.
And when's theilast time you saw hey?
It was at the 2nd Street station.
We all walked her tofthe station...
How did she seem at that time?
We parted at the ticket gate
but she was her usual self.
And that was around 6:30PM?
And the three of you were together
until discovering the body, correct?
Yes...
Did Kiyomi have any enemies?
Seiji, you just told us she kept turning you
down you are the most likely...
You've got to be kidding.
I'm not the only one...
Yukiko, you hated her for stealing your
boyfriend, didn't you?!
No, I didn't...
And Shizuka, didn't you tell me she
stole your design?!
What're you trying to say?
I see, so all of you had motives.
Don't be hasty, Mouri. The estimated time
of her death is somewhere around 6:30PM.
That's about the time we left her
at the station
es... right after you left
Were you three really together
the whole time?
Yes, we had dinner together.
It's a place we always go to so you
can verify it if you want
Since they all have alibis, I'm sure we can
exclude them from our list of suspects
I'm pretty sure it was a random
killing by a crazed person...
we have the names and addresses of the
passengers me let off
I just hope the killer's among them.
However, since her bag was found open, I'd
Iike to check through your possessions too.
Why did the killer kill her in the train?
And why stab her in the
ears of all places
and her ears were laid flat as if they
had been pressed...
it's too strange to be a random killing.
So you're saying you know
no reason for anyone hating her...
An MD player and a headphone
with a bent arm...
Every disc has.a label on it...
Index labels for the MD
What's this?
Strange...
None of them have a front label...
This color...
That's it!
Something was bothering me.
Now I know what it was
Yes, it would be possible to kill Kiyomi
and have an alibi if one were
to use that method...
There's no mistake,
that person's the killer!!
If my deduction is correct, that
person is the killer,
but I don't have enough proof...
Aren't you through searching
our things yet?
I'm sure they're almost done...
We have no reason to steal something
out of Kiyomi's bag
You people have a lot of nerve.
That's enough, Shizuka
They're just doing their job.
What's that...?
Hey!
Oops!
What're you doing?
I'm sorry.
Conan, look what you did!
I'm sorry, Seij.
I'm really very sorry
No problem. I perspire a lot
so.l always carry an extra shirt.
Inspector. Would it be alright if I
got a shirt from my things?
I guess it's OK.
Hey! Takagi!
BB g- =
That was very naughty.
You have to behave!
I'm going to apologize to him.
Excuse me, Kiyomi and the three of you
were good friends, weren't you?
Sure, I got a little excited back there
and made it sound like we all hated her
but we weren't really on bad terms,
we were all good friends...
Of course, you were.
Take today for example, Yukiko dropped
Kiyomi's MD player
and it broke but that Kiyomi,
she didn't even get mad.
She forgave Yukiko.
Kiyomi and Yukiko were especially close,
I thought they'd fight after
she stole Yukiko's boyfriend but
you're too young to understand
Didn't Kiyomi get on at the same
Second Street station like us?
That's right
But she was sitting in the 2nd car,
wasn't she?
People usually get on the car
closest to the ticket gate.
It seems strange to deliberately walk to
another car furthur away
Not really, when the train stops at
Kiyomi's stop. the ticket gate is
right in front if you're in the 2nd car.
That's why whenever we take the same
train, we have to walk to the 2nd car.
Which means they knew she'd be
in the 2nd car...
I've got it. I'veesolved everything.
Inspector We're done looking through
all their possessions.
I apologize for the long wait.
You,may all leave now.
If something cames up, I'd appreciate it
if you'd give us your cooperation
We can't have you leave just yet.
What's the matter, Mourn...
Aha, that pose!
This was no random killing.
The killer is one of you three!
One of us?
And the murder weapon is
right there among your things.
But Mourn...
We all have alibis, remember?
We were having dinner!
But it was still possible to kill her
Firstly, the killer knew Kiyomi would leave
early so while seeing her off at the station,
the killer checked the schedule
of the train she would take,
and calculated how long it would take for it
to return carrying}Kiyomi's body,
After that, all the killer had to do
was go to dinner,
creating an alibi then retrieve the murder
weapon from the body when it returned...
Weapon? What kind of weapon?
Don't you know? Something that would
appear natural when put onto the ears.
Yes, I see! If you planted a poisoned
needle in the headphone.
Right, which means, the killer is
Yukiko Morn!
Yes you!!
You broke Kiyomi'ssMD player
and lent her yours
with the poisoned needle in it!
And pretending to buy some juice,
you boarded the front car
and retrieved the weapon
You knew Kiyomi always
sat in the 2nd car from the front...
it doesn't take long to get the weapon
since you know where she'd be
But the cord was caught on her shoulder.
You pulled on it too hard and the
headphone got bent.
Yes, I see, it certainly is bent.
The mark from the cord was
found on her arm.
And her ears were laid back against her
head proving she had a headphone on...
I just went to bu, some juice.
I didn't do what you just said.
Your friend's body was in front of you,
you should have been in shock,
but for some reason, you fixed
the collar on her dress
I'm sure it was because when the cord
got caught, it'made the collar stand...
Actually you intended to retrieve
the weapon. .and leave the body
But your friends came looking for
you from the other car
So you had to pretend you discovered the
body with the other two and play out your role
So the victim pricked her own
ears with the poisoned needle.
But why kill her in the train of all places?
There aren't too many
passengers on this line on Sundays...
Very few people get into the 2nd car
It's the perfect place when you have to
retrieve the weapon after securing an alibi
I:'see...
On top of that, an unspecified number of
people go in and out
so it's easier to make it appear
a random killing.
All she-had to do was-make
a mistake at work
so they'd all have to go in on a Sunday.
Proof, where's the proof?
I don't see anything that looks
Iike a needle
I believe she used that handkerchief
to pull it out
there was a piece of sponge stuck on it...
I was sitting here all the time.
Right here with all of you.
When your things were being checked,
you said you didn't feel well
and went off alone.
You mean she had to be alone so she
could take the needle out...
May I see your handkerchief?
Alright...
It's no use now, Inspector.
It's a tiny needle. She's probably
already thrown it away somewhere.
Mouri, are you telling me this is all
supposition and you have no proof?
The proof is in that MD player.
What?
If you mean fingerprints, she was a friend.
It's only 'natural-for hers to be on it.
I didn't lend it to her today!!
Then will you take the disc out of it?
What's wrong?
Yukiko, thank you«by Kiyomi
You: didn't lend:it«to.her...
you did say that, didn't you?
If you didn't lend it to her, how was
she able to write a message dated today...
and with the ballpoint pen we found
among her things!
You're right.
The color of these letters matches the
color of the pen-found in her bag!
That's right, Kiyomi left you a message
She never dreamed
you were going to kill her.
Kiyomi... I just couldn't forgive you.
You stole my boyfriend
Today is his birthday,
I knew she would rush home...
So that's why you chose
today to kill her...
Yes...
ORIGINAL GomiC 8 OKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Mich Hiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
Junichi hoka
CRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIR CTR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIREC "ORSYOF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaoa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
Il Rights Reserved
Takagi did you find out how
she got the poison?
Yes, it's a fast acting alkaloid poison
they use on darts in South America.
She confessed that she bought some
when she wasyabroad a few days ago.
She coated a tiny needle with it.
Poison for darts...
We took so long identifying the poison,
Mouri, if you hadn't figured things out
this case might have gone solved.
Vs AL
poison for darts... yes
well, I had a feeling that's what it was
Really, so you figured that out too.
Mouri you're great!
Give me a break,
ou haven't even fi ured out I've been
knocking you out!
What?! A curse?!
Oh no!
Mr Oda!!
This rope...
That can't be...
his legs don't reach the railing?!
Yes, this is definitely a suicide!
this is a murder!
(sin?)
LEGEND OF THE MYSTERIOUS
5-STORY PAGOD =PARYT1™>
Led O &
(Bu iE)