Inspiration flashes,
piercing through to the truth.
Once he gets going. nothing can stop him.
Todays mystery takes place deep in the
mountains.
The legend of the 5 storied pagoda
gives way to an impossible crime.
The one & only truth is brought into light
He looks like a child but§he's got the
brains of an adult.
His)name is. . Detective Conan
STORY PAGODA-PART I
Led O
Shizuoka, zu
Temple gate of Genkai Temple
Beautiful!
What a great change.
Yeah, we owe it all to you for
winning this-prize in the contest
But Conan. you solved
the puzzle for me
I couldn't believe how easy it was.
Dad!
Let's go!
I hate il here! This place ls so-depressing!
These freestrips.really'are lousy!
What ferve, when you first heard about it,
you were so excited about the free trip.
You two go on without me! I'll just go back
to the hotel and soak in the bath!
Excuse me There's no smoking
allowed on temple grounds.
Shigekichi Okabe
Oh, I didn't know.
We're terribly sorry.
It's no problem. But it's.true, this place
may be boring for tourists.
That's not true!
You-don't see sights like this living
in the city. It cleanses the soul for me.
How nice of you. you're young
but very admirable
If you like, I'll give you a tour of the temple.
Really?! Could you?
Count me out!
Yqu're very rude dad?Let's go!
This temple was built 400 years ago.
400 years ago? It's very. old.
Because of it's ace, there are many
REE Troll SEE Tero,!
For example, there is an old
well near the pagoda
which had been listed until
the middle of the Edo period.
Why did they stop using it?
It suddenly went dry.
Legend says that a young woman who was
heartbrokenfcried for
3 days in front of the well.
When her tears ran dry. the water from
the well filled her eyes And:it was: used: up.
Hahaha. what*rubbish...
There's a frightening legend
behind this pagoda.
What kind of legend?
In the beginninc of the Edo period
there was a young monk
who the head priest picked to become
the successor of this temple, but...
He fell in love with a girl
from the villnge, broke his vows,
Ieft the temple and ran
away to get married.
perhaps it was a curse. the monk
was taken away by the goshawk.
The monk was later found dead.
Hanging from the pagoda...
How awful.
Tihere'sfmore. in the middle
of the Edo period...
A misguided priest sold the temple's
furnishings and used the money for liquor.
But one day he disappeared...
A few daysllater, he was found
dead hanging from the pagoda.
Since then. it's been said that whoever
breaks the vows of the temple will be cursed.
Hey. stop making thosed spoo « fac s.
A ghost
Tankail
Don't be afraid. he's the head priest.
Head priest...?
So, you're pretending to be a family this time,
what are you looking around for now... 7?!
what are you looking around for now...?!
Tankal
He dsPriest
DULY
OD oe
No, wait. They're only tourists.
Humph! They look suspicious.
I don't trust them!
I dongliwanlsyou toYbring strangers
around without my permission!
But tourists are the temple's...
Nonsense! Don't forget there are those who
will desecrate this temple for that very reason!
Uh...that's...
But soon. punishment will
befall the unbeliever...!!
Punishment by the curse...
Uh: is:something wrong?
The truth is, a tour company took control
of- this property and
they/ve decided to build
an amusement park here
Then this area's going to change?
Yes, the head priest is opposing
it, saying he was tricked
He has become bitter even toward
tourists as you saw
He has some nerve!
Scaring people like that!
Come on, let's get out of here!
Dad wait!
I'm sorry, my father's short tempered...
Don't apologize. the fault was all mine...
By the way. is your father
by chance Kogoro Mourn?
Yes; well...he's a private investigator
Oh! I knew It. hers thal famous
private investigator!
Gee. what an exciting story I have
to tell my grandchild
Gee. what an honor, thank you
for inviting us to dinner!
The honor is ours.
Yosuke Kajimura
Hotel ODA manager
WE TR
Our hotel just opened. for a
famous person as yourself
Yosuke Kajimura
Hotel ODA manager
Our hotel just opened, for &
famous person as yourself
to stay here is excellent advertisement.
I'm most willing to be of service
if someone such as I am needed!
You certainly have a beautiful 'hetel here!
Hideaki Oda
Do you like it?
UT Be
IE] ZR A7 (58)
The amusement park I proposed
ill be completed next year.
Hideaki Oda
or Be
The amusement park I proposed
will be completed next year.
This place will be even more enjoyable!
Really. it must be costing you a lot of money.
Oh, just about 80 billion!
But once it's completed. I'm expecting
to make several hundred billion annually!
That's incredible...
Oh, forgive me, I'm the
general manager of this hotel.
Kajimura, you:re being impertinent
Futhurmore, you were very careless.
I can't believe you didn't realize
the infamous Kogoro Mouri was)
staying here until Okabe told you!!
I hope you learn from this!!
Yes..I'm terribly sorry...
By the:way. aren't you going
to Tokyo:tonight on 1 business trip
Do you think you should be
wasting your time here?
Well "Mr. Mouri I hope you enjoy your stayO™
Useless man!... Huh?!
Oh: forgive me. I sometimes forget myself
You are very strict...
I get. like: 'that when it comes to business.
Isn't that a diamond on your tie pin?
Oh this, it's nothing much.
It-s only about 5 carats.
Wow, 5 carats, you say! That's huge!
Stop that dad! You're embarrassing me
There, there young lady. Your
father's just reacting naturally.
Hah, you call that natural?
Sir. your cigar.
Hey! Where's the receipt!
Huh?! Sorry!
The nerveljican write this off
as company expense!
Do you always carry around so much?
Humphthatys justypetty change.
I hate. to use charge:cards
Kai Shun
Genkai Temple Heir
Look at yourself, enjoying
a leisurely meal! You are a disgrace!
Kai Shun
Genkai Temple Heir
Why if it isn't the heir
to Genkai Temple.
Have you completed your
training at the head temple?
My father is ignorant of worldly
affairs and you deceived him,
you won't get away with this!!
I've come back to the temple
to make sure of that!!
Calm down, watch what you're saying!
We discussed the matter carefully! .
Enough!
You told my father he should sign over the
deed to the temple to Oda Tours temporarily
in order to raise funds for the preservation
of the temple's environment.
He trusted your advice!
But he;siprepared to take you to court now!!
Is that all you have to say?
What?!
I am.entertaining my guests now
If there's something more
come to my office tomorrow.
You're sadly mistaken if you; think
you've heard the last from me!
Let me go!
Forgive all the intrusions, it's a mad house.
Having trouble with thes
people at the temple?
It's nothing. They-'re suspicious
of the development plans
and some of them are protesting, telling us
well destroy the atmosphere of thatatemple
They're going to gain from
the tourism business too,
what a bunch of fools.
Ran. didn't we hear that a curse will
fall on anyone who harms that temple? -
Conan. no! Don't talk about that now],
I know about that legend! A lot of
people have warned me aboutait!
SAG 1 T000010 Do Ura)
to draw the tourists,
it's a matter of how one looks at things!
Haha. this guy's a shark...
Yes. Mouri Detective Agency.
YinE O ON
I showed you around the temple yesterday!
It's awful! The curse, .itxs come true!!
What!? The cursell
Please come to the temple right now!
Hey. wait al minute
Mr. Mouril This way. hurry!
Hold it. I want an explanation!
The ffightening curse has come true!
What curse... he's just reciting the matins!!
What curse..'he's just reciting the matins!!
Matins-moerning prayer
No. there! Over there!
Mr. Odal!
It's the curse!!!
The crime lab is done
with their investigation...
so the body will be lowered now
How does it look?
Belet
Shizuoka Pr
The victim was found with the
rope tied to the railing,
Shizuoka Pr
The victimrwas found with the
rope. tied to the railing.
The other end was swung over the
edge of the roof and around the neck.
He has been tentatively identified as
HideakFOch. manager of a tour company.
A private investigator who knows him
I's going up thereto make a positve ID.
Private investiga or? What's the name?
It's me. Detective Yokomizo.
WAH RE adMe. Mourilall's been
along timell Why ares ou here?
It just turned out this way
To come straight to the point.
What do you think about this case?
From the evidence. it looks
Iike suicide but .
Well, the circumstances are strange
but it's definitely not murder!
What makes you say that
be able to carry him all the way up there!
And even If the killer
managed to carry him up
the width of the stairwell is very narrow,
just enough for 1 adult to pass!
It's possible to drag him up but.
His clothes would get torn
and the body would get bruised!
And I didn't notice any of those
things just now!
I see! You've deducted so much already!
But why did he pick such a place...
A.little more, more... that's it, STOP!
A_little more, more... that's it, STOP
This is a new mark...
wonder how it got here?
Huh!? Te rope's new but
it's frayed in some places...
What is it?
How're we going to get him down?
He doesn't reach the railing!
That's not possible. right? If his feel doesn't
reach the railing, (he cant commit suicide)
Hey you kid! What are you
doing here! Get down!
Uh: I was lookifg Tt the-toilet:
and} got lost...it's not herg, is it
That's strange...l wonder where it is
Who was that kid?
Beats me.,
According to the crime lab there
wasn't much dust inside the pagoda
so they couldn't find the victim's foot prints)
And we had the.town:doctor dO an autopsy.
He didn't find any external injuries.
The cause of death w s determined to be
suffocation due to pressure on.the neck.
Meaning the direct cause of death
Wks [on Inestinge ling.) oo
The estimated time of death is
somewhere between 3 and 4 AM.
Mr Oda was using a suite in- his
hotel as hist office;and home but
the front clerk said he saw Mr. Oda
Ieave the hotel at about:2:30 AM
Judging by the time, I think it's safe
to assume he came straight here.
Any will?
We haven't found one yet!
Mr. Odal
Mr. Oda! Why did you kill yourself?
You should have waited, just a little longer...
Excuse me, who are you?
I am employed as the general manager
of Hotel Oda. My name is Kajimura.
It seems you weren't here last night?
No I had a sudden business trip...
Do you know of any reason why
he would commit suicide?
The truth 1s. the purpose of.my
business trip was to raise funds...
If I failed, the checks the firm
wrote this month would bounce
wasn't the only one... Mr. Oda was also
very worried about that...
But he was carrying so much
money on him last night.
Mr. Oda had a lot of pride, he never
showed his weaknesses to anyone
and of course. he always
put on 1 bold front
But last night, when he was threatened
to be taken to court by the temple,
he seemed very concerned.
Look at this]
He doesn't have his wallet!
Wallet?
There was no wallet in his possession.
Isn't that strance? He didn't
change his clothes
but the wallet he had
with him last night is gone!
Who carries a lot of money on them
when they're committing suicide!
Don't wander around the scene,
Hm alwaysitelling you that!
Uh, but his tie pin's gone tool
Are you alright? You mustn't
interfere with the police work.
Mr Mouri, about the tie pin,
what's he talking about?
Mr Oda had it on last night.
The huge 5 carat diamond tie pin
IS indeed missing!
Which means he could have been robbed!
Even if he was robbed. he was on
his way to commit suicide,
he probably gave up his
valuables very easily)
So it doesn't refute the suicide theory at all! £
If he was strangled. he would struggle
trying to get free and scratch
his own throat with his fingernails!
But there are no traces of that!
And even if this was a murder,
how would the killer,
hang the victim from the top
of the pagoda
Aside from suicide? it is
physically:impossible!!
If there was a killer, though
it'd be that curse.
It's a curse!
Heavempunished the unbelieverl"!
I am Detective Yokomizo of thee
Shizuoka Prefecturall Police.
May I ask who you are?
Humph! Can't you tell by looking?! I am
Tankai, the head priest of this temple
Hm his son. Shunkan
I am Okabe, the sexton.
Can you all tell me where
you were between 3 and 4 AM?
What is the meaning of this!?
Wasn't this Ya suicide?
No. we haven't.reached a decision.
And since some of Mr..Oda's
valuables;are:missing...
What did you say!? Are you accusing us
men serving Buddha, of thievery?!
Oh. no. we just need your
alibis for our records...
You'd probably be happy if I said
I was meeting with that no good liar
but I was in the main hall
chanting at that time!!
Chanting!? You were chanting
at that time of night?
I had a premonition that the
curse would come true!!
I see. curse: yoursay?
And what about:you:sShunkai?
I was asleep! Although I got up at 51
Then Mr. Okabe came with the
news that Mr. Och was dead!
I was so shocked I called
Mr. Mouri right away!
I see...why did you call Mr. Mouri
first and not the police?
This man's Oda's spy! He was the
one who introduced me to Oda!
Tankai! Oda told me he wanted to help
the temple by increasing tourists!
He lied to me too!
You too?
It seems the head priest here was deceived
and got the deed to the temple taken.
So there are 3 people
who hated Mr. Oda!
So what if we did hate him?
That private investigator said there's no way
that suicide theory can be disproved
And in a suicide, there is no killer, is there?
Well, we haven't concluded it as a suicide...
« Then make a decision and
get off of this property!
I can no longer tolerate having these sacred
grounds trampled by those who are impure!
Mr. Oda's wallet and tie pin
are .indeed. missing
but from how things look, suicide
seems to be thewronly answer!
But something isn't right!
His elbow's dirty.
It's grass. did he fall
and hit his elbow?
There's dirt on both heels!
Why is there dirt there?!
Wait a minute!
If you look closely. you can see °
this rope's, Charred!
Maybe!
There it is! The tie pin!
There's no mistake! This is where
it really happened!
WW" theory is correct...
Mr. Oda didn't commit suicide!
He was murdered]
And the killer as the person
who said what he did, it's him!
ORIGINAL COMIC BO IKS BY;
Gosho Aoyama
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyzrna
PRODUCERS.
Michiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARA TER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi lHka
SCRIPTS BY
Kany Kashiwabara
Azunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Azunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
BIRECTORSYOF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Minsk: Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
T1krhisd Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
En]! or ama
Enjr ocama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in associition with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogdkukan
Il Rights Reserved
How could that be... I
If he stood on the railing
& his neck didn't reach the rope,
be couldn't have
committed suicide!
Well. let's just say for the time
being that it was murder
how could someone hang him
from a rope 50 centimeters too short?
Oh, you're right!
This side was tied to the railing
why use a "Yoroi" knot?
STORY PAGODA-PART II