Inspiration flashes. piercing
through to the truth,
Once he gets going. nothing can stop him.
Today we solve the mystery of the legend
the trick & the evidence
iS beyond your: imagination.
The one & only truth is brought into light
He looks like a child but
he's got tho brains of an adult.
1s name is... Detective, onan
We came to an old temple
with 15 story pagoda while on vacation.
But development of the tourist attraction Has
brought trouble with the tour-company.
And the next morning. the president
of the tour company,
Hideaki Oda was found
hanging from the pagoda.
Exactly like the legend
surrounding the pagodn...
It's tie curse!
TE WO fk Aged Ol
This I's where it relly happened!
If my theory is correct .
Oda didn't commit suicide!
He was murdered!
The killer is the one who said what
he did hack then!
LEGEND OF THE MYSTERIOUS 5 STORY
PAGODA (PART II)
Led OD
LEGEND OF THE MYSTERIOUS 5 STORY
PAGODA (PART II)
Hey! What are you doing here!
Isiwtgthal tie pin over there
Mr. OdTs?
What!?
Eh!?
How about it Mr.- Mourn!
Is it Mr. Oda's tie pin?
Yes. Most likely! Diamond lie pins
aren't very common!
Mr Kajimura: I'd like you to
Iook at this too™.
Kajimura
e Genera anager
Yos! There's no mistake
This belongs to Mr. Ode!
Kajimura
tel General Manager
Yes! There's oO Mistake
This belongs to Mr. ( dal!
There, you sue». H And you accused
us-of being thieves!!
Kai Shun
1 5G6
ARV) IN
Mis wallet is probably around here
somewhere too .
Ke Son
[3X3
I" \W\J4/
38 OD A
how about doing a
thorough search!
Now we know Mr. Oda wasn't robbed!
His tie pin probably fell when he
hung himself.
But Mr Mouri! The pagoda's
over 10 meters from here!
Don't you think it's a bit too far to.fall?
It could have happened like this!
Mr. (we: was deciding whether to kill himself
hore or not! And he didn't realize it fell off!
But tie pins don't fall off so easily!
Excuse me!
Y There was grass stains on
Mr. OQdn's elbow.
So what?
Wasnst?the tie pin found here?
That's itl" So the stain's from the
grass around here!!
Mr. Mouri I'm positive Mr. Oda
struggled with someone here and fell!
And another thing. when they were taking
{ns MOC Coding, 0 DO wks O xo ar ail,
and Mr. Oda's feet didn't
reach the railing.
Hey men! When you were lowering the
body. did his feet reach the railing?
No sir! It was about 50 centimeters short!!
HoO can.it bell
If he stood on the railing and the rope
didn't reach his neck,
he couldn't have committed suicide!
Mr. Mouri! How do you explain this?
Don't worry about it.
It doesn't mean a thing.
Eh?! What do you mean?
After a lot of deliberation. Mr. Oda
climbed the pagodn to kill hillself!
The rope may have been 50 centimeters
short, but there was no turning back!
The otis (JO Jue) 80 (wo
and put it over his head!!
Bul there are so many circumstances
indicating it was murder!
Alright, let's just say for the time
being tht it was murder!
The killer would have to carry the
hefty, unconscious Mr Oda
up the narrow stairway wide enough for one
and the killer would have to drag the body!
But there was no indication of this
on either the body or the pagoda!
And how would the killer hang Mr. Oda
with a rope 50 centimeters too short?
Yes that's true!
The murder theory is beginning
to sound far fetched...
That's right! Unless it was suicide, there's no
wy he could have hung from the pagoda!
It looks like, ou're showing
everyone how foolish you re!
You're nothing but a mere human. you'll
neverghe 1ble to solve the mysteries
of heaven's wrath
Give up and leave this place at once!
W's (rue, there are many
unanswered questions.
But there's not enough evidence to prove
this was a murder made to look like suicide.
But... this is definitely murder!
The problem is. how did the killer
hang him from the roof of the pagoda?
Unless I can solve this trick. this
case will be classified as suicide!!
This was the end tied to the railing...
Why did the killer use
a knot like his to tie it?
ON MUN ASR
Thegess this method! fihe fog is
finally starting:to-clear!!
Using this method} litt possible to
tie the rope to the railing!!
Hey kid! You're nol supposed "0
touch the things around here!
I'm sorry!
If my theory is correét. that
thing should be around here!
There it is!
NO doubt about it. with thissmethod
Mr Odn's death
can BO made to look like suicide!!
Humph! A fresh scratch is on it.
Curse. ou sew 7?
You thought"up one fantastic-trick.
Using the legends+1s your guide!
But now for the evidence!
I've got to find proof he:s the murderer!
This was a strange suicide
but it's settled now!!
Are you sure? Something about it
still bothers me...
Why are you so stubborn!
Alright then. go ahead and write down
on your report, death by curse.
You. you've got lo be kidding!
If I do that, I'll be 1nughed At
Excuse me. 4
Yes?
Would it be-awlriqhtPiH
returned to the hotel now?
I'm sure the employees are
shaken up by this...
Let's see... I suppose it'll be alright.
But to be on the safe side.
Give me your contact number
I'll be.at thé hotel. so... oh!
Look at all that money
Thank you very much, boy
Here, you can french me here.
Yes I'll do that
Mr. Kajimura. you sure have a lot of
monay on you
it couldngl be
Mr. Odn's could 1t?
Of course nell re, @da's wallet
is" AinQther color!!
This money is:for the payment I have to
make to one of the hotel's:suppliers today!
It was just a joke, a joke!
You scared me
Hay! Now that Mr. Oda's dead,
the plans for that amusement park
are dead too. aren't they?
Y. yes...if construction .isn'l
stopped right away,
our company will go bankrupt!...
I'm sure the deed lo the temple
will be returned to you.
What! ? Really?
Yes. Mr. Oda gave me the deed
to hold on to,
I think it's best if
I gave It back to you now .
Isn't that wonderful, Tankai?
Mr. Kajimura, you are a very
understanding man!
I was wrong about you!
That's very flattering...
As for the deed. I'm sure it was just
a misundestanding between you two.
In lieu of Mr. Oda's last act of generosity.
I will recite a prayer for him!
Now that my mind lis at ease. I can go back
to the head temple And resume training!
If I leave now. lllltget there
by evening...
I'll start cleaning the pagodn
I've found 1! The undeniable.
Solid proof!
He's the murderer after all!
Detective YokomizZo...
What do we do now?
Mr Mouri
This is definitely a suicide!
Yes. I see . since you're so sure
about it...
I was forced out of bed so Sariy this
morning. I'm so sleepy
I'm going to the-hotel
and get some. sleep...!
What the?! Oh nol
I'm so sleepy...
Now to put this button speaker
on Kogoro's forehend...
I have no choice
Alright! This is a suicide case!
We're going back to the station!!
Just one moment!
Just one moment
Detective Yokomiczo,
VA) E112) ox xol RIN 7 (exox=1k=5X
Uh... are you talking about me?
You were being.given so
many hints didn't you renlize that?
This was no suicide: il's
murder!!
I Knew itl!
But Mr Mouri. why didn't you tell
us earlier?
Because I Wantedfyou to
solve it and get the credit!
I didn't realice that... forgive me
for being so dense...!
I's ok=NOw I want you to pay close
Attention to myamystery solving show...
Now. Detective Yokomizo.
I would like to conduct an experiment
May I enlist the aid of your officers?
Of course you may!
Men! Get ready!!!
Essiri!
First. we'll put a bag weighing
the same 18 Mr.,Odn, on the grass
Tie a rope around the bag's head,
Iake the rope up to the 5th tier of the pagoda
and drape it over the edge of the roof.
Then you pass it through the railing,
until it reaches the ground and tie it
to the scrap metal left
on the old unused well!
And to make one side of the scrap metal
easier to drop, it is placed top 1 steel rod!
Here ou are!
Now. Detective Yokomizo.
Pull hard on that string!!
It, ites hanging?!
Just hke Mr. Od was. I!
What do you think? This is
the identity of your so called curse!
The rope was charred because it rubbed
on the edge of the roof, causing friction!
Although the rope was Brand new.
It was frayed because of the friction!
And since we found the tie pin
over there in the grass,
I assume that's where it happened!
But how did the killer get the
rope around Mr. Odn's neck?
Mr. Oda would have put up a fight,
but examination of the body
showed no such marks!
Yes. that's a very good question!
Let me explain things in
the order it happened...
First. the killer called Mr. Oda to
meet him here...
Then. when he saw the opportunity.
He put the noose around Mr Oda's neck .
And pulled the string at the same time,
dropping the scrap metal into the well.
Before Mr. Oda is pulled up. the
rope around his neck would come off!
So the killer grabbed his legs
causing him to fall!
Since It was dark. even a
slim man would be able to topple
a large man like Mr. Oda
who's caught off guard!!
The grass stains
on his elbow got there at that time
This is when the tie pin also fell.
Mr. Oda had no time to undo the rope.
He was pulled up
I'll positive Mr. Oda was tripped!
If he wasn't. there'd be no way he would
get dirt on the heels of his shoes!!
I get itl!
Wait a minute Mr Mouri!
Are you saying more than one killer
was involved?
It seems you've come across
that dilemma. eh. Detective Yokomizo!
After all, Mr. Oda is a heavy 100
kilograms!
If the killer tried to tie
the rope te the railing lone...
He wouldn't be able to wind the
rope around his hand. only squeeze it!
The moment the rope was cut, it would
be pulled out of his hand!
It's not possible to tie the rope
to the r1iling by himself!!
Oh but it is possible!
Even if the killer was alone!
Thales ridiculous]
Exactly how was it done?
The killer used a "yoroi
knot on the railing!
A "yoroi" knot?
It forms a loop on the rope.
I've given instructions to the officer
on the pagodn.-have him start.
Hey! Cut the rope and tie it to the railing!
Yessir!
First he needs to pull the
yoroi" loop. in.
Then, pass.a stick into the loop
making a stopper.
Then he cuts the rope on the: outside.
Pulls the cut end through the loop and tie it.
The stick is pulled and the
ruse is complete!
Detective Yokomnzo! The rope
Is tied to the railing
It's possible to do it alone
All that's left is to collect
the rope that has fallen...
and throw it into the old well!
And this. ends my explanation of how
a legend was used to cover up a murder.
The only mistake the killer made was.
The 50 centimeters difference between
Mr. Oda"s feet and the railing...
because that's what made me suspect
it wasnst suicide!
The only one capable of rigging
Il of this is...
Someone who Is familiar with the temple....!
Hold on there'll Are you insinuating
one of us is the killer?
That's right! The m TN responsible
for this charade ls Mr. Kwjlmura!
Mr. Mouri, you can't be serious!
I don't know very much about thisyitembplel
You are the general.manager
of Mei-Harm "och.
But you are alsoran
executive of Od Tours!
It's ea8y for you to get the blueprint to this
place, just say it's for the construction.
You calculated the height of the pagoda
the distance to the well and it's depth
And wasn't it you who (old
the construction workers
to put the scrap metal near the well?
So you could use it in your scheme.
Yes. I may have given the orders!
But if I did. it was due. lo, some work
related matter!
Mr Mouri. you too are. aware that I was on
a business trip Inst night. I wasn't even hersal
Then how did you know about Shunka
and Mr. Odsrs argument last night?
When you came here today. you said...
But last night. when you threatened! to take
him to court, he seemed very) upset.
Shunkai came back last night
right after you left!
But hod you know about that?
Th, that's... I had a call...Mr. Oda called
me on my cellular 1t the hotel in Tokyo...
No. you're lying!
You heard their-conversation
right hero on these grounds!
When you calledOMr. Oda to meét
you here so you could kill him!
Enough of this foolishness!
All you have are accusations!
Show me some: proof!
Proof that I was
here last nigh"!
You have the evidence on
you! Irrefutable evidence!!!
Are you sure, Mr. Mouri...?
Yes. look inside his wallet
May 17?
Humph! If you're talking about Mr.Oda's
fingerprints on the bills,
Weta TO OTE Re CRVQRT&!
the money himself!
Mr. Mouri, what am I looking for? 4
It should be stuck betw @n
the bills! It's a receipt!
A receipt »
Let's see... . I's a receipt for the
Hotel (N11...
HOTEL-OI
TE. 00-1354-0070
MG AIZE (8B) 1900010
%00:02-207¢
HOTEL . 01
REDS DE TRI HINRIIS TA DWIRIOTRC lg & TEN
HOTEL-Of
pohg=tdoxaty Welding RR YOu, ory off Ems,
HOTEL-0/
XX yox=ilor 9200, 99906. Go1 Gl x 2s,
HOTEL-0
- c=yeX¥=tnlx=171724, 1 NO. Roxy Hk EXE,
110121.01
Nepox¥ztanlexa1r DEX, 18000, Rory Gf pits,
HOTEL-O
September 12th, 19:40... for cigars.
That's right] We saw Mr. - 'da get that receipt
Iast night while we were having dinner!
You left after that and if you hadn't
seen him since then,
tell us how did the receipt Mr. Oda
got:'endup in your wallet...?
I'm pretty sure after you killed Mr. Oda,
you saw his wallet lying in the grass so
you kept the money as cash earned.
But you didn't notice the receipt
stuck Gt den the bills)!
If you ¢ eck the receipt. you'll find
Mr Oda's fingerprints on itl!
What have you got to say. Mr. Kajimura!
Are you still going to deny it?
How stupid... what a-silly thing to
get caught by...
What was your motive?
Taxes
when the companygbegan
having financial difficulties,
Mr Odd told me to file a fake
financial report...
sure, I profitted from the-scheme too.
Bul then I realized he was
Ietting mo profit only hecuse
ihe eventually intended to make me
tke the fall for everything...
So you killed him...
Yes... before he chopped me
off like some lizard's tall
after I'd worked myself to the
ins) SOX In) CEYDEI/...
OPIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Go-ho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
MY hihiko Suwa
Masai: to Yoshmka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi hoka
SGERIPTS BY.
Kan) Kaslwabara
Khzunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi1 Takatani
Haruo Oogiwiri
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kiawimura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIREGTOR.
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIREC OR OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Trkasht Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Tak1hisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR:
Kenji Kodima
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in assoctafron with
Yomiuri: Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyaria / Shogdkuk:in
II Rights Reserved
What a bummer, I thought we were
going to enjoy ourselves,
why is that everytime you're with us.
Dad. we get involvod in a case?
Humph! How would I know!
Dad-ma. be ousire cursed?
The temple's right here. why don't we
have you exorcised?
Th. that's stupid! Vina private detective!
I'm supposed lo be involved with cases!
That's what feeds us!
Trouble is My business!
Humph!
Cases are supposed to follow a
famous dele: tive around
Dad!
He's right. he's never lacking trouble
Wh. what is this!?
If the killer came in
through the waterway, then
the 1 should be sopping wet!
I see . So that's why) that person did that...
Next Conan. MURDER AT RYUSUITEI.