Inspiration flashes,
piercing through to the truth.
Once he gets going,
nothing can stop him.
Today's setting is an unusual restaurant,
the crime arrives by water.
The one and only truth is brought
into light.
He looks like a child but he's got
the Brains of an adult. I
His name is...
Detective Conan
Murder at Ryusuitel
RYusuitel
Oh boy, We are 30 minutes early
for our reservation!
Sorry,sbut this is a very popular place
If we are late, they will
cancel our reservation.
I'm tired of waiting
and I'm getting hungry.
Alright #4. sake is ready!
Got it!
== RB
I see a restaurant where
the food is served by boat.
No wonder it's popular
Do you like it?
There are bigger boats too
What happens to the boat
once it gets to the room?
The customer takes
the dishes off the boat
AnNnzar « ouko
Host
then pushes a button in the room
AnNnzar « ouko
Host
and it goes back automatically.
AnNzai « ouko
Host
Lr 5 &
Wow, that's neat!
Excuse me
We have reservations.
Mr. Kaneda, you reserved
the Hachi-no-ma, didn't you?
Eh... 1?
Hey, Kaneda...
Not me...there must be a mistake!
Hey, Kaneda, Aral!
You're late,
I was getting tired of waiting.
Sorry... Kaneda was late...
Go on, apologize.
Humph... this wasnst; my-idea! t*
Come on! This is to celebrate your
promotion to assistant professor,
the Professor's treat!
Just because we were hired the
same time doesn't mean we're friends!
Starting today, address me as
Assistant Professor Kaneda...
understand?!
And you're my assistant,
Aral...!
Er...
Out of my way...
You what's the most expensive
dish you have?
SS... blowfish milt
Then bring us 3 of those...
you don't mind,
do you Professor?
Uh. no... it's fine with me!
It's fine wi
Iwama Nobuo
professor of science
Jomon. University
Iwama Nobuo
professor of science
Jomon. University
Tonight's your night...
Iwama Nobuo
professor of science
Jomon. University
We'll have 3 orders of blowfish milt
Yes, right away
Let's go inside.
Did¢ ou see that?
That Kaneda's a real stinker!
I wonder why Professor Iwama
always orders so much food?
Maybe he likes a full table!
But he usually leaves
without eating much.
I'm dying of hunger!
Those men are next door...
Wow... here it comes...
What-a huge boat!!
Look at all the food! Gee.
I won't be able to...
hey 1 Om
Rats, it wasn't ours...
Professor. all this food
It's a celebration.
By the way, I wonder
what's keeping that Kaneda
He probably went to the toilet.
He'll be back soon...
Ah~! Delicious!
'Conan. how's the sashimf?
Hey. where'd it go?
I dropped my contact lens!
Oh no, now I've done it!!
Here. I found it! What a relief!
For a professor.
He's quite a scatterbrain...
7:50 pm
For a professor.
He's quite a scatterbrain...
19855057
Boy that was the best.
»20850057
8:00 pm
If there were geishas here.
It'd be heaven!
20850057
8:00 pm
Da~d!
There's a child present!
I was kidding. it's a joke...
ah?!
Hey Ran. we're out of sake!
Order me another!
1 is enough!
We're going to have
a delicious dinner now!
Rats...!
It's not just her personality.
Now she's even beginning to
sound like her mother Eri.
Eeeek!!
What!
somebody come quick!!
What's going on!?
What happened?
Th, the customer is...
Eh!?
What the!?
Th. that' s...
Ka. Kaneda!!
He's dead.
This is a murder...!
Notify the police immediately!!
Professor lwama...
what ha: ened?
K. Kaneda is dead in this room.
Wh-at!?
A murder has just taken place...
until the police arrive.
The police will probably want to
question everyone
your cooperation will be appreciated!
Since he fell at this angle,
I guess Mr Kaneda, who was sitting
at the far end of the table,
greeted the killer and was stabbed
in the chest while facing him
Then he fell onto the table.
If the killer came here
by the waterway,
this room should be sopping wet
but it's not!
Huh!?
What is this black thing on his thumb?
This smell is
How many times do I have to tell you
not to wander around the crime scene!!
The victim .issKeizo laneda,...
assistant professor of science
at Jomon University
He was stabbed in the heart with
a dagger and died instantly
Time of death is estimated«to be
at.about 19:50.
Also, we have confirmed the alibis of
+ all:the restaurant employees.
This is Professor lwama and
Mr. Aral is an instructor,
both men work with the
victim at the university.
We were celebrating Kaneda's promotion
to assistant professor tonight...
I thought he was In the toilet.
Who would've thought something like
this was possible...
And a certain party just happened to
be on the scene...
Yes! The famous private detective
Kogoro Mouri here!
Inspector Megure!
And + oko Anzai you were the first
to discover the body!
Yes... the customer went into the room
but never placed an order
sol went in to check on him,
that's how I found him...
But why was he in the Hachi-no-ma?
Didnt he say he didn't make that
reservation?
That's why I called out to him
when he started to headsfor that«room.
But he said he was meeting someone
there...
Hmm... so he was meeting someone
secretly.
That person must have killed"him...!
Did you see anyone besides the victim
enter the room?
No no one...
You're positive?
Yes. I was standing at the register and
Iooking out at the garden...
The front door is the only way to get
explains in
and everyone has to cross the bridge
to get to their rooms.
Then how did the killer get into
the room?
Inspector, from the waterway...!
It was designed to go past each room,
SO you can get to the room
by using it!!
I see... so you're saying
this is an inside job
Alright, Takagi.
Ask all the customers if they saw someone
using the waterway!!!
Yes sir!
Hong
We were looking?at the waterway a lot
but we didn't see anyone on it.
ADM 5D. QM
oi Io Hom
No, no one like that.
I didn't see anyone either.
No idea
No one went by
If someone was walking in the water,
we'd notice.
Only boats went by!
No one saw anything...!?
No! All the other rooms were
parties of Yor-more
butsno one saw anything other than
boats go past!
Maybe the killer went underwater?
No! The water's only about 50
centimeters deep,
it's not possible
to swill underwater.
Besides, if the killer went underwater
the room would be sopping wet!
Did you say something!
No, I was talking to myself...
Either way, since coming in
from the outside is impossible,
it must be an inside job!
We've got to confirm
everyone's alibi...
Mr. Iwama, where were you at about
7:507
I never left our room, the San-no-ma
Isn't that about the time you were
shouting?
Yes, that's right....!
While I was looking for my contact lens,
I knocked some dishes over...
After that. I saw the screen close
In your room
so your alibi's OK.
Mr. Arai, you came back to
the restaurant after the murder
After kaneda left,
the professor asked me to buy
him a pack of cigarettes
so I went to the convenience store
I told him where to go...
we didn't have the brand
he wanted at our register...
I took me about 10 minutes
to walk there...
I have a receipt.
Hmm...
the time on the receipt is 19:52
Which means these 2 men have
perfect alibis!!
The killer must be
one of the other customers!
No...
with the other parties of 4 or more,
the killer would have to foolsthe others
as well as Mr. Anzai togget to that room,
so it's impossible
These 2 are the only ones who
were able to be alone
and commit the crime...
Takagi!
Let's split up and verify
the other customers' alibis
Yes sir!
Uh-ma'am, I want to see the\boats.
Not now Conan, it's a bad time.
It's alright.
I have nothing to do now.
Thank you so much.
See, this is it.
Is the door always locked?
Yes, that's right.
We don't want just anyone
going in and out of here.
I'm the only employee with a key!
Here we are, go on...
5 boats altogethe
and one of them is huge...
huh?!
This is the same stuff that was on
Mr. Kaneda's finger...
But he wasn't there when the
food got to their room...
Was the whiskey and ice on this boat
just now?
Yes, the reservation specifically stated
this boat was to be used,
the food was to be served at
7:30 and the drinks at 8:00.
Hmm.
A small motor and sensor...
there's a lot of space Inside...
so all that's left is the alibi...
Thank you very much.
Or & - 28
Hmm?
There's one wrapper missing...
This is...
IDUU.
So that's why that person did that...
I found it...
a tiny hole and a wet spot It
That person's alibi
has just been cracked!!
On top of that,
I've got undeniable evidence!!
Sir. may I talk to you!
Go away, you're bothering me!
I found something really weird.
Something weird?
What? I can't hear you!
Ack!
All the customers in Nana-no=ma
have alibis
how much longe
do we have to stay?
Yes, you're right.
I suppose you two can go.
Not yet! It's too early!!
Eh!?
The truth is, I know how
the killer got to the room!
You do!?
Why don't you explain?
We were right
the killer did use the waterway
Come on now...
Mr Mourn,
Iisten... all the witnesses agree
there were only boats on the waterway.
That's right .
The killer used a boat!
A boat...?
A small person could hide
in the big boat,
there's enough room!
Nay,
First, p
the killer requests that the larger boat
be used to serve their complete meal.
he takes the food off and
removes the clapboard.
Then he gets in!
The boat returns to it's berth by
sensor
before it gets there,
he turns the sensor off using his foot!
The boat's motor goes off
and it reaches the Hachi-no-ma room
Kaneda must have been
really surprised at first!
But he wasn't worried
after all,
he would never suspect
a friend would come to kill him...
The killer used this element of surprise
and killed him!!
Then, so no one would think he came In
through the waterway,
the killer made Mr Kaneda
face the doorway!!
Oh, I see...
but then, how did*the killer
get back into his own room?
It's simple...
he got back into theboat
and turned the sensor back on
thesbdat will automatically
go back to the dock...
all he needs to do now is wait...
As directed. the boat would carry
their drinksto the room at 8!
But unfortunately for the killer,
I noticed something!!
Wh, what was that?
The waterline....!
There was only that whiskey set
on the boat,
yet the waterline was extremely high.
What it proves is that
the killer had been in the boat!
W. wait a minute...
the only one who could have remained
in thesroom alone
and who was a friend is
Yes...
the murderer is Professor lwama!
It could only have been you!
P, Professor...1?
You probably told him
you wanted to speak to him
in private in another room
and had himjreserve the
Hachi-no-ma!
And when the food arrived, you sent
Mr. Arai out to buy your cigarettes!
Deliberately asking for a brand they
don't sell at the register
>> 1.
So he'd have to go to
a convenience store...
Hold it right there, Mr. Mourn!
You yourself testified that I was In
my room at the time of the crime!
With that alibi, how could I have
killed Kaneda
You have a tape recorder don't you?
Of course I do.
It's a small one I carry around
in my bag for meetings...
Even if I could use it to
tape voices and sounds,
how would I close the sliding door?
How about by using a rubber band,
a pin, a chopstick wrapper and ice?
First you use the pin to hold the
rubber band in place
to the sliding door and it's frame...
then you stuff the chopstick wrapper into
the sliding door on the other side
and tack one end down
Then you pull the door
with the rubber band
attached to the chopstick wrapper
and pin it through the chopstick wrapper
the finishing touch you took ice
from the food
and put it on the
wrapper circle
the ice will melt
making the paper wrapper soft
and when it breaks
the rubber band will snap back
closing the door!
Yes, I see!
When you returned to the room,
Mr. lwama,
you got rid of the rubber
band and tacks and erased the tape...
And if you threw the wrapper
into the waterway,
there'd be no evidence left!
That's right...
there's no evidence...
If you're accusing me of
killing Kaneda
show me the proof
show me!!
Mr. Aral...
when you took the food off the boat
did you spill the sauce
for the blowfish milt?
Y, yes, I did...
on the clapboard...
Mr Iwama,
when Miss Anzai screamed
and you came out of the room,
you had your jacket on, didn't you!
No one would bother to put their
jacket on in an emergency...
But you did because the sauce
got on your shirt
when you got into the boat,
isn't that right?
Mr. lwama...
will you remove your jacket?
I do have a sauce stain on it
but I got it when I spilled the sauce
while I was looking for my contact lens!
I wonder...
Mr. Kaneda left the room
before the food arrived but
he had some sauce on his thumb...
Eh. 17?
I wonder when he got it... 7?
Uh... uh... it can't be...
That's right...
When you stabbed him,
he grabbed you there!!
Right on that stain on your shirt!
Consequently, Mr. Kaneda's fingerprint
IS on your shirt!
Kaneda heard that in the past,
I had put my name on a student's thesis
paper and passed it off as my own.
He threatened to make it public
if I didn't recommend him
for the assistant professor's position
to the selection committee...
On top of that,
he wanted me to
give him 5 million yen
I couldn't put up with it any more...
The blowfish milt was
an unexpected order...
If he hadn't ordered it,
I would have gotten away...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Mi*Rihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hi onobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment Ltd
in association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
Gosho Aoyama / Shogdkukan
Il Rights Reserved
Remenber "Ryusuitel ?
Since the murder,
they've gotten popular again.
Hey dad take us somewhere again.
Sure...
as long as there are geishas there...
How about if I serve you then?
No, no thank you...
Ooh scary
I don't understand this at all but
This is so exciting!
The more I don't understand,
the more excited I get!
The curiosity inside me that
I Ynever satisfied!
(ma)
The Secret of The Moon, The Star, & The Sun