Inspiration flashes piercing
through to the truth
Once he gets going, nothing can stop him
Today's episode is a special,
It's the start of Conan & Shinichi's era
the very first mystery
The one and only truth is
brought into the light
He looks like an child but he's got
the brains of an adult
His name is... . Detective Conan
FLYING COFFIN-SHINICHI'S FIRST CASE
PART 1
3B ED ee ce LY << DD CD
=, Tm
Narita Airport
Look, that's the one!
That's the plane we're riding!
Wow. it's so big
Boeing 747! It's a jumbo jet
total length, 70.7 meters!
Rats! Why's a famous private
detective like Kogoro Mouri have to
babysit a bunch of kids on
his trip to Okinawa...
You have your nerve...
Last night you were saying, "Wait for
me my little beach angel
I didn't know these brats
were coming:along...
Good grief! Doctor Agasa entered a
contest on the internet
& won this trip to Okinawa. that's why
we're able to go!
Just be grateful you can go along!
Yeah yeah
I don't see that lucky prof es
anywhere. do you?
Now that you mention it...
The professor's not coming
I just called him & he said he came
down with a cold & won't be able to go
What?!
But I don't think it's too bad!
He asked me to buy a lot of gifts...
What about An?
She said she'll pass because she's
taking care of the professor
Oh. I see...
then let's buy her a lot of souveniers!
Wow, the houses are
getting smaller and smaller!
Conan. look look!
Are you sleeping?
Shh... he was up all night reading
Huh?! What're you smilling about?
I'm just thinking about
the plane ride last year...
Shinichi fell asleep right after
we took off too...
Oh, I remember that's when I won a
trip at the neighborhood drawing &
while I was gone. you & that kid
detective ran off to Los Angeles...
How many times do I have to tell you!
We just went to visit his parents!
Kids just in high school don't go off on
overseas trips, at least not:normal kids...
Well that's because his parents sent
me a ticket too!
He didn't try anything funny. did he?
What do you mean, anything funny?
Well, uh... you know... I mean...
How do I say this...
Oh! You kids! Sit down!
Of all the...
eoe0s E008 Pl 0000
Pp occosseste @00 °
excuse me
Huh... 7? Who, me?
Do you mind not smoking?
This is a no smoking section
it's bothering the other passengers
Il... if you want to s
please do it in the smoking section
in the rear of the plane
Kazuhiro Otaka
Photographer
Sorry about that. I'll try to be
careful next time
Kazuhiro Otaka
Photographer
ow OD
Sorry about that. I'll try to be
careful next time
For goodness sake Kazuhiro,
stop that!
Why you...! that's no way to talk to your
soon to be filthy rich boyfried!
Watch yourself!
Kazuhiro...
Come on. be happy...
the newspaper company over there said
they'd pay a lot of
money for these negatives!
IF they're real, right?
They're supposed to be scandal shots
of a powerful American senator when
Ill +88 (29)
JIT XS
They're supposed to be scandal shots
of a powerful American senator when
Chizuru Tachikawa
Photographer
They're supposed to be scandal shots
of a powerful American senator when
he was in Japan but it'd be embarrassing
if they were of somebody else!
You've got to be kidding!
I already faxed 2 copies of the pictures
over there & got it confirmed!
It doesn't matter, just remember,
e're on vacation...
Your negatives come second!
Alright already! I'll show you some
real great surfing moves!
Hey Washinuma!
NASIWTY
What's with him, he's sleeping already...
Noboru Saginuma
Cameraman
NASTY
Noboru Saginuma
Cameraman
Oh well, I guess I'll get some rest too!
Good night!
2 J-Je-7 JAr
Edward Crow
Freelance journalist
2 J=Jv-=F JAR
2J)-IJv-F JAM
Yes. May I help you?
Sorry... I seem to have gotten airsic
do you have motion sickness pills?
I'll be right b
Sir, May I help you?
I don't like flying, being box
in makes me restless...
I have an idea!
Could you do me a favor?
Yes, what is it?
Hey, are you alright?
I think I'm airsick... the stewardess
IS getting some medicine
Did you drink the motion sickness
pills I gave you?
That's strange... I gave some to
Noboru too & it seems to be working...
How about if we switch seats?
Maybe sitting by the window will make
you feel better
Let's see...
Here, the medicine's for her!
Here you are
Thank you.
Here, your pills.
I just noticed, where'd Kazuhiro go?
He got up awhile ago & went somewhere
I wonder if he didn't feel good &
ent to the toilet...
Hey. you in there! Hey!
Excuse me... is something the matter?
I've been knocking a long time but
whoever's inside doesn't answer!
Excuse me? Hello?
Excuse me...
Are you feeling ill
What was that scream?
It came from the rear...
Ladies & gentlemen. may I have
your attention please...
a passenger has become seriously ill,
If there is a doctor or nurse on board.
Please contact the nearest
cabin attendant...
Excuse me...
Yes?
Megure of the Metropolitan Police
Department... is someone really ill?
Uh. the truth is...
I went for a look!
Somebody's dead!
Really?!
Yeah. inside the toilet in back!
Hey, come on-wake up!
Something terrible has happened...
I don't believe it...
Where is hel?
Why. Ran, is that you?! Taking a
trip on the long weekend?
Er, uh... well... Never mind me.
I just heard someone was dead!
Calm down. we're about to look
into that now...
No one has touched the; body have.ithey?
Well actually... a strange young boy
has been hanging around...
A strange young boy?
Cause. of death is probably suffocation due
to damage to the cervical pith!
The murder weapon is probably something
with a sharp point like an ice pick!
Before the victim was stabbed.
There's a possibility he was forced to inhale
something knocking him unconscious...!
Who would do such a thing...?
We don't know that yet!
But don't worry...
the killer is still flying over the
Pacific Ocean
inside this huge metal can...
the killer won't get away!
Hey! Who the heck are you?!
That's right...
This is the beginning...
Shinichi Kudo! I'm a detective!
This was Shinichi's first case...
Ku, Kudo...
You couldn't be Yusakuls...
It's been a long time, Inspector Megure...
Ooohh, you're his son Shinichi!
You're the splitting image of your
father when he was a boy!!
The last time I saw;you you were in
the 6th grade!
Ou certainly have grown...
But that's beside the point!
I'm sure you just became a high school
st»udentjdidn't you!!
You shouldn't be
disturbing the crime scene!!
Excuse me! Could you borrow someone's
camera & bring it here?
I'd like to photograph the crime scene!
Um, er... if it's photos. that boy
already took some...
He what?!
About 60 of them... I borrowed a camera
from one of the passengers...
Also...
Yes?
We did as he asked & kept a close eye
on what he did, but...
We didn't notice him hide or wipe any thing
or do anything the least bit suspicious...
But... if an amateur handles the body,
the stiffened muscles could be damaged
throwing the estimated time of death off...
Based on the condition of the death spots &
the fact that the jaw had started stiffening...
He was dead about 1 or 2 hours!
3 things struck me as odd!
#1 a few drops of blood had flown onto
the wall the victim was leaning on
but the clothing pressed against it
wasn't stained...
#2- the scratch like marks to the lower
right of the fatal wound...
#3- and the inside of his left pants
pocket was soaked!
But the victim's hands were dry .
Even if he stuck his wet hands into the
pockets, they wouldn't get as wet as that...
Which means, someone for some reason
wet it deliberately!
Listen you! You just keep out of this!
Let the police handle the rest!!
Excuse me, please go & wake that
fellow who's sleeping next to my seat!
He's withthe police too
Yessir!
Come here!
What do you mean, [I'm a detective],
you're just a high school student!
I didn't have a choice did I?
They wouldn't have let me examine the
body if I didn't say that!
The thing is! You shouldn't go off
Iike that without telling me!
I was worried that you were the victim!
I have no interest in waking a girl who
Iooks like a fool when she's asleep!!
What do you mean, looks like a fool!
Like this...
Inspector!
You're late Takagi!
A murder?
Yes...
Cause of death is suffocation
due to damage to the cervical pith...
The murder weapon is something that
Iooks like an ice pick with a pointed tip...
Judging from rigor mortis & the
death spots of the body,
he's probably been dead ahout 1-2 hours...
Un... %! An empty bottle & handkerchief!
It seems the killer carried this
handkerchief soaked in something
Iike chloroform in this bottle
& used it to knock the victim out just
before killing him!
Excuse me, I'd like to save the evidence,
may I have a plastic bag or something...
Uh... is something wrong?
It's just amazing, you're doin
the same things that young boy did...
What boy
You know, he was standing in the doorway.
The one in the black sweater...
Who is he?
He's the son of a friend of mind... gm
whenever I got to a deadend on a case,
I'd go to my friend.
Who's a mystery writer, for advice...
when he was little, he'd come to the crime
scene with his father & wander around but
who'dve thought.he/dracquire enough
to expertly analyze a crime scene...
Gee, he's going to be a great help!!
You fool! He's a civilian!
He's just a kid in high school
who thinks he's a great detective
because he's read a lot of
mysteries & medical books!
At any rate. find us some witnesses!
There are 4 suspects
There were 4 others. excluding the victim,
who were in the toilet at that time!
My seat is in the rear of the cabin!
I'd been watching but no one came to
the smoking section in the back.
That you can be sure of
You were watching it?
Were you up-+all*night?
Well, uh... I couldn't sleep...
Why, for heaven's sake?!
I thought you fell asleep as soon as
we got on the plane!
Uh. er! Is that so?
Oh boy, you're like a baby, going
to bed early &
getting up in the middle of the night...
Aw nuts... how can I sleep with you
sleeping so soundly next to me like that...
I'm not all that mature yet...
Alright then. how about telling us
who those 4 are!
Un, sure...
Let's see... the 4 are...
This girl &...the girl next to her...
and across the aisle.
The man in this seat and...
this man in the front seat, these 4!!
Their seats are close by
Yes...
Wait just a minute!
What's going on?
Ka. Kazuhiro! Kazuhiro!
Why... why...
Tsugumi
why was Kazuhiro killed?!
That's what we're trying to find out...
Maybe that negative is responsible?
Negatives?
He was bragging about it...
he said he was going to sell it to a
newspaper company & make a lot of money...
Don't tell me they're gone?!
he didn't have them on him §
That can't be...
So that means the killer is someone who
knew about the negatives. isn't that right!
Everyone in this business knew about it!
He offered to sell them to a lot
of newspaper companies!
Hey officers... Ohtaka was stabbed once
in the back of the head. wasnHhej?
That's right...
Then the killer's a pro! Those 2 are
just camerawomen...
you're barking up
the wrong tree, suspecting them
No... with a little medical knowledge.
Anesthetic & a murder weapon
anyone could have done it!
Even a woman!
Now then. why don't the 4 of you tell us
what you saw when you went to the toilet...
I went to the toilet because I
wasn't feeling well...
but when I got back to my seat
Kazuhiro was still there in his seat!
I called the stewardess later
to bring me some medicine
That's why I remember it well
Is that true?
Yes... he was asleep when I saw him
Yes, I saw her from across the aisle!
It looked like she was asking for
ome medicine...!
I went to the toilet right after that,
I was in there for about 5 minutes, I guess
You said across the aisle...
but isn't your seat facing the same
disl Mas the victim's?
I get restless thaving to sit still for long
periods of time, so I was walking around
Then when did the victim leave his seat?
When I brought the water & pills.
He was already gone...
I don't think it took me more than a
minute to bring them to her...
I went to the toilet after Tsugumi
got her medicine
& I guess it was 20 minutes later that
I noticed Kazuhiro still hadn't came
back so I went to check...
but he was still alive then.
Well, I knocked on this door & asked if he
was alright & he knocked back
Are . ou, surer!
But how did you know it was him?
It had to be!
I opened the other 3
doors & they were unoccupied!!
So he's the only one left...
When did you go to the toilets?
he said, "Unfortunately, don't remember"
I guess it's only natural...
What's wrong?
That man's cologne is so strong...
Oh come on, how much longer are you
going to keep asking
those meaningless questions?
Whoever has the weapon is
the killer. righ «
Then ..wouldn't it be quicker to do a
search of their things & their bodies?
This has nothing to do with me though
since I was asleep & didn't go to the toilet!
You're lying! I saw you leave your seat!!
What?!
Your seat is directly behind the
victim's isn't it!!
What are you talking about?
Remember. I told you when I went to
the toilet,
the victim was still asleep in his seat...
Well, I'm positive this man's
eat was empty...!
Hey old man. don't lie! You 4 were
the ones who went to the toilet
HE just said so!!
Right. kid?!
Yes... well...
What's the matter. Don't be vague...
Now that I think about it. I think
I was distracted for a second...
At any rate, you 5 are considered
suspects so we will search your luggage
& you will undergo a body
check in the toilet!
What?! You didn't find the weapon on
them or their luggage?!
No! None of them had anything
Iike an icepick!
To be on the safe side, we're searching
places in the plane that
it could be hidden In...
Hey! You're positive these people were
the only ones
who went to the toilet. aren't you...
Shinichi, answer him
Shinichi!
This is getting interesting!
If they can't find the weapon in the
plane. that means
the killer still has it somewhere!
I'll bet that's the killer's trump card...
Il find it... I'll get that trump card...!!
Before this huge metal bird
rests its wings!!
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kan]! Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIR CT@R
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS YOF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hi onobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaeca
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting orporation