Inspiration flashes piercing
through to the truth.
Once he gets going,
nothing can stop him.
Today's episode is a special.
It's the start of Conan and Shinichi's era
the very first mystery
The one and only truth
s brought into the light.
He looks like an child but
he's got the brain of an adult.
His name is...
Detective Conan
FLYING COFFIN - SHINNICHI FIRST CASE
PART 2
Huh?
What?!
You want us { Wook again?!
Do another body check
and go through their luggage.
One more time...
Is that what you're saying?
Shinnichi!
Yes...
If you couldn't find the weapon
in the cabin,
the killer could still have it
In their possession.
Inspector Megure!
Miss Tachikawa's ba
passport, wallet,
handkerchief and cosmetics!...
Tissue and her boarding pass...
Sunglasses, camera...
notepad and a ballpoint pen.
That's it. Nothing resembling
a weapon is in here...
How about that pen...
Huh?
Did you check inside the pen?
Oh, uh of course...
Alright then...next
Miss Amano!
Uh, Yes!
Passport, wallet,
handkerchief, knit hat
boading pass,
camera, cosmetics and a sewing set,
a few motion sickness pills...
The only sharp instrument would be
the tiny sewing scissors and
needles in this...
but you couldn't kill anyone like that
with these, it's impossible.
Next!
Mr. Ukai...
Yiessir
Passport and boarding pass...
wallet, hankerchief,
razor and towel,
shavin cream
Next is...
Edward.
Huh?
Let us check your belongings just in case.
Well if you must, you must...
He'll cooperate!
Go ahead
Huh?
That's strange...
the cologne on his neck was
very strong but
doesn't he have any on his hands?
Passport, wallet,
handkerchief, boarding pass,
towel, newspaper,
2 paperback books,
eyeglass case,
sewing set,
American National Bank.checkbook...
'Excuse me Mr. Edward,
could you explain this checkbook?
He said he was going to buy some art
objects sold at an auction here in Japan...
but since he didn't find anything
interesting, he stopped payment.
Hmm... I see...
alright... the last...
Here
I'm the last one...
Passport, wallet,
handkerchief,
camera and negatives.
Wristwatch, cigarettes,
O lighter.
0. & O o : 0
medicingyfor air sickness...
You seem to have a lot of medicine...
I get air sick very easily...
both Chizuru and TsuGumi
gave me some
Right?
May I see these negatives for
a little while?
Why you!!
The man in this picture... Isn't it
Mr. Dickson, the American senator?
Why you're right... He's with a woman
in this picture
Hey! That's enough
Wait a minute, those are the same
as Kazuhiro's!.
He same, you mean...
And if they're in your possession.
That means...
No. no! Wait...
These are definitely mine!
Ohtaka & I were staked out at the hotel
together, we both took those photos...
They're...
not as good as Ohtaka's but I was
going to a newspaper in Los Angeles
and... sell my pictures too
Besides, you should find the weapon
efore accusing me...
Now now... we'll listen to all your
complaints after the body check
Now... ladies &gentlemen
just like before» I want you to come
to the toilet one by one...
The women will be examined by the flight
attendants & we will examine the men .
So this where the victim sat.
According to the seat numbers on
the boarding pass}
Mr. Saginuma was behind him &
Mr Crow in the front...
Miss Amano to the right &miss
Tachikawa on the inside.
And across the aisle to
the left is Mr. Ukai...
Why this is!
A piece of a negative...
what is something like this
doing beside Mr. Saginuma's seat...
Shinic
They're done with the body checks...
It seems no one had the weapon...
Which means... that's the only answer...
There. you see!!
We didn't have the weapon!
I had to undress twice!
I don't want to go through this again!
What shall we do, Inspector?
Hmm. we've searched everywhere...
No, not quite everywhere
What?!
There's still one place we haven't
searched...
Inside the victim's bags!!
Which one is his?
Uh... it's that black bag in the back...
Is something wrong?
No .l just remembered something
strange he said...
Something... strange?!
It was about a week ago, he said he
forgot his bag at the studio
& someone cut it to shreds...
That's why...he bought a new one...
for this trip...
Maybe someone was after those
negatives
that's why it happened...
Passport, camera, film, sunglasses,
3 packs of cigarettes...
wallet, towel ;:2 magazinesi:-boarding
pass &a wristwatch...
Nothing that appears to be the
weapons fy,
Shinichu...
Shinichau...
Really?
What's this? Kazuhiro Ohtaka...
Mr. Ohtaka... is he the fellow who won
the Nichiuri Newspaper's
Photo contest 3 years ago...
Why yes. . that's him
I knew it...
What is it, Takagi?!
Look... it's that picture of a mother trapped
in the fire, she's handing her
k... it's that picture of a mother trap
daughter to the fireman on the ladder
Oh...
Forget about that!
That's not the issue here!
Are we or aren't we cleared?
Which is it!!
But you 4 were the only ones who
went to the toilet: at the time the
crime was committed...
That boy gave the statement.
Humph! I'll bet that kid who
thinks he's a detective...
fell asleep &missed a.couple
of people...
It seems you've read a lot of books &
id a lot of studying but...
this is a real murder! It's not like
your book...
Children should behave. go back to
your seat & take a nap
Shinichi! Why don't you say something!
What is it with this case...
the weapon can't be found... and all
their alibis just don't add up...
How about telling us the truth
What?
It's you, isn't it? You killed him...
Hey come on now...
Tithe only one among all of us obviously
telling a lie, is you...
I saw you!!
When this girl was asking the flight
attendant for medicine,
the victim was asleep & your seat in
the back of him, was empty!
You're a liar!!
I am not lying! The truth is...
truth is we... both...
There... that's the flight attendant!
She &ll, that flight attendant is my witness...
And that's his statement...
Is it true?
Es... this passenger was wandering
around the cabin so I called out to him...
he asked me to caution a<passenger.in
the non smoking section:who was smoking...
And? Was this man in this seat when
you got there?
No... I don't believe so...
Hey! You, are you blind or something?
You were the one who brought the
You saw me sleeping in my seat.
Didn't you!
No, I don't remember clearl
Excuse me... when you brought the
medicine, could it be possible that...
could that have happened?
That's right! But I though
was my imagination...
Therese n ydoubt about it!
That's the killer!
That'll explain, everyone, except
the killer's story
& why a piece of negative was on the seat...
the unexplainable blood on the toilet wall,
&why the victim's pocket was wet.!!
But why?
Why didn't the killer have the weapon?
Because it couldn't be gotten
rid of, is that possible?
Is it something the owner would miss
if it was gone?
Wait a minute... I just realized
that person did...
Hey! Shinichi Inspector Megure's
calling you
He wants you to go around the cabin &
see if anyone else went to the toilet!
Mind that Ran, you're...
school, aren't you?
What? Of course I am...
Then let me...ask you...
What?
Tell me quick!
I'm embarrassed to ask this...
Yes... that's right! Most of
them are like that now...
I see, so that's what it was...
do you mean by that...
do you look so satisfied?
I finally figured it out! I know what
the killer's trump card is.
What was used to snuff the life out of the
VIC II'mn.
At any rate! The only one who acted
suspiciously, is you
Mr. Saginuma, onl you!
No. not...
No, no...
You're wrong, Inspector Megure
He's not the Killer!
He was never near the crime scene so
his chances of being the killer is zero!
But, but...
See, what a relief!
I had nothing to do with all of this!
No... that's not exactly true...
Mr. Saginuma...
you were taken advantage of without
your knowing...
By a person in that group... the one
person who gave a false testimony...
the killer...
Which means, Inspector... it was Miss
Tachikawa who said she went to the toilet
to check on the victim & knocked
on the door & got a knock in reply!
Wait just a minute!
No, she wasn't lying
There realll was someone inside the
toilet at that time...inside with the victim...
Mr. Crow...Yes, you!!
Are you sure about that?
He put his hand into Mr. Ohtaka's
pocket looking for the negatives &
realized the cologne on his wrist
rubbed onto the pants!
So he hurriedly washed his hands to
wash the cologne off then he wet his
handkerchief to wipe the telltale
scent from the pants...
The proof is, there's no cologne on
his Wrist
That's not what I'd consider proof...
besides, to get his statement, we'll
have to ask him in English...
No... he speaks Japanese!
Isn't that right Mr. Crow?
The boy's right...
He... spoke!
Japanese...
Of course he did!
He intended to buy those negatives
with the check from the National Bank
Buy?!
That's right
Senator Dickson himself asked me to...
So was it you?!
Did you kill Ohtaka?
No, he's not the killer...
Because when he went into the toilet,
Mr. Ohtaka was already dead
What was that?!
Isn't that right... Mr. Crow?
Es... when I heard he had gone to th
toilet.
I thought it was my chance to
ake a deal with him...
but there was no answer when I knocked
so I opened the door &went in
he was dead. Of course, I didn't
get the negatives
Then YOU answered my knock?
Yes...
Hey, don't be fooled by this! He's
just confirming that kid's guesswork!
Guesswornk?
Absolutely not...
There were bloodstains on the toilet wall...
Yet there was no blood on the victim's back
although he was leaning on the stains...
this indicates someone else moved the
body after some time had passed...
Someone who found the body but
didn't notify anyone...
the only reason I can come up with for
moving the body is,
to look for those negatives.
But unable to find them. the
person searched his pants pocket...
Ly one who would do that... w
be someone sitting in front of the victim.
Someone who couldn't see what the victim
was doing, that could only be Mr. Crow!
Yes, I get it!!
Alright then... who did it?
Who's the killer?!
We have now eliminated Mr. Crow
&Miss Tachikawa
who was outside knocking on the door
Which leaves us Mr Ukai & Miss Amano
This is the crucial point...
Mr. Ukai testified that when Miss Amano
asked for the medicine,
Mr. Saginuma's seat behind the victim,
was unoccupied!
I'm sure about that!
And I'm telling you, I was there all
along, sleeping!
He's right... Mr. Saginuma was asleep
in his seat...
The killer put a knit cap on his head
& covered his eyes with an eyemask!
Hat was that...!
That style. do you mean...
That's right. . that is Mr. Ohtaka's
sleeping style...
After killing¥him. instead of return
to their own seat,
the killer, sat next to Mr. Saginuma &made
him up to look like Mr. Ohtaka
then called the flight attendant!
To give the illusion Mr.
Ohtaka was still alive at that time...
Hold it, you mean...
I don't believe it
That's right...
The person responsible
for killing Mr. Ohtaka
& using Mr Saginuma to fake an alibi is...
Tsugumi Amano!
It's you!!
No way, he's kidding isn't he?
Tsugumi...
Tsugumi?!
1.... we can't blame the flight atten
for making a mistake...
after all, the cabin was dark...
& the only part of his face not covered by
the blanket, was the nose up...
While the flight attendant was getting the
medicine,
Miss Amano went back to her own seat...
Then woke Miss Tachikawa by moaning
exaggeratedly!
Making sure she noticed Mr.Ohtaka's
seat was empty...
This gave Miss Tachikawa & the
flight attendant the wrong impression about
when Mr Ohtaka went to the toilet!
Then... the empty seat I saw...»
Just by chance, there was an empty seat
behind Mr. Saginuma
But she wouldn't have been able to
use this trick if the seat was occupied!
She made several reservations &unless she
cancelled, the seats would remain empty...
if the medicine she gave Mr. Saginuma was
sleeping pills, rather than air sickness pills,
he wouldn't wake up so easily...
the knit cap was in her bag...
and she knew his habit of using an
eyemask so there was no problem!
But what if the flight attendant noticed
Miss Tachikawa wasn't
next to her the first time...
All she had to do was create a camouflage,
drape a blanket over her bag...
I believe she cut the negative into
small pieces with the scissors in the
sewing kit &flushed them down the
toilet bowl.
The killer wanted us«to think the
murder was linked to the negative.
Drawing attention away from her...
I found a piece of the negative she
cut on the seat next to Mr. Saginuma
it was stuck to her clothes &fell
there when she sat down...
Check it out!
Yessir!
This is how it went...
She waited for Miss Tachikawa to
fall asleep &told Mr. Ohtaka
she had to talk to him &told him to wait
in the toilet...
Then she got the bottle containing
the anesthetic soaked handkerchief &
weapon &headed for the toilet...
As soon as he opened the door.
She pressed the handkerchief over his
mouth knocking him unconscious
then stabbed him in the cervical cord...
after that, she cut the negative up,
flushed it down the toilet bowl &
Iocked the door from the outside
Using this trick... when she returned
from the toilet, it would appear
Ohtaka was still alive...
alibi was perfect!
But-what if someone goingsto the
toilet saw her leaving the scene...
I'm sure that while committing the
crime, she left the door unlocked
That way, even if someone tried to get in,
it's so narrow in there, it wouldn't open up
if someone held it closed from inside
& realizing someone was inside, the
person outside would go to another toilet...
That's enough!
After all these accusations, I'm sue you
have proof, don't you!
Proof that Tsugumi did it!
I have the murder weapon &the proof
I'm sure she still has it on her!
Hah! What are you saying! She's had
2 body checks!!
Because it's something we would never
suspect...
It'll even pass the metal detector at
the air ort...
Something only women use...
Something only we use?
Ridiculous. nothing as convenient as
that could possibly exist!
Tsugumi... you didn't...
Miss Amano...
it's the linger you're wearing .
It's the wire under your right breast...
Hahaha. a woman couldn't possibly
kill anyone with something like that!
If you sharpen the end & stic
it into the back of the head.
Putting all your stcength into it & push it 5
to 6 centimeters into the cervical vertebrae.
The tip will reach the
cervical cord
even a woman could do it!
Along with the fatal injury on Mr Ohtaka's
neck. there were many scratch marks...
That's where the unsharpened end
moved &scratched him
The reason Miss Amano didn't get
rid of the wire is.
If it was found at
the scene, we would suspect
the woman with wire in only one
side of her bra. that's why...
I understand! We'll just have her go
through another body check!!
No Mr Saginuma... it's no use
If they search me again... théy'lll*find, its.
Tsugumi
It's true... I killed Kazuhiro...
3 years ago, he won the Nichiuri
Newspaper's news photo contest...
was that photo's fault...
What are you saying! That photo's the one
that brought you two together, isn't it?
That's right... I became interested in
im because of that photo...
I was so impressed that anyone could
have captured the ferocity, the tragedy,
the grief of that fire which took my
brother's life, all that emotion in a photo...
So why... then?
That photo... wasn't the only one he
took that day.
I found a mountain of them in his room!!
Some showed smoke rising from
the condominium my brother lived in...
and there were so many shots of the
condominium BEFORE the fire!!
You don't mean. . Kazuhiro...
He set the fire himself...
That's right!
When I asked him, he practically
boasted about it!!
You can't just wait around for a great
hot to come along...
You have to make it happen...
That's what he said...
I'm so upset...
I was so sure no one would figure out
where I hid the murder weapon
It's the arm you raised...
When you were about to lower his
bag from the cabinet,
you raised your left arm &then stopped but
then raised your right arm to take it out
That's what gave you away
The sharpened end of the wire must
have shifted
& poked into you making
you stop, isn't that right...
You mean... a detail that small
made you suspect me?
The smallest, most likely to be overlooked
detail usually
turns out to be the most important...
Your seemingly
casual action... in my eyes,
appeared unnatural & thus stuck with
me...
Her arm... did you noticeiit?
Inspector!!
No... not at-all
By the way, Inspector. why are you
going to LL. A.7?
Oh uh... to pick up a Japanese national
on the International wanted list...
I see...So that's what it was about...
That's why you asked me about it...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIR TOR
Yukihiro hibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama Shogdkukan
Il Rights Reserved
But you said,Show me your bra!!
There's wire in it, isn't there!
Is that how you're supposed to ask?
That, Shinichi, is considered
to be sexual harrassnent!
Oh no... don't tell me... that Ran,
she's dreaming about that case...
Hey! What are you talking about!
Did that creep so something to you?!
I wonder what she's dreaming about
I dreamt about stuffing myself
with eel on rice...
Sir... we will be in the landing
position soon,
please return to your seat...
You idiot! How can you expect me to
remain calm when my daughter is suffering!
But sir!!
Hey... what does sexual
harassment mean?