Inspiration flashes that pierces right
through.
Once he gets going nothing can stop him!
Today there's an autumn treasure hunt.
Tithe Junior Detective Squad is
challenged-with a secret code!
The one and only truth is brought into light.
He looks like a child but he's got the
brains of an adult.
His name is... Detective Conan!
Secret of the Moon, the Star, and the Sun
Part 1
Dr. Agasa! Is there really hidden treasure
at the place we're heading for?
Yiup, plenty of it.
But, that's If you can use your brains
to find it...
If the Junior Detective,Squad
makes the scene
we're sure to»find a whole lot of treasure!
Hey, Professor
Huh? What is it?
The treasure you're talking
about wouldn't be
all these toys you made me buy
would it?
Shhh! Keep it a secret from the children!
That's why Haibara. didn't ome along.
Feelin pretty rich ain't you...
the car's new too...
Professor .... have you made some sort
of wild machine and
pulled a bank into the picture...
I, Idiot! I wouldn't do that!
Actually...l owe it all to this!
He Masked Yaiba
A person I know has a toy company and
I helped them develope this new product.
I got a nice bundle of contract money!
And? What is this suppose to be?
Yaiba reco-changer!!
Surprised?
We got one from the Professor this
morning 100.! this Yaiba Reco-Changer!
Yaiba Reeo Changer?
It records your voice and transforms
it in all sorts of ways.
It's the newest Masked Yaiba item!
It's no different from
this Bow-Tie Voice Changer...
Well, what do you think!
The "junk" you're always accusing me
of inventing will be on the market
nation-wide!
Wowwww! What a big house!
Professor, is this reallygyour a
Uncle's second house? If
Yup. that's right!
My Uncle Kurisuke Agasa was
a quite well known man around here...!
Fifty years ago, that uncle hid a great
fortune somewhere and passed away...
And so, this time... I called you out
here to see if we could use
the brains of the Junior Detective Squad!
Then, it's really, really true!
Yes! The Professor didn't come up here
ahead of time to hide the treasure!
Didn't I tell you! The Professor would pull
a kiddy trick like that!
Isn't that right, Professor!
A Ann... of course...
You can already see right through this...
Search this room first!
Where?! Where?!
Ooks like it's not here...
Not here either...
n the painting your uncle?
Ah, yes, it is...
I see...
Looks like it's true that your
Un le was really rich!
Look...
the fireplace painted in the background
is the same as the one in this room.
In other words, the artist was called out
to this house to d she painting!
To do something like that, you'd
have to be rich!
Ahn, that painting was supposed to
have been done by a young artist
a year before my uncle passed away
from illness.
Who is the woman with him?
That's Aunt Teiko, his younger sister who
Iived here and took care of him!
Uncle hated people and she was the
only one he accepted.
I heard she was a teacher at an
elementary school near here...
After my Uncle died,
she went back home...
and no one has set foot in this house
for the past 50 years since then...
But, there's a lot of things left here yet...
books... dishes and things.
In his will, my Uncle said that he wanted
this house left alone
for 50 years after his death.
Of course, there isn't any hidden
wealth Ieftffihere]
And therhouse is already set to be
broken down next month...
I see...
Nd... before it's broken down. yo
thought of having a treasure"hunt
with the kids in this dusty house...
Exactly!
Where's the treasure!
Ah, here here... don't make a mess
of the place!
If you-make:a more detailed observation re
of the surroundings,
you'll surely find a clue!
That's right... for example... the strange
Iooking letters nearsmy feet
that have been obviously carved...
Ahhhhhh, it's true!
MO, ZA, RI, SA, WA, SO, DE, RU?
What's this?
Is it English?
No. its not... it's probably Arabian!
It's not that simple...
No even Shinichi would...
Where has he gone?
SS. Shinichi, could he...
Looks like even you weren't
able to solve my puzzle!
Why, of course! I thought about it for three
days and three nights without sleeping...
Oh, if it's the wooden treasure box
you hid, Professor...
I found it under
the bed in the bedroom beyond!
I haven't peeked into the box yet, but...
It seemed a bit obvious sol covered
it with a cloth and
pushed it further under the bed!
You...
What bothers me is the other mystery
about this house
The other mystery...?
Yes...
This... what do you think... Professor...
What's this. what's this ?
It looks like an ordinary 1 yen coin...
I picked that up beside the bed...
Then, it may be something I dropped...
No; you couldn't have... there was
a lot of dust on it...
and there weren't any signs around it
that showed that it rolled...
One yen coins were first made in 1955...
44 years ago...
Something like that covered with dust
found in this house means...
T, That means...
someone came in without permission
when the house was left empt ?!
No, entering the house wasn't all he did.
I think he lived here for a while...
An old person extremely skillful
with his hands...
Lived here? Skillful? Old person?
Hey, hey, what does this all mean?
I don't get it at all...
Then, compare that 1 yen coin with one
of yours!
Compare it...
What are you saying is different...
1.It's definitely thinner than my 1 yen coin...
and a size smaller...
That 1 yen coin was probably shaved
from an original coin and perfectly
reduced to size... An extremely skilled
person!
And the character "country" is in
an old character, isn't it?
I don't know if it*was done deliberately or
by mistake. but
only an elderly person would use
a character-like=that...
But, how can you say the person
Iiving here made this...
Oh... there's no mistake that
it was made here!
It was carved while reading...
While reading
There's fragments of aluminum
from the 1 yen coin between the pages.
And, white hair too!
Also, there isn't a person who could
carve a 1 yen coin like that in a short time!
That's proof he was living here for a
Iong time.
1... I see...
Then, why a 1 yen coin...
ell.... looks like, just to pass th
time, but I can't really say yet...
And, I still don't know if he was
Iiving here alone too...
I think there was a child here too!
I found this a while ago... proof that
there was a child here!
Here, take a look at the
underside of this vase.
Nderside...
This is...
T, This is... 7?
A child's scribbling, isn't it?
If it's something like that. I found some too!
Me too!
What?!
Look! There's some on the underside of
this candle stand too!
On the back of this plate too!
He must've been a rascal!
Rather than that. let's hurry and
solve the code on the floor!
But, this is strange...
My uncle has no children...
the old person living here
must've had a child with him...
Professor...
Do you know "the dancing doll"?
Dancing doll"...?
Ah, yes... it came out in the Sherlock
Holmes novel...
you're talking about that
strange picture of dolls lined up and
Iook like they're dancing, aren't you?
If I'm not mistaken, that's a secret code
made to look like a child's scribbling...
C,Could this also be?!
Ahn, no mistake about it! The vase...
the plate... and the candle stand...
If you compare the arrangements of each...
You can see that the three figures
on the right side of each are the same.
In other words, it's a secret code
with rules!
Right... ifs a'secret code...
What is it?! You seem happy.
That code... can'you read it?
Nope, I don't know anything...
not a thing about the old person...
or the 1 yen coin... but...
I'm excited! The more I don't know...
the more it excites me!...
That unsurpressable
curiosity inside of me!
T "Yblood of a detective is
being aroused...
Hmmm? Come to think of it... I've seen
this figure somewhere before...
What! Professor «really!
Where! Where have you seen it?!
Oh, don't rush me!
Hey, Conan!
Think about that secret code on the
floor with us!
You're the only one that's slackin
off in this treasure hunt!
Ah ahn, right.
MO ZA RI SA WA SO DE RU
Can't tell what it is with just this!
Codes like these
often use a 50 sound arrangement with
a letter shifted before or after!
Using that theory, if we slide the
Ietters back one...
RU, SHI, WO, TA, DO.
JI, RU, SHI, WO, TA, DO,
Follow the arrow!
Alright! Find the arrow!
H,Hey wait a minute!
Ah, what, what?
When we entered this room, wasn't
there an arrow that caught your eye?
N.,Not really.
Didn't see anything like that...
Look, that clock!
Clock?
Is something wrong with that clock?
It's unnaturally stopped at 6:30, isn't it?
What's wrong with that?
It's just stopped because it's broken,
hasn't it?
Take a good look!
On a usual clock,
at 6: 30, the hour hand and the minute
hand would be slightly apart, wouldn't it?
The hands being one on top of the other is
proof that someone fiddled with it!
That someone who hid the treasure...
Ilvother words, the hands of that
clock is"the beginning arrow!
Right!
Then, we'll have to search
below the clock next!
There's cards scattered!
The ace of spades is in the center,
isn't it?
For some reason, it's set in place
with a thumbtack...
Wow, you're right!
I see! Tthe ace of spades is the arrow!
Then, the next is...
that chess piece!
Ah, look at how the pieces are arranged!
The arrangement of the pieces?
See! If you look good, you can
see that it's shaped like an arrow!
Oh, you're right!
It's stuck to the board with
glue so it won't come off...
there's no mistake about it!
Then... the next is...
It's that room!
y there isn't an arro
nywhere 10 sight...
this is where the erson who hid the
treasure really racked his brains!
Hun?
See... on the desk in front of the door...
Dust has been swept away In
three places, right?
That proves that something was there!
Something....
Ah, could it be...
about this airplane on the floor?
Yes, match it with where the dust has
been swept away and put it on the desk .!
Aha! the bed!
This airplane is facing the bed!
The tresure is definitely hidden in this bed!
Ohhh, there's a box under the bed!
That's probably a treasure box!
But, that_strarnge#... I definitely put
the airplane there...
but I-don't remember dropping it...
Hurry up and open it! Hurry!
What?!
This is terrible
cutting it up like this with a knife...
Yeah...
The person who hid this wanted
to startle us...
You're wrong! The Professor
wouldn't do a thing like that. A.
Professor...
Then, the one who hid this toy
is the Professor?
To play a treasure hunt game
here with you!
Then, from the time the Professor hid
them until today...
S, Someone came here and...
He probably saw the secret code the
Professor left and
found the treasure box in the bedroom!
He looked inside got angry...
and cut them up with a knife...
That's probably when the airplane the
Professor left on the desk fell to the floor!
But, why was he here?
Beats me! He accidentally passed by
and came in out of curiousity...
Or, maybe
he came in looking for something from
the very beginning...
Looking fordlsomething? What?
Maybe it has something to do with that
8 figure
Figure?
You knows the ones you guys found...
that strange code with the sun, moon,
and stars lined up!
That scribbling was a secret code?!
Probably...
Just maybe. & here reall is an
unbelievable treasure
hidden somewhere in this house...
Oh, Professor... what did the police say?
Ah, they said it's probably
a bad petty thief?
They'll be here to
check it out tomorrow...
Anyway, looks like it'd be best for us to
pull out without touching anything...
You're right... That secret code bugs-me,
but we wouldn't want to mess up
the scene more than this
H.Hey! What're you doing!
What do you think! We're looking for
more secret codes to find the treasure!
Idiots! The criminal might still be
In the area!
I. I found it, Conan!
On the back of this card... that secret code!
RR, Really?!
Look!
'Alright, Ayumi and I will take the
first floor...
Genta and Mitsuhiko take the second floor.
Let's split up and find it!
Good grief...
Justamy imagination...
Conan, there's another one!
Nothing here.
Nothing here either...
In total, we've found l7 more secret codes...
Cards!
French dictionary!
Record.
Airplane!
Wine glass!
Portrait!
And. this gadget doll...
Come to think of it, my aunt used to
say that my uncle liked gadget dolls...
D... the first§three we found
Plate'...
andle stand...
Vase...
total of 10...
But, you can't telihwhat it's all
about withsjus athis...
Ann... if only there were
something longer like a sentence...
a diary...
Or a letter...
Ietter...
Oh, that's right! I remember!
Letter, the letter!
Remember, I said that I'd seen
that figure somewhere before!
I had completely forgotten that my
aunt had shown it to me!
When you say "aunt, you mean the
woman in this painting?
If I'm not mistaken you said she was
an elementary school teacher...
Ahn, that's right... It was about
5 or 6 years ago...
My aunt consulted me about an eerie
Ietter she'd been receiving once a year
from an unknown sender for the
past 10 years...
If I remember right the contents of
the letter were all in "hiragana" and
it said things like "Hello, teacher
and "Please-take care of yourself"...
Isn't it just a letter from a student?
Maybe, but... it was written in
hiragana" for a period of 10 years.
That's definitely strange...
And? The secret code and those letters...
what connections do they have?
It was on the letter... That figure...
it was drawn around the letter...
Iike a design!
What happened to the lette
I didn't know what to make of it, so
Ilhad\ our father look at them...
Ah, no... I mean I had a friend who lived
in the neighborhood look at them...
He was a detective story novelist.
H, He showed them to Father?!
It seemed that that novelist was busy with
work, and at first he look like
he was in a bad mood
But, as he looked at the letters. . his
expression turned to one with excitement...
He took the letters and hid himself
in the room
It wasn't a few minutes before
he came out and told me this...
Give this envelope to your aunt.
I really enjoyed it
Professor, you're like the sun!
Thanks to you, the gloominess in me
has been blown away!
What was that envelope?!
I haven't any idea...
The contents of the envelope is probably
how to decode the secret code!
What?
That novelist knew too.
This secret code was all in "hiragana
H,Hiragana?
Onan, is it really...
The letter was written entirely in
hiragana" as a key telling
the reader
to read the figures in "hiragana"!
I see...
It's best to think, that the sender of those
Ietters and the person who
wrote this secret code, are both the
same person...
But... why did he send the secr
code to my aunt...
He didn't want anybody but your aunt
Oo know...
For example, someone was after him...
Come to think of it... my aunt said this...
A strange guy often peeks
into the mailbox...
That's probably the guy who slashed
up the toys...
Something's going on after all...
This house...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Mas 1hito. Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR:
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi1 Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
O Gd§ho AoyarrFaJ 'Shogékukan
II Rights Reserved
Hey, is the treasure really hidden here?
What's this... there's nothing here...
A secret code!
There's a secret code carved!
All a minute...
if you connect these with a line...
Skeleton!!
Take this!!
(ma)
Secret of the Moon, the Star, and the Sun
Part 2
(am)