Inspiration flashes that pierce right
through
Once he gets going nothing
can stop him.
Today, the secreticode is solved!
A small hint becomes a big thing!
The one and only truth is brought
into the light
He looks like a child but he's got
the brains of an adult!
His name is... Detective Conan!
He planed the treasure hunt for
the Junior Detective Squad.
The location is the second house of
Agasa's uncle.
No one should be in the house
for:50 years sinceihe died
but there were traces of someone living
theretsecretly with strange codes
There were symbols like a moon, a star, and
on things like a vase, a plate, and
a candle stand.
We found out toys hidden by Dr. Agasa
for the treasure hunt were tattered
so, we felt that there was a big
secret in this house
We found out 7 secret codes after
Iooking around the house.
Card
French-Japanese Dictionary
Record
Airplane
Wine glass
Portrait
and gadget doll
Dr. Agasa also remembered
the same codes
on a letter from the his aunt
and he brought it to my father,
a detective story novelist...
Right
That novelist knew too...
This secret code was all in "hiragana
H Hiragana?
Conan, is it really...
It's best to think,
that the sender of those letters
and the person who
wrote this secret code
are both the same person...
B, But... why did he send the secret
de to my aunt...
He didn'tfwant anybody
but your aunt to know...
For example, someone
was after him...
Come to think of it...
y aunt said this...
A strange;guy often peeks
nto the mailbox...
That's probably the guy
who slashed up the toys...
Something's going on after all...
This house...
SECRET OF THE MOON,
THE STAR, & THE SUN
But...even if we know that this
secret:code is in "hiragana"...
we haven't the faintest idea
what's it about...
Don't worry, if there's a hint...
we've got it in the bag!
What?
White sun moon, star...
and... black moon...
there's differences in the
shape of the stars...
but none in the black sun...
In "hiragana...
what's the letter that
doesn't have a "step" or a "line"...
an outcast letter?
Doesn't have a step or line...?
Nn outcast...?
I Know!
Un"! Isn't it?!
That's it! The black sun
represents "~un"!
The next thing to look at is...
the three figures on the right that
are the same In all the codes!
It means that they hold a different
meaning from the ones in the front!
I. I see...
xt... is the'small black and wh
circles around the figures!
We don't know the meaning of the
black circle onthe bottom right,
but the black:and white circles
n the upper right...
judging from the position...
they're probably G, Z and P
sound points of "hiragana!
Hey, what does G, Z and P sound points
mean?
Don't you remember learning it at
school...
G, Z sound points are those two raised
slash-marks on the top right of the
Ietter...
they make up the "G" sounds
and the"Z" sounds!
The P sound point is that raised
circle on the top right that
make up the sounds
PA PI, PU, PE, PO!
Let's take a look at the code again...
The crescent moon facing up...
has a black circle...
a white circle... and no circle...
there are three types
In other words, this crescent moon
facing upward is one of the "HA" line
Ietters...
I see! The "HA" line is the only one
that has G,Z and P sound points!
With that in mind...
The easiest to read would be
this wine glass code...
The four letters excluding
the three on the right...
The-third black-@'sun,r,is""Mn"
the fourth is a letter in the " pa"
Iine...
A word that uses letters " un"
and one in the " pa" line...
Panty. hairpin, pelican...
Anpan bread, melon bread,
curry bread...
Personal computer, Japan, lamp...?!
It's cards!
That's right! This probably
says " cards"!
Wait a minute... if so...
The secret code written
on this candle stand...
e first letters "pu"... a
the fourth letter will be " ra
PU...Ta...
pun u r001, n pen , u ran
I see! It's "propeller"!
Wait wait...
if this black crescent
moon is " ro"... this code...
FFUPBIIBLU... TU TU
Iook... Look at the propeller!
There's a code written on the backside
of the plane's propeller!
There sure is...
If the black circle on the upper right
Isa G, Z sound point...
thevsecond, letter is "bu"...
he third letter is "ra"...
Look at
bu ra"...
Look at the oil painting!!
It's talking about this portrait!
Alright, I've got it!
The phrase, "look at" is stuckvon to
erything named in this house...
In other words, if you follow those
clues you'll reach something...
something so important a secret code
had to be used to hide it!
RR, Really 7?!
Okay, we'll solve all the codes and
get the treasure!
Hey, is there really a treasure
hidden here?
Ahn, I don't know if it's treasure,
but there's no mistake that
something is hidden!
LELS See... Ue Code Onl ule plidile
IS...
The third is "un"... the second is a
Ietter that has a G, Z sound point,
$000000
Let's see... "ka", " bi" "un"?
Vase! The vase!!
The secret code on the dictionary is...
Let's see
It's the .fireplace!!
If so... then, the code on
he gadget doll ls .
All ll fill, ll unll, "gull, ll rall, ll
It's the wine glass!
Uh? Conan...
Until now...
there's 17 letters that we know!
And, if we make deductions from the
e... from the blank portions.
Are you saying something?
Here, take a look at this!
This is the chart to decode the
secret code!
Oww! This is great
As you can see, the sun, moon,
and stars are "AE 1 O U" that mark
each line!
And, all of it follow the same rule...
You can tell it goes
sidewards too, cant your?
For example, the sun and star...
The thorns surrounding it are missing
clockwise from the top...
The moon goes clockwise too...
And, the black circle on
the bottom right, that was a mystery,
was a mark added when
there wasn't enough-figures!
hhhhh, I see...
Furthermore, if you use that chart
to read all the secret codes and
connect them together...
This is what it becomes!
( AL BT FD)
(59%<7 TE 23)
7 (das
2(H Head?)
Let's*see... Look:at'the: vase
Look at the candle stand
Look at the propeller
Look at the oil painting
Look at the record
Look at the doll
Look.at the wine glass
Look at the card
Look at the French dictionary
iii
ook at the fireplace...!
The fire place!!
Then, the treasure is in the fireplace!
Gee, there's nothing here?!
It's a code! There's a secret
code carved!
What! Really?!
Ayumi! Lend me that decoding chart!
Sure! Conan, you mean this, don't you!
Let's see... that code is...
Hey! What's written?
Hurry up and tell us!
Conan!
Oh! Don't keep us 'waiting!
Plates».
Look at the plate...
What ?1
P, Plate? The first plate we saw?
Good grief... we're right back where
ored look. we started...
The code is spinning us in circles
You're kidding...
It's just a bad joke...
Joke? That can't be...
using a secret code that maybe
wouldn't be able to-decoded?...
Would he do something
so complicated?:But...
if you follow the code...
you go back to the beginning...
or... is it saying that thisxdecoding
chart is wrong
J! dS. 4 .
No... that can't be...
There's gotta be something...
Nn the order of this code...
true meaning...
It can't be helped...
Let's put everything back to where
they were before the police arrive!
Let's see...of
The plate was in the cupboard...
Wait a minute
if you connect the first letters of these
plate and vase
sa ka r0 pu ah re ni wa tofu da...
What's that. @f&
The vase goes here...
Maybe... if you change it
Oo roman characters...
The candle stand goes on
the fireplace...
guess not...
Professor, this airplane... where was it?
Oh, it was beside that vase... I took
It to the bedroom!
Beside the vase, beside the vase...
Maybe I should try changing
it to English?/
No, maybe French...
r. maybe German...
Record we
Nothing seems to ring a'bell...
Doll, dol...
Hey!
Huh?
Why don't you help out a bit... don't
just sit in the middle of the room...
Hey, Professor... you said the cards
were in this room too, didn't you?
They were originally right below the
clock, but I used them!
Which means...
all the items with the code written
n them were in this room...!
Wait a minute...
if you connect them with a line...
Start from the plate...
the vase... the candle stand...
Propeller... oil painting... record...
oll...... wine glass#O. card...
French dictionary... fireplace...
nd the plate...
It's concentrated in the center of the
room!!
That's why Ayuni. has passed by me
O many times...
Licuoridiy... viouolidly...
That's why Ayuni. has passed by me
so'many times...
0 many times...
But, that's strange...
this is the center of the room,
but there's nothing different about it...
it's not on the floor...
groove...
he base of the chandelier...
Let's put off the treasure
hunt until next time...
Professor! Let me ride your shoulder!
What?
Hurry!!
A, Ahn...
A, Ann...
Whoop!
VV, vviidl IS IL... IIS S0Uurna...
H, Hey... what's going on...
S, Sounds like something fell upstairs...
Let's go and see!
H, Hey, Conan!!
Uff, huff...
Right above that room...
is this room!
onan, what's going on...
here's stairs in the room...
I see... so, that's it!
That code was pointing at the chandelier
trick in the center of the room...
In other words, it was pointing out
the hidden stairs in this room!
I heard that my uncle liked gadgets
but,
I didn't think he had something like
IS set up...
Then, could the treasure be up there?!
Hn, something is hidden...
at's for sure...
Alright, let's go running up
the stairs. Let's hurry!!
T's this room...
s pitch black...
At this rate, we can't see anything...
anyway, let's open the window...
Huh... 7
nished 1 yen coins... A
is is a tube of oil paint...
Oh, look! Something's on the desk!
Is it treasure?!
Hey, what's the matter?
What is it... speak up...
Skeleton!!
What?!
W, Who is it... that corpse... 7
Didn't I tell you a while ago?
There was an old person with
skilled hands living here...
He's probably the one who carved the
1 yen coin and
wrote those secret codes!
He wasn't killed, was he...
he passed away whi
writing a letter to your aunt...
Looks like he had a bad heart...
But, how did he know about this
hidden room?
The only ones who knew about it were
my uncle and aunt who lived here...
There's one other, isn't there?
Before your uncle died
there was a person who was
and out of this house...
Fore my uncle died...
That painting...
Right, that portrait of your aunt and
It's that artist who painted that picture!
He probably heard about this
hidden room from your uncle
while doing the painting...
But, why did he have
to live and hide here?
And, those coded letters to my aunt...
hy...?
Reason...Is probably...
Huh... 7
Huh...?
Hat's this...
A 20 dollar bill printing plate?!
Counterfeit!!
He was probably as
at the desk by someone to make it!
But, it bothered him and he
ilsappeared with the plate...
To escape from that somebody,
Those letters he wrote to your aunt
were to show her his appreciation for
Ietting him live here...
He used the secret code because he
didn't want anybody,
other than your
aunt, to know where he was...
Then, that person who was
peeking into my aunt's mailbox was...
the person who order
the counterfeit!
And, the person who slashed up the toys
ou hid is also the same person...
Nn excellent answer...
I thought I'd found where that guy was
and where he hid the
printing plate...
but, there were only toys in the box...
dl slashed them up...
I heard that he was friendly with the
owner of this house
and suspected this
was the place...
but, I didn't know
there was a hidden room...
Thanks, kids...
uu rat...
Don't move! I don't want to make a
urderer of myself...
And also... if you make the wrong
move and the bullet
hits the plate,
won't be of any use...
Young lady?
Hat's right... you...
Get that printing plate from the old
an and bring it over here...
That's it... you're a good girl.
If you can bring it right over to me...
I'll give you a reward...
Y, You brat! Wanna get blown away!!
Don't panic! I'll give it to you later...
Tomoaki Okuda...
Why do you know my name...
I heard it from that person a while ago!
Ah! How can a corpse talk...
Listen... if you listen closely,
you can hear him...
His spirit is probably still wandering
ound here...
Ha ha hal You brat! If you
ake anymore wise-cracks...
moaki Okuda...
O(O 00010),
ell. just as promised...
II give you this...
Take it!!
C,Conan! Let's escape while we can!
Huh?
T, That's right! If that
host appears again...
Oh that voice...
It's this... this!
The Yaiba Reco-Changer!!
I recorded my voice and played
it over and over again in slow!
But, how did you know that guy's
name?
Oh! It was written in secret code on
that unfinished letter on the desk...
It said, "I don't want this master-piece
to get in the hands
of Tomoaki Okuda"!
I see...
He wanted to leave this masterpiece
in the hands of my aunt
whom he was indebted to in the past...
so, he left the secret codes in this
house to let her know where he was...
Ah... that aunt... what is she doing
now?
Oh, she passed away last year...
at age, 76... she never got married...
Maybe, it wasn't only because
he was indebted to her in the past...
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
RIPTS BY
Kan]! Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masaidmo Sudo
Hirotoshi1 Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS YOF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hi onobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri-Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogadkukan
II Rights Reserved
Two hours later, the police arrived
and Tomoaki Okuda was arrested...
We finally got to go home...
But, I don't understand...
Huh?
You know, those words that your
ather said...
Professor, you're like the sun!
For a while after that, he called
e "Professor Sun"...
it's just a joke... a joke!
A joke?
Look at our name with
this decoding chart!
Huh?
They're all suns, aren't they?
Oh I see!
This is funny!
I'm Professor Sun! He he!
T, There's somebody outside...!
It's finally just us...
Even we were being fooled!
It's absolutely unforgivable!
Conan!!
RR, Run!! Mitsuhiko!!
DISAPPEARANCE OF THE
JUNIOR DETECTIVE SQUAD