Inspiration flashes that pierces right
through.
Once he gets going nothing can stop him.
This time it's an overnight stay at
an inn for training...
Ayumi and Genta disappear!
The one and only truth is brought into light.
He looks like a child but he's got the brain
of an adult.
His name is... Detective Conan!
Disappearance of the
Junioror Detective Squad"
eries of thievery at inns...
The guests and managers
have suffered losses...
How dangerous...
But, well. it's larceny that doesn't
use any brains...
guess there's no reason for a great
detective to make an appearance...
Oh, dad.
But the way... I don't see that
Conan around, but...
is he still in dreamland...
Oh...
If it's Conan, he's gone to training camp!
The neighborhood's children's club...
hat's that...
The children's club will be
putting on a puppet show...
A puppet show...? And, a training camp?
Yes... at an inn on the
Kirigaoka Highlands.
He's staying over with the
other children to practice...
which means... that kidd, detective squad
is with him too...
But... wonder if it's safe?
What is?
The thevery at inns that was in
the newspapers!
Nothing to worry abo
t's a totally different area...
But, Kirigaoka Highlands,
Is famous for the heavy fog
that sets in a night.
What if they get lost...
There's an adult with them,
isn't there?
Yeah, a person who lives in
ward #3 by the name of Kaibu...
it seems he did puppet plays when he
was a student...
He's taking care of the script and acting
at the children's club this time...
Good grief!
Let's see... "That's strange,
another person has disappeared".
Wait, wait!
Genta! There's no feelings in that
dialogue at all, is there?!
Is that right?
Yes, Genta...one more time!
That's strange... another person has
disappeared! .
And... next... Ayumi' s dialogue...
Let's see... "What's this all about?"
He's acting big
that Mitsuhiko...
Next... Conan, it's you!
Ah... let's see...
The murderer is definitely-in here..."
Good grief... A high school
student and doing a puppet play...
I shouldn't have come. like Haibara...
I have no interest in those things...
Shoots! I envy that character!
Conan; that's n xgood!
You're suppose to be playing the role
of a detective...
put:more force into the dialogue...
Isn't that right... Teacher Kaibu™?
Mitsuhiko... let's cut-out the "teacher" bit...
his is my first time at producing too...
Conan's role is
you're definitely rig
Conan... can we try it again?
Yes...
The murderer is definitelyaln here!!"
Umm... The movement of the puppet:
snNn't quite night...
That Mitsuhiko... what's he all
so " gun-ho " about.
That Mr. Kaibu moved into
Mitsuhiko's neighborhood
and they quickly became friends.
He even let him help make this story.
But... if I'm not mistaken. this is...
And, no one was left...
Anybody can see that it's been taken
from Agetha Christie's famous.novel...
I know the story! People are invited
to an island
and they're killed off one by one.
Rather than that... am hungry...
h, Genta...
Alright,
Then.? let's call it quits forenow!
One hour later, after dinner,
Iet's try it again...
Yes!
Gather the puppets together so they
won't get lost...
Yes!
Great!
Inner ime. inner ime.
It's dinnertime!
Oh... that Genta
Conan, great job!
Well.... well
ardon me...
Everybody still has a long way to go.
Hard practice is necessary!!
What?!
Hard practice! Hard practice!
Good grief...
What a thick fog...
guess that's why it's ca
Kirigaoka Highlands...
wow. . just great... I'm full!
It's no good... I can't move an inch!
Everyone! Rest 30 minutes and it's
practice again!
Practice again? Mitsuhiko! Give us a break!
Genta, there's a midnight snack prepared
00 but...
What!!
I'll do it! Let's go!
Everybody! Has someone
seen the Teacher around?
What's the matter?
Well... something's wrong.
He suddenly disappeared. . It's already
time to practice...
Come to think of it... the ward #3
uys aren't around too...
You're right... wonder where they've gone.
This is a problem...
Hey, have you seen them?
Nope...
h.... just as I thought...
The dolls are missing too!... Those
belonging to the Ward #3 kids...
You're right... the Teacher's is gone too!!
Hey, hey... this is just like
Those Wrad #3 kids probably too
it along with them...
But, where?
Well... maybe they went home...?
At this hour?
In this fog?
Someone's outside...
It's no good!! I can't see anything
th this fog...
No mistake about it!
Someone was here...
even those kids are go
What!
The dolls are gone too!!
Only ours are left!!
Darn it... this is a bad joke...
And, no one was left"... it's exactly
he same...
Is that... the story this puppet
play is based on...
up... in the original story, th
characters get killed off one by one...
and, the dolls disappear as each
person gets killed...
As they get killed off... you gotta
be kidding!!
All the children who
disappeared have been...
You're joking...
Calm down! Wesdon't know for sure
about that yet!
The backdoor!!
The fog is heavy overhere too...
(It's the footprints of those children, isn't it...
LIgie 5 Ole Tote pdit... Lose Ol Ally aU,.
Who's are they?
Could it be from that guy who was at
the window...
the size andikind of shoe fr
those prints are different...
11111 vwilo 111 peel SOI al
the managing office said
this is the only inn with guests today...
which means...
I don't know... but, there's no doubt
that there's something going on
in this foggy lodging area... Something.
I Know!
Huh? What do you know?!
It's the doing of that thief who raids-inn!
The one that's in the news lately...
That's right...
There's no mistake about it. He's
probably locked everyone up somewhere.
In thermeantime; he's planning to
raid all the inns in the area!
So, that's it...
Okay! If that's the case. the Junior
Detective Squad in gonna snag that thief!!
Agree! It's time for the Junior Detective
Squad to move into action!
Alright, let's do it!
Hat's the matter? Conan...
No... nothing...
But, if it's a thief.
Putting the kids aside...
Why did he take the dolls?
Darn it!! This is full of things
I can't understand!!
Anyway... it's best that we contact
the police...
it won't be too late...
even if the Junior Detective Squad
makes its appearance after that...
What?
Conan, what's the matter?
Can't you get a hold of them?
Yeah... the phone's dead...
With this...we've been completely
Iocked up in this fog...
Conan, what are you going to do?
There should be someone at the
management office over the hill...
Are you planning to go there?
Yes.
That's strange... weren't there a
flashlight and candles around...
Yes... when we got here, we checked out
the emergency'exits:and saw them...
They're not there?
No... somebody probably took them...
Somebody...? Who...?
Gee Genta... who else would it be
but he thief!
No... we can't be sure of that yet...
But... at this rate, we'd get lost even
if we tried to get to a nearby inn...
Anyway let's try to find some leads
this Inn...
Can't count on that too much...
Let's go! Conan!
Ayumi, stay here with Genta...
Can't be helped...
Genta! Take care of Ayumi...
Okay!
Be careful... Conan...Mitsuhiko...
Just leave it to us!
Goodjgrief
This is Mr. Kaibu's room...
hall we try going in...
What's this?
It's a map of this area...
Inns here and there are marked.
What's this suppose to mean...
What's this?
Could it be...
You're kidding...
acher Kaibu is...
Genta! Ayumi!
Where are you!
This is...
What's the matter? Conan?!
You're Kidaings...
We're the only one left...
I got it! I know...
The teacher... that teacher, Kaibu is
the thief that's raiding the inns...
The proof is that map and that tool box!
To raid the inns at Kirigaoka,
he used this puppet play practice
as a coverup...
He even fooled us I can't forgive him!
Mitsuhiko, wait a minute! Not only the
children have disappeared,
but the dolls as well.
I don't think it's just a simple burglary...
Conan, you're over-thinking on this one!
In the first place, Teacher Kaibu is the
only one who can take the dolls out!
That's true, but...
Anyway, all we can do is try to find
Genta, Ayumi, and the others
That's right!
And, we're going to catch the criminal...!!
With our own hands...
The next inn was In this direction,
wasn't it.
Yes...
Huh? I think this is too near
to be the next inn...
Let's try going anyway!
E.Everyone!
Kaibu!
It's him... it's him after all...
I's him... it's him after all...
Where's everyone?
We're going in... hurry!
No one's here...
It's mo good...
I'll go check out the second floor!
Conan.
Stay here!
Please make it quick...
Conan!
Mitsuhiko!!
What?!
Conan!
What's the matter!!
What're you doing?!
Conan?!
Run!!
Mitsuhiko! Run!!
Conan...? Conan?!
You're kidding...
onan too...
ell..."And, you're the only one th
was left"...right? Mitsuhiko!
You're joking...
You're joking?!
Somebody!! Somebody!
Help me!!
Mitsuhiko... there's no use in running!
Alright... come with me... Mitsuhiko!
Don't come... don't come!
Ko... don't play the spoiled
Hurry!
H no, oh no...
Terrible... terrible...
Gee... thanks...
Conan?!
Everyone?!
Then...... this is.
Mitsuhiko, sorry about that... We were
practicing the puppet play.
I had each person come one
y one to the Inn...
You're kidding... I didn't hear
anything about it...
Sorry about that... I forgot to tell
you four about it.
Then, what were those pliers and
screwdrivers for in your room?
H... I thought of making some simp
stage installations.
I wanted all of you to get the atmosphere
of drama as quick as possible...
What about that m
Of course...
It's so we wouldn't get lost here...
I heard that the fog was
really thick around here...
Is that what it was all about...
Those dolls that disappeared were,
of course, used for the practice.
I bet it really scared you, didn't it?!
H... Genta, you were just as scared.
Who? me? Not really...
But, when we were doing voice training...
you thought we looked like
we were tied up...
But we really thought you were...
Isn't that right, Conan!
Mitsuhiko. I'm sorry... Even I scared
you in the end...
Actually, at that time,
Run! Mitsuhiko!
Calm down... Conan...
All of you...
Is that what this is all about!
Mitsuhiko is the only one left.
Everyone, continue practicing...
Wait!
That guy was acting big all day today...
so, let's scare him a bit!!
I think that's being too mean...
t... it may be good drama practi
Hey . hey... what are these gus anyway?
You're kidding... even you, Ayumi...
It's a shock!
Hey... Mr. Kaibu... but. why did you
cut the telephone lines?
What are you talking about...
Teacher, wasn't it you?
What does it mean? If it wasn't the
teacher...who'd do a thing like that?
Could it be?
Mitsuhiko?!
Let's go!
Mitsuhiko!
A real burglar?
You saw me!!
Help!
Mitsuhiko!
Mitsuhiko!!
Conan! Everyone!!
The one who cut the p
Iines and took the flashlights is...
Right... it's his doing...
e work of a real burglar...
Don't come!!
Don't you-care what happens to him?
Everyone! Never mind me... get this guy!!
Mitsuhiko!
Don't make noise!! Be quiet!
Get him!!
We did it!
That was a close call!
It was dangerous...
I'm saved...
Conan, close your eye a bit».
Okay
Close your eyes tightly...
Mitsuhiko! I'm sorry about that
omment a while ago...
You really impressed me...
ee, I don't care if I die...
Mitsuhiko! I won't forgive you!!
Lease stop it! Genta...!
ORIGINAL GOMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Mich Biko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatdomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi lioka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaca
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
II Rights Reserved
Three day later; the
town's Children's Club was held, a
and our puppet play was performed
Oops!
The result is, ofgcourse,
a great success!
A trick ridge
Spider mansion
thumbtack...
The surface is rusty but
e needle is new...
But Father said not to leave the room...
Uncle. wake up!!
Ran is inndanger!!
Mystery of the Spider Mansion of Totton"