Inspiration flashes piercing right
through to the truth.
Once he gets going nothing can stop him.
Taday's setting#is Trick Ridge.
A spider's thread eerily tangles
in the case.
The one and only truth is brought into light.
He looks like a child but he's got
the brains of an adult!
His name is... Detective Conan!
Mystery of the Spider Mansion of Totton"
(Part 1)
Tottori Prefecture Trick Ridge
I feel like we're going around in circles...
Hey, Heiji... could we be lost?
There hasn't been a person or car
that's passed by
I've forgotten me cellular phone,
and we can't call anyone...
nd to top it off, the bike is out of gas...
We should've caught a taxi after all...
Be quiet!!
If it's the map of this area.
Ust leave it to me...
Aren't you the one who forced your way
onto the back of my bike?!
But, what're you going to do?
Didn't that letter say for us to reach that
Mr. Takeda's house by tonight?
Yeah, that's right!
He doesn't write a phone number to
contact and
he sends money along with a request
to check out a strange case
I've gotta return the money to that idiot...
Thought I'd solve that case while I'm at it...
The sun is setting...
Looks like we're gonna have to campout...
Campout?!
I don+<t want to! In a forest like
this without a tent or blankets!
It won't be funny if we catch a cold!
We can get through the night if we
wear a lot of the clothes we brought
along and sleep close together...
Ieep close together...
But, don't get any horny ideas...
That's my line!!
Hey, hey...Don't start a fight...
Kazuha, let's go...
Retend you didn't see it...
You're right...
Hey, wait a minute...
It's just a joke... a joke!
Robert Taylor (26)
Came aman
y name is Robert Taylor...
I'm American!
Robert Taylor (26)
Cameraman
A cameraman who loves
the nature of Japan!
I was just taking this beloved forest!
I haven't been here since receiving
r Takeda's indebtedness
Takeda? Do you know the house?
Ss... 1 was just about to go visit him.
Oh, so were we!
Then, will you show us the way?
Well, looks like I got overly taken
n by the scenery and...
You wouldn't be lost, would you?
But, aren't you going to Mr. Takeda's
house too...
Looks like it's a campout after all...
Oh no! No, I don't want to!
What can we do! Nobody's passin by...
Hey! Wait a minute!!
I said to wait! Didn't IT!
Hey! It stopped!
What do you think you're doin'!
Darn it!!
Sorry, sorry... didn't think it'd
you for real...
Wow! You're?!
Oh, Hattori, it's you!
Which menas...
I had a bad hunch
omething was gonna happen...
What's that?
You-ve received a request on the case and
you-fire on your way to
Mr. Takeda's place too?!
But, mine is different from yours.
Wis official.
The request came from
the present master of the
Takeda household, Nobukazu Takeda!
I've already received a nice lump of
$5,000 on the investigation fee...
Then
what is this equest
that came to me?
Is there another house: by the name of
akeda around here
) Hey
Iet me have a look at that!
Sure
Let's see...
Next saturday,
please come to the
Takeda home at
Trick Ridge before the sun sets...
If you don't,
another living doll willprobably become
e victim of the spider...
Victim of the spider?
That's definitely about us...
Nasty things have been going on
and that's how the folks
in this area call us...
The spider mansion of Trick Ridge...
uzou Takeda (35)
rd son of Takeda family
»3 ¥>
uzou Takeda (35)
rd son of Takeda family
if you don't want to be cursed,
stay away...
uzou Takeda (35)
rd son of Takeda family
that's what they say...
uzou Takeda (35)
rd son of Takeda family
EH 38 - (35)
that's what they say...
wd ED
Trick Ridge
ASpider Mansion!
What?
Misanpasseduaway 3- earsnagm.
Why?!
Two, 3 days after you left here...
Yoko Takeda(33)
Takeda Ryuji's wife
£55.
KEHRE_OE
(Yoko Takeda(33)
ITakeda Ryuji's wife
EVI RE - JX
she was found hanging on the second
floor of the doll storehouse...
Yoko Takeda(33)
ITakeda Ryuji's wife
EH _ooE
she was found hanging on the second
floor of the doll storehouse...
HH BF (33)
0051.;
THe WI
as it a suicide...
And soon after that...
next was sister
even Misa's mother
was found hanging
in the same place...
But why...
Well, don't know.
And, that's not all.
There's still more?
Yes.
Just the other day...
Negishi, whom
brother was indebted to, was
found in the barn
In the same way...
while we were out, he quietly...
Did that person
come in and out of here quite often?
Brother is a doll master
and Mr. Negishi sold
and transported the dolls.
It's about that Mr. Negishi.
The mystery Brother wants you to
solve is
Dear...
I'm Ryuji Takeda,
second son in this house...
yuji Takeda (38)
d son of Takeda family
You haven't got an accent,
have you...
Yes,
that's because
e're always in Tokyo...
We came back on vacation,
but Mr. Negishi's incident came up,
and Brother
told us not to leave
before the
detective got here...
Hmm...
Ohhh. Detective Mauri.
I mm Nobukazu Takeda,
the one who requested you.
Nobukazu Takeda (45)
First son of Takeda family, Puppet master
Sorry to, have you come all the way out
here in the mountains
Nobukazu Takeda (45)
First son of Takeda family, Puppet master
Oh, it's nothing to worry about...
And, Mr. Detective...
to be honest...
I think Mr. Negishi was killed by
someone in this house.
Huh?
That's the situation...
If you find out who the murderer is...
only tell me who he is!
Are the four in the back your children?
If I'm not mistaken, I heard you
had only two...
Oh, well, you see.
Excuse me, Nobukazu...
it's been a while since we met...
Oh, Robert!
It's been a while.
Haven't seen you since
summer vacation three years ago
I came to see you to thank you, but...
Well, come in!
Your good friends,
Sae and Emi have just come home too...
Oh, you're there!
Oh, Sae! Em!
You've grown so big!
Murder .
Murder...
Huh. LL?
Huh. .""
Daughters of uji and Youko
e came to kill again...
Daughters of Ryuji and Youko
Daughters of « uji and Youko
He sure has
U's frightening...
Daughters of uji and Youko
Frightening frightening...
Daughters of Ryuji and Youko
You two!
What are you saying?!
Oh no! Mother is frightening too!
Rn sorry...
h, don't worry about it...
hie Takeda.(71)
akeda brothers mother
Hey, Mother... why do Emi and I
have only half a fish each?
Why?
I'm sorry...
I only bought just enough
fish and so I was short two...
Please bear with it...
o way...
Ah, then, have this...
f What'sthe matter Kazuha...
if you don't like fish, I'll take it!
ROoo {
Hey, you...
Delicious...
Huh?
Where are you taking that?
Miyuki Shiotani (26)
Maid
To Grandmother...
Miyuki Shiotani (26
Maid
Miyuki Shiotani (26)
Ever since the Negishi incident,
Maid
she says it's a curse and
won't come out of her room...
MiyukitShiotani (26)
Maid
she says it's a curse and
won't come out of her room...
so I'm taking it to her.
S that so...
Alright!
I'd better get started in putting the
finishing touches to that unfinished doll!
Well then... Mr. Mour...
Huh?
Please do a good job
on that investigation from tomorrow.
Yes, sure!
Well then,
relax and enjoy yourself.
Hey, Yuzo...
Don't you have to go and
help Brother?
Hold on to your horses...
11 have this one last drink...
Excuse me, can I borrow your car?
I'd like to go and visit Misa's grave...
At this hour?
Yes, if I go now... the moon would be peeking
over the mountain on the way to the grave...
The moon over the mountain...
May I go along too?
Of course!
Hey, Ran, would you like to go too?
Sure, sure!
Ister Ran...
Conan, wanna go too?
Take this along with you. . you'd be
ingtrouble if something happened?
Here!
Something happened...
Take it along, take it along!
I don't know what it is, but that
kid is showing first-class jealousy!
Idiot! That's not it...
Well, then...
Then, dear, we're going to take a
bath first so please watch the firewood
Okay.
Those two are suspicious, aren't they...
You're right...
Hey! Brother! Brother!!
Yuzo, what's the matter? ,
Brother isn't around! In the workshop
or anywhere else!
What!
What's that?!
What about the barn?
Did you look in the storehouse?
I looked in both places,
but he wasn't there.
How about th second floor of the
storehouse?
No, I haven't checked yet.
Something's wrong The second
floor window of the storehouse Is open.
Two people have commited
suicide there and
no one wants to go close to that
The stairs are over there!
Hey!
It won't open! It's locked from inside!!
Somebody, bring an axe or something!!
Sure...
TTS 88occccs 78
Brother...
Brother!
Hurry, call an ambulance!
That's not what you need...
You've gotta call the police
not an ambulance...
E's already cold...
I'd say it's about an hour since he died...
What...
What are you talking about?!
Don't come in!!
This may be the site of a murder...
Murder?!
I received a letter...
A live doll will be the victim of the spider
here again tonight
a letter that
forecasted this murder!
Again means
an incident has happened before!
That's why I came
to stop the murder tonight
and to solve the
mystery of the previous ones...
But, it was boldly done In front of me!
Who are you, anyway?
Heiji Hattori. A pretty well-known
detective in the Kansai areal!
Detective?
Well, I think I've heard about it...
the story of a really sharp young
etective in the Osaka area...
But, is it alright? That
id is in the room too...
Oh, never mind, never mind! That kid
s like my assistant...
A thumbtack?
The surface is rusty,
ut the needle is new...
Looks like it just came loose.
But why is it here?
Anyway...please hurry and call the police!
Oh..Yes!!
But, if this is a murder, how did
the murderer get out from here?
It must be that small window...
he probably used a rope or something...
That's impossible.
That window is only big enough to
barely let a child through.
What?!
Wait a minute! The door was locked
from the inside
so we broke the
door down and came in!
And, if a person can't get out of
that window...
Then, this is a murder
in a.sealed room.
t's her Excellency...
The spider empress used her six long
Iegs to climb the storehouse wall
and from the window, she strangled
Nobukazu with her thread...
She wanted to get even with Nobukazu
or building a storehouse here...
Frightening, frightening...
You're detectives...
If you keep calling it a murder...
her Excellency will curse you too...
hat's the spider empress...
It's an ancient tale of this area.
Long ago at this ridge. . there was
a woman as beautiful as an angel.
She stopped travellers who passed
this ridge and asked them riddles.
Do you think there's a heaven?"
Would you like to go there?"
All the travellers were taken by the
strange beautysof the woman
and replied, " yess
they were taken deep into the forest
and*'wa"sf neverseen,;~again
A doll master heard of the rumor and
put a human-sized puppet on the road
of the ridge and watched.»
As expected, the woman appeared and
asked"her riddle,
but the doll did not reply...
The woman became angry
showing«her-true identit. as a giant
spider, she attacked the puppet.
The doll master who was watching,
shot a fire arrow that*he brought
and, the giant spider, who was engulfed
in flames escaped into the forest.
The doll master followed the spider
and found it burnt to death with her
children in their nest.
After that, the village people who
feared a curse,
built a small shrine on that nest
calling it the "spider empress
And, they came to call
this ridge, "Trick Ridge".
It's just a fairy tale! Why does
there have to be a curse with that?
This storehouse stands where that
shrine used to be.
The shrine was broken down?
Yeah... Father was a doll master and,
after Brother took after him,
he built this storehouse against the
wishes of the village people
Three years after the storehouse was
built, Misa, Brother's daughter
and his wife, Kinuyo
was found having commited suicide...
The two were found pitifully
tangled up in a spider's web .
And, again three years later
the other day,
This time Mr. Negishi was found
in the strings in the barn.
Strings?
They were tangled around Mr. Negishi's
hands and legs.
Strings used for marionettes.
Just as Brother was...
As if they were wrapped in a
spider's threads...
Ee .... that's why it's called
spider mansion of Trick Ridge
es... somebody's using that curse
to commit these murders.
Come to think of it, the area around the
grave, where Robert and the others went
used to be the place where the
Spider Empress appeared.
Oh no!
Could it be...?!
Making Ran take that cellular phone was
the right thing to do after all.
Rn... the house phone is in use...
Hey, Uncle!
Lend me your cellular phone! Hey!!
Uncle!!!
Here!
The cellular phone I borrowed! Who
are you going to call?
Kazuha. & ou were back...
What's the matter? You're out of breath...
I told them that the place that you
went to had a mysterious past
they turned pale and went flying out.
Oh, you were worried?
Idiot! That's not it!
It suddenly started raining, so we
came back early.
A lot of landslides occur in this area.
Dear... what' s all the noise about?
Ell, actually...
What?! Nobukazu has died?!
On the second floor of
that storehouse again?
Dear is that really true?
Yeah... and the door was locked.
And the police?
Iyuki is calling them now...
It's terrible!
There's been a landslide and the
police won't be here until tomorrow!
What?!
Can't help it...
Robert? Can I borrow your camera?
Yes, sure.
What're you gonna do with a camera?
What else!
We're gonna do the investigations!
We can't wait until daybreak!
Who's "we"?
Who else could there be?
Me and this old man, right?
Then, everyone, until the police arrive
tomorrow, please rest in your rooms
Please don't undertake any
activity on your own!
Gee... that's strange...
What's the matter?
The mascot that was on
my pouch is gone.
I thought I had it before I
got in the car but.
Then, maybe it's in the car?
Then, I guess I'll have to go and
find it tomorrow.
Do you wanna go look for it now?
Huh?
Yuzo has forgotten the car keys that
he had lent to Robert
and I have a pen light
But dad said not to leave the room.
It wouldn't hurt to just take a peek
How is it? Is it there?
Nope... looks like not...
hmmm... I probably dropped it in the
mountain... darn it...
Maybe, it was before you got in the car!
Remember, you dropped your pouch
and picked it up in a hurry!
It was probably then
Was that mascot that important?
It was that Kudo who bought that
mascot, wasn't it?
It's no good trying to hide it!
It's written all over your face!
Boy, I envy that guy Ku
You think about him so much.
Where has he gone?
If I were a man, I'd take you away
from a cold guy like him!
Shinichi isn't my guy!
And he isn't cold!
He always seems to be looking over me.
Huh? Is he close by?
Re... I just feel that w
If I'm not mistaken it was in this area where
Robert parked the car.
And we came running over.
H... Ryuji called out t
I dropped my pouch when I turned around.
Oh no! I'm almost out of battery!
There's some batteries in
my CD player so I'll go get them!
Oh...
She's really a nice girl...
Leaving a nice girl like that alone...
That guy Kudo...
where could he be roaming around...
Huh? What's this? This white ball.
It's come after all...
sure has...
We saw it, didn't we...
We did, we did... the spider's thread...
It's frightening, isn't it...
Frightening, frightening...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michikiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
CRIPTS BY
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Hioure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi1 Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORSYOF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
Gosho Aoyama / Shogdkukan
II Rights Reserved
Hey, what's that sound?!
Shhhh! It's the stairs!
Heavy feet...It's not Ran...
ho could it be...
Kazuha! Where are you!
KazuhaH!!
dd "SN
MYSTERY OF THE SPIDER
MANSION OF TOTTORI
Ff OO¢€ A
(ERE)