Inspiration flashes piercing right
through to the truth.
Once he gets going nothing can stop him.
The case at the "spider mansion
becomes more complicated.
Ran and
Kazuha are in a danger situation.
The one and only truth is brought into light
He looks like a child but he s t
the brains of an adult.
His name is... Detective Conan!
We were called out to the Takeda home
at Trick Ridge in Tottori Prefecture
Heilji Hattori and Kazuha
Toyama get lost in the forest
and meet up with an American by the
name of Robert Taylor.
We happen to pass by and find outsthat
we«had -all'fbeen:- called out to
to the Takeda home to solve the mystery
of the curse
at the "spider mansion of Trick Ridge".
On the night we arrive, the eldest
on of the Takeda family: Nobukazu,
commits suicide on-the second floor
of the doll storehouse.
Furthermore, someone suspicious
appears behind Kazuha...
MYSTERY OF THE SPIDER
MANSION OF TOTTORI
I'm sorry Kazuha! I've found the mascot
I was looking for!
It was caught on the Cover of the
CD player
Kazuha? Where are you?
Kazuha's penlight...
Kazu ha. . . .Kazu ha'?
Hey, look at this!
Looks like he's been hit on the back
of the head with something!!
What?!
Then, the murderer hit him and then...
Yes, the time of death is about 9:00 p.m.
just around the time Nobukazu
Ieft the living room.
At that time, he had already been
called out by the murderer.
The murderer met Nobukazu
here-and hit him,/on the head
put him unconscious then,
strung him up by the neck.
That's right! He wrapped a lot of
string around the body
to make it look like the curse of
the "spider empress!
Ummmm... But, I don't understand...
How did the murderer escape from the
room after he committed the crime?
Nobukazu's sandals and flashlight
scattered on the floor also bothers me.
It's also.strange that there's no
dust on the shelves and floor.
The room was-supposedsto have been
Ieft alone for three years.
Hey, kid!
H, that small window...
A child can barely fit through it but
Is there something to it? A reason
why it had to be left open?
No... I thought heard.
Ran's voice outside the window...
Huh?
And, Kazuha's voice too...
Idiot! Those two are probably in their
room fast asleep...
Hey! What was that sound?
Shhh! The stairs!
Someone's coming up the stairs!
Heavy feet... It's not Ran...
Who'd be coming here?
Never mind...
Let's meet him in person
and ask him what the reason 1s!!
Good grief! It's the housekeeper.
What's the matter?
I thought you'd be hungry sol
brought you some rice balls and tea.
Oh, this looks delicious!!
Kazuha! Are you here!
Answer me If you're here!
Kazuha!!
Oh, so you know Misa Takeda
who died three years ago?
Yes, we were nurses at the
same hospital
but, the.work was too hardsfor me and
I quit...
I became a housekeeper here through
Misa's introduction.
Thank you.
Misa was a really nice girl...
always attentive and kind...
But why?
Why does a person like that have to
commit suicide?
Just maybe... that could be. the reason!
Misa's father Nobukazu, came home
from the hospital for some reason
he grabbed his wife, Kinuyo, and was
In great anger.
He said, "you really deceived me for
the past 20 years!!!
Deceived him... about what?
Well... I have no idea...
And, that's when Misa got badly hurt.
Badly hurt?
Yes... Misa went between them to stop the
fight, but Nobukazu pushed her aside
she hit her head:on-ggpiller and
had to have 7 stitches on her forehead.
Misa became gloomy... and rested from
work at the hospital until she met Robert.
Robert?
The day of a landslide three years
ago, Misa accidentally found him.
He was caught in a landslide while
taking photos and was badly hurt.
Unfortunately, the hospital rooms were
filled that day.
Misa had no choice, so she had him
treated at the hospital and
brought him here and took care of him.
In the beginning she had a hard time
taking care of him.
The inside of Robert's mouth was
cut-up with the landslide
so he couldn't speak well.
Robert could speak Japanese, but it
seems he couldn't read or write it
and the conversation with Misa took
place on paper with roman letters
But, when Robert got better and
was able to talk
they seem to be enjoying things.
They told all sorts of jokes...
Japanese foods are delicious
especially on rainy days
dirt and sand are excellent"
I'm a prince of a certain country, and
I came to find a bride who is like light
By the time Robert's wounds had healed
and a farewell party was to be held
Ryuji and his family were home and
he became friends with them too
Misa also became bright again.
But, that makes it more confusing...
Wasn't it 2 or 3 days after Robert went
home when Misa committed suicider.
I don't really know, but after Robert
went home, Misa became gloomy again.
She suddenly disappeared and everyone
thought she ran away from home.
Yuzo is the one who found Misa dead
on thesecond floor of the storehouse.
Nd, several days later...
her mother, Kinuyo, also committed
suicide in the storehouse...
After the two died, was there anybody
who had a change in attitude?
Nobukazu came to the funeral
without tears or sad expression,
but on the other hand, Ryuji was
the one who was a big problem.
Huh?
He.cried in a voice so loud it echoed
throughout the neighborhood
The other would be Sae and Emi...
Oh, those twins...
Those two were such good friends with
Robert but...
2 years ago when they
came back to visit,
they suddenly
started saying something strange.
It was Robert...
Robert is the one who killed Misa...
Isn't it terrible...
Terrible, terrible...
But why did the children say something
Iike that?
I don't know... Mr. Negishi who came
to pick up the dolls was also surprised
Because after they talked to him, they
suddenly started saying those things.
What did they talk about
Well.... Mr. Negishi said they only
asked him his name
Hmmmmm... that's the Mr. Negishi who
died in the barn the other day.
Everyone was out to attend
to the neighborhood gathering.
Yoko came home ahead of the others to
prepare dinner and found him in the barn.
At that time, weren't you around?
Nobukazu and I were at the supermarket
buying the grocery for dinner.
With Nobukazu?
Yes, after his wife died, Nobukazu
took control of the-household money.
By the way the rope used to hang
Nobukazu and the string around him
can they be found in this storehouse?
Yes, for the string...
there's a'lot of it because it's used to
make the marionettes.
The ropes are in the barn
Would you like to go and see them?
Gee. it's raining hard
Hey, Kudo... Do you know who it is?
The murderer?
Not who the murderer
the sealed room trick
not a single lead...
After Nobukazu left the living room,
Robert went to the barn to get the car
and left with Ran and Kazuha
he didn't go near the storehouse even
once. It's impossible to be him.
Yoko, who was in the bath with the twins
and the housekeeper who was
cleaning up in the living room with us
and the old lady who was in her
room are also clean.
Yeah.
The ones that could have done anything
are Ryuji, the one making the bath
And Yuzo, who was looking all over the
house for Nobukazu, those two
But something bugs me.
Something...
The string... isn't it?
Why did the murderer have to use the
string to make it look a curse?
It was a sealed room.
If he didn't do a thing like that, we would
have thought it was a suicide.
And, that request letter that was sent
to you also bothers me.
H... if that was sent by the murdere
IS he taking me lightly and
putting up a challenge?
This case, something fishy is running
behind it.
Let's see... the rope is...
Is somebod. there?!
Ran?!
What's that?! Kazuha is missing?!
Is she really?!
Only her penlight w
on the ground...
When I thought someone carried her off,
I panicked...
Anyway, let's split up and search for her!
Yes!
Kazuha! Where are you!
Hey!
Kazuha!
Hey! Have you found her?!
Nope... she's nowhere!
What's the matter? Hattori?!
The door to the storehouse
Isthought Irclosed it, but it's open!
This is...
Ka...Kazuha!!!
Kazuha!!
Hey! Get a hold of yourself. Kazuhat!!
Hey! Kazuha'!
Hel...
Kazuha!
What*happened to me?
If I'm not mistaken... I was waiting
for Ran in front of the the storehouse, but...
I suddenly felt faint...
Be quiet! I'll cut you loose right now!
Kazuhat!
You don't have to worry .
Looks like you were just hanging with
the strings.
I'm sorry! I'm sorry, Kazuha!
I didn't search hard enough, and got
youlinto this terrible situation.
Then the mascot?
I'm sorry... I found it! It was
caught in the cover of the CD player.
I'm really sorry... if I had taken a
closer look...
I'm glad you found it...
on't lose it again
Okay!
Hey, Hattori.
Oh yes! I know!
Old man! Please take care of Kazuha!
Huh? What?
Don't you see?
He tried to use our blind-spot by hanging
Kazuha up in the storehouse
we were in a while ago.
After we left, he brought Kazuha here
and wrapped her in the strings
then all he/had to do was put that rope
around her neck
and the curse would be completed!
There's only one reason
why he had to stop!
The murderer noticed my footsteps when I
ran overhere, and he left in a hurry.
Which means,
The murderer is still
in this storehouse!!!
Hey, Kudo! Are my deductions wrong?
No, nothing' s wrong
Then, let's have a look at the
murderer's face!!
Hey, is he around?
Nope...
That' strange... it hasn't been 3 minutes
since we came to this storehouse.
We were guarding the entrance on the
first floor so there's no placexto hide!
The only place to escape from would
be that tiny window
Is it really possible?
Is there a way to get out from there
in such a short time?
What!! This time that girl from
Osaka was attacked?!
Osaka was attackedr.!
By who?
I don't know!
Kazuha is resting in the room right now,
but she may remember in time
one of the faces among you!
One reason we had you gather here is
to prevent anymore murders
from taking place
and the other is to confirm your alibis!
Alibis? We were asleep in our
rooms all this time.
It's the same for me.
I was in my room too, but I wasn't asleep .
Where were you? I didn't see you when
we were searching.
I was searching outside the house
In other words, everyone doesn't have
an alibi
You're kidding...
Yuzo isn't arou
Oh, if it's Yuzo, wouldn't he be in
the workshop?
I was here working all the time
I was putting the finishing touches on the
doll Brother had to complete by tomorrow.
Mmmmm. you can make dolls too
Three years ago, my company went
bankrupt and I came back home
Brother taught me all sorts of things
and let me do the simple constructions.
Three years ago... that's the time of
that incident?
Yes, I came home just
after Robert had left
But I wasn't allowed to make fixtures
or do repairs.
Brother's marionettes cost $10,000 a piece
and he charged $7.000 for repairs.
He sold them for $10,000 and repaired
them for $7,000?
Can he do business like that?
Yes. . seems like there are some people
who request repairs more than 10 times.
He charged quite a bit for
the marionettes.
With the money he saved, he often
went abroad with Mr. Negishi to play
After leaving the sales of the dolls to Mr
Negishi, they began to sell at high prices
Hey... what's that big doll?
Oh, that's the marionette
of the "spider empresssn
When Father was alive, dolls of
that size were used at every festival
to do plays of the "spider empress
but the number of people able to
handle dolls that big gradually disappeared
and they quit doing it...
What are those boxes that are
stacked up?
It's the dolls that Mr. Negishi wa
suppose to take that day.
After Mr. Negishi died, Brother
realized that he was one doll short.
The customer called directly and he
had to make one more.
Anyway
please stay in the room everyone is
gathered In.
It's dangerous to be by yourself.
Sure...
Alright, now's our chance!
The repair fees for the dolls
are extremel high
Despite the price, there are customers
who request repairs more than 10 times.
A simple puppet that's
expensive means
What's inside is probably...
« narcotics!!
As for the marionettes
you can only put the narcotics in
the head so the price is cheaper!
I've got it! Now I know the reason
why Nobukazu called a detective
to find out who the murderer is.
A large part of the entire picture
has come into view.
What's left that we don't know is the
the sealed-room trick and
why Kazuha had to be attacked...
Sae! Emi!
What is it... what's the matter?
The two daughters I brought to the
restroom aren't here!
What's that?
Mother...
Ohhhh... you worried me!
Didn't I tell you to wait in front of
the restroom when you were through!!
But, there was a smell!
There sure was... a funny smell!
It's probably the spider children
burning in the furnace!
They're burning!
Grandmother said so, didn't she...
She did! She did!
The furnace??
It's true, there's something strange
burning in here...
Hey, come to think of it... what was
the meaning of that?
Huh?
You said it, didn't you?
You called Robert "murderer"
The day Robert was leaving,
Misa told us to go and ask him what his
feelings were
so we went to the bus stop!
We asked him, "how do you feel about Misa?"
Then, Robert wrote a terrible thing
down on paper!
Didn't he!
A terrible thing?
He wrote, "die!"
Die?
It's terrible!
Terrible, te rible
Don't let it bother you
The children probably saw wrong.
I shouldn't have shown that name card.
Name card?
Let's see... I'm sure I have it here...
this is it!
They. found this name card inside the
wallet and made a lot of noise.
« hey asked, "who did: you get this
from?" "where is this person?"
Look at this!
I got it out somehow!
Hey, this is...
You're kidding...
Isn't it a stungun?!
Kazuha!
Oh, Heiji! I feel much better now...
Take off your clothes!
Huh?
Just let me see!
What're you doing!!
Wait a minute Conan!
Why am I the only one to get hit!
Well... I'm a child.
T's here...
small burn marks on her back
She was knocked out with a stungun
after all! And?
Did she say anything else?
She didn't see the murderer,
but she said she found a strange ball
in front of the storehouse §
Ball?
She said that it was a ball about
this small.
BB-shot!
That's it!
There was that method!
If that's so...
That thing...
Should be somewhere...
In this room!
I found it! Hattori, it's here!
The marks of a thumbtack!
I've found it too!!
Strange string with loops on
the beam ends!
It's just as we thought, isn't it!
Yeah!
There's no mistake... that person is
the murderer!!!
ORIGINAL COMIC B OKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
Gosho Aoyama ll Shogakukan
II Rights Reserved
The murderer didn't need to
escape from here!
That's crazy!
It was to avenge Misa who committed
suicide in this storehouse three years ago!
Misais revenge?
There's only one person
who could have done it
without anyone noticing!!
And, that's you!!
(FR R48)
(seam)
MYSTERY OF THE SPIDER
MANSION OF TOTTORI
!(Final episode)
(4% R $8)