There's{no shape to running water.
There's no form to rustling wind.
You're free to make deductions no
matter what the case may be.
Mystery of Trick Ridge is coming
to an end.
Heiji and I solve the mystery perfectly.
He sees through
to the one and only truth.
With the appearance of a child and
the brain of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
Hattori and Kazuha are called out to
the Trakeda home
on Trick Ridge in
Tottori Prefecture.
The two get lost
and meet up with a foreigner, by the
name of Robert Taylor.
We were also
called«~out to the Takeda home
and accidentally meet up with them on
the way there
We were called
to solve the mystery of the curse of the
Spider Mansion of Trick Ridge
On the night of our arrival,
Nobukazu,
the oldest son of the Takeda family
commits suicide on the second
floor of the storehouse.
In addition
Kazuha was attacked
and found tangled
in strings at the same storehouse!!
It's...
Kazuha!
Business card?
Yeah.
I got it.
Hey it's...
Can it be...
Can this be a stun gun?
She didn't see the killer.
But she said, she saw a
weird cicular objects.
Ircular objects?
Something this small.
BB shots!
That's it!
I never thought of that!
If that's the case.
I found it!
I found it Hatton!
Same here.
An bizzare string
with loops on both ends
Yeah.
We found the killer!
Ly (TD AA
tw ID AA
Mystery of the Spider Mansion of Tottori
(Final episode)
PL TD AA
What?
He figured out who the murderer is?!
Did 'Mr. Mouri really say that?
That's right!
He said for everyone to gather on the
second floor of the storehouse!
Oh yes
and he also said to bring
that big doll in the workshop too...
and also, it would help if there
IS some spare gasoline.
Hey, hey... what's that kid from
Osaka up to...?
Bringing the corpse down
without permission!
Did he really say to wait here?
Yep!
That's right!
Here it comes...
Oh, you're all here.
Well, let me start...
to tell you about the many incidents
that have happened here at the
Takeda's home.
Mr Mouri, please wait...
When we found Brother,
the door was locked from the inside.
There's only that one small window
barely large enough for a child to
et through...
I don't think it's a curse,
but if you say there's a murderer,
will you
first explain?
How the murderer
escaped from this room!
If there is a way like that,
I'm the one who'd like to know
how it was done.
Huh?
Yes...
the criminal had no need to
escape from here.
That's because, when the killer
murdered Nobukazu,
the murderer wasn't,
in this room!
No way!
Then, how did he do it?
The strings used for the puppets!
The murderer used
puppet strings, ropes,
and thumbtacks to commit
this crime In a sealed room!
The set-up is simple!
First, the rope is set-up so that the
Ioop closes when it is pulled
and it is tied to the beam.
With small loops made on both
ends of the string,
the loop of the
rope is pulled to four corners,
and fixed to the small window
with thumbtacks
Another long string is attached to the
base of the loop of that rope...
it is put over the beam
in the center of the room
and leads out the small
window and the set-up is completed!
Look!
Like this!
Little boy...
All that's left to do is
call Nobukazu out here,
make him look out
of the window,
and pull the string...
The loop of the rope closes and he is
able to murder Nobukazu.
But, why did Brother lock the door?
And...
Anyone would think it strange if he was
told by the person he was waiting for to
Iook out the window..."
He locked the door
because it was something important
and he didn't want anyone to see him.
He looked out the window
because he probably heard a sound.
A sound?
the criminal fired BB-shots
at the window with an airgun,
so that
Nobukazu would look out the window.
It was to take revenge
for Misa, who committed suicide here
three years ago!
Revenge for Misa???
Yes!
The criminal probably thought
that Nobukazu, having found
out that Misa wasn't his real daughter
went hard on her and forced her
into committing suicide.
Not his real daughter?!
What does it mean?
Isn't that right...! Ryuji!
Dear...?
I'm sorry... Yoko...
I knew I had to tell you about it
sooner or later, but...
Misa...
that child...
Is the daughter
made between.
Brother's wife, Kinuyo, and I!
You're joking... aren't you?! Dear!
It's true...
It was before I met you...
Kinuyo was told at the hospilal that
Brother could not have children...
and she pleaded me with tears...
He wants a child... please
make his dream come true" she said...
That was the first and last time...
Brother and I have the same blood type,
so he wouldn't have found out.
Until three years ago
when the doctor at the hospital
ipped his mouth...
Misa ended up committing suicide
and Kinuyo, feeling responsible,
followed her...
It's ..%wlt's all because I listened
to her plead...
Dear...
But, how did you know
Lh was.Misa's father?
Kinuyo and I didn't tell anyone...
Her name...
Misa and the daughters of you and
Yoko resemble each other
and form -a circle .
I recognized that and knew...
You secretly made the names of your
daughters have relation to one another.
It's also seems like
you were unusually upset
at Misa and Kinuyo' s funerals...
But, Mother named all the daughters...
I already knew!
I named the three to form a circle
for you.
What???
Don't take an old person
for a fool!
When Kinuyo
came home from the hospital
with the baby .
I knew right away
from the way you two acted.
But,
I didn't think you'd take revenge
for the daughter suicide,
Nobukazu, was responsible for
What?
Making it look like the curse of
the Spider Empress!!
You're disgusting!
Mother, you're wrong!
Didn't kill Brother...
Ryuji isn't the murderer!
I said it, didn't ll...
that the murderer
fired an airgun at the window
and when Nobukazu looked
out the window, the string was pulled.
And he was killed
Even if the room was sealed,
If someone made movements
in front of the storehouse like that,
he'd immediately be suspicious.
The way this set-up was made,
there would have to be
more than human strength used
or the rate of failure
would be very high.
To make it successful,
you would need the strength
to pull the thumbtacks,
on all four corners, off at once!
Without being noticed by anyone...
there's only one person
who could have done that...
You're the only one!!
Without being noticed by
anyone...
there's onl «one person who
could have done that...
You're the only one...
Robert! You used the car
to visit the grave with the girls!
You're the only one
who could've done it!!!
After dinner,
when you were going
out to visit the grave...
you parked the car
in front of the storehouse...
you waited for the girls to come
running over to the car that waiting.
You could have shot at the storehouse
window from the driver's seat.
And,
beforehand, you could have lead
the strings out the window
If you tied it to the car
before dinner...
all you would have to do is
drive the car off...
You'd be able to pull with great
strength...
The string that was left on the car.
Was retrieved in the mountains
when you stopped to look at the scenery...
and was thrown away somewhere
along with the airgun.
Please wait a minute!
Yes, I'm definitely
the one who moved the car,
but it could have been someone else
who tied the string to the car!!
And,
I hadn't been here for 3 years.
I just arrived today!
I completely forgot the location of house,
that I got lost
From the time I arrived here to the
time we went to visit the grave,
I was with you almost all;that time
I wouldn't have the time to rig a set-up
Iike this...
I hasn't been three years since
you visited here.
It's several days ago!!
Yes!
You murdered Mr. Negishi
and rigged this set-up on that day!
What?!
That's why only Mr. Negishi was
killed in the barn.
He avoided this
room that was rigged with the set-up.
He called the high school detective
from Osaka with a strange request letter
He made the meeting on the road
Iook accidental
to make it look like
he hadn't been here for three years...
No one would suspect a person,
who was lost and picked up
by an Osaka detective on the road,
to have something like this
set up beforehand.
Ut... why kill Mr. Negishu...
I don't know that
but If know for sure
that Robert found out
about Misa's suicide
and the narcotics at that time!
Narcotics?!
IT CO.
Nobukazu worked with Mr. Negishi
stuffing the dolls with
narcotics
and selling them at a high price.
Brother dealing narcotics?!
That can't be true!!
If you don't believe me...
check the dolls in the workshop later.
The dolls are filled with narcotics.
And, after killing Mr. Negishi,
Robert stole one of the dolls that
Mr Negishi was planning to take with him
The next day,
he made the plans to
call Nobukazu out to this room.
If you're interested in narcotics, I've got
some good drugs... wanna make a deal...?"
that's probably what he said on the phone
Nobukazu suspected someone in the family
of killing Mr. Negishi
and stealing the drugs
and he jumped
at the phone call!
He was called out to this room where
the trap was set up and was murdered.
Am I wrong?
Stop!
You don't have proof
and you're making false accusations...
And, you're forgetting something
important!
Explain the mystery why Nobukazu was
tangled in the strings...
Huh?
Was he really?
Ah . yeah...
Huh?
Hey, old man! I'm ready!
Right, right!
I completely forgot about it
until you mentioned it...
that thing about
Nobukazu being tangled in the strings.
That set-up has been taken care of,
hasn't it, Conan?!
Look... It was dark and you probably
didn't see it, but...
Strings are attached to the rope
that's tied to-the-beam!
Proof rather than discussion...
Let's actually try it.
Then, Yuzo...
stick the head of the doll,
you have, out the window...
Ah... sure...
That's it!
Just like how Nobukazu
Iooked out the window...
Robert confirmed the situation
and then moved the car off.
The string tied to the
car is pulled
the thumbtacks come loose
as the rope choked Nobukazu, it
pulled in the opposite direction
and the back of Nobukazu's head bangs
into the beam!
The string is pulled more
and it snaps
Nobukazu's body dives into a
sea of strings
and dangles from the ceiling as if
tangled in a spider's threads!
The question is... Robert,
How did you know that
Nobukazu' s body was tangled in strings?
The only ones among you who knew
about it were
Ryuji, Yuzo, Chie and Miyuki. The four
who came to the scene of the crime.
Of course, these four were told
not to tell anyone
about the scene of the crime.
And, one more person...
in other words,
that's the murderer who rigged the
set-up to kill Nobukazu.
Obert...
How...
How did you know?!
It sounds funny!
You kept everyone from talking
and waited for me to make the slip!!
The number of fish!
The fish we had for dinner...
The unexpected guests were suppose to be
me, Kazuha, and you three people but,
she was short only two fish!
That means
you were an expected guest that
somebody had already invited.
At first, I thought you and Yoko, who
bought the fish, were suspicous
but hearing that Nobukazu handled
all the money
the only suspicious one
Ieft was you...
I sensed something was going to happen!
Nothing had happened yet,
so I let Kazuha go to visit
the grave with you...
but Nobukazu was murdered
and I panicked
If you were the murderer, you migh have
run off with Kazuha find Ran
You dangled Kazuha in the strings
on the first floor of the storehouse
but didn't kill her to make it look
Iike a curse.
And to create an illusion to make us think
that there is a way to escape from this room.
Of course,
there's also the reason
that Kazuha found the BB-shots...
But why? Why even Mr. Negishi?
Several days ago,
when I came by here,
he said this...
If it's Misa you're looking for,
she committed suicide after you left!
Nobukazu was picking
n her anyway...
Well, it cant be helped,
she wasn't his real daughter...
A girl like that,
nobody would marry her anyway.
There'd be nothing good
even if she were living.
With eyes that were high on drugs...
he laughed and told me that!
I desperately learned to read and
write Japanese
because she wasn't
good at English;
I finally was able
to come and meet her.
I looked forward to
eeing her smiling face...
But, don't you think you overdid it,
for putting Kazuha in that situation?
I didn't care who gets hurt, or who was
suspecting me
I didn't care about that anymore!!
Even everyone in his household,
who let her die!
Hey, I thought of not telling
but I'll tell you anyway!
When Misa was In an unstable
state of mind.
When she was conversing with you in
roman-Japanese,
Stop! Hatton!!!
The real reason why she committed
suicide was...
maybe... just maybe!
Shine?
Yes, that's right!
S-h-i-n-e" is shine!
It means to be bright
Maybe for Robert,
Misa was a bright light.
Light?
Come to think of it, Robert said
he wanted a bride that was like a
Iight...
We've got to apologize to Robert.
Apologize?
Because, it was the same as the letters
from Uncle Negishi's name...
So we thought Robert wrote a terrible thing
and gave it to Misa.
We thoughtihe wrote..."die"...
Morning came and Robert was
taken off by the Totori Prefctual police.
In the police car,
Robert repeated the same words
over and over again...
Why wasn't I Japanese...
Why wasn't she American.
Like a broken puppet
he repeated
over .and over again...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatdmo Sudo
TORY EDITOR
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashlwabara
- dzunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahis3 Owaoa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
Gosho Aoyanta: / 'ShogdkuKan
Il Rights Reserved
Hey .
Why did Robert go off with the police?
Why? Why?
But the murderer
is'the*Spider Empress...
We saw it!
Before we went to take a bath,
we saw that long spider's thread
coming out from the storehouse window!
Oh that's probably...
Yep!
Huh?
It's the doing of the Spider'Empress.
Robert just went back to his country.
So there's nothing to worry about it!
You're right!
Grandmother, tell-us a story again!
Then... how about "the White Rabbit of
Inaba...
We've heard that one before!
It's Grandma, after all...
How beautiful!
What's that?!
Drowning...
In other words,
due to some sort of accident,
she wasn't able to
escape from the shell.
No... #4!
this isn=tean accident!
U's a planned murder!
Next episode.
The Kiss of Venus"
Next«Conan's .hint!