Just as! flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
In each and every case to be solved
Today's episode is at a hospital.
Kogoro is surprised
and Ran is acting strange too.
He sees through to the
one and only truth!
With the appearance of a child and
the brain of an adult...
His name is Detective Conan!
Yeah...ll can't come home for a while yet.
Gee, what on earth are you doing?
All the others in class are also
worried about you too.
I've got no choice.
I'm handling a dangerous and difficult
case, right
Uh, you know what...
Oh, I'm sorry, Shinichi! I have
something to do and gotta go.
What?
Bye, then, and take care because it's
getting cold!
There's something...something strange
about Ran recently...
She seems to be giving me the cold
shoulder when I call her...
She's not raving, "Shinichi, Shinichi
Iike she used to before either...
And, the strangest thing is...
Ah, Conan!
I'mOgoing out for a while!
I left your dinner on the table
so warm it up with the micro-wave
before you eat it, ok?
Oh, okay...
She recently goes out n the evenings
almost everyday .
Although Ran says she's going to karate
Iessons...
Something bothers me about the way
she looks so happy...
Blind Spot in the Darkness Part I
FA AA
Blind Spot in the Darkness" Part I
One day...
What?!
You were going to the hospital?!
Yeah...I'm going to get
the results of the test now.
Is something wrong with you?
I feel a bit tired recently...
You're probably drinking too much.
Right! I don't see why you
have to take us with you
when we just came back from school.
Why make such a big thing of it.
The doctor told me to bring my family
along when I go to the hospital...
H..Hey, don't tell me that you...
Mr. Kogoro Mourn...
Mr. Mourn...
Mr. Mouri...
Another...six months...
I know exactly how you feel but,
unfortunately for the next six months
have to...
Hey, you!
How cruel can you get!!
Suddenly téllingfme that
I only have another six months to live!!
If I'm that seriously ill,
isn't it only manners for:you
as:a doctor to give it to me slowly...
Huh?...Seriously ill.
I just wanted to tell you to stay away from
alcoholic drinks for the next six months...
Huh?...Alcohol?
Yes... The results of the tests show that
you have kidney trouble
caused"by over drinking
Although the symptoms
are still very slight...
Just as I thought...
Dr. Araide, you really scared me!!
Telling-me to bring my family
along with me
For a person like you who likes
alcoholic drinks,
Yoshiteru Araide (51)
Doctor
the cooperation of your family is a must...
Yoshiteru Araide (51)
Doctor
the cooperation of your family is a must...
Please reduce your daily intake of
alcoholic beverages
Yes, I'll make him quit drinking for good!
Hey!
You have a call from Ms. Sugita. She's
asking you to give her a house call...
Not again...
What a troublesome patient
All she's got is plain ulcers,
but«she's such a worrier
Patient?
mi WT AG)
3:  2
Patient?
Yoko Araide (46)
Wife of Yoshiteru
KE OD BE
Good grief...she's his lover...
Yoko.Araide (46)
Wife of Yoshiteru
Fi 546)
Oh, it's nothing. He'll be through in a
Iittle while, so please wait here a minute
Excuse me.
May I use the restroom?
The restroom for patients is broken...
my...
I turned right at the corridor so...
It's this way+...
Yes, the examination room is
right up ahead...
Gee, what a large house this is...
Wow!
Oh, no, it's my fault for being
absent minded...
Okay, that's all.
Oh, thank you...
Uh, who are you
I'm Kogoro Mouri's daughter, one of the
doctor's patients.
Oh...Mr. Mouri's daughter...
that doctor! I'm Tomoaki and
moaki Araide (25)
Son of Yoshiteru / Doctor
share the work of examining the
patients here together with my father!
Moaki Araide (25)
Son of Yoshiteru / Doctor
= BF (
But, I'm going to be working at a hospital
In Aomori starting next month...
Hey! Don't tell me it's you again!!
How long is it going to take you
to get used to this house anyway?!
You're the one who wanted
to be maid hereXright?!
I'm sorry!!
Come now, father,
ge Ing ooexcie Is Aa or your ear .
Listen!! If you do something like this one
more time, you're fired, understand?!
Hopeless scatterbrain, I tell you...
Hikaru Yasumoto (22)
House Keeper
REA UH (22)
F==LY
Thank you very much!
ecp away rom nn ng an we ong.
After all, you have the same name
as the famous Kogoro Mourn.
Oh, you've never heard of
the renowndetective...?
Uh no, so, you see...
What?! \ ou're the famous detective...!!
Yes!!
Well, ll was wondering
from the time I saw, your name
but you're him in person, eh!!
I was completely deceived,
because you acted like
you knew nothing about medicine...
How, about having dinner over
at our house tonight?
Lets talk about medicine, the two of us!!
No! I've got homework to do,
and Ran has karate practice too...
4 right?!
Why not? Lets have dinner here!
Resting one lesson couldn't possibly hurt
something... something's
strange -after all...
You graduated with honors from
Tohto University, Tomoaki!!
Fantastic!!
True, isn't it, Tomoaki!
I was just lucky.
How about thinking of marrying
my daughter?
Come on, Dad!!
My I think you two make quite
a nice pair. What do you say?
Oh, please knock it off, Mom.
Agh!!
Are you all right?
Please be careful since
the steamed dish is hot.
I'm sorry...
Is it all right?
Weren't supposed to have a meeting
tonight about your class reunion?
Oh, that's right! I have to call Masae!
Well, if you want to marry-her,
Iet me know anytime!
If we join hands, we will indeed be like
Holmes'and. Watson's
Every case"ll be solved in no time!
Give me a break!
Besides, I don't think that a detective
and a doctor make a good pair.
Our mission as doctors is
not to perform an autopsy
so that the killer can be arrested
to save the victim's life...
Oh...you got me there!
It's hard to tell who
Holmes is. isn't it, Ran...
Ran...
Dr. Araide sure is late.
He should already be finished working...
He's taking a bath...
He has a habit of taking a bath
before dinner.
Ms = 7 (7494)
BRODIE
He has a habit of taking a bath
before dinner.
Mitsu Araide (74)
Grandmother of Tomoaki
wi = (74)
He goes in before everybody else
and dirties the water.
Mitsu Araide (74)
Grandmother of Tomoaki
Fr HH
BADE
He goes in before everybody else
and dirties the water.
FH = (74)
BR DEB
Grandma, that's not nice
He sure is the bread winner of this house
to be the first to take a bath!
Phooey! Some bread winner!
All he did was take after the family,
and yet he acts so big!
Grandma!
The only person that is related by blood
in this house is you, my grandson!
And to think that you're going to be
Ieaving this house
at the end of this month...
Are you telling me that I should die?!
Randma...
Oh, Mother, what about dinner?
No thanks, why don't all you strangers
enjoy dinner together!
Oh, don't let it bother you.
Grandma is upset because
father changed the toilet and bathtub
from Japanese style to Western style.
Western style?
She was especially enraged
when he changed the white cedar bath tub
to one with a shower curtain.
She shouted saying, "Are you trying to
dirt on the tradition of this house!
Well, she sure is an energetic
elderly woman.
Oh no! A black out?!
It seems that the black out is only in
this house.
The lights of the house next door are on...
Kyaah!
Are you all right?
Uh, I'm sure there's a flashlight in that
drawer over there...
Here it is!
I'll go check the breaker!
Can you handle it?
Watch your step, Hikaru.
What's up? What happened?
There was a black out.
Oh, no, isn't this the sound of rain?
1 CO...
Bummers...
Oh, the lights are on.
Oh, I'm sorry! I thought you were Dad...
What on earth is going on?
Oh, mother...
nd... about the charges.
Well, I think 30,000 yen
is a bit too expensive.
Did the lights turn on?
You idiot! Can't you see for yourself?!
Maybe you'd better go check on how
father is doing?
He's probably angry that the lights
wen ut.and besides,
I'm worried about his heart to...
I guess so.
I'll go check then.
Oh, I'll go too!
Why did it black out...?
I wonder...
Probably a short circuit somewhere or
the fuse blew out...
Kyaah!
Huh? What is it?
It's from the bath tub...
-- . SL ~-T SA
Father!!
Don't touch him!!!
If you touch him,
you'll be electrocuted too.
Electrocuted?!
Hey, come on, don't tell that...
He was Killed because of this razor that
IS connected to the extension cord...
I'm going to try CPR, Mother,
please prepare an ll.V with cardiotonic
drug! Hikaru, call the ambulance!!
FHurry!
PY Yes!!
Oh, and call*the police too!
Okay!!
There seems to be no doubt that
this extension cord got soaked in the
water and he was electrocuted...
He used the mirror above the bath tub
when he shaved using the razor
But, why did he shave while bathing...?
Wait a minute,
don't tell me that this is...
Unfortunately...
Mr. Yoshiteru Araide has passed away.
He did have a weak heart to begin with...
Oh no...
And? Under what circumstances was
Mr. Yoshiteru Araide found?
Oh, well...
His head was faced this way, and
he was slack...
I wonder why he used his electric shaver
while soaking in the tub...
He had a habit of doing so.
He always shaved while making
his guest wait...
He even made sure that we smoked
proofed it...
What a strange habit; -to'take a bath
while his guests are waiting...
Father liked to take a bath and
he always took a twice a day,
in the morning and before dinner,
saying that sanitation was a
must for doctors...
Phooey! It serves him right!!
The heavens punished him for not taking
heed of Chiaki's warning!
This is probably chastisement from
Chiaki who is in the world beyond...
Grandma!
Chiaki...?
She's my mother who died in a traffic
accident 4 years ago.
Chiaki always warn him about
using the electric shaver
when taking a bath saying,
Don't use it with the cord on
because it's dangerous.
And you, Yoko?
I'm his second wife and married him
two years ago.
I used to be in the same class
as Chiaki in nurse school,
and she used to complain to me a lot.
Inspector, please watch!
He tries to shave using this mirror,
the part where the shaver is
plugged into the extension cord
stops on the edge of the tub.
Very dangerous indeed.
Where were you all during a black out?
We were all in the kitchen.
I saw mother go up the stairs by the
corridor opposite the bathroom too.
If so, then the only likely conclusion
would be that...
Mr. Araide mistakenly pulled the cord
of the shaver into the water
while he was shaving, and electrocuted.
This is an accidental death.
I guess so...
Hey!! Cut out that mischief!
But, my head is messed up and feel like
falling down.
Huh? Why?
Well, the man who died
was shaving standing up,
and Detective Takagi
was copying him, right?
If so, when he got electric shock,
his head is supposed to come
this way like Detective Takagi, right?
But, that man's head was
faced the other way. I wonder why?
That's true.
Hey, this may probably be...
Phooey! No big deal!
While Mr. Araide was shaving...
he realized that the cord was going to
fall into the water...
and rushed to pick it up...
but he pulled it into the tub instead.
He then touched the railing
accidentally and was electrocuted.
So, you see!
Hmm...pretty good, Pops.
Agh! No! Don't touch that! The razor is
vital proof, isn't it?
Touch it? I'm just holding it!
How about you, Detective Takagi?
No, I only held it in my hand too...?
How about the Investigation officer?
I just took pictures.
Strange. Then I wonder who played such
a bad prank like this...?
Just what are you trying to get at?!
Because look, the switch of the razor is
turned off!!
What's going on?
It is strange after all!!
If he was electrocuted while shaving
the switch would have to be on...
The switch must've moved when you fell
Iike so...
Huh? The plug should've been pulled out
to avoid danger.
Yes, I have it right here!
I see! This is the battery charge type!
Then, why was it switched off?
I wasn't moving when
the body was found, was it?
I think...that's only natural.
Somebody didnlt want the noise of the
shaver to be heard!
Huh? Who didn't want it to be heard
by who?
Beats me! I'm just making guesses!
Maybe,
someone could put the cord into
the tub without Mr. Araide noticing?
You idiot! He'd inotice* *
If you did something like that, even if
the shaver wasn't making any noise!
Besides, everyone has an alibi when the
the house blacked out...
When the lights went on, it turned off
once then went on again, right?
Hikaru? You were the one who went to
Iift the breaker, weren't you?
Yes!!
Did you lift the breaker twice back then?
Oh, I'm sorry!! I seem to have touched the
wrong switch,
The breaker of another place
seems to have been lowered,
so I put it back again right away...
I'm really sorry!!
Inspector, the second one was the
overload current breaker...Maybe this is...
Maybe a timer was rigged so that there
would be a black out,
and if someone went into the bathroom
to sneak the electric cord into the tub,
anyone of those four could've done so...
It's possible...
Uh, what are you whispering about...?
Oh, no, it's nothing.
I would like to confirm your alibis before
the black out occurred, just in case.
We just gave you our alibis a while ago?!
Huh? Are you saying that
the killer is among us?
Like I just said I'm doing so, just in case!
Oh, you were on the phone all through
the black out?
Yes...from the time before the black out
till the lights went back on.
I was on the phone
by the kitchen entrance.
I was talking to my friend, Masae about
arrangements on the reunion.
Oh, I did receive a catch phone, though
No one answered when I picked it up,
and the person hung up right away...
Detective Takagi, will you verify this
right away!
Yes, sir!
Was looking for a flashlight when it
blacked out and handed it over to Hikaru.
I was here in the kitchen right through...
Can someone verify that for you?
No not really
Tomoaki was here all the while.
After Hikaru went to raise the breaker,
I was scared, so I was clinging on to
Tomoaki until the lights went on!
Are you sure?
Why?
So like I said, I thought he was my dad.
Next, Mitsu, where were you?
I had just finished climbing the stairs
when the lights went out.
And, I fingered my way to
my room upstairs.
But, I hear that when the lights went back
on, you were downstairs near the kitchen
I felt a presence.
Just as I was about to hit the sack,
I felt a presence outside my room...
Don't tell me...
Someone else other than all of you
had snuck into the house?!
I felt that way and*followed the
sound downstairs. But, I found out.
What did you find out?
It was the sound of the rain.
And, finally you, Hikaru.
Yes!
I went over to the breaker to turn on
the lights...I'm still not used to this house,
so I got lost a bit, though...
You didn't notice anyone suspicious,
did you?
No nobody...
Just as I thought.
I noticed you were
holding your arm...
You're always much too tolerant
from before.
A burn?
Excuse me,
but I'd like to treat her wound
so would it be all right to go to the clinic?
Yes, but please have the officer in the
corridor accompany you!
We'reiunder surveillance, eh?
Oh, and one more thing!
You seem to be the only one who had left
the house between Spm and 7pm
where were you?
I went as-temporary basket ball coach for
alhigh school basket ball club!
It's my alma mater, and since my mentor
broke his bone,
I'm substituting for him until he recovers.
You, a doctor, a basketball coach?
You can go ahead and ask Ran about it.
I go to coach for Teitan High School, the
school that Ran goes to
You know, the advisor of the basketball
club Mr. Tabuchi, don't you?
Oh, yes.
Hey, don't tell me that the reason for
karate club that Ran was going to daily is...
It can't be?!
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hoka
CRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunarl Knuth:
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS YOF PHOTOGRAPHY
Tika By Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogdkukan
II Rights Reserved
Just as I thought!
Will you please go check the breaker?
Okay!
I wonder why the lights went out?
Come to think of it, that man was saying
something about experimenting while
taking a bath.
Don't tell me that Dad...
You're the killer, aren't you?!