Just as' flowing water has no form,
the breeze is invisible, deductions
take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
The case is solved by a person's feelings.
I want to find out how Ran really feels.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene.
Pops only has 6 months to go...!"!
But it turns out to be Pops' mistake...
Pops was told to stay away
from alcohol for 6 months.
Dr. Araide invites us to stay fordinner
at his house. However...
After an instant of black out,
Dr. Araide was found
deadqin the bath tub!!
Fit
Blind Spot in the Darkness" Part ll
z= Dr
You're a doctor and coach
of a basketball club as well?
You can ask Ran about me.
I coach at Teitan High School,
the school that«she goes to.
Don't tell me that Ran's going to
that karate class everyday because...
she wants to see him?!
Co Is that right, R
Yes, you can verify the fact
If you contact the high school.
So I'm going to clinic now.
Ok...
Oh, and I want you to come
to the clinic too, Grandma.
You can't fool me!
I see you've been trying hide the fact
that something is wrong with your leg
when you walk, since some time ago.
Hey...
What happened here?!
When the lights went out
and I came down here,
I stepped on something strange!
May I go to help him treat everyone?
Sure, go ahead.
Inspector!! I've verified the person that
Yoko was talking to on the
phone when the lights went out!
Oh and?
According to the person
she was talking to,
the time it took since Yoko told her that
the lights went out to the time she reported
that the lights went back on,
was about a minute!
I'd like to hear from Yoko what they were
talking about, and see if they match.
Will you tell us?
Yes, after I finish
help him treat everyone.
H...if it's okay with yo
I can go help him instead.
I'm pretty good atwdoing things like this.
Oh, then will you?
Huh?
The contents of
they say they talked about match...
A catch phone came in, and their
conversation was interrupted
only for a matter of 6 to 7 seconds...
There is no doubt that Yoko was
on the phone right through the black out.
True...
Why, of course!
If you have the blueprint of this house,
I would like to take a look at it...
Yes, of course...
This is the bath tub where your
husband was electrocuted to death...
So, this is the kitchen where we are now.
Yes...
Uh, where's the breaker?4
Go left the corridor in front of the kitchen
then go left twice, and turn
right once... It's over here.
Hikaru left the kitchen to check the
breaker at just about the same time
that you were telling Masae
about the black out on the phone?
Yes...
If so, isn't one minute much too long?
It looks to me that it wouldn't take
30 seconds to get to the breaker.
Hikaru is a newcomer here and
she's still not used to this house.
But, when the young
doctor saw Hikaru's burn,
he said,"You're always
too tolerant from before."
Oh...Tomoaki was talking about his days
back when he was a medical student at
Tohto University, and Hikaru
used to be one of his patients.
It seems that she was tolerated pain
so much that her appendix almost burst...
So, that's how Hikaru
came to work for this house?
Yes.
Since Mother is aged,
and it's hard of me to keep
such a large house in order,
I was looking for a live-in maid...
I feel wretched, because
I hear Chiaki used to handle
everything by herself...
Chiaki?
Oh...You mean Tomoakiis
mother who passed away...
The one who passed away of a
traffic accident four years ago...
I hear she was drunk driving...
She wasn't a strong drinker,
and she never really drank much.
So, I still can't believe it
actually happened yet...
Uh, by the way,
where is grandma's room?
Oh, it's upstairs...
You go up the stairs
to the left of the kitchen
and the large room in the
foreground is her room...
An elderly has a room that is upstairs?
Yes, mother likes the room where she
can have an overall view of the garden...
Hikaru's room is situated right next door
so that when something happens
she run right over...
Hmm...
Inspector, the killer probably
used the catch phone.
While Yoko was distracted
by the catch phone,
the killer went by the kitchen,
went to the bathroom and
soaked the electric cord into the water...
You idiot! How's the killer
going to get back out then? Huh?!
I guess so...
What are you whispering
to each other about again?
Uh, well...
Hey!
Why don't you just have everybody do
they were doing when it blacked out?
I guess you're right .
Let's have them act it out while
their- memories are still fresh...
I'll go get everybody then!
Wow...
You're pretty good at wrapping
bandage too, aren't you?
Oh, yes.
When I was little there was this
brat who used to always get hurt.
That's why I'm so used to...
This was really long ago though.
Ouch!!!
Hey.
What a bummer. The one
who is treating the patient gets hurt...
Well, but all you need to do is wash the
wound and bandage it. Then it'll be fine...
Uh...
Hmm?
Agh...
What's up, Conan?!
The Inspector told me
tell you all to come.
Okay, we'll go.
Hikaru.
Yes.
Will get a band aid from
that shelf over there for me?
Okay.
You idiot...why'd you
have to show up...
Uh, where's the breaker?
It should be around the
corner to the right...
There it is.
That must be it!!
Hey, Conan!
Look out, because this is the place
that Hikaru cracked the flower vase.
Huh?
I cleaned the pieces of glass
of the flower vase with Hikaru,
but she sure had a tough time...
Dr. Araide bawled her out saying,
Next time you goof, you're out!"
Wait a sec...maybe this is...
Okay, are you all ready?!
Let's get'started!
Yes, everything's fine by the stairs!
I'm in position under the breaker!!
Okay, Takagi lower the breaker!
Okay!!
Hikaru, please go over to the breaker...
Yes!
34 seconds...She didn't
take a minute after all...
Inspector...
Please take a look...
If you go across this garden, you don't
have to go pass Yoko to get to the tub...
Hey, hey, don't tell me that...
Yes...that person could've
committed the crime...
Hey...
That's enough!!
Like I already said, everyone in this house
has an alibi just before the black out!!
So, what's the use of checking
on:alibis after the black out?!
So that's...
Wait...
All it looks to me is that you guys are
making a big thing out of nothing and
amusing yourselves over
a mere accidental death!!
Uh...
id I goof again...
No...
An alibi...
Who of the four among them have an alibi
during the time that the killing
can be carried out?
That person's the only one...
Among the remaining three,
the most suspicious person is...
Hmm? A piece of something?
I wonder if this red thing is blood?
And:iwhat is this thing stuck on to it?
It can't be?!
Just as I thought...
It was that person after all!!
Which means that there is only one.
Only that person could be the killer!!
It takes about 10 seconds
to make a round trip...
seems that she is capable of
committing the murder after all.
Then, the thing that
we were concerned about...
es... I guess it was of no use...
What the... Hum...
Hey, it's come to you?!
S...I've just figured
what went on...
I'll explain,
so please take me to the bath tub.
My legs have gone weak,
since I've figured everything out.
Huh?
What?! Take a bath?
Uh-huh, he's wet with rain,
besides, he says he wants to see
if he can really be electrocuted to
death by using a shaver in the tub!
Huh? Where are the Inspector
and the other officers?
They said they'd call it a day
and left just a while ago.
Oh, what a waste!
What a waste? «
Because Pops said that he'd
be putting on a deduction show
after he finishes taking a bath!!
What?!
Did Mr. Mouri really say so?
Yep! He says he's figured out
who the killer is!
Killer? Didn't my
husband die of an accident?
Beats me...l don't know about it...
He says he wants to put his thoughts
together while taking a nice bath,
so he wants you all to wait awhile!
It's already been 20 minutes
since he went in...
Mr. Mouri sure is late.
I"can't take this anymore!!
That flimsy mustache dude!
Come on now, mother...
Um...
Hmm?
Uh...
Don't tell me it's another black out?
Hikaru... Will you please
go check the breaker?
Uh, yes!
I wonder why it blacked out again...
Come to think of it, that man...
was saying something about
experimenting in the bath tub.
Don't tell me that something
appened to Dad...
Huh?
How quick...the lights
went on already...
No. it's too soon!
A h...
Officer?
you were the one after all,
Yoko Araide...
Huh? That little boy
and Yoko's not here...
Huh?
A trap...!
Huh?!
Inspector?!
I'm the one?
What are you talking about?
I just came to check because
I was worried about Mr. Mouri
doing his experiment using
the shaver in the bath tub!
You wanted it to look that way, and kill me,
who figured out what happened,
then, pose as the first one
who had found me, isn't it so?
Don't be ridiculous!
I was on the phone all
through the black out!
You rigged a timer somewhere,
so it would short circuit and black out.
And, using that pen light, you found yourself
through the darkness to the bath tub...
which after you soaked the extension cord
into the tub
that your husband was soaking In.
You set it up so that
when someone lifted the breaker,
your husband would be electrocuted...
Like I said, I was on the phone
with my friend throughout the black out.
Ow could I have done it...
It's simple if you hide the
cordless phone of this house
and a cellular phone into
your pocket before hand.
You used the cordless phone...
Moreover, the main phone
has a built-in rechargeable battery that
makes it usable even during black outs...
Right after Hikaru left the kitchen, you
used the cordless in place of the receiver
that you were holding and went to
the tub. Then, you used your cellular
to call that house again, and
interrupted the conversation once...
You went to the bath tub,
grabbed the extension cord
that was plugged into the outlet
and put it quietly into the water...
At that time, you probably said
something like be careful and
Iead your husband to grab the railing...
Then, you returned to the corridor
before the kitchen while talking
on the phone using the cordless.
You switched from using the
cordless to the receiver
of the main phone and
waited for the light to go on.
Right after Hikaru lifted the breaker, that is
why the short circuit breaker was set off.
The lights go on, but it blacks out again.
As soon as the breaker was lifted,
an over flow of electricity ran through
the railing, and your husband died of shock!
But, Mr. Mouri, I wasn't the only one
who'd be able to do that, right...?
Ight...According to your plan
you were supposed to set up your alibi
by staying on the phone,
as well as set everyone else alibi up
by blocking the corridor.
But, your calculations didn't work...
Since Hikaru took 30 seconds more
to lift the breaker,
her alibi could not be established.
Why did she take so much time, then?
Do you know?
The steamed dish...
When it blacked out, Hikaru
cracked a dish in the kitchen.
She carried that dish under her arm,
and hid it in her room upstairs
before going over to the breaker.
She did so because your husband
threatened her saying that the
next time she goofed, she's out...
That's how she got burnt, then?
Yes...she got burn wounds and
Mitsu hurt her leg at that time.
Mitsu who went out in the dark,
stepped on the piece of glass
that Hikaru had dropped.
If Hikaru makes a round trip to her room,
it would take her 30 seconds more,
and Mitsu was definitely
upstairs at that time...
Tomoaki, who was grabbed by the arm
by Ran throughout the black out
is out of the question...
You understand now, don't you, Yoko...?
The only person who could've
committed the crime back then is
you: -Yoko!!
Inspector! Let me go to the bath tub!!
We're still investigating!
Setting up a trap, you call this
investigation! You've gotta be kidding!
What a stupid kid...
Hiding the dish won't help because all one
has to do is:icount the dishes to find out...
If Hikaru didn't do something like that
I wouldn't have been suspected either...
No...even if she didn't hide the dish,
I took it to be you, anyway.
What?
The hand that you held the receiver In.
Before Hikaru left the kitchen, you were
holding the receiver in your left hand...
But, after the lights went on,
you were for some reason
had switched it to your right.
So, I thought you may have
walked away from the phone once.
You went to the bath tub
together with Hikaru because
you didn't want her to be
electrocuted by accident.
If Conan didn't stop Tomoaki who came
Iater, you were going to stop him too...
Yes that's right...
because the late Chiaki had
asked me to take care of him...
Yes, four years ago,
before the car accident
she called me and told me,
Protect Tomoaki for me... .so tha
he won't turn out to be like my husband.
I didn't know what she meant back then,
after I married him and found
her dairy, I understood everything.
That he was a man who made passes
and dated with every woman
he saw. He had no morals...
And that he was the very one
who made cheerful Chiaki
drown herself in alcohol
and drove her to death!!
If possible, I'd advise
you to turn yourself in...
y how kind of you
No, it's not for your sake.
But, for Hikaru's sake
Huh?
You don't understand anything.
You are the one who set the murder up,
but, Hikaru is the one who pulled the
trigger when she raised the breaker
If she ever finds out, she'll have to
carry the burden for life...
You mean the you didn't mention that the
first black out was rigged because...
Yes, because we didn't want
her to think she was responsible.
I'd like to make a suggestion...
Could you:please confess that
you soaked Mr. Araide in the water,
put him to sleep with medication then,
put a cord attached to a timer
inside the water and electrocuted him
Which after you retrieved the
timer during the black out?
In other words, say that the black out
was not the cause of the murder...
Of course if you were
to leak the fact that
asked you to confess as such
we would be put in hot water too...
Yes, I'll do as you say...
I'm still not ready to give up
having a heart-yet...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hoka
CRIPTS BY
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi1 Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro hibutani
DIRECTORS YOF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaca
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama ; Shogdkukan
II Rights Reserved
I'm sorry to have kept
you here for so long...
No:problem...
I want you to relay something
to your Dad for me...
Who me?
Don't tell me that,
No!!!
I'm sorry that I got carried
away like that awhile ago,
and that I'd be willing to cooperate
If he should .need anything...
How silly of me.
Iv TN
I'm sorry to impose on you at a time
Iike this!! But, if it's okay with you...
What?!
Could you lend me that
hand knitted sweater for awhile?
Sweater?
It's like this over here.
Uh, and here...
«CoP POOP
My, What's with that-sweater?
I borrowed it because I liked the pattern!
My, look at the pattern!
T's difficult to knit...
My, that placeiis not right.
Here lend it to me...
Oh, don't! I'm going
to knit this by myself!
Sure? It's not my fault if it
doesn't come out right, okay?
Oh, that's why, if I don't know how to knit#it,
knit it beside me again and show me.
I've already knitted two sweaters for you!
I sure would like to ask the owner of the
sweaters some (ft or somethin
as a token of appreciation!
Oh, come on. He's doing
he best he can too...
Oh my, how envious.
Uh, over here it's like this...
Oh, and as for the sweaters
that I've knitted will you please get
rid of them because I don't need them?
Okay.
Few days later
Um, did you get it?
Yeah, Dr. Agasa sent it to me yesterday.
Few days later
And, did you try it on?
Yeah, I'm wearing it now. Thanks!
What's so funny?
Oh no, it's nothing.
Hey, what's so funny?!
I'm not telling you...
Shoots!
Preview of the next episode
What was that?
Sonoko?!
What's up, Sonoko?!
(21115?)
Dying Message Revives" Part 1