Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
In each and every case to be solved.
Sonoko makes an appearance
\@ after a.long absence today.
A man and crime at the skating rink.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with
the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene
EA. NA.
Dying Message Revives" Part 1
There they are! Loads of them!
More and more of them!!
Loads and loads of them!!
Wow take a look at all of them!!
Look at all those choices of good looking
men. We've got«big catch.
Hey, Sonoko?
Sonoko!! What about Mr. Kyogoku?
Ell... Makoto is more like a scarred al
over the place samurai, than a prince.
Besides, he hasn't contacted me at all
after he's gone abroad too...
I've kind of lost my passion for him...
Oh, come on, talking like that again.
He's got a lot of girl fans who'll beat you
to a pulp if they hear you saying that...
Please don't put me in the
same boat you're on, will you?
What?!
You're the type who'll wait patiently forever
for your husband to return home, aren't you.
I, I'm not waiting for Shinichi!!
My, my, I never even said
a word about Shinichi, did I?
Now, you listen, Sonoko...
Besides, didn't you choose this rink
because it's a memorable placesa. .#
that you two used to always
come together to: right?
L'have no good memories!! s
Shinichi looked down on me because
I had a hard time learning how to skate.
Aha...
So, he taught you holding your
hands, feet and hips, right?
What's with you today, Sonoko?
Cut out teasing me.
Ah, so what I'm trying to say is, today
it's your turn to teach him how to skate!
Oh, no, don't bother...
Huh? What? Can he skate?
I wonder, because this is the
first time I've come skating with Conan.
Can you skate? Conan?!
Oh my God!
Maybe this is his first time?
Maybe I'll teach you.a lessonstoday
because you'retalwaysracting so'sassyl...
Cut it out, Sonoko...
Sonoko...
Out of my way!!
Out of my way move!!
Out of my way, move!!
Conan'!!
Chihiro Itami
Secretary
Ouch, ouch...
Chihiro Itami
Secretary
Hey, are you,all right?
Are you all right?!
Yasuharu, it hurts!
That's what you get for
speeding despite being a beginner...
Yasuharu Misawa
Banker
Ch CD LIA
R Ea (29)
But...
You're not going to be able
to attract the attention of men by
acting cute like that
for very long anymore!
Chihiro, an active, curious
rich young lady is over the hill
Izumi Sano
Office worker
LYWrds
after 30 years of age, you know...
How rude!! Why do you
always say things like that?
You annoy me.
Okay, that's enough you two. It's been a
Iong time since we've seen each other,
and, we're all Clay comrades,
aren't we? So let's not argue, okay!!
Wow, are you all Clay shooters?
What is that?
The game in which you throw a small
plate and shoot it down with a shot gun!!
We just went this afternoon
and finished a shooting!
A group is more fun than one after all...
We haven't seen each other
since that accident 6 month ago.
The accident 6 months ago?
Right! Will you hear me out, boy?
It's a sort of stupid and scary story...
Huh?
Are you nuts?
Why tell a kid something like that?
Besides, I already told you that if you
talk about him, I'm leaving on the spot.
Kunitomo Oda
reig er
Besides, I already told you that if you
talk about him, I'm leaving on the spot.
Bi = (2
Tr VIS he
Wow, what a handsome guy.
He's as much a samurai as you can get.
Hey! Oda, are you really going to leave?
Aren't we going to drink up?
I'm,just going to:take.a puff
somewhere nearby,
since some idiot made me recall
something unpleasant.
What's with him!!
Just because he's a bit handsome
it doesn't mean he can act like that.
But, it's your fault for bringing that out.
My tongue just happened to slip!
And he has the nerve to call me stupid,
don't you think?
I hate that guy!!
He's not cheerful, and has a foul mouth.
He's always not part of the group.
Not part of the group?
Hey, I've always been wondering about
Isn't it about time you explain things?
Huh? You mean you still don't know?
Uh...
I don't really understand either.
Same here.
Why isn't he part of the group?
Are you serious?
I don't believe it!
So, why don't you hurry up and tell us.
Talk about annoying!!
No way!!
You're the last person I'm going to tell!!
So there! ,
Since you guys are not curious and young,
I guess you'll never find out!
Where are you going?
To the ladies room!
If you can't figure it out till the time
I come back, I'll drop-you a hint.
She makes me so mad!!
And?
Curious lady of Suzuki Financial Group,
do you happen to know what it's about?
Beat me.
Don't you think this place is
getting crowded?
Probably because of the fireworks!
Oh, you mean the one that goes up
every night at 7:00?
Yep! This rink is a special place where
you can see the fireworks and
Oh, you're quite knowledgeable!
I'm not going to watch it like always.
I'll go get a cup of coffee nearby.
I've seen the fireworks many times.
Huh? You're not going to watch either?
I'm a bit hungry
I'll come back before the fireworks start,
so wait there for me.
Wait here? I've been waiting to go to
the restroom for a while now
You may go!
We'll be skating nearby
for a while yet so.
When your friends come all we have to
do is tell them to wait here, right?
Yes, I'm sorry to trouble you.
I'll be:right back,
so could you do.that for me...?
Sure!
Hey, hey...
It's already 6:55pm.
What oniearth are .you'doing?
The fireworks will start
If you don't hurry up!
They're all so late.
Uh-huh
Sorry, Ran,
I gotta go to the restroom too.
Oh no!!
You're late!
Huh?
To the restroom, restroom.
Huh? What's wrong?
Look at this!
FOES
Cleaning
kOotehisSo bk
It can't be...
Wait a sec...
What's the use of saying the accident
back then was my fault at this point.
Aha, ha...
besides,
no matter how much you hide
your face with that outfit, if you shoot me
people will hear you and gather here,
then you'll be:arrested right away.
Huh!
Don't tellfme that...
Uh, excuse me.
Are you going to take a while longer?
If it's not this toilet, I'll have
to change shoes.
Huh?
Oh, no...
Hey, the fireworks have started already!
Where? Where?
Oh, well...
Hmm?!
Huh?
Wow, how beautiful!.
Really,
the first ones are the most fantastic.
Huh? So, you came to watch after all?!
Yes...
I thought it'd be nice to watch fireworks
once in a great while.
I made it!!
I thought I wastgoing t $miss it...
\Hey!
Where are Chihiro and your friend?
Huh?
Didn't you see them at the restroom?
I wonder if I missed them?
They were.cleaning-the restroom,
so I changed shoes and went to a
different restroom.
Sonoko sure is late, though...
Kyaaaah...
Hey, that scream just now sounded like...
Sonoko?!
Hey!
Sonoko!
What's up?!
What's the matter, Sonoko?!
T...That...
Ah!!
,- 3000000
Dad!!
Huh?!
Dad! Get:up!
Dad!!
Hmm?
What is it, Ran?
I thought you wanted to
Ieave after watching the fireworks?
There's no time for that!!
There's been a murder!! Homicide!!
A person's been killed in the restroom
near the skating rink!!
Huh?
Someone slipped and fell in the
restroom near the skating rink?
Hmm?!
Just come!!
Hurry!!
Why was Chihiro killed?
Police is here!
Please let us through!!
All right! All right!
Everyone except authorized
personnel move back!!
Whaaa!!
How ruthless...
Yes indeed...
There's nobody inside, is there?
No, when we got here
this boy was in here...
Hmm?
Conan?!
Which means? Don't tell me that...
Well, this is a coincidence,
Just a mere coincidence!
Please don't get angry,
Inspector Megure!
Ha, ha...
I don't have the energy to get angry.
Inspector!
It seems that this shotgun is the
murder weapon!
Right, okay,
check the registration number
of the gun and find the owner of the gun.
That gun is mine.
It's the shotgun I use for Clay shooting,
I left it in the electronic
Iock locker with everyone else's...
Everyone else's?
Yes,
the three behind you are members of
the Clay shooting.
Who locked the electronic locker?
Hmm...
Everybody knows the number to locker.-
When we all came here before,
we all decided on the number together.
T's"9017".
Well, checking you four,
for gun powder reaction,
we'll find out soon enough.
All four of us will definitely have reaction!
We all went Clay shooting this afternoon.
Besides, maybe the locker wasn't locked
as it should've been too.
If so, somebody other than us could've
taken the shotgun out of the locker and...
No, I don't think that's possible.
Have you forgotten?
It's our duty to make sure
that the case with the shotgun inside
doesn't look like something
that contains a gun.
Izumi's gun case is a plain leather case.
Moreover the shotgun is disassembled,
so it's not something
just anybody can handle.
I see
so it has to be someone who knows
that there is a shotgun inside the case
Moreover, it has to be one who can
assemble the gun...
Which means that the most likely
suspect would still be among you four.
Oh well,
go and check immediately to see if
there were any suspicious person
near the toilet around the time
was committed!
Yes, sir!
Uh...
I saw someone...
What?!
What?
The killer come out of this restroom...
Are you sure, Sonoko?
Uh-huh...
A sign that read "Cleaning" was hung on
the door of the restroom
There was no answer when I knocked
SO...
I was waiting in front of the door...
Then the fireworks started
I pulled away from the door,
I tried to look at the fireworks from a
window nearby.
It was at that moment!
A strange person wearing a long coat
came out of the toilet!!
Did you see the face of that person?
No...
the face was covered with the hood
and a scarf...
If the killer shot the gun and muffled
it with the sound of fireworks and
wore a long coat as disguise
when fleeing,
be planned murder!!
Please come to another room so that
I.can separately ask you questions.
Then we can figure out who suggested
to come to this amusement park.
Hey, just a minute!
We all decided
togethento come here!
Well, you can talk more about
it during questioning...
No, that's not necessary!
What"?!
It hit upon me the minute
I came to the scene.
But, Sonoko's remark just now
verified my feelings.
The one who shot
Ms. Itami to death is...
Ms. Sano
What!
You.
Don't be ridiculous!
Why me?
There are three factors
why you areithe killer
First, is this restroom which is the
scene of the crime...
You got the people to move away using
the "Cleaning" sign.
Then you kept the victim inside.
In other words, you promised
to meet her here...
That:is,
the killer is a woman!!
@@eoecer
t@voooe
'tecpser
Second is your relationship
with the victim.
You both just couldn't get along with
each other,
isn't that right?
What're you talking about?
Are you going to
set me up as the killer just like that?
Lastly, the most conclusive evidence is
the trace of blood on the wall beside
the face of the victim.
Trace of blood?
To you, it like the trace of blood that
was made when the victim struggled...
But, it was clearly legible to my eyes.
Left behind before she ceased
to breathe.
Her dying message!!
The "SS" of the name Sano!!!
I asked you for your name before the
Inspector got here, didn't 1?
The only one who
has the letter "SS" in the name is you!!!
Is that not right?
I don't think so!!
Hmm? Huh?!
I think you can tell just by looking,
the victim has been shot in the chest
and has died on the spot.
Therefore,
it would've been impossible for
her to write a message on the wall
fter she was shot...
I guess you're right...
Besides,
If one says that a woman had relayed
a message telling him to wait here,
the person could've been a man.
Then, the letter "SS" is.
Yes,
someone left it there to set
Ms. Sano up as the killer!
Besides, the shotgun that was used as
the murder weapon was also hers.
But, doesn't something bother you?
Sonoko knocked the door just before the
murder was committed, didn't she?
If the killer had the gun pointed at the
victim while before fireworks went up,
why didn't she shout and call for help?
The killer was probably hiding
In the toilet next door,
until just before the fireworks went up
Something sticky is on it.
See, at the tip of the gun.
T,This is saliva!!
I get it! The killer had the gun
the victim's mouth for a while until the
fireworks went up!!
And simultaneous to the fireworks going
up the gun was moved to her chest...
If so,
then we three are not the killer!
Because we were with her at the skating
rink before the fireworks went up.
Isn't that right, Ran?
Uh, yes...
Were they really with you from the start?
It doesn't take 30 seconds from here
IS restroom to the rink...
But, all three of them were here when the
fireworks went up the first time.
It was no more than 10 seconds between
the first fireworks and the second...
And,where were you then?
I was by the bench near the rink,
with my back turned against the
fireworks and smoking.
He's the only one without an alibi.
But, we still have no proof.
We don't know his relationship
with the victim yet, either.
But, it's easy to tell that
she doesn't like being cold.
She's about to be shot, and yet she
has her hand in her pocket!
A cellular phone?
Here is nothing on the display.
Maybe she was shot
before dialing 911...
Why don't you try re-dialing?
Then, maybe you can find out
where she called last?
Yeah...
Iet's give it a try...
'Huh?!
Eight "#sin the telephone number row...
She probably tried to search her way
through the numbers and failed.
KIX?
K-1-X.
Wait a sec.
I remember this from somewhere...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihitko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS YOF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyanta: /'Shogdkukan
II Rights Reserved
S,Suicide?!
Wasn't that:supposed be an accident...?
It's a lie that she always uses to get
herself out of hot water!!
Don't tell me that's a dying message
Ieft behind by the victim!!
Herefore, the killer...
IS none other than you!!
Dying Message Revives" Part 2