Just as flowing water has no form
and the breeze 1s invisible
deductions take all shapes-and styles
in each and every case to be solved
A very strange message
The trick is solved
and the killer is determined
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved when Detective
Conan comes to the scene
Like always, keeping Sonoko company
in her search for men we all come to
the skating rink at Tropical Land
There, we meet 5 members of the Clay
shooting club and get acquainted
While we're all waiting for
the firework to go up
mSonoko's scream is heard
from the restroom
Kyaaah!
I runfover to find .
Waiting there...
the dead body of Chizu Itami,
who is shot to death in the chest...
#000000
the dead body of Chizuéltamp
who is shot to death in the chest...
Thexdead body of Chizu Itami,
Since the letter "SS" written in blood is
Ieft near the corpse, Pops deduces that
the "S" stands for Izumi Sano's last name
so that she is the killer. However...
I don't think so!!
Hmm?! Huh?
I think you can tell just by looking,
the victim has been shot in the chest
and has died on the spot
Therefore, it would've been impossible
for her
to write a message on the wall
after she was shot
Moreover, the letter WKIX" were
registered
In the cellular phone
of the victim
K.I.X...wait a sec...l remember this from
somewhere...
Dying Message Revives" Part ll
KIX... I'm sure I've seen it somewhere...
Officer!!
May I at least change shoes?
I came straight from the rink
Oh, if you let an officer escort you,
that be no problem
But, please make sure
you come right back
Hey, Officer Chiba,
will you please escort them?
Oh, yes sir!!
Don't cry, Yoriko...
Chihiro's been killed...
You know...Yoriko...
nm sure e oO cers wi wO In er.
Stupid!...
Sonoko?
That cellular that you have is
is the same as the one
the lady that was killed had!
Don't tell me that this kid is...
suspecting me?
What?!
No! I just want to have a look at your
cellular phone
Here
Come on, Conan...
Yiourtshouldn't be fooling around with it!
The sound of the fireworks you heard,
was it really the sound of fireworks?
Yes, of course!
It went "hyuuuuh" then,
I heard one big boom!
Huh?
Huh? Did you change your cellular,
Sonoko?
Es, well sort of...
Locker Room
I've more or less figured out the trick...
But...anybody could've committed the
murder if this trick were used...
In order to figure out who did it...
Pull yourself together
I just happened to remember
that incident...
Yoriko...
I envy you, Izumi
because you weren't at Clay shooting
when that accident happened
I was sick in bed on that day, remember?
I wish you wouldn't call that lucky
I'm quitting Clay shooting as of today.
I can't help feeling that there is a curse
Besides, I don't want to die because of
the gun accidentally going off,
Iike what happened to Narita
Huh?!
Enough of all the small talk,
Let's go back.
Yeah? .
I get it...so that's what it was...
That's why he wasialways left out!!
But, I've still got no proof
If couldn't possibly corner the killer with
that message alone...
Hmm?
Two black dots...
on't tell me that... :
What?!.
Conan?
Huh!
It can't be?!
Don't tell me... 7?!
I don't believe it?!
Hey...
There 1t 1st
This is it!!
I've found it!! I've found conclusive
evidence!!
With this I can corner the killer!!
A h...
Just what are you doing here...?
Ha, ha, ha...
Qmhg
I tell you! Stop using the scene of the
crime as a playground...
Inspector Megure!
Hmm?!
This coat, thought to be that of the killer
was found in the trash can
that is located between the skating rink
and the restroom
Okay, verify it with Sonoko who witnessed
the killer!
Yes, sir!! Okay!
Uh, everyone; wait!
Where are you all going?
We're going to return the skates...
You can question us after that, can't you?
We've all got alibis that we were watching
the fireworks at the time of the crime...
Yes...the alibis of everyone except Oda
who's not interested in fireworks...
I'm sure glad I watched the fireworks...
If I didn't watch it as usual,
I would've been suspected too.
Izumi...
It's true, isn't it!
Okay, first I'll put Pops to sleep with the
anesthesia, gun...
Let's not play games anymore...
huh?
Let's get things straight, since the answer
s already obvious...
IN... No, Pops...
Oh! Have you figured out who the killer is?
Yes...this time for sure
The one who waited for Chihiro
in the restroom
and killed her with the shotgun is...
Mr. Kunitomo Oda!
Yes, you!!
Uh?! No...
Hey! Wait a minute!
You ran into the wrong guy...
Leaving a dying message written in blood,
near the victim attempting to fool me
But, too bad!!
You were completely deceived,
weren't you?
That letter was written by you.
A person who was shot in the chest and
died on the spot
couldn't possibly have written it...
And, the comment that Ms. Izumi Sano
made just now, brought everything to light
That the killer had calculated on framing
Ms. Sano up as the killer
by committing the crime
when the fireworks go up
so that Ms. Sano, who usually does not
watch ends up without an alibi...
The letter "S" from her name was used
as well as her gun, for this reason!
However...she unfortunately decides to
watch the fireworks.
So, you end up being
the one without an alibi
Your scheme collapsed...
Oh no...
Ha-hi-fu-he-ho. #4
As a result, the killer lead us to believe
that Mr. Oda was the killer
and successfully was removed from
the hist of suspects.
This indeed was
what the killer was after.
Then, who on earth is the killer?!
The one who killed Chihiro Itami is,
Ieaving Mr. Oda aside
one of the members of
the Clay shooting club...
is you!!
The one who killed Chihiro Itami is,
Ieaving Mr. Oda aside,
one of the members of
the Clay shooting club...
You! Izumi Sano!!
Izumi...?
S...You used your own g
and left that letter written with blood
in order to mislead us...
A Killer would never leave his own shotgun
or an initial pointing to him
at the scene of the crime...
You took advantage of this psychology
and set a trap!
You moved the mouth of the gun from her
mouth down to her chest
because you wanted the letter writte Tin
blood to look real
A person who is shot in the head
would never be able to write on the wall...
What're you talking about?
I was watching the fireworks with Ran
from the very beginning
If the murder was committed
when the fireworks went up,
I would've been possible for me
to carry it out!
That is, if the murder was really committed
when the fireworks went up...
Will you cut it out!
Don't you remember what Sonoko said?
That when the fireworks went up, the killer
was still in the restroom!
No... The sound that Sonoko heard was
not the sound of the fireworks,
but rather the sound of
a shotgun being fired!
Don't be ridiculous...
There's no way a person can mistake
the sound fireworks with that of a shotgun.
Boom!
Huh?
Well? Did that sound like fireworks?
But, how did you do it...7?
This, with this!
Hmm?
A five yen coin?!
She puts it between her lips and
whistles.
The sound gets loud and hoarse
and sounds like that of fireworks!
It did kind of sound. something like that...
Right, Pops!
If only the shotgun were used,
it wouldn't sound like fireworks
But, if one is expecting the sound of
fireworks,
and the time of the show beginning was
approaching...
Under the circumstances back then,
it's understandable that
Sonoko would be deceived...
As proof, Sonoko mentioned that
only one burst of fireworks went up.
However, the fireworks actually started
with three successive shots of
red, blue and yellow
That's right, isn't it, Sonoko?
1 CO...
Uh-huh...
It was lucky that...
Sonoko coincidentally
happened to be in front of the restroom
It seems there were 2 or 3
other people there too
This is the only restroom you can use
wearing skates
It is predictable that with the "Cleaning"
sign hung on the door,
2 or 3 people will wait...
In other words, Ms. Sano promised to
meet Chihiro in the restroom...
She drives people away by hanging the
Cleaning sign at the entrance,
then she locks the entrance door.
She holds the shotgun that she had taken
out of the locker
and head for the restroom
where Chihiro was waiting
You pointed the gun at her about a minute
before the fireworks
were about to be set off
made the sound with the five yen coin,
and fired the gun.
After that you wrote the letter "SS" with
and rushed back to the rink
before the real fireworks went up
in order to set Oda who was not
interested in fireworks up as the killer.
Hey, 1s that true, Izumi?
Izumi.
I guess so...if I do so, it's true I could've
committed the murder
But, how can you say it was me? The other
three could've used the:same trick tool!
Izumi?!
I don't know who you are but,
will you cut out all your nonsense...!
KX...
Huh?
Do you.know what this means?
Oh...the letters that Chihiro randomly
input in her cellular?
No, she didn't input them randomly
She probably input these letters
in her cellular
while you were blocking her mouth
with the gun
Then she kept pressing the arrow button
to send out her message!
She hoped that we would eventually
press the re-dial button
and find out what she did
I see! That's why the row for telephone
numbers were filled with #"!
Pressing:on the arrow button displays
the "#" symbol
Hey...which means that the letters on the
display of the cellular are...
are the real dying message?!
So what?
Is K.I.X supposed to be my name or
something?
I heard that Chihiro said...
That Oda is always left out of your group.
What are you trying to get at...?
The name of the victim is Itami...
The two who are behind are
Komatsu and Misawa
Your name is lzumi Sano.
You still don't get it?
Would putting it this way, help you then?
The name of your friend who died of an
accident 6 months ago was...
r. Narita...
I get it! Airport!!
All your names are names of where
airports are located!!
Is there an airport in Sano City though?
Ight...Besides, I can't see how it I
connected to K.I.X...
Huh!
Ahhhh!!
Yes... K.ll.X. is the three-letter-code for the
Kansai International Airport!
It refers to the airport that is located
In Izumi Sano City in Osaka...
Now, do you understand Ms. [zum
But, that could be a message that
the killer used to frame me!
If I show you this, it may convince you
A strange blood stain the was on the floor
near the victim's left toe...
What?
Blood stain?
Hmm?
That is the trace of the blade of the skates
that was left behind
that Ms. Sano touched after
she finished writing the letter in blood
She still hasn't realized that the same
blood stain was left on the corridor
that she fled along
That Chihiro's blood is still left on the blade
of her own skates!
I see the name of the location of an airport
Just as would be expected of a Ms. Rich
who is still living off her parents and
traveling around...
Then, you did kill Chihiro after all?
But, but...why...
Narita...
Narita?
I avenged Narita's death by killing Chihiro
who lead him to commit suicide
Suicide
But...l thought...that was an accident...
was brushed off by Chihiro...
That day...
And he pulled the trigger himself...
And, it was mistakenly concluded that
he accidentally died
while he was checking his gun.
I told him repeatedly to forget her.
But, why kill Chihiro because of something
Iike that...
If he just committed suicide because
he was brushed off, I wouldn't have done this!
I went over board because I found out that
somebody was two timing!!
Two-timing?
Yes... that day, I was sick in bed.
I got a call from Narita...
He said that his best friend
had betrayed him...
That odarwas going with Chihiro...
He sounded like he wasichokingiin tears
Huh? But wasn't Oda going with you,
Izumi, back then?
Right! This guy knew how Narita felt about
Chihiro,
and yet he had the nerve to two-time
Chihiro and me, snickering at us...
hat's not true...
She just did what she usual does to keep
herself out of hot water
Then, why didn't you tell Narita that over the
phone that day!!
He said he asked you but you were aloof
and didn't lend him an ear...
Yeah...l know it sounds wretched, but his
words didn't reach me...
Because I was concerned about:you;
being sick in bed that day...
Maybe it would've been better for me to
have been shot by you...
We'll hear the rest of your story
at the station.
Hey...
Is it okay for me to believe what you just
said? No matter how far apart we are...
Yeah, don't worry...
I'm very grudgeful and persistent.
Thank you.
ORIGINAL COMMIT BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Mi Hihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunar! Knuth:
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS YOF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DET LCTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogdkukan
Il Rights Reserved
Is it okay for me to believe what you
said?
No matter how far apart we are
What's this, a young girl acting
Iike an old...
Will you be quiet, because you don't have
the slightest idea how I feel!!
Oh, the phone call.
Oh yes, hello?
I won! I won! Sonoko!!
I've won the championship*of the Winter
Karate:Tournament!!
There sure are unimaginably strong fighters
in the world
You idiot!!
Idiot! Why didn't you call me
sooner.!
I sent you my phone number
2 months ago!!
Oh...I'm sorry...I didn't want to call you
and have nothing to say
Um, you know...
Sonoko, I hear that the cold is going
around in Japan,
so please don't go out
wearing short skirts, okay?
I'm wearing something real long
today too...
Just as I thought!
Sonoko seems to have bought
another cellular phone just for Mr. Kyogoku
I guess so
A telephone just for two...How nice...
few-days later...
I sent Ran a cellular phone
as a token of my appreciation for the
sweater
At first, she seemed to be puzzled
But, she seemed happy at the same
Ce so I guess I did the right th
Three people turned themselves in saying
they committed the murder...
Accomplices...?
There is only one victim and yet there are
three people saying they killed him!
Very Interesting...!!
The Man Who Was Killed Four Times"