Just as flowing water has no form
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
He sees through to the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult,
No case is left unsolved
when Detective Conan comes to the scene.
MURDER ON THE 5.5. SYMPHONY
20 YEAR VENDETTA
2 NA TL
I've figured it all out...
now all I have to do is prove it...
Oh excuse me
We're looking boy
who speaks with a kansai dialect
That kid asked us the same thing
and we've been looking for him too
but we-can't find him anywhere...
Sorry, Dr. Agata!
I can't talk now.
I'll call you later.
Eh?!
Wh, what did you say
We'll get the entire. crew #
to search the:ship.again
I'd appreciate:that
Good: grief. . what are youtdoing here?
Oh uh...nothing'...
I'm getting worried,
where didlhe go to anyway?
Who re you talking:about?
Are ou serious?
Heiji, of course!
Oh.4 him?
He's probably swimming
with the fishes somewhere
Mouri...
This guy... might just be...
I know what you m
Huh?
# Sf \
Dad?
Sir? What's wrong?
What're you doing?
Dad?
Ran,
tell all the others:to come here!
I've figured everything out.
Go on, hurry!
You what... 7?!
Is-that true?
You've solved the case'?
That's right... I've figured everything out
the entire truth behind this case...
You're not going to say that
Kanie's not the killer, are you?
Kanie is the Kil
Like you said, he pretended to be dead
then lay in wait
for a chance to kill...
Mr. Kuijirai, that was you!
Then whose body is that set on fire?
It's Mr. Kameda
Mr. Kanie lured Mr. Kameda out
and shot him then hid the body inside
the emergency ladder box at the
bow and returned to join the others
Then he set the flag on
the upper deck on fire
And when everyone ran up to
the deck, he set fire to the box...
The reason why he didn't
change Mr. Kameda's clothes
as soon as he was put in the box is,
he was waiting for the Superintendent
to giveyup the search for
the old man named Kano
it takes a Ion \time to dress someone
he couldn't risk being seen
by the Superintendent
And the proof is the way the victim's
arms were up beside his face!
If you raise the arms when
putting the body into the box,
even after rigor mortis sets in,
dressing the body is easy
And the reason the watch
wasn't clasped was,
his watchqprobably dfdnét fiflMrrKameda.
Before setting the fire,
Mr. Kanie called
Mr. Kujirai out to the stern
and tried to set him up as the killer...
Because the first person
found hanging around
a crime scene usually
viewed as a strong suspect
But why?
Why did he have to make it
Iook like he was dead?
He wanted to surprise his next victim,
which was Mr. Kujirai, and fill him with fear
He wanted vengeance against the men
who betrayed him 20 years ago...
Be...trayed?
Yes! That old man
named Kano was also
a ruse to scare the men,
the old man did not really exist...
Look at this,
the wound on Mr. Kanie's body
This old bullet wound is the very proof!
You..don't mean...
That's right!
This is Saizo Kano
the man everyone thought
died 20 years ago,
the Mastermind in the shadows!
You're lying...
it can't be...
I don't believe you...
You're lying...
this man couldn't possibly be Saizo Kano...
Because... Kano is... Kano is...
is my father!
Y...your father...?
That's right
Saizo;Kano, the Mastermind
in the shadows. is my real father...
The reason I joined this tour is
I wanted to find him
it was rumored he was killed
20 years ago by his accomplices
but I thought that maybe...
he was still alive...
but no one here reminded me of him
But... what if he'd had plastic surgery
and changed his appearance?
Don't be ridiculous!
I'd recognize him
no matter how he looked!!
Do you think I couldn't
recognize my own father?!
And it'd be the same with him!
If he saw me? you'd
know by his:reaction!!
20 years may have gone by...
but it we'd know each other...
That's exactly what I wanted to hear...
Forgive me Nagisa...
I had my suspicions but I needed proof...
So that I could completely
destroy the killer's plan...
The killer's plan...?
The killer rigged it to look ll
Mr.Kanie shot Mr. Kameda,
dressed him in his
clothes and set him on fire,
this would make us think
he faked his death
and hid somewhere firing shots
Ieading us on wild goose chases
but after failing in his
attempt to kill Mr. Kujirau,
and realizing he could not escape
he killed himself, that was the scenario
It was all a ruse to make us believe
Mr. Kanie was Saizo Kano
so that the killings on this ship were to
carry out a vendetta against the men
who betrayed him 20 years ago
Then . you mean. the killers...
That's right...it's someone else...
and he's right here!!
Oh come on now...
what are you talking about Mourn
You know for yourself
When the explosion went off at the bow
all the passengers here
were on the upper deck!
And all the other crew
members have alibis...
besides, you said so yourself, you'd
need a timing device to have set it off
So how can you...
I found it!
I found the timing device
You found it? In there???
He used a cigarette...
He »laced a li hted ci arette
in the space in the box
just over the can of gasoline
If you wind it with thread,
it'll take about 10 minutes
for the thread to burn
The cigarette will fall inside
And a fire will start automatically
But then...
how do you explain the 4 shots
that came from the bow
and the 2 from the prow?
Even then all of us here were
He used a cigarette then too...
He probably taped some fireworks
with a cigarette to the railing
That way, after it explodes, the
evidence will fall into the ocean...
There were burn marks on the railing
and some paint had been off,
that proves my theory!
By the way, regarding the flag
burning on the upper deck,
he used the same trick,
first soaking the flag in gasoline then
attaching the cigarette with fireworks...
Which means, by using this method
Anyone could have
committed the crime...
Uh... .er...
So who did it!
Who did all that!
It's...oh geez...
it's too late!
What was that!
There was an explosion in the rear!
Stop all engines! All
stations check for damages!
Lower deck! Any damages?
No damages!
No need to worry
The bomb went off about 100 meters
behind the ship, that's all...
100 meters behind the ship?
Was that a bomb?!
Just to be on the safe side
We put it on a rubber boat
which we tied a rope to,
the other end was attached
to the ratlin on the bow
then we let it out on the ocean...
Mr. Ebina...
Yes, it was the bomb
we found in your trunk!
Eh?!
Trunk ..7?
How... how did you know...7?7
Your room was very clean,
even your sheets were unwrinkled...
and your trunk looked like
it hadn't even been opened,
then when I noticed how
concerned you were about the time,
it made me suspicious...
That bomb was probably meant
to kill all the members of
that robbery 20 years ago,
you prepared it a long
time ago, didn't you...
You wanted to avenge the death
of your co-worker didn't you?!
Co-worker?
The distinctive way he counted money,
indicated he worked in a bank.
Also, he whispered the name
of the female bank teller
who was killed in the robbery
Yoshimi Samezaki...
She wasn't just another co-worker...
she was...she was the most
important thing in the world to me...
You mean you're...
you're the one who cried so
Ioudly at my daughter's funeral...
Yes, that's rightly
I quit the bank that day,
I've been going from job to job ever since
Iooking for those killers in my own way!!
Even after the statute
of limitations ran out...
I see...so it was you...
So you're the special person
she asked me to meet...
If...if only you'd ve have... .that day...
If only you'd come to the
bank like you promised!
She...she'd probably...oh God...
Forgive me...
one of my men was stabbed that day
I heard about what happened...
when I was at the hospital...
You saw that ad in the paper
and joined the tour too.
Yes... thought this might be it...
if 1 was wrong...l intended to throw
the trunk into the ocean
before the bomb went off...
Sot was you?
Did you kill all those men
involved with the robbery?
No..it wasn't mel! I didn't do
I brought a bomb with me!
I don't own a gun!
It's the truth! Please believe me!
It's alright...l believe you...
I know you're not the killer...
Like I said before, to set
Mr.Kanie up as the killer,
one had to make this seem like
Saizo Kano's act of vengeance,
or it wouldn't seem plausible...
the reason the killer disguised himself
as an old man then left the ship
and returned as someone else is,
he wanted to create the illusion
that Saizo Kano was alive.
He left a message on
the bill hinting of Kano
on the upper deck
This was all part of
his plan to make us think
Kano was trying to scare
the men who betrayed him...
And all of this was so that we would think
that the gunshot wound on Mr.Kanie's
body was the wound Mr. Kano got
when he was shot by one of
his accomplices 20 years ago!
You mean. ..that wound...
He probably got that when he served
in the foreign army long ago...
Remember, one of the
suspects was reported
to have served in an foreign army
And... he was one of the accomplices...
so that means
Yes, the only one who could
use that fact in this scheme
IS someone-whq8knew
about Mr Kanie's wound...
ou don't mean...
One of his old partners!
Mr. Kujirai! You're 'the
only one, aren'tfyou?
Th...that's insane... .haha...
First, you saw Mr. Kameda
Ieave the restaurant
then you mentioned
Saizo Kano's name
in the excitement, you
went to the engine room
where you had told Mr. Kameda
to wait and you shot him!
Then you hid his body
in the box on the stern
He was killed in the engine room?
Yes... I've already found
blood stains, a shell casing
and the letter he used to lure
Mr. Kameda in the engine room
You probably slipped the
Ietter under the cabin door...
Mr: .Kujirai came back to the lounge
waited for the Superintendent
to call off the search for Kano
then went to meet with Mr. Kanie
probably in the restroom
next to the restaurant.
Mr. Kanie was probably already
asleep due to being drugged...
then you stole his
clothes and his wristwatch
and put them on Mr. Kameda
then set up that timing device...
The reason why you deliberately
called attention to yourself
and had the crew see you, was
to make them see the box
was not on fire then
and also to give us the impression you
were called out there to meet someone...
The reason why you left the note
in the trash can in the restroom,
was to pretend to be afraid of Kano
and have us think
he was coming after you...
You were probably going to say
that it was in that book of matches
It was all to make us believe
Mr. Kanie was behind everything
that he had lured you out...
You set the cigarette device on the flag
before you changed
the clothes on the body...
that way, you could run up with
everyone when we heard the explosion
we would be your alibi...
You moved Mr. Kanie who was
sleeping, from the restroom to the prow
while we were all concentrating
on the burning body at the stern...
Then you watched our movements
after some time had passed,
you placed another device at the stern
after hearing the sound,
while we went running,
you went back to the prow
pulled Mr. Kanie back up and shot him.
Then you shot yourself
and fired another shot
through the window into the restaurant
After that, all you had to do was set
2 more devices and you were ready!
You came back to the stern and
had us all gather in the restaurant
where you gave us your false confession
and waited for the
explosions to go off
If you fell at the first explosion
it would look like the shot
came from the prow!
Wait a minute, hold it right there, Mouri!
I was with him
when he fell and I saw
the wound right then.
If he shot himself earlier,
there'd be more blood...
He used a tennis ball!
Before he shot himself in the arm,
he had the tennis ball
pressed against his artery
it was to stop the flow of blood!
He held it there tightly
until the explosion went off...
Ran found the ball under
the table in the restaurant.
He probably threw it there in the
confusion after the second explosion
But why didn't he kill Mr. Kanie
when he first took him to the prow?
If Mr. Kanie committed suicide
right after we found the burned body,
the killer's trick would seem unnatural...
The trick with disguising
the body with Mr. Kanie's clothes!
The reason he raised the body's arms
and unclasped the watch
was to create an illusion!
And he hired Heiji Hattor)
the private detective
from Osaka for the same reason!
Of course Mr. Kujirai probably figured
we'd to do our jobs as detectives as well
But you hired a private
detective from Osaka
because you lived in Osaka, didn't you?!
When people who live in the Kanto
area put cards back into the case
we don't use the term fix...
So that's how you knew...
now all we need is evidence...
You'll probably find it when you check
the area around the shattered glass,
you'll get a luminol reaction...
There'll be just a trace but
you'll find some smears from
when he wiped the blood
that splattered when he shot himself...
No! It wasn't me!!!
What?!
This is a trap!
Someone set this trap to frame me!
Why you!
Don't try to fool us!
That star...sure is beautiful...
What?!
Huh? What is that?
What is that strange star
approaching from the left?
What is that?
Look! Isn't that...
It's Heiji!
That's right... he found Mr. Kanie tied to
the prow but you knocked him out
and threw him overboard, he's our witness!
Oh... .rats...
You cant deny anything
any more. Mr. Kujiral?
But how did you figure it all out?
That Kanie wasn't the real killer?
The watch
The watch's stem is on the opposite side
because it's made for a right handed
person but it was put on his left hand,
at that point, I crossed
Mr. Kanie off as a suspect
You tried to make him look like you
but you were made a big mistake
by putting the watch on wrong
You were done in by
your partner's expensive watch...
By the way, it was also Mr. Kujirai who
put the ad for this tour in the paper
You all probably decided 20 years ago
that on the day the statue
of limitations runs out,
you'd place;an ad in the paper
under the name of Masaru Furukawa...
The reason the 3 got together was
were going to get the money they
put into a safe deposit 20 years ago...
To take the money out of the safe
deposit box you rented 20 years ago,
you needed the key,
the seal and the signature...
You 3 each had one of the items,
it would also be your identification
when you met each
other after all those years
after having plastic surgery done
Mr. Kujirai'whoiwas.in charge
of the signature,
saw the seal and key
Mr. Kameda and Kanie displayed nonchalantly
so he knew right away who they were
and he immediattely set his plan in motion
I...
after killing them, stole the key and seal,
he intended to take
the money all for himself...
What a fool...
the statute of limitations had run out
he went through'so much trouble...
I wanted to win...
I thought up a perfect plan...
but that Saizo Kano...
20 years ago, he said
Your plan is full of loopholes..."
I wanted to outdo him!!
But I don't understand!
Why are there so many people involved
with that case all over this ship?!
I didn't even mention the
name Kano once in the ad...
You mean...you didn't know
what Masaru Furukawa meant?
It's the nickname Kano used,
he said there were just a few
strokes so it was easy to remember
so we were to use it when we
needed to contact each other...
No one except us is
supposed to know about it...
Hahahaha, this is hilarious!
Turn-the name sideways!
It becomes Saizo Kano!
What?!
That's why I joined this tour.
Also the statute of limitations
ran out of that day...
I had my doubts but...
Masaru Furukawa was Kano's alias
which he picked intending to be funny!!
No way!
You were never
any match for Kano...
After all, for the past 20 years
Kano had you by the coat tails...
( RI ¢INAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
Masato Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi hoka
CRIPTS BY.
Kanji Kasimwabara
Razunari Xouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Ti¥kashi Nomura
Hi onobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
OGUsho Aoyarrfa / Shogdkukan
YTV / TMS
II Rights Reserved
What?! You fell in the ocean?!
You're kidding .
It's no joke!
Someone pushed me from behind and I fell in!
Didn't you notice I was gone You're cold!
But...you were lucky, you're alive!
Whenil"was:floating in the ocean,
that fishing boat captain found me!
It was awful!
I had to take all my clothes off in water
and use my flashlight to signal
ships sailing faraway
Worry a little!
You...took your clothes off?
Of course! Wet clothes soak up
so much water so they're heavy!
If I didn't take them off, I'd ve drowned!
The only thing I kept was my pants and
this thing I forgot I had in my pocket...
this here amulet
Il don't Know whether
it really works or not though...
Wh, what're you staring at me for .,!
Come now, don't play dumb!
You were looking at the amulet
Kazuha gave you all dreamy eyed...
No I wasn't.
This amulet's bad luck, I was
thinking of throwing it away!
But I didn't want something bad to
happen, that's why I'm holding on to it!