Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
In each and every case to be solved.
He sees through to the one and only truth.
A child in appearance wtih the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
when Detective Conan comes to the scene.
MURDER ON THE 5.5. SYMPHONY
20 YEAR VENDETTA
- J At, TN
I would never have thought Hattori.
That. you were interested in dolphins!
Rolwins (dolphins)?
Yes, didn't you come here after
reading the ad in the newspaper?
Nope! No way! I'm here
because I got a strange letter!
A strange letter.
Yeah, about a week ago...
I received a letter saying
someone wanted to hire me
so I was to go to Ogasawara...
There was 100,000 yen
in there for my fee...
100,000 yen?
That's right, but you know
it was pretty weird,
all the bills were the old design,
and there was no return address.
What about a name?
Masaru Furukawa was written.
Furukawa?!
Oh, so you know who he is?
What are you talking about,
«<P»
Furukawa is the name of the man
who planned this whole tour!
Is that so? I had no idea.
The letter told me I'd be able to get
aboard if I showed the bill at the gate
that's all...
So Heiji, you were invited on board
to work as a private investigator...
I've never taken a job
where I got paid first so
I intended to return the money
personally, that's why I got on board...
Besides, I was pretty interested in
what kind of case it was...
But what a coincedence!
Here we are, all on the same ship!
Actually, I called you when
I got to Haneda Airport
I thought I'd ask Kudo... I mean
r. Mouri to come with me...
But...no one answered the phone...
We must have just left
Butlhere we are anyway...
That's why they say
monkeys will attract monkeys and private
investigators will attract their lot too, huh!
Right, kiddo!
So you're the other private investigator?
You're awfully young...
That ll am!
And so, have you found that
so called Saizo Kano fellow?
No, I think they're still looking for him
Here...
You want to use this?
Thanks, I appreciate it...
No problem, just ask...
Hey, why don't we all play some poker?
We can go to the lounge over there
Good idea, but what about cards?
Don't worry, I brought a deck with me.
How about you fellows?
You look like you need
some entertainment.
Find him?
No...he isn't anywhere!
Ats... where'd he disappear to
We have less than a hour...
Mourl...
Yes!
I'm not giving up...
not on this case, not until
the very last second...
I swear!!
Superintendent Samezaki!
Let's search one more time!!
Yes, you're right,
Iet's go over the ship one more time
Mouri, from top to bottom!
Ro er!
Tada!
Full house
Good grief, you won again...
Alright! Alright!
After the next game,
whoever has the lowest score will
change places with Mr. Kujirai.
Excuse me,
do you know what time it is?
Yes, it's 11:55 pm.
You've been asking
the time so many times,
are you expecting something?
It's just that tomorrow's...
a very special day...
There, 2 pairs, aces & nines
I'm the loser...
Alright, Mr. Kujira's turn up next.
Alright now girlie, be gentle with me.
Hey, when you said tomorrow's
a special day, did you mean
The anniversary of your girlfriend's death?
Your cocktail
It's a Bloody Mary, isn't it?
Don't tell me it's the day a Princess
you adored passed away...
Oh..no...nothing like that
Dad!
Did you find him?
He's nowhere to be found...
Where's the former
superintendent of Police?
He says he'll search until time's up...
Would you like something to drink?
Water...
Yes sir...
I guess... I'll be calling it quits soon...
That's it for me too
Yeah, me too...
Alright then, after we're done, I'll fix the
cards and bring them to your room later.
I'd appreciate that...
How much us my bar tab?
Let's see...
you had 2 martinis...
I'll pay my bill too
Oh..no...my wallet's...
Could this be yours?
Yes it is...that's mine
It was on the floor in the
corridor so I picked it up!
Oh come on. I haven't taken anything!
S..sorry...but I just want to be sure...
Are you quitting too, Mr. Kujirai?
Oh no, I'm just going to
the restroom, let's take a break...
I'll be back soon.
Time's run out...
we can't touch that case now...
But then since I retired 2 years ago,
I have no authority anyway
Superintendent...
Can I still eta drink?
Sure, no problem.
Give me a beer.
Yes, Sir.
You did your best, sir.
Mourt...
Come on Mouri, let's drink up!!
Alright! I'm with you all the way!
Ahahaha, the drinks are on me!
Gee, that's generous of you!
I realize it was his case but isn't
he taking it a little too personal?
What was that sound?!
It came from outside...the upper deck!
A gunshot!?
Mouri! What time is it?!
12:08 am!
The flag!!
The flag's burning...
Hey, what was that?
It sounded like fireworks...
Hey Kudo, do you think
this just some prank?
CL Look at that, Hatto
What?!
What is this??
Something's written on it!
Don't touch the knife!
Who're you talking to! I'm no amateur!
Excuse me, go get me a plastic bag.
Yes, sir!
Do you always carry those things around?
Old habits are hard to break!
What's written on it?
Poseidon, the God of the Sea
gave me life, thusmy
shadow is resurrected.
Oh... no..."
Mr. Kujirai?
E...he's alive...
I knew it...the guys's...
he's...
Alive!!
What is that?
Captain! Explosion on the stern!
Stop all engines! Extinguish the flames!
Stop all engines!
Hat happened?!
There was an explosion
at the stern this time!
What?!
What's on fire?
This is the box the emergency
escape ladder is kept it.
But why... would anyone do this...
A body!
Somebody's being burned!!
It's burnt to a crisp...
It's so bad we determine the time
of death or identify the victim.
Uh...it's possible the victim is Saizo Kano,
the man who disappeared from
the ship what do you think...
We can't say for sure until we do
a thorough investigation
I think it could be Mr. Kanie.
Huh?
There, look.
The wristwatch he's wearing.
When I asked him for the time, I'm
pretty sure that was the watch he had on...
Now that you mention it...
although it's badly burned, that
Iooks like the sweater he was wearing...
Those slacks look like
the ones he was wearing.
How awful...
why would anyone kill Mr. Kanie...
It's pretty funny though...
Funny?
Just look at him, looks how he's posed...
His upper body and his arm is raised,
It looks like he's delibertely
tryng to show us his watch.
Aha...let me explain!
It's heat stiffening!
When a body Is burning...
the heat causes the skeletal
muscles to coagulate and shrink
Heat Stiffening
the result IS heat stiffening!
there are more muslces to bend the
arms and legs rather than stretch them.
And the joints begin to bend halfway
and the result is, the body looks like
it's in a boxer's fighting position
So you see, the body gets into
that position quite naturally!
Wow, I didn't know that...
But the important question is
his watchband.
Watchband?
What about it?
Take a good look, it's unbuckled, isn't it?
That doesn't mean anything
see the can near the victim's feet?
That explosion was probably
set off with the gasoline in this can...
The explosion was powerful enough
to destroy the can it probably
blew the watch loose
You're probably right...
it was must've also blown
the plastic sheet off.
Plastic sheet?
Yes...when the Superintendent and I
came here looking for Kano,
it was on the box...
Just like that one.
And then? You did look
inside the box, didn't you?
No, as you can see
the box is tied securely from the outside,
I didn't think anyone could hide inside.
Besides, no one was inside the box...
when I got back to the lounge,
Mr. Kanie was still there.
Hey... Mouri...
Who is that smart aleck kid?
His name's Heiji Hattori.
His father's the Chief of Police of
the Osaka Metropolitan Police.
You mean, he's Heizo's kid?
No wonder he knows so much...
So you know the Chief of Police...
Yes, during Kendo practice we
sparred with each other quite often.
But I was no match for him.
Hey Hattor!.
Huh?
Look at that strange thing on his face.
What?!
Why this is?!
It's silicone!
Yes, the material is
polygemethylcyclosun...
commonly known as silicone!
The fire warped it but these things are
widely used in plastic surgery to
heighten the bridge of the nose
So that means this fellow
had changed his looks.
Yes, I'm sure about it!!
Excuse me!
We'll cover him with this.
Why would he have plastic surgery?
Well...maybe he's 1 of the 4 who
pulled off 400 million yen robbery
he could've been part of the gang.
If the victim really is Mr. Kanie...
then there's a strong possibility
Mr. Kameda is also part of the gang,
they seemed to get along so well.
It seemed like this was a get-together
between friends who'd had plastic surgery
and hadn't seen each other since then...
Which means the other partner is...
could be Kujiral,
he seemed so interested in the case
and he looks very nervous...
he seems a likely candidate...
You may be right...
He acted a little strange when
Mr. Kanie gave him his lighter...
And another thing bothers me...
it's what he shouted on the upper deck...
he's alive...
Il Knew it... he's... alive...!
It was so obvious, he panicked
when he saw the knife through the bill!
The writing on the bill said...
Poseidon the God of the Sea
gave me back my life,
thus the shadow is resurrected...
The "shadow" is referring to Saizo Kano,
the Mastermind in the shadows and
resurrected means he
was once killed somewhere!
He was probably killed by his
3 partners in that robbery...
and then he took on the identity
of the mysterious old man.
But I don't understand...
not just about the identity of the old man
who disappeared from the ship...
but why do all 3 of the men involved in
the robbery have to be on the same ship
on the day the statute of
Iimitations runs out?
And putting out that strange ad to boot...
And I'm curious about that fellow
Masaru Furukawa who put out that ad...
Is that the real name of
one of the robbers... or is it...
Anyway, that old man holds
he key to the mystery...
I'll bet we'll find a lot of skeletons
when we rattle the closet.
That's for sure...
What? You don't remember?!
I hear you very clearly!
Back on the deck, you said
I knew it, he's alive.
Did I say that?
Don't play games with me!
Come on, tell the truth, you'll feel better...
You meant Saizo Kano, didn't you?
on NOW... on now any Ing...
I really don't...
We re not getting anywhere...
Superintendent!
I've talked to the crew members!
And, how did it go?
All their alibis check out...at the time of
the explosion, excluding us passengers,
all the crew members, including the
Captain were always working in a group
And since the explosion took place after
we heard what sounded like a gunshot
and ran up to the upper deck,
It means the only person
capable of starting the fire is someone
who wasn't with us on the deck...
So it must be Saizo Kano,
he's the only one we can't account for...
No, there's one other person, isn't there?
You know...
Mr. Kameda, he went back to his cabin
because he wasn't feeling well...
No one's seen him since...
Not that you mentioned it...
Well go to his cabin right now
and bring him here!!
Yes sir!
I'm going with him!
Me too.
Hey...come back here!
Wait for me!
I'm going with you!
Yes...l understand...
I'll see you there then...
roger and out!
Continue on to Ogasawara!
Aren't we turning back, Captain?
No, they're sending a helicopter
out first thing in the morning.
Our ship is loaded with cargo
they need on the island.
And as soon as they're ready, the Coast
Guard will also send their boat out
so until help arrives, those detectives
will have to do their best...
Start engines, raise speed up to 20 knots.
Start engines!
Mr. Kameda.
Mr. Kameda?
Seems he's not in.
Go borrow the master key again...
Oh? It's not locked.
Mr. Kameda? I'm coming in!
What's this?
It looks like no one's in...
If so, we'd better hurry and report this
to Mr. Samezaki... .Isnrt that'right=Heiji'...
Hey, where are you?
Conan?
How'd it go! You find anything?
Yeah, in the engine room below.
There was a little blood on the floor and
I found empty shell casings
And this strange letter...
I found a suspicious piece of paper too.
It was crushed up and
thrown away though.
Where'd you find it?
You know the restroom at the
entrance to the restaurant?
It was In the trash can inside.
Inside the trash can in the restroom?
And then? What does the letter say?
Waiting in the engine room.
Masaru Furukawa"
Masaru Furukawa again.
Blood stains and an empty shell casing...
There it is! One shot to the temple!
There's no doubt about it,
it's a gunshot wound!
The victim came to the
engine room because of this letter...
And...he was shot in the head
then put inside the box...
Yes...ll think that's reasonably correct.
What about that piece
of paper you found?
It was probably written on the
same word processor as yours
Meet me at the stern. Masaru Furukawa"
this is proof that someone
Iured that fellow Mr. Kujirai out!
How do you know it was Mr. Kujirai?
Two of the crew members saw him...
It was past midnight, that guy looked scared
He was yelling "Hey, I'm here!
And when the crew man called out
to him the fellow got shook up
Please don't tell anyone you say me here!
That's what he said then it seems he went
back to the lounge where we all were...
Those crew men thought someone might
show up there so they kept watch but
no one came. And just when they
were about to return to their posts
they said they heard
gunshots from the upper deck...
And was that box burning?
Of course not!
And there didn't seem to be
any timing device either...
What this means is, the killer fired
a shot on the upper deck then
set the flag on fire and when he saw
everyone was on the upper deck,
he shuck down here
and set the box on fire...
If that's true, then Mr. Kujirai's
fear is understandable...
Yes...
after all, if he was unlucky, he'd
been killed and set on fire here too...
One problem remains,
is it possible for the killer to fire
the shot on the upper deck then
come here without
being seen by anyone?
Well, I have an idea who the killer is,
and in time I'll be able to prove it
You've figured it out too?
You mean you have too?
Then shall we compare notes?
First, the mysterious old man
calling himself Saizo Kano
Like you said...he left the ship
and no one noticed that he returned,
but somehow he was on board, then...
That's a trick set up by the killer...
a fake!!
There are only two people
who could've done it...
That's right! What we have to
Iook at very carefully here is...
The heat stiffened body's elbows
were:in frontlofihis face and
the fact that his knees
were completely bent!
It proves both arms were raised when
the body was put in the box and shifted!
Only one person had
a reason for doing that!
But that too was a ruse!
The real killer faked his death and
Is still hiding somewhere on this ship.
Huh? What are you talking about?
Look at this! This watch us the proof!
Hat are YOU talking about?
That's the killer's trump card...
Hmmm, this is very interesting...
How unusual, our
deductions aren't the same...
Yeah... this has only
happened once, when we first met.
Alright then
Let's see whose deduction is correct...
Shall we make a contest of this?!
Hey!...Wait up!
Oh...I almost forgot!
Fix that watch, will ya!
Are you telling me to get this
burnt up watch moving again?
Of course not!
Silly! I mean put it back
where it came from
Oh... I see...
What?! Kameda wasn't in his cabin,
Is that what you're saying?!
we looked for him for awhile but...
You fool!
I don't know so many
people can just disappear!!
Outta my way!! I'll look for him!
I'm off to search for him too...
so I'd like all of you to wait
here for just a little longer...
I refuse!
You're a private detective
and the other man's a former
police officer, isn't that right?
I don't think either of you have
any right to keep us here.
B...but, listen...
Sorry but I'm going
back to my room and rest.
Is\m going too.
MM. me too...
Wait...come back here!
You should't move!
No need to worry.
We can take care of ourselves.
Right?
Of course...
It has to be here!
If my deduction is right...
there has to be a place someone can
hide without being discovered...
Huh?
It...can't be...
A good hiding place?
Yes, you have an idea don't you?
Some place that you usually can't get into
You know, some place that's off limits!
You little troublemaker! There's a
killer on board and you go galivanting!
Hey...
Where's Heiji
H?... ..You didn't run into hi
it's wrong!!
It's wrong!!
Kudo and I were both wrong!
Captain!
The ship's route is clear
for the next 30 kilometers!
Good!
Raise speed up to 293 points!
30 knots!
Speed to 30 knots!
Alright then, who?!
Who is the real killer?!
Hey, didn't you hear
a strange water noise?
Huh?
Strange water noise?
A bonito probably jumped.
ORIGINAL COMIC 8 OKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaoca
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation