Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
In each and every case to be solved.
He sees through to the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
when Detective Conan comes to the scene.
MURDER ON THE S.5. SYMPHONY,
20 YEAR VENDETTA
2 MA TAS
I know I heard it!!
It sounded like something fell into the
ocean, it's very suspicious!
Like I told you, it was
probably the sound of fish jumping!
I hear there are a lot of
bonito and flying fish in this area.
Listen! Did you see the young guy
who speaks with a kansai accent?
Kansai accent?
Oh. he came here to borrow a
flashlight?
Flashlight!
That means...chances are,
he went out on the deck to look
for something!!
Then...that sound...it couldn't be...
It can't be!!
No! Wait!
It's impossible! He'd never let that
happen...
Not in a million years!
Hattor!!
Hey!
Where are you!!
Answer me!
Hey!
Hattori...
31... can't be true...
Hattori....!
Hey!
Hattori!!!
Hattori!
Hey kid!!
You've got to be careful!
You couldn've fallen over...
Oh...thanks...
He's right, kid!
The ocean is extremely vast,
a person were to fall in...
a mere human bein would be hel less.
death is a certainty...
Conan!
What in the world are you doing?
You see, Heiji's...
Well, that kid again...
he's probably off somewhere
Iooking for clues!
Dad's right!
Don't worry, he pops up soon...
Yo...Yoshimi...
Oh..uh..er...
Your voice, it sounded just like
someone I knew... haha...
Never mind that, what's going on here?
What are you 3 doing here?
She asked us to help her look for something...
You were looking for something?
My pendant.
I noticed it was gone just when I was
going to bed,
I was looking all over for it when
I ran into these fellows...
They didn't look like they had anything
to do so I asked them to help me...
there's a better chance of finding it
with 3 rather than 1 person searching
Oh!...Could it be
Are you talking about this locket with the
The clasp was unhooked, I found it on the bow
Yes, this is it, thank you.
I must have dropped it this evening
when I was up there...
Then, the little girl in the picture is you, Nagisa?
Is that your father carrying you?
£ ot » CC
TV, yes...
For goodness sakes, why didn't you
return it to her earlier?
I meant to...
There was a hole in her father's face & I
didn't know who it belonged to!
After all, it could have been someone else
carrying their daughter.
I intended to ask who it belonged to
during dinner but I forgot!
I'm sorry, I didn't realize
there was a hole in it.
It's alright...it's an old photo taken
over 20 years ago.
This is the only thing I have left...
to remind me of my late father.
Are you all out of your minds? , .
A killer is on board and you're all: wandering
around!
Mouri!! Why did you let them out of the
restaurant
Well...they said they wanted to go
back to their cabins and rest.
That's right! You have no right to give
us orders!
didn't want to stayghere anymore!
Especially not with a hysterical old man!
Nagisa Isogai
Passenger
1.&9 Owl
Wh, what did you say!
If you say being alone is dangerous.
Then I'll lock myself in my room
with these kids
and spend the night playing cards
At least it'll be better than being here],
Isn't that right!
Excuse me...
I don't think it's a good idea to split up...
I think it's safer
if we all stay together in one place.
By the way,
Have you found Mr. Kameda,
the man you were looking for?
0...he seems.to have disappeared
Along with Mr. Kano!
Oh, have you seen Heiji Hattor1?
Good grief, are you telling me Heizo's
son is also missing?
What is going on on this ship?!
Alright then! I don't anyone of you to go
anywhere alone!
The killer could be someone outside this
group...or it:could be one of us
The killer could be lying in wait for us to
be alone!
He may be right...when we heard the
first gunshot,
Mr. Samezaki was with us in the lounge
And Mr. Kujirai had just returned
from the restroom.
And right after
we all ran to-the upper deck
there was an explosion at the stern
the box with the body inside was
set on fire.
We all ran up to the deck together,
and even Mr. Ebina and Ms. Isogai who
joined us later
wouldn't have been able
to start the fire.
Which means that-since we can't at
present identify the fire victim,
the only one capable of setting the fire
were the men not on the deck with us,
Mr. Kameda, and Mr. Kanie...
And the old man calling himself
Saizo Kano
But... something's bothering me...
it's the strange behavior of the people
in this group
And to add to everything else,
Mr. Samezaki's almost fanatical reaction.
Something had happened?!.
What happened during that robbery
20 years ago...
I'm going to the restroom, please wait for me!
Darn it all! If only Hattori were here
He'd easily be able to
ask Kogoro and Samezaki about the case
Where in the world"d he go off to.
Dr. Agasa's house
Hello...? Hi there, how're things going?
Pr Gasa's.house
The 400 million yen robbery 20 years ago?
14'-
« We were, just watching a special
on that case!
The statute.of limitations is running out
so they've been doing a lot of specials
on it since last night!
I thought you'd probably want to see it
SO we're recording it.
Did they mention something about the
theives?
Wait a second...I'm sure there was
something!
They identified the ringleader Saizo Kano
but as for the remaining 3, all they had
were montages and no names!
Did they mention whether Kano
died or not?
Yes...his blood stained coat
with a bullet hole
was washed: up on shore
so the police deduced
he was Killed by his
3 accomplices after a falling out!
But how did they know it was Kano"s coat?
In the inside pocket of the coat
they found'a photo. it was the one
he always.carried on his person
It was a picture of him carrying
his daughter
What?!
It.certainly was a tragic case
the alarm went off that scared
one of the robbers,
then he panicked and fired wildly
One of the bullets hit a teller named
Samezaki'and it killed her
En? You mean someone was shot!
A female teller,
her name was Yoshimi Samezaki
The poor thing, she was still so young
Yoshimi Samezaki?!
It can't be...
but it's just too much of a coincidence.
Why are there so many people connected
to that case here on this ship?
Who is this Masaru Furukawa
who sponsored the tour?
Who in the world is he anyway?!
Wh, what was that!
I have to go now!
Call me if you think of something!
Hey, wait!
Where'd that come from?
The stern I think!
Alright then! I'll go from the left,
you go around from the right!
Hey! Conan!
NO. one's. here...
That's impossible!
Look around!
Alright!
Hattori... where are you?
Why don't you show yourself?!
If you'd heard that sound,
you'd be the first one here.
What's happened to you Hattori?!
Superintendent!
Do you suppose he went this
way back inside...
It's Kano...
Kano is the killer, I just know it!
He's trying to confuse us
by firing shots all over the ship!
But what's he trying to do?
It's me...
He's... he's trying to kill... me
I..don't want to die.
L...don't want to die...not yet...
Please, protect me, please!
I'll tell you everything...
Yes...that's right.
I was one of Kano's accomplices
in the that robbery 20 years ago
I'came aboard this ship because
the three of us wanted to celebrate
the end of 20 years of hiding out.
One of the others sent me a letter.
He said there was no chance
of being caught
once the ship sailed because the
statute of limitations would run out.
There was an old 10,000 bill in the letter,
but it'd been so long since we'd seen
each other.
We'd all changed our faces and our names
so we didn't know who was who,
until Kanie called out to me.
And he told me our other
accomplice was Kameda.
And?
So who's the one trying to kill you?
Th...that's the thing
I don't know who it 1s
You're lying. It's Saizo Kano, isn't-it?
The man you and the others
double-crossed!
That's impossible! One of:.the:others
shot him to death'20{years ago.
Then it's probably one of the others.
He wants all the money for himself!
You haven't used that money yet, have you?
That's what I thought at first
but something's strange
it just doesn't make any sense!
What was that?!
Arggghhhhh!!
Everyone! Get down!
Are you alright?!
Kujirai!!
Where! Where were you shot?! Wy
Don't move!
You've been shot!
Where'd the shot come from?!
Hey kid! Get down!!
Somebody's out there.
There! On the bow!!
It's the killer!
I'm not letting him get away this time!!
SS... Superintendent!
Hey! You've no where to run!
Throw your gun down
and surrender yourself!
Hey Kano! Are you listening to me?
You are Saizo Kano, aren't you?!
Come on! Say something!
Ahh!
Kane?!
That's impossible!
1 shot to the head
He died instantly.
Looks that way.
The body's still warm.
His blood hasn't coagulated vet
There're powder burns on his temple
indicating he placed the gun there
and pulled the trigger
When the gunshot was heard, everyone
except Kane was in the restaurant
There's no other explanation, Kanie shot
himself in the head.
Which means
Kanie, who was hiding out on the bow of
this ship, was so upset to hear
his old partner blab about the robbery
20 years ago,
that he tried to shoot him...
but failed to kill him!
He gives up and commits suicide.
What a fool.
Doesn't that seem strange to you?
The burnt body atithe bow
was wearing Mr. Kanie's clothes
and his wristwatch, wasn't he?
Then whose body is that anyway?
Well, it's either Kameda,
who is. another of the accomplices
who disappeared earlier
or Saizo Kano
Either way, Kanie here was the killer.
He disguised the body to look like him
and set it on fire to make it
appear he was dead.
The question is,
how did Kanie manage to evade our search
and hide out here...
Hey, what's this...?
There's something weird tied behind
this guy
Huh?
Hey! This is...
Rope ladder!
No one would find this hiding place
If you were playing hide and seek!
I get it...Kanie hid here,
hanging on to the ladder
There's some rope marks on his arms
and legs. So I'm sure you're right.
But I don't understand.
Why go to all the trouble of making
it look like you died
and then hide out here.
The only explanation I can think of is
he wanted to surprise his next victim
by appearing suddenly before him.
Filling the guy with fear... that's my guess
But who was Kanie trying to kill that
he had to go through so much trouble?!
Kujirai, who just got shot was
one of his old buddies, wasn't he?!
Oh... haha, you're right.
Good grief, look+at all the blood.
It looks like an artery's been damaged.
He needs medical attention right away.
Ran's gone to get the first aid kit.
You are arvery lucky person.
You got off with only a hole
through your coat and arm.
Hey Mouri, I found it!
I found where the bullet passed through.
I'm pretty sure Kanie fired the gun from the
bow and it passed through the window here
Now...all we have to do is find is
the bullet which should be
embedded somewhere
Do you mean this?
Yes, no doubt about it, this is it!
Boy, what a sharp shooter.
He missed his target but
He fired the shot fromiway over there
with a pistol.
Have you forgotten?
One of the men Kano hired to help pull off
the job was very handy with firearms.
That's right,
we were able to learn
he probably served in some foreign army,
but that was about it.
Yes, so"that must-have been Kanie!
Dad!
Good! You got the first aid kit!
We've got to stop the bleeding!
Hey? . . Where's Conan?
Hun =
Isn't he somewhere around there?
A boy with a kansai accent?
He came to borrow a flashlight
but never returned
he hasn't come to the bridge either.
Somethin's wron
Where could he have gone?
Listen, could you search everyone's cabin
just to make sure?
Sure but I doubt we'll find him.
That's right, when we were looking for that
Kameda fellow with Mr. Samezaki
we went through all the cabins too.
Oh. well did you happen to notice
If he might been searching
for something somewhere?
You see... he's a private detective too.
Hmmm...
I didn't notice anything.
Besides, all the cabins 'were locked.
Except for Mr. Kameda's.
Come to think of it, there is
1 cabin we didn't search!
Oh that's right.
It was so neat we didn't bother
You know, that guy with the glasses,
Mr: Ebina, it:was his room?
There was only a trunk
in the middle of the room,
the bed looked like it hadn't even used.
It looked like he hadn't even
even unlocked his trunk, remember?
Yeah.
Hey!
Can you show me where that cabin is?
Mr. Mouri asked me to look inside!
Conan?
Conan!
Hey kid...are you sure
Mr. Mourn wanted it hike this?
Yes! And he also said he didn't want
anyone else to know about it.
Quick, let's get back inside!
That body's giving me the creeps.
Yeah...you're right.
Go back to the inside soon!
Okee dokee!
Boy this tour sure turned into a nightmare
I heard the killer committed suicide though
And that guy Furukawa who planned
this tour,
I'll bet he's waiting at Ogasawara
for the ship to dock,
thinking everyone's having a fun.
Masaru Furukawa...
The man who planned this tour,
all the mysteries start here.
If the killer is Kanie...and this Masaru
Furukawa is also Kane
Then all the pieces to this case will fit,
but I'm still not convinced.
There's the watch the body had on
and that Furukawa seal Mr. Kameda had
IS another puzzle.
Darn it, I wish I at least knew who this
Masaru Furukawa is.
Uh, excuse me!
Did you see a little boy weaing glasses?
LI..don't believe it...
Masaru Furukawa is
A burn mark...?
And the paint's coming off
on the other side.
Maybe?!
Conan!
Here's another.
And other here.
I've got it...that's how you can control the
time and everyone's movements.
And that's where Hattori's role
as private detective fits in.
T... why Hatto
He's famous in Osaka but that's all.
Why hire a private detective all the way
from Osaka?
Conan! You're always wandering around
and making us worry!
)h...l...was just about to go bac
Th...that's why I...
I'm begging you
Don't leave me alone...
What?
Conan, you know what:a scaredy cat I am.
If you get lost, I'll have to search this
spooky ship all by myelf!
By the way,
where'd you get this tennis ball?
Back at the restaurant just now, I found it
under the table while I was looking for you.
I asked who it belonged to but no one
came forward.
Did Mr. Samezaki say something
when he saw it?
No, because he and dad
went off somewhere before seeing it.
They were talking very loudly.
It was something about
an OU 6 WOLIM
they found on Mr. Kanie's body.
Listen...
where was everyone when Uncle Kogoro
and the others left the restaurant
the first time to look for Mr. Kano?
They all left too, separately.
But when they came back with Heiji,
the others were already back.
I HTT
I've figured everything out.
I've solved the mystery behind this
strange case!
O 1 ¢INAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hdka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kizunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIREC ORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Ttkashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Tikahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yormiuri Tel casting Corporation