Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
He sees through to the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene.
It's the bottom of the ninth, the score's
3 & 2 with Chunichi leading by a point
ace relief pitcher Komatsu is on the mound
with 2 outs & runner, Oh, on 2nd base...
Yeah
I shot him 4 times. I'm sure he's dead.
Saizo Kano the Mastermind in the shadows
IS now drifting like seaweed in the sea
Probably the current in this area is strong
Before the body floats up,
it'll be food for it'll be food for the fishes
but why'd we have to kill him?
You fool!
Do you think
we could let that coward go,
he said we should turn ourselves in
becaause we killed one lousy bank clerk!
Besides, the police had him indentified
Never mind him,
now what re we going to do?
That money's hot
He's right
The serial numbers of three hundred million
of the four have been recorded, right?
Don't worry
we already pulled off the big job.
All we have to do now is
wait until the right time
Here!
This is our farewell gift to you
No rud es. OK?
Boss...
0.9,
MURDER ON THE 5.5. SYMPHONY
20 YEAR VENDETTA"
2 tA TL
Record! Record!
What? *
This answer to the quiz, I'm positive it's
record!! *
What areyou-talking about anyway?
This here!
CC!)
What!
Read this, here!
Huh?
Special announcement?
Let's see?
Something important most people
In Japan had during the Showa era...?
Do you:still have it?
It's something we almost never see now
The first 10 people...
The next part! Read the next part!
Good grief, don't bother me.
Who bringsthe correct item will win an
WM all expensesgpaid trip to the Ogasawara
Dolphin Tour?
See, let's give a try, come on.
There's still time, let's take a record
down there! Come on!
Conan, you want to see the dolphins too,
don't you?
Don't you, Conan
Eh...!1? Oh, sure...
Come on, you don't mind do you?
#Werdonitthave anything to do
this long weekend anyway
Forget it!
# Therstour sounds boring
Besides...your-answer:s wrong!
Ifsitewas records, they wouldn'tdhave
written "people in Japan
Alright then, what's the right answer?
You fool!
Samurai spirit", that's what modern Japanese
have lost! No doubt about it!!
How in the world are you going to take
bring something like that down there?
Besides, I've never had samurai spirit,
and I doubt I ever will!
Alright then, maybe it's a yoyo or
bell bottom pants,
how about that mushroom tea?
Designer brands...family computers?
Yeah, I know what it is-how about that
frilled lizard
It was pretty popular back then!
What, is it anyway?
Excuse me
I think...the answer is...
You're right!
Right this way to the cruiser
Alright
We did it! You were right Conan
I was just lucky ,
Next contestant, step this way!
We sure wererlucky
we still one of the old bills!
Hey, put that away right now,
the others in the back will see it
You're so stingy, sir
Hahaha, don't worny.
It's not something they pull out of
their pockets so readily.
You're kidding...it's now a rubik cube?
Wrong!
Really?
He was right
Next contestant
Wait!
Wow, this is real fancy
I'm so excited!
Congratulations!
This is a pamphlet for today's tour
Oh. thank you
Uhswhat number are we?
There's 3 in your party but not counting
the boy,
there's 1 more opening on the tour
Gee...we just made it, huh!
How lucky!
That's right the maximum number for
the tour was 10
But this sure is a.huge ship for such a
small group
Conan we're oin!
WW VY Nr -—) 781889
OK, coming!!
Wow!
It's like a hotel!
Goin to O asawara on this
won't be be bad!
Congratulations!
Thank you.
Party of 3, are you 1 family?
Yes...sort of
So I'll put you in a twin room
room number is 110.
May I ask you a question?
Mr. Masaru Furukawa, the man who planned
this tour, is he on board this ship?
Excuse me?
I wanted to thank him for giving me the
opportunity to sail on this fantastic ship!
The thing is...none ofgus crew members
have met him either
You haven't met him?
) No!
The reservation for the cruise as well as
the method for selecting the passengers
everything, was done by phone
charter fee was also directly transferred
through the bank
I'm sure he'll be waiting for the ship at
Ogasawara, though
Yes...l see
By the way,
I please have your name?
Of course
actually, my name is Kogoro Mourn!
A former detective with the Metroplitan
Police Department
Now an awe inspiring
well known private detective!
Isn't that right?
Police Superintendent Samezaki!
Don't call me that, I'm not a Police
Superintendant anymore!
I retired 2 years ago, thank you.
Uperintendent Samezaki
I'm just an old fogey now
uperintendent Samezaki
My, It's been ages!
Why, is that you Ran?
You sure have grown up
to be quite a beauty!
But what brings you here?
I just got a hankering to see the ocean
Remember? Today's a special day!
A special day?
Hahaha
I'don't blame you for forgetting, after
all, you left the force 10 years ago
hahaha
By the way,
how's that gorgeous wife of yours?
Don't tell me you two are still separated
As a matter of fact, we are.
Nevermind that,
don't mention that woman
Dad!
H...excuse me.
What is it?
Teruyoshi Kameda
Oh...sorry...it was my mistake
A seal?
You dropped this
Oh...thank you!
Thank YOU very much!
Eh?? Oh, of course
Huh? You picked up his seal,
so why'd you thank him?
Never mind, it's nothing.
Hey.
Wh...what is it? Are you talking to me?
8.12X46)
I've been waiting for you
Korehisa Kanie
c.1195
I've been waiting for you
nl Ue
0-308
qT TAWG
How about it,
Iet's go have a drink over there.
Sir! Allow me to carry those!
No thanks, I'm fine!
Phew
Party of 1, sir?
Excluding that boy,
this man's number 10,
he's the last one
Alright, we can set out then, can't we.
We're already behind schecule
No, we can't go yet!
Remember the first passenger, the old man?
Well we left to go get something
he forgot, he hasnit.come back yet!
Really? That old man was just here
he said he wanted to take a short nap
before dinner
so he didn't want to be disturbed
Are you sure?
When'd he get back anyway?
Well, at any rate,
we have the 10 passengers.
The contest's over,
regretably,
we have to the other contestants.
Alright! I'll go!
Now then sir, you'll be in room 107
F11al ND
Wait just a minu
Excuse me,
but haven't we met somewhere before?
N...no...you must be mistaken,
Minoru Ebina
I've never seen you before today
Hahaha did you find someone on the
Police wanted list?
Eh, Superintendent Samezaki!
Thanks to you people, Mr. Mourn,
I'm certain we'll have a safe journey
Huh?!" .
After all, he's a former-police
officer and you're a private investigator.
There're 3 of you on board!
3 of us?
There's someone else besides us?
Yes! Another private investigator,
although he "doesnét look it
Thank you all for joining us today on
the S.S. Symphony,
we will now leave the dock
we are scheduled to arrive in
Ogasawara tomorrow morning,
relax and have a pleasant journey!
I'm on top of the world!
She said she wanted to that once
in her lifetime
She's been watching too many movies.
What's she going to do if we really sink,
waa a omen.
Hahahaha
Don't get so upset,
with this great expanse of
sea colored by the setting sun
Sadao Kujiral
fH 2 #50)
and the fantastic view right in front of us,
Sadao Kujiral
853 Et (50)
I don't blame her for wanting to shout
Iike that
Sadao Kujiral
1-7 SF J
gH FE #50)
Ahhh, that felt good!
The sea certainly is wonderful
Itris'mltsmakes you forget
all the unpleasant things!
You're right...the sea does do that
It hides everything
Painful memories...the uncertain future
Nagisa Isogal
and...even corpses
D..did you say...corpses?
Oh, I'm sorry,
I shouldn't have said
such a horrible thing.
It just slipped out...you see, my father
drowned a while back
I'm sorry to hear that
We've all got to be grateful to this
Mr. Furukawa got sponsoring this tour
I know who he is!
Eh?!
Remember that seal I picked up?
That's when I saw it
The name Furukawa was on it
Conan, you saw it too, didn't you!
Yes!
So that's why you thanked him back then
That's right!
So you see!
That man with the seal is Mr. Furukawa!
I'm sure he intends to reveal his identity
during dinner and surprise everyone.
That's strange
I asked him his name but
I'm positive he said it was Kameda
You re kidding
Hey Mouri! They're announcing dinner!!
Alright, we'll be there!
Wow, so you're the infamous
Sleeping Kogoro
That's right
What an honor
Phew...I'm going back to my room to
rest for a bit
You stilliget sea sick, huh?
May I pour you more wine?
Yes, thank you'll
This ship is so huge and
there're so few passengers on board,
it seems like such a waste
I agree with you!
Countingjthe 2 passengers
resting in"'their rooms,
there's only 11 of you on board
That's)if you include me!
The 2 passengers you're talking about 1s
that the other private investigator
and the old man?
Yes!
I passed.that old man in the corridor
He seems to be the quiet type,
what does he do?
Wells iteseems
he's a marine researcher and
uh... His name is... Saizo Kano
What!!
Saizo Kano?!
Where is his room?
His room number's... 101
Saizo Kano...?
I've heard that name somewhere before
You idiot! How could you forget!!
Many years ago,
you and I both were after him
he was the mastermind
behind the 400 million yen heist
he's Saizo Kano
the Mastermind in the shadows!!
He's Saizo Kano
Saizo Kano
he's Saizo Kano
the Mastermind in the shadows!!
Saizo Kano
NODo> EEO
Fro > 3 RE ae
Huh?
You have the master key, don't you!
Yes!
Listen, if it is him,
he may have a gun
as soon as you open the door,
get out of the way!
Yes sir.
Don't worry! Please calm down
I've...unlocked it
Let's go!
What is this?
It is strange...
It looks like no one's beenO*inside
Are you sure this is the room?
Yes! There's no mistake!
Rats!
I'll look on the lower deck!
Mouri, you check the upper!
Yes sir!
Hello?
Where are you?
I know you're in here!
I read the letter!
Hello!
If he's not in the room
then...he could be on the deck
Huh? Who's in the room next door, 1027?
It's the other private investigator's room.
He hasn't been out of his room since he
boarded the ship
That sounds pretty suspicious
Excuse me sir, may I come in?
Sir...7
Here, let me do it
Hey, you! I know you're in there!
Answer me! Hey!
Guess we have no other choice
Will you unlock this door too?
Be quiet!
What's this all about?
Keep the noise down!
Eh...? Good grief... Mr. Mouri
what are all of you doing here?
That's what I'dvlike to ask you
Mastermind in the shadows?
Now that you mention it,
I remember my dad telling me about it
a long time ago
His real name's Saizo Kano
he was the mastermind behind
the 400 million yen heist 20 years ago
The plan was perfectly calculated
nothing went wrong
The job went off without a hitch
and they escaped the police so smoothly
He was called "Mastermind in the shado
He changed partners with every job.
He was a loner.
His trademark was he never hurt anyone
during the crime
But then during the robbery 20 years ago,
he killed his first victim
And since that incident,
he was never heard of again
You mean that fellow was sleeping
in the room next to mine?
Yup...but when we got there, he was
Iong gone
Mr. Samezaki's looking for him now
That's real strange,
I'm sure the reports said he was dead
They found his clothes washed up
on some beach,
there were bullet holes
In them and blood stains too
My father told me
He's not dead!
That coat was planted to fool the police
You can't kill Kano off that easily,
kid he's no fool
I had a feeling that about this time,
he and his partners were out there
somewhere counting their money,
can't believe he'd be on the same ship
But... the statute of limitations on
that case ran out 5 years ago
even if you caught up
with them you can't do a thing
Idiot! Did you forget,
the statue of limitations
for murder is 15 years
But in a civil case, the statute of
Iimitations is 20 years!
If you're ordered to return the money,
you have to!
That's right... unfortunately,
the statute of limitations has run out for
Kano"s arrest
but his 3 partners can still be arrested.
If we can find Kano and make
him tell us where the others are
we can get the money back somehow
There's a possibility his partners are
on this ship too.
Then when we get to Ogasawara,
Iet's notify the police and
get them to help us search the ship
After all, we're out at sea,
they can't get away so easily
You fool! There's no time!
Like I said, today's a special day
Huh?
Tomorrow's the 20th anniversay
of that robbery!
At exactly midnight tonight,
the statute of limitations will run out
they'll be free men so nobody can
touch them after that!
You mean...in just 2 hours
The statute limitations on the crime will
run out completely
Hey! Is that you, Hatton?
Hi, Ran, long time no see!
What's going on?
I didn't know you were on this ship too
Yeah,
I was sleeping peacefully in my cabin
when this old guy came banging
on my door
Is Kazuha with you too?
Why bring her name up
she's not my girlfriend or anything!
We're not as close as you two!
H...who're you talking abou
Oh..uh... ll mean
you and your dad, you're so close
You don't know what you're talking about!
Did you find him, Mr. Samezaki?
That shadow man you were talking about
No, your father and I were just leaving
to continue the search!
Alright then
we'll be in the restaurant downstairs!
Hey, wait a minute!
We've got to help them
What did you say!
Are you telling me to wait all by myself
when there's a dangerous man
Iurking somewhere on board...?
Well..no, uh hahaha
Alright then dad...I'll just wait for you
I'll be waiting
I'll be waiting, dad!!
Is something wrong, sir?
Oh..no, it's nothing
Alright then,
Iet's start from the top deck and
work our way down
Sure
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
CRIPTS BY.
Kan 1 Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation