Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
Today's crime is quite a surprise.
Using my head and chest,
I will solve the case step by step.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene.
And, what is this difficult case that....
you need the renown Detective
Kogoro Mouri to help you with?
If it's a silly case, treating
me only to lunch won't do!
H,Hey Mr. Mouri, lower your voice.
An officer wouldn't come pick
you up if it were a silly case.
Moreover, all the way from
Shizuoka, paying his own way....
As a matter of fact, Mr. Mouri....
about the....
.....Do you know that man?
Oh, no, but I have a very confidential
favor to ask of you so......
Mr. Mouri! About that
Komiyama Yasushi....
Komiyama?
Oh, you mean that famous actor...
What about him....?
Huh? Don't you know?
He was killed 3 days ago.
K,Killed?!
Didn't you know?
This case was a very
incomprehensible one indeed...
You can't find a suspect no matter
how much you investigate?
....Just the opposite....
?!......The opposite.....
Three people saying that they killed
him have turned themselves in!!
Huh?
Ha-han....
One victim and three people
who turned themselves in.
...very interesting.....
"The Man Who Was Killed Four Times"
What do you mean by three
people turned themselves in...?
Not accomplices....?
Well.....it's not that simple....
Tell me about it....
yes, sir....
The murder was committed 3 days ago.
The last day the victim was to
perform on the stage,
2 hours before the performance began...
Komiyama.....
Are you asleep, Komiyama....?
Hey, I'm coming in....
K,Komiyama!!
The victim is Yasushi Komiyama, 58.
Yasushi Komiyama (58)
actor
The estimated time of death is
2 hours before the victim was found.
It seems that he had been hit on the
backof his head with a blunt object,
The corpse was sent out
immediately for autopsy
because homicide was suspected
We also went on to question
three people for testimony.
The three are also performers
on the show, eh....
Yes....
The room Mr. Komiyama was found in,
is in a corner where outsiders
cannot get to very easily.
We got testimony from the security guard
that they were the only ones
who were in that area
during the victim's estimated
time of death.
I see.....
Mr. Kengo Katsumata wanted the role
that Mr. Komiyama had
played for the past 20 years.
Yumiko Araide was seriously troubled
about Komiyama pestering her.
Mr. Haruyuki Hoshino liked Ms. Araide,
and disliked Mr. Komiyama.
Anyway, I summoned these three to
the station and heard them out.
Then...
I'm very sorry,
I killed Mr. Komiyama.
Kengo Katsumata
actor
Huh?!
Mr. Komiyama suddenly came
shouting in to the room.....
I don't know if he was drinking,
but he was a bit unsteady.....
W,What's the matter, Mr. Komiyama?
What the hell were
you reading just now?!
W,What the....
Never mind, just hand it over!
So, you were reading this again!
Listen! This script was
written for me to read!
I'm not ever giving my role to
a half-done performer like you!
I'm taking this to the grave with me!!
hooey! You scum....
Thinking that I had to do
something about the corpse,
I decided to drag him over to his room.
I thought that if I left his body there,
it would look like his wife killed him....
His wife?
Yes,
because everyone knew that
Mr.Komiyama and his wife
weren't getting along....
She came to see him at his
room back stage yesterday,
and they, like always, were fighting....
I see......
Damn....
I wonder why Komiyama suddenly
came into the room shouting....
But then...!!
W,What?!
Like I just said, I killed Komiyama
with my very hands!
Haruyuki Hoshino
actor
J,Just what do you think
you're doing,barging in like that!
Don't you dare forget!
Yumiko Araide is mine!!
I'm not going to give her
over to you. You shrimp!!
I didn't want to leave
his corpse in my room.
So, I moved Komiyama
over to his own room.
But, officer, thinking back on it now,
I feel I did something unnecessary.
Huh?
Because I don't regret
being arrested at all.
I did, after all....rescue Yumiko from that
lewd poison pest with my very hands....
What's more!!
W,What did you just say....?
Mr. Komiyama suddenly
came into my room...and....
Yumiko Araide
actress
Please, no, Mr. Komiyama!!
Why do you run from me?
We're going to be acting
on the same stage,
I'm just trying to be friendly, Yumiko!
No!!
I don't know how Mr. Komiyama's
corpse got back in his room....
But....
I'm the one who killed Mr. Komiyama.
I'm very sorry.....
And investigations
following her questioning,
revealed that the vases found
in all three of their rooms...
had traces of the vases
having hit the victim....
Hmm....
I have already reserved a room for you!
Please think it over
until tomorrow morning,
and find us a conclusion
with your sharp deduction.
Mr. Mouri!
W,What is this...?
The investigation documents.
T,This much?
Yes!
Oh, is that right.....
Huh?
Isn't there something strange
about this picture?
What's so strange about it.......Huh?!
Ow...Ouch!!
This is not something for a kid to look at!
But, if someone hits you on the head,
don't you hold your head like this?
This person is holding his chest,
isn't he? I wonder why?
Come to think of it, it's strange....
The direct cause of his death is his heart.
His heart?
As a result of the autopsy,
the wound on the back of his
head was not that serious,
but he seems to have
had a heart ailment.
According to the producer who
discovered Mr. Komiyama,
he says that Mr. Komiyama had
an attack the morning he died,
but somehow held it down with
the medication he carries around.
In other words, at this time,
when he was hit on the head,
it sent a shock to his heart
and he passed away....
I guess so.
But, I wonder why he didn't
drink his medicine then?
You idiot! He didn't have
time to drink his medicine!
Well, maybe he did want to drink
it, but his pill case was empty.
Empty?
If he had drunk his medicine,
he could've held down the attack....
Which means that his pill box
was empty from the start....
....It can't be.....
Please excuse me, Mr. Mouri.
It's from the station.
I'd like to excuse myself.
I wonder if he'd not noticed that he had run
out of medication that is vital to his life?
But, it was in fact, empty.....
The only possible conclusion is....
T,That's reckless!!
But, department head,
I understand how you feel,
but....yes....
Why did the victim not call for help....
One out of three chances, eh....
Well, if I rack my brains over
night, it should be duck soup.
I'm sorry, sir!
H,Hey, what is this, all of a sudden....
You don't have one night.
Huh?
We need you to give us your deduction
as soon as we arrive
at the scene of the crime!
As soon as we arrive~~~~?!!
Hey, hey, what are
you going to do,Pops...
....We've arrived....
Hey, Officer Yokomizo!
M,Mrs, Komiyama...
Atsuko komiyama (36)
Yasushi Komiyama's wife
When on earth are
you going to give it back!
Oh, well, it is evidence, after all,
so we can't return it
until the case is solved...
Then, hurry up and solve the case!
....Who are they?
She is the victim's wife, Atsuko,
and the the producer, Mr. Tsuda.
They look very angry.
they want the things that the investigation
headquarters have in custody,
and are rushing me.
Isn't he the man that found
Mr. Komiyama's corpse?
.....Yeah.
Just as I thought!
Oh, where are you going Conan?
To the restroom!
Gee.....
Excuse me, I've got to
go to the restroom too....
Mr. Mouri, the restroom is that way....
Oh, I thought so...
On the day that he was killed?
Uh-huh, Mr. Mouri of the detective
office asked me to ask you.
The man called Komiyama had an
attack that morning too, right?
Yeah, when he was talking to me
at the coffee shop in the hotel....
You're telling me to quit acting?!
I'm telling you as a friend.
In your health condition, continuing
acting is like committing suicide.
What will there be left of me if
you take acting away from me!
Komiyama?!
What's wrong, Komiyama?
Do you want me to call your wife?
She's in the room,isn't she?!
....It'll be fine if I take my medicine....
I'll drink one....
His attack seemed to subside
as soon as he took the medicine...
I see.....I've figured out.....
how the murder was committed....
As well as who the real killer is!
Hello, I'm Kogoro Mouri from the
Mouri Detective Office in Tokyo,
who was invited over
by Officer Yokomizo....
There is something we would like
you to check on right away.....
You've gotta be joking.
I was personally asked to give you help!
And, you're the one who asked, right?!
Well, absolutely....
I don't know how it got to
the department head's ears....
I'm so sorry!
So, will you please begin?
No way!
Please, Mr. Mouri, I beg you....
Our department head is really looking
forward to you solving the case too,
saying that he gets to hear
your deduction in person.....
That's only your side of the story!
Besides, you said that tomorrow
would be fine, didn't you!
What's up, Pops?
I don't think it's nice
to keep people waiting.
If you can't solve it, you may
as well apologize right away.
You Idiot!
There is no case that the renown
Detective Kogoro is not able to solve!!
Okay! I'll solve it!
No rehearsal, it's show time!!
I am the renown Detective Kogoro Mouri!
I was asked to talk about the murder
of Mr. Yasushi Komiyama today....
But, I would like to first talk about....
why I decided to pick being
a detective as my profession.
Never mind the formalities!
Who of the three is the killer?
Huh, you mean the real killer?
Yes~~~~~The real killer is.....
Uh.....Well~~~~
How should I say it......
Oh, no, Dad.
the real killer .....probably....
Even your impertinent deduction
is not making its appearance....
I was hoping that it
would buy some time....
I've got no choice...!
H,He's got into position, he's going
to start deducing, department head!
Hmm!
I've finally figured out the
killer now,Officer Yokomizo!
If it is exactly as the
three people say it is,
the victim Yasushi Komiyama
would've been killed three times.
He entered each of
your rooms back stage.
but, the problem is the order
in which he entered the rooms.
Kengo Katsumata's
confession goes like this.
Mr. Komiyama came
shouting into the room.
I don't know if he was drinking,
but he was a bit unsteady.
That's right.
However, if Mr. Komiyama
had a heart ailment,
I don't think he would've
drunk until he was unsteady.
And, more so, if it was just before
he was ready to go on stage.
....True....
Then, why was he unsteady...
Probably because it was after he
had been punched by someone.
Next, according to Mr. Haruyuki Hoshino,
back then, Mr. Komiyama was.....
J,Just what do you think you're
doing,barging in like that!
Don't you dare forget!
Yumiko Araide is mine!!
Yes.....
However, Mr. Komiyama
acts weird here too.
He suddenly burst into the
room and pounced on Yumiko.
Something must've
triggered him to do so.
Yes, he made passes to you,and
Ms. Yumiko Araide, you rejected him.
You already understand, don't you?
Mr. Komiyama approached
Ms. Yumiko Araide's room first,
and he was hit on the back of his head.
Yumiko, who thought she had
killed him fled from the spot.
However, a little while after that,
Mr.Komiyama regains consciousness.
...Then.
He had only fainted.
Then, Mr. Komijyama headed
for Mr. Hoshino's room,
thinking that Yumiko keeps rejecting
him because of Mr. Hoshino.
However, Mr. Komiyama is
hit on the head there again.
He must've had a very
hard head or something....
He snaps back to himself once again.
What a hard head....!!
Absolutely....
However, not learning his lesson,
Mr. Komiyama goes on his way again,
in order to take his
anger out on someone.....
for being hit on the head twice in a row...
I see,
that's why he came over to my place
and spitted out those rude words....
Then, you did it, Mr. Katsumata....
So, like I've been telling you
from the start,I hit him....
No, Mr. Komiyama is more than that.
What do you mean?
When his corpse was found,
Mr. Komiyama looked to be
holding his chest in pain.
Despite the fact that the corpse was
dragged along by Mr. Katsumata.
I'm sure that Mr. Komiyama's hands
were loosened to both sides of his body.
Then, why were both his hands by
his chest when he was found....?
There is only one answer....
Mr. Komiyama had already regained
his consciousness three times...
It was after all this that Mr. Komiyama
had the heart attack that took his life.
I see! When he realized it, his
medicine container was empty.
I wonder if there is a person...
who would not realize that
such an important thing is gone?
Moreover, he already took his
medicine that morning too.
There is no reason he would not realize!
B, But, he in fact....
Somebody took the important
medicine out from his pill container!
But the victim always wore the
pill container around his neck.
the person who has access
to his pill container is.....
There is just one person.
After he had his attack, in order
to wash off his perspiration,
I think Mr. Komiyama took a shower,
isn't that right, Mrs. Komiyama?!
He took off his precious pill
container from around his neck,
so as not to get it wet.
It's true that from circumstantial
evidence,everything is against me...
However, Mr. Detective,
You've got no proof, right?
That I secretly emptied out
his pill container do you...?
Maybe, he really did forget....
I didn't say that you emptied it.
If his pill container was really empty,
I'm sure he would've
called someone for help.
But, he didn't do so.
I think a different type of pill
was in his pill container.
Just one different capsule....
Mr. Komiyama naturally drank the
pill with no suspicion what so ever.
However, his attack wouldn't subside,
After struggling for some
time, he passed away....
Yes, this is Yokomizo...
Stomach medicine?What do
you mean by stomach medicine?
If I tell Mr. Mouri he'll understand?
Oh.....stomach medicine.
the one that I'm always drinking....
What on earth are you talking about?
I had the content of the Mr. Komiyama's
pill container checked.
To see if there was
something strange inside it.
Oh, so the last medicine that
Mr. Yokomizo drank was......
stomach medicine....?
Whew.....what a fix I'm in......
If you guys didn't hit him
in the head repeatedly,
the police wouldn't
have stuck their nose in,
and he would've just died from the
heart ailment that he had always had....
That, of course goes for
Mr. Detective over there too.....
Well, well, just a rumor has it,
you're really something, fantastic.
Well, no big deal...
When on earth did you check
the contents of the pill container?
That's well, uh, you see....
That, of course is a business secret!
it's just that you don't
know the answer, right?!
Gin....?!
Oh no! He's found it!!
Probably apotoxin, 4869.....
It's the medicine in question.
"Re-Encounter with the Men in Black"
(Haibara's Story)