Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
Today, those guys finally appear.
I'm going to expose
their black conspiracy.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the ll.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene.
Hey, did you see yesterday's game!
Twas really something, wasn't it?!
Yeah, you mean Hide's
over head kick,right?
He game's over...
That was Indeed a work of art!
Hide is the best!
It's time to wake up from your dream...
Let's celebrate our re-encounter .
With a rose, the flower that you like...
With color as red as that of blood
Yeah...Sherry...
Whew...what a terrible dream...
Re-Encounter with the Men in Black"
(Haibara's Story)
Here's the MO I borrowed!
Please tell Dr. Agasa that the game
was way more than we expected!
Yes... I'll tell him...
I didn't really care for the
boss character.though!
But, it was way better
than the previous game!
Wow, look, look!
See! It's snowing, it's snow!
What?!
No joke?!
Snow...
Let's celebrate our re-encounter.
With:a rose, the flower that you like...
With color as red as that of blood...
Sherry...
See, why don't look at the
snow by the window too, Al!
Don't touch me!
Huh?
Is something wrong?
I'm sick and tired of this place...
If I could, I\want to disappear
from here, right this minute...
it'll turn out that way in
time anyway,ll guess...
Huh?! Are you
changing schools, Al?!
Don't tell me that
someone Is bullying you?!
I'll get the guy so tell me who!
So, don't say that you're
going to go away!!
Only joke...Don't take me seriously...
Huh...?
was jus In 0 annoye
because I have a cold...
I didn't want to give it to you.
Oh, it's just a cold...
They say people get fussy
when they get sick so...
Come along, if you've got a cold you've
got to go to the infirmary to take a rest!
Here you go!!
I did it!
You're gonna get it, Mitsuhiko!
This is not where I belong...
I've got to get out of here fast,
so that I don't get those kids involved...
I'll bet you're thinking of
something stupid like that?
Don't worry.
It is a dream story for a body
to shrink with medicine.
Nobody would#believe it
nor even think of'it happening!
We've got to keep on acting like
children so that this won-tibe disclosed
ntil the time is right...
Don't worry!
If things start looking bad,
I'll do something about it for you!
Bye!
See you tomorrow!
Bye-bye!
Bye!
Shinichi...
you don't know a thing.
They're not people that
ou can take on alone...
If we are ever off our guard,
that's it...they won't let us be...
Yes.... if...
Iike in my dream...
they are looking for us somewhere...
in this town...
What is it? Is something
wrong with that black Porsche?
Porsche 356A...
It's a classical car of 50 years ago...
The owner seems to be away.
I've only seen it on TV and in books,
but I guess there are people who
are really riding these cars around...
Gin...
Gin owns this...
?1 Gin...?]
Yes...
this car came out in my dream...
Hey, just what are you...?!
Oh, Doc? Willyyou bring-the following
things to the intersection of 4th street?!
I'll explain later! Hurry!!
Hey!
Did you bring the stuff?!
Y,Yeah... A wire
hanger and a wrench...
What are you going to
do with these things...?
H, Hey...
Old cars can be opened like this...
Shinichi?!
Just what are you going to do?!
I'm going to set a-wire tap
and transmitter up In the car.
But, you don't even know yet, if it's his...
Hmm? What's the matter?
OO... On the other side of the street...
On the other side of the street?
Gin... Vodka...
You idiot!!
Hmm...
The ground around the
car sure 1s messed up...
Maybe the passersby
were looking at your car,
ecause it's rare...
mF I11ioOoOocCcy... 1 Call LIHITITInK 101
myself, you German frog...
Bull's eye...
What a place to run into them...
I'm delighted... Gin!
I'm not letting them get away this time!!
Go straight...l want you to go after
them without getting too close...
No...
You won't be able to do a thing
even if you figure out where he is,
in our bodies now...
Do you have any idea,
what dangerous situation you are in now?
Shut up! Be quiet!!
Lephone...
Yeah, it's me...how's it going...?
What, he's hasn't come yet?
Phooey not big deal.
The target will come to Haido
City Hotel at 18:00 sharp...
Not even aware that it is going
to be his farewell party...
Target? Farewell party?
Anyway, we've got to shut him
up before he is arrested...
We can use that poison if needed...
The poison...?!
Don't goof, Pisco...
Pisco... .?
I've heard that code name before...
though I've never seen the person...
Haido City Hotel...
Reddish brown hair...?
Boss? What's up?
What is that...
It's probably a transmitter
and a wire tap...
Oh no, he's found it!!
W, What?!
I didn't think you'd
appear from your side...
I'm honored and welcome you...Sherry...
What're you going to do?
Things look really bad.
Your transmitter and wire tap have been
crushed, so we can't pursue them...
Moreover, the chewing gum that you
used to place them into their car...
IS In their hands...
If they ever check on that...
Don't worry!
I got rid of my teeth marks too,
and the most they can figure out
from my saliva is my blood type.
I wiped off all the
fingerprints in the car too.
Then, we should turn a corner and
pull away from them right away...
It's dangerous»to just vaguelyyfollow
the traces of their car like this...
Yeah...I'll stop pursuing them...
But, that doesn't mean
I'm going to run from them...
The Haido City Hotel...
They're planning to make a guy named
Pisco assassinate somebody there...
We've got to go to that hotel to
at least prevent the assassination...
My, how righteous...
Not for me
Besides, I'm not interested in
something abstract like righteousness...
I don't think we can do much anyway,
going to such a dangerous place...
Yeah...l don't intend
to take you along either.
It'll be too dangerous to take you along,
since they know what
you looke Mike, as a child.
Well, you just wait in the car with Doc!
If worse comes to worse, I'll at
Ieast try and get back the poison!
He poison...
Gin was saying,
We can use the poison if needed.
It's probably the APTX4869...
the one that shrunk our bodies...
the poison in question...
Yeah, right, Sherry...the chick
who betrayed the organization.
She should be headed that way soon...
If you don't know what she looks like
her up on the organization's data base.
After I check on whether she left anything
more than the wire tap and
transmitter that found,
I'll join you.
Yeah...I'm sure...she'll come...
because I mentioned the poison...
Its up to you whether you want to
take advantage of the dopey detective,
though...
Anyway, as soon as you find the chick,
how me what she looks like...
Yeah...No problem...
if she's gone from neck down...
Ghadsnlnl thought
you weren't interested?
I had no choice .
Because I'm the one
who made the poison.
I don't want you calling
me a killer anymore...
Be careful...
It's easy for them to tell too
the one who set the transmitter
will show up here too...
If they find out that you're involved...
Il be fine...
You got rid of the evidence, didn't you?
a simple prank or...
something done:by someone who
has a grudge against,the organization...
Are you sure it's this hall?
Yeah...Gin said that
it was a farewell partyO...
The guy called Pisco and-his target
are also supposed to come-here too.
That's enough talking already...
Here we go...
Damn...l know it's a farewell party, but
get a load of all the people in black...
Each and everyone of
them look suspicious...
Sherry...
A. Agh...
What's the matter
Iittle girl? Are you lost?
Uh-huh... we're looking
for them together...
Let's go, Hana!
Hey, what the hell is the matter
with you? It's not like you...
You're the one who said you
wanted to come along, right?
I saw asterrible dream...
A dream?
Gin found me on my
way back from school.
I was cornered into a back alley and...
You were the first one to get shot...
And with the dry sound
of the pistol going off,
people were killed one after the other...
Yes...just because they
were all involved with me...
Maybe I should've been executed
by them right there and then...
Do you know? You wear that
and nobody can tell who you are!
Oh my, then are you supposed to be
Superman without your glasses?
ThoughOI:can't fly!
Well, I guess it's better than nothing...
hank:wyou...
You've seriously got bad personality...
But, boss...l wonder if
she's really going to come?
She's that kind of ch
She'll try and stop the
poison from being used...
unaware that we will
e waiting for her...
What if she doesn't come?
At least I know that she's hiding
In the Beika Town vicinity...
If we find a clue as to where she lives,
hunting her down is no problem,
because traitors cannot
cover their smell up...
Indeed a farewell party for a master...
Look at all the big shots...
\ Mika Nanjo (38)
novelist
A woman novelist, winner
Ueki Award...
Mika Nanjo (38)
novelist
Mika-Nanjo (38)
Yasuo Mikame (62)
owner of a pro baseball team
HR RE S< (62)
DEIR RES -
The owner of a pro baseball team...
Yasuo Mikame (62)
owner of a pro baseball team
Naoya Tarumi (35)
musical producer
A top-notch musical producer...
Naoya Tarumi (35)
musical producer
2 IRF -bk (29)
A famous actress from the U.S...
Chris Vineyard (29)
actress
abe ad Cu
rig essLe
Yoshiharu Tawara (58)
university.professor
sl BS
La gsc ess.»
REAR
A famous university professor...
Yoshiharu Tawara (58)
university professor
&LL 2D
gue ssue
RFFIR
Yoshiharu Tawara (58)
university professor
rum esasue
NF IX
Yoshiharu Tawara (58)
university professor
guess Le
Kenzo Masuyama (71)
& On O
Ft WE - (71)
ERE XX -)-==F
Oops, a big shot of the world
of economics is also here...
Kenzo Masuyama (71)
Er Oh TI
fill! QEUI)
BRNX-=&
Kenzo Masuyama (71)
YE UMN TO
su == (71)
BhNX--7 =
And? Did you figure out
ho Pisco's target is...
Yeah...Gin was saying that the
target would be here around 18:00,
and is someone on the
wanted list of the police...
It's got to be that guy who is surrounded
by reporters at the entrance.
I...
ShigehikQNomiguchi (56)
PO 1 Icilan
The politician who made
the headlines sweating,
ShigehikofiNomiguchi (56)
politician
es IF
while justifying himself received...
ShigehikmNomiguchi (56)
politician
501 MES (56) )
Shigehiko:Nomiguchi (56)
politician
IX 5 #X
If they want to shut him
up before he is nabbed,
could he be a member
of the organization too?
I wonder... We'll find
out when he's nabbed.
Please explain it so we understand!
Will you excuse me...?
My. Inspector Megure...!...
I called him from the restroom a
while ago,using my, voicelchanger...
and told him that somebody
is after the life of that politician...
ow what, Pisco...
You couldn't possibly assassinate
someone under this condition could you?
If you intend to carry out
your mission aggressively,
I'll put you sleep with this gun of mine...!
Ladies and Gentlemen!
Naomichi Mugikura (43)
announcer
EE HE 43)
77"???
Now, we will view a secret film...
Naomichi Mugikura (43)
announcer
Pro?
Naomichi Mugikura (43)
announcer
director Sakamaki had
hidden all the while he was alive!
Naomichi Mugikura (43)
announcer
77"???
S. Slide?!
Now, can anyone tell me where
and when this film was taken?
Hey, that politician is leaving!
What?!
Hey, hurry up and look for him!!
Yes, sir!
Damn, where the hell
Is he?'Where'd he go?!
This is one of Dire
Sakamaki's major films!
The one that received various awards
the filming of "The Rainbow
Colored Handkerchief".
This is an important slide of the time
the director's hair was still fluffy.
How is it?
No, we can't find him yet!
Look closer!
Yes, sir!
Let's go on to the next picture.
This looks to be a snap shot of lunch
they are having in between filming...
Although I'm pretty
sure you're all familiar.
Director Sakamaki used to love soba!
Since the filming of the "Rainbow
Colored Handkerchief" was in Shinshu,
everyday at lunch time,
he would go here and there to try out
one soba restaurant after another.
By the time filming ended,
it is said that-herused
to say gregariously that...
All the soba shops in
Shinshu are mine."
Let's go on to the next slide!
Let's roll it,one after the other.
Huh? A flash?!
Oh, I know how precious the picture is,
but it won't come out if
you use a flash unit!
What's that?
What was that sound?!
Above?!
Hat the...
W, What was that sound?!
Hey, what's up?!
What was that sound?!
Hurry, turn the lights on!!
What the hell is going on, anyway?!
Handkerchief...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS BY
Kan 1 Kashiwabara
9 a 090
Kazunari ouch
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS YOF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaea
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
ixYomiuri. Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyanta Shogakukan
Il Rights Reserved
here they are! Just as I thought.
Pisco is one among the seven of them!!
Haibara, big trouble! They're coming!!
Haibara