Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
Danger is closing in, Haibara and Conan.
There are many people
appearing in-this episode.
He:sees through the 'he and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene.
On the way home from school,
we run into the car of one of
the men in black, Gin's car.
+ I'set a transmitter and wire tap
up in the car and we pursue them!
However, Gin finds the gadgets.
He realizes that Haibara is around!!
We found out about Gin and
his men plan to kill somebody.
We head for a memorial
service of a movie director...
To be held at aido City¥Hotel.
Hey, that politician is gone!
What?!
What was that?
A handkerchief...?
Re-Encounter with the Men in Black"
(Conan's Story)
The chandelier .
WwW, What happened?
T,This ls...
Oft IN Bo
VY FICHBIDIrD
What is going on?
Wonder...
What on earth is it?
Hey! Will-'somebody
explain what's going on?!
Quiet please, everyone!
I am Inspector Megure
of the police department!!
Oh----you're here so early for a change.
omeone repor e a a mur er was
going to be committed here tonight...
That someone was after
the life of Mr. Nomiguchi!!
How is he, Detective Takagi?
No good...he's not breathing...
I see...contact the
department right away.
Yes, sir!
He's the killer
One of the men in black
who shrunk my body...
Code name, Pisco!!!
Hers still somewhere in here!!!
Oh...l see...
Then you were the ones
closet to Nomiguchi
when the chandelier came falling?
Did you see anyone
suspicious at that time?
I didn't have time to be looking...
Yoshiharu Tawara (58)
university professor
universityiprofessor
because I was almost crushed
by the chandelier too
Yoshiharu Tawara (58)
universityiprofessor
because I was almost crushed
by the chandelier too
Take a look at this!
The chandelier skimmed
y my suit and it tore...
I see.
Inspector, she says she hasn't
seen anyone suspicious.
It's an accident, a mere accident!
Naoya Tarumi (35)
musical producer
The chain of the chandelier
got old and broke off,
Naoya Tarumi. (35)
musical producer
and the politician coincidentally
got crushed to death under it...
Naoya Tarumi. (35)
musical producer
But, somebody reported that there
was going to be a murder, right?
What about that?
Kenzo Masuyama (71)
Uh I5
BX-73
Before you suspect us,
Kenzo Masuyama (71)
2 DOA TS
LJ OE
RST ID
I would sure like to know more about
the person who reported the murder...
Kenzo Masuyama (71)
HE >< - Fy
After all ythat person
may be the murderer...
The person was using a voice changer
that we couldn't make out
whether it was a man or woman...
It could've been a prank then...
chi Mugikura (43)
(43)
Many people detested Nomiguchi
for being suspected of bribery so...
hi Mugikura (43)
Many people detested Nomiguchi
for being suspected of bribery so...
That's right,
and it just so happened that the accident
happened after the crank call
He was punished by the heavens!
Yasuo Mikame (62)
owner of a pro baseball team
Yasuo Mikatme: (62)
owner of a prof baseball team
You really can't get
away with evil doings.
Yasuo Mikame (62)
owner of a pro baseball team
I don't see how you can
at in this situation...
Phooey! I wish timid
greenhorns would shut up!
Hey, somebody go get the chef!!
What's the matter? Did you find
a cockroach in there or something?
That's because you ate a time like this
You're being punished
by the heavens too!
Come, now, let's all calm down...
T.This is...A piece of broken
chain from the chandelier?
Was it. found there...
Anyway. politician Nomiguchi
died because the chandelier
Mika Nanjo (38)
novelist
which came falling from
above crushed him, right?
Mika Nanjo (38)
thovelist
which came falling from
above crushed him, right?
If it were homicide,
then there would have:had
to be a rig of some kind.
And somebody would've had to
take him under the chandelier
after the place got dark
Hot...
there seems to be no such
rigs on the ceiling
that it was hanging from either...
Therefore dmurder'd be impossible!
Now that it's cleared.
May please be excused
That's true
Dropping the chandelier
on the target in the dark,
would've been impossible unless
something were to be set up beforehand
But, the killer succeeded in doing so. %.
Hey, where're we going
We're getting out of here.
It's too dangerous to spend
meaningless time here any. longer!
Besides...
If Inspector Megure and
the others see us here,
how are we going to
explain why we're here?
The.only clue there is,
is the broken off piece of chain
that you.picked: up a while ago.
You couldn't possibly figure out
who the killer is with just that...
What if I have two cluesy
After the'chandelier fell and
before the'lights came back on,
this handkerchief came falling...
So what?
The name of the killer
is not written on it is it?
See, look in the corner of
this handkerchief:the words,
Memorial Service for
Director Sakamaki" are sewn on
The owner of this handkerchief
received it here at the reception desk!
Besides: look*at everyone around you...
See, that man with the glass cup,
the plump lady next to him,
and the old man with
the beard who is beyond,
they all have handkerchieves...
The colors are different!!
What does that mean?
Probably...
because they passed out
handkerchieves of 7 different colors
in memonr of Director Sakamaki's
best movie, "Rainbow Handkerchief"
In other words,
if we check at the reception desk on
who received purple handkerchieves,
we have more or less a clue!
But...
we won't be able to determine whether
the owner'is involved with the killing.
Yeah...
still can't tell what it was used for or
whether it belongs to the killer or not...
But, the possibility that it has nothing
to do with the killing is not zero, right?
Excuse me, officer
Hmm?
May I go to the restr om?
Okay .. £
Hey, hold it, what're you all doing here?!
Is it true that politician
Nomiguchi passed away?!
I hear it was an accident...?
W about it?!
We'll explain everything later
so stand back everyone!!
Hey, wait!
Please answer us!!
Sherry
Huh? Who I gave the';
purple handkerchief to?
Ep! I picked that handkerchief up.
So I want to give it back to the owner!
That handkerchief was supposed to
be used for something later, right?
Yes, at the end of the gathering,
a certain color of handkerchief
was supposed be chosen,
and the people. with that
color of handkerchief
was supposed to make comments...
Can you give me the names!
I'll go look for the person who
doesn't have a handkerchief.
What shall we do, Inspector?
If we hold them back any longer,
e may cause a racket.
It looks like an.accident no matter
how you look at it too,
SO maybe:we should
Iet them go for now
Yes, sir...
I've found the person, sonny!
The ones's who are.in the room now,
re the seven people here... There
Thank you!
I see, those seven...
I can't be absolutely sure...
but maybe one of their members
sco is among the seven...
Hey, they're.coming out!
Excuse me. were you nearby
when the accident occurred ?!
I don't 'know! :Get.out.of my'way!! *
Please tell us the-details of the accident.
Ask the police, not me!
Damn, let's go back to
Doc's car-for. now, H3ibara!
Hey, Haibara?!
Where are you? Answer met
gh, wait
Hey, where are you?!
Answer me!
Haibara
Al. Wake up, Al
What's thegqmatter?
We're having class now
Could it be because of your cold?
Maybe you should go rest
in the infirman after all...
A dream...
Ga . >
rLirgrie... rigger ase Co
It can't be coincidence that
I ran intothimvin town...
All my dreams are the sameirecently...
wonder if I'm tired.
Haibara...
Answer me, Haibara...
Who is it?
Hey,-Haibara?!
Who is it?!
Haibarar!
Haibara??!
SS, Shinichi?
Haibara? Is it you, Haibara?!
Where are you?
In Doc's car in front of the hotel!
I'm using the microphone and
speaker that is built into my glasses
and communicating with you.
What happened...to me?
That's what I'd like to know!
What happened in the
corridor in front of¢the hall?!
I $front-of'the hall?...
Oh, I was swallowed by the crowd
of people .-VYand'lost track of you...
Somebody came at me from behind...
What from behind?
Somebody made me sniff' something
and I'm confined in a
wine cellar or something.
H Hey, somebody, don't tell 'me that...
S...The one who committed th
murder under the ven eyes of the police
is one of the members
of the organization...
Pisco!
What?!
Don't tell me he's near you?!
No, that somebody
is not here right now...
The door of this room is
securely locked.though .
The only thing that I see here are a box on
a baggage cart, and a janitor's overalls
Overalls?
Yes...after I was made
to sniff something,
he probably took me to the restroom
and changed into overalls,
then, he put me in this cardboard
box and brought me here...
I think that if he goofed killing
that politician in the hall,
he was going to carry out the killing
in the restroom and bring him here...
Okay, we've got to find a way to get you
out of there, and we've got to do it fast
Listen, Shinichi, listen very carefully...
The "Apo" in the Apotoxin
486 J3*thatishrunk my body
means. death of program
es...cells have a
self-destruction structure,
and is existing because of a
signal that keeps that in check...
hey AIAadl d
But, this drug not only guides apotosis,
it also waits for the
activation. of trimorphism
and increases multiplication efficiency...
Cut it out, Haibaral! I'll listen to all you
ave say after you get out of there...
Never mind, and just listen, williyou!!
Because I'm never going to be «
able...to...to talk to you again...}
What?
Can't you tell?
They kidnapped me
despite me being a child.
Even if were.to.able to get.out of here,
they would track medowniin'a day or two
If that happens. they will annihilate
Dr Agasa.who had sheltered me.
As well as everyone I am involved
with in order to protect their secret...
Now, do you understand?
Whether I am killed here
or whether I get out of here
I will never be able
Oo see you all again...
Haibara...
That's why I'm going tojgive you all
the information on the drug while, I can.
Taraaah! "The Great Adventure
f Dr. Agasa Part II"
H,Hey, what was that...
Oh, the game that DrsAgasa made that
Mitsuhiko gavelback toime atsschool...
They probably checked the
MO that was in my pocket...
A cellular phone connected
to the computer means.
Just as I thought.
They were searching my face...
Hey, you're not tied up?
That's why I'm rushing! .
They wouldn't leave me for a long time
without even tieing me up, would they?
0...They won't be back for a while yet
Huh?
After you disappeared, I called
the: Inspectorimmediately...
And told him not to let the seven
who received the purple handkerchief
out of the Haido City Hotel
using Shinichi's voice!
The fact that you're not bonded,
and thatthe cellular is connected
to the computer goes to show
that the guy who confined you
wanted to leave the hotel...
just for a while for something,
but was stopped at the door by the
officers.and is being questioned now!
Moreover, it is ve: likely'that'he ;
made contact with those outside.
It's been an hour since
you disappeared, and yet,
it's unthinkable that nobody including
the guy who kidnapped you isn't back.
Just as I thought...
the guy who committed the
murder is among the seven
He assassinated his target
And confined you there
the guy called Pisco!!!
Then, you mean I'm still
inside Haido City Hotel?
Yeah, most probably!
If we can find proof that
he committed the murder
before he contacts the others,
and hand him over to the police,
you're still safe!
The longest the Inspector can keeps
them in the room is another hour...
I'll go ask the employee of the hotel if
they have a wine cellar that's not in use,
and get you out of there!
If I say . that argirlrisilocked.-in_ 27 _
You idiot...
Didnt I just tell you. what will:happen
to people who. get involvedywith:me?
It's not my fault.if something happens
to the enmiployee:who helps:me-out*
Then, why don't you find a way
to get out of there yourself!
In the mean time I'll go and figure
out which of the seven is Pisco...
You sayit.like it's "so simple,
but there is no escape route
here... 'only an old fireplace...
Can"you climb up that:fireplace?
Impossible...it's too wide to climb.
If I weren't this small,
I could probably use my hands and
Iegs and get out of here, but...
Isn't there.a rope or something?
I wonder...would they have
a rope in a wine cellar...?
Are there all kinds of liquor in there?
It seems that they pac
Iiquorifrom*all over the world.
Into this room that is not
being used anymore,
and turned it into
wine cellar...
Do you see something
called Paikal there
Paikal?
Yeah, it's a very strong Chinese liquor.
I don't know...
Look for it!
} wonder if ll can...
Why do you want me
to look for it, anyway...
How's! your cold?
Didn't you say:you were coming
down with one-this morning AN
What areiyou'a.scatter.brain...
Never mind, how are you feeling?
Thanks to being left lying on the floor
for a while, I think my fever went up.
1 HDTCo
You sound a bit happ
Sort of 4
I found, the Paikal...
But, what do I do with this liquor...?
I'm going to help you get out of there...
I'm going to put a real
ancy spe on you...
That was the scene.
Right after the accident?
MP rT
In-a-rogmjylocated near
the scene of the accident,
ittseems-that:several people have
been called in for questioning.
The names of these people
have not been announced...
This was brought to
you live from:the scene.
From the televised broadcast just now,
I've figured out the approximate positions
of the seven right after the murder.
But, this isn't enough...
Um ..what's the spelling
for Et Liqueur Poalo?
Hey. what're you doing?Did you
drinksthe Paikal like I told you to?
VesBidid.
I don't know what you're trying to do,
but Imsfeeling as worse as ever...
Give me the spelling for Poalo...
it's H-e-r-c-u-l-e P-0-i-r-o-t,
why do you want know
I'm trying to download the data
of that drug to Dr.,Agasa's MO,
but it requires a password.
No good...l can't open
with Poirot either...
What do you mean
the password is Poirot?
People of the organization
used to call this drug in its trial.
Serial number 4869 was coded
Sherlock... for inefficient detective...
That's why I'm entering the
names of all the detectives...
I can think of one after the other...
I, guess its not all that easy
Shelling Ford...
Huh?
It's spelled. S-h-e-l-l-i-n-g F-0-r-d...
Was there'a detective by that name?
Never mindNjust enter it!
L-L-I-N-G-F-O-R-D...
Mt opened... why?
The name Shelling Ford,
is the temporary name that Conan Doyle
named the detective of his novel,
before the detective
was renamed Sherlock.
In other words, this detective
was in his trial stage!
Oh...itys a pretty fancy thing
for the organization to do
We.don't have much time left...
How're you doing?
Of course hm doing terrible,
rinking that liquor...
I'm going to download the data of the
drug into the MO, and hide it here,
so come get later, okay...
After they come to get me...
H Hey.
S Shinichi, in front of you...
It sithem:-- Don't tell me
they've .come'for Pisco...
No, no-way!
Before the seven people are released,
the Inspector is 'supposed 'to call'me'...
Don't tell me that a transmitter was built
in to the computer that Ai was using...
I see, since they couldn't get through
by phone, they followed the transmitter...
Ail, big trouble!
They're coming! Hide in the
fireplace or something for now...
Hey, what's up?!
Inspector, Shinichi here!!
Huh?! A man in black?!
ORIGINAL COMMIT BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Mich Biko Suwa
Masah to Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Kxtsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatdmo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi loka
CRIPTS BY.
Kanji hashiwabara
Kizunarir ouch:
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORSYOF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Trhkash Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ovaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okadr
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in association with
Yomiuri-Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyanfay/ 'Shogdkl an
TV / TMS
II Rights Reserved
Pisco isn't here...
urn mar s. IC means
hat this chain was...
e...So, that's what it wa
I really missed you Sherry...
Ay -11