Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
e ucions a ea S apes an Syes
in each and every case to be solved.
The story takes a sharp turn.
The secret of the Black
Organization is coming to light.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the l.Q. of
an adult, no case is left unsolved
when Detective Conan
comes to the scene.
On the way back from school,
Al and I run into the car of Gin,
one of the men of the
Black Organization.
I set a transmitter and wire tap
into his car:and pursued him!
But, the devices were destroyed
by Gin who found them.
They have realized the existence of Ail!
Finding out by wire tap about the
murder plans of Gin and the men,
we headed for the memorial service
of movie director Sakamaki to be
heldesat the Haido Ci. Hotel.
During slide showing time at that hall,
the chandelier comes
falling from the ceiling,
and a politician named Nomiguchi
was crushed when the chandelier
came falling right at him and died.
Moreover. Ail was
kidnapped by someone,
and was locked:up in the
wine cellar of the hotel!
Listen, Shinichi, listen very carefully...
The "Apo" in the Apotoxin
4869 that{shrunk my body.
Means death of program...
es...cells have a
self-destruction structure,
and is existing because of a
signal that keeps that in check...
Hey...Haibara...
But, this drug not only guides apotosis,
it also waits for the
activation of, trimorphism
and increases multiplication efficiency...
Cut it out, Haibarall I'll listen to all you
ave say after you get out of there...
Never mind, and just listen, willfyou!!
Because I'm never going to be
able...to...to talk to you again..."
What?
Can't you tell?
(Case
Re-Encounter with the Men in Black"
I'm going to download the
data of the drug into the" MO,
and hide it here. so come
get it later, okay.!...
After they come to get me...
n,ney...
S Shinichi, in front of you...
Huh?
1.It's them
Don't tell me they've come for Pisco...
No, no way!
Before the seven people are released the
Inspector is supposed to call me...
Al, big trouble! They're coming!
Hide in the fireplace or
something for now... now...
Hey, what's up?!
Hey?!"
Inspector, Shinichi here!!
Huh?! A man in black?!
IIsco's not here...
He promised to meet us in 30 minutes...
But, we don't hear a thing from him...
SO we use the transmitter
as a guide and came here,
only to find the computer
and no sight of him...
Where on earth did he disappear to...?
What's with this liquor cellar anyway...?
Probably a room that Pisco
had kept, just in case...
If the goofed in killing the guy at the hall,
he was probably going to kill the guy
some place else and bring him here...
I think we'd better get out of
here really fast, boss...
Yeah...
Hey?
Yes.
And? What:about your cloth IN
You lewd bastard!
I'm dressed!
In the overalls that I found in the cellar.
I also have the MO with the data
of the drug that I copied too.
What a surprise!
I wonder if that liquor called Paikal...
has an enhancing factor that quickens
the speed of cell multiplication?
That's nothing to be relieved about,
because the effect is only temporary!
Get out of there from the chimney before
your body returns to that of a child!
I feel just like Cordelia
crawling out of the well...
h...talk about a long way to go.
Sigh...by the way...
Did you figure out who Pisco is?
No, not yet.
I don't have enough information...
Look, Shinichi, tomorrow morning's
5» paper that is on the internet!
I saw that a while ago,
ut I didn't see anything...
No. the place to look
is the show biz section!
What?!
The camera man.who was at.the hall
seems-to have taken it
just before the chandelier fell...
They are the two among
the seven, right?
Ait a sec! Maybe...
The traces of a burn!!
Which means that this chain...
CL OD
So, that's what it was...
Haido City Hotel
The old building
RT )vi8
I.I'm out...
Good work, All
Can you tell where you are?
On a roof somewhere...
Is Shinichi there?
He was talking to Inspect
Megure till just a while ago,
but he went rushing into the hotel...
V Rushing ins'
Don't worry!
He told me to relay this message to you.
I figured out Pisco's identity!
I'll. go pick you upright away,
so stay put and wait for me."
Fuh...I'm fine!
Even if I wanted to move...
I'm so worn out, I can't move an inch...
missed you, Sherry...
(G,Gin...)
how beautiful, white
snow that flutters in darkness.
Bright scarlet blood that
spreads over the snow...
That glasses and overalls you
are wearing to deceive us
are miserable attire for dying...
But, this place is just a great place to die,
right, Sherry?
H.How did you figure out I was going
to come out of this chimney...?
Your hair...
I found your reddish brown
hair near the fireplace...
I don't know if Pisco got you,
or if you snuck into that
Iiquor cellar yourself, but...
you trembling as you
breathed from within the fireplace...
I could've killed you right on
the spot in that dirty fireplace.
But I thought I'd at least let you die
a little more glamorously.
Oh, well thank you so very much, for
waiting in such a cold place for me...
Phooey! Now, won't you tell me
while your lips are still moving?
The trick that you used to disappear from
e gas CC am er o e organiza ion...
Huh? The liquor cellar?
Uh-huh! I think it's a room
with a large fireplace in it...
I wonder if we had that kind
of a room in this hotel...?
Maybe)it's-inzthe.old building that
Is,going to be renovated soon?
Old building?
Yes! I heard-that, they're using one of
the rooms there as a storage room
A storage room? That's it!!
Hey, wait, sonny?!
I'm sure that: Pisco is headed there too.
If he joins those two. theyll. find, out
that Ai shrunk because of the drug»
Damn! If only Inspector Megure could've
kept them confined another 5 minutes.
Hmm?
What?! Al was shot?!
Right!! On a\roof somewhere by
them!! Hurry and go there or.
Hey, Doc! Doc
Damn! The battery's dead!
s...she won't tal
We've got no choice...
I guess we'll just have to send her off...
To where. we: sent her older
sister before 'her...
A needle'?!...
Agh, boss?
The chimney!!
Go inside the chimney!!
W...Who are you? You're?!
Hurry!
Shoots!
Boss!! What's the matter, Boss?!
Oh~~~how wonderful!
I guess you don't remember
because you were still a baby,
but I was on very intimate terms with
your parents who were scientists.
They told me a lot about the drug
they were in the process of developing
Who is he?
But I didn't think you
had developed it'this'far...
I'm sure that your parents
who have died of an accident
is truly happy about this too.
Who. are you?
Ut this is an order...
Shiho...
That's it!!
Mr. Masuyama?
Or should I call you Pisco, instead?
Who are you?...
You may think that you
succeeded in-dropping
the chandelier,on Nomiguchi
and made it look like an accident but
You're not getting away with that
You're the one who dropped it, right?
When you used the gun with a silencer!
Your guide was the fluO ascent
paint that you had painted
on the chain of the
chandelier beforehand.
When the lights were turned out for
the slide show and the room got dark...
The glow of the chain could be seen!
If you fired just like that,
then the people around you would
notice the sparks from your gun...
If you put the handkerchief
on the tip of the silencer
the handkerchief would go off
at the same time you fire your gun,
so the sparks wouldn't be visible!
You probably used the handkerchief
that was handed out at the hall
because you thought that you wouldn't
have to go and retrieve it but...
unfortunately...
Most of the guests who hadereceived the
purple handkerchief had alreadyjgone home,
and the suspects left were
only the seven of you
Mr. Tawara and Chris who were right
below the chandelier
and couldn't aim it are innocent
Mr. Mikame who spit out the piece of chain
from his mouth, that was used as proof,
and the MC Mr. Mugikura are also innocent
Mr. Tarumi and Ms. Nanjo
who were embracing each other
just before the incident
are out of the question.
In other words the only one who could've
committed the murder at the hall is...
you, Mr Masuyama!
There!!
And, Mr Nomiguchi came below
the space in the wooden box chandelier
because fluorescent paint was
paine ono re oorrig un er
You probably threatened him, who
was going to be arrested any minute
by saying,
You'll be given another chance so when
the lights go out, go to the glowing spot
and wait for further orders!"
Isn't that right, Pisco?
A speaker?!
W., Who are you?!
Who the hell are you?!
Conan Edogawa, a detective!!
A A detective. 7?
Don't-tell me that§you're the one
who called the police
while w, we were being questioned?
Uh... You 1nd the other two "bove
will be arrestedrby the police anyway.
Before that I'd like you to tell me,
why did you have that purple
handkerchief on you during questioning?
That's why the Inspector had
no choice but to release you
Why in the world did you
have that handkerchief...
Phooey! There are things in this world
that you don't need to know about.
Besides, take a good look at the situation!
You couldn't have called the police
You had better t
a good look yourself...
at your feet!
Spiritas
It has an alcohol content as strong as 96!
You understand, don't you?
What will happen if you smoke in a
place where such liquor is evaporating?
A fire broke out from room
404 of the old building.
I repeat, a fire broke out from
room 404 of the old building
What?!
Let's go check it out!
Hmm!
Hey brat, where the hell are you?!
Come out here!
Damn!
Where the hell are youl!
So that's where you:are...
J.Just what do you think
ou're doing, Gin
Have*you gone senile, Pisco?
Why didn't you kill that camera man off
right away and get rid of the film?
Camera man? What're you talking about?!
The picture that's supposed to make
the front pages tomorrow morning
has been switched to your face
The zoomed up picture of you
pointing the gun at the ceiling!
D.Don't! If you kill me, you
won't be able to find Sherry
I have an idea of where she is
And, besides if you kill me,
who has served that person,
you'll get yourself in trouble too
I'm sorry, but I just got orders personally
from that person a while. ago to kill you!!
What?!
You borrowed the power of the organi
zationiarid'made it all the way up here
I'll bet you've already
seen enough good dreams...
Dream the rest of your
dream:in the world beyond...
What?! Gin shot Pisco to death?
I heard this throug
glasses that Ai left by the fireplace,
but it seems that he fled from the
chimney right after shooting the guy.
Strange! Why can he move despi
te being shot with the anesthetic gun?
I figured that though such a big man
He wouldn't be able to flee from
the police if he fell asleep...
And it also bugs me that they new too
much of what Ail was planning to do...
It seems that they knew that
Ai was going to be at the hall,
and besides can you usually tell who
the person is just by looking at the hair?
You know what Ail. when
you were at the organization .
And,
Did they find out that I shrank...?
No, I don't think so, nojneed for worry.
And what do you intend
to do from now on?
Well...
As long as they know I'm hiding in this
town, I can no longer stay near all of you
And besides, the MO that I had in the
overall probably went up in flames too,
that I have no reason to stay here anymore.
Don't worry, I'll leave by tomorrow...
Hey, hey. you can't possibly
Ieave in your condition!!!
All righto
Don't worry about that!!
Huh.
Aren't you going to look
for the chick here in this town?
I don't like to waste time
She's not stupid enough
to stick around in this town
knowing that we know what she looks like!
You're really into that lassie, aren't you...
Phooey! Well, I'm so sorry, Bellmott.
A woman of your,rank was called
in just to assist that old fogey,
and all he ends up doing is goof.
Really..l went out of my way to give him the
handkerchief before questioning and yet...
He did right to die...
Doesn't the guy who's sticking
around with that lassie bother you?
Ah...l sure would like to see the f
of the guy that's drooling all over her
es...his dead face distorted with fear.
Are you gong back to the States again?
No, I'm going to rest working
as an actress for a while
I'm going to take it easy in Japan...
Besides. I have something
that concerns me too...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michilitko Suwa
Masai: 70 Yoshloka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Misatdomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kizunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatdmo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
T1kashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIREC OR OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Tvkashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Jaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Ok1da
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DET CTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyant / Shogdkukan
Il Rights Reserved
At any rate, Inspector! Please don't leak
the fact that I was involved in this case
That's all right with me, but what
on earth is going on anyway?
The family of the murdered
Nomiguchi disappears,
and the house of Chairman Masuyama,
the suspect, burns down completely.
I don't have the slightest
idea what is going on
I can't tell you anything just yet!
I'll contact you when I figure it out...
H, Hey! Shinichir
es...get rid of anybody
and anything suspicious
This is the way they carry on.
Now you know, don't you?
That we can't afford to have
anybody know our true identity...
Yeah! Do I!
Know now that I've got to.crush
them all no matter what the cost!
WwW. What was that?
This is...
Strange... What's that supposed to mean?
Did he get hurt in the restroom or
something? But...Why...?
Doc! This is homicide!
What...
Coffee Shop Track Crash"