Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
Today there is a coffee shop
Iocated by a slope.
A truck comes crashing.
Is this a case or an accident?
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of
an adult, no case is left unsolved
A child in appearance with the l1.Q. of
when Detective Conan
comes to the scene.
Heave, heave...l can't walk anymore
Hey, hang in there.
Just a little more to go...
According to Doc's map it's right
around the curve up ahead...
Hang in there, Genta.
Hey, maybe taking the bus
would've been faster!
No way. We're going to
be treated to lunch,
so if we take the bus it would
render everything meaningless
You mean you just wanted
to save bus fare?!
What a tight brat...
Coffee Shop Truck Crash"
Uh, it's supposed to be around here...
Hey, Mitsuhiko, isn't that it?
Huh?
Peach Sunday!...
This is the place after all.
Can you read English, Mitsuhiko?
No big deal...
Come on let's go inside. I'm starved!
Yes, let's!
Hello.
$ an du
Uh, we're...
The Youth Detective Squad, right?
You're going to meet. with
Dr. Agasa here, aren't. you?
This way please.
Hi there, welcome to our shop.
Dr. Agasa called me about you...
He said that he's going to be a little late,
so for you to eat anything you like.
All right!! It looks so good!
Hey, Genta, ladies first.
Of course!
Thank you.
Hello.
My name is Ohara.
I have reservations...
Oh, please come this way.
The most recommended
menu here is Sundae!
It's the master's original menu!
I'll take that, then!
Me too!
What would you like, Conan?
Huh?...
Oh, the same as all of you is fine...
Four Peach Sundaes please!
Okay.
It looks delicious!!
This is reall , delicious!
You see!
Aren't you going to eat, Conan?
Aren't you goingpto eat, Conan?
Huh?
Give it to me then!!
Ah, Genta!
What a waste if the ice cream melts.
What's that?! Leaflets again?
It's a rush job.
They're going to be passing it out...
at the shopping arcade
this coming Sunday.
Kazuo Ohara
Ohara Planning President
You should just refuse
such a cheap paying job.
Toru Aida
Ohara Planning Designer
I can't do that.
This is*the kind of job that leads
to a stable income! Right?
Right...
Will you think about the you know
No matter how many times you ask me
my answer will not change.
Is it money you want?!
If so I'll increase the amount...
I don't think you can, with
the work that doingfhow!
Maybe not just yet, but
I promise.that-Somedayl'll...
There you go again...
Can't you do something about it?
Talk about persistent.
I don't want to end my
Iife making leaflets.
Working-with you is ruining my*talent.
Take it easy. I'll bet you don't )
have any on the pamphlets...
of the resort hotel that I'm asking
you to work on this time.
Yeah, as for that, I'll take the job as pay!
You can't handle it any way
if I leave, you?
What...?!
But, I promise to finish these
Ieaflets before I leave.
Let's get started.
You're in a rush, aren't you?
I'm<going to the restroom.
It was delicious!
Huhy.!
Two of them?
Mitsuhiko, what's your
second recommendation?
You'll get a stomach ache
if you eat too much.
I'll be fine, no big deal
I told you so
I have to go to the restroom.
Agh, Genta somebody's
using the restroom now...
Huh, somebody's inside!!
Boy, that was good!
It's indeed worth recommending.
Oh, Genta, someone was inside, right?
Yeah.»
I don't know who's in there, but
he doesn't answer when I knock!!
Oh, he's come out.
Whoopee! Saved!
If you're going to order another
serving, order one for me too!
Huh?
He's using his right hand this time...
He's ambidextrous.
Hello.
Oh» Dr.¢Agasa.
I'm sorry I'm late
We're all digging in
OhAea »all you-like.
I won the raffle at the shopping arcade!!
Okay then I'll take...
Chocolate.parfaitqpudding a la mode
and strawberry short cake!
Is your stomach okay?
No problem, no problem!
Look at that bus.
I wonder what it is. It's beautiful!
Truem.
I think I dropped my lighter. I'll go check.
I want it done by sundown.
I'm countin Yon you
Yes yes...
Hey Conan, what are you going to have?
Oh, I'll have coffee.
Coffee?
Oh, no, I mean...
W What Is this?
W Whatyis this?!
Which means that you just
happened to leave your-seat,
s \ ou were spared?
Yes, I just happened to go to
the restroom to look for my lighter...
Thank goodness you were spared...
Oh, you're the president of
Ohara Planning...
The office is located right
above this hill, isn't it...?
Mr. Saito!
I've found the driver of the truck!!
Okay, I'll be right there!
Did you park your car part
way up the slope like this
and make your delivery?!
I'm sorry, I usually park on
a flat place up the slope
but that car was parked here today,
so had no choice but to
park my car in front of it.
I made sure my side brakes were locked
and had my gear in reverse
just to be safe!
Mr. Saito I went to the site right away
checked the driver's seat but
the side brakes weren't locked!
It can't be!! Please
check more carefully!lq
I'm positive that I pulled my
side brakes and locked it!!
Of course he's lying!!
Ida was...
Aida was my precious right hand man...
Without him, my company Is finished...!!
Oh no . did someone pass away?!
President!!
S.Segawa...
What are you doing.in a place like this?!
If we don't deposit the money today,
they're going to stop
shipment of the goods!
Michiko Segawa
Employee of Ohara Planning
I know... But, this is no
time for something that...
Aida passed away...
What?!
He got mixed up in an accident...
OO. Oh no...
Strange...l wonder what it means...?!
Hey, Conan!
Conan!
Hey, this place is off limits!!
I forgot something in the restroom.
He was licking his finger when
he first came out of the restroom...
I wonder if he got hurt in the restroom...?
But...why...?
Bloodsstains?
These are traces of a hand
touching the frame from outside .!
I see
The blood got here when he
came back from outside...
That's why therewas no
answer Genta knocked.
Mr. Ohara wasn't in the toilet then.
He hurt his left hand
when he was outside.
That's:.why he held the pencil
in his right after coming back...
But...where did he go to do what...?
Before the accident, Mr. Ohara seemed
very concerned about the time...
Did he have to go out at a certain time...
time.
Time...
Hey Conan, where were you?
Oh, I just went to get
something I forgot...
Does anybody remember what
time the accident occurred?
About 14.10. It was right
after Dr. Agasa got here.
There's one at 14:07...
Is something wrong?
Yeah...
I wonder what route
the bus that left here
just before the accident took...?
I think it's about time it'll come back.
It supposed .to make a round from the
complex back to the shopping arcade.
Why was that bus parked?
This is the terminal as well as the depot,
so the buses take a 5 to 10 minutes
time adjustment break time.
What is it?
Do we have a case?!
No fair Conan! You're
always hogging the clues!
He's right!
Hey I'd like to ask you kids
some questions too,
so come here, will you.
Okay
A piano cord...?
I see, I've got it!
This is homicide!!!
And the killer is...
I'm sure it's him!!
Uh, officer
Yes?
I have some urgent business to attend to
so I'd like to be excused for a while.
We can't allow that.
I have to go make a bank
transfer to one of my clients.
30 minutes, no:20 minutes, please.
Has he been interrogated?
Yes, briefly.
I guess, you can go, then.
Thank you so much!
No good! If he is released, he'll go
and get rid of all the evidence!!
Doc!
This is homicide!
WwW. What....?!
Move your lips like always for me!
OO, Okay!
Wait just a minute!
Who, me?
Yes, I can't have you leave just yet.
What are you talking about?
We've got a homicide case!
Who are you?
I am Dr. Agasa.
Will outsiders stay out of this!!
Hold it, let's at least hear him out.
Dr. Agasa, do you have any lead?
I not only have a lead, I even have proof.
R. Ohara...
I have proof that you are the killer
Don't be ridiculous!
No matter how you at it,
this is an accident caused by the
carelessness of the driver
whose truck crashed into the shop!
That's not true!
Let us hear, Dr. Agasa. «
All right, let me start with the
trick involved in this case...
Nonsense!
I'm a busy man! I don't have time to
wasting listening to a fabricated story!!
Mr. Ohara!
It'll just be a short while,
so let's hear him out.
Please go ahead.
Mr. Ohara, you parked your
car on the top of the hill
where the courier truck always parks
Then you asked Mr Aida
to come with you
to the coffee shop
at the bottom of the hill.
And then, you made him
sit by the window
so that he couldn't see the
slope from his side...
Isn't that right?
I didn't make him sit by the window
so that he couldn't see the slope!
The place is sat just happened
to be by the window!
See...Then, you left a while late
in the middle of negotiations...
pretending to go to the restroom.
I wasn't pretending!
I really went to the restroom!!!
That's strange...Genta here says,
he tried knocking at the door many times
but that you didn't answer?
That's right. My stomach was
so sore, I thought I'd die!
Hat's because...
Back then, you snuck out of
the window of the toilet,
and went over to the courier truck...!
You placed a wooden linchpin
that you had set up beforehand
in front of the front tires of the truck.
Don't be ridiculous
Why would I have to
do something like that?
It's was a trick to make it look like
you weren't committing the crime!
You tied a piano cord to that linchpin,
and then tied the piano cord
onto the rear end of the bus
that was parked for time adjustment.
Then, you shifted the gear of
the courier truck to neutral,
and released the side brake.
You then returned to the coffee shop
as if nothing had happened...
When the time came,
and the bus starts off,
the linchpin would come off.
That would make the courier truck,
roll down the hill on its own!
All you had to do next, was wait for
the bus to go by the coffee shop
and get out of the way...
by pretending to go to the
restroom to look for your lighter!
I see!
The thing;'that was shimmering
at the rear of the bus
was the piano cord!
You mean this?
Here you go.
Oh, yes!!
It's just a plain piece of wood...
The wooden linchpin is dragged
along by the bus,
and shatters as it bounces
on the pavement.
That is what is left of the linchpin.
OO « - ny
Ie carw Ic ya gaine
speed because of slope,
crashed into the
window of the coffe shop
and burst inside, just a
you had planned!
Mr. Aida was hit by the truck from
behind and passed away.
L...Let's say the trick is as you say...
But, do you have proof that I did 1t?!
I have proof!
Your mistake was, when you tied the
piano cord on, you hurt your finger.
My hand got stuck to the knob
of the door of the restroom!
The courier truck can be
operated with just one hand,
SO you :1:n eave any
blood stains there.
But, when you went in
through the toilet window,
you touched it and left blood stains on it!
Blood is left on the inside of
the window of the toilet...
After returning from the restroom you,
continuedimaking arrangements.
But since you hurt your left hand,
you held the pencil with your right hand.
Conan witnessed you licking
your left hand occasionally.
Isn't that right, Conan?
Yep!
I It's true tha Jllhurt my finger!
But like I just said, I scraped
It by the doorknob.
Can something like that
be considered proof?
Can't it, officer?
True...
Shut up.
Yes, sir!
Anyway, if you insist that rm the killer,
show me concrete evidence!!
Hey, what's that?
There's a glove with a
strange pattern in the car!
What is the meaning of this Mr. Ohara?
If the piano cord;on the bus is checked
your blood should also be detected on it.
The wound that you acquired
on your hand the toilet,
and the glove with blood
stains on it is in your car.
The blood stain on the frame of
the window of the toilet shows
that you held the frame from outside.
Furthermore, your blood stains are also
on piano cord that is tied to the bus...
How are you going to explain all this?!
How about it, Mr. Ohara?
I killed him...
That guy... Aida, he dared forget
all that I did for him now,
and betrayed me by saying he was
going to quit working for me...
If he quits the company my
company may go bankrupt...
If it were going to go bankrupt any way,
I figured I should kill him making
it look like an accident,
and at least get of hold of his life
Insurance money as compensation.
To tell the truth, I was undecided
until I began making arrangements
with him at the coffee shop...
But, he had the nerve to say,
he was:going to take away
a big job that I found,
as retirement pay,
SO...
What a thing to do...
I'm very sorry...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS BY
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hi onobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DET CTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama + Shogakukan
II Rights Reserved
. CW Suny,
Renovated and reopening
Thank you so much, Dr. Agasa.
Thanks to you, my innocence
has-been proven
No problem, no big thing, I can
handle things like this hands down...!
I am the one. who taught that
famous School detective Kudo
the skills of being a detective, after all!
Oh, really?!
H yeah, sure...!
Oh well, who cares...
It's dated 10 years ago...?!
This is 10 years before
Misaki got married!
Oh no!!!
Could there be more than one killer?
What is this a debris of?
Just as I thought. This is...