Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
Today's episode is about
a visitor from France.
The will to kill harmonizes
in the melody of the piano.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene.
AER)
Tray
TA ANA
Nocturne of Red Will to Kill" Part I
The Kana Amusement Group
IS a very big company.
Yoshinori Kana
20 BB BO RAR1G5)
What would the chairman of such
a company want to talk to me about?
Well, we're going to be making the
CD of Gerald Tenma at our company
And, we're going to be holding a private
party upon the signing of the contract...
How nice Mr Tenma is finally
going to make his Japan debut?!
Do you know him?
Of course! He's a mysterious singer
that is the talk of the French
world of Chanson!
No one knows anything about
his personal history,
isn't that right?
I'm amazed that you know
Ever since the day we decided
on the day of the party,
eerie things have been happening
around his wife, Misaki.
Eerie things happening?
Repeated phone calls
without no caller responding.
Rose bouquets sent by
Nn unknown sender...
This letter came with
the bouquet of roses...
Blackmail...
Those who do not realize my love,
will surely fall to the pits of hell.
We got the other one yesterday.
Tithe curtains will be opened to
commence the party of revenge
Enjoy a part. of terror
0 your heart's content...
The party will be held in three days.
We can't cancel it now and
I'm also worried about my wife...
Do you have any idea who this may be?
We are carrying out
contract procedures secretly.
Therefore, the only ones who know that
there is going to be a party are
my wife and I, and the other
four who are scheduled attend...
You left me behind all alone,
but I haven't forgotten you still.
Three days later
My eyes are always on you."
I hear your'voice and
I am just so delighted.
What on earth is that?
Oh come on! It's the Japanese lyrics to
Mr. Tenma's "Nocturne of Red Love!"
Uh...? "I'll send you a flower a day."
A red:rose, A marigold, a roberia,
a bright red dahlia, and a love song...
You are forever mine."
Ugh....1 wonder what she likes
about a song like this?
I'm so happy that.I'm.going to
get to see Mr. Tenma.
Thisvis work now, remember?
We're supposed to be members of the
Morita family, a friend of the chairman,
understand?
All right!
I can't have them finding out
that I'm a top notch detective
Don'tiworry, because you don't look it!
Really you two better
behave yourselves!!
That's for me to say, not you!!
Wow!
Going from the gate to the
entrance of the house by car,
is like:what I've seen
in movies from abroad!
Oh! This is really some house... «
They must be millionaires!
Doesn't it look like a castle that
comes out in horror movies...?
Hunder...
It was such a fine day until just
a while ago, and now it's so...
Didn't you want to see Gerald?
Being scared is another thing!
Mr. Morita?
Yes, I'm Morita.
Thank you for coming.
Please come in...
Mr. Morita! We are waiting for you.
Thank you for inviting us.
Thank you for coming!
She is my secretary...
I'm Masayo Tokudaiju.
EAI EX (29)
How do you do?
Masayo Tokudaiji
Secretary
(it? QR (24)
It's nice to meet you!
This is the reception room.
Oh, well, well.
The art work here is also fantastic!
It's all my wife's taste.
Come this way please.
Uh..may¢I take a look around
your residence before doing.so?
Oh, sure!
Ms. Tokudaiji!
Please show them around.
Yes, sir
I'll show them around.
She is my wife, Misaki
She is the president of the group
company, KanalMusic Publisher.
How do you do?
Shall we go?
Misaki Kana
an AB = BX (32)
MI XQ)
On, yes...
Please prepare things
in the kitchen, Masayo.
Your wife doesn't like me, does she?
Hey...
This is the room right above
the large reception hall.
The room?beyond is the piano room.
H how wonderful...
You even have a spiral
corridor within the house...
Hmm? This sword...
Hey!
Don't you dare touch it!
It's not all that fragile.
Although it's-decoration,
it is made of the same materials
and in the same way as real thing.
In other words...it's the real thing?!
The room next to the piano room is mine.
Come this way please
This room Is also of good taste
Is this a picture of your wedding...?
How beautiful!
It was taken 10 years ago today.
In Fiji...
How nice...
We belonged to the same
music club in our university days.
We went steady for a year
and then got married.
My, how I envy you.
H... Hello?
Who is It?!
He person hung up
Hello}...
It hung up...
Does this. kind of thing happen often?
Yes .
In a hoarse man's voice, things like
Mon amie" and "Je taime"
are whispered.
And when I answer,
the phone is hung up immediately.
You have no idea who it is?
That's not all
Together with a letter, I got this too...
Was this taken without you being aware?
This is what I found together
with the bunch of Marigold
I found at the front door this morning
This seems to have been
taken yesterday...
I feel like someone is always
watching me that I'm scared...
Aftersthe rose-is the marigold
ays beingywatched...
Worry no more! I will protect you
Misaki over my dead body!
Chairman, the guests have arrived.
Oh all right...I'll be right there.
I'm!sorry to have kept you waiting...
Thank you so much for coming.
Yoshinori, this is
Gerald Tenma's manager.
I'm Michelle, nice to meet you.
Michelle
Manager'.
Thi" Yis my older brother, Yoshinori Kana
and his wife, Misaki.
How do you do?
Thank you for coming
Where is Mr. Tenma?
I'm sorry, he had some
other work to attend to
so he will arrive here
about 30 minutes later.
Yoshinori, who are they?
He is my old friend, Mr. Morita.
They are his children, Ran and Conan.
Mr. Morita, he is my
younger brother, Hideki.
He is the vice president of
Kana Music Publishers.
Hideki Kana
Vice president
an BB 3 #8 (30)
Yoshinori, may I have a word with you?
What is it?
Excuse me.
Please come this way and have a seat.
Oh; what delicious looking dishes!
Don't forget why we're here...
Why did you invite outsiders here?!
This is an important time when we
have to sign a contract with Gerald.
The contract?
You leave for France your own
and suddenly bring Gerald along...
Thinking of the company, .l don't
see anything wrong in what I did.
For the company, eh.
I guess so, because if
this doesn't work out,
you can't make yourself
Iook good to Misaki.
W...What a thing to say!
I hear you've been making
passes to Misaki persistently!
Who said such a thing?!
How about you and
Ms. Tokudaiji, Yoshinori?
The rumor's going around
all over the company!
Don't be ridiculous! There is nothing
going between her and me!!
Anyway! I'm going to make this contract
go through no matter what it takes!
Wh 4
It's about time for Gerald to arrive.
I'll go wait for him by the front door.
Et me go with you...
I'll: go.tosthe restroom before that.
Please get the next dish ready will you.
Yes ma'am.
You don't have anything
to drink, Mr. Morita.
I'll go get you some.
Oh, thank you very much.
Will you excuse me
while I go fix my make-up?
Don't drink too*much, Dad.
I know, I know.
Come on!
Um, you know what...
Don't you have to go guard Misaki?
Oh! That's right, Dad.
You've got work to do!
I couldn't possibly go into a room
Ran, you go.
I guess: so.
Oh no! It's a black out!
A thunder bolt probably fell somewhere.
IS is bad...
aaah!
Upstairs?!
Darn!!
Help!
The door ls locked!
Out of the way!
Help!
Hold it!
Misaki!
Here the heck is he...
Where'd it go?!
Misaki...
What's the matter?! Are you all right?
Somebody lowered the breakers.
Misaki!
What's the matter?!
Suddenly somebody attached me!
WwW, What's that...?1
No!!
Roberta!
Ust as I thought, this is...
Ran, flowers by that name come
out in that song too, don't they?
That song? Oh, "Nocturne of Red Love"
A rose, marigold, roberia...
Which means that all the flowers that
the person had sent up to now are...
I am always wa ching you
Hearing your voice delights me...
Are you saying that someone
Is threatening Misaki
according to the lyrics
of Gerald Tenma?!
Threatening?!
It means that someone is
stalking your beautiful wife.
Although I know we are all
in the midst of a party,
I'd like to question all of you.
Are you the one who lifted the breaker?
Yes! On my way here,
the breaker at thé¥top of the stairs...
Where were you at that time, Hideki?
Mr. Morita, who are you...
Oh, excuse me, I am not Morita,
but'Kogoro Mouri, 'a detective.
Kogoro Mourn?!
You mean that famous detective?!
Yes, that's right.
Misaki, you locked the door, didn't you?
Yes, just as I was about to
fix my make-up,
the lights went out*and
I was attacked from behind.
You didn't see what the attacker looked like?
No...
I did.
I couldn't see very clearly but.
He was wearing a cape
and had a facial expression...
He looked like a foreigner...
Like a foreigner)!
Me? Why Ffierd
Pardon me, where were you:atithat time?
Hwehfito the front door to meet Gerald.
The lights went out and I came inside
because it began to rain.
I saw Hideki, and heard
a voice scream, "Help!"
We cameihere together.
Will you cut it out.
Michelle is an important guest.
Gerald!!
He looks like'the attacker...
Let me introduce you, this is our main
guest tonight, Mr. Gerald Tenma!
There seemed to be
no one downstairs so I...
Gerald Tenma
Singe 1
We had a black out here
May I speak to you downstairs?
Please come with me too, everyone.
The door of the room was locked...
Which means that the attacker
was already in the room.
Everyone who left the large reception
room beforehand had a chance
Which means that someone lowered
the beforehand had a chance...
Could there be more than one attacker?
Huh?
What is this a piece of?
The crack is still new...
There are other small debris around.
No, the size is different.
Hmm? What is this a trace of?
Where were -you;all"when
the-the incident occurredy
I was in the restroom.
I panicked when the lights went out.
I was in the kitchen checking
on the cake Misaki hadibaked.
Mr. Tenma, you were
drenched, weren't you?
That's because I got off
the taxi by the gate...
Is that true?
Well, why don't we take a break then?
Excuse me...
Ah! Where's Conan?
Don't tell me he's missing again!
Are you all right?
Can you go and get
medicine from my room?
Yeah, okay.
The picture that was taken last night was
Huh?
Oops!
They seemed to have
struggled pretty hard...
Misaki and Gerald Tenma?!
This is dated 10 years ago!
It's 6 months before Misaki got married!
Hey!
Conan, you going to be
scolded by Dad again!
Uh? What's that...
Well, this is, you see...
Show it to me!
Oh, no!
Huh?!
What's the matter?
Oh no!
What is the meaning of this!!
Did you have relationships
with Misaki in the past?!
What shall I do?
Yoshinori, what a rude thing to say!
Hideki!
Don't tell me that you knew about it!
Why would I do such a thing!!
Stop it!!
Misaki!
Dear...
It true, that before I married you,
I was going with him.
HIS real name IS Junya lenma,
and I used to go with him.
He was a nameless artist back then...
But, on a certain day, 10 years ago,
your suddenly disappeared.
Isn't that right?
When I saw the papers of Gerald Tenma
that we were going
to sign a contract with,
I was surprised to find that
such a coincidence existed
It's been a long time, Mr. Tenma.
Eah...
Mrs. Kana, I have a gift for you!
It's hand made wine, something
that you cannot get in Japan.
I would like to taste the wine...
There seems to be
nothing wrong with it.
Le «s have juice»
Now, let's all have a toast.
Cheers!
She's still on her guard after all.
Yes, this sure is good wine!
Agh!
Oh, excuse me!
No problem
Oh yes! I was baking a cake.
Masayo, will you go to the basement
in the yard and get me the silver tea set?
I will serve you all a special
hand-made cake I made.
Please wait a moment.
As one of the conditions of publishing
the "Nocturne of RedylLove
from your.company,
I have slightly changed the lyrics
and"made new arrangements.
One with a new arrangement?
Gerald insisted-on doing so. a
I found this bunch of
flowers at the entrance...
Dahlias...
Dahlias stand for betrayal...
Betrayal?
Thank you for waiting.
It's secret, everyone.
Mr. Tenma, won't you
play your music for us?
After all, you're here in person...
Sure.
You attacked Misaki, didn't you?
Not that again.
Who else but you could've done it?!
I have to make preparations,
so please leave me along.
Don't tell me yousie running away!
Will you cut it out!
They seem to be having an argument.
Let's go check on them.
Gyaaaah!!
It's Mr Tenma's voice!
What's.wrong?!
No, 1 didn't do It.
Gerald?!
Ahh?!
Gerald!!!
This is?!
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michthiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Kats ? Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
MaSatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Yunichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRE TOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshflkobayash:
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
En]! 0( ama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
O Gbsho Aoyama /eShog %ukan
Il Rihts Reserved
Nocturne of Red Love!!!"
This song was one that Mr. Tenma
had written for Misaki 10 years ago!!
Is this blood?!
OO: It's not...
He's the one who attacked Misaki!!