Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
Lowers hold deep meaning behind them.
Time ls no obstacle
for songs or the will to kill.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene.
We got a request for a job from
YoshinorieKana, chairman of
the Kana Amusement Group
He asks us to attend a party
and protect his wife, Misaki, who is
being stalked by someone.
There is a black out during the party
Misaki is attacked in her room!
Suspicion falls on Gerald Tenma
the main guest of the party.
However,
Gerald Tenma himself, is killed!!
Nocturne of Red Will to Kill" Part II
The murder weapon is
the sword of:the knight.
Hmm?
A tuning fork used for tuning the piano...
I wonder what this scratch is...
And,
why is the piano chair over here...?
It's stuck under the large sofa.
Huh?!
You stay put!
Please move over to
thetWaiting room so that
we can keep the scene of
the murder as is.
Erald...
Yoshinori,
are you the one who killed Mr. TenmaO?
No! I didn't!!
I was in the waiting room!
Rightdhere!! »
Tenma ignored me
and went alone into the piano room!
Without a choice,
Just as I was about to sit in the chair...
I heard a thump and a scream,
so I went to look,
and"found Tenma.dead!
But, back then,
everyone else was
IN: the large reception room downstairs.
That's right, Yoshinori!
Of all things, what a thing to do?!
I'm telling you, I didn't do it!
You didn't like the fact that I decided on
this whole thing on my own
in the first place!
So, when you found out that
Misaki and Mr Tenma
used to go with each other in the past,
you were enraged. weren't you?!
Well, that's...
So, the Kana family is finished...
t's too bad, chairman...
«un, Wii»
I wonder who is going to be
taking over the
Kana Amusement Group from now on?
I'm innocent!!
And, dids ou see the killer?
Well...
when I got there...
there was already no one there
Hey,
when we were guided in there by Misaki,
the lid of the piano was closed, wasn't it?
I wonder if Gerald opened it?
No, in a room this,size,
sound will go around
even without opening
the top of the piano.
Gerald would never open it...
come to think of it...
The top lid of the piano was open
even before Tenma came into this room.
Which"means...
that the killer could've. opened the piano
the top lid of the piano
beforehand to block our view...
The only way out of this room is
to go through the waiting room...
One of the windows was open,
but below it, is the sea way blow...
Even if the killer were to jump in,
it would be difficult to avoid the rocks.
Huh?
There is a scratch on
this window frame too...
It looks like a scratch made from a string
or something that has scraped it...
Huh?
It's the same as when
Misaki was attacked!
If a rope were used, you could flee to
the top forward or bottom?!
Well, that is a possibility...
But, I wonder if one could flee so quickly?
A scratch made by the tip of the sword
piercing right through the floor is
vertical?
His means...
Maybe!
Let's organize the position of all of you
during the time of the crime, once again.
Let's all go to the room next door.
The small chandelier on this.side is
positioned higher
than the big one over there
When we were lead in here,
I'm sure it was positioned lower.
Huh?
There is a scratch here too
It resembles the one
that was by the window...
So, this is the chain that moves
the chandelier up and down.
I guess it's easy to roll it up.
Only this box has no dust on it...
Hmm?!
Nocturne of Red Love"!!
That song was one that
Mr. Tenma had written for
Misaki 10 years ago!
Wait a sec?
Sosyswhat does.this mean?
Hmm?
What's that?
On the piano?
Is it blood?!
No!!
Inside the piano too?!
Officer Kobayashi.
What is it, Conan?
Lend me. our ear, please.
What? The Inspector said to?
Look for Beethoven?
Yep.
Is it really inside the ocean?
Yep! Good luck.
At any rate, I'll have to have you
come to the station with me.
I didn't do it!
How many times do I have to tell
to make you believe me?
Misaki! Help me!
Dear!
If this piece fits into that part.
Just as I thought!!
These are the debris from
the decoration up there!
Only that person could've committed the
murder!
I'll take care of the company, Yoshinori...
You're already thinking of selling
a memorial CD of Gerald Tenma,
aren't you?
How dare you!
That's the one who attacked Misaki!!
Achoo!!
Huh?
Inspector Megure!
Just as you have said,
this statue of Beethoven was
found on the beach!
Huh?
I never you asked you to do such a thing!
Shoots!
Um, what's this?
There is a scratch below the railing
that looks to have been made by
scraping a thin string or wire on it...
Huh?
What's this?
What is this string called?
Isn't this the string that
you use when fishing?
It's called a fishing gut.
Inspector, there was a fishing gut and
this stick on this chest statue...
What?!
I see!
The scratch on the railing was made by
the fishing gut scraping against it!
All right, Pops, that's the way to go!
But, why the statue of Beethoven. ?
See, there's Mr. Beethoven
in this picture too!
What is this?!
That was a picture that was taken
secretly of this room last night.
This is just about there...
Oh, the statue of Beethoven is not here?
I see, I've figured out
the trick of the caped monster!
What?!
Yes...the statue of Beethoven
belongs in this room!
F this trick were to be used...
Don't you think that beam fits
the length of the stick?
Hmm...
Hey!
Doesn't that piece that was found,
fit right into the crack over there?
Right!
Let's try it from the balcony
on the other side
Would you please lend us a fishing pole
If you have one?
Yes...
The eaves protrude more than
the railing, but
if a fishing pole were used, it's simple.
There is a loop at the tip of the string and
a weight at the end to carry this out.
Then, pull this string under the railing...
Officer Kobayashi,
please put your finger through the loop
of the fishing gut and hold it in place.
Inspector Megure,
may I borrow your coat?
Huh?
So, now we're all set.
Officer Kobayashi,
struggle with the monster
and let your hand go when I signal,
then, pull the string.
All right.
Let's begin.
Aaagh, help me!
Now!
Pull the string!!
Let the string go!
This is fantastic! It's perfect!
Ugh, hey?!
My coat!!
That movement just now was exactly
the same as the attacker
ho attacked Misaki
Then...
Don:t tell me...it was you?
In a dark room it looked like
the caped monster fled...
That is, the victim and the attacker are
one and the same...
The killer lowers the breaker
that is in the corridor,
and goes back to her room right away,
Iocks the door and screams.
Isn't that right, Misaki?
Misaki?
Perfect, just as would be expected of a
renown detective...
However, all the pranks and blackmails
I have experienced up to now
are a matter of fact.
I wanted you to believe me
so I put on an act...
I see...
But, this is not directly connected to the
murder of Mr. Tenma.
Yoshinori,
please come with me to the station.
Okay...
This won't do...!
Whaaaa!!
What the...?
The piano room?!
Aaagh!!
Conansxwhat's.up?!
Where are you!
Huh!
What is it now?
Inspector Megure,
please wait about
taking him to the station.
What?!
Oh, so it's come?
Yes. I've finally figured it out, Inspector.
Please look at the sword mark
on the floor.
The angle of the scratch is perpendicular.
MB The result of the investigation
SNOWS likewise.
And, the railing of the spiral corridor
by the window.
The scratch left on the tuning fork
that Mr. Tenma was holding...
If we connect all the traces left behind,
a certain horrible trap
comes for the surface'!
Huh???!
There is a chandelier right above
the scratch on the floor.
That is in fact, the last point
that connects all the traces.
It can't be?!
Yes...!
The sword that was suspended
from that chandelier
fell straight down, pierced Mr. Tenma
and left a vertical mark on the floor.
Oh, no...
0O0O0OO0ODO0OO
But, Mr. Mouri,
even if he were to be standing
conveniently right under the place
where the sword descended,
wouldn't he have been
stabbed in the head or shoulder?
However, Mr. Tenma
was lying on his stomach!
No such thing could be done!
The answer to that mystery is
the tuning fork.
Tuning fork?
And, the pianos«chair!t
The space between
the piano and the chair is
good only for one person.
This was the trap!!
When;Mr. Ten'ma comes before
the keys of the piano to play,
the chair was toppled beside the piano!
He also finds the tuning fork used for
tuning the piano on the floor.
Well, Mr. Tenma would naturally
go to pick it up.
Yeah...if so, he would turn his back
against the sword...
And, the tuning fork that he picked up
Is the very thing
that made the sword come falling!
What do you mean.!
This horrible trap,
was set up by setting the sword
in the middle of the long string,
then gathering both sides of the string,
pulling them through
the metal faster of the chandelier
using the railing of the spiral corridor
as support,
one side is wound once
around the large sofa
then the tip of the string is
hooked on to the tuning fork.
The other end of the string is
Ieft outside the window,
with a weight attached to it...
All that's left to do next
is to for Mr Tenma to pull it out
from under the chair.
The string that was hooked
on to the tuning fork
is released by the weight of the sword,
And the heavy sword probably
came falling in an instant.
On the other hand, the fishing gut
that was holding the sword in place,
was pulled by the weight
that was suspended outside the window
and dropped into the ocean below.
I see!
And, who is the one~who set all this up?!
Lease recall...
The trick using the fishing gut...
The method of throwing the evidence
into the sea by using heavy weight,
is exactly like the one
that used with the caped monster
that was just demonstrated, is it not?
Misaki?
Yes, the killer ls you, Misakl!
After we all drank the wine,
you pretend to go to the kitchen
and set your trap up here, didn't you?
By rolling the chandelier to the very top,
you made harder to find the sword,
as well as
heightened the power of it to kill, right?
I thought.you*were a
renown detective but
I guess. I was wrong!
Do you have proof that I did it?
I'd like you to take a look at the lid of
the top of the piano
and the stains inside it.
Oh?!
This is...wineyp
Judging from the place where it is spilled
it must've dripped
when she opened the lid.
The one who spilled the wine is the killer!
How can you be so sure?
Because the wine is
what Michelle brought from France
and one that is not sold in Japan.
S...this is unmistakably the wi
that I brought.
We were all drinking that wine.
Misaki is the only one who didn't drink it!
When I bumped into her
and the wine spilled,
the wine that was probably left
in the gap of her brooch spilled out
when she opened the lid
on top of the piano.
You not only made it look like
you were attacked by Mr. Tenma,
you set it up so that the picture of
you two in the past would be found,
and tried to frame Yoshinori
who you knew would be
enraged as the one
who killed Mr. Tenma, isn't that right?
Misaku, Is that true?!
How are you going to explain
the stalker incidents before all this!
She probably acted it out herself.
The prank call that came a while ago was
probably made by Misaki herself,
using her cellular!
Why would Misaki want to kill Mr. Tenma...
The date of the picture that was found of
Misaki and Mr. Tenma was
only six months before her marriage,
wasn't it?
It can't be?!
And the "Nocturne of Red Love" was a
song that was written for you,
10 year ago!
Huh?!
Really? (In French)
The song at first glance
Iooks to be a love song.
But the passions
that the flowers stand for are,
Red roses symbolize passion,
marigolds, hopelessness, roberias evil,
and dahlias betrayal.
In other words, this was a song of hate
written for someone who had
betrayedrone's lover!!
Hmm...is that true,
Misaki?
Yes...
10 years ago on that day...
He insisted on not leaving me,
so I called him out to a nearby beach...
and pushed him over the cliff...
Then, you married Yoshinori.
However, Mr. Tenma miraculously
made it out alive,
and achieved his fame abroad...
When you found out
Gerald Tenma's true identity,
you figured you had no choice
but to kill Tenma again,
In order to keep your previous crime
from being revealed!!
But, why did you try to frame
your husband as the killer?
Because of Masayo!
If I get caught my husband as well as
the company will be taken away
But a man who is in prison
cannot be taken away from me.
I was planning to take over the company
until he came back...
Misaki...
When Mr. Tenma's body wasn't
found 10 years ago,
I was always in fear that
he may be alive...
Because I also knew
the meaning of that song.
Well...the fact is, whenever Gerald sang
this song at his concert,
he would whisper .the following phrase
without fail.
Pour compenser ton coeur blesse."
In Japanese it means
To compensate your heart that is hurt.
The new arrangement had new lyrics,
but most probably...
Yes! Except for red roses,
the flowers have all been changed to.
Hyacinth, laurel tree and olive!
The flowers stand for,
sadness peace and glory...
I see.
Mr. Tenma having realized that he had
cornered Misaki into committing murder,
continued singing this song
with feelings of compensation,
and probably deliberately decided to
sign a contract with the Kana Group.
Yes, he once fell to the pits of grief,
but he no longer hated Misaki
and'having achieved success and
happiness himself,
he probably wanted her to hear the real
octurne off Red Love"...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Kats: 8 Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
MaSatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR:
Junichi loka
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazumari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Hioure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hiroto<hi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshikobayash:
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecastine Corporation
O Gosho Aoyama / Fog 'kukan
YTY / TMS
II rights Reserved
That's right!
I've been hooked on
what flowers stand for since then!
Okay then Sonoko, bye-bye.
Oh, Conan you're back.
Here, I saw this at the flower shop,
so I bought it.
Huh?! You, Conan? For me?
Thank you!
Wow, what beautiful peach blossoms...
Uh.\ this flower stands for...
To be...unrivaled... in the world...
Hey Conan. just...
what do you mean by this?!
Uh... well you see...
Just what do you mean-to be
unrivaled in the world?!
Ha, ha, ha...just that...
Hurry!
Let's get outside
before they get into the elevator!!
No use fleeing!!
What I want to say is,
you're not Misato, but an impostor!!