Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
Today's stage is an ordinary condo.
The Youth Detective Squad use their
brains and bodies to solve the case.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene.
{ili e- oF akhe tt DO
Cile- + d=. Diego
ong Bcacfi/Los Angelbfis/Sqn Diego
The Great Search-Nine Doors
I wish I could find something
nteresting to do...
The world is full of cases
Oo be solved and yet...
It's strange that nothing's
happening only around us.
Nothing's strange about it.
That's the way it should be...
What's that?
It's a ring!
I wonder where it came flying from?
There was nobody on this side.
I think somebody threw it
from the window of this condo.
Aaagh?!
Huh?
All the windows are closed
A prank?
Hey, watch it you!
I wonder why it's on something like this?
It's an "SS" shaped hook.
There's one here too.
Maybe that hook was also
attached to the ring
but came off when it fell
to the ground...
Wait a minute!
What's up?
Hey, hey, don't tell me...
Look!
Doesn't this look like a word?!
SOS?!
Yes!
This ring and "SS" shaped hooks are an
SOS sign that somebody is sending us!
Ha, ha, ha .
I expected them to say that.
If so, it must be a woman.
Huh?
There is lipstick on the hook.
She's right! There's lipstick on it!
Hey, hey, you're getting carried away...
Mitsuhiko, will you show me the ring?!
This is a wedding ring!
See, MM to A
1999 March 21 is carved on it!
This means that the ring was sent from
somebody with the initial My,
to someone with the initial A.
And that they were married ony
March 21, 1999.
Wow, it's amazing that
you can teliwAYum:!
My parents' ring has the same thing
carved on it!
So this ring is one that
the woman was wearing!
Her husband's initial is M
and her initial is A!
Uh-huh!!
Will you lend it to me
The size of this ring is about 11.
Regularly take sizes 7 to 9, so
this woman ust have pretty fat fingers.
Listen, you guys...
There's no mistake about it!
The one who sent out an SOS...
is somewhere on the 1st to the 9th floor
of this condo,
and is for some reason is
rendered immobile!
Ould it be an accident...
Maybe she's locked up.
Hun?
All the windows are loosed.
Which means that either she closed them
right after she dropped the ring
because she sensed danger,
or the one confining her
closed them, right?
We'll have to find that room in a hurry
because she may be in danger!
All right! The Youth Detective Squad,
to the scene on the double!
Let's go!!
Yeah!!
Hey! You.
Don't tell me you seriously think
it's a kidnap case?
I don't know.
But it's a good way
to pass the time, isn't it?
What's the matter?
The door is an auto lock door
and it{won't open.
Behind you...
Oh! Have a nice day.
So, we got in, but what now?
Let's check the initials of the couples
who live in the rooms facing
the little window that we just saw,
and the room numbers
from the 1st to 9th floors!
But, how?
There doesn't seem to be
a manager's room here either...
The-road we came from is
exactly west of this condo.
All we have to do is find a room in this
condo that faces exactly west!
This way!
Okay!
He's pretty good, isn't he?
That's nothing to be amazed of!
Tsutomu Otake...
The initial of his first name is "T"
for Tsutomu.
It's notsthis room.
All the rooms above this one should
have a number 5 on them.
Let's split up and check the name plates!
Al and Ayumi, go check
the odd number lead,
W'll go check the even number floors.
You can count on us!
Goju...kaze.
Unusual name.
It's not read like that.
It's read Igarashi.
Shima...
We have no way of knowing
with just the last name.
Uh-huh...
Shinichiro Ohyama...
the initial off his first name is "S"...
It's not this room.
No...
We did it!
The names of the entire family
are written!
FIEse RAE
Kosaku Horikoshi, Natsue, Yohei...
EEE PHF
Too bad, no good again.
Their initials are "K" for Kosaku
and "N" for Natsue.
And all their initials were displayed...
Akihiko and Misato Uehara...
A" and "NM".
We did it! Isn't this it?!
Genta, we're looking for
a husband with the initial "MM"
and a wife with the initial.
This is the opposite!
-_ aa
I OCC
Look here!
Michihiro Ishida!
The initial of the first name is "MM"!
We can't tell what the name of
his wife is...
He may be living alone.
Oh...
Five rooms may be a possibility.
Out of the five, four only had
their last names listed outside...
Um, maybe their names may be
written on the post box outside!
Oh that's right!
Let's go check!
Good thinking Ayumi!
Wait! Please stay here Genta.
If we all go out
we won't be able to get back in. 8
okay...no fun!
Rooms 205 and 305 have only
the last name listed, after all
But look! 805 and 905!
Yoshio and Eisuke...
Y" and "TE" so they aren't the ones.
So, we've only got three more to go.
Room 205 and 305.
I wonder if there's any way
we can check the names?
Hmm...
There is a way.
Huh? Uh, where are you going?
Agh, hey, just where are you guys going?
Hey, don't leave me here alone...
Here it is!
4-11-10 Beikacho. It's the address
of this condo.
The name is, Toru Igarashilyg
Thesinitiaks "T" so he isn't the one.
Here it is!
Masakazu Shima!
The.nitial of his first name 1s "MM"?!
All right!
So, the possibilities now-are
Mr. Masakazu Shima of room 305
and Mr. Michihiro Ishida of room 705.
But™this~is as far asswe can check...
Hmm...
Hmm. ..7
How about if we check the bicycles!
On, that's a good idea, Mitsuhiko...!
Oh, shoots! What're they doing?!
Hey.
Agh...
Oh no, don't close...
What's up?
It seems that you've gotten interested.
\ They!re so serious about it, so...
I found it!
Mr. Shimars bicycle! -See!
Asuka,
her initial is "A"!
Then, the husband's initial is
MM" and the wife's initial is "A"?!
Bingo!
We've finally found them!!
But, there's still Mr. Michihiro Ishida left
If it's just one family,
I guess we couldvask the neighbors.
I guess nobody's home
If the neighbor's not in,
Iet's go right down below.
This is the room where the initials "A"
and "WM" belonged to the wrong person.
I made a mistake!
What is it?
were doing research for
our Japanese class...
What, I can't hear you very well!
And, we're checking on
Japanese names in particular
Do you happen to know the name of
Mr. lshida's wife, who lives above you?
How should I know the name of
the wife of person who lives above me?!
What a lady!
If right below 1s no good then...
Let's go right above, right?
Mr. Ishida's wife's name?
I'm sure it was Fumiko
U-M-I-K-O...
Once before a postal delivery for her
was mistakenly delivered here.
Fumiko, which means
The initial of her name is "FF".
Her child is called Yuta and
he's a smart kid.
He got locked up in the closet
once before and couldn't come out!
Huh?
A closet, you mean the room
to the extreme west?
Right! Right!
What do you think he did?
He dropped toilet paper
out of the window of the restroom,
and let the people who
were walking below know.
Miss!!
Do all the people who live in
this condo know that story?!!
Yes, I'm sure they do.
It's a well known story
within this condo so
Oh my God!
It's been done before!
Conan!
What on earth is the matter?
We're going to the 3rd floor!
Because the only ones with
the initials "MM" and "A" are
Masakazu Shima and
his wife Asuka of room 305.
What's going on,
you're: suddenly so interested
He starting to think that there something
going on after talking to the lady.
What?
Hide! &
Huh?
Wait for me!
They're thieves!
They're wearing gloves!
Sunglasses too!
You don't even finish the job right!
Huh?
Why'd you kill for?!
Shut up!
K, Kill?!
We're too late!
What shall we do, Conan?!
Let's call the police!
Hurry, into the elevator!!
411 £-
We've got to get outside
before they get on the elevator!!
Whew, that was a close one...
Police officers!
Huh?
Let's tell them!
Big trouble!
It's armed robbery and murder!!
What?!
In that condo over there!
You'd better hurry
or the crimnals'll get away!
Please hurry!
Hold it!!
You're not getting away!
Huh?
What is it?
It's them!
They killed a woman!
They may be armed with a gun!
What?!
What's with you guys?!!
What on earth is this about?!
Freeze!!
You kids go outside!
Please check inside room 305
The dead body of Asuka Shima
should be there!
Dead body?!
What are you talking about.
There's no such dead body!
Don't lie!
Then why did you say,
Why did you kill?" Just a while ago?!
We all heard you,.right?!
Yep!!
Ah come on!
That's about an insect.
An insect?
I was angry because
he carelessly killed my insect.
And, besides, I'm Asuka Shima.
TH RETEB/T40DOT110D1
See, my driver's license.
TEPPHEIEWIE 123
BF WHREBRTEMIIEEAD1IO0 RE) Tra 68
£01829830662
I on ON
Ghads, talk about being a nuisance.
There was no dead body anywhere!
Besides, we checked with the neighbors
and they verified that those two
were Mr. and Mrs. Shima too.
All of you, apologize to them.
Yes sir...
es Sir...
Were really very sorry...
No problem.
We confused you with the subject
we were talking about too.
But, officer,
it's true that someone is
being locked up!!
No, that's enough!
Don't you ever doll
something like this again!
WY 4 sh
Yes sir...
48 ow
ad r of
They were married...
We completely mistook them
to be armed robbers and murderers.
There is no other room
where the occupants initials
are "MM" or "A" Is there.
Something bothers me...
I wonder what it is...
Um...
Maybe the person's name in room 705
IS read Ayako and not Fumiko?
Huh?
Right! If it's read "Ayako"
the initial would be "A"!
We're: luc « to buy the meat
so cheap, weren't we, Fumiko.
We sure were, mother
So, it's read Fumiko, after all.
So, they're safe.
Hurry up, Yuta.
He's the toilet paper boy, isn't he!
What a skinny mother.
My mom is so over-weight
that she's wearing dad's tee-shirts
Over-weight...?!!
Ayumiy let me see-the ring!
Conan?!
Agh! What's with him?!
«Hey, Conan?!
What's up?!
Open up, what're you saying, Conan!!
He's gone...
You again?
What now?
H,Hey!
What's with you, anyway!
This is what was bothering me after all!
Hey, get out of here, will you!
Are you Mr Akihiko Uehara s wife?
Is your name Misato?
Huh? Y...Yes
This is yours then, isn't it?
I picked it up in front of
the door a while ago
he initials "A" for Akihiko and
for the initial of your fist name
Is carved on it...
Try it on.
Take a good look at the ring lady.
The initials "M" to "A" are carved on it
Huh?
From Misato to Akihiko.
Yeah
that's actually Akihiko's ring
But, Misato was wearing it.
That's why it was hard to tell!
According to the neighbors
they say that
Misato has recently gained weight.
Not being able to wear her own ring, she
probably wore Akihiko's ring instead...
Because many Japanese men don't
wear rings even after getting married...
And besides, I think that Akihiko has
slender fingers for a man.
What are you trying to say?
Aren't those shoes a little
too small for you to wear?
Phooey! What are you getting at?
What I want to say is that
you're not Misato, an impostor!
Huh?
If so...
What?!
That was real close...
Mrs Misato Uehara?
Yes, who are you?
I'm Conan Edogawa, a detective.
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
GloshoAnyama .
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Kath 8 Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRE TOR
Yukihiro Shibutanr
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshlfikobayash:
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUGED BY
IMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
OGbsho Aoyama / §hog 'kukan
II Ri§hts Reserved
Her name is Ilkuyo Hasegawa.
She was used to be Misato Uehara's
husband's ex-colleague, Akihiko
since Akihiko had found that she had
embezzled money from the company,
she was fired
from the company.
She had committed
the crime out of hatred for him.
Ikuyo had visited the condo
in order to kill Akihiko
When Misato answers the door,
Ikuyo put her to sleep using a drug,
and locked her up in the closet.
Misato, who came to a while later .
Connects the ring to the "SS" hook
and throws it out of the window
in hopes of getting help
But, right after that,
Ikuyo who comes to check on her
closes the window,
and was put to sleep again with the drug
Wow, you really did a good job!
Take care on your way home!
Yes sir!
Not fair, Conan!
Really,
taking all the good part for yourself.
Yeah;you get me so mad!
You hold all this as punishment!
What?!
Am I supposed to hold all this?!
Of course!!
Hey, wait!
W What the ?!
Thanks for holding mine too.
Hey, hey not you too...
J It's my turn-to send out an SOS signal...
What is Chronin??
Chronin is deadly toxic so...
Huh?!
Hey, these are the gloves for 120 yen!
We can make mole balls with it...
Youth Detective Squad,
I've found the bicycle we're searching for!
Come to the scene on the double!
Who does that guy intend to feed it to?
Dangerous Recipe