Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved
today's point is a shopping receipt
A small piece of paper-says a lot.
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene.
Whoopee, whoopee,
how's about it, Mitsuhiko!
Yaiba Kick!!
Whaaaa!!
Damn, I'm beat!!
It's my turn next, my turn!!
How long are you guys going to
keep this up?
There, Ayumi! Go for it!
I'm not going to lose! There!
Oh....No, no.
Yaiba Punch!
Yaaaaah...
Dangerous Recipe
Br Lory IDA 3D KZ
Dr Lia L&KDA 3D BB
an wll. 4
"I =uanuvu
An ice cream cone after a battle
IS delicious!!
You can say that again!
You should've played too, Conan.
Yeah, maybe next time.
It sure Is crowded, isn't it?
It's already past 16:00,
so they're all here to buy things
for making dinner.
Dinner...l wonder what it is today.
I hope it's eels over rice...
Right!
Why don't we play
a menu deduction game?
A menu deduction game?!
What's that?
Well, it goes like this.
We deduce what the shoppers
are having for dinner
by looking at the receipts
they leave:behind.
Okay, here goes.
Potatoes, onions,
Keiran' six pack...
What's a "keiran?"
Eggs..meggs of a hen.
AOh...
Uh, next...
Ground beef, and bread crumbs
and the answer is?
I got it! It's croquette!!
But you also need flour to make it,
don't you?
Maybe she's already got the flour.
Oh, I see...
It's my turn next
WAIL LMRAUNT
A ea (MM) 15:08
Uleoooo
Chicken thighs, ketchup, green peas,
tomato, lettuce and celery...
Chicken rice!
With vegetable salad.
Okay, next it's my turn!
Okay, here goes!
Uh...
potatoes, onions, beef, flour, sugar
the answer is...
Um... meat with potatoes... no...
Cream stew or gratin...?
But, then it should be
salt and pepper, not sugar...
Maybe the sugar is going to be used for
something else?
The person doesn't have to be
buying ingredients
only for tonight's dinner, right?
I see, that's true
Then, here's the next one!
Pe... Peli. 1 . ? Petite knife,
cutting board, grater, handy.gloves,
Food# case... dustpan...
Isn't that the receipt for
a different section?
What is this thing called petite knife?
It's a small knife.
Something like a knife for cutting fruit.
What're handy gloves?
Gloves used when cooking?
Do you wear gloves when cooking?
Oh, I get it.
That person probably just moved in,
and is going to start cooking from tonight!
That's why the shopper bought a knife
and cutting board too!
The grater's going to be used for
grating onions!
they're deductions are pretty good.
The dustpan's going to be used for
cleaning!
Obviously
I wonder if she's a young woman?
It could also be a man...
Uh...the third one is...
Oh, it's Kamen Yaiba color ball!!
Huh, then maybe there's a child?
The fourth one is...
Size #2 batteries, handle light...
What's a handle light?
I think it's light that you attach to
the handle of a bicycle?
The items are not all food, are they...
The fifth one is...
This one is of another store.
Drugstore Satoshi Kobayashi...
The drugstore:-next door!
The name of the drugstore
changedarecently, right?
Never mind<athat,
what's onsthe shopping list?
Hmm...C...Chro...chrOnin...?
Chroninr.!
Genta, show me that!
The receipt of the food products section
that you read at the beginning too.
WwW WhatOs with you, Conan...
Hurry, give it to me!
Aaah...
What's wrong, Conan?
He's right...chronin...
What on earth is that thing called
chronin??
It's a colorless or whitish crystalline
substance
usually used to sterilize or
disinfect the skin...
There is another way
this substance is used...
Another way...?
Chronin is deadly toxic...
What!!!
D,Did you say...toxic?!
well, it's usually used to make
mole balls to get rid of moles...
The ingredients for making
those mole balls are
on this receipt,
potatoes, onions, beef, flour, and sugar.
Then maybe the shopper bought them
to get rid of moles?
Genta...
Do you think that there are moles
in a city like this?
Oh, that's true
Maybe we see mice sometimes but...
Then maybe it's going to be used
to disinfect the skin after all.
The potatoes and onions are going to
be used to make stew or gratin.
Well...l uess so...
Conan...
If it bothers you so much,
why don't you ask the employees here?
Eah, you're right...
hag v3%,
15:20...
It was bought only an hour ago...
The person in charge is Masako Aral.
Thank you for waiting.
I remember that person very well.
All right!
He was about 20 years old.
At first I thought what he wanted
was out of stock
so I told him it'll come in tomorrow.
But, he insisted he needed it today so...
How did he act?
Hmm...well he seemed sort of jittery
and didn't look all that calm.
Do you remember his face?!
The color of his hair?!
Was he fat like me?!
Huh? ¢
Please tell us!!
Hey...
Height about 170 centimeters...
Brown hair and wearing glasses.
Skinny and wearing a blackish top...
The point is
why this man bought chronin...
a If he used it to disinfect his
it bothers me that
e didn't seem calm
Um, what happens if
humans eat the mole balls?
It won't kill the person,
but probably numb the body
making it unable to move...
Unable to moveg
I got it!
The guy was trying to
make mole balls after all!
He was going to make
somebody eat them
and then, kidnap the person!!
Kidnap?!
If so, it's understandable
why he bought the ingredients
to make mole balls despite no moles!
Anyway,
Let's search the identity of this man.
I wonder, I don't remember
because there are a lot of shoppers...
This is the one!
Petite knife, 1980 yen.
Although it's small,
it's enough to cut potatoes and onions.
The cutting board is plastic
and is also the smallest one around.
The grater is also plastic.
Everything looks like something a man
who doesn't usually cook, rushed to buy.
Hey...these are the glove for 120 yen.
Very thin gloves made of-polyethylene
If these are used to make mole balls,
no fingerprints would be left behind
Disposables.
But, it's more than enough to
carry around-the:mole balls!
This has got the longest
and thinnest handle.
But, what does a dustpan have to do with
the sales floor mole balls?
I can't tell... either...
Maybe a guyssomething like that
bought it.
Do you have any idea who he is?
No...
Did you know that this pole...
glows in the dark!
It's made with fluorescent paint.
What does this have to do with
the mole balls?
We didn't notice anybody like that
buying it, did we?
And, we were playing right behind too...
This handle light
I remember it well
because it's a new item
that just came out only three days ago.
See.
this is an important piece of evidence!
Was the person who bought it
about 170 centimeters
and ah skinny, wearing a blackish top,
with brown hair and glasses?
Oh, you really are knowledgeable.
He also bought batteries.
But, I have no idea of
who or where he lives
Okay, we'll buy that
Are you going togput that-on
your bicycle too, Conan?
(:56
If so, you've got to buy batteries too.
I'm not going to use it.
We'll use it as a clue to finding the man.
But, how, without even knowing
his name or address
No, we've got a clue.
The sixth receipt.
We havenOt looked at
the sixth receipt yet!
I ¢s*a receipt from a convenience store.
Utopia, Beikacho Park Branch.
A vinyl umbrella was bought at 14:50.
14:50'?
That's about the time
we were at the Beika Library.
Yeah, and there was a sudden
pour of shower.
200 meters from this shop,
there is a bus stop for
the Beika Station bus.
The man probably rode the Beika Station.
I think
this guy walked from his residence
and headed for Beika station
But, since it suddenly began to pour,
he went into. thisgstore and
bought himself and umbrella.
Judging from the fact that he bought
a knife and cutting board,
he probably doesn't live with his family,
but rather alone
in an apartment or a condo.
I see, living alone...
It's most likely that
he frequents the convenience store!
Maybe we'll be able to find out
who he is or where he lives!!
Okay, let's go to that store!!
The man remarked that
he had to have the chronin by today
If the plans to make the mole balls
by today and make someone eat it...
We've got to hurry.
We have no time to lose!!
This way!!
Keep
Hmm...
Brown hair, wearing glasses,
about.20 years old,
about 170 meters tall:-and a male...
We have a lot of'customesrs like that...
He bought a large vinyl umbrella
at about 14:50...
Oh, maybe-it could be him.
Do you know him?!
He comes here every so often...
Do you know his name or address?!
No...
But, I think he lives nearby,
because he comes here
wearing sandals most of the time.
We couldn't find out who or where
he lives:after all, could we..2
We've got no choice
but to split up and look for him.
What?!
But, how?
The bicycle!
Bicycle?!
The man didn't go shopping
with his bicycle
because it wasn't equipped
with a basket to carry his things in.
And, I'm positive that the guy's bicycle
has a new type handle light on it!
I see!
So, we're going to look for a bicycle that
doesn't have a basket and
has a new type handle light attached to it
parked in the apartments nearby!
Uh-huh!
Take this, Genta
so you don't make a mistake!!
Aye!
For you, Ayumi and Mitsuhiko.
Ugh!
Okay!
Listen, like I said before,
the man's house is near here
opposite the bus stop.
He lives some distance away that
it is too much trouble to go back home
to get his umbrella.
If you find him, report so,
» Using your badges!!!
See you.
Huh?-Conan!
That way's.the bus stop!
Where on earth is he going?
I'm sure Conan has something in mind.
Let's go ahead and look for the guy!
He probably went to buy
the handle light today,
Because he's planning to use
his bicycle tonight!
We've got to be ready for that too!
But, I wonder what he's going to use
the dustpan and pole for?
I found it!!
Ah-ah-testing microphone,
testing microphone.
Youth Detective Squad
Youth Detective Squad,
the bicycle in question has been found!!
Report the scene on the double!!
Good work, Genta!!
Genta!!
So, you've found it!!
Only Conan's not here yet?!
You went back to get your skateboard?!
0, he lives here...
But, I wonder which room he lives in.
Let's hide and watch.
He should be coming out.
Aye!!
Somebody's come out!!
About 170 meters tall, skinny,
wearing a blackish top,
brown hair and glasses...
Is it him?!
Wait.
It's definitely him!!
Okay!
Me too!
Same here!
Me too!!
Ghads!
Hang on tight!
Conan, he's pulling away from us.
At this rate, we'll lose him!
Can't you speed up a bit more?!
You guys are too heavy!!
Aaaagh!!
He's gone...
We've lost him after all.
Aa aa [_ a
Ne Jur ult 1nicioc...winuiy nwnicais...
It's most likely that he went into
one of the houses nearby...
Should we check
one house after another?
Huh?!
I don't want to go in this alley.
There's a house with a large yard,
with a big dog that barks a lot here.
Maybe?!!
Did you know this pole glows in the dark!
This dustpan has the longest
and thinnest dustpan handle.
Bow-wow!
Bow-wow! Bow-wow!
Don't.
What you are about to do,
IS a crime, you know.
Bow-wow
No use trying to flee!
Your name is Murakami, isn't it?!
We know where you live too!!
Bow-wow
Well, Mr. Murakami,
are you still going to run?
Genta, take off your shoes!!
Huh?!
The shoe!
Aaagh!
'Sh u
bow-wow!
My shoe...
After this, the neighbors call the police,
who arrive in no time.
Murakami is arrested...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Kats 4 Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
MaSatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hoka
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kaz mari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Misatomo Sudo
Hiroto<hi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRE TOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi-Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
O Gbsho Aoyama Jo og Rukan
Il rights Reserved
ATION
To think that he was going to give
the mole balls to the dog.
I heard from the officer of
Beikacho police station over the phone
that the guy was saying he was going to
Kill that dog one of these days,
everyday when he went out for a walk
along his favorite path,
that dog would bark ferociously at him.
That dog really does bark a lot.
He learned of making mole balls
in a book, and yesterday afternoon,
when he passed in front of the house,
he happened to find out that the entire
family was out on an over night trip.
He suddenly decided to
carry out his plan.
He was going to feed the dog
the mole balls,
and after it became immobile he was
going to hit it with the stick and kill it.
The menu game that we decided to play
ended up saving that dog's life, didn't it?
Let's play it again!
I brought the receipts!!
Don't pick things like that up!!
Okay, here goes!
Sashimi, Mayonnaise, cup noodles...
eel sick...
That sound just now was one of gun fire!!
Hmm?! What is it?