Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
Today is a special of a cursed mask.
A mysterious room and an eerie smile.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene.
Ong Beach/Los Angeles/San Diego
ong Beach/Los AR eles/San Diego
ong Beach/L eles/San Diego
Dad, be careful driving, will you!
She's right,
Remember, you're going to be performing
on a charity show held for children
who have lost their families
In traffic accidents next week, Pops!
If you get into an accident
in a place like this
we couldn't face up to Ms. Beniko Suou,
the hostess of the show
who chose you as a guest!
I know!
Ms. Suou invited us to a part. today too.
If I get into an accident,
I'll miss out on all the good food!
Sigh
Uh, that person called Suou
used to be a famous singer, right?
Yeah,
she used to be a big star,
once called "Canary of the Orient.
But nowadays she is busy
taking care of a show biz promotion
called "Kurenai Promotion".
As its president,
that she rarely stands
n stage anymore...
Dohwhaaaaa!!
Of all things...
Talk about dangerous!
Why is this tree in the middle of
e road like this...
Uh, there's something posted on it!
Hat's this...
Hmm...7?
Don't participate in the charity party
held by Beniko Suou. You'll regret it.
Messenger of the cursed mask." 7?
Oh no...
what's that supposed to mean...
Messenger of the cursed mask...
The Cursed Mask Smile Callously"
Oh...
what a mansion...
This is some mansion, isn't it...
Huh? He's...
camera man, Masanori Katagiri...
Huh?
You mean the one
who travels around the world
Masaki Katagiri
Photographer
taking pictures of
eautiful landscapes...
Masaki Katagiri
Photographer
Aagh!!
The king of homeruns,
baseball player Mamoru Matsudaira?!
Mamoru Matsudaira
Proffesional Baseball Player
Huh? And you're the renown
detective yourself...
Mamoru Matsudaira
Proffesional Baseball Player
Huh2-And-youjr ithe renown
detective yourself...
Mr. Kogoro Mouri, right?
Yes! Are you guests on the chant show
to be held next week too?
Yes!
Hmm...?
Wow! What a beauty!!
S Haruka Nagara...
Huh?
You mean the tarot fortuneteller
that is super popular
on TV and in the magazines?!
You know her too...?
Every time I stand on the batter's base
I wear the color of gloves
that matches the luc « color of today
that she announces!
«And that's*how you became
the king of homeruns?
11S 15...
What seems to be the matter?
Nagara Haruka
Tarot Card Reader
I feel something ominous
about this mansion.
Nagara Haruka
Tarot Card Reader
I feel that there is going to be
Iarge disaster...
Nagara Haruka
Tarot Card Reader
I feel that there is going to be
Iarge disaster...
W, What an eerie thing to say...
Well, rather than talk out here,
shouldn't we ask to be let in?
W,Why yes!
But, which door dotwe take
to get into mansion?
There are two entrances...
Thank you all for coming.
Oh, so that side's the entrance...
Huh?
Thank you all for coming.
Huh? WhatOisshappening here...?
Shimogasa Honami
Suou House Maid
Will Mr. Mouri and his party enter from
this side which is the east entrance.
Shimogasa Honami
Suou House Maid
Huh?
Only us...?
Mr. Katagiri, Mr. Matsudaira
and Ms. Nagara
Shimogasa Minaho
Suou House Maid
come in from here, the west entrance.
Shimogasa Minaho
Suou House Maid
Huh...
why are we going in separately?
The inside of this mansion is
divided to the east and west.
Those who will be spending the night
In the rooms on the west side,
enter from the west entrance.
And those who will spend the night
in the rooms on the east side
will enter from the east entrance.
It is a tradition practiced here.
Hat a stran e lace...
If we don't stick to traditional practices
in this mansion...
Disaster befalls us.
Disaster befalls...?
What makes you say that...
Well, because this is the place where...
Because this ls the place where...
The cursed mask resides...
Cursed...mask...?
It's a mask
There's one on this side too.
Mrs. Suou likes to collect masks.
This way, please
Agh...
Next, it's the mask of a cat...
Your baggage has already been
brought here,
so please wait in the room of masks.
Huh? the room of masks?
Agh...
Huh? Mr. Moun?
So this room connects the east and west
wing of the mansion.
Wow, this is fantastic!
There are so many masks...
een. look at all this...
Hmm? What is this?
A remote control...?
Huh?! What the?!
W., What on earth is this?!
Hat's with all these masks...
What is all this...
What're are all these masks...?
These are called the masks of Chableu...
Huh?
Y You are...
Beniko Suou?!
Beniko Suou
Singer
'Eli
Beniko Suou
Singer
VF @uE-avik
Thank you so much everyone for coming.
Beniko Suou
Singer
Kazuyolnaba
Suouis Sec etary
How do you like my precious collection?
Uh, yes, well I guess you could say...
You just mentioned
the masks of Chableu,
but are you referring to the masks
overing the sides wall...
Yes, it is said that the Spanish sculptor,
Chableu Gonzales made it
just before he died.
It was the 200th mask that he made.
It ls also called the "Cursed Mask."...
Huh?!
Cursed mask?!
Uh, what is this
rsed mask all about...
Chableu Gonzales,
IS a sculptor of tragedy.
Although over flowing with talent,
trapped by the jealousy of his brother,
his fame, glory and estate were
all taken away from him.
Chableu who became
very wary of people,
began making masks
as if obsessed by something.
After finishing his 200th mask,
he killed himself.
The masks that were scattered around
his body were splattered with blood\\\_
and the masks looked 'to havebsucked
the blood themselves.
Since then,
Chableu's reputation was restored,
and his masks were handed down to
various people.
However, many who owned the masks
seemed to died tragic deaths.
An English head of the bank,
fell off his horse
the following day after getting hold of
one of the masks, and died.
A French jeweler was attacked
by robbers and killed...
And with the passing of time,
this mask was called,
The cursed mask that sips
the blood of its owner,
and was feared by people.
Are you all right,
owning all 200 of such masks...?
No need to worry.
I had a great clairvoyant seal the curse in
It's starting to get more and more occult
around: here...
But, Ms. Suou,
the evil will of a living person may be
even more frightening than a curse.
Oh, what do you mean?
Well, on our way here,
out path was blocked by a fallen tree,
and we found this pinned to the tree.
Mr. Mouri! I received a similar sort of
Ietter three days ago!
Huh?!
1, I got one too!
Same here...
What?!
It seems to be more than just a prank...
Whaaa!
Touya, you're late.
I'm right in the midst of
a nation wide tour
Touya Aikawa
Rock Singer
Ovosr7A
Give me a break for being tardy.
Touya Aikawa
Rock Singer
Give me a break for being tardy.
Who is he?
Oh, Conan, don't you know him?
He's the most popular rock singer
these days, Touya Aikawa.
You received a strange letter?
The name of the sender is not written.
The lettering of the name of
the addressee is also odd.
It seems a rulerwas used so that
the handwriting cannot be identified.
May I open it?
Yes, please do
11S 15...
The.cursed mask will sip blood tonight...
From the messenger of
the cursed mask...
Ms. Suou, you'd better call the police...
There's nothing to worry about.
Ever since I've started the charity show,
I've been bothered by pranks like these.
Yes, this stew Is very delicious indeed!
This wine sure is good too!
Dining Room
Talk about top class!
Ladies and Gentlemen,
I am greatly thankful that
you have all pleasantly accepted
to appear as guests
¥ on-the chari. show that I will be hosting.
Ms. Suou, may I ask you a question?
What is it?
How did you come across the idea of
saving children
whose parents who have become
victims of traffic accidents?
I started charity about 15 years ago.
But, to tell the truth,
» my manager caused a hit-and run case...
A hit-and-run?
Yes... ever since then,
I could not stand being
indifferent to traffic accidents...
There are people saying that
shggis-a-publicity seeker
-g¥utlit'ssreally-not anything likesthat.
Um...what happened to the manager
<after the incident». .?
She-committed suicide.
What...?
That manager happened to be
my mother.
You: mother...?
Since I lost my father at a young age,
after my mother died,
I was sent around to my relatives' homes.
I really had it tough
But, Ms. Suou here helped me
In every way she could...
I'm what I am today, thanks to Ms. Suou!
Touya's mother was more a cherished
friend of mine than a manager.
There are many at Kurenai Productions
that have lost their families
in traffic accidents.
Ms. Suou is puttingda lot of effort
inthelping the:children
of traffic accident victims,
become independent.
Kugh! What a touching story!
I'll cooperate as much as I can
at your charity show next week!
Same here.
In fact, I lost my wife in a traffic accident
20 years ago...
I'm sure that my wife in heaven is happy
that I'm going to be taking part in
Ms. Suou's charity show too...
West Wing Third Floor
Suou's Living Quarters
{HPIK
Uh, I'd like you to investigate
something for me, Mr. Mourn.
West Wing Third Floor
Suou's Living Quarters
OmED JUD
Yes, I know.
You'd like me to figure out the one
who sent out those letters, right?
Well, I wonder if you can check in detail
on the traffic accident
that took Mr. Katagiri's wife.
Mr. Katagiri's... 7?
May I ask you why...7?
There is something that bothers me...
Would 2 million yen be enough to do it?
2 million yen?!
I'd be more than glad to!
You're pretty good, King of Homeruns!
It's just luck!
Mr. Mouri, this year is a good year
for you to begin something new.
What, really?!
Why then Mr. Mouri, how about making
a debut as a singer from our company?!
What, a singer?!
I'm sure it'll make a great hit if it is sung
by the detectives f the Heisei Era,
Kogoro Mourt!
I guess I'll sing you a song then...
We're sorry...
Oops!
Everyone,
when the clock strikes midnight,
we have a tradition of locking the door
of the-room--oftMmasks.
When the door is locked,
we will not be able to pass back and
forth between the east and west wings.
Therefore, we would like you to go into
your rooms before that.
Midnight is still too early
o hit the sack...
Is there a reason for locking the doors
at midnight?
Theymasks of Chableu like pranks
and begin playing
(on their own come midnight.
Therefore! we must lock the doors
and keep them confined.
T, That's ridiculous
It's true.
Come morning
the masks are tilted unnaturally,
or down on the floor.
This has happened many*timesstill now.
Now, please go into your rooms,
'everyone.
En. how occult can the
East Wing Second Floor
Guest Room
=A BE
His snoring is so noisy
at I can't sleep...
Bugha?! Ugho!!
N extension phone...
Funyah...
Hee-hee-hee-hee! Ha, ha, ha!
Who are you?!
Messenger of the cursed masks...
Messenger of the cursed masks?!
What the?!
Hand it over!
Hey!
The cursed masks are starving for blood.
Who will be the sacrifice?
WwW What?!
You'd better hurry before it's too late.
Kugh!
Hat bastard...
Kugh! It's locked!
Ran, Conan, wake Honami up
and bring the key to this room!
Okay!
Hah!!
Ss locked...
The phone a while ago was
from an extension...
The person's in this mansion...
Dad!
Honami, please give me the key!
Aaaagh!!
The masks of Chableu are gone...!
What is the meaning of this...
What the?!
Hat was that...
It came from above...
Ms. Suou's bedroom?!
You can't go that way!
What?!
In order to get to her room, you have to
take the stairs on the west side...!
Ugh...
his door is locked too...
I'll wake Minaho
and make her open the door!
Hey, what on earth is this racket about...
In the middle of the night...
Aaagh?
He masks of Chableu are gone...?
What on earth is going on?!
Ms. Suou! Ms. Suou!
Kugh, this door is locked too!
Crack that glass!
Hmm?
Mr. Mourn,
just what are you going to do...?
Is anything wrong with Ms. Suou??
Hey, how's Ms. Suou?!
It seems that she's hurt.
She bleeding badly!
What?!
The masks of Chableu are scattered
all over the room!
The masks of Chableu?!
Aaaagh...!
Re there any other entrances...?
Agh?!
There's another door over there!
That door's no good!
It's been sealed off
for quite a while already!
Hoots...
I'll go in from there
and check out the inside!
I guess there is no other choice...!
Dad! Here you go!
We're counting on you!
Yep!
Hah!
The door is locked all right...
Ss a double lock too...
Hurry and go check on Ms. Suou!
Yep...
How is it?!
No good... too late...
Oh my God...!
Kugh...Ms. Suou... .!
Ms. Suou!
Don't come in! Please stay here!
Kugh.
Slashed in the throat in one blow...
How cruel...!
D. Don't tell me, Mr. Mourn...
that this is... murder?!
It can't be!
The door was locked, wasn't it?!
From the looks of the corpse
suicide is impossible...!
My curse has been fulfilled...
hat was that...
This is a declaration
vhat'a 'murder will be committed.
from the messenger of
the cursed masks...!
What the...?!
Huh?!
What?!
It's a curse!
The curse of the masks!
She cursed to death by the masks!
Ms. Suou was cursed to death
y the masks...
hat's ridiculous...
But, the scene of the crime is
a locked room.
How on earth did the murderer
Kill Ms. Suou...?!
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa.
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
MaSatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi-Kobayashi
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR:
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation