Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
Today is a special of a cursed mask.
A mysterious room and an eerie smile.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene.
The Masks Smile Callously
The messenger of the cursed masks...
Why didn't youlreport it to the police
when you first found this letter?
Well, the victim, Ms. Suou
mentioned that she had been receiving
similar pranks for some time,
and to not worry about it...
So, these are the cursed masks...
Yes...
We heard a groan and a loud crash.
It could've been the sound of the Killer
scattering the masks.
You said that this door was
Iocked from inside?
Yes, that's why
I cracked the glass above the door,
made Conan go inside
and verified Ms. Suou's death.
The door was definitely locked.
All two doors were locked...
wo doors...
Ms. Suou always locked
both locks on her door.
His door lock...
and then this padlock...
Why did the victim have
two locks on her door?
Well, according to her secretary,
Ms. Inaba...
when Ms. Suou went to have the curse of
the masks sealed in by a clairvoyant,
she was told to carry out several things.
One of them was to put two locks
Nn the bedroom door...
clairvoyant, eh...
Which means that the victim herself,
opened the door and let the victim in...?
Well, it doesn't seem so
Hmm...?
It seems that Ms. Suou was suffering
from insomnia lately,
and was taking sleeping pills.
That's why there were no traces of
the victim having struggled?!
If the victim locked the door as usual
drank sleeping pills and went to bed,
how did the killer get into the room...?
Hmm, what IS this door .
There us a bedroom next door too,
but that door seems to have been
closed off for many years.
It seems to be nailed shut,
and there are no traces of
it having been opened.
The railing above the door,
is that bar removable?
I checked on it, but it was not.
The space between the bars is
about 5 or 6 centimeters,
so not even an arm can go through.
How about that window
on the other side?
That window is fixed on.
There Is nothing abnormal about it.
If so, how and where did the killer
go in and out of this room?
The only door that could be opened
and shut, was locked from the inside.
'Lihe door to the-bedroom next door
IS nailed and sealed.
The space between the bars above it,
isso-nanrow-that
not even an arm can get through.
The windows are both fixed on
and there-seems-to be
nothing wrong with them.
It's also impossible for the victim herself
to have opened the door
and let the killer in, because she was
under the effect of sleeping pills.
The room is a locked room,
where you can't get in or get out of!
I wonder if Ms. Suou really drank
the sleeping pill herself?
Huh?
If she didn't drink it herself,
who would make her...
uh? Wait a sec...
I've got it, Inspector!!
What?! Is that true?!
The killer met Ms. Suou
in the middle of the night,
made her drink something
with.a'sleeping- pill in-it,
put her to sleep...
Then, the killer carries Ms. Suou to her
bed on the bed and kills her there!
I see!
And, how did the killer lock the door
when leaving the room?!
OO. Oh well...
I don't know just yet!
VAgh...
only half of the locked room mystery
can be.explained...
The door is the only possible way
that the killer could've come in from,
but how on earth did the killer lock
the door from the outside?
If the lock were just a handle
that could be turned,
then using a string or something
may unlock it...
But, the padlock ls the problem.
In order to lock this,
the door has to be closed first.
Then the door and the metal piece
on the door frame has to be matched.
Only after doing so,
can the pole be stuck into
the two metal fixtures.
I feel that it is impossible to do all this
rom outside the door...
What kind of trick
did the killer use anyway...?
- » Tas
O Ira er wa IC - e 1 er use
why didn't the killer
make it look like a suicide,
ter doing all this to kill her...
The killer called our room
just before the murder was committed...
As if to let us know beforehand
that murder was going to take place...
This knife seems to be
the murder weapon.
This is what was decorated
in the room of the masks.
It was poked into the bed pole,
but there's something odd...
As you can see, the handle of it is also
smeared with blood
It sure is odd...
If the killer is holding the handle,
there should be no blood there...
Talking of blood,
there were masks among the masks
that were scattered on the floor
with blood splattered on them too.
This was found on the bed.
It seems to have been splattered
with blood at close range.
I think that the killer was wearing
this mask
when committing the murder...
If so, there may be some traces of
the Killer left...
Are there other masks
that have been splattered with blood?
Yes, but it's quite strange...
All the other masks had blood
nly around the mouth...
There is a spook story
concerning the masks
that says the masks sip the blood of
the people who own them...
Don't be silly...
Could the killer have scattered the masks
to confuse investigations
with occult stories?
That's most likely...
I wonder if that's the only reason why
the killer scattered the masks?
No, I'm sure there is some other reason.
If I could only figure that out.
Inspector!
Oh, Officer Kobayashi, how was it?
We checked ever nook and crann
surrounding the mansion,
but maybe because of the snow
that has accumulated,
there are no signs of
the killer having gone in or out!
Which means that the killer us...
A person that is within the mansion...!
Aside from Mr. Mouri and his family,
those who were insthis mansion are
camera man, Masanori Katagiri,
pro baseball player, Mamoru Matsudaira,
popular Fortune-teller, Haruka Nagara,
rock singer, Touya Aikawa,
the victim's secretary, Kazuyo Inaba,
and the twin maids,
Minaho and Honami Shimogasa.
A total of 7 people
We can narrow down
the suspects a bit more.
What do you mean?
111]
You can't get to Ms. Suou's bedroom
which is on the 3rd floor,
without using the stairs of the west wing.
At the time-of the incident,
the doors leading to the east and west
wings were both locked.
This has already been verified.
In other words,
you couldn't pass from the east wing
to the west wing at that time.
Which means that the killer is someone
who was in the west wing
of the mansiong,
Who were in what rooms?
First, on the 1st floor of the east wing,
were Mr. Aikawa and Honami
In the west wing
were Ms. Inaba and Minaho.
On the 2nd floor east wing were we three,
2nd Floor
in the west wing, were
Mr. Katagiri, Mr. Matsudaira and Haruka.
2nd Floor
There are 5 sus
Mr. Katagiri, Mr. Matsudaira, Ms. Nagara,
Ms. Inaba and Minaho
Yes, the messenger of the cursed masks
are amongethe five...!
H...everyon
I hate to have to do this,
knowing how tired you all must be,
but I'd like to ask you a few questions.
The incident occurred,
in the wee hours of the
morning at around 2:30.
Please tell me in order, what you
were doing at that time.
First, Honami?
I was fast asleep in my room until
Ran came to wake me
You got the key and
headed for the 2nd floor?
Where do you keep the key?
On the kitchen wall that
Is next to this dining room
So anybody could take
it and use it at will?
But, the key was
definitely there at that time
Ran?
She's right.
Are there any spare keys?
They are old keys, so
we canst make spares.
When we unlocked the door
and went into the room of masks
we noticed that the masks of
Chableu were gone.
That was when we heard the
groan and loud noise from the 3rd floor
Yes, and while we were waking Minaho on
the extension phone,
Aikawa came along.
I was sleeping in my room on
the 1st floor too
I realized that they had come to
wake Minaho but,
I didn't think it was a big deal.
Then, it started getting noisy,
so I went to the 2nd
floor to check things out
I was awakened by Honami
on the extension phone,
took the key and went to the 2nd floor.
I was also sleeping
in my room, but since it
started to get noisy outside,
I got up and went out
into the corridor, just as
Minaho had come up the stairs.
Same with me
Me too...
Ms. Inaba, I heard that you did not appear
at the time the corpse was found?
I over drank wine last night
and was totally passed out.
So, you didn't realize
all the racket going on?
N.No...
Oh, Mr. Katagiri, have you ever
met Ms. Suou before?
No, I met her for the first time yesterday.
Why?
Ms. Suou asked me to check on the traffic
accident that took your
wife's life 20 years ago.
Huh, Ms. Suou did? Why?
Do you have any idea why?
No, I don't
Ms. Suou asked Pops to check on the
traffic accident that took
Mr. Katagiri's wife's life?
Why would she want to check on a traffic
accident that happened 20 years ago?
Your mother got into a traffic accident
twenty years ago too,
didn't she, Mr. Aikawa?
Huh? Yeah, that's right
Huh? Don't tell me that?!
Mr. Katagin?!
Will you tell us about the traffic
accident that took your wife's life?
You'll find out sooner or later
even if I didn't tell you
Yes, my wife was the
victim of the traffic accident
that Mr. Aikawa's mother had caused
OO. Oh no
Didn't you know about it, Mr. Aikawa?
No...because I was still only six years old
But, how is that traffic accident
connected to today's murder case?
The police think that
the murderer is among
us, isn't that right?
What?!
Oh no! Is that true, Inspector?!!
Oh, no, not really...
I recall that it had
stopped snowing after 12:00
I'll bet you couldn't find
traces of the killer on the snow?
Ugh...
Is she right, Inspector?!
It can't be helped
Yes, it's true that there are
no traces of the killer
having entered or left the mansion
Oh no...
You mean the killer is among us?
Moreover, since the room of masks was
Iocked, the killer has to be one of the five
that was in the west wing!
Mr. Katagiri, Haruka, Ms Inaba,
Mr. Matsudaira and Minaho
null; vvdit d sel tidL wWdo d slidiiye
remark.
Why that remark?
But, it's difficult to determine the suspect.
I think there is a way.
Don't tell me that you're
going to find the killer
using your cards, are you?
From the looks of the scene of the crime,
killer probably was
splattered by a lot of blood.
Although it is possible to avoid blood
on the face by wearing the mask,
it would not be as easy remove the
blood from the hair and body.
I see! The killer is someone who had time
to wipe the blood that splattered on, off!
W., What?! Are you saying
that I'm the killer?!
The only person who had
time to wipe blood off
IS you, because you
weren't at the scene where
the body was found
You've got to be kidding!
Why would I have to kill Ms. Suou?!
Hey, you!
Agh!!
Cut out your nonsense!
Please calm down!
You fraud fortune-teller!!
Agh!!
That's what happene
I was completely deceived
by the trap that the killer had set
But, the trick's over!
I've figured out...the curse of the masks!
Huh? What's up, Conan?
Mr. Mouri says he has a favor to ask you.
Huh...?
What is it? Hey, what?
On the chest over there. Take a look at it!
What a nuisance...
There's nothing h
Leave the rest to me, Pops
So, this is the bedroom next door...
So a bedroom that looks
just like Ms. Suou's was right next door
This room, with the same structure
as that of the room
where the crime took place,
is what helped solved
the mystery of the locked doors
as well as reveal the identity of the killer.
What? You mean
Ms. Inaba is not the killer?
I've been saying that I'm not!!
Have you solved the
mystery of the locked doors?!
Yes, I've figured everything out.
Who on earth is the killer?!
The killer who killed
Ms. Beniko Suou in a locked room
Messenger of the Cursed Mask" is
you!!
The "Messenger of the Cursed Mask" is
You!
Mr. Touya Aikawa!!
What?
NO...
Oh no...?!
WwW. What on earth are you
talking about, Mr. Mourn?
How could I, who was
in the east wing of the
mansion have gone to
Ms. Suou's bedroom?
Yes, it's true that you
could not go to Ms. Suou's bedroom
In order to prove that
You called us on the extension phone,
just before you committed the murder!
But, if he couldn't go to her':bedroom,
how could he have committed the crime?
I've been suspicious
from the time the body was found.
I kept thinking of why the Killer,
despite having committed the crime
behind a locked door,
did not make her death look to be suicide.
It was because he couldn't
Mr. Aikawa
killed Ms. Suou without
entering her bedroom at all!
WwW, what?!
Without going into her bedroom...?
Phooey, impossible...
It's possible, with the help
of the cursed masks
D,Don't tell me that you really believe in
things such as curses?
No. But the masks of Chableu are indeed
the key to committing murder
behind locked doors.
I will replay that method here.
Officer Takagi!!
Yes sir!
Huh?!
I borrowed a knife that
Is similar to the murder weapon.
There is a rubber rope attached through
the hole at the rear end of the handle
Next for the mask.
The rubber rope is passed through
both eyes of all the masks
And the rubber rope attached to the knife is
passed through the
mouth hole of all the masks.
After all of us went to bed, Mr. Aikawa
went to the kitchen to get the key
to enter the room of masks.
He stole the masks of Chableu and a knife
en OC G 8 OOI an
returned the key to the kitchen.
He brought the masks
and knife into this room,
and carried on with the rubber rope trick.
He dropped the masks and the knife into
Ms. Suou's bedroom through
the space between the railing
The size of the space is 5X5 centimeters.
A thin mask would easily slide through.
Can you really solve the mystery of the
Iocked door doing something like this?
Well, please watch.
This is the last mask!
After placing all the masks inside the room
he pulled the rubber
rope towards himself
Now everyone, since
the mask is 15 millimeters thick,
if 200 are piled up one
on top of the other,
the pile would be 3 meters.
The position of the neck of the victim
asleep in bed was about
3 meters and a half from the railing
So, then what...
Aaagh!!
Whaaa!!
From the edge of the knife to the
victim's throat is only 10 centimeters.
All he had left to do now, was to push
the masks out using a ruler or something
By using these stairs that only the people
who are in the east wing
of the mansion can climb
Mr. Aikawa killed Ms. Suou
without setting foot into her room at all.
I see! One of the masks
was badly covered blood because
it was the mask on the very top,
wasn't it?!
The reason why several masks
had blood by the mouth,
was because Ms. Suou's
splattered on them
And he finally severs the rubber rope
that was passed through the eyes
of the masks and the handle of the knife.
His is...
So, that's it for the locked door mystery!
It's all baloney! Just where do you
have the proof that I used that trick!
Mr. Aikawa, you're acting in bad grace
Haven't you realized that you've already
confessed that you are the killer?
What the?! What do you mean...?!
While you were being
questioned a while ago,
you said,
I noticed that the kids came
to wake Honami up.
Yeah, because I was in my
room on the first floor then!
When you said, "Those kids" who
and Ran were you referring to?
Who else but the kid named Conan!
Huh, how strange.
I didn't say a word back then,
and yet how did you know I was with Ran? WW
Right, I opened the door a
bit and looked out.
That's why I know that he was with her!
Really?
Really!
Then, it's even stranger.
Because I didn't go with Ran
I went to check if the doors
around the house were locked!
OO, Oh no...
Is that true?!
Y. Yes
I went to Honami's room alone
I did tell Ran and Conan to go get
Honami back then.
Didn't you think that they
went together to Honami's room
because when you heard me say so,
you were in the room in the 3rd floor?
Only because of something like
that. ..you.
Touya! After all she did for you,
how could you!
Shut up! After all she did for me?
You've got to be kidding!
That lady blamed the hit-and-run accident
that she caused on my mother,
and made it look as if
she committed suicide!
Is that true?!
It's true! Although I found out
about it just 2 months ago.
I was cleaning out my
mother's belongings
when a letter fell out from
behind the cover of her diary
and the truth about the incident was
ritten in it...
That's a he! It's all baloney!
No it's not! Mother had an alibi!
The accident occurred on the
night of October 31st
October 31...
Touya s birthday...
Right! Mother was with
me right through on that day!
Which means that the one who
hit-and-ran my wife
was Suou
Moreover, she didn't even
know that your wife
was the victim of a
traffic accident, Mr. Katagiri!
I guess she asked me
to investigate on the case,
after she heard Mr. Katagiri
talk about it at dinner.
Ms. Suou is a fine person who has
been hosting charity shows for 15: years!
What a laugh!
That lady embezzled the money
that was raised to fatten her own pocket!
Mw That's a lie! Ms. Suou wollldinever
do any such thing!
You also got part of the cash, didn't you!
You're not playing dumb with me!
I wanted to keep Mr. Katagiri
from participating in this corrupt charity
no matter what
That Lady
Beniko Suou was a devil wearing
the mask of person practicing good will!
Just to think that I felt grateful
for her having saved me, all these years
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Kats 8 Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
MaSatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazi mar Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu HorikosHt
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
ED TOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Keri Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
O Gosho Aoyama 7 Jog Wukan
I! Rights Reserved
It could be that Mr. Aikawa was
possessed by the curse of the masks.
Curses are only superstitions!
Curse! This is a curse...!
That's no curse, Pops,
it's just that you're a klutz