Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
In television, movies, and books
detectives are everywhere
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved when
Detective Conan comes to the scene.
Grr! Humph! Come on!
Ow, I bit my tongue
Drive safely will you, pops
They advertised the place as being
a very secluded & little known hot spot!
Of course it's going to be hard to get to!
Yes, I can see it now
Hey dad, this road is paved
Weren't we supposed to take
this road to get here?
Look! They've got an archery area!
You're just trying to change the subject
I figured....
Look out!
I'm so sorry!
It went off course
Are you alright?
Look you!
Oh! I know you! You're Kogoro Mouri the
famous detective! It is you isn't it?!
Well, uh, yes you're very perceptive.
Are you staying at the villa too?
Hmm, you mean you are too?
Yes...
I guess this means the two famous
detectives will finally meet...
Huh?
MURDER OF THE FAMOUS DETECTIVE
PART I
What is this, isn't anybody on duty
Excuse me!
Good grief, what was that...
Those were gunshots
The forest around us is hunting grounds
What?!
The Mouri party I presume.
Yusaku Akashi
Sansou's Innkeeper
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting.
I'm here alone today
Dad! We drove right through that forest,
we could've been hurt.....
Actually...the hunting areas are marked
with signs & fenced off
but there's always the danger of
being hit by a stray bullet
we've already been baptized,
only it was by an arrow...
Welcome back
Here's your key
Who does he think he is anyway!
We're very proud of our garden
restaurant here, please have dinner there
Garden restaurant?
Just have a look
Wow, it's beautiful
Wow, Ran, look at this!
There's a mountain stream down there!
Conan, be careful!
OK
Oh dear, rain!
Oh brother! If it keeps raining
we won't be able to eat in
this great garden restaurant!
...Why, you're!
That's right...Jack the Ripper the 5th!!
Who's there?!
Why, you're!!
that's right...Urban hunter Bannai Kujirao,
at your service!!
How can you watch such junk
How rude, it was getting to the best part!
Humph, he's no detective
REAL cases don't get solved so easily
week after week like that
I'm very sorry you think their so easy...
Urban hunter
Bannai Kujirao at your service!
Oh wow!! It's really you!
.....Uh huh......
This is Kazuyoshi Sunaoka
the actor who plays Bannai Kujirao
I'm his manager, Noe Tanigawa.
It's nice to see you again
You're Kogoro Mouri,
the genuine detective.
It's a pleasure to meet you
You know, I'm actually a big fan of yours.
Can I have your autograph later?
Oh brother
Well, well, well thank you!
And here's my calling card, just in case
It's such an honor to be at the same table
with the famous detective Mouri!
The same goes for me! I never dreamed
I'd get to meet a famous actor!
Are you filming here?
Sh! Actually, I've been given secret
orders to come here & protect you!
We're here to discuss the show
& just to relax.
Naturally, no one besides us knows that
the popular star Mr. Sunaoka is with us
Katsuaki Nagatsuka
Producer
You're a great team
Sunaoka & I went out this afternoon
to enjoy some hunting
We took cover under the rain &
stayed out all day but got zilch....
I can't believe how anyone could shoot
live animals...
Noe Tanigawa
Sunaoka's Manager
that's why I opted for archery....
Oh! I did, however nearly spear
some humans!
Yes, it was a close call, we nearly
ended up as trophies on the wall
What do you mean by that?
By the way, and what were YOU doing?
You don't look like you've gotten rid of
your stress
That's because I stayed in my room
thinking up a plot for the next show
Toshiaki Tahara
Scenerio Writer
That man's kind of scary....
And did you come up
with something good, sir?
Kazu!
Lately it seems the viewers solve
the crime before I do. That just won't do
Mr. Sunaoka, put yourself in my shoes.
I have to write scenarios to fit
YOUR personality
Now now, we're here to work something
out to make the show more enjoyable.
Let's have some constructive suggestions
That's easy for you to say...
all you're concerned about is the money
I know all about it, I hear you're pocketing
some of the production fees
How dare you!
That's a lie!
Alright, that's enough
Hmm...there's a lot of bad blood
behind the scenes....
Kazu, I think you've had a little bit
too much to drink,
let's get you back to your room
Leave me alone! I want to talk to
Mr. Mouri a little longer...
You're always so bossy!
But that won't be for long.
A major production company's offering
me a bundle to sign up with them
What are you talking about!
We've discussed that over & over again.
Now come on, go to your room &
get some sleep
I'm the biggest star your agency's got,
if you lose me, you probably won't
be able to stay in the business, huh.
Well, Mr. Detective
I'll catch you again later
Mr. Tahara, if you've got
any gripes against me just let me know,
I'll quit anytime
Kazu, if you quit,
the whole show will go down the drain
Tanigawa, do something
what you see on TV & reality is really
two different things....
It certainly is
I'm sorry about that scene
You may not think so but
that guy's very conscientious,
he's very serious about
making the show a success
It's just that he can't hold his liquor...
please forgive him
Yes...well...good luck to you
Thank you, and now,
shall we continue drinking?
Why it's empty
Here, I'll go get you another one
Here, your key!
I didn't mean what I said...sorry...
Goodnight
Boss...
Sorry to keep you waiting
Oh, thanks!
It was worth the wait!
These are for you two
Why thank you
Thanks
No problem, here you go Mr. Mouri
Now that Mr. Sunaoka & Ms. Tanigawa's
gone, he's suddenly in such a good mood
Tahara, why don't you join us
Sure....
Oh....excuse me for a second
That's with you
I just thought of an interesting trick!
I better write it down before I forget
It's not easy being a writer.
Oh well, cheers!
Cheers!
Mr. Nagatsuka! You have a call from
Tokyo, you can take it at the front desk!
It's 8 o'clock, who could it be at this hour
excuse me for a minute
What a drag, I'm all alone....
keep me company, you've got your juice
Dad, I think you've had enough!
Hello...this is Kogoro Mouri...
How about it? Why don't you come up
to my room & we'll talk detective?
Oh, Mr. Sunaoka, it's you...
Huh? Hold on for a second,
what is that?
Uh, hello hello, Mr. Sunaoka?
...of all the...
What's the matter, dad?
That was Mr. Sunaoka,
first he asks me to come up to his room,
then he hangs up on me
A gunshot...?!
It sounded like it came from
across the valley!
What could anyone be shooting at
at this hour?
Everyone stay inside,
it might be dangerous!
Oh it's Ms. Tanigawa...
What is it?
Did you just hear that gunshot?
So it was a gunshot after all!
I'm sure Kazu's asleep by now....
The window in Kazu's room.....
There's a hole in it!
It looks like a bullet hole!
What did you say?!
Sir, the key!
Oh, yeah, you're right!
Mr. Akashi!! Get the master key &
meet us in front of Mr. Sunaoka's room!
Hey, what's going on?
Mr. Sunaoka! Wake up!
Isn't he answering?
He never gets up
when he falls asleep when he's drunk...
Here you are!
I've brought the key but...
Mr. Sunaoka, we're coming in!
Someone tell me what happened!
Why would anyone kill Kazu!
Mr. Mouri, it's been a long time
Why Detective Yokomizo.
Take a look at this
As for you, ladies & gentlemen
Please wait downstairs in the lobby.
I'll be down to question you later
Sure, he says some harsh things
when he's drunk
but it's nothing anyone would
kill him over!
Oh what am I going to do,
I'm going to answer for this....
And they just decided to extend the show....
OK everyone,
I know how you must all feel but
the crime lab technicians are
coming in now...
By the looks of it, the only wound is
the bullet wound on his forehead
That's right, that's what killed him.
But seeing as the flesh isn't burned &
also there are no powder burns
I'd say he was shot from a distance
The height of this hole & Mr. Sunaoka's
position were he was standing is
almost the same height...
I'm pretty sure he was shot
while he was standing by the window...
which means the shooter was....
When we heard the shot being fired,
it came from across the valley
Let's go have a look
Huh?! What's that?
It looks like there's some kind of
plant fiber mixed in with the glass....
Conan!!
Always getting in our way,
what is it with you!
Come here!
You're getting fast
The only way to get to the other side of
the valley from the villa is
by crossing this suspended bridge
Be careful & only 5 can cross at a time
It's quite far from the villa
Yes it is...
Now we walk along the cliff for
about 10 minutes &
we'll be across from the villa
We're here
Finally...
It takes 30 minutes one way
But then the shooter's escape route
becomes another puzzle
Who's there!
...I..I'm sorry
Ra Ra Ra Ran?!
What are you doing here!!
Well....
Conan went charging out of the villa...
I got worried so I followed him....
So why are you hiding in there!!
Well, uh...Conan....
where'd he go?
There!!
Why the!!
Conan!!
the rifle's over here!
D, dad...
Tie him up someplace
Conan, you were very naughty
I'm sorry
We've got cartridge casings here...
I think it's safe to say
this is the murder weapon
The killer must have stood here
aiming for Mr. Sunaoka
on the other side of that window
Take these casings & that rifle to the lab
right away!
Yessir!
What's this?
The underside of this rifle is dry
Take a shot of this
Mr. Mouri, what time did it stop raining
around here?
Let's see...in the evening,
it had stopped by the time it got dark...
Then I wonder why it wasn't wet
under the rifle...
Never mind that Detective Yokomizo,
after shooting Mr. Sunaoka,
the killer escaped through this road.
You'd better get a roadblock set up
right away...
Oh yeah, you're right!
Hey, something's not right
Remember?
When we climbed up here, we didn't see
anyone else's footprints, did we!
That's right.
It was so slippery after the rain
I was so scared of that mountain path,
I kept my head down following
Conan's footprints,
so I know I didn't see anyone else's
So maybe the killer took this road
There aren't any footprints on this side
I don't understand
What gives around here anyway...
Mr. Mouri!
Take a look at this.
There's a rope tied to this tree!
What?!
I'm pretty sure the killer used this rope
and escaped by that stream...
The current's strong
so the killer probably used a rubber raft
to get here from upstream
The killer ties the raft on the shore
then climbs up the rocks
then waited for Mr. Sunaoka
to appear at the villa
then...
Mr. Sunaoka was shot
then the killer used this rope
to get back down
then probably used the raft
to get downstream...
Oh no!
Set up roadblocks in the areas
downstream!!
He's wrong!!
There was danger of being seen
by the people in the restaurant,
climb up & down from here
& the killer certainly wouldn't shoot
from this
besides, when we heard
the gunshot & came running,
there's no way the killer
could have gotten away
without being seen...
which means...
Hey, Conan!
I knew it!!
The rope's wet
Conan!
Stop! That's enough!
Alright
We're going back
You're going to get lost
if you keep wandering around
Wait up
Where were you
when you heard the gunshot?
I had a call from the station,
I was on the telephone at the front desk
so I didn't hear it
We've already confirmed it
with the other party
Hmm...so you were using the telephone
at the front desk, is that correct
Yes, but not the public telephone.
I was using the front desk's phone.
It has a cord
That's right!
Outside calls all come in on that
The battery in my portable phone
was dead
I see...
and what about you Mr. Tahara?
I was at the garden restaurant putting
ideas for the scenarios together...
I was concentrating so much,
I didn't hear the gunshot at first...
by the time I looked to where the shot
came from with Mr. Mouri & the others,
there was nobody around
That's right...
when the shot went off
it was just after Mr. Nagatsuka got
his telephone call at 8 o'clock!
When Mr. Mouri & the others came to
the front desk to get the master key,
I was just getting off the phone
I'm sure you can track the time of the call
if you check the phone records, right?
You make my job of
questioning you so easy
being you're all in the mystery profession.
And what about you, Ms. Tanigawa?
After I took Mr. Sunaoka back to
his room, I went to take a shower...
Just as I was getting out of the shower,
when I heard the sound
but it never dawned on me that
we were in danger.
There was a commotion outside so
I went out to the veranda to have a look...
A, and I never dreamed
Kazu had been shot...!
...I'm very sorry...
Mr. Akashi, where were you?
I was in the kitchen washing dishes...
the fan was on & I'm so used to hearing
the shots from the hunting grounds
so I didn't hear a thing
That's right...
it was physically impossible for anyone
in the villa to fire the rifle
from that spot...!
The only ones staying in the villa
besides us is that group....
Although it was kept secret that
Mr. Sunaoka was here,
it wouldn't have been too hard
to find that out...
But if the killer was someone
from the outside,
it would have made better sense
to shoot him on the hunting grounds &
make it look like he was shot accidentally
by a stray bullet.
And to find a safe hiding place,
there were other options.
So why deliberately use a boat &
rope to escape
& risk being seen from the restaurant
I'm absolutely sure that was a camouflage.
And there's only one reason for going
through all that trouble!
The killer needed an alibi.....
Which means the killer is someone
from the villa!!
Yes....that's right,
one of those 3
is the killer.
There's an exit to every maze....
this seemingly impossible murder...
I vow to solve this case on behalf of the
murdered detective!!
I didn't embezzle any money
from the production!
You'll know when you check on it
You mean one of us is the killer?
The most suspicious person is you,
Miss Tanigawa!
How dare you!!
Those things mixed with the
pieces of glass...
Where'd they come from?
I knew it! Just as I thought!
MURDER OF THE FAMOUS DETECTIVE
PART II