Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
That unforgettable melody
brought us an unusual case.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the l.Q. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
I get involved in a case &
end up getting hurt
The-blood-transfusion
from Ran saves me...
But Ran has guessed who I really'am!!
An antidote Al makes for me
changes me back into Shinichi,
and then she disguises
herself to look like Conan
so that Ran's suspicions will vanish...
Please...l need just a little more time...
she's waiting for me... U
I can't turn into Conan
again now...not;yet...
Ha iHaibara?! You...
Why ..Why
24 minutes over time...
I guess that's the maximum
tolerance level...
I'll consider this a loan...
Conan?
(RAR)
THE ENTRUSTED MUSIC BOX
PART I
What is it?...
The antidotesfor the apoxin 4869!
You stilllhave some, don't you?
May I have some?
Not on your life!
I wouldn't think of giving you any,
not with your habit of unthinkingly
getting.involved with
any dangerous crime you come across
Forget'about it!
Well let me apologize then...
I'll try to be more careful next time...
I already told you!
Hat was+*a trial drug...
I can"tygo around
administering'unperfected drugs...
You could really die from it next time...
I guess you can't come up with
the real thing using
only the ingredients for paikal
Yes...
If only we had the data for the real drug...
Oh well,
you should just be grateful she fell for
our ruse and count your blessings
Oh rats!
If I'd known.it was going
to turn out like this,
I should have just told her
what I intended to!!!
It's Doctor Agasa
Conanxare you sure you won't come?
We're going to the city's indoor pool...
It- has a wave making machine,
it's reallypyneat
Sorry, I've still got a cold
See you later!!
Tee hee...
Al, you're in a good mood...
I bet something nice happened to you!
Yeah, the school lunch today was curry!
She's not you, Genta!
Well, here we go.all over again...
Good grief, and it's already summer
I guess Spring won't be entering
my life for a long time...
Huh?...l1 know this song...
It's "Haru yo Kol
I'm back...
Hi Conan, welcome home!
Why I didn't know you had a son too
I don't,
I'm just taking care of this kid and...
What's wrong with this music box...
it sounds like it's skipping
a few keys here & there
This is none of your business!
How old are you, son?
Uh, er, 7, I think...
He's in the 1st grade but
he's very perceptive &
he's a big{help when it
comes to solving crimes!
I see...l guess that makes you
a little detective doesn't it...
Ehehe
Oh, that's right!
Why don't you tell Conan about it?
Maybe he'll be able:to help.finding
the person Haruna'is looking for!
She's looking forisomeone?
The truth is...
A bell friend?
You're looking for
a pocket bell (beeper) friend?
Yes, that's right... His name is Shugo
We met 3 years ago.
Haruna Yuki
Art student
I came to Tokyo around then
to attend an art university
Haruna Yuki
Art student
I came to Tokyo around then
to attend an art university
I had a hard time making
friends & I was very lonely,
so I started pressing numbers
at random onwmy pocket bell...
and sent messages saying,
My name is Haruna,
will you be myafriend?
And who would have imagined!
I got a reply:saying
My first girlfriend's name was Haruna.
This must be fate, let's be friends'!
We've been bell friends ever since...
Gee...
He seemed like such a nice old man
that I could confide all my secrets to...
Then if you.send a message with your
pocket bell that you want to see him,
won't"he come?
That's no longer possible...
You see, his pocket bell...
Is here, with me...
It was last Christmas...
I'd been working part-time
to pay for my tuition but
it was hard making ends meet
so I'd decided to quit school
& go back home, so I figured that
before I left, I'd meet him just once
so we decided to meet in front of the
Hachikostatue at the Shibuya station...
I waited for a long time...but no one
fitting his description appeared...
And just when I decided to
give up & leave...
I looked inside & found his pocket bell...
along with this music box
But how did you know that
that was his pocket bell?
There was a message
on that pocket bell . it said
This music box is worth a lot of money,
please use it to pay for your tuition &
don't give up your dreams, Haruna
I couldn't very well accept such an
expensive present, now could I?
Thatis why I thought I'd have it looked at
& maybe the owner couldrbe found,
then I could giverit back
I took it to an antique shop...
But the antique dealer said it was
just an old, broken music box...
And I've started gettingtstrange
messages on my pocket bell...
Strange messages?
It said, "I have something to ask you.
Meet me at the place
I've indicated, come alone...
And then? Did you go?
No...because the tone
just wasn't Shugo's style
it scared me somehow,
that's why I didn't go. O
Later that night though, I got messages
reading. Thief'. more than 10 of them...
More than 10...
Thief, eh... Do you know what it mean?.
And there was no way to contact
the 'sender to ask what it meant.
I thought it might have
something to do with Shugo,
that's why I came to you for help...
And are you still getting those messages?
No. thev kept coming but not anvmorjes
Hmmm
Hmmm...
that means this music
box is our only clue...
But what can an off tune
1usic box possibly tell us...
I don't think it's a lost cause
Huh?
Here, look!
The pins on the drum of
this music box are broken.
And it doesn't look like
they broke off naturally
because of long use,
it looks like they were
deliberately twisted &
broken of, doesn't it...
You're right...
It could be some kind of message!
It's possible...
the song is, Haru yo Koi" & the missing
notes are the la, do & la at the end...
Ladola?
It sounds like some kind of monster...
Do you know the words
for the missing parts?
Eh. Let's see...
that part of the song goes,
Onmo e detai to matte iru, which means
the missing parts are...
[Mo] and [de] and [ru]
Mo..de..ru
IModel!!
Shugo's a model!
Now that we know that much, we can
ask around all the model agencies...
That won't be ncessary,
it'll be faster if we go
talk to him personally
Stupid, she can't do that,
that's why she's here...
But you have the number
for his pocket bell, don't you?
Then you can explain
the situation to Officer Takagi
and have him contact
the pocket bell company
I'm sure we'll be able to get an address...
Way to go, Conan!!!
We've got the address
AND the telephone number!
You could be smarter than Shinichi!
Not really...
Officer Takagi did the work...
Humph
that's what I call abusing his authority...
By the way. Haruna, are you sure
he said you could visit him?
Yes...
but I don't think he was the
one who answered the phone
Everyone in his family seemed to
know he was very much into
pocket bell communication.
So when I told them that
I wanted to return the pocket bell and
music box I was keeping for him,
I was told to come by anytime...
I'm really looking forward to meeting him!
Yes, so am I...
Excuse me!
It's me, Haruna!!
Yes!
Please come in...
Oh my, you've brought friends along...
Kazuko Ogata
I guess you could say we're her escorts...
Mother, we can talk about that later...
Shiro...
The infamous Haruna
has come to pay us a visit...
Let's have her relax
in her room for awhile...
After all, she was such
a comfort to our grandfather...
Your grandfather?
That's right
but first, why don't you
offer him some incense...
Did she say incense...
You don't think...
Did he pass:away?
Yes, very suddenly
at thelend ofllast year...
Th, that's terrible...
Did he do any modelling?
What?
I guess not, ahaha...
Hahaha...
By the way,
about the music box
you got from my father...
Yes,
this is it!
Here you are...
I understand it's worth
a lot of money so I'd like to return it!
That's very kind of you...
this tune...
Haru yo koi...
You...
It's the song mother
often played on the harp...
Mother...
The woman in the photo...
That's right...
that'symy mother Haruna next to
father's photo, she died 3 years ago.
Haruna?
Th, three years ago...
I think you reminded my grandfather
of our late grandmother
He was very happy,
he told everyone
Haruna hadrcome back...
I realize this is rude,
but isn't it rather unusual for
a man his age to be using a pocket bell?
Not at all...
you see, after mother died,
father took to taking late night walks...
we made himycarry one along
because we were worried about him...
Aha...
Uh, by:the way...
Was there anything in the music box?
Like what?
Well, for instance, uh...
Stamps.
A set of four, they're hand carved
and worth about 200 million yen
Minoru Ogata
Jini!
There's only one reason
for you to come all the way here,
grandfather told you where he hid it
and you're here to look for it, aren't you?
That's not why I'm here...
Oh never mind...
you'll show your true colors eventually...
you just relax and have
a nice stay. Haruna
Ld°O
Good grief...
Don't mind him. He's just irritated
because his company's
not doing too good.
I see...
We appreciate you coming here today,
why don't you join us for dinner
and we'd like to hear
about dad from you...
I wonder what that guy meant
about'stamps worth 200-million yen...
and I wonder what those missing keys
on the music box mean...
What does it mean...
Phew...
boy, all those questions,
questions, questions during dinner.
Poor Haruna, I feel sorry for her
Andron top of that, it starts to pour so
we end up having to spend the night...
Hey, don't you think this is weird?
Yes, everyone in this family except
for Shiro, the second son. is weird...
That.s'not what I meant...
-- Look at that,
behind Shugo's mortuary tablet...
It says he died on December 6th...
So what about it?
Well Harunaysaid:she;got
A the music"box last year at Christmas
Which means,
if Haruna is telling the truth then
it wasn't Shugo that gave it to her,
it mustshave been someone else, right?
Let's just forget all about the
unpleasantness and get some sleep...
Hey, what's the matter, Ran?!
An, an old man with a cane just walked
down the corridor and-went to the left...
Who's there?!
Huh?
There's no body out there...
But I'm positive I saw him go left...
But that's where I'm sleeping!
What's wrong?!
Has something happened?
It's nothing, my daughter thought
she saw a strange shadow of someone...
Someone's shadow?
I think their imagination
got the best of them
It wasn't our imagination!
Didn't the guest who
stayed with us the last time
say they thought they felt someone walk
past their pillow when they were asleep'?
You meaniit happened before?
Well, uh...yes...
we should be the only ones here tonight
By the way, where's Minoru?
Probably 'in the bath
Good grief, now what?
It sounded like a bowstring breaking
You don't think it's. fromithe.room
where mother keeps her 'koto...
Let's go and have a'look!!
Hey, wait for us!
Mi, Minoru!
Minoru!
Hang in there Minoru! Minorut!
Minoru wake up!!
Hang on, Minoru!!
It's impossible...
What's wrong, Haruna?
Haruna!
I don't believe it...
I was waiting for you Haruna?
What?!
Y7T323 /N\NJ)LF
Tar sa
RTIYPEE LAT
Do you suppose this means that old
mans shadow we just saw as well as.
What just happened is all the work
of Shugo, the man who died last year...
You idiot! Once a.person dies,
they can't do anything!!
Instead of wasting time
making silly deductions,
get on the phone and call the policell
This could be a murder case...
Hey, wait
Ouch...don't go killing me off...
Minoru...
Minoru, what in the world happened?!
How should I know!
Somebody came out of nowhere and
hit me on the head with something hard...
Something hard
You mean that koto?
Probably...
Isn't that koto the one
grandmother loved the most?!
Haruna
don't tell me YOU
were the one who hit me!
1. I would never
You're wrong!
When we heard the loud noise,
we were all in Ran's room...
Right?
Huh? Yeah, that's right...
Then who did it...
Why are you asking?
You saw who hit you, didn't you?
What?
Because see, you were
hit on the forehead!
That means you were hit
from the front, right?
Humph! It was so dark,
I couldn't. see anything...
Eh? You mean this room
was dark too, when you got hit?
That's right...
When I heard a strange noise and felt
someone's presence in the dark
it was too late
But isn't that strange?
What do you mean?
What were you doing
all'by:yourself in the dark?
Eh?!
Well?
Minoru...
Minoru?
You idiot!
I'm sure Minoru came into this room
because he could
\ feel someone's presence
And just when he was
about to turn the lights on,
that person hit him with the koto!
Isn't that right, Minoru?
Yes...
I guess...
Then dad
what about the message on
Haruna's pocket bell?
Oh that...
that's probably from one of her friends
A friend?
You had probably promised
to meet a friend tonight...
but you forgot all about it
and came here...
and so that message,
I was waiting for you"
was probably from
your friend complaining...
Am I wrong, Haruna?
Yes...
I don't remember
making any such promise
Yes, well, a lot has
happened to you today,
I don't blame you for forgetting
Then what about the
old man's shadow I saw?
Huh?
Humph!
OR that...
M. maybe that's who
attacked m brother...
I don'tithink an old man with a cane
could lift a koto as heavy as that
and knock someone out...
You're absolutely right!
Even if that old man did exist,
he wouldn't have been able to
knock Minoru unconscious...
Besides, the old man Ran saw was
heading toward the end of the corridor...
and even if he tried
toihide inithe room at the end,
that's where Conan and I were sleeping...
Are you saying...
That old man was probably...
Probably
Just your imagination...
What?
As people used to say, Ghosts
are usually withered eulalia grass.
Now wait just one minute! I'really saw...
You're so scared of seeing ghosts,
that's why you imagined seeing one!
Dad!!
Anyway, ma'am,
you'd better call the police!
There's one thing we can be sure of,
someone else besides us is in this house!
Yes, right away!
Could the old man be right,
is somebody hiding
somewhere in this house?
If there is, what*doythey want...
By the looks of the room,
nothing seems to have been touched...
So whoever-lit is,
Minorulis the-target...
But this isn't his room
and I have a pretty good idea
what he was doing here in the dark room.
But I wonder how and when
the attacker found out about it
And about the koto used as the weapon...
Did the attacker have a reason for
picking the koto as the weapon?
Rats.
There's so many unanswered questions...
the shadow of the old man
Ranssaw is another mystery...
Was it really just her imagination?
And the last mystery is...
the off tune music box!!
I'm positive the music box is the
key to a very important secret...
It'll tell us where the very thing everyone
in this household is searching for, is...
It'll tell us where the stamps
worth 200 million is hidden!
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
(108170 Joyama
PRODUCERS .~
Michihitko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
KatSu8 Ono
CHARACTER " ESIGNS bY
MaSatomo Sudo
TORY EDI1TOY .
Junichi hoka
Kanji Kashiwibara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Hieure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshr Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
{itsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
T1ikashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
YDkihiro Shibutan:
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaca
RECORDIN , DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terunwltsu (Mad?
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]! Kodama
PRODUCED BY.
IMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecastine (corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gbsho Aoyama'! ghog 'kukan
YTV / TMS
All RiJhts Reserved
What does this sharp mean?
, Oh, that indicates an A major
A major?
Uh. no. I got the
music box last Christmas...
Th, that's ridiculous!
My father died lastiyear,
on December[6th!
H, how can that be... 1?
You-re not implying it was a ghost...
CC. Conan!?
THE ENTRUSTED MUSIC BOX