Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze has is invisible,
deductions take all shapes & sizes
in each & every case to be solved
A ghostly, a pocket bell,
stamps & a music box.
Seemingly separate mysteries
come toa singular end.
He sees through the one & only truth.
A child in appearance
with the l.Q of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
A young woman named Haruna Yuki
asks us to locate her pocket bell friend
who she hasn't been able to contact
because she wants to return his music box
but when we arrive at her friend
Shugo Ogatajsghtime
we learn that he is dead...
Later that night,
Ran sees the suspicious shadow
of an old man walk down the corridor.
And Shugo's grandson Minoru,
has been attacked by someone!
And then, Haruna gets a mysterious
message on her pocket bell...
Toker seu
THE ENTRUSTED MUSIC BOX
PART II
Eh?! You didn't find any
evidence of a break-in...?!
That's right...the rain has made
the ground pretty soft
but there're no footprints out there...
And even someone got in before the rain
there should be
footprints leaving the place...
But we didn't find
anyone suspicious inside!
The only thing we:werefconcerned about,
was the unlocked backdoor right? ¥
Yes...
The back door?
Oh that...
the lock on that dooms broken,
it opens even when the wind blows...
That does bother me...
hen why don't you take a look yourself?
Even if someone did
get in through that door
don't you think there should be some
footprints on the ground? It's so muddy
Hmm, that's true... .there're no footprints
If there were, then maybe we could
believe that story Ran told us
about seeing the shadow of an old man...
I told you, it wasn't my imagination!
Huh?
Oh no!
Would you mind moving
your patrol car a bit?
Yes, right away...I'm terribly sorry!
First, let's go over all the details one
more time, then we'll check out the house
All right .
Young lady. where did you see
the suspicious shadow?
Uh, right here...
In this corridor.
The old man with the cane was here
then he:disappeared back there...
Then he must have hidden
in that room at the far end...
No, I was in that room
and I would have noticed...
But I saw it!
I saw his shadow through
the screen door in this room...
And I saw it too!
Hey, whose room is this?
Oh, that room's my wife and mine
When the girls saw the'shadow,
were you and your wife in this room?
My wife and I were in the kitchen
Aha!
D, did you findithe(intruder?!
No, I didn't say aha, I said ouch...
I stepped.on this hair pin
that was onthe floor...
Did you say hair pin...?
How many times've I told you
not to get In my way
Let me continue. Was your son that
got hurt.also with you in the kitchen?
No...we all thought he was
taking a bath though...
And 'could you tell me what
you three were doing in the kitchen?
Shiro was giving us a scolding.
He said we were being very rude to
Haruna, bombarding her with
so many questions after she was kind
enough to come all the way to visit us.
What kind of questions? wg
Well, uh, the truth is, Shugo. the head of
this household and I were bell friends...
And they wanted to know
we talked about and such
That's right...
the three of them. Minoru included were
practically interrogating
her like;some kind of criminal!
Oh, but it didn't bother me at all!
I talked about how Shugo's interest in
stamps-got me to collect them too
and I got to reminisce
about a lot of good things,
why l.even asked if I could come back,
so that shows you
that I wasn't'bothered in the least
Speaking of stamps,
Minoru did mention something about
hand carved stamps worth 200 million...
Where is he now?
. Perhaps those stamps have something
to do with what happened tonight...
I think Minoru's in his room next door...
Eh'?
They disappeared?
Yes, that's right!
Grandfather had a great collection
but those hand carved stamps were
by far.the most impressive...
We counted on the money
it'd bring when we would sell it
so we started buy all sorts of things...
You said "we"?
Yes;\mom and dad agreed on it...
Hey, listen...
Eh...7?
What isit'?
Is your room next:door?
Yes it is, why? 7
OK then
And whose room is on the other side?
That's grandpa and grandma's room...
Then maybe...
Hey, kid?
I knew it...
this is the room Minoru got attacked in!
Which means...
so the roomslay;out;is;likeithis;-eh.:.
I think I know how it worked«now,
ve figured out the, trick O"
Now;to figure out
whose shadow Ran saw
and why the music box Shugo gave
Haruna is off tune...
I wrote down the notes to the song
Iistening to another music box
but I~donst really know what is what...
That's the music
for that song. "Haru yo Koi"!
How did you get it?
Uh, I, it just happened to be part of my
homework for music class...
Let me see that! I'll rewrite it so it's right!
Hey, .give it-back!
Let's see...
Oh brother...
Ran...
Huh?
What is.it?
Oh; nothing, nothing at all...
Here,
I think that's right!
She's good as I suspected...
Hey, Ran
What are these three # (sharps) for?
that stands for A major!
A major...?
Why that's it!
If anything comes up,
feel free to call us anytime
Thanks...
Well the mystery remains, we still don't
know whether it was a thief or a ghost...
Yes...
excuse me,
Has anyone seen Conan?
Boy, this is so simple...
I've got it now...
I've figured everything out...
I know the identity of
he ghost in the house...
& and who sent the mysterious
message on the pocket bell
and I know what that
off tune music box means
and Shugo...
I knowswhere you hid those
precious stamps of yours!
Now allil've got to do is,
put.old Kogoro to sleep as usual and...?
Ouch, ouch, ouch!
Listen you!
How many times: ve told you
not to go wandering off!
Ouch...
Come on, we're going home!
Going home?
Aw, but I just found something interesting...
There, look at that!
Huh?
See what what're you talking about?
Move a little to the right!
To the right?
Ugh?!
Ho boy...
Dad?
I see...so that's how it worked...
Ran,
Tell everyone to come here!
Yes...sir!
Wait, before you-do
get me some black paper,a pair of
scissors, and some cellophane tape...
OK, where is he?!
You found the thief didn't you?
Thief?!
There wasn't a thief in the first place...
You're not going to tell us
it- was father's ghost, are you?
Of course not, that also never existed...
All the strange things that happened
tonight, were orchestrated by one of you!
Eh?!
What?!
But then ghostly things have
happened before tonight too...
Before tonight...?
Yes, I'm talking about the time Haruna
got the music box from Shugo...
Yes, she told us that story many times!
It's about the time
gramps gave her the music box without
telling us about it, 2 Christmases ago...
Uh, no...
he gave me the music box
LAST Christmas.
Th, that's impossible! Dad died
Iast year on December 6th!
Th, that can't be...?!
And on top of that, father had been
hospitalized since that Spring
and was in
no condition to move around...
Hey now,
what's going on around here?
It's very simple...
omeone preen e 0; e ugo an e
the package containing the music box at
Haruna's feet while she!waited for him in
front of the Hachiko statue, that's all...
Isn't that right. #? Shiro
Sh, Shiro did it?
Is that true?!
Hey, Shiro!
He asked me to...
grandpa asked me to...
He said, Even after I'm hospitalized,
I want you to look after this girl...
she reminds me of your
grandmother and she's very lonely..."
Do you mean. you've been sending me
messages since last Spring...
Yes...
I've been communicating with you
on my grandfather's behalf...
Actually, I intended to tell you the truth
when I saw you that Christmas, but...
when I saw you standing there,
with that red muffler around your neck,
that was how I was to recognize you,
you looked so excited and happy.
That's why I just couldn't
bring myself to do it.
But, how did you know it was me?
I knew from the start that it was you
who gave Haruna the music box...
I knew it the moment you came
to meet us at thelfront door...
I don't believe you...
When you saw Haruna, you put your hand
on her shoulder and said this didn't you...
After all, she was such
a comfort to our grandfather...
Atithat point,
we still hadn't introduced ourselves
and Ran, who's about the
same age asyHaruna, was also present...
And yet, you knew
exactly which one she was,
although no one had
actually met her yet...
hat's when it suddenly hit me...
maybe it was YOU
who gave her the music box.
If that's true, then was it you...
did you drop that koto on me because
you got mad that
I was giving her the third degree
No, that wasn't me!
Ran, turn the lights off!
Hurry!!
Yes sir!
Co, Conan?!
Hey? Conan, where are you...?
Ran, I'm over here! la
Eh? How'd you get over there?
I've always been here!)
Liar...l just saw
your shadow on the screen door...
Take a look at the glass out in the hall
The glass out in the hall?
What am I supposed to see?
Why, this it...
There's a piece of
4black paper taped to the glass!
It's shaped like Conan...
I put it there a little while ago
because Uncle Kogoro told me to!
Then are you saying that
the old man Ran saw was...
That's right, Ran saw a shadow picture...
An old man's figure, cut out of black
paper is taped to the glass in the hall.
If a car approaches the back street,
the lights from the headlight will
shine through the half open back door
and the shadow of the paper cut old man
will be reflected
onto the screen door, that's the trick...
Now that you mention it,
when I saw the old mans shadow.
I did hear a shwooshing sound...
That was probably the sound of)
a car "passing on the rainiwet road.
>» CT &
so by using that trick,
you don't have to actually be present
when the old man
makes his appearance...
Shiro...even you could've
Like I told you before, I was right here...
same as when you got attacked .
You could have done that too.
While being in this room...
Eh?!
It's a simple booby trap.
All you need is some
fishingvine and
some hair pins to make it...
A booby trap?
The person who caused this commotion,
hung the koto from the ceiling in your
grandfather's room and then let it fall,
it was just coincidence
that you got hit by it...
Minoru, you snuck in there
to, check out the koto...
that's right, that's how you got hit...
You. you don't know
what you're talking about,
why would I want to search the koto...
Because during dinner,
Haruna mentioned thatthe
music box played "Haruo Kol
And since it was
your grandmother's favorite.song
and she always played it on the koto,
you thought the stamps just might
be hidden inside the koto...
B. but even if the koto
dropped down from the ceiling,
I don't see how it could have
knocked him unconscious,
there wasn't enough momentum.
Besides,
if he was going to look inside the koto,
wouldn't he have turned the lights on?
When we got there,
the room was dark, wasn't it?
Minoru didn't NOT turn the lights on,
he COULDN'T...
the device the culprit rigged raised the
Iight up, close to the ceiling & in the dark,
Minoru didn't know
where the light cord was
Left with no other choice,
Minoru got down on the floor &
felt around the area the koto usually is,
when he found it,
he intended to take it to his room...
then he heard the sound of the string
rubbing against the fishing line
& he looked up,
and of all the bad luck,
that's when it fell on his head...
Minoru...
OK, so you're right, you've got me!
But how was it rigged
to drop the koto, anyway?
Hah...itys very simple
First, you get 1 very long fishing line
wrap the light cord
around the middle of the fishing line,
then pass both ends of the line
under the string
the koto is then probably
temporarily placed on the chest.
Next, both ends of the line is passed
through the transom
& went through Shiro's room,
then Minoru's & then Mr & Mrs. Ogata's
until finally reaching the room
Ran & Haruna were staying in...
Then, so the line wouldn't sag,
both ends were tied
then set in place
between the doors with a hair pin.
Now for the finishing touch, all the culprit
had to do was take the koto off the chest,
Ietting it hand & walla,
your booby trap is complete.
After that.
All you had to do was open the door
and the hair pin would be released
& that would lead to the koto falling...
Now wait just one minute,
you're not saying that...
That's right...
the person responsible for
tonight's ghostly apparition is
the person who opened that door...
Kazuko...
it was you, wasn't it?
MM. mother?
But why?
It's probably because she didn't want
Haruna to go looking for those stamps...
I'm pretty sure she rigged;the:booby trap
while we were eating...
when she left to goprepare.our. bedding...
Then when she heard Ran & Haruna scream,
she came running
& opened the door nonchalantly,
causing the koto to fall
And then, while everyone was
rushing to Shugo's room,
she removed the cut out from the window
& sent a message to Haruna's pocket bell
from her cellular,trying to scare her...
she was trying to frighten Haruna
away from this house...
B but what did she do with
all that fishing line after that?
Mom was right behind us
when we got to grandfather's room...
She didn't have time
to take the paper off the window
& remove all the fishing line
while using the telephone
She had a very handy helper!
It's right behind Ran...
A fan. «7?
I'm pretty'sure
she cut the tied end of the line
& pulled one end into this room
then used tape to tape it...
To thewback of this fan syblade!
Yes, I see...
All she had to do was turn the switch on
& it would automatically reel the line in...
I still can't believe it though...
how could you think of such a thing
in the short time you had during dinner...
It's not impossible...
after all this trick with the fishing line,
is something I picked up from
the pranks the boys used to:pull
when they were children!!!
What about the cut out of the old man...
Oh that; a guest who stayed with us once
thought some leaves stuck to the window
was someone's shadow,
I remembered that...
Haruna scared me
she mentioned she collected stamps
& she said she wanted to visit us again
Uh...were you the one who sent me
\ the messages before saying. "Thief"...
Yes, that was me...I'm sorry...
Mother, that was terrible...
how could you break grandmother's koto
over a thing like that?
Oh. . .thatikoto isn't worth anything...
How can you say that...
The truth is, I pawned the real koto
& got a cheap replacement...
My new system kitchen, your new-car,
Minoru's computer...
we were so far in debt
Then I guess we'll just have to sell
the music box grandfather gave me...
Oh but I had it looked at & I was told
it was just an ordinary souvenir item...
That's strange...
grandfather told me that in
appreciation of my posing to be him,
he was giving me his music box
those who knew what they were looking at
would realize it was worth 200 million...
200 million? That music box?
Dad bought that:as:a souvenir
when he went to a hot spring...
Grandpa pulled a fast one on you...
The music box itself isn't worth anything.
It's the missing notes...
In Japan, we use
the DoReMi musical scale
and also the native notation, I Ro Ha.
The missing notes are [La], [Do] & [La]
& if we use the I Ro Ha scale,
it would be [I], [Ha] & [1]...
Wha?!
ou don't mean...?
I don't believe it. 7?!
It can't be... 7?!
I don't believe it...?!
It's impossible!
Ive got it!!
This isjit!!
Oh thank goodness!!
Hip~hip ghurray!
What's going on?
Oh thank you so much!
Now I can buy that koto back!
We owe it all to you!
Who are you anyway?!
Well, uh, the truth is.
My name is Kogoro Mourn...
THE Kogoro Mourn?
The famous private detective?
That's me!
Why didn't you tells .that-earlier!?
If we'd known that,
we'd have asked you to: look for stamps!
And Minoru wouldn't have gotten hurt!
Yes well...
Haha... what a selfish bunch...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS: BY
($116110 Anyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihihko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Kat-u8 Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS bY
MaSatomo Strdo
TORY EDITO!
JunmiThi lioka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kodchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
M. so tomo Sudo
Hirotoshr Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Tikashi Hyodo
ART DIR («TOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu HOrikoshr
Takahisa Owaca
RECORDIN , DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
( HIEF DIRECTOR.
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
IMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecastine (corporation
9 Gt%ho Aoyamn ) Bog %kukan
TV / TMS
All-RifJhts Reserved
Thank you for everything!
No, we should thank you...
Are you sure youthave no regrets, though?
Shugo might have intended to
give you alone, those stamps...
I don't mind. Because I got to
keep something .worth even more .
It's grandfather's pocket bell!
Haruna gave it to me
and she asked if I'd continue
to give her moral support...
Tihank you from the bottom of my heart!!
You know, I think Spring's here!
Spring? It's almost Summer...
Never mind, for Shiro, it's Spring.
What's that supposed to mean?
Spring, come to me... .hurry to me...
Don't hold your breath...
Look out!!
A bump?
It wasn't such a big bump,
I don't understand why
you're making such a big deal about it
But Sonoko warned me
& I know "that guy would too...