Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles in
each and every case to be solved
A parent is a parent but not the child.
Ran"s challenge outdoes Kogoro.
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult,
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
UNSEEN WEAPON
RAN'S FIRST CASE
It's so hot!
He Akasaka Princess Hotels
a nice hotel but this hill's a killer
You're so right!
I'd like to change right away
and jump right into the pool, don't.you?
Listen Ran...
I'm going to find me a gorgeous guy
so don't you get in my way, understand?
Yes, yea, I understand completely...
By the way, have you heard
anything from Shinichi?
No not since he left
Is he working on another case?
I just don't understand how one can get
so worked about a case...
Look at that car
This doesn't look good!
Look out!!
I'm so sorry! Are you two all right?!
We're fine
Just barely...
AKASAKA PRINCESS HO EL
So Ms Yoshino,
you're an instructor
at a flower design school...
Yes, I commute to Shizuoka,
5 days a week.
Did you say Shizuoka?
That's very far, isn't it
Chie Yoshino (31)
Flower Designer
No, in fact,
Chie Yoshino (31)
Flower Designer
I was on my way to school just now
when I remembered today was a holiday...
Chie Yoshino (31)
Flower Designer
FF ==
I was on my way to school just now
when I remembered today was a holiday...
So I called my husband,
oh, he works for an insurance company
and we made plans
to meet here at this hotel...
we were going to have lunch
Oh, I see...
I'm really very sorry about
what happened.
I suddenly got dizzy and
Iost consciousness for a second.
I've been getting dizzy spells
and splitting headaches a lot lately...
Maybe you're sick?
No, the doctor couldn't
find anything wrong...
It's probably the weather...
the temperature's been fluctuating
so radically lately, hasn't it?
And I guess the
fatigue's been building up
since I have to drive to
and from Shizuoka every day.
The proof is, when there's no school
or when it's cool, even if it's a weekday,
I feel fine, nothing happens
Is that so...
Chie!
Oh! Hi there!
This is my husband, Akio Yoshino
Oh hello
This is Ran Mouri and Sonoko Suzuki...
I had another dizzy spell
and nearly ran them down
Again...?
Were you hurt in any way?
No we're fine! But it was a close call
Your wife was nice enough
to treat us to lunch...
I St...
Please accept my apologies
And how do you feel?
I'm OK...
I felt fine after I rested a while.
Good. I'm so relieved
He seems so nice
Excuse me, I think we'll be going now
That's right,
you were going to the pool, weren't you
All right then
Where do you two live?
In Beika
Why, that's near us. We live in Haido...
We live very close to the park,
please drop by sometime!
Thank you!
A bump?
Eh?!
Oops, What is this!
Ran, be careful! There's a bump here!
OK...
Well?
Don't you think it's strange?
What is?
I just told you he knew she had
just had a dizzy spell,
so why didn t he warn her
about-the bump?
She couldn't gotten hurt badly
if she had tripped and fell!
If she had tripped and fell!
I don't see why you're
making such a big deal out of it
But Sonoko warned me about it...
and I know that guy would too...
What?! That guy...?!
Who're you talking-aboltit?
Oh, nothing. /
Anyway!
I'm very curious about that couple...
I think I'll go over to visit
Chie and check things out
And do what?
I want to find out what's causing her to
have those headaches and dizzy spells!
What?
You're no doctor, don't poke your nose
where It doesn't belong
I'm not.stupid, I can figure it out!
If you're going to insist, go ahead and try
I most certainly will!
what's with her, live never heard her say
anything like this...
But she does that a point,
something's fishy
Hey, can-I*go with you...
Do you wantito-come with.me.,
Then I'll ask Sonoko to come
along and we:-ll7all go together!
Humph, what do I care
I guess I'll have my rice now
Get it yourself!!
What?!
What a grouch...
YOSHINO'S HOUSE
Wow, this place is super nice!!
The garden's so well cared for.
Your home is so beautiful
Thank you!
We just-finished building
this place a month and a half ago
I had a feeling it was new
A new house, how wonderful!!
But carrying a loan of
40 million yen is pretty rough
That's why we both have to work,
otherwise we'd never make ends meet...
Here you are
Thank you
I apologize for barging in on you
when it's your day off
It's quite all right!
Unfortunately, my husband
went out this morning, so I'm alone today
Your husband seems so nice!
Yes, I suppose he is...
he loves cars and he's been
complaining lately
that he hasn't been able to
go out for drives like he used to
I guess that's why he goesOout walking
every morning, to take his mind of it.
And while he's out,
I fix breakfast, that's our daily routine
Umm...
this may be a strange thing to ask
why do you go
all the way to Shizuoka to work?
To help pay for the loan...
I used to teach at
a design school here in the city
but my husband told
me about this school in Shizuoka...
the salary was better there
Oh I see...
But still, it's pretty hard on you, isn't it?
Driving there every day
That's right!
If you took the train, you'd at least
be able to get some sleep...
Actually, I enjoy driving.
The entrance to the highway is near here
it's much more convenient when you have
a lot of supplies and large-equipment
isn't it?
I guess...
By the way, have you kids-ever
thought about insurance...
oh dear!
I forgot, you're still in school
Eh? What was that?
I'm terribly sorry
my husband works for an
insurance company and
I've gotten into the habit of
suggesting people to get insurance
As a wife, you're
helping your husband, right?
Yes, well...
I felt bad about just
suggesting it to others
so I just recently adjusted
my policy to 100 million
A hundred million?!
My husband asked me to...
the monthly payments are very high
but it's the kind of policy where
after the fixed period has passed,
even if you cancel the policy,
you still get the premium back
I figured it'd make
his job performance look good
Uhm you're really
crazy about him. aren't you?
Eh. Oh, do you think so
100 million yen...
he wouldn't. .but then...
Excuse me, when did you start having
those headaches and dizzy spells?
Let's see, about a month ago I guess...
A month ago...s
half a month after the house was built...
Maybe that's what they call
sick house syndrome
Eh.»
Sick house syndrome...
Did you say "Shiku haku 7?
I said sick house syndrome!
SYNDROME
It's when people get sick
from the gas given off
HOUSE SYNDROME [M15 C5 (
It's when people get sick
from the gas given off
the«dumber and paint used
when building a house!
Sonoko, I'm sure you've heard of
orma ey e
formaldehyde
FORMALDEHYDE
Don't make fun of me!
Of course I know about those things!
I'm not sure...but don't think that's it
Why not?
The contractor who built this house is
a friend of my husband's...
My husband would have told them
not to use anything that was dangerous
But I still think
you should have it checked out!
The contractor could have deceived you...
Sonoko!
Do you know of any companies that
specialize in checking for
contaminated building supplies?
Well, sure...
my father would probably know,
we could ask him...
All right then, let's ask him right away!
Chie, I think you should have it
checked to be on the safe side!
Well, OK...
Ran, you're acting strange today.
Why did you insist on
getting her house checked?
I had my reasons...
Ran thinks Chie's husband,
Akio, is trying to kill
her to collect the insurance money
Ran, is that true?!
Yes.
What's going on?!
First, Akio gets the contractor to build
the house using dangerous materials
so that Chie's health starts getting bad...
And on the other hand,
he suggests she take the job in Shizuoka
Eh? But why?
Chie does as he suggests
and drives to and from work
on the highway every day
if she should have
a dizzy spell while driving...
No...l don't believe it!
Ran, your imagination's working overtime.
After all, wouldn't
the house make Akio sick too?
He does live there too you know!
But those materials could've been used
only for her room and the kitchen
Of course, we have no proof.
But as long as the possibility exists,
I thought it was best to check it out
At this point,
we still don't know if
Ran"s suspicions are correct, but
something, something wasn't right
I.couldn't put my finger on it...
This Is the instrument that
measures the amount of formaldehyde
According to room,
there's a possibility that different
materials were used in each room
so I think it's best if we checked
every room to be accurate
Fine, you may start anytime
All right then let's begin
When Chie told me about this,
I was shaken up
but then there is a possibility the
contractor did use those kind of materials
so I figured it might be
better to have it checked
Yes, of course, we agree
Well, I'm going for a walk...
I'll pick up some cake on the way back
That would be nice
See you later...
He really loves to take walks!
I'm going to take a walk too!
Hey Conan, don't stay out too long!
Okay
That customer's going to buy it, isn't he?
Yes! He used to come
in all the time on his days off
but I think he's made up his mind now!
Eh?!
25 million yen!!
Oh come on, is he serious?!
We have the results!
Every room shows a level much lower
than 0.08 ppm which is the level
the Ministry of Health and Welfare
has declared safe 4 years ago
Are you sure about that?
And what does that mean?
It means this house is absolutely safe!!
What a relief...
I guess it's not sick house syndrome
that's making me sick
You're just tired
Let's try to get to bed earlier
T Co.
I don't understand.
Is there something else going on here?!
I told you so!
That's what happens when
amateurs try to do a professional s job!
I wonder, could it just
have been my imagination...
I hope you didn't tell them you were
the famous Kogoro Mouri's daughter
Of course not
That's good,
I hope this taught you not to go sticking
your nose into other people's business
Well, answer me!
I understand
I guess I just can't compete
with that guy...
Phew...
Conan
Ran, I don't think you were wrong
I overheard the salesmen
at the place they sell sports cars,
Akio Is going to buy
a car that costs 25 million yen!
25 million yen?!
Where's he getting the money from...
the insurance on Chie?!
So he trying to kill Chie!
Yeah...
even after he pays off the loan on
th Shouse, he'll still havel60 million left
But there-was no sign
the air in the house was contaminated...
Maybe he was poisoning her food...!
But I think she does all the cooking
That's right...
What do you think?
How's he doing it...?
While I'm sitting here,
danger could be creeping up on Chie...
Oh! Shinichi, what am I going to do!!!
Something's bugging me.
And it's been bugging me ever
since Ran told me about it...
What is it?
Wait a minute, I'm sure Chie said...
That's it! I've figured it out!!
You want to know what
Chie told me the first time?
Yeah!
What did she say about her dizzy spells?
I'm pretty sure...
It's probably the weather.
The temperatures been
fluctuating so radically lately, hasn't it?
And I guess the
fatigue's been building up
since I have to drive to and from
Shizuoka every day.
The proof is, when there's no school
on Saturday or when it's cool,
even if it's a weekday,
I feel fine, nothing happens.
That's what she said...
See!
If it was something in the house
then wouldn't the symptoms
be worse on her days off
when she's at home longer
instead of when sheys out?
You know. .you're right
I think the thing that's giving her
headaches and dizzy spells
isn't in the house
It's some place else?
Oh, maybe at the
design school in Shizuoka?
Some place between
her house and the school...
You don't think!
NEXT DAY
I'm going for my walk now
OK, is ham and eggs for breakfast
okay with you?
Sounds good!
I'll be hungry when I come home
so make a lot!
41% UN
ATT UM
ATTN [UV
Hey, what the...?!
What are you kids doing here?
Mr. Yoshino, what did you
just put in your pocket?
Eh? Oh, this,
it's an air conditioner disinfectant,
I wanted to protect Chie
from cold germs and other bacteria
OK then; when the police get here,
you'll show that to them, won't you
Eh?!
I just called them.
I have a friend on the force
P, police...!
I'm sure Chie would never have dreamed
her husband, the man she most
trusted, was spraying
an unseen weapon into her car's
air conditioner every morning.
That's why Chie never got sick
when she didn't drive to work
or when it was cool enough where
she didn't have to use the air conditioner.
Ch, Chie...
AKIO...
Later. the police investigation showed
that the can of spray contained a diluted
agricultural chemical
composed of organic chlorine
Akio Yoshino had
embezzled several million
from his company
and was trying to cover the deficit
but he also wanted a new sports car
and that's why he thought up this plan,
that's what his confession stated
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS:BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACK AROUND MUSIC
Kats: 8 Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi loka
, Ye »
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Misatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshfkobayash:
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
O oho Aoyama I Fog 'kukan
Il Rights Reserved
Eh? You mean Chie sold the house?
Yes and along with
some friends and flower shops,
she opened her own
flower design company!
Look
Ts DA q
Wow!
Fis Ahk FO
She looks good!
Chie Taniguchi...she got a divorce
and went back to her maiden name
Boy, women get over things so quickly...
And Ran sure was sharp, getting
suspicious about Akio Yoshino
over a little thing like
a bump on the ground...
I'm so glad things worked out.
If you hadn't noticed anything and done
all you did, Chie might be dead now!
Hold on now!
Maybe you're getting to be like
you know who". huh?
Oh don't be silly...
But I guess you could say I wanted to
understand him a little more,
maybe get to feel closer to him...
Yes, I understand
so, do you understand
Shinichi a little more now?
No way!
Who can understand that mystery fanatic!
Oh of all the!
But never mind that, let's go eat
some yummy cakes!
Well, I guess it's for the best
Eh?!
Was he trying toxdamage his own car?
Hey, doesn't the president have
a mobile telephone with him?
Ran?!