Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and sizes
In each and every case to be solved
Owning a super car is everyone's dream
and emotions run as high as the price.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
TRAP OF THE SUPER CAR
PART 1
mum"..-uuunnnulununalnnmaunnun h
Wow, how beautiful!!
You can see the ocean!
You sure can!
Hey...
wheres Mr..Mourn?
That's strange,
he was walking with us just awhile ago...
Why do you guys get to rest,
that's not fair
Good grief,
winning first prize in the drawing
was real lucky but why's the hotel
In such an inconvenient place
and there's no buses either...
Hurry up, Dad!
What an inconvenient hotel...
I knew it was too good to be true
The eat all you can shabu-shabu
2nd prize would've been better, huh
You can say that again...
Aw come on,
don't be a spoil sport!
Well I can't help it...
when"re we going to
reach the hotel anyway?
We're almost there, don't give up!
That place we can see from here,
I wonder if that's the Kirigamine Hotel...
Pleasedfill in the registration card...
Mouri...?!
Huh?!
yes the Mouri party...
you'll be room #201
You know...
this is a pretty nice hotel
but why don't you provide your guests
with pick-up service from the
nearest train station or something
Stop it dad
3 ™ FRAN
sg Uw Wii JUST PR
I'm terribly sorry...
HisashiSuguru
BE 5 ZX FE (28)
BR vTTIVOOUNE
Iet me show you to your room now...
- ov es
1Isas ll uguru
0% UL
BR tvTIVIOO/ NR
Thank you.
Let's go Conan...
where'd he go?
Conan? Where are you?
Neat, look atithat...
This is great!!
Conan, what are you doing here?
Good grief, you re always wandering off
Look at that, isn't that neat!
Look at all those old sports cars!
They are impressive
This 1s a Jaguar XK120!
Jv 7-xki120
The long nose and the beautifully curved
fenderdi its characteristic features and
It looks like a real jaguar, doesn't it
Even today, many Jaguar collectors
dream of owning this car
And this...
This is a
Mercedes Benz 300SL, Gull wing
Gull wing means the wings of a seagull
when you open the door,
it looks like a seagull with it's
wings spread out, doesn't it?
You re right
Isn't that a Cadillac over there?
Yes, a Cadillac El Dorado.
It's a 1953 convertible! 7
it's said to be the most powerful
and ultimate American model.
Production was limited
to only about 500 cars
and I heard they virtually disappeared
\\from the show rooms in no time
They say collectors still talk about
the El Dorado legacy!
You know a lot of about
these cars don't you, kid...
This is the historic car show room
we ve just put up
I see...
The owner of this hotel is
quite a car enthusiast
You could say he rebuilt this hotel
just for this show room...
What's that?
There's an open space back there
Yes,
that space is reserved for the
owner s persona errart lino
What?
When you say Ferrari Dino,
you don't mean the 206 GT do you?
I certainly do
iV Wow
Conan, what kind of car is it?
They only made 152 of them and
it's close to impossible
to get your hands on one now.
Dino is the nickname of Alfredino Ferrari,
the only son of Enzo Ferrari,
Ferrari's creator
the only son.of Enzo Ferrari,
He died when he was 24 years old
but the engine he helped
design was built into the car
That's why Enzo Ferrari named the
model after his beloved son
So that's the story behind it
Katsuro!
Why isn't the head of the front desk at
the front desk, what are you doing here?!
I'm sorry...
By the way, guests
This show room will be open
for viewing starting tomorrow,
Zenkichi Kuroiwa
+ ilk RIL AEC
This show room will be open
for viewing starting tomorrow,
Zenkichi Kuroiwa
HD TABS
$2? §=5(45)
BE RFIVEERA
until then, it is off limits to
unauthorized personnel...
Zenkichi Kuroiwa
DD CA BS
sx £3 - = 5 (45)
Bri/RFIVZEA
I've seen that guest somewhere before...
I'm glad you arrived safely, sir.
Uh huh...
This car's worth more than my life
Daigo Teraizumi
but driving it from Tokyo sure wore me out
1 >)Lttd
Sir, the cars are already in their places.
Why don't you take yours there now...
Hold it, just wait one minute,
don't rush me...
I want to spend some time
with my friend"!
Once it's on display,
I won't be able to take it for a spin
whenever I feel like it anymore
Sir,
Iook at this...
Huh?
A detective...
What is this, there's only 1 bed in here!
Don't complain.
We should just be thankful we
got first prize in the drawing
Do they expect all 3 of us
to sleep on 1 bed?
Let's tell them to give us a bigger room!
Never mind, we'll use this sofa
Hahaha. he's such a baby
Don't worry!
I'll take care of it!!
The opening ceremony's at
3 tomorrow afternoon
Tonight's going to be our last chance.
That's right,
don't worry
we're going ahead as scheduled...
understand?
Conan, get In here!
Let me go Ran!
Stop being so stubborn, Dad!
The hotel's not so busy,
what's the big deal
I'm going to make them
give us a bigger room!
But won't they charge us if we do that?
And if you make too big a fuss,
they might throw us out!
Mr. Moun?...
A threatening letter?
Letesisee here...
Don't open the show room.
Or you'll be sorry
That letter arrived at the hotel
a few days ago...
my staff and I were just discussing
what to do about it...
For a threateninglletter,
it doesn't sound so threatening
maybe it's just someone's idea of a joke?
I hope you re right.
But just to be on the safe side,
would you mind guarding it
until tomorrow's opening?
We'd like the infamous private detective
Kogoro Mourn to help us In this matter
Did you contact the police?
If you accept this assignment,
As a special favor, the hotel will let you
stay in this suite, which is our very best
This suite? Really...?!
All right!! lil. do it
Thank you very much
I can rest at ease now
You can all get a good night's sleep,
I'll take care of everything.
By the way, Ran
would you like to go for
an after dinner drive with me?
You mean in the Dino?
Wow...
hey sir can I go too?
Of course you can
Can I go too,
Dad?
Geez this is delicious'
this fillet is the best I've ever tasted...
boy it's good...
How embarrassing...
Boy that was good!
Bring.me another serving!
Oh no!!
Did it get on you?
Don't worry,
it's not too bad
Dad, you've had too much too drink!
Sir!
There's trouble in the show room!
What?!
Let me go,
don't try to stop me!
Calm down Mr. Otake
Don't do it!
Get out of my way!
Let go of me!
Let me do as I please!
Don't be a fool
Shut up!
I'm going to wreck this car!
Mr. Otake, what's the matter with you!
You love this car more than anything!
What?!
Eh?!
He's trying to wreck his own car?
Mr. Otake, how could you...
How would you know how I feel!
What is this all about!
L...I'm going to destroy this
darn show room!!
This car
this 1953 El Dorado convertible
was my dream...
I worked night and day
Ichirou Otake
Ta - EBB (5
ETHEL DD TAIWAN
IRTITVE IRE S
and finally saved enough to buy it
Ichirou Otake
XY - BR (55)
RITICERES EN
and finally saved enough to buy it
Then why are you trying to destroy
something so precious?
I'd rather destroy it with my own hands
than let someone else have it...
that's why
Let someone else have it?!
What do you mean?
Humph
ask Teraizumi over there what I mean,
then you ll know
What is this about, Mr. Teraizumi?
It's all a gross misunderstanding...
Mr. Otake,
you should be thanking me
rather than hating me%*
Thank YOU?
Not 1 single person is looking forward
to this show room opening up.
Except you, of course.
He's right
I understand perfectly how Mr. Otake
feels about wanting to destroy his own car
It is true, no one is looking forward to
seeing this show room open up
Excuse me, who are you two?
My name is Shinsuke Sagara...
Shinsuke Sagara
LL 29 L+LeD UD Cjiad LIN
NBII Le &
Iike Mr. Otake, I was also forced
to let this Mercedes Benz go...
Shinsuke Sagara
Li TO
HE FF, (37)
ZZ L225 DO cL adv Rn
RHEIRWEIE LIB
Iike Mr. Otake, I was also forced
to let this Mercedes Benz go...
I'm Joji Kameoka...
the former owner of that Jaguar
Joji Kameoka
Or LEO UL
Sh EDT DLL + LVR
FEST ER
That Teraizumi over there, swindled the
3 of us and took our cars away!
That's just nonsense.
You brought that bad luck
upon yourselves
What do you mean, he swindled you?
Although it wasn't big,
we all ran our own businesses.
I ran a travel agency
I was a realtor
I ran a automotive repair shop...
but with the economy so bad,
we were having a difficult time
And that's when that Teraizumi
approached us and said that
if we put our cars down as collateral,
he'd lend us money
at a low interest rate...
Of course, we accepted the offer
But it was a trap...
We didn't find out until later,
but that fellow was working behind our
backs,and sabotaging our businesses
we couldn't meet the dead line to repay
our loans and so he got our cars...
Teraizumi intended to
cheat us from the very start,
that's why he offered to lend us money!
How dare you say things
Iike that about me...
do you have proof
I sabotaged your'business?
If you've got the energy to tell
idiotic stories, why don't you go out
and do something about getting
the money to pay me back!
Why you thief!!
Humph...
you don't scare me...
aha,
so you're the ones who
send me that threatening letter
Threatening letter?
What are you talking about?
Don't play dumb,
this show room WILL open,
no matter what you do!
Huh?!
Those shoes
Donit.worry'slsli'take care of it!!
The opening ceremony's at
3 tomorrow afternoon
Tonight's going to be our last chance.
That's right,
don't worry
we re going ahead as scheduled
Understand?
Excuse me... Mr. Sagara,
what room are you in?
I'm in 202...
Hmmm
Why do you want to know?
No, uh .
That car's really something else
and I just thought I'd drop by
and ask you all about it...
Well, tonight's not a good time...
I have plans
What kind of plans?
I don't think that's any of your business
Yeah...you're right...
Room service?
I didn't ordered anything
I think you've made a mistake
£L=NO,
you're the owner's guest and this is
compliments of the hotel
Please feel free to call me if there's
anything else you need...
Well, if you say so!
Maybe I'll have some wine then...
something from the Bourgogne region
No Dad,
Hahaha.
I'm very sorry about ruining
your pants earlier
No problem...it was nothing.
I changed right away...
That's the Dino's engine...
Now that you mention it, I hear a
car engine too, but it's very softO.
There's no doubt about it
it'sithe Dino
Are you sure?!
Sir, where are you going at this hour?
Those guys put me in a bad mood...
I'm going for a drive
Mr. Teraizumi
the fog ls thick tonight,
I don't think you should go
It's safer than spending the night in
the same hotel with those guys!!
Remember, drive carefully
I will
Sir, Mr. Teraizumi hasn't returned yet
Oh for goodness sakes,
and it's already 9:00,
where could he be...
He's still not back?
He's such a hopeless case
But then the opening ceremony's
not until 3,
there's still plenty of time
You've got to be kidding
we've got to get the Dino set up
and the guest will start
arriving at about noon
I think it's odd though,
he hasn't called at all...
Did I hear Teraizuml's not back yet?
Mr. Kameoka, Mr. Otake
If he s been involved in an accident
and can't get back,
then I guess the opening ceremony's off
God's punished him, I know it!
Doesn't Mr. Teraizumi have a
cellular phone or something?
Oh, that's right, I forgot all about that
Let me have that,
I'll give him a piece of my mind and
Iet him know how worried we were
Hello, is this Mr. Teraizumi?
It's me, Mourn...
Where are you?
wh. . where am [I...7?
It, it's pitch black...
Pitch black?!
Hello, Mr. Teraizumi,
Mr. Teraizumi!
What's the matter?
It sounded like he was hurt
he said, Where am I, it's pitch black
and then the line went dead.
Pitch black?
But it's all white outside with fog
Mr. Mouri, what did he mean pitch black...
Hmmm...
Sir, it's 10:00.
We've got to start preparing for
today's ceremony...
Yes, you're right.
Katsuro, I'm counting on you...
Yes sir...
Today's ceremony is cancelled, cancelled!
God s punished him for sure
Good grief,
It's just like the threatening letter said
Eeek!
Ran?!
Ran!
Where are you!!
Conan! Over here!!!
Ran!
Ran what happened, are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine
What happened, Ran?!
I'm sorry
I was taking my morning walk
when I heard this voice in the fog
and it just scared me...
Aren't you Noda, the security guard?
What are you doing here?
Well.
Kazuo Noda
JIT" <<
FE - 8 Go
I saw this young lady walking in the fog
and she was heading for the cliff
Kazuo Noda
FH - kt (60)
Hn-rw
I saw this young lady walking in the fog
and she was heading for the cliff
Kazuo Noda
so I thought I better warn her
and then all of a sudden,
she starts screaming...
I'm sorry...
Good grief, you scared everybody!
It's a car...
Maybe Mr. Teraizumi's
finally come back...
No, that doesn't sound like him.
That's Mr. Sagara's car...
Eh?!
What's going on?
Why re you all out here?
You were right,
you can tell whose car it is just by
hearing the engine, that's fantastic
Hahaha,
I know most of our regular guests.
Well, I've got to get back to work...
Uh, Mr. Sagara,
where were you last night?
Uh... well...
I went for a little drive around here
Did you see Mr. Teraizumi's car?
Now step back,
I'm going to go park my car...
it's already too late to get
the Dino on display
Uh huh
Oh well, since werdon't know
where Mr. Teraizumi is,
there's nothing we can do
Somebody, come quick!
STerTeraizumi's...
Something's wrong!!
He's in his car!!
What?!
Mr. Teraizumi!
Mr. Teraizumi!!
Get a doctor,
call an ambulance!
It's too late
he's already dead...
the cause of death
IS carbon monoxide poison.
The engine is running and the car is
filled with exhaust fumes...
I guess the exhaust fumes
- flowed backwards into the car...
So that means this is an
accidental death
Huh?!
The window's slightly open...
What does this mean...
Why?
Why is the window open...
was this really an accident?
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Kat$ 8 Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
MaSatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi hoka
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazumari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRE TOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi-Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR:
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
OGfisho Aoyama [ghog 'kukan
Il Rights Reserved
You can stop the charade now Mr. Kuroiwa
Tell us the truth,
you're relieved he's dead,
aren't you?
I didn't hate him!
Not like those men!
Then-the engine was running?
How'd you know that, kid?!
Don't tell me it was you...
No, you're wrong! It wasn't me!
What'is this?
It breaks off straight across...