Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
Tonight, we solve the case
Involving the super car.
No one's ever seen anything
Iike it before.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the l.Q. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
Semis 105as NESSES RANI RANGER ARR LINEY an
We have come to the Izu Highlands
after winning first prize in the
neighborhood association's drawing
which was a 1 night's stay in a hotel here.
The owner of the hotel
turns out to be a real car buff
and a historic car show
is opening at the hotel the following day.
The uests that
show up though, all have had
their valuable cars taken away
by the owner through deceitful methods.
That night, the owner of the hotel
goes for a late night drive
and the next morning
he is found dead
in the driver's seat of his car!
(£282)
TRAP OF THE SUPER CAR
What do you think, Doctor?
The cause of death is probably
carbon monoxide poisoning
caused by the exhaust fumes...
And I see no other external injuries
The estimated time of death is
between 9 and 10 AM
That's right, he was still alive when
I called him on his cellular a little past 9
You talked to him?!
How did he sound?
He sounded like
he was in pain and he said
Where am 1? and It's pitch dark',
gibberish like that...
I guess the carbon monoxide was
making him delirious
That means he must ve died
right after you called
Excuse me, Detective Yokomizo...
doesn't that mean
Mr. Teraizumi was'here wa Tbefore 9:00?
Of course, you nincompoop
By the way Mr Mouri
About the window on the driver side
why do you think it's slightly open?
Survival instinct!
The exhaust fumes were suffocating him
and he must've opened it in desperation
But why did he die then?
Because by the time he got the
window open, it was too late...
What is this?
It breaks off straight across
Hey you there...
You shouldn't be
wandering around here!!
I'm sorry...
I was just wondering
what this black stain was...
That's coal tar, it s made
when fuel is imperfectly combusted!
It dripped out of the muffler!
It happens arlotsintthese old cars
Gee, but it looks*rso shiny and new
Yeah, it s been polished so good,
there's hardly any fingerprints on it...
What is it? Is something wrong?
It seems this car's been in
an accident lately...
there's a crack in the left head lamp
and we found some fibers in it
A crack and fibers...?
Well, here we are...
Sorry to keep you waiting so long
Let's start right away...
which of you ls Mr. Sagara,
the one who first discovered the body...
That's me
Will you give us the details of
how you found the body?
I got back from my morning drive
a little past 10
Shinsuke Sagara
LA Ti
HER Fr Q37)
Z3 Le led DD J3LJULAL
and I was just about to park my car
in the parking lot
Shinsuke Sagara
B'S LULA TO
HE FT 37)
I ESL BD TOHLDBVNAW
HIS IZ3Y LA x5
and I was just about to park my car
in the parking lot
Shinsuke Sagara
when I nearly crashed into the Dino...
You see, the fog hadn't lifted yet
And when look in the car,
I saw Mr. Teraizumi
slumped in the driver's seat
Is there anything else you noticed?
Now that you mention it,
I saw all these other people
all gathered near the parking lot...
Uh, that was my fault
Eh, what do you mean, Ran?
Ran let out this loud scream
that scared us
so we all ran out to see what was up
e Og was SO 1C Cou mn See
and when the security guard
called out to me, it scared me
I see...
by the way, about the late Mr. Teraizumi,
we assume he returned from his drive
and sat in his car with the engine running
and died from
carbon monoxide inhalation
does anyone know why he would sit
in his car with the engine running...
The truth is, Mr. Teraizumi loved that car
morelthan anything, why just yesterday...
Zenkichi Kuroiwa
The truth is Mr. Teraizumi loved that car
more than anything, why just yesterday...
Zenkichi Kuroiwa
ET TO
Iv Buch
The truth is, Mr. Teraizumi loved that car
morelthan anything, why just yesterday...
Sir the other cars are already
In their places.
Why don't you take yours there now
Hold it just 1 minute, don't rush me...
I want to spend tonight with 'my friend!
Once it's on display, I won t be able to
take it for a spin whenever I feel like it
I guess that's why he couldn't tear
himself away from his beloved car
after he got back from his drive...
see,.
and then he must have fallen asleep
Mr. Teraizumi was really looking forward
to the opening of the show room today...
I feel so sorry for him...
You can stop the charade now,
Mr. Kuroiwa...
Tell us the truth, you're relieved
he's dead, aren't you?
Wh, what are you talking about!?
I know all about it, Mr. Teraizumi was
just about to lay you off
ouswere being, laid off?
Is that true?
Yes, It 1s true
Bull didn't hate him!
Not like these me here!
What do you mean by that?
They all hated him....!
They had their precious cars
taken away by Mr. Teraizumi
when they couldn't repay their debts
And don't forget the.threatening letter
A threatening letter!?
Oh that was nothing but a prank...
Hmm...but this could mean
his death was a murder...
A murder?
How can kill you someone
by carbon monoxide poisoning?
But you see, Mr. Mouri...
Detective Yokomizo?
Mr Kogoro always says that
the most important thing is
everyone's alibi, {isn't that right?
Yes, you're right Conan...
Well, does anyone have anything to say?
When that private detective over there
called Mr. Teraizumi,
he was still alive, wasn't he?
Od Br
We were all with that detective after that
that's right...the only ones missing were
Mr. Sagara and Suguro, over there...
Eh!? Are you talking about me?
Oh come on...
the only time I left everyone is...
Hisashi Suguro
flu,
Oh come on...
the only time I left everyone is...
to prepare for the opening ceremony
and that was for only 5 minutes,
from 10 to 10:05...
That's when we heard Ran scream
and we all ran out into the parking lot
I couldn't have killed him
In just 5 minutes!
You're right about that...
Mr. Sagara, you stated that
you were out for a drive?
That's right and it was Mr. Sagara
who found Mr.Teraizumi dead!
Mr. Sagara! Don't tell me it was you...
No,, ou're wrong! It wasn't me
I was on the veranda yesterday and
I heard Mr. Sagara talking on the telephone
Don't worry about it!!
I'll take care of it!
The opening ceremony's
at 3 tomorrow afternoon
Tonight's going to be our last chance...
that's right, don't worry
We're going ahead as scheduled,
understand...
Do you want to explain, Mr. Sagara?
The truth is, I borrowed
some money from a friend...
You borrowed money?
Yes...l was going to repay
Teraizumi and get my car back...
but I figured paying him back
wasn't good enough,
I was going to throw the money
In his face at the opening ceremony
and put his nose out of joint...
That's why I rushed to Tokyo
Iast night to get the money.
If you call my friend,
he'll confirm my story
It seems everyone has an alibi...
It must have been an accident after all
Excuse me, Detective...
I d like to put the Dino on display
In memory of Mr. Teraizumi.
Yes, you're right
We're done inspecting the crime scene,
I guess it'll be all right
Thank you very much!
If it wasn't Mr. Sagara...l wonder?
Last night, he...
Mr. Kuroiwa, excuse me...
Huh? What is it?
That guy fromethe crime lab
just told me that
the Dino's headlight cover was cracked...
Eh? Is that true?
It wasn't there yesterday,
and If Mr. Teraizumi hit something,
he'd have made a big fuss and
have it get it fixed right away
I knew it...
Mr. Teraizumi hit something
when he got back from his drive...
But how did the killer commit the murder?
Wh, what was that?
Are you sure about that?
Yes, I checked the parking lot
a little before 10
but Mr. Teraizumi's car wasn't there
But the fog was very thick,
maybe you overlooked it
No, I'd never make that mistake.
There was another car
parked in his space
Another car!?
Yes...l didn't get a good look because of
the fog, but I think it was gray
And I'd never heard that engine before so
I know it wasn't one of our regular guest
Then the car's engine was running
Yes, and I d recognize
Mr. Teraizumi's car engine anyfdlay
What does all that mean!
Detective Yokomizo
Please come with me
What's up...
That's it!!
Excuse me, Mr. Noda,
at that time, just by chance...
What!? Mr. Sagara did what!?
Yes, he said he'd repaid
the money he owed
so he was taking his car back right now...
Darn. .we ve already got our hands full!!
Let's go!!
Yes sir!
How'd you know that, kid!?
So I'm right!!
Yes, you sure are, kid
Now I know everything!!
I know why the tar was
broken off straight across...
and why that gray car was
in the parking lot!
And I've solved the mystery of
the cracked headlight and the fiber....!
I have all the answers now...
He's the killer!!
Wn Stop it, MreSagara!
You can't do this!
What do you mean!?
I just paid the money back
didn't 11?
I'm taking my car back
no matter what you say!!
Wait a minute Mr Sagara!
What's going on here?
I'm glad you're here.
Mr. Sagara insists on leaving with his car
We can't allow that.
You have to stay here
until we've cleared everyone
What do you mean,
wasn't it an accident?
Well, it appears it may not have been...
Did you find something?
When the security guard Mr. Noda
checked the parking lot a little before 10,
instead of Mr Teraizumi's car,
he claims that he saw
a gray car parked in his spot!
What!? That means...
oh boy
here we go again...
Mr. Mouri, are you all right?
Mr. Mount???
I've finally figured everything out,
Detective Yokomizo.
What you just said confirmed it all
What do you mean...?
Mr. Teraizumi s death
was not an accident.
It was pre-meditated murder!!
Detective Yokomizo
before I start explaining
how the crime was committed,
I'd like you to prepare something
I understand. What do you need?
First, could you call Mr. Noda,
the security guard here
Go on...
Yes sir!
And another thing,
I need a large vinyl sheet If possible
one like the kind they use to cover cars...
A car cover.
If it's one of those, Suguro,
your car in the parking lot is
always covered, isn't it?
Uh, huh...
You have one!
Do you mind lending it to us?
Sure, no problem
Now that everything is ready, let us begin
When Mr. Teraizumi got back
from his drive,
the killer used a sleeping drug
to put him to sleep,
then put him behind the wheel of the Dino
and left him there with the engine running
Hah, that leaves me out.
When I left for Tokyo,
Mr. Tieraizumi wasn't back yet!
I wouldn't be so sure about that
What!?
No one saw Mr. Teraizumi return
So can you prove
he didn't get back before you left?
How dare you!?
Just calm down...
Let me remind you Mr Mourn,
when Mr. Noda the security guard
made his rounds shortly
before the body was found,
he claims Mr. Teraizumi's car was
not in the parking lot
But in truth, it was already there when
Mr.Noda checked the parking lot
He s already stated
there was a gray car in that space...
And that car was Mr. Teraizumi's!
What was that!?
Uh, but still Mr. Noda said
the engine wasn't Mr. Teraizumi's
Yes,
That engine wasn't Mr. Teraizumi's Dino.
It was another car!
Alright Detective Yokomizo,
turn the 1 nition on
Alright
Yes sir
Mr. Mouri, the engine's running
OK .how about it, Mr. Noda
it's not the same, that's not
the car I heard in the parking lot
Now, Detective Yokomizo
could you cover the Dino with that cover
This cover?
All right Mr. Noda
Listen very carefully
All nght
Thus IS it!
This is the engine I heard!!
Are you sure!?
But why cover the car
I've got 1it!! That's why the window...
That's right!
That's why the window was down...
so that the exhaust fumes
would enter the car!
After the killer put Mr. Teraizumi to sleep
he lowered the window
then covered the car
and anchored it down securely
so that the fumes wouldn { escape
Does everyone remember
Mr: Teraizumi's last words
over the telephone...
Oh...hello Mr Teraizumi?
W's me, Mourn . Where are you?
Ugh, wh wheream ll 7?
It's, it's pitch dark...
Pitch dark!?
I've got it! Mr. Teraizumi said it was dark
because the car was covered!
That's right.
And the exhaust fumes trapped
under the cover
entered the car through the open window
causing him to die of
carbon monoxide poisoning
Then the killer waited
until the right moment,
returned to the car,
and took the cover off leaving us with
what he thought to be the perfect crime...
But then something the killer
didn't anticipate occurred!
And what was that?
One, Mr Noda saw the car
with the cover on...
It was coincidence that you went to the
parking lot at that time, wasn't it?
1 CO,
Mr. Kuroiwa had asked me to look for
Mr. Teraizumi, that's why I went there...
The second thing was Ran"s scream...
Huh my scream...?
Yes, I'm sure the killer had gone
to take the cover off,
but when Ran screamed he got scared
and forgot to close the window...!
Which means, that the killer,
is the person who arrived
Iast where Ran was
Suguro, it was you!!
Ka ..Suguro...
You can't be serious
Just because I arrived late
when your daughter screamed
don't make me out to be the killer...
Suguro, explain
the stain on your trousers
The stain IS from the wine
you spilled on them last night...
That's night
but when you brought
the room service order to our room...
I'm very sorry about
ruining your pants earlier
No problem...it was nothing.
I changed right away
So why did you change back
Into a pair of stained trousers?
That's none of your business
The head lamp on Mr Teraizumi's car
was cracked and
- -ell -
Some « er Was Suc oO.
when Mr. Teraizumi returned
you stopped his car
and it accidentally hit your knee
and it tore your trousers, didn't it?
You're just making everything up...
Mr. Noda,
when you saw the strange car in the
parking lot, why didn't you check it out?
Well Suguro told me
to check the front entrance
He's lying!!
Please check under Suguro's car cover
Iook at the part that goes over the muffler
you should find some black liquid on it?
Some time has past, hasn't it!
I found it! A black stain
just hike you said, Mr. Mourn!
At the scene of the crime,
we found stains from the tar
that flowed out of the Dino s muffler
It looked like it was cut off straight
across, as if it had been blocked off...!
I'm sure when we have it analyzed,
we'll find the composition
of the stains are identical...
What have you got to say, Katssuro?
Are you going to insist you're innocent?
OK you got me!! I killed Teraizumi!
That Dino...was once MY car.
But he cheated me out of it!!
You killed him over something like that...
Something like that!?
Don't put me In the same boat
as those rich good for nothings!
That car was about to be scrapped
en go 1, sacriice my OO money
and worked hard on it to get it
Iooking like it does now.
And then Teraizumi comes along and...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACK ~ROLND MUSIC
KatO 8 Ono
CHARACT R DESIGNS BY
MaSatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR:
Junichi-hoka
SCRIPTS BY
, Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazumari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure *
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yikihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshhkobayash:
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR:
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
OGbsho Aoyama / Jog kukan
YTV / TMS
Il rights Reserved
Getting there was so much fun
but when it comes time to leave,
all the fight's gone...
Like they same, getting there is
half the fun but leaving is horrible
I guess we should have take the eat
all you can Shabu shabu dinner after all
Hey dad, maybe we should have asked
Detective Yokomizo to drive us.,
That rat! He didn't even offer! #8
Are you coming down with a cold, sir?
I don't know, I suddenly felt a chill...
Take care of yourself
I've never caught a cold
Really?
I'm never gonna help you again!!
Even Er's crazy about
younger guys these days...
MM, mom!
I can't find dad!
He's not in our room or
in any of the other 3 people's rooms!
What's going on?
DD dad!?