Just as flowing water has no form,
& the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes & styles in
each and every case to be solved.
Kogoro's always messing things<up
butsthis time HE'S in a mess, big time!
He sees through the one & only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
KOGORO MOURI THE SUSPECT-PART I
Peaches and
« Melons
and kumquats
Oh I just love summer fruits!
And they're so ripe.
Na, Na.
An, why you...
YOU suggested we spend a night at a
hotel since we were coming to Karuizawa
to get away from
the heat in the city, hah!
How come you're the only one
who brought swimming trunks!
The whole idea was so he could
Iook at girls in the pool, I bet
Hey come back,
I'm not through listening...
Too bad!
I'm not lending this to any dirty old man!
Besides, mom bought this for me!
Hey, wait! Wait up!
You can't blame me,
I've been so busy working lately,
the stress has been building up!
But I've been letting you sleep haven't I?
Don't you think
you're being unfair to mom?
You can't tell what she's doing
about now either!
She could be going after
some young guy,
MM, Mom?!
I don't believe it...
what are you doing here...
I just told you.
I came to Karuizawa with a lawyer
colleague 10 do some sightseeing, that's all
Then what about that neck tie
you were buying just now?
Oh that... .uh,
a friend asked me to buy one...
and I asked him to help me choose one,
isn't that right?
Norihumi Saku
Really? I didn't know that.
I thought you were buying it for me
Norihumi Saku
This is no joking matter, Saku!
You're not a little kid,
can't you choose one on your own?
Well excuse me!
Good grief...
Very interesting.
Why Ritsuko!
The great Queen herself is
reduced to a mere commoner
Ritsuko Usui
when it comes to her husband, I see!
Did she say Queen?
Didn't you know?
She reigns so mightily in court,
no one dares approach!
She's such an eloquent speaker,
even judges are left in awe...
That's why she's been nicknamed
Queen of the legal circle
Will you stop saying that?
You're the only ones who call me that
Kenzo Shiozawa
I don't know about that,
Tg [. - :
I heard some prosecutors say that when
they're in court up against Ms Kisaki,
Kenzo Shiozawa
Uh TO
I heard some prosecutors say that when
they're in court up against Ms Kisaki,
they feel like traitors defying their Queen!
I think I understand how that feels...
But now the #1 female lawyer is you,
after you got a ruling in
the second trial reversed
& took that famous case
all the way to the High Court
Anyone could have won that case
Let me apologize then
I was the lawyer In first trial
and I guess I wasn't good enough
I was the lawyer in first trial
and: guess I wasn't good enough
Yuji Mikasa
Attorney)
that's why I lost the case
that anyone could have won
Yuji Mikasa
Attorney
that's why I lost the case
that anyone could have won
No, Ill...that's not what I meant...
What I really meant was that
winning a case like that doesn't put me
even close to Queen Eri's class!
Enough already
You two may be separated
but I still envy you,
a female lawyer who never loses
and a private detective who always
solves his cases, what a couple!
Oh no
I'm just an worthless man who is ever
so proud to be married to a grand lady
You're right...
Tihenstha emust-mean I'm a stupid woman
who's picked a woman chasing
private detective,
a low-life who looks for the dirt
In other people's lives
asatheman to share her life-with
Good grief, how can you say that...
everytime Mr. Mouri solves a case,
Dr. gn o em
you Cu Ou earicein ee newspaper
& put it in your scrapbook!
No, I don't!
Dad does that too!
Late at night, he sneaks & reads all
articles on the cases mom is working on!
Right, dad?!
Don't tell her you idiot!!
Come on now
here we are, all in Karuizawa!
Let's just call a truce for tonight
fhave a-good time!
Well, if Eri doesn't object [I'll oblige...
I I don't mind ..not one bit...
What is this? What's going on?
Could it be? They're still in love?
No way...
I'd like to hear Ritsuko's sweet voice
pleading my case in court too...
Mr. Mouri, are you drunk?
Dad!
Oh Ritsuko,
your little hands are soooo cute
You're my type
Mom, wait!
What a drunkard...
Wait a minute!!
Mom, you know that dad always gets
Iike that when he's drunk
Besides, you were with a man
today yourself...
you looked so happy, choosing that tie...
You're right...
I shouldn't have bought thisfthing...
I let my guard down for.one moment
and now I'm so mad
I think I might explode...
I don't believe it, you mean...
that tie's...
Yes, that's right...
tomorrow's our.wedding anniversary...
I felt sorry for you and I thought
maybe it was time for me to forgive him
so I figured I'd give him a present...
but I'm glad I didn't...
Then I'll take that!
Hey wait
I'll give it to him for you!!
come right back here!!
Ir...
I, 1 think I'll give it to him myself...
Good grief!!
Did everybody leave?
Dad too?
Uh huh!
He said he was going back to the room
to sleep because he felt drunk...
I think dad's in his room!
Good luck!
Oh, all right!
Yes...
why, Ms. Kisaki...
I know it's late and I apologize
but is my husband here?
No, he's not, why?
Alll «AE.
SCC.
Is something wrong?
I can't find dad, he's not in our room
or in the other 3 people's rooms
vs *%
Maybe he's wandering around outside,
he likes to feel the night air...
I'm sorry we disturbed you
we'll go look outside
Excuse us
Let's go find him!!
Yes, let's go!
Forgive me Ms Kisaki,
but I've finally discovered that I'll never
be like you, no matter how hard I try...
the only way I can ever rise above you...
is you've got to fall a few notches
If you thought there was something
between your beloved husband and me,
your ability to think clearly would be
affected and your work would suffer,
then you'd be forced to
relinquish your title as #1 to me...
Ritsuko Usui!!
Good grief, are they back again?
How persistent...
h...What can I do for yo
Eh? Mr. Mouri's still not back?
Are you sure about that?
Yes...
We've looked everywhere,
the hotel grounds, the roof,
the stairways, everywhere...
It's already 2 AM...
That's strange...
He left with Miss Usui because he said
they were staying on the same floor...
Nam a
I OTC.
So that leaves...
Ritsuko's room is the only one
we haven't checked...
Hey? This wasn't here
when we came here earlier...
earlier...
We came here earlier to ask
but she said he wasn't with her...
Of course he wouldn't be
I doubt those two:.would...
Mom, what are you doing?!
Sh!! Be quiet...
I don't believe it!
There's no mistake!
That's his cellular phone!
It can't be...
Mikasa!
I hate to ask but could you go to the front
desk and borrow their master key?!
You bet!
Ladies first...
Look, the door chain's on
What's the matter?
H, hey, that's...
Isn't that Ritsuko?!
Bell boy! Get the chain cutter, quick!!
Huh? Oh...
Stand back!
There's no time to waste!
Ritsuko?!
Come on! What's wrong?
Wake up!
Stop!
I don't feel a pulse...
Th, that's impossible...
What happened?
Boy, what's all the racket about!!
What's going on here?
ID, dad!
K, Kogoro...
740,
Wh, why are you here...?
The chain was on the door
Ritsuk0's body was on the floor...
And only 1 other person was in
this locked room...
Hey now! What's going on here...
Don't step on that
That telephone cord on the floor
IS probably the weapon!
M, murder weapon?!
Look, over there!
See the thin marking around her neck?
I see...you're saying she was strangled
with the telephone cord™.
H, hey! Whyss Miss Usui lying on the...
Eh? Did you say strangled...
By who?
You're the one who could've done it!!
Why'd you kill her...
Now just hold on!!
I'm sure this 1s some kind of mistake!
My father would never kill anyone,
would he,
mom?!
Penal code #499 .
A person charged with murder
will be sentenced to life
or a minimum sentence of 3 years...
the death penalty!!
What?
MM mom?!
Ran! Why are you standing around?
Call-the police at once!
He's got to be kidding...
Hmm...let me get this straight
Your husband was missing,
you thought he might be in this room
so you called him on his cellular...
- and as you suspected,
you heardghis cellular ringing in this room
when you used the master key
tofunlock the door,
you found the chain was on
and you could see the victim lying on the
floor in the space between the door...
gs By UL
When you broke down the door
and entered the room,
Keiji Yamamura
ASNT
When you broke down the door
and entered the room,
Keiji Yamamura
When you broke down the door
and entered the room,
Keiji :amamura
DA. TL
When you broke down the door
and entered the room,
Keiji @amamura
you found the victim was already dead,
Keiji Yamamura
IA. TUN
you found the victim was already dead,
Keiji Yamamura
and your husband was asleep
on this bed...right?
Yes...
Then I'm sorry to tell you this
but your husband is the murderer...
That's not fair!
Just wait a minute! Dad,
don't just stand there say something!
Hey? I know you...
arentyou Xogoro Mourn?
Uh, yes
With a famous private detective
Iike you on the scene,
this case's good as solved!
Why don't you tell me your thoughts
regarding this murder?
Yes dear .
Why don't you tell him
all about what happened here...
while: youswere snoring up a storm...
Mr. Famous Private Detective...
Eh? He's your husband?!
You're married to Kogoro Mourn?!
But, then, that means .
Then, then YOU'RE the murderer?!
I don't believe it,
what's going to happen withThe Sleeping
Kogoro's Mystery Solving Show 7?!
What do I care!!
Detective Yamamura!
Shall we take Mr. Mourn
down to the station for questioning?
I suppose...if Mr. Mouri doesn't mind...
Dad...
Aw rats... really wanted to see him
solve the case in his sleep...
I guess you'll be
his pre-indictment lawyer then?
Pre-indictment lawyer?
It s a system where a lawyer
can be present with the suspect
so he gets treated fairly by the police
Sorry, but I pass
I'm not taking a case
when I know the suspect's guilty!!
I'm not going to spoil my perfect record
I wasn't going to ask you anyway!!
And don't you show up at the police
station either, or you'll be sorry!!
DD. dad!
MM, mom!!!
Alright then, I'll take care of it,
besides, I don't think Mr. Mouri did it...
Let's go then...
Thank you very much!
How could you...
Mikasa, will you
and Shiozawa leave the room?
I have something to say to the detective
Sure, no problem...
What are you going to say
Excuse me, Detective...
Yes?
Would you mind lending me your gloves?
Did you say gloves?
Mom, what are you going to do...
There are 3 things that don't add up
the first is the telephone cord
used to strangle the victim...
if he killed while he was drunk
and without pre-meditation
he would have ripped the cord
out of the jack
but the telephone is still neatly in place...
and there s no indication the cord was
forcibly removed from either end...
The second thing is his cellular phone...
I have a feeling it was
deliberately left near the door
so we could hear it ringing from outside...
And the third thing is his hands .
Only about 40 minutes had passed
since the time we last spoke
to her then found her body
If he had strangled her with the cord
there should still
have been marks on his hands
unless of course, he wore leather gloves
or something of that sort.
But we found nothing like that here...
Yes I see what you mean,
it is strange...
Mom, are you saying the reason you
didn't go with dad to the station was
you wanted to check things out here...!
Of course=silly™.
I've known him-much=longer than you!
Sure, I wasiangryavfirst
but I know better than anyone
that he isn't capable of murder
Then when dad said he didn't want
you to show up at the station,
what he really meant was he wanted you
to find the evidence that would clear him...
I wouldn't know...
maybe he said that because
he really didn't want to see me
what's this...
There's a memo pad on the desk...
and a page has been ripped out...
Maybe it's this? Is this the page?
It's kind of wrinkled
but it has, some writing on it, see?
Jig;
Hmm...yes, it is her writing...
Hayashi...? And is that the number 2?
It could pertain to Hayashi a lawyer who
she'll be teaming up with on her next case
He's been wanting to contact her
to discuss that-certain case
What case is that?
It's the case everyone's talking about,
regarding a company polluting the water
they approached us at first
but neither Shiozawa nor I
wanted to handle it
and Saku's a criminal lawyer
so Ritsuko and Mikasa ended up with it...
They lost the first trial
but were able to win the second...
She asked me to introduce
another lawyer to replace Mikasa
because she wanted to win the case
and I thought of Mr. Hayashi .
But ll hadn't told her about him vet
it's strange though...
I don't think I told him
the name of this hotel...
He said Mr. Shiozawa told him...
Oh. I'm sorry, I'm the one who connected
the call from Mr. Hayashi to this room
Who told you you could come In here!!
I uh something was bothering me so I
thought I'd better tell you about it...
So what's bothering you?
Actually, Mr. Hayashi called twice...
the first time he called,
he got through, but...
The second time he called, there was no
answer and the call came back to the desk,
I thought it was strange
so I came up to the room to check...
I checked twice...
You checked twice?!
Yes...the first time, I rang the doorbell
and there was no answer
so I told Mr. Hayashi
she might be resting, but...
Mr. Hayashi said
she might just be taking a bath
so he asked me to check again...
and there was a do not disturb sign
on the door and a note
door and a:'note...
Yes... it said...
I'm very sorry please tell him
I'll repay the money
the writing was very distorted
And did you give
Mr. Hayashi the message?
Did you?!
Allcbv
but he sounded very confused, he said
he was calling just to change the time
of their meeting the next day from 2 to 4
I don't understand...
the note we found
In the waste basket was
probably the memo regarding
her meeting at 2 with him...
« hat's right...
but the note on the door was
about something totally different!
If she was killed
before the second call, then...
that means the killer put the sign
and the note on the door!
But why would the killer do
something so stupid...
it would only be leading us to conclude
Kogoro didn't commit the crime!
Ne \ > a 4) 2 \
ORIGINAL COMIC BO@KS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACK ~ROLUND MUSIC
Kats: 8 Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
MaSatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR:
Junichi hoka
fir
Kan]: KaShlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRE TOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi-Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
enji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
O Gosho Aoyama / hog 'kukan
All Rifhts Reserved
I'm almost positive
your husband is the murderer!
What!?
Eh!?
I'm pret. sure...yes, I'm sure...
I see... so that's why
that person left that note...
Unless you're the murderer...
There s no reason for
anyone else to enter this room!!