Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and sizes
In each and every case to be solved.
Kogoro the suspect is in a real pinch.
Only a certain person can save him.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
The three of us are staying
in a hotel here in Karuizawa,
where by mere chance,
we run into Eri Kisaki
who is also here with
a group of her lawyer colleagues.
Later that night,
Kogoro becomes drunk and
when he doesn't return
to his room, we go looking for him,
and discover the body of fellow lawyer
Ritsuko Usui in her locked room.
On top of that,
we find Kogoro asleep in that room.
Naturally, Kogoro is
considered the prime suspect
and he is taken to the station
for questioning.
We are left behind and.
Does this mean the reason you didn't go
with dad was so you could stay here to...!
Of course silly...
I've known your dad for a long time!
Sure, I wasgmad at-first
but I know better than anyone
that your dad isnitscapable of murder
iii £5)
KOGORO MOURI THE SUSPECT
PART II
I'm sorry, please tell him
I'll repay the money
that sounds strange
It seems hard to believe
but it sounds like there was a money
matter between the 2 lawyers...
I know for a fact Miss Usui, the victim,
and Mr. Hayashi have never met!
Besides, I hadn't even told her
about him yet,
so they couldn't possibly
have been making a money deal
I didn't think so either!
And Mr. Hayashi, who
would be working with her
wanted to contact her
as soon as possible
So he asked Mr. Shiozawa,
one of her colleagues
where she could be reached
and called her here...
And judging from the memo
we found in the waste basket
and the bell boy's statement,
it is certain they were
going to meet the next day at 2
But how do you
explain the note on the door?
I remember you...
I'm positive you were with
Miss Yukiko
when I was working on another case
in the past...
Yikes,
I knew I'd seen this
guy somewhere before,
He's that incompetent detective with
the Gunma Prefectural Police....!
Elji Yamamura
eiji Yamamura
Oh, that
what are you doing here, Karuizawa is
in Nagano prefecture, isn't it?
Yes...but this place is right on
the borderline and it's
In our jurisdiction!
So you've met Yukiko
and this boy before?
Yes...ll think her husband
came later though...
They certainly caused a lot of trouble,
disrupting our investigation and all!
Especially this kid
Oh...th, that grouchy man was guilty,
wasn t he!!!
Uh, yeah, I guess...
Detective Yamamura!
Huh?
A, are you sure about that?!
Madam. .l regret to have to tell you
but.it;seems your husband¥is:guilty...
Wha?!
Your husband's fingerprints
were on the telephone cord,
which was the murder weapon!
And on top of that.
We have witnesses from the bar 'stating that
your husband was drunk and making
advances to Miss Usut!
I'm almost positive
your husband is the murderer!
Now wait just a minute,
weren't you listening?
I told you there were no marks
from the cord on my husband's hands!
He s a top notch private detective!
In other words, he's a crime specialist.
He d know how to avoid
getting marks on: his hands
B., but just because he was
drunk and making advances doesn't...
The real motive though,
is probably his job...
he sees mutilated bodies
nearly every day...and he snapped,
he decided he wanted
to commit a murder too!!
Gee that's scary...
This is bad...
if we let this dummy handle the case,
he'll get Kogoro convicted for real
Listen! I found something
weird by the door!
I ER?
See, here, here!
If youaestalking about the thread, I gave
it to the officers from the crime lab
Thread?
IUD...
I found it...
it was about 3 centimeters long
with one end tied...
It was on the floor along with
a piece of the door chain which probably
flew off when the door was forced open
Then did you take a good
Iook at that piece of chain?
Yes, I did
I saw a strange mark on it
Eh? Then...
That's right...
I'm pret. sure
1 figured out the trick as:to
how the room was locked, but...
1, trick?
But...
I know ..proof...!
We know why the killer used the
telephone cord to commit the murder,
and even why the sign
was left on the door
we even know who the killer
is but there s no proof!!
Do you have that MD player
I bought for you?
Eh? Right here, but...
Can I borrow it?
I"*can'tithink straight unless!
I listen to music
What I can't figure out is that strange
note on the door'.
Hey?
There's no music on this disk...
Eh? You're kidding...
Oh no! You're pressing
the record button!!
Oops...
I'm sorry.
The MD player we have
in the office is only used for recording,
I pressed it without thinking...
Good grief!!
Without thinking...
wait a minute...
I'm pretty sure it was on the desk...
Im-pret. sure
yes, I'm sure...
Now I etit...
so that's why that person left that note...
No! You mustn't do that.
You shouldn't§stand on chairs
with your shoes on
But-l-m:hungry
Good grief,
sometimes you act like such an adult
but sometimes you're such a little kid
I can't help it, I'm starving .
Oh all right.
I'll order you something from
room service later
What you just said...
Oh, Saku...
How did it go?
How is he doing at the station?
Actually...
it seems Mr. Mouri was so drunk, he
doesn't know why he was in her room...
even the police
can't believe he's the suspect
so they're in a state of confusion too...
I OTC...
Ms. Kisaki, I hate to say this but
your husband is the only
one who could've done it.
Miss Usui's room was
Iocked from the inside!
And Mr Mouri was asleep in her bed...
There's the issue of how he killed her...
it would be considered
an accidental death if she died
as a result of say, hitting her head
against something when he pushed her
while he was in a drunken stupor,
but she was strangled to death
with a telephone cord.
That's first degree murder...
I agree...
he stands to face
a minimum sentence of 10 years
if he's charged with murder and rape...
at worst, it'll be a life sentence...
and there's always
the possibility of the death penalty...
Mother, how can you say that!!
Didn't you just say, someone else did it?!
Oh that. I guess I was wrong after all
Oh, by the way, Ms Kisaki...
what did you want to ask
Yes...there's was something
I just couldn't figure out
so I thought I'd get your opinion.
Your specialt is criminal law, isn't it?
So I thought you'd know
more about these things...
Uh huh.
Come on, let s go!
Ms. Kisaki
WM. mother!
What do think will happen to that trial...
You know the case she was working on,
the one dealing with
that pollution problem...
Do you think I should take over
that case then?
But unlike Ritsuko,
the issue's not what I specialize in
so at best, I'd probably just
get both parties to settle out of court...
oh, it's my phone,
sorry, but you could you go
on ahead to her room
Sure...
Let's see
where was her room
huh?
Good grief...
Oh, it's Mr Saku!
Hey? are you all alone, kid?
Uh huh! The police are all gone!
What are you doing here?
Oh...Ms. Kisaki said
she wanted to talk to me...
I bet it's about
that short piece of thread
that we found on the floor by the door
along with a part of the door chain!
I heard her talking!
She said thatsyou could
use that thread from the
outside to make it look
Iike the door was locked!
That's ridiculous,
I can verify that the chain
was fastened securely, that's why
I had to break the door down
to get in
how can you lock the door with such
a short piece of thread...
What if the chain was
cut from the very beginning?
What if the thread was holding the
Ioose ends of the chain together?
And what if the knot and the parts
of the chain that
had been removed where put
on the floor in a spot
that when the door was opened, it would
be in a blind spot...
Well?
Yes...and after that, when the
door is opened with force,
the thread will break,
the chain separates
and all of us there
will have the illusion,
that the door had been
chained from the inside...
Isn't that right, Saku?
You did it, didn't you, Saku...
1, 1 don't know what you're talking about!
Mr. Mouri was asleep in the room,
if he'd gotten up and taken the chain off
the whole plan would be blown...
That's why you used the
telephone cord to strangle her
So the phone wouldn't ring
and you took my
husband's phone away
from the bedside
and put it near the door
then you put:the Do Not Disturb) sign out
SO No one would ring the
door bell, isn't that right?
All that so my husband wouldn't get up...
But then I'm sure you put
his celluar phone near the door
so that we could hear it ring from the hall,
and that way we'd know he was inside
you knew that would make us
get the master key to get inside
If I hadn't called his phone then,
you would have, I'm sure of it
Humph...
Nice going Ms Kisaki.
What you say makes sense...
But it would be wiser for you
Ondo san up wn ours ee ense
and charge me for it...
after all, you have no proof I did it
and your perfect record would be ruined,
you wouldn't want that, would you...
You fool,
the only reason I have a perfect record
is because I've had
a streak of ood luck...
it's about time it ended anyway,
then at least the pressure would be off.
Unfortunately though,
it seems my luck is still strong.
Want to know why?
It's because you're confessing...
it started the moment
you stepped inside this room!
I'm surprised you knew
this was her room...
Wh, why shouldn't There's
the hayashi rice outside the door...
Oh my, how did you know
about the hayashi rice
Well, uh...
That's right the door bell
probably rang while
you were s 1 In e room
working on the door chain
after killing Ritsuko...
when you looked through the view hole,
you saw the bell boy standing there,
and saw the memo on the desk,
Hayashi 2
Then to prevent the bell boy
from ringing the door bell again
for when the bell boy would returned,
you wrote a note inferring that
the hayashi rice should be taken back
but you would pay for them
then you taped the note on the sign
and hung it on the door knob...
Unless you did those things,
there's no way for you to
know about the hayashi rice
It was just coincidence that I saw them...
I saw the bell boy standing
in front of her room
holding the plates and he looked upset...
that's how I knew this was her room...
I hate to tell you this.
But that memo you saw
meant she was to meet
Mr. Hayashi at 2 o'clock
You saw the memo on the desk along
with the open room service
menu and you jumped to the conclusion
that she meant hayashi rice...
Uh, uh...did I say hayashi rice...?
I meant to say I knew this was her room
because I looked at the room number...
Oh my, haven't you noticed?
the door chain in this room isn't cut, is it?
We made a sudden request
for the hotel to let us use this room...
her actual room is 2 doors down...
which means...
you had absolutely no reason
to enter this room,
unless of course,
you were the murderer...
Please forgive me for setting this trap...
but when I realized
you were the killer, I knew
I had to be convincing or
you'd never fall for it...
I think I understand for the first time.
How the prosecutors must feel
going against you in court...
but how are you going
to convince the prosecution?
You're the only one that
saw me come into this room
and being a part of Mr. Mouri's
family, your testimony wouldn't count...
Oh but I'm not the only witness
You're not talking about this kid, are you?
And I'm not the only one either!
Isn't that right, officers!
Eh?)
That's right, we saw everything!
Right through the view hole in the room
across the hall!
Isn't that right, men?!
Yes we got a good look!
A real good look...
And.we have everything
on video tape too!
But it was all this little guy's idea...
Now tell me, was the case
she was working on
your motive for killing her?
1 OO...
the village that suffered
from the pollution is where I grew up
I really wanted them to win the case...
Actually, I intended to drug her in
the doorway and after she was asleep,
I was going to lock the room up
and make it look like she
committed suicide...
But Mr Mouri was asleep in the room
and no one would believe
she would commit suicide
after inviting a man into her room
and then orderin room service...
so I decided to strangle her instead
and frame Mr Mourn. .
It would have given the judge
a bad impression if
the villagers killed the lawyer
so they could win the trial, wouldn't it...
I intended to settle the case out of court
quickly then turn myself in...
But even if you turned yourself in, unless
there's evidence to prove you did it...
Oh, but ll do...
It's that weird shaped mark left by the
pliers you used on the chain, isn't it?
There's only 1 pair of pliers
in the world that leave that mark...
you were going to take that
to the police, weren't you?
Uh, yes
Ritsuko only took that case because it
was assigned to her,
you didn't have to kill her...
I would never have done it if
she had taken the case to
support her livelihood or because she
considered it her job...
but when I learned she was
deliberately making things
hard for the villagers and
taking the case
so she could outdo you
and gain recognition, well,
I just couldn't let her get away it
To outdo me?
and I think she took
Mr. Mouri up to her room
for that very same reason
I don't believe it, it can't be true...
As lawyers, our job is to trust our clients
and defend them as best as we can,
but you're too trusting...
there's a hidden side
to every human being...
To be perfectly honest, I was one of the
men who was trying to get you...
Why, thank you...
But flattery's not going
to make me take your case!
Oh, sorry!
Boy, I wished you could've seen it!
Your wife's reconstruction of the
crime was brilliant!
She's Sleeping Kogords wife,
no doubt about it!
The Queen of the court room!
I got goose bumps watching her work!!
And what were YOU doing while
she was doing all the work?
I followed her instructions and put the
hayashi rice where it was supposed to go
and then I went to the room
across the hall and waited as I was told!
When I saw them coming down the hall,
I called your wife on her cellular,
and then and then,
when the suspect entered
the staged room,
fan fare went off in my head!!
Boy, I'm glad I became a detective!
And then?
So where IS she now?
Over there, see!
At that table over there...
It's dad
We're in luck!
Now we can get some breakfast!
Oh...
Hold it!
Don't they look friendly,
this looks promising...
1, uh really appreciated it Erni...
I had faith in you...
I knew you would prove I was innocent...
And uh, by the way,
I'm kind of getting tired
of Ran"s cooking...
I guess I sort of miss your
rather strange cuisine...
What I mean is...
would you mind coming home now...
I can't take it anymore...
and oh,
since'today's our wedding anniversary...
I thought it'd be a good time
to get back together
Hey you!
Did you hear me?
Yeah
What is it?
Uh nothing
Mom!!
Quick, tell me what
you were talking about?
I was just telling her that for a first rate
Iawyer, she sure was working slow
getting her dear husband
cleared of the charges...
Did you say dear husband,
it should be darn husband, shouldn't it?
What did you say?!
Well I guess you've learned your lesson,
you should go easy on the liquor,
you moustached, lecher!
Why you, you.
Dad!
Oh Ran, I nearly forgot...
I'm going to hang on to this disk!
I've gotten to like this song...
Well, I'll be seeing you
Mom!!!
Humph!
Don't you ever show your face again!!
For goodness sakes, dad,
you're a fool, a foo!!!
Ho hum...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
MaS4tomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hoka
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hirot hi Takatanr
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi-Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
OG'§ho Aoyama [aghog 'kukan
YTV 7 TMS
II Rihts Reserved
would you mind comingjhome...
I can't take it anymore...
and oh,
since today's our wedding anniversary...
I thought it'd be a good time
to get back together
What/I mean is...
would you mind coming home...
Not quite yet!
Saying something like this
isn't going to get you off the hook...
Am I getting a cold?
Idoubfifl.
Someone probably
poisoned the tea in this bottle
Hey! What's going on In this village?
What happened In
this village 7 years ago?
What's going on? I don't get it...