Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze IS invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
in each and every case to be solved.
Today s episode features
a nostalgic bonnet bus.
It also carries the memory of an incident
that happened many years ago.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the ll.Q. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
(BI%R)
THE 10TH PASSENGER
PART
Umm, it feels so good
The air's so fresh
This bus is like the ones in the old days
I like it because it doesn't have a cooler
Good grief...
I don't understand why
anyone would actually
WANT to ride in this rundown bus
It's BECAUSE it's old
that gives it charm!
I've never ridden in one before
that's why I'm enjoying it!
What do they call this type of bus again?
It's a bonnet bus!
There were a lot around until
30 years ago
See .
The front's narrow, isn't it...
that's what makes it fun
when we pass another bus on a curb
You're absolutely right!
You sure know a lot, kid
I read about it in a book
This kid knows a lot of useless information!
You're wrong!
It's not considered useless information!
Not to those of us that
Iive in Kagekuwa Village
The bonnet bus is a
valuable tourist attraction!
Oh, uh I didn't mean it like that
Oh, uh, I didn't mean it like that...
Oh uh, I didn't mean it like that
Huh?!
My name is Takuro Yabe,
I'm from Kagekuwa Village
Hmm...
head of the youth association...
On behalf of the bonnet bus
and Kagekuwa Village,
I welcome you!
Ladies and gentlemen!
Kagekuwa Village has nothing to offer
except all the nature around you!!
Please enjoy yourselves to
your heart's content!!
He's very cheerful
Uh huh
Eh...?!
Toko Natsume
Natsume,
guide the way
Eh. 2?
Yes!
I'm sorry
Whoa look at this huge rock,
It must've fallen from up there
Eeeek, look at that!
Can we do it?
That was scary
Sure was...
Huh?! 7
A memorial tower?
Kagekuwa Village
Ahem!
Oh, yes the seat's open
Go away!
Deputy Mayor Sokichi Okumura
Ot HES (60)
M+ Rh
That's MY seat!
Deputy Mayor Sokichi Okumura
DAR HS (0)
CERT EDIT
Your seat. 2?!
Does this bus have reserved seats?
Mr. Okumura behave yourself!
Today's Sunday!!
I know that!!
We agreed at the village meeting
that unless it was a weekday,
we would give up
our seats to the tourists!
Humph!
The village mayor and you and
your group decided that for yourselves!!
How dare you!!
So, what? tie you going to do...
Force me to follow orders?
Go ahead, see if you can do it!
Of all the .
Get out of my seat, scat!
This has been my seat for 40 years!!!
I'm terribly sorry about that, sir.
Please take another seat
What's with this bus anyway...!
Gee,
it gets pretty crowded
That's because to the locals,
this isn't just a tourist attraction,
it's how they get around
Argh!!
En 7!
Whoa ?!1 What was that?
Eh...rd
What's wrong, Mr. Okumura!!
What happened?!
Wh, what's going on?!
It looks like someone got sick
I, I'm taking this bus to
the hospital right now!
Mamoru Kajita
It's no use!
Eh Ti
Mamoru Kajita
& Mamoru Kajita
do you mean, it can't be...
He s dead
Someone probably poisoned
'the,téaiifnnthisibottle.!
Stay In your seats...!
No one gets off this bus
until the police arrive!
Aw rats do we have to?
Now wait just a minute!
I don't think that's necessary...
I especially mean you, Mr. Yabe!
If this is a case of murder
you'd be our prime suspect since
you and the victim had an argument
and your seat is directly behind his!
MM, murder...
who do you think you are anyway...?
My name is Kogoro Mourn,
I'm a private detective!
Eh 7!
Mouri, you mean
the famous private detective....!
That means this is a big case!
That's right! It must be!
I wonder who did it?
I'm at your service!
Hinkai
Patrolman Hitoshi Shinkai of the
Kagekuwa station, reporting!!
Hinkai
It will be an honor to work with the
infamous private detective Kogoro Mouri!
Ahem...!
Yes well!
You seem to be a very promising officer!
I'll be glad to be of servi ell
Thank you very much.!
By the way...
it seems you claimed this was a murder,
but...are you sure...?
If it is,
then we have a serious situation
on our hands...
Eh...?!
Well h, we've got to
investigate it thoroughly first
It's murder alright
You again!
Always sticking your nose in where
it doesn't:b&longTh,
Look at the plastic bottle
Plastic bottle?
You can see it's leaking...
I think it's from that tiny hole,
It looks like a needle hole...
He s right...!
Maybe they used a hypodermic
needle to put the poison in...?!
Alright!
Uw Let's search everyone!
Whoever has a hypodermic needle
IS our murderer!
Wl wouldn't know about that
What?!
The windows were open
sq it could ve been)
tossed out at anytime. .!
And besides} the killer could've
gotten off at one of the other stops
Grrr...
Oh, oh, I feel a storm coming
Eh...?!
No, it'll be bigger than a storm...
there's going to be a war in the village...!!
What?!
WwW, war...?!
This is terrible
What'll we do?
A lot of blood's going to flow...
Blood will flow 2?!
Mr. Mourn,
the hypodermic needle has been found!
It was on the side of the road
where the bus passed!
There was some poison in it,
but very little!
What about fingerprints?
Officer Shinkai!
Detective Hino
You shouldn't be giving out
information without permission!
Detective Hino
HE B83 41)
raLstit UL
You shouldn't be giving out
information without permission!
Which means, you didn't
find any find any fingerprints, did you?
Huh. ?
If you did,
you'd have taken our. fingerprints
the minute you arrived, to compare them
As a matter of fac an .ou're right...
Who are thesempeople?
Sir;-this is Mr.:Kogoro Mour,
a very famous private detective!
He just happened to be on the bus...
With your permission, I,
Sleeping Kogoro',
will be happy to assist
in the investigation
That's ridiculous!!
Huh...?!
While you're sleeping,
I'll bet somebody else is
solving the crime for you!!
Hahaha. he's almost 100 / right...
Oh well,
you can do your thing,
as long as you don't get in
the way of our investigation
Of all the!!
What a rude fellow!!
Alright then, let's do our thing!
Huh?!
I know you can solve the case
without those policemen's help
You can bet on it!
Just watch, Detective Hino!!
I'll show you!!
Mr. Mourn,
I may not be much help
but I d be glad to assist
You won't get away with this .!
Committing a murder
right under my nose like that...!!
I'M going to find the killer on my own...!!
Excuse me,
please wait here until the investigators
get done with the questioning...
Of course,
this is the only lodging
there is in the village...
Why Officer Shinkai,
what do you mean
we're the only lodging, that's quite rude
Oh Ms Komai! That's not what ll meant...
Tee hee...
Kinu Komai
I was just kidding...
Kinu Komal
Welcome to the Komai Inn
Kinu Komai
It's a wonderful place.
It has a lot of character
Yes, I love wooden buldings!
They're human friendly
Thank you very much
Besides this place is neutral
Neutral. 7?
You re been babbling strange things
about storms and wars and what not
Well, uh, you see, it's like this...
You'll find out soon enough...
but for now,
please follow me to your rooms
Wow you can see Mt. Fuji from this place
This is great
Why you're Conan, aren't you?
Is that your room?
You're the bus guide!
You live next door
because you get the best view of
Mt. Fuji from around here
Mr. Mourn! Big news'!
What happened?
I have big news!
The investigators are
questioning Mr. Yabe and...
I knew it,
so he's the prime suspect after all!
I'm not sure about that yet,
I'm talking about
WHERE they're questioning him!
What do you mean?
They didn't take him to the district station,
they're doing it at the substation here!
And both the pro and con factions
have stormed their way in and...!!
Pro and con factions...?
Everyone go home!
The police will do
a thorough investigation!!
We don't trust them!
Give us Yabe!
He killed the deputy mayor!
Yeah, that's right!!
That's not true!
Yabe didn't do it!
He's innocent!!
Mayor, you told Yabe to do it, didn't you!
You won't get away with it!!
Get him!!
S, stop4sthat!!
I'll arrest you for
interfering in police business!!
What's going on...
Stop that!
Everybody calm down!
Everybody, just calm down!
Move it!
Whoa!
Heeeeee
Uncle Mourn!
Dad!
Mr. Mouri, are you all right?
Please stop...!
I said STOP IT!
Yes, the crowd's breaking up
and things are settling down now again!
Thank you very much!
There, that should do it
Mr Mourn,
thegpolice car transporting Mr. Yabe
has arrived safely at the district station!
Never mind that,
what's going on in this village?
Actually,
nothing: like this happened here
$ until a year ago
but ever since it was decided at the
village assembly that the bonnet bus
would be used to promote tourism,
the faction backing the
development of tourism
headed by the mayor and Mr Yabe
and the opposing faction
Ied by the victim, Mr. Okumura,
the deputy mayor have been at each
others' throats
That bus had always been used by
the villagers as their mode of transportation.
It's a small village
and everyone knows each other
so naturally,
they all started to have their own seats,
it was just the way things worked out...
But then it wasr'decided that.on weekends,
the seats would be for the tourists...
And Deputy Mayor Okumura and his
opposing faction didn't like the idea
No they didn't .
And things got worse...
but, who would have thought
it'd lead to murder...
Yabe IS innocent!!
Eh...?!
I'm sorry about how I acted before,
I'm the mayor, Takehiko Funaki!!
I hear you're a famous private detective?
Ayor TakehikoiFunaki
Ayor TakehikosFunaki
MS <O OD BABY
Mayor Takehiko Funaki
Tot Ve.
RAK KE (48)
MICO OS VASES
mit HM
I'd like you to work for us!
Mayor Takehiko Funaki
kt Oc
BAR XE A)
MIKO OS 'ABD
Br Rm.
I'd like you to work for us!
Mayor Takehiko Funaki
Huh...?
I can assure you Takuro Yabe
did not kill the deputy mayor!!
I don't like to talk ill about the dead
but he had a lot of enemies...! vy
Some in his opposing faction tool}
Please find the real killer!!
But it could turn out
to be Mr. Yabe after all
We'll cross that bridge
when we come to it!
I just want things in the village to be
back to normal as soon as possible!
Everyone was finally beginning to
forget that tragic incident 7 years ago
and now this...
What incident 7 years ago?
Oh, uh, nothing you
should be concerned about!
By the way, how does a fee of
1,000,000 yen sound to you?
One, one million...?!
1, uh just want this case to be solved
and things back to normal!
Well, I'll be counting on you!!
Alrighty! Let's start asking around!!
Then I'll be your guide...!!
Uh, excuse me
Did the victim, Mr. Okumura
always take the bus at that time?
Go away!!
Huh...?
I'd like to ask you a few questions...
Excuse me, I'd like to...
Of all the!
Hey! What's going on In this village?
Actually, there're :more villagers
against the proposal...!
And I guess
everyone's heard you're working
for the mayor who's on the other side...
that's why
Rats!
How can we find anything out!
Hey, Ran,
You and Conan go back to the inn!
I'm going to try a little longer!
Oh, don't wait for me at dinner!
I don't know what time I'll be back!!
Uh, officer!
Huh?
What is it, Conan?
What happened
in this village 7 years ago?
Oh, you're curious about what
Mayor Funaki said back there...
it was an accident...
a bus accident!
A bus accident?!
Did it involve that bonnet bus?
IUD...
we had it repaired
What caused the accident?
Did anyone get hurt,
was anyone killed?
It happened 7 years ago,
before I got transferred here,
sol don't know all the details...
but I heard about 2 people died...
Hmmm
What does that have to do with anything?
Oh nothing! I was just curious!
Hey Officer Shinkai!
Come on!
Yes sir!
Right away!!
The bus accident 7 years ago...
Mayor Funaki's suspicious behavior
and that huge fee,
something fishy is going on here...
Wow, everything looks delicious
I hope you like it
It's a meal using edible wild plants
Toko!
Miss Natsume!
Conan, what're you doing?
Toko.-are. ou home?
What is it, Conan?
There's something I want to ask you...
You shouldn't do that from here it's rude!
I'm sorry
It's all right.
What do you want to know?
It's about the bus accident 7 years ago...
I'm sorry, Conan.
I only came here to work 6 months ago...
I heard about the accident
but ll don't know much
I see...
But since we pass the spot
it happened every day,
I'm reminded of it...
it's the spot where the memorial tower is!
Oh, that place
That scary part of the cliff
I heard that 2 of the passengers were
drinking.and they started fighting,
that caused the bus to lose control
and they went over the cliff...
I'm terribly sorry!
My hands slipped...
I'll bring another right away...
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine
Toko, is something wrong?
Oh, it's nothing...
well, I've got to go and prepare dinner,
I'll see you later, Conan
Good grief! I don't believe this!
It's not only the con faction.!
Even the ones that agree with the mayor
won { cooperate!
Dad, keep your voice down,
other people will hear you
Humph!
Who cares!
Besides, this is neutral territory!
Why won't they cooperate?
According to Officer Shinkai,
although they support
tourism on the one hand,
the tourists leave their trash behind,
they destroy nature and
they stay up late making a racket...!
I They're giving
the villagers a pretty bad time!
Hmm,
gives us something to think about, huh?
Yeah,
but that won't help me do my job!!
It's not going to be easy if we
can't get any information...
Darn it all!
Eh?!
What the, dad...?
Are you in your case solving sleep mode?
What's this...?
He's just drunk and fell asleep...
Oh I knew that!
Conan!
Tell them to clear the table!
And tell them to lay out our bedding)too!
Hurry!!
Yes, ma'am!
Huh...?
It's the innkeeper.
Where's she going at this time
with those flowers?
Conan!
Good grief, where'd he go now...?
What's this?
Conan's shoes are gone!
Did he go outside...?
Oh...Forgive me...
forgive me...
It's Toko...!
What's going on?
I don't get it...
Conan, where are you?
Kagekuwa Shrine...
Would he come in here...?
Hey you!
What are you doing!!
Is that you!
Conan, is that you?
What are you doing out here?
1, I was just playing hide and seek...
Don't scare me like that
Did something happen around here?
Mr. Yabe was released
for lack of evidence
so I figured I should let Mr. Mouri know
Argh!!
That was Mayor Funaki's voice!!
Co, Conan!
Wh, what are you doing?
Eeek!!
Ran!!
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Kats: 8 Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
MaSatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi loka
Kan]: KaShlWabara
Kazimari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshr Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRE TOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikosh
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi-Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
O Gosho Aoyama / hog 'kukan
TV/TMS
All Rights Reserved
Stabbed once in the chest....!
Death was almost instantaneous!
You're under arrest! Give it up!!
What in the world
happened on this bus...
What was that?!
A killer is on the bus?
Th, this can't be happening!
The brakes-don't work!!.
Oh no!!