Just as flowing water has no form,
and the breeze is invisible,
deductions take all shapes and styles
In each and every case to be solved.
A quiet village is in an uproar.
Like the case,
the: bus is also out-of-control.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
Ran, Mr Mouri and I are being
rocked in a
nostalgic bonnet bus on our way
to Kagekuwa Village
to do some hiking.
But a murder takes place on
the bus we re on
The victim is
Deputy Mayor Okumura,
who is the leader of the group against
using the bonnet bus to promote
tourism because it is a vital means
of transportation for the villagers.
The police take Mr Yabe,
who is for promoting tourism,
Into custody and
things in the village begin to heat up.
To complicate matters,
a bus accident that happened
7 years ago is involved in some way.
While that murder remains unsolved,
Mayor Funaki,
who is also for tourism promotion,
is attacked on
the grounds of the shrine
and Ran IS also in danger.
==. 4&3;
THE 10th PASSENGER
PART II
Ran!
Conan?!
Are you all right? Are you hurt?
No, I'm fine, I just got ran into...
Never mind me,
I think there's somebody lying over there
Mayor Funaki!
Stabbed once in the chest!
Death was almost instantaneous!
Ran, did you see the killer?
I don't know if it was the Killer,
but I did see who rammed into...
What did the killer look like...?!
Any outstanding features?
How old, how tall?
Well, uh actually...
It was Mr. Yabe...
the leader of the Youth League
What?!
I don't believe it...!
What?! Mr Yabe killed the Mayor?!
No, I ss too early to tell...
Take me to his home!
Hidoshi Shinkai (28)
u can, w!» '\
I contacted the district station and
Hidoshi Shinkai (28)
LY O&EL Leh +
we'll have to wait until
one of their investigators arrives
Hidoshi Shinkai (28)
VOE&EL LA
1301 BE
Listen...!
Ran could have ended up like the Mayor!
Now take me to his home right now!!
Yes. okay...
Yabe Come out here!
Don't play games
Mr. Mouri! We don't have a warrant
Yabe! Come on on!!
Damn! He got away,
The evening paper's
still in the mail slot...
I don't think he came back here
That means he called
the Mayor out as soon as
he was released and killed him!
And now he's on the run...
he planned this...
Mr. Mourn!
Listen! Have road blocks set up!
Yes sir!
Huh?
A savings pass book...
There's 200,000 yen being deposited
every monthistarting 2 years ago...
But why is he using a bank
tha ¢s not even in the village...
wonder if this money's...
The next day, the search for Mr. Yabe
was about to start...
Well Mr. Private Detective, it looks like
we're after prey, huh
Humph!
I don't want to work with you but
we can't let a dangerous man like him
remain on the loose
so I'll join in the hunt
The villagers are
also joining the search...
but the tension between the 2 factions
was reaching its peak...
Did the killer count on the villagers
to:cause acommotion...
or was he planning something else?
In the first place though, is the killer
really Mr Yabe...?
If these murders were premeditated,
he d have taken his pass book!
There are other things
I don't understand...
The look of fear on the inn keeper's face
when she dropped the food!
And the reason she was crying in front
of the memorial tower...
And why was Toko watching her...!
I'm pretty sure all of this has
something to do with
the bus accident 7 years ago...!
Damn,
the 1,000,000 yen the Mayor promised
to pay me is poof gone .!
Yabe, you rat, I'm gonna catch you,
you can bet on it!!
Hello...
Why, Shinichi!
It seems you're involved in
a big case there
Yes, and I need you to look through
some articles from 7 years ago!
Sure,
I can access the newspaper company's
homepage for that information...
There he is! Over here!
Wait! You re not getting away!
I want my money!!
Let's see...
7 years' ago, 7 years ago...
Aha...this is it!
Bus accident! 2 are killed!
8 people are injured
Does it list the names of the deceased?
Yes, it's a local paper so
they've listed all the names'
First, the ones with minor injuries...
Arggh!!
I've got you Yabe...!
Don't fight it!
It wasn't me! I didn't do anything!!
Takuro Yabe (32)
You ran, that proves you're guilty!!
Takuro Yabe, you're under arrest
for suspicion of murder!
Wh, what did you say...?!
Deputy Mayor Okumura's name
wasn't on it?
No, I don't see that name on the list...
Then, maybe,
Deputy Mayor Okumura was Killed...
Here re the names of
the 2 men who were Killed...
Yoichi Tezuka, 28 years old and...
Kohei Moritsugu, 55 years old!
Doctor! I need you to locate the
relatives of those 2 men right away!
No! You're wrong!!
When I got to the shrine,
I heard the Mayor scream
so I ran over to see what happened,
that's when your daughter came...!
I knew that if I stayed there,
everyone would think I did it,
I got scared, and
when I tried to get away,
I bumped into your daughter
Don't lie!
Then tell us why you went there
in the first place!
The Mayor called me and
told me to meet him there
He called you?
Why would he want to meet you
at such an isolated place?
Well uh . it's...
Listen carefully...
you don't tell us anything and yet
you want us to believe you,
don't you think
that's asking a little too much?
Explain this.
It's a savings passbook we found
at your place...
200,000 yen is being deposited every
month for the past 2 years!
And you're using not the post office
savings or the Farmer's union...
you're using a bank that's not
In this village...
which means...
it's money you don't want anyone
in the village to know about, right...?
I was leaking information
Information...?
Were you a spy?
For the opposition?
IUD!
Deputy Mayor,
the man who died in the bus
was the leader of the opposition,
he was paying me
and I've been telling him
what Mayor Funaki
was planning and his schedule...
But why was it so important that
Mr Okumura went to so much trouble...?
If there was a new project in the works,
then the village funds would be paid
to companies Mr. Funaki favored
and naturally, the companies
the Deputy Mayor
and people in the opposing faction
were connected with would be excluded,
that's why they had to crush
the plans for the project before it started
The Mayor found out about it
and told you to meet
him at the shrine, is that right?
ICC...
It seems when I was being
questioned the first time,
he went into my home
and found the passbook
So that means you killed Mr Okumura
so that you wouldn't be caught
and then you killed Mr Funaki
because you were!
No, that's not it!! You're wrong!!
I didn't do it!!
Kinu Komai (42)
Ma'am, would you mind
explaining things to me?
Eh...?!
What if these murders
that are supposed to look like
it has to do with the fight between
the 2 opposing factions in the village,
Is really connected
to the bus accident 7 years ago?
The bus accident 7 years ago...?!
Th, that's impossible....!
If that's the case,
then Mr. Yabe's.innocent!
Because, on that day 7 years ago,
he was on that bus!
And Ms. Koma...
so were you!
What in the world happened ?
On that bus...?
All clear
Toko Natsume (25)
Mamoru Kajita (35)
LB JA {ES
That's the truth behind
that accident 7 years ago
I knew it...!
That's why Mayor Funaki was so afraid
the truth would come out,
he offered to pay Kogoro all that money
so he could control the situation!!
Hello, oh, Doctor...
I've located the relatives of the
2 bus accident victims!
It was on a follow-up article!
Yes...yes...
What was that?!
That person's...
I understand! Thank you!!
Ms. Koma!
If I want to take the bus
at the same time of the accident,
what time does it leave the station?
H...?1 If it's that bus, it's left already...
Oh no!!!
Ms. Komai, I'm counting, on you!
You've got to catch up with that bus!
I don't want that person
to kill anymore people!
Oh please, let us make it in time!!
Th. this cant be happening!!! .
The 'brakes-don't'work!!
Are you serious?!
1. I don't believe It!
That's ridiculous!
It's all downhill from here!!
Eh?!
Mr Yabe killed them?
Yeah, he's going to be transferred
to the main precinct this afternoon.
Does that mean your job's finished?
It sure Is.
Not only did I lose out on the money,
I had to work for no pay on top of that.
Good grief,
what a hiking trip this turned out to be!
Yes...
Oh my.
I just realized,
where did Conan go?
I see it! There it is!
Mr. Kajita, do something!! Engine brake!
I'm already doing that!
The wire's cut from the emergency brake!
The bus' brakes aren't working!!
Ms. Komai,
drive this car alongside the bus!!
Eh?! What're you going to do?
I'm going to get on the bus!
Don't do it, son!!
It's too dangerous! Don t do it!
Th, this is just like what
happened 7 years ago...
Th, that's right,
even the passengers are the same 4
That's impossible...
this is just coincidence, isn't it?
No! This is no coincidence!
Conan! When did you get on?
A certain person told me the story...!
7 years ago,
all of you were on this ven bus!
Even Mayor Funaki who was killed
and Mr. Yabe, who is suspected of
killing him, were on board...
a total of 10 passengers!
You all remember what happened,
don't you?
Ms. Komai, the proprietress: of
Komai Inn was the bus guide then...
Aw come on!
Come and drink with us!
Yoichi Tezuka (29)
Kinu Komai (35)
Somebody help me!
Yoichi Tezuka (29)
Kinu Komai (35)
Don't be so unfriendly!
Somebody stop him!
Help!
You! Stop that immediately!
She doesn't want to drink with you!
What'd you say?
I'm just trying to have some fun,
don't interrupt, shoo!
Arggh?!
The 2 people that died
in that accident were.
The man who was bothering Ms. Komai
and the man who tried to save her.
And miraculously,
the 8 villagers survived...
In the end, you all kept your silence!
And you made it appear the accident
was caused by the 2 men fighting....!
You people caused the
death of 1 brave man
and you hid your guilt
deep in your hearts...
After everything I've said,
you should have come to realize...
the 2 murders were committed by
a member of that brave man's family...
one of Mr. Moritsugu's children
the motive is revenge!
Isn't that right, Toko!!
Natsume is your mother's
maiden name, isn't it...
Your real name is Toko Moritsugu...!
Eh'! Toko's his...?
She s his daughter!!
What did you say?!
The killer is on the bus?
And who is it?
I don't know!But the-busyy
MB has no brakes-and it's.out of control!
Hey! Call the main precinct!
Yes sir!
Uh...and that little boy of yours
is also on the bus
Eh?! How did Conan get on the bus...?
Toko wantedfto know
how her father died
sosshe moved here
anddbegan investigating
then she found out the truth!
She probably heard it
from Mr. Kajita who
worked with her
and befriended her...
Ironically
one of the men she wanted
to take revenge on,
Mr. Yabe, was arrested
because he and the victim
were on opposing factions
in the village dispute...
Toko knew all of you would be
on this-bus today
going shopping
and running errands,
and meddled with the brakes
so you'd all be killed!
At the same spot 7 years ago...!
Isn't that right... Toko?
Sheesh, I, I don't believe it
I don't know what you're talking about...
No use pretending...
Why are you so calm then...?
Because you're about
to commit suicide, aren't you,
you're going to die along
with everyone else!
Good grief!
What a bothersome child!!! «
Get off of this bus Conan!
The bus will slow down
on the next curve,
if you're careful, you'll just
get a few bruises!!
So are you admitting I'm right?
You're behind all of this...!
Yes! I confess!
I killed both Deputy Mayor Okumura
and Mayor Funaki...!
When the bus was crowded, I put
the poison in Deputy Mayor's drink...!
I waited in the dark and stabbed
the Mayor on the shrine grounds...!
Ugh!
That's right!
I came here to get revenge
on the people who were on
this bus 7 years ago!
My father was a very righteous man!
He only did what was natural, when he
saw someone in trouble, he went to help!
But that day...
If even.one of you had backed him up.!!
Hurry! Conan, you've got to jump now
It's too late...
even if you let me go,
it still won't change the fact that
you killed the wrong person!
Eh...?
Deputy Mayor Okumura, théifirstivictim,
wasn't on this bus 7 years ago!
Wh, what did you say?! That can't be!
As the busfguide,
you've seen him everyday
so you know what he always says...
This has been my seat for 40 years!!
When someone. has continued to say that
and if you were to*askihim
about that incident 7 years.ago...
You did ask him about it,
didn't you...?
Of course, I asked him personally!!
7 years ago. .? No mistake,
I was sitting right here in my own seat!!
He was very clear about it!!
But on that day,
Deput. 'Mayor Okumura had-<afcold
and his fever was very high
so he was in bed!
His name:wasn't'in'the newspaper either!
You're lying...
I read the newspaper myself...
He was probably so convincing, you just
thought you saw his name listed
But, then...
who was the 10th passenger...?
That person died 2 years ago
from an illness...
So you see,
Deputy Mayor Okumura had
nothing to do with your father's death!
Th, that can't be...
You forgave Ms. Komai, didn't you?
she.
Oh...forgive me...
When I saw her like that...
just couldn't bring myselfito kill her...
She's not the only one,
I believe all the people
who were on that bus that day
have been carrying
a heavy burden in their hearts
Please forgive us, Toko!
We were cowards...!
Please accept our apologies!!
Oh...
If we crash at the same place
then maybe Toko:s; father will
forgive us and rest in peace...
No!!
Conan has nothing to do with this!
Do something!!
There's nothing I can do...
I may be able to make
the next curve but
there's no way I can make
the curve at the scene of the accident...
Don't give up!
There's bound to be
a way to stop this bus!
There s a ditch!
Get your tires into the ditch!!
Ugh!!
It's no use!
I can't keep the tires down!!
That's it! The suspenders
Doctor Agasa invented.
They're stretchable
and snap back to it's original length!
Oh no!
Rats! Maybe it won't hold a 10 ton bus!!
We've...stopped .
Phew...
Conan, who are you anyway...
I'm just a busy body private detective!
Thank you
my little private detective...
That's for making us worry!!
Ouch!!
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama.
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACK AROUND MUSIC
Kats 8 Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
MaSatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi loka
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazumari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRE TOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu HorikosH
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
OG'5sh0 Aoyama I§fiog 'kukan
Il Rights Reserved
The case us solved,
and the bonnet bus continues to run
carrying it's passengers and
the memories they keep inside.
Slowly, into the greenery...!
Chizuru...
who were you arguing with?
It can't be!
Here goes!
Oh no!!!
I hate to say this, but a lot of
time has passed since the victim died
No one has entered this room!
I'll testify to that!!
Why... l