Flowing water has no form.
The breeze is invisible.
No matter what the case maybe,
deductions are free to made.
Today's stage Is at
a hotel in the highlands.
A nas. customer
attracts an unwanted case.
He looks through
the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the brains of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan
Excuse me,
I'd like to go to Hotel Arimor...
Oh, cross this bridge
and go straight down the road.
Thank you very much.
Dad, how did find
a hotel in a place like this?!
This place is:well known for beer
that is distinct of this areal!
Pops is after liquor after all...
Oh, it's over there!
We've finally arrived!
THE BLACK WINGS OF ICARUS
PART I
Welcome!
I am Mourns,
and I have reservations here.
Mitsuyuki Arimori
#0 be
BRE JETT (32)
TFIVERA
You're Mr. Kogoro Mouri I believe
Mitsuyuki Arimori
#0 be
RIVERA
Mitsuyuki Arimori
#0 be
BHF Af (32)
TSI SEE AC
We've been expecting you.
I am Arimori, the manager here.
Mitsuyuki Arimorl
Ba HXTT (32)
'i ifilziiA
Yes nice to be here.
Please fill in this card.
Welcome!
Agh, you two are...
Inaho Shimogasa
Honanii Shimodasa
the ones that were involved
in the case of the cursed mask...
inaho Shimogasa
onami Shimogasa
Thank you so much
for all you did for us back then.
Inaho Shimogasa
Honami Shimogasa
What brings you here?
An acquaintance introduced them to us.
They were both
Iooking forward to seeing you too.
I hope there are no cursed things here...
I'm Shiromoto
and I have reservations here...
Welcome!
Mr. Shiromoto...
Mr. Hidehiko Shiromoto?
You have reservations for two?
Io...
Hidehiko Shiromoto
My wife and I.
I'm sure she'll be here in a minute...
Hidehiko Shiromoto
I don't know if it's some problem
that the producer has or what,
but, he has no right to tell me
to give my part up, just like that!
What? You're headed this way?
You don't have to come!!!
I tell you...!!
She's actress Chizuru Bizen.
Y. Yeah...
You, just what is the meaning of this?!
Huh?
I heard it was a nice place, and I'm
brought all the way out in the mountains!
Chizuru Bizen
It's a nice quiet place
I can't stand to think that I'm going to
have to spend 5 days together with you!
Front desk clerk!
Please give me a separate room!!
Oh, but, well...
You can give my wife the suite
that we reserved.
And, get me another room...
Yes, Sir...
Take care of my bags, will you!
They don't even have an elevator!!
She sure is different from what she
portrays to be on TV and in the movies...
U,Uh-huh...
Minaho and Honami!
Please show them-in's
Y,Yes sir!
This way, please!
Mr Mourn,
if it's all right with you, would you
Iike to rest a while in the restaurant?
The restaurant?
We can serve you
some cold herb tea if you'd like.
Wow, how nice!
Dad, let's drop in for a rest!
Oh, all night...
I'd prefer a shot to herb tea though,
guhee-hee-hee...
Wow, what a nice restaurant...!
Welcome!
Huh?
She is our chef
Shinobu Shimon
I am Shinobu Shimon.
Welcome to our restaurant!
Shinobu Shimon
S "Ydesigmned:everythingifrom
the layout to interior of this restaurant.
Wow!
It is my wish that our guests
enjoy their meal in a relaxed atmosphere,
with dishes made of ingredients
that are unique of this district.
Boy, I just can't wait for dinner time.
I hear that you ve got some
really"good local beer here...?
Of course,
we've got that ready for you too.
Shinobu, please serve
our guests some herb tea.
Yes, sir.
Oh, I'd like to taste
some of that local beer
Wait till night time!
Puhaa, this sure is good!!
Dad, why don't you stop drinking
and eat something?
This soup is really good.
I've never tasted such lousy soup!!
What?
And, you claim to be a chef?!
Cut it out, Chizuru.
You stay out of this!
Uh, would you please tell me
what you don't like about the soup?
A guest is saying it tastes terrible!
Can't you at least apologize?!
I am very sorry OI'll bring our}
a new bowl of soup of soup immediately.
RShinobu!!
Mr. Arimori...?!
That's what you should've
«done in.the*first*place!wr
I heard from my husband that you are
the renown detective Mr. Kogoro Mourn.
It's an honor to meet you all.
1.1, 1 am the one who is honored!
I'm always looking forward to
your great capacity of: solving cases.
Oh?!
Wow.
I am Chizuru's husband, Shiromoto.
Huh?!
Since I'm here on an inspection tour
of the development of Leisure Land,
we've decided to spend
a holiday here while we're at it.
O, Oh, so you're a business man!
So, the rumor about
the development was true after all...
Huh?
There are unusual butterflies
inhabiting this highland area,
as well as alpine plants.
What are your plans
on the preservation of all these things?
Ah, as to that we are planning to
have a discussion
with the local people here, in time...
Heck with the locals!
There are people who are all worked up
about preserving nature
and all that anywhere!
It's about cash, plain cash.
What a thing to say, Chizuru...
Oh, did I say something upsetting?
I'll divorce you
any time if you want me to...
But, I wonder if you can pay me
alimony in your state of affairs right now?
Chizuru!!
Ugh!! 7
Chizuru, please, just this time,
please forget about the part, please!!
You're still talking nonsense like that?!
For what reason, in the first place?!
Uh, well, Chizuru,
I can't talk about that...not here...
Il can't talk about that... . not here...
Kota Miyabe
Never mind, just tell me!!
The sponsor doesn't want you.
They want somebody who's younger.
Rather, they want to use Reika,
who debuted last year, since
her popularity is on the
They say they won't
dish out the cash otherwise...
Reika belongs to our production too, so...
If this movie goes down the drain
we'll be thrown into hot water.
Please try to understand, Chizuru!
W What! What's with
that look on your face!!
I'll bet you'll all wishing that I were gone!!
Okay, I'll die just like you want me to!!
Chizuru!!
I tell you...
Well, don't let it bother you too much...
Um, is this you, Mr. Arimon?
Huh?!
Huh?
See, that picture...
Mr. Arimoiii is in the middle and
the one to-the very right is Shinobu, right?
Yes, that's right.
We've been doing
hand-gliding together from
Hand-gliding?
We used to be able to hand-glide in the
highlands at the
peak of a mountain before.
We can't do so anymore because of all the
developments that have been going on...
Oh, that's too bad.
I used to do it too when I was young.
Who is the man that is standing
to the left of you, Mr. Arimori?
O, Oh, that's my younger brother.
We used to fly a lot together in the past...
We haven't flown for 5 years already...
The hand-gliders are left stored
in the storage on the roof...
Conan, let's goy
to the highlands tomorrow!
It's just perfect for the sketch
you have to do for your homework.
Okay!
Pops is snoring so loud
that I cant sleep...
I'm going to go buy some juice...
1, I can't reach the slot...
I've had enough!
What on earth did I do anyway.
I have nothing to do with it!!
I wonder why...
Chizuru's so angry...?
Next Morning 9am
J! (535
4g19:00
Mr. Shiromoto...
How is Chizuru?
I'm sorry about what happened last night.
She always like that
so please don't let it bother you.
I'm sure that she'll soon...
Uh Chizuru...
It 'JEGKSHJ
Oh well, I mean...
Hey, lady, you know last night
Ugh!!!
How-rude to-address her like that!
Please don't let his remark bother you...
Oh, no...
Daaaah...what am I supposed to do!
Its impossible to convince her now.
What do you say we go fishing together
while we wait for her to cool off?
My work schedule starts from tomorrow,
so I was planning to
spend the whole day fishing today.
I'll lend you a fishing pole
if you need one too.
Yes, I'd like to go with you.
Dad, let's go to the highlands
at the top of the mountain!
You guys go on by yourselves!
I've got an important mission to carry out!
A mission?
First, I've got to watch Yoko Okino's
new release promotion video.
Then,
I'm going to watch her concert video
which I got a hold of by a top secret method.
Furthermore,
I've got to watch the rerun
of Yoko s drama special!
Dad, what on earth
did you come all the way here for!
The rerun is broadcasting
only in this district!
So, you came all the way
here to watch it...
If you don't mind, would you
Iike me to show you up the mountain?
Huh?
That would be a great help!
Oh, that's right, why don't you
go along with them, too, Shinobu?
Huh?
Ill Keep watch over the hotel!
Oh, but I have to get
everyone's meal ready so...
As for lunch, all you have to do is
Ieave us some box lunches or something!
We're going out too,
so box lunch'll be fine.
But, Izstill have to get dinner ready...
Why don't you have barbecue
out in the yard then?
That'll save you
the trouble of preparation, won t it?
Since my wife gave you
a bad time last night,
why don t you go out today
for a change and enjoy.
We can handle preparations
for the barbecue for you.
We aren 'tiexpecting any guests today,
so why don't we
accept their kindness and go?
Go ahead gofahead!
Okay, thank you so much.
It'll only take about 15 minutes
to the lake by car. Do you know the way?
10:00 AM.
a110:00
brawl! D
toes
Yes thank you.
10:00 AM.
Fa 10:00
LreolEdD
You'll get better catch
after sundown there.
Okay, we'll take our time
and enjoy. fishing till night then...
Bye!
I'll follow from behind using the van
after I check if all the doors are locked,
SO you go on ahead.
Please hurry, okay.
Sure!
I'm sure that Chizuru
will start feeling better
if she came out with us
instead of staying locked up...
Mission number 1!
Watch Yoko's
new release promotion video
and master her-new song completely!
Mr. Mourn.
Y, Yes!
These are the master keys.
I'll leave them to you
Sure thing!
I tell you, really, dad's hopeless!
Mr. Arimori's not here yet?
Huh?
Oh, there he is
10:50 AM.
at the highlands
10:50 AM
OSTA ESSRS
BEEN
The wind sure feels good...
Wow!
How wonderful!!
Fantastic!!
Whaaa!!
Wow!
The real color of the sky is
a clear blue like this one, I see...!
Now we know...!
I feel like I could fly
to the sun if I had wings
You talk like you were Icarus don't you?
Icarus...?
He appears in,Greek Mythology.
Icarus, who had wings...
He forgot his father's warning telling him
to keep from going to high,
and flew high,
believing that he could fly to the sun...
However, since Icarus had flown
too close to the sun,
his wings could not tolerate the heat...
And, Icarus, whose-wings were burned,
went falling straight. down to thésground...
A sad story...
Kyah!
Wow,
how cute!
Oh, it's called Miyama White Butterfly and
Iives only up here in the highlands here.
Oh the butterfly. .!
This butterfly cannot live
unless the water is clean...
Yoko!!
Yokooo!!!
Love you! Love you!
12.30 PM.
at hotel lobby
nWJoJ)vuiac -
Love you! Love you!
12:30 P.M.
at hotel lobby
Yay!!
12:30 P.M
at hotel lobby
FIvOoE
12:30 P.M.
at hotel lobby
JIN JUVE
I absentmindedly forgot my lunch.
Is Chizuru still in her room?
Yes, she hasn't come down since.
I guess I'll go check on her...
t the lakeside
I wonder if...
Chizuru's in a better mood by now...
1:30 P.M.
at hotel lobby
F%1:30
R)Lae
Oh, how's your wife doing?
1:30 PM.
At hotel lobby
SjiCO
Oh, how's your wife doing?
It seems that she's asleep
because she won't answer the door
In spite of me knocking.
It's not easy having a wife
who's strong willed, is it?
You can say that again...
I'm going back fishing.
Enjoy
There!
1:50PM.
At'th shighlands
There!!
Whaaa!
Line out!! It's Conan's win!!
What do you say,
it's about time we have lunch?
My, it's already this time of day...
I'll go get our lunches.
ASP WM.
at:the lake
Wow, this is a big one!
AS PM.
at the lake
{£2115
15 P.M.
at the lake
We've got a big catch today!
Yes, very true!
Agh!!
2.25PM
at hotel lobby
TILOe
2:25 PM.
at hotel lobby
TT SAL 3
No, Yoko!
2:25 PM.
at hotel lobby
T>ilbOe
Don t go that way!!!
2:25 PP M.
At hotel lobby
F&£2:25
'FF-Junk:
How beautiful...
Really...
Tithe view of the sunset
from here is always beautiful...
alla A442
ww FCC -- .
The building that is lighted up at the
foot of the mountain is Hotel Arimori.
Wow...it's so far below...!
So, shall we start heading back...
6:05 P.M.
#6095
EF TAD LL
"Fl-HIE
What's the matter?
The engine seems to be in bad shape.
You can go on ahead.
Okay.
7:00 P.M.
at the hotel
We're back!
7:00 P.M.
at the hotel
7:00 P.M
11TH:
You should've come with us, dad.
The sunset was beautiful!
We saw a rare butterfly too!
One that is said to
never to come near people...
But, that butterfly stopped
on Mr. Arimori's shoulder!
Oh, yeah, okay okay!
Hi, there.
Big catch we have here!
Welcome back.
How ls Chizuru doing?
Come to think of it,
she hasn't come down at all...
Not at all...?
What a nuisance...
Mr. Mouri, could I have the master key?
Oh yes, yes, sure.
Thank you...
Here go the catch for today
I'll leave the rest up to you two.
Yes, Hotel Arimorl.
Here go, the catch for today.
I'll leave the rest up to you two.
Yes, Hotel Arimorl.
Oh, Mr. Arimorl.
I can't get my car started.
I hate to trouble you,
but could I have you come pick me up?
Okay.
I will go with you, just in case!
I'm very sorry, Ran.
Mr. Mourn!
Chizuru doesn't look well!
What?!
I opened the door of her room
with the key, but the door guard is set,
and she won't answer no matter
how much I call out to her!
Oh no!
Chizuru! Chizuru!
Let's break the door open!
Y. Yes, sir...!
There!
Agh MI.
Ugh!
Aaagh!!
7:20 P.M.
Aaagh!! Chizuru!!
Chizuru!!
MM. Mr. Mouri, how is she...?!
I'm sorry to say that it's been a while
since she's passed away...
It can't be...?!
Kugh...!
Hmm...?
The metal part of the door guard...
cratches...
on't tell me that...?!
Just as I thought...!!
Chizuru...
did not commit suicide...
She was killed by someone!
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY:
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Kats: 8 Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS BY
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hirot hi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRE TOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terunitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodam 2
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
OGfisho Aoyama I» hogdkukan
Il Riflhts Reserved
Look!
There are strange looking scratches here!
Scratches?
You mean the metal part
of the door guard...
The air conditioner...!
When the corpse was found
the air conditioner wasn't running!!
D.Don't"t tell me that Chizuru...
You mean she was killed...?
The murderer is among us...?!
IUD...
the murderer is...