Just as flowing water has no form.
And the breeze is invisible.
Deductions take all shapes and styles,
in each and every case to be solved
Today, the case is solved.
A most unexpected killer,
unexpected motive and unexpected trick.
He sees through
the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
We took a.summer trip
and arrived at Hotel Arimori,
Iocated in the mountains of Nagano
We ran into business man
Mr. Hidehiko Shiromoto and
his wife, actress Chizuru Bizen there.
The following day, Ran, Mr. Arimori
and Shinobu went to the highlands;
while Mr. Shiromoto and Mr Miyabe
went out fishing to the lake
Night falls, and since Chizuru
had not come out of her room at all,
we went to her room to check on her...
Chizuru didn't commit suicide...
She was killed by someone....!!
THE BLACK WINGS OF ICARUS
8:00 P.M.
At the highlands
At the hi hlands
F#8:00
CITA
Mr. Arimori
Mr. Arimon?
Where are you?
Over here!
Huh?
Mitshiko Arimori
DD #0 ke
I was absorbed in watching the stars,
since they're so beautiful...
Mitshiko Arimori
&O be
Oh...come on Mr. Arimorl...
Hello? Oh, Minaho...
WwW What?!
All right, okay,
I'll head back right away.
What's up?
Chizuru passed away
What?!
I'll just leave the van here.
Let's hurry back to the hotel.
QOkay!
8:20 P.M.
at the hotel
The victim is Chizuru Bizen,
an actress, 30 years old.
She was staying at this hotel together
with her husband Mr. Hidehiko Shiromoto.
Hmm and what is
the estimated time of death...?
Oh, the estimated time of death is
between 1:30pm to 2:30pm.
The cause of death seems to be
suffocation by strangulation of the neck.
You said that when
the corpse was found
the door was locked
using the door guard?
Yes, and we had no choice
but to break the door open...
The window was also locked from
the inside, so I'm sure it was suicide.
But, isn't Chizuru Bizen
a famous actress?
Did she have any
reason for committing suicide?
Well, to tell you the truth,
there was some hassle last night...
A hassle?
She was laid off from the part in a movie
that she was supposed to star in...
She seemed to be really shocked
I see...
Hey, you!
You can't o in there!
Oh8but...!
That kid not again...!
You just-keep still, understand!?
But, there are strange scratches here!
Scratches...?
That's the part that the metal part
of the door guard used to be...
There are strange scratches
on the metal on the floorpart too.
These scratches could've been made
when someone tried to create
a locked room from the outside!!
What...?! What do you mean?
In other words,
after the killer locked the window,
he probably used the screw driver
to remove the door guard from the wall.
Then he went out to
the corridor from the door,
which after he hooked
the metal part of the door guard on,
inserted his hand through
the space between the door
and put the screw back on
But, since
trying to screw the screw back on from
such a narrow space was too difficult,
the killer inadvertently
Ieft scratches in the vicinity.
The metal part probably
fell off in one blow at the door
because the screw wasn {
screwed on tightly enough.
Um, Chizuru moved this table from
the window and climbed on it, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Then...
Ugh!
Don't bother the officer!
Um, are there foot prints
on the soles of the legs too?
Of course!
Why don't you check your feet...!
Oh, wait! Chizuru had no shoes...
Barefoot!!
Were Chizuru's footprints on the table?!
Uh, no!!
What?! Which means that...
Someone carried Chizuru up
and hung her...
Which means that
this is homicide, not suicide...
Last night, Chizuru was arguing
with someone in the restaurant...
Darn, if only I had confirmed
who it was back then...
I wonder if there is no other evidence...
What's this...?
There's some white...and powdery...
Geez...this room sure IS hot...
The air conditioner!
It wasn't running
since we found the corpse...
Did the killer turn it off...?
I would like to ask you a few questions
about the victim, Chizuru Bizen
First of all, Mr. Shiromoto.
Yes...?
We hear you were on bad terms
regarding a divorce thatiwas pending...?
Hidehiko Shiromoto
iE St TE E= (46)
the alimony she demanded
was such a huge sum so...
Hidehiko Shiromoto
1, oe - 4
HL jiOI \HU)
Hmm...
Next, Mr. Miyabe,
I hear you wanted her to drop the star role
she was originally supposed to play?
I'm not the one who dropped her.
Kota Miyabe
I had no choice because
that's what the sponsor wanted...
Kota Miyabe
I see...
Now, I'd like to ask all of you
It is estimated that Chizuru died
between the hours of 1:30pm to 2:30pm.
I would like\to know what
you were doing during that time.
Just what do you mean?
It's as if you're checking on our alibis...
D.Don't tell me that Chizuru was...
Judging from
the circumstances at.the.scene
it is highly probable
that this is a homicide case.
N.No II
I hear that both
Mr. Shiromoto and Mr. Miyabe
went to the lake
together to go fishing?
Yes yes, yes!
I left the hotel
at 10am in the morning
and was at the lake right through
until we returned at 7:00pm!
You too, Mr. Shiromoto...?
No, I forgotimy lunch...
so I went back to the hotel once
around 12:30 noon.
I had lunch with Mr. Mourns
and left the hotel at 1:30pm.
Did you see Chizuru then?
I went to check on her as soon as
I-got back to the hotel, but...
since she didn't answer the door
when If knocked, l.returned .to thé. lobby...
Which means that Mr. Miyabe,
you were all alone
while Mr. Shiromoto
was back here at the hotel?
Y. Yes of course...
I was eating lunch at the lakeside!
How: aboutyyou two?
Mr. Arimori and Shinobu?
We went with Conan and Ran to
the highlands at the top of the mountain.
We. left right after
Mr. Shiromoto and Mr. Miyabe left,
and arrived at the highlands
around 11.00am.
We were there all through
and started down at around 6:00pm.
We got back to the hotel around 7:00pm.
I hear only you, Mr. Arimoril,
remained at the highlands?
The engine of my van
wasn't functioning too well...
When you went to pick him up,
was Mr. Animori there?
Of course!
I was with her,
so there's no doubt about it.
How about you two,
Minaho and Honami?
We were cleaning the hotel
in the morning.
Since Mr. Shiromoto came back and
started eating lunch with Mr. Mourn,
we served them tea
and went to have lunch in the office.
After seeing Mr. Shiromoto off at 130pm,
we watched TV till 4.00pm
After that, we were in the kitchen
making preparations
for dinner until everyone returned
When you did the cleaning,
what did you do about Chizuru's room?
The manager had told us
not to disturb her sow...
we didn't go near her room.
Were you at the hotel
right through, Mr. Moun?
Yes, I was watching TV
in the lobby right through.
After Mr Jomoto went to check on
her at around 12:30 noon...
nobody used the stairs by the lobby.
Which means,
the killer must've entered the hotel
from the emergency exit.
Please describe the emergency exit.
There are emergency exits
at the end of the corridor on every floor.
The doors are auto-lockable,
but can be opened freely from the inside
In order to come in from outside,
you need to use
the master key to open the door.
WwW Which means
the killer as a personnel of the hotel!
No, because I had
the master key with me...
They, probably.had. made
a 'spare key"beforehand.
If so, the killers are...
those two!
Huh?!
We haven't done anything!!
Those two were watching TV
with me from 1:30pm to 4:00pm!
If so, then all three of you
are in this together!
Don't be ridiculous!
Either I, who couldn't get a hold
of the master key, am not the killer...
There is a way
to come in through the emergency exit
even without the master key...
No, there is a way
to come in through the emergency exit
even without the master key...
What?!
Huh?
For instance, Mr. Shiromoto, when you
went to check on Chizuru at 12:30pm...
the door can be opened
from the inside.
Then stick a pebble or something between
the door so that it won't close completely.
After making it look like
you returned to the lakeside,
you actually entered the hotel from
the emergency exit and killed Chizuru...
N.No...
He's pretty good...
As for Miyabe
if Mr. Shiromoto were his accomplice,
carrying out the murder
would've been possible.
What a thing to say, officer!
If you returned to the hotel
hidden in Mr. Shiromoto's car,
and went into the hotel from the door
that he had left opened...
That is enough!
You're treating us
as if we were the killers.
Uh, well, I don't mean...
What about you people?!
Just what do you mean?
There is a possibility that you people
have spares to the master keys...
You could've secretly come
down:from the mountain
Please don't say such silly things!
In order to return to this hotel
from the highlands and the lake...
it is necessary to cross the bridge over
the Tani River, that is under construction.
IV confirmed with
the workers there a while ago,
and was told that the only car
that crossed that bridge
in the afternoon
was Mr. Shiromoto's car.
In other words,
the people who were capable of
committing the crime are...
Mr. Shiromoto,
Mr:-Miyabe,
Minaho and Honami,
and you, Mr. Mouri.
Me too?!
It's exactly as Officer Mito says but...
Something's not right...
For instance...
The air conditioner that wasn't running...
The white powder
that was on Chizuru's skirt...
What on earth was it...
I see, maybe
This is similar to a runway...
What's that...?!
It looks like a mark that was made
by rope rubbing against the wall...
Officer.
Mr. Mouri told asked me to...
What...?
So, 1d like you all, Mr. Shiromoto,
Mr. Miyabe, Minaho, Honami,
and Mr. Mouri to come to the station
with me for more detailed questioning...
You, just who do you think
I am anyway?!
Ugh!
Siege : is overtaking mice.
What's the:matter; Mr:Mouri?!
Please wait! It's the beginning
of the Sleeping Kogoro!
What...?! So this is the rumored...!!
Please leave the rest up to me!
You mean you know who the killer is?
Yes! I know who the killer is,
as well as the trick that was used!
I he tric 7
The killer has wings
Magic wings which
makes what seems to be impossible
possible...!
Yes .the killer is
% oul!
Yes, the killer is you,
Mr. Mitsuhiko Arimoni!!
WwW .,What are you talking about?!
I was with Ran and the others up
in the highlands right through, you know?
That's right!
Mr. Arimori could never be the killer!
That's why I just said that
Mr. Arimori has magic wings...
What do you mean by magic wings...?
Hmm?
What was that...
That's the magic wings.
This was in the store room on the roof.
It's a hang-glider.
What?!
And, there were marks
of the wall of the roof being rubbed
against by a rope or something
right above the victim's room.
I see...!
Mr. Arimori used that hand-glider and...
flew from the highlands to the hotel,
then landed on the roof:
He went down to the veranda
of Chizuru's room using a rope.
After killing her,
he flew back to the highlands
with his hand glider...
That's impossible...
the only time I was away
from everybody is when
I went back to the car to get the lunches,
which took me only 4 to 5 minutes...
It would take at least 15 minutes
only to set the hand-glider up too...
Besides, judging from
the direction of the wind and the height,
I think it'd be impossible to go from
the hotel back to the highlands
Mr. Mourn...
It is indeed as you all say.
But, if only to strangle Chizuru,
4 to 5 minutes would be enough,
If she were near him!
What?!
W., What are you talking about?!
Chizuru was back at the hotel...
I get it!
The van!
Right.
Before leaving, Mr Arimori said he was
going to check if the doors were locked...
and let Shinobu and the others
go on ahead of him
He then, went over to Chizuru's room,
passed her out
with a stun gun or something,
Ioaded her into the car
with the hand glider
and headed off for the highlands.
Officer Mito,
when you went to check the room,
did you realize that
the air conditioner wasn't running?
Yes.
What you're saying is that Chizuru
was not in her room since before noon?
Exactly.
And at about 2:00pm,
after telling everybody that he was
going to getthe lunches, he left them,
hung Chizuru,
who was passed out in the van,
with a rope and killed her.
He stayed back at the highlands alone
saying that his van
wasn't functioning right.
He then assembled the hand-glider,
carried Chizuru on his back
and flew off the highlands.
The roof is brightly lit so
I don't think he had
any problem getting to his destination
After you landed on the roof
you went down using a rope,
into the room from the window
that you had left opened beforehand,
and hung the corpse.
After rigging the door guard
and closing the door,
You left the hotel
from the emergency exit...
Ridiculous!
So, how did I get back
to the highlands after that?!
Right! When Ran and I got to
the highlands Mr. Arimori was there!
Maybe he used
a motorbike or something?
The workers at the bridge
would see him, wouldn't they?
If he were to have flown off
from this hotel which is at a low position,
it wouldn't been impossible for him
to get back to the top of the! mountain!
That's why I've been telling you,
Mr. Arimori used magic
Magic that would
enable him to get back
to the highlands
without anyone noticing him!
Not your incomprehensible
+ remark again...
The seed of magic is your car, Shinobu.
What?!
Mr Arimori
who asked you to come to
the highlands for him on his cell phone,
hid in the trunk of your car!
Without, realizing it,
Shinobu was used
as a means of
transportation for Mr. Arimor.
When the car arrived in the highlands,
Mr. Arimori waited for Shinobu and Ran
to walk away from the car,
and snuck out of the trunk.
Then he appeared before the two ladies
as if he had always been there...
Mr. Arimorl...
That's...
That's no more
than plain assumption!
Do you have any proof?!
Yes... Yes, that's right All right.
Mr. Mouri the inspection officers
have informed us
the powder that was
on the victim's skirt
was the scale
of the Miyama White Butterfly!
So, there it is
It has been verified that the scales
of the Miyama White Butterfly
that exits only in the vicinity
of the top of the mountains,
was found on the skirt of the victim,
who had not set a foot out of her room.
According to Ran,
the butterfly stopped on
Mr. Arimori's shoulder and died, right...
The scales probably rubbed off
on his shirt at that time.
Unaware, the scale
rubbed off on Chizuru's skirt
when he carried her on his shoulder.
Why did you kill her?
To avenge my brother's death...
What?!
Revenge. .?
When my younger brother Teruhiko
was going to a university in Tokyo,
he met Chizuru who was just
starting her career as an actress...
Teruhiko instantly
fell in love with beautiful Chizuru...
To Chizuru...it may just
have been a playful love affair...
Rather, she was after
his money to begin with...
She needed a huge amount of cash
to get herself started...
Having acted in a drama,
she eventually started becoming popular.
That's when she started
staying away from Teruhiko.
In order to keep Chizuru
from parting from him any further,
he began spending
more and more money on her...
He even went as far as
to use this hotel, that was
the estate our father left us as collateral
for a mortgage without telling me...
What? Which means that this hotel is...?
Someone else owns it now.
I'm working here as manager
thanks to the owner's kindness...
And, what is your brother doing now...?
Teruhiko who was crushed with grief,
recklessly maneuvered
the hand-glider and...
My younger brother got too close
to the sun named Chizuru,
burned his wings and fell to his death.
He ls the wretched Icarus...
You did it because
of a grudge you had against her?
I invited Chizuru out
to the restaurant last night...
I just wanted hero say
one word of apology to my brother.
However...
I don't remember a thing!
What's with this picture!
How should I know who he is!
I am your ex boyfriend,
Teruhiko Arimorfs, older brother.
My brother died In grief...
W., What are you getting at?!
I went with him only because
he was really persistent!
He fell in love of his own choice
and died of his own choice!
It is not my intention
to blame you for anything at this point
My only wish is that
you visit my brother's grave
and say a word of apology to him!
Cut it out, won't you!
What did I do?!
It is none of my business!
That is when...
I decided to kill Chizuru...
I wonder if your younger brother
Isthappy about this?
Butterflies are said
to be the soul of the dead.
To me, it looks as though your
younger brother's soul tried to stop you,
and stopped
to rest on your shoulder...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
MiSatomo Sudo
STORY DITOR
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure *
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshr Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRE TOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi-Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR:
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
O Gosho Aoyama 7 hogakukan
I! Rights Reserved
Dad sure is late...
- I wonder where he's buying the stuff...
Over there...
Huh?
Hey girlie let's have tea together!
Hey, there cutie-pie!
Daaaaadd!!
Yikes!!
Huh?
This Icarus sure Is helpless...
Because of the
mysterious name that the officer
who was run over kept repeating
towards the hit-and-run criminal,
this case was named
the Shushiro case.
A grand investigation network
that had never been seen in the past
was carried out but...
Because the officer who
was thought to have the case...
had died...
the case stayed as Is .
And, 3 years ago the case expired...