Be strong I say to my heart
And step into the essence
with strong rhythm
Officers always busy at work
Take time out between cases for love
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with
the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan
uh, fuh. fun...
There, that's a good boy...grow...
grow huger...
and leave the claws of flames behind...
Just once more, just once
more and the eve will be over...
Hmm?!
This rotten town will be lighted.up:.
Th crimson flames...
And the beautiful carnival shall begin...
ee, hee, hee...
Ayumi?
What are you doing?
H, mother...
me on, let's go home...
Okay!
TA AA
Love Story At Headquarters-Ill
PART I
Metropolitan Police Department
I see...
And how did the eyes of the man
he had eyes like a fox
It was like this!!
His eyes were-slanted...
ybe...
He looked like this?
His is completely different...
Oh. - really?!
You re not a very goodz:drawer,
are you...
That's no better than a child's doodling...
Isn't there anyone
who can draw better...?
It can't be helped
because Mr. Tomogawa,
the onein charge is out sick!!
Whaaa...
Excuse me...
But... Ms. Sato.
Yes?
We can't pass this sketch
around to the investigation officers,
I don't think...
Well,
I guess it does have a sort of
Interesting touch to it, however...
Oh=~.so what, are you two going to
sketch for me instead?!
Uh, well, I don't thinks so, I can't draw...
I only draw abstract...
Agh, Inspector Shiraton!!
Dirty rat!
Agh! Besides, we're not really sure if the
man she saw is really the arsonist yet...
What?! Are you saying that Ayumi is lying?
Don't take us lightly because we're kids!
But, it's not like you saw
the guy actually cause the fire, is it?
No doubt about it!
Huh?!
He was wearing a leather jacket
despite this hot weather.
He had gloves on
and his pants smelled of kerosene
as he loitered around the back alley
fire took place,
and was grinning.
It would be more difficult not to suspect
him of being the arsonist.
Well...?1
t's right, isn't it, Ayumi...
All right...
Let's head off to that back alley,
and check the place out!
You're going to check the site
I'll go with you.
Et me take you in my car...
Okay...
but I have to stop over some place first...
It's on the way to the site, anyway...
What?!
Today is a special day for me...
A special day...?!
Your birthday or something?
No...
he opposite...
The opposite?!
I wonder where's sheis stopping over...?
A special day...
Oh I see, now I remember...
Today is...Police Commissioner,
Her father's memorial...
The day that he died on duty...
Oh? It is?
Eah...
It was exactly 18 years ago today...
When he was going after a robber...
this intersection...
At this intersection?
Yes, he was run over by a truck
this intersection...
Unfortunately,
it was raining hard that day
so the ambulance arrived late...
Inspector Megure told me that the
Commissioner died in the ambulance
that Ms Sato rode along in
with his family watching over him...
If I remember correctly...
the name of the case was...
hushiro...
What?!
Right!
Hushiro!! Shushiro...
The officer who was run over
by the truck...
repeated that name over and over
towards the person
hat fled from the scene...
Because of this mysterious name...
this case was name The Shushiro Case,
and an all out investigation network
that saw no precedent was set up...
However, since the officer
who was thought to have the key
to the case passed away...
the case remained stagnant...
And expired 3 years ago.
That's what Pops told me!
Yeah...I've seen that case repeatedly
Nn TV sol know about it too...
Oooh, that was close, real close...
It was a crime
that was carefully thought out
that the only clue was the 10 second
image of the robber
on the surveillance monitor of the bank
that was robbed...
Nobody even knows
how thelofficer who died
duty was able to specify the criminal
The case was thrown into oblivion
and is still unsolved...
But...
I had no idea that the officer back then
as Ms. Sato's father...
It can't be helped...
Although the name of the case...
And the name of the criminal remain
in the minds of people...
Nobody except police personnel...
could ever be expected to member
the name of the officer
who died on duty In the case...
Ms. Sato...
Well, after all we're not doing our job
because we want to be remembered so...
But...
maybe the driver-of the truck saw
who the robber was?
The robber was wearing a long raincoat,
but we don't-even know
If the person was a man or woman.
Even in the picture taken by the
surveillance camera the robber was
wearing a cap, sunglasses...
a mask and coat...
But, the name of the criminal was know,
wasn't it?
That was Shushiro?
There was nobody by that name
that was capable
committing the crime...
Well...l guess that
case was bound to go unsolved...
Because all the police had to
go on were three clues...
The picture left on
the surveillance camera,
the fact that a raincoat was
worn and the name Shushiro.
There were four!!
The fourth clue was written in
my father's police l.D. memo book,
three mysterious letters written in
atakana...
KA-N-O'...
KA-N-O?
Hat's a first...
The police seemed to have kept
It from being disclosed...
It was deduced that the word was deeply
involved with the case,
so my mother and I were
repeatedly asked,
Did you ever hear
Masayoshi say this word?
And?
I've never even heard him say it
and besides,
I don't have any idea
what it means either...
When I was a child I used to...
glare at the three letters,
and always thought...
that if anyone ever appears
and nabs Shushiro
I would grant that person's every wish!
Huh?
Grant every...
VVIOoltl...
If I find out will you treat me to
a thousand eel over rice bowls?
Yes, of course!
I d llke 10...
Iive in the castle at Tropical Land...
I'd like a boarding pass
to the International Space Station...
I'd like a brand name bag...
C,Could I have the ticket to
the next World Cup Soccer game?
IF VCO...
OCT...
how frightening, they're so realistic,
hmm. [J
What if the matter with you two...?
Hmm &
Oh, flowers...
Huh?
Aah...
It's been a long time
since I've seen you last!
Oh Is it you Miwako?
You've really grown to be
a nice woman...
Do you know each other?
Yes...
he used to be on the same high school
baseball team as my father!
He is ace Mr. Hidero Saruwatari who
had was a batteryteam with my father!
Saruwatari
5 BA (50)
How do you do......?
Saruwatari
5 BA (50)
He is Mr. Shuji Kano, who was known for
his strong arm and swift legs...
He used to be the team's reliable
main batter... Mr. Mitsuo Inomata.
Mitsuo Inomata
Fr ES
Mk ( BE \JU)
SAPS nLite Less
AL NMR ZR Td The IX
Mitsuo Inomata
E& (50)
SABI RILe Lead
MET Hm
Ha, ha, ha...
Mitsuo Inomata
BE TH GO
AD OL Le LeoBad
BEN am
And, she is the beautiful,
Mrs. Choko Kandor,
who used to be their manager...
Oh come on
I'm a 50 year old middle
aged lady already...!
What brings you all here today?
Ome time
since we've all seen each other,
so we've decided to
get together for a drink...
But, before we go,
we came to say hello to
Sato who used be
the captain of our team...
Oh, I see...
He sulks if we don't ask him
to come along too...
We re going to the pub
hat we always go to,
We're going to the pub
Yes...Shiratori here...
So why don't you pop by too, Miwako...?
So why don t you pop by too, Miwako...?
Oh, Inspector Megure...
Huh? Now?
We are at 4-chome Haido-cho... :
Huh?!
A suspicious person who looks to
be an arsonist was witnessed?!
Right!
The address is 6-chome Shinagawa.
The officer who was on patrol was
questioning him, when he fled!
They're in the midst of pursuing him now!
He has long hair, is wearing
an hat and a gray coat.
He seems to be near where you are now!
Leave the children to officer Sato.
You and Takagi
head for the site on the double!
So, that's the story!
Let's go officer Takag!!
Y.Yes sir!
What's up?! Hurry!
My police I'D. book...
Y gun
Agh?! Oh no!!
Officer Takagi!!
The handcuffs... I left the handcuffs on
the desk of the 1 section at the station...
Hey, hey...
we've got no time to go back and get it,
you know...
Are you all right, officer Takagi...?
I'm okay...if worse comes to worse,
officer Shiratori has his...
and besides, my fortune in the magazine,
it said today is
a super lucky day for me...
I can do without handcuffs,
he's only an arsonist...
Please be careful, dear...
Don't worry! According to today's fortune,
I'm supposed to be super lucky...
Hun 7
Father forgot to take the handcuffs...
Huh? M My husband...
My husband was run over by a car?!
And, where is he now?!
It's not right...Why...
Father is. ..fighting for justice and yet...
He's fighting against the bad, and yet...
Why...
You idiot. .the word "justice".
The word "justice...
Officer Sato?!... Officer Sato?
Huh?...Oh...
Are you all right?!
Yes...
We ll be on our way, then...
Please take care of the children!
Uh, wait...
Please-wait-Officer Takagi!ls
Officer Takagi!
Oh yes?!
Huh?
These handcuffs sure are rusty...
If you don't have your handcuffs,
take those!
Okay...
hose are my father's keepsake...
I broke my handcuffs during
Mr. Hi ashida's case
so I was...
using those for a while.
They're just right as
a lucky charm for you!
C,Charm...
I thought your father died on duty...
Just take them, okay...
Be careful both of you.
Agh, Officer Sato.
Officer Takagi,
Oh...yes sir...
Bye...
What's going on?
Why be armed with a gun
when,dealing with a mere arsonist. %?
Well... .they're both officers of the
violent crime investigation section...
I don't see why they have to go
after the arsonist...
A stabbed body was found,
near the fourth site of the
fire set by the arsonist!...
We don't have proof, but the victim...
most likely witnessed the crime...
or tried to stop the arsonist
and was stabbed.
That's what we suspect!
So, I want you all to stay close to me!
O Okay...
Shinagawa Station
Oh, Inspector Shiratori here!
We just caught the suspicious man who
was on the run...at Shingawa Station!
No I'm not the one!
However...Inspector!
He insists that he is not
the arsonist... but, just a thief...
Huh?
He insists that he is not
the arsonist... but, just a thief...
I get it! So that's what it was...
I've solved the mystery!!
Today is my lucky day after all...
Okay, I'm going to call Officer Sato...
Officer Takag:.
Yes, Sir...
Whaaa!
MITSUTEC
Officer Takagi?
Where are you calling?
Uh. .well...
Nowhere special...
I'm...going to:the men's room.
Uh...
Yes, yes, this is the one.
I was buying this toy of Kamen Yaiba,
when a weird man...
ame out of there...
mm...Hmm...
Yes! Sato here...
Oh. Officer Takagi... l
So, what with the suspicious man...?
What?! You've figured out
the criminal of 18 years ago?!
1 CO...
according to my deductions... most likely,
Listen to this...... he was there...... today.
Mong the people that we met...
That person...
Agh?!
WwW. What is it Inspector Shriatonri!
Officer Takagi! You are acting strange...
A,Ah come off it...give me a break!!
Yes...Yes...that's right!
I've figured everything out!
The true meaning of Shushiro too...
he secret of kanno as well...
now I know why your father...found out
and was able to specify the killer.
Although the case has
already expired...
And? Who... Who is it!
Who is the killer?!
The... killer is...
Ahhhhh!
H Hey Officer Takagi?
Officer Takagi!!
Officer Takag!!
Officer Takagi!
Officer rakagi?! Officer Takagi?
What's wrong? Answer me!!
Officer Takagi! Answer me!!!
Fficer Takagi!!
Fficer Takagqu...
Hello?!
Takagqi...
Okay-. Please do... &
Yes, Shiratori here...
Oh Y Officer Sato,
the suspect was just taken
to the Shingawa Police Station...
Huh, Officer Takagi?
Yes... I was with him. just 4
to 5 minutes ago.
Then the place and time
where you last saw him...
call headquarters and give
the central command room the info!!
What?
Officer Takagi's been attacked
by someone!!!
Just a while ago while he was talking to
me on the cell phone!!
The attacker may be the arsonist
that we're after so please be careful!
Uh...Officer Takagi was attacked just
when he was about to tell you
who the killer of 18 years ago was,right?
Hen...the killer is...
No...
because that case expired 3 years ago...
and we can't even be sure
if Officer Takagi's deduction is right.
You know the four
that we met at sundown...
They were saying they were going to
drink at the pub they usually go to, but...
where is it?
Here...
The name of the pub is..."Nanamagari.
It's located...
In front of Shinagwa Sation...
If Officer Takagi said
that he saw the killer of 18 years ago
mong the four that we met...
then somebody within that group who
was also in front of Shinagawa Station
could've coincidentally
heard his conversation with you...
The killer may have attacked
Officer Takagi to shut:him up, right...?
I'm going to head off to
Shinagawa Station...
so you all go home by train and
come to headquarters again tomorrow...
But the one who attacked Officer
Takagi may also be the arsonist, right?
Then, I. don't see why
you're not taking Ms. Yoshida's
who's the only one
who witness the criminal...
I'll do my best!
Me too!
I'll cooperate too!
Oh well...
From headquarters to
ailing all stations...
Officers in the Shinagawa area...
The place is...
in the vicinity of Shinagawa Station.
Details are... One officer...
whose whereabouts
seems to have been struck
by someone:or wounded.
Investigate on the double
and report investigation results!
From headquarters to
ailing all stations...
Officers in the Shinagawa area...
The place is...
in the vicinity of Shinagawa Station.
[TTY VINYLS
t...It can't be...
To think that the killer is
among the four...
The one that killed my father is
mon the four...
It's not true, Is it'? father?!
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DET CTIVE CONAN
OGosho Aoyama / Sifogakukan
YTV / TMS
All Rights Reserved
Agh...?!
He's the one...!
He's the bad man that I saw!!
They're gone, the children!!
See, now can you see them clearly?
Don't tell me that you're the one
who attacked Officer Takagu...
Come and let's toast in celebration,
shall we...?