Be strong I say to my heart
And step into the essence
with strong rhythm
Mystery after mystery,
the case of arson and robbery
The two cases overlap and become one
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
After Ayumi says
hat she had witnessed the arsonist
of the succession of arson cases
in the city,
we, the Youth Detective Squad,
Officer jakagi and Sato
start investigating the case.
That day also happened
to be the memorial day
when Officer Sato's father died on duty,
so his friends during his school days
were also having a get together.
LOVE STORY AT HEADQUARTERS-III"
Part 2!
What're you doing?!
What's the matter?
Officer Sato, you re soaking with sweat...
It's this pub...isn't it?
Okay then let's get off quick!!
No!!
M in there alone...
I'm coming right back so you all stay put!
Shoots...
Huh?
What're you doing, AI?
Since we've got nothing to do
while we re waiting,
I thought I'd check the places
that were attacked
by the arsonist up to-now 7".
Do any of you remember the places
where the fire took place?
Oh, I remember!
All of them happened near the
station...
The first. happened in Ikebukuro,
uh...the second one in Asakusabashi,
the third in Tabata
and the fourth in Shimokitazawa.
&# The third in Tabata
and the fourth in Shimokitazawa...
And the fifth is Yotsuya,
where Ayumi saw the arsonist!
It's just a simple trapezoid
even if connected
There seems to be no special consistency
or anything...
It sure looks like a scooperefrom here!
You mean-a-soup ladle, right...
soup ladle...
Maybe this is the shape
of an unfinished Big Dipper?
Because if so, the handle
of the ladle should be on the left side...
Hey. Conan...
Why don't you help us out...
Huh?
He's one!
ot-again...
Huh, they left?
All four, together?
Yeah... just about 40 minutes ago...
Something about feeling uncomfortable
about the arson still at
Iarge in this area, so they left.
Um, do you know what the four
were talking about with each other?
C Conan?!
Yeah!
They were having a ball saying that
good things kept coming!
Mr. Inomata was saying that today
was his company's 15th anniversary!
Something about his company had never
been in the reds since its establishment.
Mr. Kano was saying that
tomorrow was his 50th birthday!
He said that his studying in Italy
for 3 years bore fruit,
and that his shop was doing just great...
Mrs. Kandori looked happy saying that
her daughter just got married
to a well-to-do man yesterday!
As for Mr. Saruwatari, he said that
his son just had their second baby boy
this morning...but he added
he had mixed feelings because today
was also your father's memorial day...
The killer of that case is
sure a ruthless one, isn't he?
Not only did the robber take off
with 500,000,000 yen...
He killed the security guard
that tried to stop him
by hitting him on the head with the rifle
that he had hidden behind his coat.
On top of that
he kills the Police Commissioner...
K.Killed...
Didn't he die of an accident?
There was a witness...
Huh?!
Who said that
it looked to be that my father was pushed
in front of the truck from behind...
I'm sure that Conan's in the store!
He's really good at being sneaky...
Don't tell me he's eating something
in there?
Like fried chicken or pork skewers!
All you have in your head is eels
over rice and meat, don't you, Genta...
Youill have to eat vegetables
to orgyou"ll die young...
Agh!
The bad guy was saying something about,
he had just one more vegetable
and it'll be over!
Vegetable?
Yes,
vege...eve...or something like that...
Eve?!
Just one more and the eve will be over?
On't tell me that...that this is...
Darn...
I wonder what he's eating?
Huh? AA?
I'm closing the door...
Oh...okay!
Hey! No fair, Al...
What? She's going to eat something!!
Stay out until I get back!
Shoots
how come we end up staying in here.
Hmm?
What's wrong?
H He's the one! The bad man that I saw!
What?!
But...don { you think
the shop owner is too well-informed...?7.
What?
Like knowing that
e was struck by a rifle...
I Knew nothing about it.
On the day of the incident
the shots thatywere taken by the
surveillance camera was aired on TV!
It was too violent so It was cut immediately
I'm more worried about
Officer Takagi, right now...
The least we need to figure out
IS whether the one
who attacked him was the killer
of 18 years ago, or the arsonist.
Otherwise, there is no way
rrinding him...
hinagawa...
Al?!
The next place the arson is going to
show uplisiShinagawa...
Huh, Shinagawa?!
Look!
Leaving the first arson
that occurred in Ikebukuro
and the 2nd arson
that occurred in Asakusabashi as is,
then connect the third site of the arson
that occurred in Tabata
to the 4th that
occurred in Shimokitézawaz.
with a line to the 5th site Yotsuya
Fire?!
The arsonist was writing
the Japanese kanji
character fire on the ground of Tokyo
in the correct writing order of the word...
Then don't tell me that the one
who attacked Officer Takagi is...
Yes.
If the arsonist mistakenly thought:that he had
been witnessed, it's possible...
If that were to be true...
there should be a corpse rolling around
nearby the next site of the fire,
ust like In the 4th case...
Okay, everybody...
Huh?
What? Oh no...
They're gone!!
Huh?
Fficer Sato...
Oh, Inspector Shirator!
Didn't you see the children?
Weren't they with yo
Well, you see...
Conan, Conan. can you hear me?
Ayumi...
Hey!
Where are you guys
and what're you doing?!
Don't yell, the killer will hear you!
What? the killer?
The man that Ayumi had seen before
coincidentally walked by the pub,
o we're tailing him now...
What?!
We're at the warehouse district
in Shinagawa 6 chome right now...
Hey, take a look at that. He's pouring
something onto the newspaper...
What? The guy hasn't set fire yet?
Which means that the one who attacked
Officer Takagi wasn't the arsonist?
Um, Inspector Shiratori,
did you notice anything strange
before parting with Officer Takagi?
I think he was looking up at
the board with the names of the stations
on the platform of Shinagawa Station...
Station name board...
I see!
That's why Officer Takagi figured it out...
The meaning of the last words
of Officer Sato's father, Shushiro',
the identity of the kan-n-o0
that was written in his police book,
and the reason why he was able to
specify the killer with only a few clues...
There's no doubt about it,
the killer is among the four.
And the one
who attacked Officer Takagi is also...
Hey! You guys!
We'll head on that way with Inspector
Shiratori's car right now, so don't move!
Huh?
Let's go in my car, then...
your destination is not there,
Officer Sato...
Huh?
You'll have to go and settle the case
that happened 18 years ago...
Settle the case?
It's most likely, that...
it hasn't been settled yet...
eah, that'ta boy...grow...
Hey, hey, I don't believe it...
Agh!!
25 Em
The hint is the row of the Roman
alphabet where the letter na is...
I'm sure that Officer Takagi realized
it when he was looking at the board
with the names of the station on it...
It's a very simple magic of letters...
That person probably also knows
here Officer Takagi is...
Although it may be impossible
to arrest him now,
he may reveal the truth to you...
The truth of what happened
18 years ago...
Is it going to be okay?
The fire is getting bigger...
1.I'm sure everything will be all right,
because Conan should've contacted
the fire deparment by now...
Don't we need to tail the arsonist...?
Remember, Conan told us not to move?
But, I think that it's been 10 minutes
No, not even 5 minutes have passed yet...
It's too dark that I can't see.
Huh?
There, now you can see, can't you? Brats...
I'll line you all up in a row...
as the sacrificial offering of the
real carnival that is about to begin...
uh? Miwako...
Did you finish work?
Well, sort of...
But, as you can see,
they're almost ready to close.
Who cares!
Let me at least treat you to a drink!
Tomorrow's your long awaited
50th birthday, isn't it?
I guess so...but at 50 you don't
really care about birthdays anymore...
Oh...I'm sure you've been
Iooking forward to the day...
Because after midnight this evening,
the "Shushiro incident
that occurred 18 years ago
Ill to your joy expire...
So, let's have a toast, the two of us...
Mr. Kan-n-0"?
Amnit...
hat the hell is going on...
I remember...
Somebody hit me from behind...
1,I've got to do something
about these handcuffs.
All right! My gun's still here!
Kay, I'll shoot the chain off...
a-n-0 .
The three mysterious letters that were
written in my father's police l.D. book...
If written in Roman letters
it is read "KANO".
If n" is put together with the vowel "0",
it is read...
Kano...
I called Mr. Saruwatari and the others
and confirmed with them
0o just awhile ago.
They told me that Ka-n-0" is probably
the nickname my father gave you
when you used to play baseball together
IN your school days.
But, until I asked them about it,
they told me that they thought
you used to be called by a strange name,
something like Kan-o" or "Kao"...
They never really figured out for sure
what you were being called...
The reason why my father specified you
as the suspect was because
he saw the picture of the man
who hit the securityguard with the rifle
on the surveillance camera...
Father used to always tell me...
that although you had
a unique batting form,
you were the most skilled batter
of the team...
Ha, ha, ha...you've got to be kidding,
suspecting me as the killer
just because of something like that...
Besides that case expired
3 years ago, didn't it. .?
No, not yet. To put it accurately, there's
still 8 minutes and 17 seconds to go...
You should know,
that if the suspect goes abroad,
the period that the suspect
IS abroad is counted out...
I've already checked it out
with the Ministry of Justice...
And, I've also figured out
that you set it up
to comeback from Italy
on your 50th birthday,
so that you wouldn't forget
the expiration date of the case!!
No! Not until you tell me
what really happened.
Father used to say that a suspect who is
on the verge of confessing the crime
always gulps and reaches
out for a cup of tea...
and if you give the suspectithe tea
he will swallow
the confession together with the tea...
I won't let you swallow
this case into yourself,
Not even if your throat gets so parched
t you dry out and wither...
Agh, Ayumi!!
No. no. no, no
you all come here quietly too...
Huh?
What's another way of saying,
being kicked in the rear end?
Butt...7!
Utt kick...
Right!
Ig... sure IC € some Ing
ally stupid again...
Inspector Shiratori! This way...
Huh?
This way, this way!
A can of kerosene and matches...
I think we've really got him this time.
Uh, is that warehouse
going to be all right,
etting it burn on like that...
Ss burning pretty badly...
That warehouse was scheduled
to be demolished next week anyway,
and it's empty inside.
Besides, the firefighters are busy
extinguishing the fire now.
Darn!
Congratulations...l lose...
I didn't mean to kill
You mean my father?
The security guard!
I just fried to brush him away bull seem
to have hit him in the wrong place...
What about father, then?
You kicked him at the intersection,
didn't you?
No...I'm the one who was kicked...
Huh?
Back then... he saw through all of me
nd I was about to be...
taken to the station by him...
I suddenly got scared
when I thought about my future...
that I dashed out In front of the truck...
e pushed me...
He gave me another chance
o do my life over again...
But, what good is it, getting back on
my feet with the money that I robbed...
No...
I haven't touched that money!
I have it-hidden
under the Buddhist altar at home!
I was planning to give the money back
as soon as the case expired!
This is true!! Please believe me!!
Sure, I'll believe you
Officer Chiba, did you hear all that?!
Yes, all of it!!
Get a warrant immediately
and confiscate everything!
If the license number matches,
we've no better proof!
Attach the tape of this conversation
onto the money
and send it in to the criminal
Investigation section
make sure he is indicted today,
understand?!
Y Yes...
Hurry,
because we've only got one day left!!
One day left?
You mean you didn't realize,
that when you came back from Italy,
remember, there was a typhoon?
Y.Yeah...
The flight that was scheduled
to arrive at 21:00,
was delayed and arrived at 00:04...
Which means that your calculation
of the expiration date
of the case, was one day off...
y sympathies...
I had a bad feeling...
Because your face
when you came here today
Iooked just like yourfather's back then...
If you refused to confess,
I was ready to turn your house over
and look for the money
In order to arrest you!
But, not father!
He could've told me your name
In the ambulance,
but he believed you, so he didn't...
My father turned towards you
as you fled from the intersection and said,
rn yourself in...
Because his gasping remark sounded
Iike Shushiro to the people
who were there at that time,
they heard wrong...
Now, tell me where Officer Takagi is!
Where is he?
Inside a dilapidated warehouse
n Shinagawa 6-chome...
I was going to report it to the police later
and inform them though...
Hey, that's...
I.Is that true?
Is Officer Takagi really in there?...
If so, he's probably already...
What do you think you're saying?
You'll still make it!!
Move!
N No Officer Sato!!
Move, I said!
You idiot...
I have been appointed here today
My name is Wataru Takagi!...
Uh, Officer Sato...
O,Officer Sato?
Officer Sato!
Ou Idiot, idiot...
It seems that
today is my super lucky day...
foolish Takagi
Oh, yes.
Ah... I'm sorry .
1, Takagi!
Just what are you doing there?!
W. Well, Im...
When I pulled on the bars it came off,
so I got out through the window...
1.1 was walking back and forth, then was
istaken for one of the onlookers...
Il.ll\.;...
Get an ambulance!
How can you walk around
urt like this...
What? Come on, you've got your gun!
Why didn't you use your gun
to blow the chain off the handcuffs?!
He didn't want to break
those handcuffs...
That's your father's keepsake,
isn't it Officer Sato?
That's why he didn't use his gun!
Really cool!
He's the type that'll die young...
You fool...
' dL ¥ \ ) y «& jp
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi1 Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
ECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
GGosho Aoyama / Si¥ogakukan
All Rights Reserved
Huh? Oh nevermind, I don't deserve
any-tokenfofiappreciation...
No! A promise is a promise!
Okay, then,
ould I ask you out, just the two of us...
Oh, is that all you want?
Okay,
then wait for me next Saturday at 18:00
in front of the main entrance
of the Budokan.
I'm sorry
Did you wait long?
Uh, No, I just got here too.
I'm sorry. Remember the arsonist?
E started confessing so...
got all absorbed.
L.Let's not talk about work...
Right, we're dating today, dating!
R.Right!
Sato here! I've caught sight of the
younger sister of the guy in question!
Huh?
Okay, keep tailing her!
Make sure she doesn't fine out
that you're a cop!
Yes, sir!
U,Uh, Officer Sato?
Don't tell me that this is...
Okay, let's go, Officer Takagqi...
Officer Sato!
To think that a detective as renown as
Kogoro Mourn was not able to
stop a murder that happened right
efore his eyes...
We appreciate your cooperation.
?1 Huh...?!
We'll keep this evidence
that you have with us.
D Don't tell me that...?!
But, if thought of that way,
It Is convincing....!
Even Pop's superb power
of deduction....!