Be strong I say to my heart
And step into the essence
with strong rhythm
Be attentive today and listen well,
because it is a unique mystery that
can be experienced only with Conan...
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with
the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan
AN OVERLY SUPERB DEDUCTION"
Beika Station
Hey Ran,
walk a little slower, will you
I tell you!!
Since it is a hassle having to pick you up,
if you have to drink, don't go and drink
on the other side of the station!
Ell, well...
Huh?
Talk about hopeless...
From 20-00 to 22:00 all you can eat.
All you can drink, it says!
You're always going for ads like that!!
What do you mean!
I got to eat three times the amount
I paid and drank five times the price too,
gah, ha, ha, ha ha!!
Hey, stop throwing things! Go on home!!
Takayuki Irie
tr oB
Hey, stop throwing things! Go on home!!
Go on home? What do you mean
go on home, you bastard!!
Whaaa
J, Just what do you think you're doing?!
L.Let me go, Nakamoto!!
Shut up!!
What shall we do, dad...?
We can't ignore them, can we?
I'll go stop them!
Oops!
Ah, dad...
Ha, ha, ha...they"ll be fine.
Hey always fight like that...
But, the next minute
they'll be smiling at
each other and make up.
Right?
That's a good boy.
Uh, shucks, I worried for nothing.
Let's go home!
Hey, dad!
Wait for me!
You've got to watch your step.
Come on, get a hold of yourself!!
Something bothered me,
so I went to check the apartment out
the following morning...
We'll get the details
after the autopsy but...
the estimated time of death-is between
22:00 to 23:00. last night...
H,Hey, you're joking, right?!
Not you-again!
Well, you:see...
Then, how else would you explain this?!
Inspector Megure!
It's just as Mr. Mouri says!
The residents of the apartment
also heard them!
It seems that at the time in question,
a man called Nakamoto was having
a heated argument with the victim,
Mr. Irie.
Hmm...
and who is the guy called Nakamoto?
I'll go check!
To think that a detective as renown
as Kogoro Mouri was not able to
stop a murder that happened right
efore his eyes...
I'm truly ashamed...
Damnit! Only if that old man who was
taking a walk didn't say what he did
I would've gone in to stop them!
& WW &
P,Please help me!
Mr. Mourn!
U Uh...l used to be a member of
the Beika University physics
U. Uh... used to be a member of
Hiroshi Nakamoto
research lab together with the victim Irie.
My name is Nakamoto.
Hiroshi Nakamoto
U3 UL
research lab together with the victim Irie.
My name is Nakamoto.
What?!
Nakamoto.
Y, You're the one who killed him last night?!
N No!
I was summoned by the policejfor
testimony, but didn't do anything!!
I didn't go to Irie's room last night.
Please believe me!!
Huh...?
Listen!!
We definitely heard you arguing with
the man who was killed.
So, what do you mean
by you didn't go there?
A tape!
Somebody recorded it on tape to make
it look like I went there!!
What?!
Made it look like you were there?
CC Pee eo
Irie set the time...
and probably pressed the play button...
Hey, don't throw things! Go on home!
Go on home?! What are you
talking about, you bastard!!
You mean he acted it all out alone?
Yes...he was creating my alibi.
Alibi?!
For what purpose?!
He snuck into the house of our mentor,
Professor Demura...
In order to murder him!
What?!
The professor is secretly selling the fruit
of our research off to businesses!!
Even if we were to file charges against
him, he has tremendous authority,
and we'd be ousted!
That's why! . . That's why...
We decided to break into his house
when his family was away
and make it look like a case of robbery
Nd homicide...
B,But, it didn't work out as planned!
We snuck in but,
the professor wasn't home!
I waited one hour but he didn't come home
So, I eventually gave up
I went to the professor's house at 22:00
and left at 23:00.
If what you're telling us Is true,
you could not have
Killed Mr. Takayuki Irie.
But! The professor seems to have testified
that he was doing some writing
in his study all last night, and
never left his home!!
That sure is strange...
Yes... don't know why
the professor is lying!!
But, if things go as is
I'll end up being a murderer!
I wonder why the police let you,
who happens to be a prime suspect go...
I heard at the station that you,
the renown Detective Kogoro Mouri,
was also nearby the scene of the
crime last night
This is probably no coincidence,
please I beg you, help me!!
It's true that I am not
totally uninvolved in this case, but...
So, you don't believe me either,
do you, Mr. Mouri...
If only I can find that recorded tape!
Are you sue there really is something
Iike that to begin with?...
Well...ll was told that there was no such
tape anywhere in Irie's house!
I'm sure the killer took it with him.
If that cannot be found,
the killer can frame me!
What shall I do... .I'm sure that the killer
has gotten rid of the tape by now, too...
Dad, why don't you at least
try searching for the tape
If you solve this case, you'll regain
your reputation again, won't you, Pops.
Regain my reputation! Okay, why not!!
There is only one way
in and out of the apartment. .\\
The exit after the crime was committed is
this street which leads to thegstation
The killer is sure to have
wanted to get rid of the tape
which would serve as evidence
as soon as possible
Wait! Wait up! That trash!
W,What is it?!
It can't be...this is too close.
I found it!!
1, That's the tape!
Talk about duck soup!
Thank you for your cooperation.
Officer Takagt!
I'll take the evidence.
So, they were keeping watch
over the prime suspect...
Wait! You re not on 10 take that
tape with you, just like that, are you?
Go home? What do you mean,
go home, you fool!
This is the same remark we heard last night!
Right, Conan!
Yep.
- ) - a.
I...
Now, It's been proved.
Mr. Nakamoto is not lying!
I'm glad! I've finally found
someone who believes me!
But...l wonder why the professor lied
You can say that again
I wouldn't have been suspected at all if
the professor didn't lie in the first place!
That's just it!! He wanted
to set you up as the suspect!
But, what advantage would the professor
have doing something like that?
Oh? It could be that the professor was
somewhere he didn't want anyone to know
Could it be that he was
on his way to kill Mr. Irie...?
That's a possibility...but
That's not possible!
It'd be a different story if he knew
about our plan!
We planned everything out in lrie's room.
The professor couldn't have
even eavesdropped on us!
Avesdrop...
Oh, maybe?!
This?! The screws of the lid are loose
It's probably in here
Oh, is that right, I see... Thank you.
There seems to have been evidence
of a wire tap being set, after all?
So, now we know!
Although Professor Idemura had been
making money stealing the research
by Irie and Nakamoto
He became wary that maybe
one day you would take revenge
Therefore, he set up a wire tap to keep track
of what you were both doing.
I wonder how he snuck in?
If he stole the key from
Mrairie's locker in the lab,
he could've easily made a spare key, right?
Exactly.
And, while he was tracking your
conversation through the wire tap
He found out of your plan to kill him
That's when he thought about using the alibi
that you had both made up,
his advantage...
Last night,
Mr. Irie went on with his one man act
of creating the alibi tape
as usual at a little past 22:00
Then the professor sneaks in using the
spare key and Kills Mr. Irie.
He then steals the tape, retrieves the
wire tap and leaves the site.
If Mr Irie's body is found, the police would
naturally take it to be a crime committed
committed by Mr Nakamoto, from the
testimonies of the people in the area.
In other words, Professor ldemura,
after killing Mr. Irie, set it up so that it
would look like Mr. Nakamoto
committed the murder!!
Our plan was used to his advantage
Very skillfully indeed. BUT,
he was unable to fool
the eyes of the top-notch,
renownwDetectiveKogoro Mouri's eyes!!
Hey, hey, what's up Pops?
Your deduction is perfect.
I guess I'm not called for this time
What are you bragging about?!
If you went into Mr.
Irie's room last night,
you could've stopped the murder
from happening, you know!
Ah, come on don't say that
Oh, I heard from Inspector Megure that a man
who was walking his dog
stopped you from going inside
Right, only if that old man
didn't say what he did
True, but that old man didnet
have any bad intentions either
Don't tell me that 7?
But, if thought of it that way,
t is convincing...!
Even Pop's superb power of deduction
Okay! So, I guess I ll go tell Inspector Megure
of my superb deduction,
of my superb deduction, in order
to regain my reputation!
Not That!
What?! What's not that?!
W. Well, it's a superb deduction after all,
why go all the way out there
and tell him about it?
Why not have him come here from his side.
It's cooler that way
I guess so. Okay!
I'm going to go out play until then!
So, the alibi scheme was used against
the very ones who made it up
I see just as expected of you, Mr Mourn!!
Well, I'm just being my usual self,
gah, ha, ha, ha
I'm sorry for having suspected you,
Mr. Nakamoto.
Oh, don't be,
so long as you find out the truth
Besides, I'm still to be charged for
sneaking into the professor's house
Well, we'll take care of that later
Officer Takagi, get an arrest warrant for
Professor Idemura on the double!
Yes, sir!!
Please wait a second Inspector!
However, the deduction that I have
presented you is;just one possibility.
The one that the real killer
wished the case to look like.
What the real killer wished...7?
Just what do you mean, Mr. Mourn?
Please sit down once again.
What I am about
to say from now is the real truth.
The testimonies of Mr. Nakamoto and
Professor Idemura are really different
That is, one of them is lying!
At a timelike that, if the tape ah,
that Mr. Nakamoto mentioned is found,
his testimony would naturally
ound to be the truth. .!
On the otherhand, suspicion against
Professor Idemura would grow!
At that needs to besdone next, is to lead
the deduction in the preferred direction.
And, make, everybody
fall under the illusion
that Professor Idemura had
indeed killed Mr Irie.
An illusion?!
Lead the deduction...Are you saying
that somebody lead everyone
to think that it happened that way?!
It is indeed possible
As for the recorded tape
The killer probably got rid of it too
Because Mr. Nakamoto had mumbled so,
I was lead to check inside
the trash can near the site...
The reason I turned my attention to
Professor Idemura was because...
I wouldn't have been suspected at all if
the professor didn't lie in the first place!
Mr. Nakamoto said what he did! And
Oh? It could be that
the professor was somewhere
he didn't want anyone to know he was...
From his remark, I was lead to think
that maybe Professor Idemura had set
off to kill Mr. Irie. Furthermore...
The professor couldn't have
even eavesdropped on us!
I was lead to imagine a wire tap from
his remark "eavesdropping"!
In other words, by deliberately casually
remarking the things that he did
about the essentials,
Mr. Nakamoto lead me to deduce
that Professor
Idemura had committed the crime!
That is, I did not make a deduction,
but rather was lead to make a deduction!
By who else, but Mr. Nakamoto himself
I see...
Needless to mention,
you never snuck
into Professor Idemura's house
The one who snuck in when Mr Irie
was putting on his one-man act,
and killed him,
Is you!
Professor Idemura was probably
in his study just as he said he was.
Of course. there was
no wire tap to begin with either.
You were the one who loosened
the screws of the outlet.
Is that not right, Mr. Nakamoto?
First of all, the story about the
recorded tape is strange to begin with.
If it were disposed of
Iast night 'right after the crime,
it would never have
been found.
Because the trash of that
convenience store is collected daily
before dawn by the trash collectors.
However, the tape that
wasn't supposed to be there, was there
Which means the tape was not disposed
of last night, but rather, today
after the trash collectors came
With the tape gone you
wouldn't have been able to lead us to it
right, Mr. Nakamoto?
You have no evidence
of anything, Mm Mourn.
That's all mere paper plan, that
detectives are known to be good at.
This is no paper plan! Unfortunately,
Mr. Nakamoto there ls a witness!
A witness?
Uh. I was asked to come here,
a while ago by Conan
I asked him to ask you to come here.
So, Mr. Nakamoto had to figure out
who he would let make the deduction
And that person had to be someone
that the police would listen to
So, you turned your attention to me,
the renown detective, Kogoro Mourn,
But, you were worried that I may turn
you down if you came to me just like that
To make sure that I would listen to you,
you deliberately got me involved
by setting me up as a witness!!
H, How?
Knowing that I love to drink, you left an ad
for an all you can eat and drink between
20:00 to 22:00 in my post box
I see! Mr. Mouri would undoubtedly fall for it!
Therefore, I would pass by Mr. Irie's
apartment after 22:00 on my way home
But, in order to get the timing right,
Irie probably started his one man act
after confirming us passing by.
He had% no way of knowing that he was going
to be murdered, so he did just as planned
But, then why is Azusa from
the restaurant below a witness?
Mr. Nakamoto,
you put this ad in the post box yesterday
morning, didn't you?
She saw you do so.
How about it, Azusa?
Are you sure it was him?
Yes! He's 'the one!!
When I came to the shop in the morning,
he was putting a red
ad sheet in the mail box.
I think it was the same
as that one over there.
Your fingerprints would most naturally
be found on the ad if checked for.
That ad was only distributed on the
other side of the station in the first place.
Why did you have to go out of your way
to put that ad in my mail box,
Mr Nakamoto?
And I thought everything worked out perfect.
How did you figure everything out?
When did you suspect me?
You just talked too much...
Oh, I heard from Inspector Megure that
a man who was walking his dog
stopped you from going inside
I told the Inspector A man taking a walk,
but I didn't give him the details
about the old man walking his dog.
I probably would've given him more details
£ "if no witness was found, though
what a klutz I am!
If I went in there and
stopped you both from fighting,
everything would go down the drain.
So, you kept me from going into the room.
The old man who was
walking the dog was you, wasn't it?
I was right after all ..Mr. Moun,
you are a renown detective after all...
No, rather you are too renown
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutanr
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DET TTIYE CONAN
OGosho Aoyama / Stfogakukan Th
YTV / TMS
All Rights Reserved
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
YTV ll TNS
All" RightsReserved
In the battle for the rights and fame
of the research they were developing,
Mr. Nakamoto deceived his colleague,
Mr. Irie, and eventually killed him.
He then tried to frame Professor Idemura
as the killer and take everything for himself.
Oh, another ad. What's this?
Starting tomorrow, 3 days sale of beer
all you can drink?!
Ah, come on, dad!!
What's the matter with you?!!
Give it back! If I drink chap liquor it'll
help with the household budget, won t it?!
Stop drinking before
saying something like that.
Hey, hey, don't you ever get
fed up, or what
Doc! Call the police and an ambulance!
Could it be a code or something?!
We're sharing the treasure, understand!
Shoots! Don't tell me that this is...!
Doc! Call the police right away!
They went to the killer who pushed
the car over the cliff a while ago!