Be strong I say to my heart
And step into the
essence with strong rhythm
Today's case Is a special one with tricks.
It is a large scaled, fun-packed episode.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with
the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan
The Entrance to a Labyrinth
The Fury of the Gigantic Goddess Statue
Mt. Tenbu, Goddess Statue
xX 8 WwW
For many hundreds of years,
e goddess of Mt. Tenbu,
Mt. Tenbu, Goddess Statue
REID
For manylhundreds of years,
he goddess of Mt. Tenbu,
x 88 LL
was worshipped by the villagers,
and protected the peace of the village!
However, those who enraged
the goddess died a ruthless death.
So, it has been told...!
What a dreadful thing to do,
digging a tunnel
through the rocky mountain ,
where the goddess stands...
The curse of the heavens
are sure to fall upon them!
Oh, that must be
the statue of the goddess?
Right!
And that hideous ropeway is
IN clear view too!!
Where are you headed for?
Uh...well we're not«all that sure...
Ha, ha, ha... we're going to
that hideous ropeway, you see...
Tenbu Station
Ill I'll
I take it that you are Mr. Kogoro Moun?
Yes! What a beauty...
So, you ve come to pick us up?
Yes, we've been expecting you.
Yaka Yoshino
fi ER" (23)
3 J<lLeB3 0
nx Hines
I am secretary to the vice president
of Dohmoto Tours, Ayaka Yoshino.
Yaka Yoshino
tax lanai!
I am secretary to the vice president
of Dohmoto Tours, Ayaka Yoshino.
Aka Yoshino
Iy TA. IX
I am secretary to the vice president
of Dohmoto Tours, Ayaka Yoshino.
Aka Yoshino
ot Bima
Uh, I'm really sorry to have brought
the kids along with me.
I am Ran Mouri and this is Conan,
who staying with us now
Hello.
Hi! Nice to meet you Conan!
Wow it sure Is bustling.
It as really an honor to have you,
the famous Detective Mouri,
attend the opening ceremony tomorrow.
No problem, Ms. Bunny...
There are people
who are against the ropeway, I see...
It seems that you not only called me
to attend the ceremony am I right?
Yes...
the president will tell you more about it...
Xe O-Joxq
Mt. Tenbu
Ropeway Resthouse
The highly reputed name of the renown
VIP room
VillR,room
Detective Mouri is well known
throughout this rural village too!
VIP room
Fig]?
Detective Mouri is well known
throughout this rural village too!
VIP room
Now, I am positive that
Eizou Dohmoto
RTE 0
<* , ~ Pg oo
Sl. 97 WS SI Lo TA. ATL,
pening ceremony will
be considered a grand occasion!
Eizou Dohmoto
aly Ag
2 + x 1Z (DI)
far - TR) A
pening ceremony will
be considered a grand occasion!
Eizou Dohmoto
No problem, if I can be of service,
it is my pleasure!
There is actually another reason why
we've asked you to come, Mr. Mourn...
There are many who are against
the opening of the ropeway,
so you'd like to see to it that the
ceremony proceeds safely...right?
Just as expected of you...
Jyunpei Dohmoto
The only ones who are happy about it,
Jyunpel Dohmoto
WA FE (30)
are the local shop owners and those
who will gain profit from it...!
Since the way my father does
things is ven aggressive,
he has a lot of enemies!
That's why I went independent
at an early age,
and started an import and export
business handling miscellaneous goods!
And, since your business
is not doing well,
didn { you come ask dad
for financial help again today?
What?!
I'm home! Long time nolseer dad!!
Oh, did-you jus sarrive here from:To \ 0.
Yes! It's a grand event for you, after all,
come no matter what!!
Rina Dohmoto
Yes! It's a grand event for you, after all,
come no matter what!!
Ah, come on,
after having left home selfishly.
You went and did what you
wanted to do to your heart's content
for one whole year, didn't you!
I'll bet you just came to ask
for a loan or something?
How rude!
What about you!!
Tourist business my eye! After all
the snickering and bickering over it!!
It...! Uh, Rina, who is
He is Mr. Tetsuya Aoyagi,
a free:lance journalist!
He says he'd like to write
an-article about this!
I'm Aoyagi!
I'm Aoyagt!
Tetsuya Aoyagi
511 Emma
# 5th (28
I've heard what you've been through as
to the opening of the ropeway from Rina.
Tetsuya Aoyagi
WA th (28
I've heard what you've been through as
to the opening of the ropeway from Rina.
Tetsuya Aoyagi
I've heard what you've been through as
to the opening of the ropeway from Rina.
Hmm?!
I hear a lot of things happened when
the tunnel was under construction...?
Re you Mr. Aoyagli...?
I see so you're the one trying
to get it going good with Rina, eh!
Yes, I believe
I talked to you over the phone...
Just a sec. what is this about?
I wonder if he has a secret or something
he doesn't want others to know about...
Vice president,
what do you say we have
Mr. Mouri and his party
test ride the ropeway in preparation
for tomorrow's ceremony?
Oh, that sounds good, let's do that!
Let s have you take a look at the
splendid landscape from the terminal
at the top of the mountain which is the
pride and joy of Dohmoto Tours!!
Wow that sounds just great
Oh come to think of it Pops is...
One sheep, two sheep...
Huh, Mr. Mouri, don't tell me
you can't take high places?
1,I'm fine, so long as I don't look below...
How nice...
It is about 3,000 meters to the summit,
and we'll be there in about 10 minutes.
What's that...?
It s an esplanade!
It's closed until we open it to the public
After going to the summit
with the ropeway,
everyone will be walking back down
while enjoying. breathing
in the fresh air of the greenery!
In other words,
the protest of the inhabitants was
settled by financial guarantee?
However, we still get blackmails
and crank calls
demanding cancellation of
the opening of the ropeway...
Do you have any idea who Is doing this?
It's not just one or two people so...
Besides, there 1s a priestess called
Shizu Kamiya who resides
in a temple nearby...
making a fuss saying
that the gods will be angered.
The local papers wrote an article,
Does The Curse Of The Goddess Exist ./
And this is stirring fear among the
inhabitants, that we are in quite a fix.
Uh...? That cable car that is
headed down is empty, isn't it?
When one cable car moves,
so does the other.
It runs like a well bucket going up
on two stays,
n on two stays,
Back and f
and is called the back and forth \ pe.
Oh, I see...
Wow?! What is that?
They are the 500 disciples of
Buddha who have attained Nirvana
In other words.
We'll be taking a tour inside the
womb of the goddess that is above here.
A tour inside the womb ?
Does it mean that we can attain good luck
if we go through
the body of the goddess?
Well I guess you could say so.
Come to think of it, that man called
Aoyagi had mentioned something
about the construction of this
tunnel, hadn't he?
I'll bet: he's thinking of conjuring
upta scandal or something
in order to suck money
ff of our company...!
Sis, should've been more careful too!
Why'd she have to tell
a guy like that about it...!
About it 7!
What:is it about?
Oh, it's nothing but family business
that is not worth mentioning...
We ll be out of the tunnel
in about 30 seconds.
See, when the ropeway
comes up to here,
the top half of the goddess
statue comes Into view.
The top half of the goddess
The roc « mountain was carved
in the shape of the goddess
about 800 years ago...
Her right hand stuck out in front
is called the form of the Yoganin.
In her left hand,
she is holding the Nyoihoju,
a crystal ball that will
get rid of disasters and unhappiness...
For those who want to
take a good look at it
there is an observatory that can
be accessed from the promenade.
Aha, ha... I sort of understand why
the priestess was all upset...
Mt. Tenbu Station
B&3 RX
JR BR
Th Bd Re
Wow, what a fantastic view!
You don't get to see
Iandscape like this everyday
People seem so tiny when you
see something as grandiose as this!
Yes but those tiny people
are the ones who work
with grandiose nature such as this,
and develop it into tourist sites!
Oh...this?
This is a keepsake of my mother.
It's a broche made out of jade beads.
That's not it... Your broche is nice too,
but, I just thought you ook
a lot like that goddess statue!
Yes, kind and refined...
Thank you...l makes me happy,
even if you're just flattering me
I'm not flattering you!
Right, Conan!
St a=
Ms. Yoshino.
Yes.
Will you please see
Mr. Mouri to his hotel?
Yes, Sir.
What are you going to do?
I'm going down the
promenad 'to do final-checks
onsthe facilities, then come back. ;
I ll see you at the ceremony
tomorrow afternoon, then.
Wow, he's a vice president
and yet very diligent, isn't he
Of course! The life of the company
IS on his shoulders.
Hotel Dohmoto
DOUMOTO
Just great!
Dad: think you've'alreadydhad enough!!
Well, they got a suite room, you know!
I want to enjoy it with my entire
heart and soul, sol don't lose out.
Well, yes, I guess it is a glamorous room.
I wonder If it's okay
They must be loaded with cash!
You don't have to worry about it!
But, it seemed like the 2nd son, Junpei
andsthe oldest daughter,
Rina had financial problems
Yes, it seemed so, and besides,
they didn't seem to
be getting along well either...
When it comes time to'/inherit the estate,
I'll bet they'll go through hell!
It'll be so bad that bloody rain
Is likely to fall!
Cut it out, dad! What a thing to say!!
I wonder why the opening ceremony
IS going to be held in the afternoon...?
Mr. Machida, shouldn't we be holding
interviews, rather than sitting here?
Hold your horses...
I didn't come here to write up a flop!
Where the hell is Conan?
He told me he had to
go to the men's room...
Conan,
it's going to start soon.
Okay.
Preparations are perfect.
Nobody's, noticed anything.
Phooey!
Your perfect can never be counted on!
You can't even get rid of
a hyena blackmailer like Aoyagi!!
But, that's...
Don't talk back to me!
In business all that matters are results!!
The way you are,
I cant leave the company to you!!
President; let's. start makingspreparations.
Ladies and Gentlemen,
the central figure.of.the formal opening
of the Mt. Tenbu ropeway, President
Eizo Dohmoto of Dohmoto Tours,
will present.his speech.
Ladies and Gentlemen, thank you for
coming today on this memorable event.
We, at Dohmoto Tours, who are
the leaders of the world of tourism ¢
have always tried to preserve
cultural heritage from the days of old...
You darn sinners!!
E of the heavens will
fall upon all of.you present here today!!
fall upon all of you present here today!!
Priestess
hizu Kamiyama
You idiot!! Just what are you doing?
Take pictures!!
OO. Oh, shoots!!!
To do something as outrageous as
to dig a tunnel
under the lotus pedestal of the holy
goddess is totally abominable!
All of you, know thy shame!!
May the curse of the heavens
fall upon Eizo Dohmoto!!
We seem to have had
a guest here that was not invited,
but please do not
concern yourselves over her!
Even-the papers have
irresponsibly written gibberish
about that statue of the goddess!!
However I, Eizo Dohmoto shall
scatter all such nonsense away for you!!
That isywhy we have with us here today,
among our honored guests,
the renowneDetective Kogoro Mourille Say.
Well, hello, everyone, I am Kogoro Mourt!
Thank you, thank you!
Mr. Machida, this is really
something! Kogoro Mouri is here!
Don't you think there's
something fishy going on?
What?!
You mean it's not him, but a look alike?
Oh, never mind...
Why on earth did Eizo Dohmoto
call us here for?
The Mt. Tenbu will now
begin its first trial run!
The second group of people
will get on the second cable
that will arrive afterithe first
cable car reaches the top!
That's?!
The two there are
journalists from Tokai Nippo,
the agency that
Is attackingaDohmoto Tours...
Why would they be here before all the
other agencies and take the trial run?
You fools
Look, look, Mr. Aoyagi,
the view is fantastic.
How do you like it, Mr. Machida?
Why not try writing some good
things about us for a change?
Are you trying to bribe me?
If you do, I'll.-make an
article of that too!
Absolutely! I wonder how long
you can keep it up?
Hmm?!
H Hey, Mr. Machida, take a look at that!
The statues of the 500 disciples
of Buddha who attained Nirvana?!
You mean you made things like that
using the power of money?!
I'd rather you take me
to be a reli ious man...
I'm sure that this would
become the talk of the town
and we'll have visitors avalanching in!
Wanting to worship and pray
to the statue of the goddess,
as well as the statues of
the 500 disciples of Buddha!
In other words, I have every
reason to be given gratitude
from the statue of the goddess,
and no reason to be cursed by it!!
Hmm? What's up?
What?! What's up?! Is it a black out?
Hey just what do you
think you're doing!! Don't!!
Y,.You're...?!
Somebody! Somebody, give us light!
Use the flash of the camera!!
Use the flash once more!!
OO, Okay!
What the?!
T,This is...?!
T, This is...?!
T,This is absurd?!
The President's?!
He's gone!!
The windows cannot be opened! The two
journalists are by the door to the left!!
By the door to the right is \ aka!
The ceiling only has a small ventilation hole!
The emergency exit...!
Hasn't been used yet!!
Then, where did he disappear to?!
What is with this talisman?!
The principle of cause and effect'?
Cause and effect?
You will pay for your sins?
D.Dad 1s over there!
What?!
That 1s indeed Mr. Eizo Dohmoto!
It looks like something
IS stabbed into his chest!
Contact somebody with
the cell phone immediately!!
No, because there are no
antennas in this area yet!
There's a phone once we
get to the top though...
This is ridiculous!!
Can something like this really happen?!
Something's happened to the President!
Get the police and let the people below
know about this right away!!
Yes, sir!!!
We'll head down over to the statue
of the goddess using the hiking path!!
This is Machida!
Please leave one page of the evening
news open! There's been a curse!!!
Eizo Dohm0to's been stabbed! on top
of the palm of the statue of the goddess!!
Ayaka, 'What's wrong? Are you okay? -
I just felt a little faint! Never mind me,
check on the president!
Y,Yes
I'll go on ahead then...
Let's go, Conan!
Mr. Mouri, the statue of the goddess
IS up these stairs!!
It takes 15 minutes to get up here!!
He's been stabbed right
in the chest and is dead!!
Father!!
It can't be!! You've gotta be joking
saying that he's dead right, Mr. Moun!!!
I understand how you feel but he's dead!
It.It can't be...
It wasn't supposed to turn out like this...
Vice president please get a hold of yourself!
Huh?! Ayaka, are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine...ll won't be able to
do my job as a secretary,
being rendered helpless at a time like this.
There!
Hi, there, so it's you?
Oh!<Mr. Mouril!
Not you again?
Just what do you mean! Am I supposed
to be the god of death or something?
If so, have the statue of the
goddess help you out this time!
Oh no! I'm just delighted that I get
to hear your superb deduction again!
Doni tell me that this is some«kind
of curse, though!
There are rumors of that sort
going around so...
No such thing!
The killer is among the ones
who were in the ropeway!
What?! Is that true?
Which means the killers
among those people over there?!
Before Eizo disappeared from
inside the cable car,
there was a sound of someone fighting.
Moreover, a strange talisman was
found pasted to the window!
The killer must have
In some way pushed Eizo
from the ropeway onto the tunnel below!
But, no one who was
in the cable car got off
until it reached the top, right?
It s likely that an accomplice
was inside the tunnel.
I"think. that's highly unlikely...
Why you! Keep your big mouth shut!!
Wait a sec. Mr. Mourn!
Conan just what do you mean?
Well, it takes the ropeway only 30
seconds to get through the tunnel!
Even if there were to be an accomplice,
I wonder if it would be possible
to move the victim from the tunnel up
to the palm of the statue of
the goddess in just 30 seconds?
Ayaka, aren't there any secret elevators
or something that can get you
from the tunnel to this observatory?
There is no such thing...Of course,
though...for maintenance purposes,
there is a path leading from the tunnel, to
part way of the stairs of the observatory
That's it! The killer used
that route and killed Eizo!!
But to get from the tunnel
to the observatory
it would take even asmant
who runs at least 3sminutes.
3.3 minutes...?! Wait a sec.!
From the time of the black out to
the time we found Eizo in the palm of
the statue of the goddess,
it took about 30 seconds.
So, if'it takes 3 minutes...
No, I think it takes even more time.
It's unthinkable that Mr. Eizo Dohmoto
would stay quiet being kidnapped!
Which means he would have
had to been killed right away!
However, if someone were to
carry the corpse on his back and go
from the tunnel to observatory , it would
take double the time, 6 minutes, not 3!
No,it would probably even take more!
Right! More unimaginable than the fact
that the victim disappearing
from within the ropeway is that!
It's a curse!!
What sight having to display a corpse
in the palm of the statue of the goddess
It sure is rightful punishment
from the heavens
for Eizo Dohmoto who
has turned money hungry!!
It's too impossible to
be called a homicide!
Don t tell me that this ls really
some kind of curse?
That it really us the fury of the goddess?
) ¥ Nf, 4 \ * 9» Cr ea ph
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi1 Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Télecasting Corporation