Be strong I say to my heart
And step into the essence
with strong rhythm
Today's case is a special one with tricks
It 1s a large scaled, fun-packed episode.
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
The Entrance to a Labyrinth
The Fury of the Gigantic Goddess Statue
Officer Yokomizo,
we've got the results of the autopsy!
The cause of death
was a stab wound pierced right
through his chest with a dagger!
We believe he died instantly)
No fingerprints or palm prints
were found on the dagger.
The estimated time of death is right after
he disappeared from the ropeway.
Well, it's just as was assumed!
Okay, block off the esplanade entirely!
Have that elderly go down
to the foot of the mountain too!
Yes, sir
Sir, what is that shed down below therer
It's a rest"house that the construction
workers were using at the time
they were constructing the tunnel...
It's supposed to be destroyed tomorrow.
Then why is there smoke
coming out of there?
1.I'm not bothering him
Mr. Yasunori Dohmoto, I have something
I d like you to verify for me
Do you have any recollection
of this dagger?
It s one of my father's collection
of. daggers.
Which means someone stole the dagger
Was it under strict security?
0...anyone could've taken it
if he wanted to
- That's not what matters though,
the problem is
Yes?
It's nothing
Really, nothing
He's hiding something...what is it?
Thus case ls about Mr. Enzo Dohmoto
being attacked?by someone w=
and disappearing in the ropeway....!
The talisman that was pasted
on the window
I can't help but come to the conclusion
that the killer is among all of you here!
First, I would like to check
on the motive for killing
Who would benefit most
from the death of Mr. Dohmoto?
If you mean our father's estate
it would be us,
who are his children.
Not really Yasunori s the very one
who would benefit most,
now that he can assume entire power
of the Dohmoto Tours
Junpei!
Yasunori,
aren't you happy now that father is dead?
Now, you don't have to get nagged
on the job either.
In terms of motive, lethink
you guys got as much motive as I do!
You guys =. You mean Mr. Aovagi and 1?
Why me?
You made up scandals of our company,
as well as blackmailed father
by writing letters and
making crank calls beforehand!
But, father ignored you, that's why you
Hold it there!!
Don t tell me that you were blackmailing
father about that story?!
Mr. Aoyagi, what does that story mean...?
Inkorder torgetythis=tunnel*ready in:time,
the construction was started
on an outrageous schedule.
This resulted in an accidental cave-in
One was buried alive
and consequently was left to die
Fearing a bad image falling upon
this Mt. Tenbu ropeway, Eizo Dohmoto
used cash to silence the family
B and the people involved,
to erase traces of the accident!
I was so disappointed at my father
and left the house!
You mean you had the nerve
to blackmail father about it?
You don't have to
make me sound so rotten.
All I did was ask
to be interviewed about it
But to assume that
I was trying to blackmail him,
he really felt guilty about something.
You approached me for that
purpose to begin with, didn't you?!
Well, you are after all, the best of all
witnesses to what happened back then.
What a guy!!
You're pretty good,
eading Rina by the nose...!
But, it seems you couldn't do
the same with father!
Not being able to get
the money you wanted,
you got furious and killed father, eh...?
I didn't kill him!!
Talk for yourself, Junpei.
Father kept refusing to give you a loan. .!
I'll bet you were pissed about it?
E¢ And, what about you, then ,!
That's enough!!
How much shame of the family
do you intend to display to the public!!
Mr. Machida,
your agency Tokai Nippo had an anti
ropeway campaign underway
Still, why was your agency.
Of all the other agencies and the others
that could've been selected,
the one chosen for the first trial run?
Who knows... we've been wondering
about that too.
Don't you think it better
to ask the vice president about that?
Yasunori, would you explain?
Yasunori would you explain?
Well, the president wanted the people
who are against
the development of the ropeway
to be first ones to ride it,
so as to make them understand
how wonderful it is.
I wonder if that's really the reason...?
Could there have been
some other reason...?
By the way Mr Machida
you were all by the door of the ropeway,
weren't you?
Are you insinuating that we pushed
Eizo Dohmoto out the window?
I don't think that's possible
Because the door on Mr. Machida's side
was locked
Moreover, its a double lock and I had the
keys so it couldn't have been opened.
Which means that
you had free access to the door
and could open it If you wanted to.
No, she couldn't have committed
the crime either.
Although it was in the dark,
I think it would've been impossible for her
to move struggling Eizo over to the door
and push him out, with her strength.
I wonder?
I don't think it Is impossible though
I was sitting right next to the door,
but I didn't hear the rattling
of the door opening.
However,
the:window cannot be opened either...
And, the emergency exit doesn't seem to
have been used
hen how...
A, Anyway, will you all please walk on
down to the foot of the mountain!
Let's talk over the details there!
Oh Yasunori,
is it okay for us
to use the special guest room?
Y,Yes of course, please be my guest.
Yasunori sure 1s acting a bit strange.
Yeah I'm sure he's hiding something.
No he wants to say something,
but is hesitant of mentioning it...!
What one earth is it, he wants to say
Come to think of it, back then
Preparations are perfect.
Nobody's noticed anything
The conyversationsback then,
and when Eizo's corpse was found
it.It cant be...
I wasn t supposed to turn out like this
Maybe he was expecting
some other*result .?
Is there such a thing as the curse
of the statue of goddess?
We come to write an article
on it and we end up as suspects
Could this really be some
kind of a curse?
Don't be ridiculous!
We're luc «! This.is'a real scoop!
He other result may be...!
Even if we were to ask Yasunori to come
to the station with us on his own initiative,
we d still have to figure out how Eizo
who disappeared from the ropeway
ended up being found in the palm
of the statue of the goddess
in a matter of seconds 7
That's right.
Well, the biggest problem.
The corpse couldn't have walked all the
way. up to the goddess on its own, so
It couldn't be that
No...but if that were to be the case
It mustzbe that shed....!!
I've found it!
What's this? There something stuck to
1 his»is...*.
Worker's slacks... Just great!
Al I need now Is
Okay! I can use that mop...!
All set.
Hey!!
Just what are you doing here?!!
You scared the wits out of me
What dofyou mean I scared you!
You d get people worried disappearing
all of a sudden!!
I'm sorry
Oh, right, Ran!
What is it?
I'm a bit cold,
so won't you lend me your jacket?
Okay. sure.
Here you go
Thanks! I'll be waiting for you
at the foot of the mountain, then.
Oh, Conan...?!
What 2? You mean
, ounre leavin 1 me: here like this
Just as I thought...!
Yasunori,
in the ropeway you were sitting
Iong side Eizo...!
It's strange that
you didn't notice a thing...!
Just what are you hiding?
L,I'm not hiding anything...!
You re talking
Iike I'm the killer or something...!!
Show me the evidence, will you!!
No, I didn't say
you were the killer or-anything
Since it's such a mysterious case,
we're trying to catch some clues
by questioning all of you
Then why don't you also question
everybody else?
Conan...!
You came down before me, and yet
why are you here after me.
I sort of got lost
Won't you please let us go, already!!
I have no motive
for killing Eizo Dohmoto!!
So, you don't want to have anything
to do with anybody here
because you can't blackmail,
any longer eh...?
I can't stand watching the ugly dispute
over family affairs any longer!!
Watch your mouth!
Well, well, everyone, cool it, all right...!
It'll only be a while longer
Officer Yokomizo!
Why don { we all try
riding the ropeway again?
The ropeway...?
Hey, you stay out of this!!
Yes, let's ride it!!
They say its best to,go
to the site a hundred times!!
We may find something new!!
We're riding that stuff again!
No curse or anything like that
is involved in this case!!
I've figured out why the two journalists of
Tokai Nippo were invited on the test run!
And, the trick as to how Eizo disappeared!
Yasunori's strange remark.
And the wrist in the incinerator!
I'm going to figure the entire mystery
inside the ropeway!!
Mr. Mouri, don't tell me that you're...?
Shut up! Does it bother you?
Oh no!
I'm relieved!
Now that I know that the renown detective
Is just as human as we all are!
Hey, Ran.
Hat...?! Why do something hike that.
Pops said to do it secretly.
Dad said so...?
Okay
10 sheep, 11 sheep
Pops, are you trying to fall asleep
or something?
Don't talk to me
I'll forget what I'm counting!!
What number sheep was it
Okay
I'll let you sleep as much as you want.
It's come
What...?! Mr. Mouri, what's wrong
+ Sorit's finally come!!!
Dad!
Take a picture of him.
He's become the Sleeping Kogoro!
Yes, sir!!!
Yasunorl,
excuse me for all my rude remarks
But I knew from the start
that you are not the one who killed Eizo!
Just as expected of you, Mr. Mouri...!
Didn { you have plans with Eizo to do
something that would surprise everyone
at today's commencement event?
A large-scale scheme
that would get rid of the rumor
of the curse of the statue of goddess that
Is creating a bad image of the ropeway,
as well as something that would be a
great way to advertise the ropeway...!
I will now attempt to replay your plan!
Hat the...?
What on earth us going on?
U myo horen gekyo...
1,It's the same thing
that happened back then!
WwW. What s about to happen anyway?
Cut it out!
RR. Ran is gone?!
Just like the time father disappeared
How on earth...
I,Is something like this possible...
Mr. Mouri,
where did your daughter disappear to?
Please look at the statue co the goddess!
Can't be...
Aaagh?! Look, on top of the palm
of the statue of the goddess!!
Ran...?! No...
A dummy wearing Ran's jacket...?
Exactly! Its made with a mop and
some branches
Come out here Ran!
What?!
U,Under the seat...?!
You thought up this grand scaled,
yet simple plan,
Yasunori, and Enzo acted out...!
Isn't that right!!
Yes..l asked an acquaintance
who us a doll maker
to secretly make a rubber dummy
duplicate of my father
The day before
the commencement ceremony
After I left your party
and started off down the esplanade,
I stopped over at the observatory
to pick up the dummy of my father
that I had asked to be made beforehand,
and put it on the palm
of the statue of the goddess
The palm of the statue of the goddess
can ony be seen from inside the ropeway
that has come out of the tunnel
- . ow
aswy I n ave oworry
about being seen by anyone
You went on to carry out your plan
the following day
during the commencement ceremony
s...after we entered the tun
I severed the circuit cord for the lights
After the lights went out, I immediately,
took my recorder out
and played the chant
After father put on an act of being terrified
he hid in the space under the seat
And, I stuck the talisman
onto the window glass
I'm the one who brushed journalist's
Nakano's camera onto the ground
Because I didn't want the trick to
be disclosed by the flash of the camera
The aisle under the seat is the place
to put emergency goods,
and weights necessary
when the wind is strong but
I had taken everything out beforehand
While everyone was headed
for the observatory,
my father was supposed to go back
to the tunnel using the empty ropeway,
then jump down
After arriving at the observatory,
he took the dummy away from the palm
of the statue of the goddess,
and after throwing it over the cliff,
went up in place of the dummy instead.
He was supposed to greet all of us
who went to check on him with a smile
Well?
Curses and evil spells...
no such things exist in this world!!
He was supposed to convince everyone
that there was no grounds
to the rumor that was going around
and get rid of it all at once.
So, that's why we were invited to come
No, that's not the only reason!
Eizo was planning to frame
Tokai Nippo up!
Just what do you mean
by he was planning to frame us up?
Do you have any idea
why the commencement ceremony
started in the afternoon?
It's probably the whim of the host
Mr. Machida, you sent in an article from
the top of the mountain, didn't you!
This Is Machida!
Please leave one page
of the evenin news o en!
There's been a curse!!
Enzo Dohmoto's been stabbed!
On top of the palm of the statue
of the goddess!!
If Eizo were not stabbed,
would you have been able to change
the article for something else?
The deadline for the evening news
is 13:30!
Right! Your agency would have put false
information in the papers!
In other words,
Eizo's purpose for scheming
this trick was to prove
that no such thing as a curse existed,
as well as to soil
the reputation of Tokai Nippo!
See...!
That's why you said
what you did back then!!
I wonder how long you'll be able to stay
obnoxious like that...
What a dirty thing to do...!!
By the way,
aside from curses and spells,
there is another sad tragedy hidden
behind the tunnel of this ropeway,
isn't there?!
The accidental death of the worker
I heard about it from Rina.
Can you tell us about it, Yasunon?
The person who passed away
was called Takahata
tHis mother was-not only sickly,
but had long years of obligatory feelings
towards the Dohmoto family,so father
forcibly made them agree not to publicize
the fact in return for cash
Did the late Mr. Takahata have
any other family members alive?
I've heard that his father
who had divorced 10 years ago,
took his younger sister
along to Tokyo with him.
It could be that his sister 1s In here
In the ropeway with us this minute!!
What?!
But, the only ones In this ropeway are
Ms. Yoshino... don't tell me that?!
Yes, the one who killed Eizo Dohmoto,
is you,
Ms. Ayaka Yoshino!!
She killed dad...?!
Ayaka is the killer...?! Oh, no
The killer had to be someone
who could act secretly with Eizo,
and someone he would not suspect... .!
Ayaka, who stayed back at the ropeway
station at the top of the mountain
because she wasn't well
got on the ropeway headed downward
Since the station at the top
of the mountain was in chaos
because of what happened
to the president,
nobody noticed you getting onto
the ropeway headed downward....!
Since you were going around
with the president,
you stabbed him on top
of the palm of the statue of goddess.
Then, you burned his dummy
in the incinerator
After you made everything was burned,
you went back to the observatory
where everyone was...!
The only one who could've committed
this crime was you,
who was capable of knowing
the secret between Eizo and Yasunori!
What you just mentioned are
all mere assumptions!
Yasunori,
will you please open the package
that is right beside me?
Yes, Sir
This one, right...?
T, This is...?!
Yikes! What's that...?!
Could this be the the dummy,s wrist?!
This was found left in the incinerator!
When Ayaka burned the dummy,
she dropped something very important
on it's hand .!
What's this...?!
It looks like jewelry or something
Oh no, don't tell me...
Yes...!
The jade that belongs on the broche
that you have on your chest....!
If we enlarge the picture that was taken
during the commencement ceremony,
it is plain to see that
nothing was wrong with your broche
before you got on the ropeway!
It's exactly as Mr. Mouri says
Could you tell us why you did it?
Although our parents were divorced,
I kept in touch
with my brother all the time,
and we used to encourage each other.
Last year when my mother
fell into critical condition
I went to see her at the hospital.
She told me about the mortifying death
of my brother while crying.
As well as the hatred she felt for
Eizo Dohmoto before she died
I hid my identity
and entered Dohmoto Tours
So that I could avenge the death
of my brother
who had been driven
to his death by Eizo Dohmoto,
as well as to take revenge for my mother
who was made to suffer by him
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi lhioka
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro: Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETE aTVE CONAN
OGosho Aoyama / sifogakukan
YIN I TMS
All Rights Reserved
Ayaka...She's so kind and nice and yet
The reason the story of the curse
of the statue of the goddess
were probably handed down
for generations to teach
that if people do wrong
or commit an unforgivable crime,
a ternfying end awaits us...
Just like the case this time...
Ugh! Oh no, I fell asleep...!
Hey where is everybody?!
Hi there, Sleeping Kogoro!!