Be strong I say to my heart
And step into the essence
with strong rhythm
Today we take a slow drive
along a mountain path.
At the bottom of the:valley
is the smell of murder.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
Mt. Ryujin in West Tama County
Tsuzura Ori Pass
Wow! Some hill this is!
We've come so far up.
We've still got a long way to go.
We've only come about half way
Oh no! You've gotta be kidding, me!
What's Up]?
Oh, man...
with all that right and left swinging.
My head's spinning...
Ah come on, what a sissy .
Ha, ha, ha, this place
called Tsuzura Ori Pass,
has a succession of 99 curves,
big and small in all...
Ugh! I'feel nhusented
just listening to you...
Huh where is Mitsuhiko?
Mitsuhiko's reading.a book in the car.
What
Mitsuhiko!
It feels just greatTout here!
No thanks, I'm reading the best part now!
Really, I-tell you!
Um, Doc, Al didn't cme along again.
Uh:oh Al was saying
she had something to do...
Doc, I'll bet you that...
This was what happened
I'm not interested in camps
snuff snuff snuff .
You're really good, Genta.
That's just like her!
Ha, ha, ha bull's eye!
What's that?
Oh no!
Doc! Get the police and an ambulance!
Okay!
GREAT FALL FROM MT. RYUJIN
You said you were resting
at the scenic spot there,
when you witnessed the car go over
the cliff, so you came running over, right?
A dent...
If so
I'd like to ask you once again...
Did you notice something else suspicious,
Iike a car or a person?
No, nothing at all...
- - - a.
I...
Oh...l see
Um, officer...
Hmm?
What is it, sonny?
MAydl.go>and take 1 look At
whatéthe men.are doing above?
No no. it's not something
for a child to watch!
I think they're almost
nished up there anyway...
It should be okay.
But.
But, sonny,
make sure you don't get in the
way of their work when you watch them!
Yes, sir!
Hey, Mitsuhiko,
don't we have to go too?
Huh?!
Conan's going to go off
on his own like always you know!
Oh... who cares,
Iet him do what he pleases...
We've go something better here!
Something better?
Okay, here!
Okay!
Uh...16.33 meters.
LN ended...
there...
It is a piece of polish that rubbed off!
Really?!
Look, it's dark blue!
Dark blue...
W-Which means...
Yeah!
so that's what happened!
We came all the way
out here to have a picnic and
get messed up in an accident like this
It's no accident...
Huh?
What do you mean, "it's no accident"?
Didn't the officer there ask you
if you saw any other cars?
Yeah
That car fell over because it was
pushed from behind by another car.
What?!
That car had a dent in the rear,
an indication of it
having been hit from behind.
Besides,
the paint that seemed to have rubbed off
from the other car was also found.
Moreover,
the car that hit from behind
most likely did so deliberately.
T-then it's homicide
Yeah .
Don't we have to
cooperate with the police
It'll be fine, after all
they've got so much evidence.
But, all they've got Is
rubbed off paint and a dent in the rear...
The Japanese police
is usually very efficient.
So long as a piece of
rubbed off paint is found,
from the color and substance they
can figure out the model of the car too.
Then all they have to do is
go asking around for details
to get to the one who did it.
Mitsuhiko,
what do you mean by something better?
Shh! Quiet! Conan will hear you!
This is it, Genta!
What is this?
It's a code!
A codes?!
Shh!
I picked it up near the site
of the accident just a while ago.
Then, shouldn't you have told
the police about it?
But. what we saw was
just an accident, wasn't it?
It's hard to believe that
a code has anything to do with it.
Right.
Codes are usually used for figuring out
where treasures are hidden, arenst they?
Right, exactly!
Treasure, eh
So, take a good.look at this!
See, on the vepy top. in the(square,
the equation 100-1 is written.
Okay Genta, what is 100-17
Huh 2!
Nnnn .nine...ninety-nine?
Right
Is there something that crosses your mind
when you think of the number 397
Huh
99...99...
Ah!»
911! Ambulance!
Nope!
Whatever gave you
the idea of calling 311 at this point?!
First aid bandage then?
I got it!
The Tsuzura Ori.Pass, right?!
Doc just explained that there is a
succession of 99 hairpin curves,
didn't he?!
Correct!
Which means that this code indicates
a place somewhere
in the Tsuzura Ori Pass area.
And, did you figure out
where it is, Mitsuhiko?
No, but this code sure looks familiar
Where did you see it, Mitsuhiko?
Hmm.
Hey you guys!
What's with all the racket?
Um, ites nothing!
Right, right,
we're not talking about any codes.
Codes?!
Oh. uh, well, the novel that
I was reading you see...
Some codes came out...
They're too easy for you, Conan, so...
On, for children's stuff...
Good gracious...
Okay then, you guys,
Doc and I are going fishing,
don't forget to chop the firewood.
Okay!
Bye.
Here goes!
Mitsuhiko, did you: really figure it out?!
It was in the book that I was reading!
Really!?
This!
What is this?
The keybOard of a computer?
Yes.
Numbers are written in
numerical order from thestop left,
and they correspond to
thessan eshinagana keys!
For instance,
1 and 4 equals the hiragana "ta.
2 and 7 equals "to" and so forth.
All right!
Let's try it!
Genta please read the number codes.
Okay!
0 and 4,
3 and 2
0 and 4 ecuals..-"u'.
2 and 3 equals "se".
3 and 8 equals tsu...
A right turn"?
What is this mark supposed to mean?
Maybe this is the shape of the road?
Right! You're probably right!
That's why the first code
can be deciphered as
Turn right at the intersection!
You're fantastic, Mitsuhiko!
Let's continue!
I'll write it down!
There, it's done!
Please read it
I'll follow along on the map.
Okay!
Turn right at the intersection
after passing Tsuzura @ri Pass.
Turn right at the forked road,
then turn left at the next fork.
Cross two bridges,
turn left after the 2nd bridge and jackpot!
Okay, it's over here!
The pension house is over here,
SO it's pretty close!
Let's go check it out!
Maybe we'll find the treasure!
I'm sure Conan will be vexed.
We:re here.
Hey, are you guys upstairs?!
We've had a big catch!
Hmm?
Hey, badsnews.
The kids-are-nowhere in sight!
What?!
2928101014
Hey, Mitsuhiko...
Are we there yet
We've only got a little:more\to- go,
so hang in there, Génta.
We're cr sing the2nd bridge now.
After we turn right at the next fork,
wed get there)!
We've still got that much more to go.
Hang in there, Genta!
If we find the treasure, you'll get a
Iuxurious serving of eels over rice!!
Eels over rice...
Okay. if we find the treasure,
Nill eat all the eels over rice Il can eat!
Let's go, Mitsuhiko,
for 100,000 eels over rice!
Shoot! This could be
Hmm?! Did you figure it out?
Doc, call the police right away!
What?!
They went to the hideout of the one
who pushed the car over just a while ago!
What?!
So this was the code they were
talking about in the car a while ago...
Darn!
We did it! We've finally come, Genta!
It's over there!
Hey, Mitsuhiko,
are you sure this is the right place?
It doesn't look like it has
anything to do with a treasure, does it?
What a thing to say!
We came exactly where the code said
to go, so it s gotta be right!
Besides, it's places like this
where treasures are usuallyshidden.
Okay, let's go inside then!
Yes, thank you!
The police will rush over
to the site immediately!
Let's hurry on over too!
Okay!
It seems that nobody is in...
Hey, Mitsuhiko, where's the treasure?!
The building farthest beyond...
Huh?!
Look!
That building over there is the only one
capable,of being locked.
Mm sure I's there!
Yep!
Let's check it out!
T-this is...
Wow!
Wow, look at all-those
foreign'.car models!
Hey, Mitsuhiko,
there's no treasure anywhere, though...
Hmm... strange...
Hey, you two...
There's something funny about this 'car...
See...
It"has no license plate.
You're right...
Hey, Mitsuhiko.
There's hone on this one too!
Maybe they're all stolen cars...
Huh!
I'm sure they're planning.to
sell them off to some foreign ountry
We've come to
the hideout of car smugglers!
Exactly!
You're the brats that were
at the site of the the accident...
Phooey!
Who cares!
Where's the guy with
the mustache and the other kid?
Just who are you referring to?
Don't you play dumb with me!
What was that sound?
The sound of gunfire!
What?!
Hurry up will you, Doc?
I know!
I'll ask you once more.
Where's the guy with 4
the mustache and the other kid?
I-I have no idea what you're talking about
What?!
Hey, Mitsuhiko...
Mitsuhiko...
No, I can't get Conan and
Doc involved in something
I got mixed up in
because of my own actions!
He's right
Yeah...
Oh... you must really:want to die.
It's me.
Sorry, I've only got 5 for now. I
Sada chickened out
and rode off with one
Yeah, I took: care .of that.
I hit him from behind at the ridge,
and he fell head first all the way down.
I'm no goof
I'll scrap the car
before the police get to it.
Once it's. scrapped, there's no proof.
That's
Hey, what's with you guys?
What's with you?!
Swinging a rifle around towards children!
Doc!
You're the one who was
at the scene of the accident...
Phooey. there couldn't be better timing...
You saved me time looking for you!
No use, mister.
See, you hear it, don't you?
That police car is headed here:
What?!
They're coming here
to arrest you, mister!
What?!
All ri ht!
Hey, hey, officers...
Before we hear you out,
give us that gun of yours.
Oh, you mean this gun?
. Ijwas only trying to scare the kids
because they trespassed on my]property.
See...
By the way, is that your car?
Yeah, that's right. Anything wrong?
Well. a car happengd to go ove 7
he cliff at Tsuzura Ori Pass...
and it seems that a car
of the same model as yours
pushed that car over from behind.
Your car has a dent too.
And it looks like it struck something...
What?!
Are you suspecting me of something?!
There are several hundreds of cars
Iike this, aren't there?!
Just how many of those
hundreds do you think
happened to be:
at the scene of.the accident?
Andwhere were you.
May-l ask, at that time?
Sorry...that was an accident...
Since the scenery was so beautiful.
I took my eyes off the road...
And the next thing I knew, crash!
He's lying, officer!
Shut up, stay out of this, brat!
No, I'm not shutting up!
You just said on the phone, that you
struck the car and pushed it over the cliff!
I heard you say so too!
Me too!
Hey}officer. are you going to
believe what those brats say?!
Just how do you think it's
possible for me to push a car
over a cliff by crashing into it from
behind at a sharp bend like that?
You did exactly that!
You succeeded perfectly!
Old man! Quit your gibberish!
Do have proof, or what? Proof!
Of course there's proof.
In the foreground of the curve
where that car fell over,
there were two pairs of tire marks,
that were left behind
when the car was hit from behind.
In other words, you collided twice!
So what?!
I wasn't looking at the road
and I collided twice!
Well, there is a possibility too, however...
Do you know the space between
the tires of the car that fell over?
Yes, 1633 meters.
And, at what speed
were you going at on that road?
Just about 30 kilos!
Well, I guess so...
The fact that you were
going at 30 kilos means
you were going at about
83 meters per second
In order to leave skid marks
at a spacing of 1633 meters.
It would take you
approximately 2 seconds.
After colliding into the car in question,
the first time, for a period of 2 seconds,
you never steered
to avoid another collision,
nor did you step on the brakes.
Rather, you collided again!
If this is not called colliding deliberately,
what else would you call it!
So...if you have anything more
you want to say,
we'll hear you out at the station.
Darn!
Mm, officer...
Huh?
There are luxurious cars without
Iicense plates in the'building*beyond.
I'm sure those cars are all stolen!
Good work, all of you!
But- listen.
Don't ever do something
dangerous like this again!
Y-y-yes sin!
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS .BY.
Kanji Kashiwabara
KazunariiKouchi
Junichi Mn ashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatormo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahis1 Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Teritmitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]! K 0 (la ma
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
« muri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
YTV / TMS
All Rifjhts Reserved
Darn I just don't seem to have
the knack for chopping firewood.
Darn, darn it!
Hey, we need more firewood!
Hey, Conan, why don t you
help us a bit on this side too?
No way!
Its your own fault for loafing around
without chopping firewood
Iike you should've been, serves you right.
Yes, yes, all right,
One "yes" Is enough!
Yes!
I hope they learn their lesson and
quit doing dangerous things
How disappointing though...
What is?
Conan deciphered that code
in no time at all!
You were fantastic too, Mitsuhiko!
Not only did you figure out the,code,
you also were right about the smugglers
Oh. I just thought so
because it was in the book I was reading!
Wow, just great.
Maybe! should look through it too.
Oh, I've got just the thing for you, Genta!
Children's Lunch Murder Case
is theititle of it
What a funny title!
I would rather have eels over nice
than a children's lunch
Hey. haven't you guys learned
your lesson or what?!
How nice and bitter!
This is indeed what you call
the world of 'Wabi Sabi'!
Huh
I wonder what's up?
Why is he+looking around like that?
Are you saying that the master
is afraid of a monster?
I wonder if there really is such
a thing as a monster?
D-don't be ridiculous!
No way should such a thing exists!
R-Ryozo has...
THE LEGEND OF THE 5 COLORED
WATER PALACE" Part