A strong heart along
with deduction and power
And step into the essence
with strong rhythm
A mysterious separate building
on the legendary pond.
The windmill turns as
the water changes color.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Mr Mourn.
You-mean that renowned detective?!
Yes, well
I got a notice from Mr. Shiro Suzuki
of the Suzuki financial group,
that someone else would be
attending in his place,
but I had no idea that it would be you.
Don't be too hard on me, please.
Just as expected from the master of the
tea ceremony. What a splendid house!
Jeez, a tea ceremony what a drag...
I wonder why I came along...
Conan, let's go.
Okay.
I guess I'll have to go through with it...
THE LEGEND OF THE 5 COLORED
WATER PALACE" Part I
How beautiful! Fantastic!
What a'terrific scenic view it is!
How wondrous for it
to be glowing golden!
You can say that again!
Is this the first time you've seen a pond?
At this time of year,
depending on the angle of the sun,
the surface of the water changes into
5 different colors.
I seal
So that's why your home is called the
Five-colored water palace"!
Right By the way,
may I 'ask whattyour names are?
Oh, how rude of me.
They are the master's disciples and,
Morio Yakura.(42)
Antique Dealer
this is the antique dealer, Mr Yakura,
Morio Yakura (42)
Antique Dealer
this is theantique dealer Mr. Yakura,
YukarifMimurn (42)
Company Owner
and she is aicompany owner, Ms. Mimura.
Yukari Mimurn (42)
Company Owner
H... Hello!
They are the renowned detective,
Mr. Kogoro Mouri and his family.
You mean that famous!
What an honor.
Now that you are all here,
I will go and inform the master.
Yoshiko Hanazaki (40)
Maid
Master?
The master of the tea ceremony.
How interesting.
I wonder what sort of reception
the finicky master is going to give
Mr. Renowned Detective?
That's why I didn't want to come
Iin his place!
I'm sorry, but Sonoko pleaded with me so
Huh?
The maid
Which means that the master is there
Is that building in the middle
of the pond the tea room?
Huh? Oh, I guess so
The solemn atmosphere is just fantastic!
It is indeed the world of Wabi Sabi!
I'm sure that's the tea room!
Yes! that's right
It is called the "5 Colored Retreat
because it is built on top of the pond
that changes color.
It was built to get away
from worldly affairs,
as well as to forget about time.
I vs called the "5 olored Retreat'?
What a wonderful tea room.
Hello, RR. oichi
He's the master's son
I'v oichi Aonogi (28)
Tea Master's Son
D O OAS
WE SAD MA T=
thank you for coming all this way.
FF « oichi Aonogi (28)
Tiea Master's Son
0 n onus
APE- (
WE SAD WA TF=
Oh, you've already heard about him?
While you're at it why don't you tell
Mr. Renowned Detective
the monster story too?
Monster? What is that about?
Well, it is what you would call
a superstition regarding this pond.
Oh, no, not that please.
I just came to say hello,
so if you will excuse me...
Tell. you, Ms. Mimura,
I thinksyou je overdoing giving
R*oichi a bad time.
Well, let me tell you about it
over some plain hot water over there.
I hear it was towards
the end of the Edo Period.
This pond used to be filled with cold.
Clear spring water,
and was much larger than it is now.
Now, a beautiful woman
appears near the pond.
She plays the flute and changes
the color of the pond,
entertaining all who come to see her.
A wealthy merchant fell for the woman
one day. and married her.
He then built a house near the pond.
The woman married the man &
under one condition saying.
AThefoond is mine,
and no one shall set foot on it."
However,
the merchant breaks this promise,
and builds the bedroom
in the middle of the pond.
Not only does he get angry at his wife
who. clings to him and pleads him to
move the bedroom away,
He kills her and
sinks her body into the pond
One night. however,
a large snake appears from the pond.
And attacks the merchant.
The serpent turns out to be the woman.
She became the monster
that resides in the pond.
Although the merchant is*badly wounded,
he somehow makes it
back to the bedroom.
Since a talisman for keeping away
evil spirits was posted in the room,
he was no longer in danger
of being attacked.
However, the monster kept waiting,
be it day or night,
for the merchant to come out.
The merchant,
exhausted beyond capacity,
is said to have hung himself
in the building
It is still said today,
that the pond changes color
because the monster changes
into the figure of the woman
and appears, blowing the flute.
To think that there is a story
Iike that about the pond...
Everyone!
Thank you very-much for waiting.
Please follow me to the tearoom.
Huh? Isn't « oichi joining us?
Although he is the son of
the master of the tea Ceremony,
he isn't the least bit
interested in the practice
Oh, that sure is a problem.
Uh, I haven't said my
greetings to the master yet, though.
Please excuse the rudeness.
The master rarely comes out recently.
He does not. in particular--
cross this bridge alone.
Master, I've brought the guests
Master?
Maybe the monster ate him up?
Just what are you doing?!
M-m-monster!
How rude of you to look inside like that!
This is a sacred tearoom, understand?!
Away with you!
1 ~.»Leave this tearoom wightithis minute!
Master please calm downy
He is our guest today, Mr. Mouri!
What? A guest
You mean that person
who came on behalf of
Well. well .
Huh? A windmill in a place like that...?
Um, is that windmill there
just for decoration?
That's used to send water
to the river in the garden.
I hear it operates electrically now.
A timer is set-and it moves accordingly.
It used to be famous
as the water used for tea.
But. ever since this tearoom was built.
The amount of water decreased drastically.
Ms. Mimura, the master will hear you!
I'm sorpy for my rudeness 1 while ago.
In spite of-you having come all this way.
Thank you for spending your time here
with me today.
Thank you for inviting us over.
A talisman for keeping away evil spirits.
There are talismans posted everywhere.
Is he afraid of the monster of the pond,
after all?
Master, did you already look at the object
that I asked Ms. Hanazaki
to hand over to you a while ago?
It is an object that had been handed
down for generations,
and given to me by a master
ceramist from Kyushu
Ryozo Aonogi (65)
Tea Master
WEFT MEL (65)
I'm surprised you got hold a of it.
Ryozo Aonogi (65)
Tea Master
H OJQQB
WEF ARIEL (65)
Ryozo Aonogi (65)
Tea Master
¥ DDD
RB) v Cos
3 L\eL
re 2 BL JC
Although it's simply expected of one who
runs a large scale business in antiques.
Ryozo Aonogi (65)
Tea Master
¥ 0&2%¥D
1 O ) so 0
£3 Les
Although it's simply expected of one who
runs a large scale business in antiques.
I shall use that tea bowl during
the tea ceremony to be held this evening.
Thank you very much.
That tea bowl is likely to be very fitting.
It will add glamour to my last practice
of the tea ceremony.
What do you mean by "last"?!
Mr. Mouri, today we have some fish that
is superb as a side dish to drinking sake
that we would like for you to taste.
Ms. Hanazaki,
will you warm up the sake for us?
Master!
Master?
Final tea ceremony?
Just what does he mean?
My feet...are numb!
Dad, how embarrassing!
I'm going to get ready for the night, &
so don't anybody come near the tearoom ID
Yes, master.
Where are you going, Ms Mimura?
I've got another engagement.
Just what do you mean?
I«ll be right back!
How selfish can she be? The master
personally invited us, and yet
Oh, Mr. Yakura, the bath is ready.
Thanks so much.
The water of the pond has changed color!
The reflection from the light is gone,
and the inside of the pond can be seen,
That's why it's green
Next it will change to crimson
when the sun tilts its angle.
Ms. Hanazakil WW-what on earth
happened 'to'this fishing rod?!
W-well...
Master told me to burn it.
I thought...so...
No, Ryoichi!
Ryoichi!
We have guests tonight, so I'd advise you
to wait till the tea ceremony is over.
I know, I'm just going
to put-my-fishing rod away.
Fishing is Ryoichfs only- hobby.
What a cruel thing for the master to do.
But. to suddenly burst out in rage,
and burn fishing goods out of the blue?
I wonder if you can call that
mere foul temperament.
His wife passed away exactly during
the completion of that tearoom last year
She took the legend very seriously
and was against the building
ofithis tearoom to the very end.
It sure sounds familiar
Yes, sort of.
Among us, it is rumored that some have
seen the shadow of the monster.
In other word's, you're saying
that the master has become difficult
to get along with because of his
fear for the monster?
Not really. He laughs it off saying,
It's superstition without any grounds.
I'll go get the bath ready.
L:guess I'll go take a bath then.
Please excuse me
I wonder if there is really
such a thing as a monster
D-d-don't be ridiculous!
W who is I rd
Huh? You're...
Are you bored?
Sort of.
Did you catch that big fish?
Yeah, right!
Conan, there you are!
Oh. I'm sorry
Shall we go to the guest room
and eat some candy?
Okay.
Hey! Conan, where were you?
He was at Ryoichirs room for a while.
There was a large fish print
decorating his room.
Well, Ryoichi is really something.
He invites me to go
night fishing with him sometimes,
but I can't come anywhere near him
when it comes to catching fish.
That's the burglar alarm
Maybe somebody's come.
Huh?
+. Why might she be looking around?
Look, the pond is red now!!
It's SO bright and can't bare looking at it.
00. Just about this tin
the sunlight diffuses reflection
Oh, I'mlso, so hot. Ms Hanazaki,
do you have 'anything cold to drink?
Ms Mimura, where were you?
What? It's none of your business, is it?
Her clothes are falling apart
and she Is sweating profusely.
She must've been in one heck of a rush.
Ms. Mimuratahow rude of you!
He invited you ever, after all, you know.
Phooey. just who the heck
do you think you are?
It's a tea ceremony
that is to be given by the master!
It is utterly rude
to run out on him like that!
Well, come now: both of you.
I hear that after all. this will be the
Iast tea ceremony he 'will be carrying out.
That's it! I'll bet you were dying
to have the master resign!
Just what do you mean by that,
Ms. Mimura?!
I would rather you not
make ugly assumptions!
Oh, all right, all right, I'm so sorry.
Oh, my, how upsetting!
Even the color of the pond looks hot.
What's wrong?
T-that's...
The master!!
¥Father?!
Father?!
Frey, what's with all this blood?!
No good, the door is locked!
Is there 'any other entrance?
The washing basin entrance is behind.
Wellelallk
The door to the washing basin
is also locked!
We've got no choice,
Iet's kick the door open!
Please move out of the way!
Master?!
Master!
No good... he's dead.
Father .
I-ites the legend! Justias in-the legend,
Master was killed by the monster!
Father!
Officer
Wow?! Well, hello there, Conan!
Officer Yokomizo?!.
Which means that Mr. Mouri is also here?
Yep, he's over there.
Hello, Mr. Mouri
I'm sure 'glad to see you again!
I'm sure not happy to see you, though.
Ah, you don't have to hide
your embarrassment.
Officer Yokomizo.,
what we've found out so far is
that this door of
the miniature entrance was locked
from the inside by a long wo den stick.
As for the window,
the sliding door was slightly open,
however, as you can see,
it is blocked by a trellis.
To the east there is the entrance
to the washing basin,
but this was also locked from the inside.
Are you saying
that all the doors were locked?
Yes.
The estimated time of death is
between 15:30 to 16:00.
The corpse was bleeding
However, the direct cause of death is
thought to be suffocation by strangulation
It's suicide. Look at the blood stain.
The master first tried to commit
suicide by slashing his wrist at the porch
But he failed. so then he maybe
he tried slashing his neck?
If so, that explains the blood stains
that are seen all the way
from here to the tearoom.
If he failed to commit suicide
at the porch and tried to hang himself,
he wouldn't have had the time
to lock the room.
The windmill is spinning
Talk about a small entrance!
There are remains of
a thumbtack or something
having been stuck in the back of the door.
Tithe rope is cut in a strange fashion.
It seems to have been cut part way,
but pulled apart towards the end.
The hanging scroll is spreadwwut on the floor.
He must've beenggetting ready for
the tea ceremony to be held this evening.
Although he was getting prepared,
he impulsively chose to die.
I guess that's what happened.
The writing is only half done
This rubbish? Wooden shavings?
Even on the tatami floor...
I see!
It's wood from the pillar
that the rope was tied onto.
Th...?7 But, there is a scrat
on the wood that served as support.
I can't see too well.
Hey, when the heck did you get in here?!
Sto>y ettin in the wa!
Will you carry me on your back?
What the heck are you talking about?!
Get out of here!
Hey, hey!
Just as I thought!
Marks of friction are left on places
other than where the rope was hung
Moreover, it's still new...
Suit yourself!
He was killed by the legendary monster?
Do ou expect me
a police.o ficer, to believe that?
T-there's no doubt about it.
From the blood stains on the porch
to the fact that he hung himself,
it's all so similar to the legend!
There may be no monster,
but he was killed as the legend said...
so it's just as if he were killed
by the monster after all.
This tearoom shouldn't have been
built after all.
Right after the completion of the tearoom
his wife dies of a heart attack
And, now the master...
This is unmistakably
the doings of the monster.
Which means...
He seems to have been pretty
worn out mental, ,
so I'm pretty sure he committed suicide.
Yes.
No, this is not suicide!
It's homicide!
Lymisu e that someone here schemed
a'very-clever trick and killed the master.
After making it look like
he committed suicide!
Who could have done this .
Who is pretending to be the monster?
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunar)-Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR.
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
T1kashit Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Tik1hisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]! Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE. ONAN
QGosho Aoyama / Sr¥ogakuka
YTV / TMS
All Rifhts Reserved
The way this rope is tied...
Maybe...
What? What's with you always making
tributes of expensive containers?!
Speak for yourself!
I hear that you're after the seat of
the master,
that you invested to the point of virtually
running your company bankrupt!
I'll bet that all you're concerned about is
how it looks on the outside
and don't care about
how it looks on the inside!
Care only about how it looks like
on the outside"...