A strong heart along
with deduction and power.
Step into the essence with strong rhythm
A pond that changes color
with the passing of time
turns crimson. and the case is solved.
He sees through the one and only truth.
# A child in appearance
with"the LQxof an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
We attended a tea ceremony
on behalf of Sonoko
and her father.
To be held at the Aonogi residence
There is a pond in the garden,
where the color of the water
changes into five different hues.
And, in the center is a tearoom that is
accessed by a connection corridor.
We were enjoying ourselves looking
at the pond when the incident occurred.
The master had hung himself and died!
Moreover, he died
exactly like legend had it
No this is not suicide!
It's homicide!!
I'm sure that.someone here schemed
a very clever trick and killed the master,
after making it look like
he committed suicide!
What is the true identity of the real
monster that is posing as the monster!
THE LEGEND OF THE 5 COLORED
WATER PALACE" Part ll
So. at a little after1 6:00. when everyone
gathered in this room,
ou all saw the master s corpse
rom this veranda...is that right?
Yesqythe water of the pond was
just changing crimson.
Yes~ythe water of the pond was
Moro Yakura
And besides, . oichi looked at his
wristwatch to confirm the 'time.
Yes, it was 16:00 sharp.
Yes, it was 16:00 sharp
« oilchi Aonogl
& O&OLY
« oichi Aonogl
D&3LY
. * Cts Ne -e
I looked towards the tearoom then,
but my father's corpse was still not there.
« Oolchi Aonogt
« D3)
I looked towards the tearoom then,
but my father's corpse was still not there.
It happened right after
Ms. Mimura returned
Where were you all at that time?
I was:taking a bath for about 30 minutes.
I had some business to attend to
and went out for a while.
Where did you go?
It was something personal...!
I don't have 'to answer you!
What about you; Ms. Hanazakir
«MN °
Ws In the kitchen making
preparations for the evening
and taking care of the guests here.
And you, Ryoichi?
As...going in and out of the guest root
I hear that the master burned
your precious fishing rod?
W.,Well...you see . that's...
Tell us what really happened?
I was told to attend
the tea ceremony tonight
It seemed that he wanted to
announce my becoming
his successor at the ceremony.
But you don't know an thing
about the practice o tea!
No way! He couldn't have possibly
said something like that!!
And, did you accept the offer?
No way! I refused!
In other words, the master
burned your fishing rod
because you wouldn't listen to him?
And, you hated him because of that?
P.Please wait.
Officer Yokomizo.
When the master was killed,
everyone including Ryoichi was
here in this room.
Exactly.
If in fact someone did go over to kill him
as you can see, we would've
witnessed it from the veranda.
I was sitting in that chair all the while,
no one was seen going to the tearoom...!
Which means everyone has a perfect alibi
Ms. Mimura brought something in
'hen she returned.
She looked to be concerned
about people seeing her
But. she couldn't possibly had time
to hide anything
Which means
Could that be it?!
This is it after all! Just as I thought!
Could I please have a glass of water?
I'm sorry,
I'm so thirsty
Here you go
Thank you so much
I'll make some tea for everyone
else right now.
Um, Ms Hanazaki.
Oh, yes sonny
Why doesn't Ryoichi want to succeed
the master despite being an only child?
WwW, Well...
Hey, keep out of this, kid!
But, yes, why?
I didn't want to become like my father.
Father was so haught
that mother was always crying in sadness.
But, isn't it only natural for a father
to want his son: to take over
the seat of the successor that has been
handed down for, generations?
Becoming a master means giving
speeches and lectures.
The pay is really good,
and you get to own tea bowls
that have been handed
down for generations.
That's all father was. ver interested in!
So, if he passes the seat onto you,
he can go on living the way
he has up to now.
That's what I didn't like about father
Let me help you, Ms. Hanazaki.
Oh, thank you.
If you didn't like him so much.
Why didn't you leave the house?
H Hey!
Right . well.
I was gone for quite a while actually
I had him come back because I was
burdened takingfcare of the master alone!
I OTC.
I came back on the condition
that I would not succeed my father!
He didn't have anyone to manage
his money,
so he said I could come back
if I handled accounting for him.
Really greedy, I tell you.
But, he asked you to be
his successor again.
Accounting? Then you know how mutC
money and estate the Aonogi family has,
don t you?
Hey!!
Is he right?
In the event your father dies before
his successor is decided on
you inherit all his estate, don't you?
Not to mention that the seat of the master
is free for you to do 'as you please
What was your real reason
for coming back home?
How rude!
Master had health problems!
Why else, but because
he was worried¥about his father!
It's okay thank Ms. Hanazaki
I'm. going to put this away
So. the master, being afraid of
the monster of the pond
stayed confined in the
tearoom where talisman
to keep it away were posted everywhere
Moreover. he extremely hated
anyone coming near the room.
Yes, he even had an alarm set up
to keep intruders away
Which means that it would be
difficult for an outsider to come in
Right
and the tearoom is surrounded
by the pond.
If anyone were to go by the only
corridor there us here,
somebody would've. seen:the person
How did the killer do it...
What's with you...!!
I'll bet you thought you were deceiving the
master by offering him expensive bowls,
but let me tell you, he wasn't dumb!!!
Talk for yourself!
L.hear you invested so much money
to the point of running your
company bankrupt!
Hold on a minute please!
All'lim asking is your relationship
with the master.
Phooey!
Huh? What's with this tea cup
Ms. Hanazaki! There's a crack in this cup.
Oh, I'm very sorry.
Dl bet that all you're concerned about is
how it looks on the outside
and don't care about how it
Iooks on the inside!
Care only about how it looks like
1 the outside...
Comeacome now,
I'm sure she's upset after all
that is. happening so.
I wonder? Ms. Hanazaki. I'll bet you're
glad that the master's dead...?
After all, he's the one who lead his wife
who was taking such good care of you
to her death!!!
I would never!
M's Hanazaki really too Al"
good care of father!
My! For all I know, I'll bet you both drove
master to commit suicide with
all your talks about the monster?
W What?!
How absurd!
Ms Hanazaki.
Ms- Hanazaki
How dare she say that I hated him.
Don't let her bother you. Like you already
know, she's always like that.
Is she his wife?
She looks very kind
She really was kind,
that just looking at
her picture comforts me.
That's why I have so many pictures
of her here.
She never got down on me for not
Iiking tea ceremony!
She used to keep company fishing too.
The knot!!
There! Somebody forced himself by here.
If my deduction is correct
Just as I thought.
Which means the killer
must be the person who was acting
at the time the corpse was found!
There must-begsome evidence
that-theskiller left behind.
That's!
I've found unmovable evidence!!
Thank you so much everyone.
Okay, so how I get to go home.
Yes, since there is no doubt it was suicide.
Darn
Of all things
Oh, Conan, we're going home!
Where's Pops?
He'll be down right rio"
Okay!
Yawn
SO it's over with.
Time to"head home
Sure; after you take a snooze!!!
All we have to do now is wait for
the coroner's report.
Yes, sir
Officer!
Pops is saying,