Be strong I say to my heart
And step into the essence
with strong rhythm
The Youth Detective Squad»
go mushroom hunting.
Beware of evil hunters.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ of an adult,
no case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan
MUSHROOMS, A BEAR AND THE
YOUTH DETECTIVE SQUAD" PART I
if!» AA.
Listening everyone?
We are going mushroom picking
However. you are not! free
to pick all you want.
Adults get to pic sup to three
and children up to two!
We'll cook the mushrooms
you-picked"back=at theOinn.
Okay!
Oh, and pass the two wire fences
is the hunting grounds,
so don't ever go inside!
Hunting grounds?
Bears appear!
B Bears?
But. don't you worry! There is
none on this side so rest assured.
Hey, come on, what a place
to go mushroom hunting.
I tell you!
At first he made it sound like there were
Ioads of mushrooms growing everywhere
There's nothing around, darn!
There, there!
It's all your fault, Genta.
You're the one who said let's go
mushroom picking, right?!
I really wanted to go apple picking
But mushrooms are the thing
to eat¥during autumn!
And besides, mushrooms are way
more expensive than apples, right.
Oh, but an apple is the forbidden fruit,
the fruit of knowledge,
that taught right from wrong
that Adam and Eve ate,
and was banned from
the Garden of Eden by God.
I think apples are way
more mystical than mushrooms.
If it's the fruit of wisdom it'd do
you good to eat a whole lot of it, Genta!
Shut up!!
The Old Testament eh!
Although the saying that the fruit was
an apple is just popular belief.
Hmm, what's up, Mitsuhiko?
What's with that look on your face?
Huh! What look on my face!
I was just looking at her.
You mean Al?
Yes...
Although she's very blunt sometimes,
I think she's actually very
sophisticated and diverse?
As well as very
much of an adult.
Don't you think there's
this mysterious air about her?
Oh, but that doesn't mean that
I have special feelings for her
or anything like that you know...
Hey. Mitsuhiko, take itsfrom me,
stay away from hen!
She's not one you can handle...
Hey... look, look...
It might be a Mushroom!
Oh, that's a poisonous
« Mushroom called agar-agar.
I can't take this anymore!!
How the hell do we look for
mushrooms without any hints!
There are hints!
Look around carefully!
See the pine needles that are yellow green!
Mushrooms get their nutrition by sticking
onto the root of Japanese Red Pines,
¥so they are slightly weakened and
the needles change color;like that.
So, that's the 'place to look
Moreover, for mushrooms to grow,
good sunshine, good drainage of
water and ventilation is a must.
If you check out the area
with those things in mind...
See, you got what you want!
What a fine mushroom this is!
It sure looks delicious!
That's our first pick of the day.
Please look, everyone!
There are red pines with
yellow green needles over there too!
Oh, really?
Okay: I'm going to find sone too.
Yellow green needles...
Under...red pine trees.
I've found a mushroom too!
Ex, WO OO
Picking mushrooms does resemble
treasure hunting in a way,
and is quite a lot of fun.
You can say that again!
Hey, where's Genta
Come to think of it,
I haven't seen him around for a while...
Il Mm sure he's off somewhere using
the men's room or something.
Well, he was gulping down
a lot of mineral water so...
He'll be in big trouble
if he gets lost in a forest like this!
Let's go back and check!
Okay!
Genta went pass the first wired fence?!
RR. Really?
Yeah! No doubt about it!
Theysoil is still new and
the spacing is narrow.
It's proof that a child went over the fence
Besides:-there a lot of red pines
with yellow green needles
that I mentioned on the other side
of the fence too...
Good gracious ..Genta's Youth Detective
badge is under repair right now so
I can't use the tracing glasses either...
I've no choice
I:llggo look for him so you all stay here...
You're going off on your own again,
and planning to get the
credit all for yourself, aren't you?!!
Well go look for him together with you.
Because we're worried about him tool
B But on the other side of the fence
How about this?
Ill go as a pair with Mitsuhiko.
You go with Ayumi
Let's split up and loo «for him!
In the meantime Genta may come back
here, so Dr. Agasa, will youlwait here?
Well, it's more effective than looking 1
around for him alone, isn't it?
W Well, I guess so
But, be careful, Al
Two fences,down is the hunting area.
It's not unusual that people picking
mountain vegetables} are-mistaken \
for animals and shot by hunters, in Japan.
Oh, thank you.
So, you're worried about me
Anyway .
Let's all meetihenre in an hour.
If we can't find him, let's have the people
at the inn help us search for him.
Let's get started
Hey, let's get tot!
Let's go!
Oh...
O; Okay!
Hey:Genta!
Where are:you. Answer me!
Pp darn!
I wonder-where.on earth he is.
That Genta...
Genta
Genta; where are you?!
Uh, may I ask you a question?
Is there something
between Conan and you?
Something?
Well, you two are always sneaking off
and talking in an adult
Iike manner with each other...
You seem to understand
each other realy well
You both have. sort of,
a world of your own...
Oh, don't let it bother you,
because it's not something
all that romantic.
B But
Come on, let's go!!!
Uh, wait
What was that sound...?
It came from beyondyr
the two wired fences, didn't it...
The wired fence is torn-apart...
He.could've gone in beyond from here
I.It can't be .
The hunting grounds is beyond here!
If he got beyond-the first: fence,
and got lost in the forest in between,
he wouldn't be-able to tell
whether the hunting grounds is
beyond these red pine bushes, would he?
Oh, wait for me
Genta?!
Come on. You worried us out of ourewits.
B.8.818 Bear...
No sweat!
It's still a cub!
It doesn't even seem to be a year old yet.
How cute.
I...l guess so.
But, we've got to be careful,
because I'm sure the mother bear
IS somewhere nearby.
What!! What!! What!!
S, Sound of gun fire?!
Don't tell me that the mother of this cub
was shot by a hunter...
Oh no! Don't run that way.
There! It's a hunter!
L<hope he doesn't think that we're prey
Hey! We're people!!
This Is
This wound
Is a rifle wound ..7!
It can't be?!
Hey! Don't shoot, please!
We're people.
Don't you see? That hunter is after us!
He thinks that we've witnessed a murder
and he wants to shut us up!!
What!!
Genta, that's enough!!
Do you have any idea of how worried
we Were about-you I
1.1 mM really sorry...
I was trying to pick mushrooms
for everybody,
and before I knew it I went on in beyond...
Of all things!!
Well, well, either way,
you came back safely.
And, did-you contact Ai and Mitsuhiko?
Well'. I've been trying-to contact them
for a while now.
But I'm not getting any response...
Ghads,,.now it's those guys.
- .W Ddad
Wm Ddade
an II
Hey. hey!
The response from Mitsuhiko's badge
Seems to be
coming from the hunting area here!
What?
Strange, after all they should know that
they are not supposed to go inside.
Ghads, let'sffind them while it's still bright
and go backt o the inn-befor Sit gets.dark!
Hey, hey, I can't make up here!
Talk about helpless.
What's up.
Coming to a place with children?
What's up,
coming to a place with children?
& Kiyoshi Yasaka
Two children seem to have got lost
in here, so we're looking for them
Did you see a boy and girl
somewhere around here. mister
Hey! Here's Mitsuhiko's Youth
Detective Squad badge!!
Really?
But...the two are...
nowhere in sight...
Blood stains!
Hey! What are these big footprints?!
It's the footprints of a bear
What! which means that
they were both eaten by a bear?!
I don't think so.
Bears are basically afraidiof humans,
and besides they don't
take human's to be .beasts of prey
But, that's true
when it'"comes to that¥centain bear!!
Matasaburou Saika
REESE 3
BSZ=EB (6
If it's the one who has a grudge
against humans,
Matasaburou Saika
» Reed 2
fifiiil=fili (67)
the two kids would be a feast for the bear
before it goes into hibernation!
Matasaburou Saika
332 =EB (67
the two kids would be a feast for the bear
before it goes into hibernation!
Yes, if it's that one eyed
Japanese bear, Jubeilll
O Oh, no
I see! So the rumor about the bear
was true after all...
My having come all this. way was worth it!!
Don't worry, girlie,
I'll avenge
the death of your friends for you!
Tomoya Negoro
RE Xt (28)
What do you mean avenge the death of?!
We:don't even know whether
they were attacked, by the bear yet!
At any rate,
Iet us help you look for the children.
Yeah! After all we know this mountain
better than you do!
Sorry, girlie.
Hey, Mitsuhiko!
Ail;
It's Conan and the others!
See! On the other side of the forest!
Hey!
Wait!!
The hunter we saw a while ago
Is with them tool!
What?! But, why?
Probably to block our path of escape,
since we witnessed him
committing the murder.
If we go out carelessly
we'll be shot to death!
And, he'll probably justify himself saying
that he thought we were the bear.
Hey. All
Where are you, Mitsuhiko!
Answer us if you re around somewhere!
Another piece of potato chip
on the ground!
It's not stale yet, and
I'm sure the two left it behind as a trail!
They're.trying to showtus
the road they took.
Hey! Shouldn't we look for Ai's badge
using Conan s glasses?
Can't do, because her badge
is on my desk at home.
I was testing whether
the transmission*function of your badge
that is under repairgis working well, so...
Oh, no...
Hey, Doc.
Can you verbally describe the place
where I found Mitsuhikosbadge
a while ago. can't you?
Yeah, because it was near the place
the wired fence was torn apart.
Then, tell the person at the inn where it is,
and have the police check
that area together with you!
What? The police?!
Don't: ou think it's strange
that a trail of their path is left behind,
and yet we can't catch up with them
no matter how hard we try?
Aren't they running from the bear?
No. there were blood stains
around the area
where Mitsuhiko's badge was found...
There was a brand new bullet mark
on a tree nearby too.
Maybe it's not the bear that the two
are running from, but rather...
Hey, don't tell me that.!
Could it be Mitsuhiko and Al?
H,Hey! What's with you!
Shoots, it got away...
A rabbit?
Are you guys out of your mind?
What if it were the two kids ys.
I've got eyes good enough to
distinguish a prey from the kids.
Don't you worry even if
that bear Jubei comes out.
I ll get him with the swiftness
you just saw...
# That flimsy shot:of yours
wouldn't even skim by him!
What?!
If you treasure your life,
don't shoot even if Jubei appears!
The minute he senses the smell of
humans, he'll sneak soundlessly up to you.
A bullet shot will not kill him.
He is a monster of over 2 meters!
I'm the only one who can hunt him down!
Because I'm the one
who got one of his;eyes 20 years ago...
What's with that old man, anyway...?
He's a well know hunter in this area.
I hear that heused to. be a hunter
in the mountains of the
Tohoku region in the past...
But, since he ran into Jubei here,
he's decided to stick around it seems...
He was a hunter?
Yeah, the boss ofga group of hunters
I guess we don't have!to worry about
when the bear shows up then
Doc, will you make the call
Oh, all right...
Just as I thought.
That hunter was going to fire at us
the minute we showed. 'up in front of him.
B.But what if we shout out loud
and wait in the middle of the'road?
They've got little Ayumi
on their side you know
He may be thinking of taking her hostage pg
and killing everybody off.
After all. he's already murdered someone.
OO. Oh no...
Judging from how he looked
when he fired at us,
it seems that he came into the mountains
with a hunter that he had a grudge against
and shot him to death...
But, don't you have to submit papers
before you're allowed to hunt?
If the corpse is found,
wouldn't he be the prime suspect,
being that he came in together
with the one he killed?
Not really. You"can submit
the papers way before you come.
Then, you're allowed
to come and hunt anytime
between the duration of the permit.
You don't need to report
when you're coming.
In other words,
if you make the person that
you're planning to kill submit the papers,
and you go on and make
yourself a fake alibi,
even if the corpse is found, chances are,
the officers will think that some hunter
had mistakenly fired at him...
WwW. Which means that
since we saw what happened...
Yes his plan went down the drain.
He's probably dying to kill us.
T.Then maybe we shouldn't have made
ajtrail with potato chips,
to let them know where we are,
but rather escape through the woods...
No! Moving.on our own in a forest
we are not familiar with is dangerous.
We have no way of
getting out of these mountains
without joining Dr. Agasa anyway
we'll be fine! If you dropped your badge
near the corpse
I'm sure that Conan will notice
something is wrong
Yes, I'm sure he will
Come on, we've got to think while walking
if we want.to<save ourselves
We've got to figure out a way to let Conan
alone know the predicament we're in...
Not only for ourselves do
we have to be careful,
Iso for this bear cub... th
some reason is coming along with us.
Y We don't want to endanger it; do. we!
N No.
I'll bet'a bear did this
The bear peeled off the outer wood
with its nails
and ate the sweet wood on the inside!
The space between the nails is wide
and it's pretty high too.
It:s'a pretty big one.
It's Jubel!
Huh?
Look,
she's bitten the tree together with the cub
that she gave binth to this winter
B.Birth to? Isn't Jubei a male?
You mean-you don't know???
It has been said:since the days of old
that the god who resides in the mountains
IS a Jealous goddess.
In order to. complete hunting safely,
it is necessary to avoid
the envy'ofimountain goddess,
% that's why the bear'has a male's name
She was named after the superb,
one-eyed 'swordsman, Yagyu Jubei
Yiou mean it's a female bear
that:is der 2 meters in height.
L-sure gotta-get a-look at this one.
All do anything to get to see it
Huh?
Is there anything on my face, mister?!
Oh, no, it's just that you talk so much
Iike one of my friends that I...
Um. is that friend of yours here
in the*mountains today, by any chance?
Huh
Because when you took your.camera .out
a while ago I saw a shotgun!
The bullet of that,gun splits
into 9 directions and flies#doesn't. it?
But the one you fired a while ago
was a one-direction gun...
I've heard that there is no hunter
that carries two types of 'bullets
when hunting...
My friend forgot to take his extra bullet
and went intotthe mountains without it.
I thought I'd give it to him if I ran into him,
and brought it along with me
But, will he be okay?
Your friend's still in there alone, isn't he?
He'll be fine!
He's been here many times,
and we always hunt
apart from each other anyway.
Do you sense something, Ayumi?
Oh, no, it's nothing
Hey, they're starting off!
Y,Yeah...
Hey, Ayumi!
Wait for me...
- wv ow »
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michithiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR.
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kudnnm
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In associition with
Yonfwur: Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
QGosho Aoyama / Sr¥crga§uka
YTV / TMS
All Ri8hts Reserved
DETECTIVE CONAN
OGosrro Auyama / Shogakukan
YTV / TMS
AILRIgWts Reserved
He's here!
Without a.doubt...
The murderer is
among the three!!
He probably wants to shut
Al and Mitsuhiko up
for having witnessed the murder!
Don't come out!!
MUSHROOMS, A BEAR AND THE
YOUTH DETECTIVE SQUAD" PART II