Be strong I say to my heart
And step into the essence
with strong rhythm
Ail and Mitsuhiko are at bay
Mushrooms on skewers, can they tell
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case 'istleft unsolved with
Detective Conan
We, the Youth Detective Squad, went into
mountains to hunt for mushrooms!
Absorbed in what he is doing,
Genta walks into the hunting area...
We split into two to look for Genta.
Ail and Mitsuhiko finds
the dead body of a hunter who ls shot
and end up being the target
of the killer themselves!
Ayumi and I ran into Genta and
went along with the three other hunters
to search for Al and Mitsuhiko, however...
MUSHROOMS, A BEAR AND THE
YOUTH DETECTIVE SQUAD" PART II
This is the last chip...
We've nothing left to drop anymore, Al.
A Air!
What's wrong?
I think I sprained it slightly
when I fled a while ago...
I was trying to walk
despite the pain, but...
Will you let me take a look at it?
I'm sorry...
H.Hey!
Your leg is swollen purple!!
I'm going to give you emergency
treatment right now, so you stay put.
Emergency treatment...
You mean you've got bandages on you?!
Nope!
But, these scissors and towel will do!
See, if you cut at every other interval
Iike this, it makes a perfect bandage...
Doesn't it!
Wrap this twice around the ankle,
go from the heels over to the top
of the feet, and back to the ankle...
Then, repeat this several time,
wrapping it firmly...
Finally, set it into place
and tie it firmly and it's all done.
Wow, you're pretty good.
Actually, when I sprained my leg
at camp some time back,
C..Conan
did the same for me,
He... sure knows a-:lot of things
and is really admirable...
Moreover,
he's moves on his own intiative...
I could never even come
close to him in any way .
Silly you...
Huh?
The important thing is not
who you learned of that knowledge from,
but rather, where and how you use it...
You're the best rescue person
around for me right now.
Thank you. You sure are a great help.
Oh no problem...
I'm happy to hear that...
Anyway...
It's dangerous staying in
the middle of a mountain path!
Let's sit down in the forest
and think things out!
Of how to let Conan and the others
know about us!
Yes, I guess so...
What?! What was that!
Are you serious?
Yes! The dead-body of a man 4
hidden under branches and leaves
was found near the place
you;mentioned-torme *
Something about him being shot in the
stomach and having died instantly...
\ Oh, and the dead body of a bear cub
seems to have been buried nearby too.
A bear cub?
Yeah, but this one seems to have had
a'rock placed over where it was buried.
At any rate,
it's dangerous in the mountains!
Leave looking for the kids to me
and you all get out of the
mountains right this minute!
Hey, is anything wrong?
And you all get out of the
mountains right this minute!
W Well...
A bear cub! We thought we found the two,
but there were two bear cubs.
We're having the owner of the inn
that we're staying at look for the two too.
Oh, what a scare.
Come on, let's go after them!
We'll be In a fix if the sun sets!
1 O on 2
» oda"
Hey! Why are you hiding the truth?
Don't tell me that maybe the killer
is among one of the hunters...
It's not a maybe! The killer is...
among them!
The killer is
undoubtedly,
among the three!!
What?!
He's planning to shut Ai and Mitsuhiko up
because they witnessed the murder.
Then, why is he looking for
them together with us?
He's blocking their path, and waiting for
them to show up on their own...
He's going to say that he shot them
because he mistook them for a bear...
And, do you have any idea
who the killer is, Shinichi?
N™wnot at all...
There aren't enough clues around..."
But, don't worry!
I'm sure that the two who are
witnesses will tell us who the killer is...
They'll let us know in a way
that only we'll be able to understand...
Hey, look, there are a lot of mushrooms
on the ground here!
Huh? Where, where?
What's with all this?
There are three mushrooms
skewed to a branch!
The other four are scattered about.
The names of the mushrooms
that are skewered are,
from the top,
Tengudake, Matsutake, Shiitake...
The ones on the ground are,
3 Shimeji, and 1 Hatsutake...
Hey, Is there some meaning
to the mushrooms?
I wonder.
No, don'timove!
But, I wonder if they'll figure it out?
They will!
That's something he really likes.
A code that we twisted
our brains and thought out!
Nonsense!
It seems we don't have to
worry about them!
They re absorbed in picking mushrooms.
Let's hurry on along then!
Strange, I was sure
there was something to it, but...
Hey, Doc, stay back!
I've figured it out!
I've identified the one who is trying
to get rid of Al and Mitsuhiko!
What?!
Get ready for this.
I'll put you to sleep with this
anesthesia gun in a sec.
What are you doing; Conang
Get out of the way!
It won't hit the killer who's right there!
The killer??
The killer is there, among the three!
But, how do you know?
What else can it be? Al and Mitsuhiko
are dropping potato chips to let us know
where they've walked by and yet,
they're running from us.
The police-had already found
the corpse together
with the bear cub a while ago and,
The dead body of a bear cub?
Conan IS aiming something at someone!
It's his wristwatch type anesthesia gun.
It seems he's figured out
the message we left behind.
When he shoots the needle into the killer,
we've got to carry the bear cub
and join Doc and the others!
Okay!
Huh?
WwW, Why?!
Hey!
Let's cut out this stupid cat and mouse
game!! What do you say, Mr. Killer?
Killer?!
What...?
I figured out who the killer is,
by decoding the mushroom message...
The mushrooms total 7 in all
It stands for all seven of us.
The 3 mushrooms that are scattered
stand for three kids
The big Hatsutake stands for Doc.
And the other three
that are skewered onto the branch
stand for the three hunters
and the rifles they are carrying.
I see, I get it!
The only poison mushroom that
Is skewered on is the Tengudake!
Which means that the killer is carrying
the rifle on his right shoulder...
D,Don't be ridiculous...
Wrong!
Everybody who: knows theymountains
knows that the Tengudake
is a poison mushroom.
If the killer figures it out first,
then everything will go down the drain.
Then which is the killer?
Remember,
I thought you how to look for mushrooms,
using tracking down
a criminal as an example.
See! You've got the criminal!
It's the Matsutake!!
I see!
Only we know about that.
Yeah, In other words,
the killer that.-the code indicates is
you!!
Yeah, In other words,
the killer that the code indicates Is you!
Mr. Matasaburo Saiga!!
What?!
The police have already found the corpse.
I don't have verification yet, but I think
its: the:man with small eyes, your friend!
What!
Al and Mitsuhiko coincidentally set foot
into the scene of the crime
and found the body...
So, Mr. Saiga fired at them...
That's why Al and Mitsuhiko figured
that they would be killed for
having witnessed the murder!!
H,Hey, gramps?!
H,Hey!!
He's got a rifle you know!
Hurry and use your anesthesia gun...
So, you can't take it anymore, can you...
Hey. Shinichi?!
No, he didn't fire at Al and Mitsuhiko
to kill them.
The real reason he fired is...
Don't come out!!
H, Hey...
MI. ricy...
W,What is that .14
Ju, Jubei...
I won't let you get away brat!!
If you show your back as you flee,the bear
will instinctively think that you are prey.
Without taking your eyes off him,
back off slowly.
Jubel! Don<t you know me!
Calm your anger down
and go back to the woods.
You've got to get ready to hibernate,
don't you.
You'd better hurry or the other bears
will take away all the good caves!
Go on! Jubeu! 60!!
Jube!
Ail! The bear cub! Give her back her cub!
The bear cub that is near you
IS probably Jubei's cub!
If you're carrying the cub, let it go!
Right, Mr. Saiga fired his gun
in order to save Al andiMitsuhiko...
as well as Jubel.
The hunter that was killed
probably tried to kill Jubei...
And in order to prevent that
Mr. Saiga shot that hunter...
Since Al and Mitsuhiko happened
to come along just then,
he fired a threatening shot at them
before Jubei had time to notice them,
and them flee away from where they were.
The blood stain that was found
near Mitsuhiko's badge
that was on the ground, is probably one
that dripped then...
But, He could've told them verbally
rather than fire at them...
Like I think<$you've noticed
just a while ago,
bears are extremely sensitive
beyond imagination
If the two were at a distance where it
was hard to still hear someone shouting,
and if the shooter was confident
about his marksmanship,
this would've been easier than
trying to relay something verbally.
Isn't that right, Mr. Saga?
Hey, hey, hold it! We came into
the mountains to hunt, you know.
Why do we have to get killed for
shooting a bear?
Moreover, it's the bear that
the old man has been raving
about being really vicious...
Besides, aren't you the one who shot
the eye of the bear and damaged it?!
Yeah,
that's right.
It's the same as if
I had damaged Jubei's left eye...
I'm alive and kicking in exchange
for Jubei losing her left eye...
In exchange?
It was 20 years ago
I came to this mountain
was still deeply covered with snow
In the spring to hunt bears.
I slipped from carelessness.
I fell several meters below
and broke both legs.
I couldn't even utter a word
Jubei appeared before my eyes when
I could not budge an inch on my own.
I gave up thinking that I would be eaten.
So, I closed my eyes...
That was when I felt this strangely
warm thing touch my face...
I frightenedly opened my eyes...
Jubei was licking my wound
over and over again...
After she finished licking every part of me,
of all things she fell asleep beside me.
Whether she was planning to eat me
after getting up,
or whether she mistook me
to be one of her kind
because of the black fur I was wearing,
I never found out...
But, It was a really comforting time for me.
I felt so good,
I almost forgot the pain in both my legs...
Then a gun shot echoed
through the mountains,
and she lost her left eye...
She left my side...
A hunter that had come after her,
thought that she was going to eat me,
and fired at her.
In other words,
thanks to Jubei finding me,
I was rescued before freezing to death.
Ever since then, I came to the mountains
everyday to find Jubei
and chase her all the way deep
nto the mountains
where she wouldn't
be found by other hunters.
Then,
all that talk about Jubei being vicious...
Yes, I was trying to keep people away
from her, by scaring them.
It seems that recently what I've been
doing seem to be having opposite effects
from what I expected though...
A hunter acting like a member
of the humane society ?
I feel sorry for the hunter who was shot!
He comes in to shoot a bear
that he figures is his enemy
and ends up being shot by a hunter
he thinks is a friend.
A bear is a gift from the heavens.
We, the bear hunters never did{Jconsider
bears to be our enemy
Besides, if a bear were to find me
and I unfortunately get hunted down,
that too, is fate...
1 will have no choice but to close my eyes.
But, that hunter was unforgivably unfair!
What are you talking about?
He's referring to the use of a decoy!
I think that hunter used
the bear cub as a decoy
What?!
The boy's absolutely right!
That man most likely shot one of
Jubei's cub to death and lured Jubei out!!
Morever, he hung
the dead body of the cub to a tree!
I doubted these very eyes-of mine...
Because while watching
the mother bear desperately trying
to pull her cub down from the tree,
the man who had his gun
aimed at the mother bear
Iooked more-a beast than she did...
An hour after the incident,
we ran into the police who was
searching the mountains...
The elderly bear hunter was taken away
by the police...
He walked away gazing sadly
at the mountains where Jubei resides...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
an frms CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Stfogakukan
YTV / TMS
All Rights Reserved
§ C DY am - = - - a
SCT.
The bear cub's grave...
So, that's when you figured
everything out.
Yeah...
At first,
I thought that Mr. Saiga killed the hunter
because he wanted to kill Jubei himself
but...
a person like that would never make
a grave for a bear cub like he did...
Besides, he would've been able to
hunt Jubei down any time
since he even knew when she gave birth.
But, If so,
why didn't he say so in the first place!
If he did so, Mr. Saiga
would've been arrested by the police
and Jubei could've been killed, right?
But, it's amazing how you figured out
the bear cub was with Al and Mitsuhiko...
I saw the excrement and footprints
of the cub on the potato chip...
as well as the mother bear that
Ayumi was concerned about,
coming after her cub too!
Bears usually give birth to two cubs.
If the cub that Al and Mitsuhiko
brought along with them are siblings,
everything makes sense.
I'm sure that
Mr. Saiga was trying to stop Jubei
who would most likely have been
outraged at having her cub killed,
from attacking Ai and Mitsuhiko
who had her other cub with them.
Which means that the old man
was more concerned about the bear
than he was of us...
Yeah, probably...
It can't be helped!
That man's been friends
with Jubei for the past 20 years...
Being humane to animals can be
a nuisance when it comes this far...
Oh, but .
But, all is well!
Because the mother
and her cub were both fine!
I hope they find a nice place to hibernate.
Yes, I sure hope so!
What's with that look of yours...
Nothing...
It seems that you mustiinsert a 100 yen
to get to watch an hour of this TV.
Hey, this is...
The ice cream is melting...
I see...
The killer still has the evidence!
The killer is that person after allt!
THE MYSTERY OF THE RETRO-ROM