THE MYSTERY OF THE RETRO-ROOM
Tohto.Monorail
Tohto Monorail
EA BORE
HEIR
Dad!
Here, your ticket!
Okay!
You should come with us
to Dolphin Land too, dad.
I'm not going to no dolphin show!
A man's dream is...
the horse derby!
I'll win really big, and treat you guys
to a gorgeous dinner tonight!
Be sure you don't run the household
finances broke, trying to win though!
I Know...
I Know!
Yes, yes, bye then!
What did Naomi say?
She wants us to hurry over.
Oh! Two beauties, beauties, beauties!
Wow, are you by chance
Mr. Kogoro Mourn'?!
What? You mean that renown detective?!
Right you are!
Oh god, I can't believe it.
I'm a great fan of yours!
Hey: cut out your rude attitude!
Oh no, she's not being rude at all!
We're going to Dolphin Land Hotel,
but where are you headed for, Mr. Mourn?
Well,
what a coincidence
I'm going ot Dolphin Land too...
He's going to the horse race track
next to it.
Uh, do you mind if we go along with you?
Not at all, please do!
C,Come now, let's go!
We have one other person with us...
Kuniko!
Kaori!
I'm sorry, did you wait long?!
Wow, another beauty!
It's still early.
You're late!
We're riding the monorail
Ieaving at 1:20, aren't we?
We still have 10 minutes.
Oh? Who is he?
He is the renown detective,
Mr. Kogoro Mourn!
We ran into him coincidentally!
We used to be classmates
of the same university.
We had a class reunion last week,
Kuniko Yamamoto (27)
Fashion Designer
but one of our friends who work abroad
couldn't come.
Kuniko Yamamoto (27)
Fashion Designer
but one of our friends who work abroad
couldn't come.
She happened to come back
to Japan yesterday,
Kaori Obayashi (27)
Editor for a travelogue
81%:
so we decided to have another reunion,
just the four of us.
Kaori Obayashi (27)
Editor for a travelogue
Which means another beaut. is coming?!
Yes, among all of us, she was the
most popular with boys, a queen!
A queen!!
Where, where, where is she?!
She's staying at the Dolphin Land Hotel.
Kanami Kaneda (27)
housewife
She's a designer for
children's clothes abroad.
Kanami Kaneda (27)
housewife
She's a designer for
children's clothes abroad.
A designer, editor, beautiful,
yet gifted with talent!
Oh, not really...
Oh, he's right,
especially when it comes to you, Kuniko!
You're going independent and opening a
designer's office of your own, aren't you?
Well, sort of...
Wow, that's really something.
I'm the only one who's no more than
just a housewife...
Oh come on,
you went ahead before all of
us and got a happily married life!
Yes, really, look at you, happily plump!!
Oh, cut it out,
You know I'm not happy
about being plump...
The train headed for Dolphin Land
will be arriving soon,
Oh, here it comes.
The train headed for Dolphin Land
will be arriving soon,
Off we go to where
the fourth beauty awaits us!!
Here we go,
along we go on the monorail!!
[Ill
Dolphin Land Station p
That's the Dolphin Land Hotel.
They just renovated and
newly opened last month!
Talk about a classical setting...
This is called the retro-floor
Retro-floor?
Yes, the original model of this hotel,
a long-established famous Japanese inn
called lruka-Tel'.
Come, Naomi's room is over this side.
Sure thing!
Hey, Kuniko.
What is Naomi's room number?
Room 503.
Room 503 Oh,
here!
We made it, it's 2:00 sharp!
Don't tell me that Naomi's sleeping,
despite telling us to rush over?
What a girl
Naomi, Naomi?
Now, what do we do?
Oh, the door isn't locked
Let's go inside!
Naomi?
We're coming in...
Oh no,
you don't know them well enough yet!
Hey, what is this?
What's wrong?!
N,Naomi...?!
It can't be 7?!
Please calm down!
Don't touch anything in this room!
I said, don't touch anything!!
It seems to have
switched off automatically.
This TV is coin operated...
Ran, get the police!
OO, Okay!
And, the body was found by you three
and like always,
the one who coincidentally
happened to be here you, Mr. Moun?
Y. Yes, Sir...
I'll have to interrogate you too
Can you wait a while?
I'll act as their bodyguard then!!
No thank you.
Hey, Officer Chiba!
Yes!
Take care of the girls, will you?
Yes, sir!
Please come this way.
Hey, Mr. Moun!
Y,Yes sir!
Well, Takagi?
Oh, inspector!
The victim is Ms. Naomi Fujimura, age 27.
Naomi Fujimura (27)
Children's Clothes Designer
Std o> YJ
Naomi Fujimura (27)
ncrens oO es esigner
BWIA)
She worked abroad
as a designer for children's clothes.
Inspector,
I found this in the pocket
of the skirt of the victim.
It's a tear gas spray used
a WEEE Gu «00
O war away sexua arrassers.
What, tear gas spray?
Maybe she was a very cautious person
eCause SS O een Wing
in the States for some time?
It is strange.
What a place full of things
from olden times.
This is called a retro-room,
It is a replica of the guest room of
an old-established renown Japanese inn.
That's why the TV is coin operated...
This is the type that you can watch a for
an hour by inserting a hundred yen coin.
So, the TV switched off as soon as
you all entered the room?
Yes, at about 2:00.
According to the operation manual
on top of the TV,
LED ER Xk
SS XEZERoELR ANT am IL&EA TESLA
Tfifllillikfifli?
CARER IEMNROHD ER. BDEY
S BUJTHAICTESHER fA BEAT
18- » pe - xed . { (0 Teg v e
Ofljflffiifilifléfiliiffitifigfifiifi
only one 100 yen coin
can be inserted at a time.
LED SERGE
€ XHROBZBANN BRIAN THEW
18 CIRACKLANZY
OEHIIIIEFIHUJEBUJWQEKDiK
Ofilifiifilllléfillfifiififififiii
In other words,
the TV was turned on about an hour ago.
What is the estimated time of death?
From between 12:00 noon to 1:00.
So, she was attacked as soon as
the TV was switched on .
Um, this candy sure is a rare one, isn't it?
I've never seen candies like these!
Not you again!
Soda candy, stringed candy balls,
squid candy and sauce crackers.
All candies that I used to know
when I was a child.
These candies come with this room
as snacks to have tea with.
They probably scattered when the killer
and the victim struggled with each other.
This is
Ice cream, although it's already melted.
Ice cream?
She was probably attacked
while she was eating ice cream
and watching TV.
Will somebody check
if there is ice cream in the freezer!
Inspector, there are a few bars inside!
These bars of ice cream
are also very nostalgic.
It seems exactly as you say, Mr. Mourn.
No, this ice cream bar
is not of the olden days!
Did the victim buy it?
What's this? It's wet?
It seems slightly wet here.
Wet?
Maybe the water from a vase
spilled or something!
You delivered the blouse that had
been cleaned a little before 1:007
Yes,
But, since the Do not disturb sign
was on the door I didn't go inside...
Was the door locked at that time?
You again!!
Well, come now,
So, was it locked?
I didn't touch the door knob,
sol don't know.
Inspector,
the victim's cell phone
was found under the table!
Right, will you check the outgoing calls?
1 CO.
Oh, this is...
Please take a look, Inspector!
11151195 PM1:08
WE Af
02058252805
Kuniko Yamamoto?
118198 PM1:08
02058252805
She's one of the three girls...
She called out at 1:08,
that's just before she was killed...
Just after Ms. Yamamoto got the call,
we ran into them.
I see
Yes, it was definitely Naomi telling us
to hurry over to her place...
It shows 108.
#8092984503
True...
Where were you then?
At the monorail
station Ichiban-cho.
We were together
with each other from 1:00.
Kanami came 10 minutes late, though...
After that,
PM 1:20
We got on the 1:20 monorail.
We arrived at the hotel at about 1:50
We got to Naomi's room at 2:00 sharp.
In other words, the girls have an alibi!
One last thing
Would you please return;
to the scene of the crime again
and explain the circumstances«of
when you discovered the corpse?
1 Co.
No, this ls a well calculated homicide.
If my deduction is correct, she is the one.
But, I don't have evidence...
What was that?
That sound of something rubbing -
against something
I see...
The killer still has the evidence...
She IS the killer,
after all!
Thank you, everyone,
you can all go for today.
Inspector,
I guess I'll go with the girls and...
Dad?
But, on second thought,
maybe not just yet!
Inspector, this is a carefully
schemed case of homicide!
What was that?!
Moreover, the killer is right here,
among the three girls!
I What?!
It can'tibe!!
The killer is among us?!!
What a thing to say
First the tear gas spray
that Ms. Fujimura had with her.
She had it in her pocket, yet didn't use it,
probably because the the killer
was someone she knew.
Second, is the room key.
The one that is on the table.
Let's say that the killer were a robber.
Wouldn't it only be natural
that the killer would lock the door
when fleeing to buy time
to delay discovery of the corpse?
1, True...
But all the girls have an alibi
after 1:00, you know?
The actual time of death
Is way earlier than 1:00.
Probably something like 12:20 or so.
How do you explain the TV, then?
It switched off at a little after 12:00,
which means the coin was
inserted a little after 1:00.
One doesn't have to be
in this room to insert the coin.
Look,
if the candies that are scattered
about the room are used!
Candies?
Just how do you do that?
I'll explain that right now.
Conan!
Yes!
» 0 - - > asl
You use this ice cream bar
and candy ball with a string attached!
With things like that?
Well, watch!
First you hook the string of the candy ball
to the metal piece by the coin insert slot
As for the bar of ice cream...
Place the channel of the TV on top of
the cabinet to serve as a bridge.
Then one end of the string 4
of the candy ball is
held down by
a packaged bar of ice cream.
Do you have a 100yen, Ran?
Ves.
Can you put it by the coin slot?
0O,Okay.
The coin is caught by the string
and cannot be inserted.
After setting all this up,
the killer left the room.
As time passes, the ice cream will melt.
If the ice cream melts, the support is lost
and the string drops to the floor
You see.
I DUE.
Candies were scattered around the TV set
was to hide the trick
So, it seems...
The channel changer and
the top of the cabinet were wet
because of the ice cream bar
that was left there.
Moreover,
that ice cream bar is one
that has recently come on the market,
so it's not something that was left here
in the room to begin with.
Naomi.could've bought it-herself!!
The killer didn't lock the door
to carry out the trick, you know!
Just what do you mean?
Because if she locked the door,
even if she were to return
here with her friends,
she wouldn't be able to show them
the instant the TV switches off!
I see!
It would be meaningless unless she
showed somebody the TV switching off!
Which means that the sign
on the door knob was...
The killer probably hung
In on the door knob.
Be it only for an hour and a half,
she had to leave the room with the corpse
inside without locking the door.
Because of course,
if someone enters the room,
everything goes down the drain!
Wait a minute!
I got a call from Naomi at 1:08,
remember!
Right!
If Naomi were killed one hour before,
she wouldn't be able to
make the call, would she!
Right Mr Moun .
Her outgoing and incoming calls
all matched up too!
The killer called
using the victim's cell phone!
What?
But, Kuniko was talking to Naomi and...
Don't tell me that...
Right She couldn't have possibly
talked to the victim...
In other words, the killer is you...
Ms Kuniko Yamamoto!!
Kuniko...
No way...
After committing the murder,
You took Ms. Fujimura's cell phone
and went back to Ichiban-cho Station
to join Kaori.
Around 1.00,
you then called your own cell phone
from Ms. Fujimura's cell phone
and pretended talking to her.
All you had to do left,
was to return the cell phone to the room
during the commotion
of the body being found
Do you have evidence?!
You've got the evidence, don't you?
What?!
The vinyl bag in your pocket.
W, What about it!
You put Ms. Fujimura's cellular in there
and took it out, didn't you?
Is that true!
Hey!
Y, Yes, sir!
Please let me check your pocket.
H, Hey!
It's here!
Hold it up to the light and look at it!
Yes, SIR!
There are several fingerprints...
There is a place where the fingerprints
are bunched up vertically ..-
Ms. Yamamoto,
when I saw your cellular,
I noticed something interesting.
1A19BPM 1:08
82958252805
020582805.
11A198PM1.08
02958252805
When you match that up
with the number keys of the cell phone,
onlyythe keys of the center
vertical row are used.
The fingerprints are bunched up vertically
because you pushed
the number over the vinyl bag!
What?
Hey! Bring the victim's cellular phone!
Yes, sir!
It's only natural that the vinyl bag
that was in my pocket
has my fingerprints-on it!!
This is the victim's cell phone!
It matches up perfectly!
I couldn't...
«forgive Naomi!
Kuniko?!
Why, Kuniko?!
At university graduation{time,
the valedictorian was to be recommended «
to a brand name merchandiserabroad...
Naomi who attained that glory,
succeeded as
a children's clothes designer.
But the fact was, I was the one who was
supposed to get that recommendation!
Naomi had the nerve to use
her feminine wiles on the Professor!
I didn't know about it until
the Professor slipped his tongue
and told me about it at a bar
we went to after the class reunion!
But, weren't you going to go independent
and open your own office too?!
I lied...
The truth 1s, I was laid off}
Just because of
one little first time mistake!
Laid off?!
I was so vexed!
Thinking why I had to go through all this!
I was made to go through all this just
because of Naomi!
Naomi took my happiness away from me!
Hat's why I . I...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS BY
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / stfogakukan
YTV / TMS
All Rights Reserved
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
YIN { TS
All Rights Reserved
How lucky that there was a night show!
Yes!
And this is the best seat too.
Well, yes, I guess we were lucky...
Kid stuff...
Okay, now the dolphins will throw balls
at the guests that they take a liking to.
Please catch the ball for them!!
All right!
Boy, you sure are popular, Pops!
My...isn't there something wrong
with that boat?
What?!
Hey, it's capsizing!!
He is Mr. Hash.
Officer,
wasn't Mr. Hashi wearing a life jacket?
Come to think of it,
he was wearing one this morning
Really?!
Then, why isn't he wearing it?