With a strong heart and power of deduction,
And step into the essence
with strong rhythm
Today s episode is a true suspense story.
Two incidents happen
in places that are far apart.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan
TA AA
BAY OF THE REVENGE" PART I
What a nice sunset...
Just watching it, takes all of
today's exhaustion away...
You can say that again.
I'm about to forget that you got stingy
about paying rental car charges,
so we end up being stalled
in a placedike this.
Is anything wrong?
This us the entrance to our villa.
It's not a parking lot...
Or, did you want to talk to me?
Oh, I'm so sorry.
We've come on a family trip,
but the car broke down.
My name IS Kogoro Mourn.
Please don't worry,
we're not suspicious people.
What?!
You're that renowned detective
Mr. Kogoro Mourn?!
Oh, so, you know me?
Yes, I am Mouri!
Pardon me for my rudeness!
Kensuke Tachibana (62)
a laywer
I'm Keisuke Tachibana,
Kensuke Tachibana (62)
a laywer
and I run a law firm in Tokyo.
Kensuke Tachibana (62)
a laywer
and I run a law firm in Tokyo.
You're the Mr. Tachibana that
I hear of every time
there is trial for well-known cases?!
He's the lawyer that'll do anything
for money, if I remember correctly.
Well, most of the cases that I handle are
dangerous. That's why I'm always in a fix,
because of people coming after my life.
Oh, and he's my secretary, Mr. Sakuraba.
Uichi Sakuraba (29)
a secretary
I'm Yuichi Sakuraba. Nice to meet you all.
Uichi Sakuraba (29)
a secretary
w3ILS
Look up the number of a mechanic
for them, will you?
Well,
please drop by at the villa for a while.
After all, it's not everyday that
I get a chance to listen to your stories.
Thank you so much!
Johan, we've got guests.
My, how cute!
Johan
Good boy.
Your name's Johan?
He s got a very unique type of fur...
What kind of dog is he?
The thing is, I don't know.
The maintenance man of this villa
picked him up
I'm just keeping him as a watch dog.
Is that right
Well, aren't you a luc « dog, Johan!
This is Indeed a case of Buddha in Hell!
I thought that I'd have to give up
eating fish for tonight,
but to think that I get to eat all this food!
This 1s really delicious.
We just caught all the fish eo
and besides Yaeko is really a good cook.
Yaeko Kamei (50)
a manager of the villa
BH/\IKT (50)
All I can make is rural,
Iocal food. That's so embarrassing.
Yaeko Kamei (50)
a manager of the villa
BF) KT (50)
21200 BM
Yaeko.
Oh, yes?
Please bring) me some red wine
and a risotto to go with it.
Yes ma'am, I'll prepare it right away.
Welcome, everyone.
Yuki Tachibana (43)
Mr. Tachibana's wife
I am his wife, Yuki Tachibana.
Yuki Tachibana (43)
Mr. Tachibana's wife
I am his wife, Yuki Tachibana.
I thought you. were*going to:
be asleep 'tonight? @
After hearing that Mr. Mouri
stopped by here tonight,
I regained my appetite.
Would you all ike to have some wine too?
I don't think so,
because we're having
some local sake just now.
Yes, hot Japanese white wine.
Party pooper...
Who could it be at this time of night?
It's Mr. Sugimura.
Yes, Please come in.
Good evening.
What brings you here at this time of night?
I just have something I want to
tell you...
Mr Tachibana!
We got:another, one of thosewetters again
at the officer
I didn't want anything to happerO
while you were on vacation,
so, I figured that
it'd be better for me to bring it over.
Oh, Mr. Mourn
she is the accountant of my office,
Sugimura here.
Noriko Sugimura (48)
an accountant at Mr Tachibana's Office
F¥1D OF (48)
Mr. Mouri... Are oub chance...
Noriko Sugimura (48)
an accountant at Mr Tachibana's Office
Mr. Mouri... Are oub chance...
Right.
He's the renowned detective,
Mr. Kogoro Mourn!
Why don't you go ahead and join us
all for dinner too, Ms. Sugimura?
Thank you very much.
What?! You don't have the parts?!
You mean you can't get it until tomorrow?
What'll we do for now?
Mr. Mourn!
Why don't you spend the night here?
You were on a trip anyway, weren't you?
Oh, this is the Tachibana residence,
please repair the car so it works like new,
even if it takes time.
Yes, thank you.
So, Mr. Mourn,
please take it easy to your heart's content.
Ce Thank you...
Talk about rich!
A western stile mansion made of stone
and a hot spring white cedar bath!
Lawyers sure must make a lot of money!
Rather,
it just goes to show that Mr. Tachibana
Is the type of lawyer he is rumored to be.
What's with these figures?!
Don't tell me that you're embezzling
money from the office?
This has been happening ever
since I've left accounting up to you!
I wonder if a man who can't even control
the way his wife wastes money,
has any right to say
anything about accounting?
I hear that your wife
Is taking revenge on you...
Revenge?
Will you hurry up and divorce her,
make money under the table,
circulate finances or,
do something for the sake of the office?!
You'd better do something before
what's-his-name T.K Kills you!
Wow,
What does she mean by revenge?
And, the initials 1 XK...
Hey!
Do you have anything on her yet?
No, not yet...
Rats!
That's why you can never
pass the bar exam!
Pardon me sir,
but you're the one who's not
giving me time to study!
Why do I have to do things
other than my own duties.
Don't you dare talk back to me!
Your rudeness will not
be accepted anywhere!
I can't eat anymore...
Johan, you sure can eat, can't you?
Oh, you're up already?
Good morning!
Did you sleep well last night?
Yes thank you very much.
I'll go and get a big catch today too,
SO you can expect a delicious dish today.
Ism-sorry for us intruding on you like this.
Don't worry about it.
Take your time and relax here
until your car is repaired.
I'm enjoying your company here too.
Mr. Tachibana, your lunch.
Take care of things for me then, will you.
Bye!!
Johan is barking...
I wonder what's wrong?
I'm sorry,
I think he wants to go for a walk.
I was busy in the morning
since Mrs. Tachibana decided to go home.
God, I'm in a fix,
because I have to head back
to Tokyo right now...
We could take Johan for a walk for you.
We've got to do something to repay you
for all the hospitality we're receiving,
right Dad?
I guess so.
We ve got to go to
the repair shop anyway too.
Really?
That would really be a great help.
No problem,
no big deal!
Hey, wait, Johan!
Cut out your running!
Hey!
I'm telling you to stop!
I'm pooped!
Break time! Break time!
I'm not going to move an inch from here!
You two sure get along, don't you?!
No way!
I'm just trying to get along with him
because his master's been so nice to us!
What's up, Johan?
Johan, where are you going?
Wait for me!
Do. ou like boats, Johan?
Maybe he knew someone on the boat.
Well, well...
It sure looks delicious!
Dig in!
It sure does!
The view is fantastic
andvitésureffeels good!
What?"
Isn't something wrong with that boat?
It's tilted at such a sharp angle...
Don't tell me that's Mr. Tachibana's boat!
What!
Hey!
It's capsizing!
Oh no!
Yaeko
please call the police!
Y-Yes, Sir.
Are you sure that
he is Mm Kensuke Tachibana?
Y-Yes...
There is no mistake, it's him...
It just happened to be high tide,
so we had a hell of a time rescuing him.
Mr Inoki (28)
a police officer
I'm sorry it turned out this way.
Mr Inoki (28)
a police officer
I'm sorry it turned out this way.
Officer,
wasn't Mr. Tachibana
wearing a life jacket?
Yes, I'm sure he was wearing one
when he left this morning!
Are you sure?!
Then why isn't he wearing it now?!
There are people who take
their life jackets off when it gets hot.
Therefore, we have a lot of accidents
Iike this happening!
But, it's winter now.
And, no matter how warm they say
this part of the region is...
He could've stayed afloat
€e was wearing 1s le jac ee an ye
My God,
and I warned«shim to be careful
because theiwaves wereshigh.
What a thing to have happened.
The more so it's hard to believe that
he would take off his life jacket.
Excuse me, may I ask who you are?
I'm Inuyama,
who rented the boat out to Mr. Tachibana.
Hiroshi Inuyama (70)
an owner of a boat rental shop
I own that boat rental shop over there.
To tell you the truth, a boat of the same model
as the one he rented was stolen.
I wonder if you could look for it,
while you're at it?
Are you sure?
Yeah!
The kids saw a guy wearing
a red baseball cap sail away on it.
Oh, we saw that boat too!
From the cape over there!
And, which way did it go?
Where would that direction be?
Since it was the road:below the cliff,
the boat was blocked by,
and sailed out of sight.
That's in the direction
where Mr. Tachibana had the accident.
Then, it could be that the boat rammed
into Mr. Tachibana's boat!
But, we saw it
about 2 hours before the accident.
But something bothers me
about that man.
It could be the man
who came to the villa once before.
What?!
A man who came to visit Mr. Tachibana
about 2 months ago
was also wearing a red baseball cap
He had an argument with Mr. Tachibana...
If he was the same man,
he probably stole the boat
to get close to Mr. Tachibana.
We'll begin a search for
the boat.immediately!
Oh, that'll be a great help!
Oh, officer...
What is it you want?
I am afraid no one is back yet...
We've got the results of the autopsy.
What shall we do, Officer Baba?
Let's wait!
Mr. Baba (42)
a police officer
2 BAN
I'd like to watch
Mr. Mouri makes his deduction too.
Mr. Baba (42)
a police officer
O-Okay...
What do you mean
you want to watch Pop's deduction?
Mr. Mouri is pretty well-known
around here too.
Besides, according to the rumor,
I hear he dances to Yoko Okino's music
as he makes deductions!
The so-called, "Dancing Kogoro™!
Just what are they talking about anyway?
Sleeping pills?!
That's what you found in him?
Yes,
it seems that
after taking the sleeping pills,
he fell in the water
while asleep and drowned
Did Mr Tachibana show any signs
of possibly committing suicide?
I wonder, suicide...
He could never have been
thinking of suicide!
Because...
You can be expecting a good meal today
because I'm going to go and get a big catch
He also told us to relax
and make ourselves at home
because he enjoyed our company.
I see...
Which means somebody
must've made him drink it.
I just got back.
I'm sorry to keep you all waiting.
I'll get dinner ready right away.
Ms. Kamei?
Out shopping?
Yes,
because the people from the office
will also be gathering here.
I can see that you're busy,
but could we ask you a few questions?
Yes.
What kind of lunch did
Mr. Tachibana take with him?
Sandwiches and hot coffee.
What kind of sandwiches were they?
Hamburger patty. pickles,
vegetable salad, and onions.
Exactly what came out in the autopsy
Which means that
Mr. Tachibana ate his lunch.
And, Mr. Sakuraba was the one
who gave the lunch to Mr Tachibana?
Mrs. Tachibana suddenly asked me
to do something for her,
so he gave the lunch
to Mr. Tachibana for me.
So, that's makes it possible for three
people to have mixed in sleeping pills.
N-Nobody would put
something like that inside!
What's this about sleeping pills?
Mr. Sakuraba?
Y-Yes...
Did you know that Mr. Tachibana
has passed away?
Yes.
I heard so from the officer
in the parking lot just now.
By the way,
where were you until this time of day?
1, I was at the Tokyo office
doing something for Mr. Tachibana!
I heard that the boat that Mr. Tachibana
was in capsized and he drowned.
Now, what does this have to do
with sleeping pills?!
It seems that someone
sneaked sleeping pills into his coffee.
Oh, no...
The guy who was wearing
the red baseball cap may have done it.
Right, that's another possibility!
It seems that a strange-letter
was received too, right, Mr. Sakuraba?
A strange letter?
«xv,
Mr. Tachibana had been receiving
blackmail recently...
Blackmail?!
Why didn't you mention it earlier!?
Here they are!
The same thing is written on
all three of them!
If you donst want your lawyer's license
revoked get 3,000;000 yen ready.
TX...
This is indeed blackmail!
In the diary says,
The guy is a hopeless devil,
blackmailing me .
After I win him an innocent verdict
despite the crime-that" he committed ~
Mr. Sakuraba, do you have any idea
what the initials T.K. stand for?
No, that's...
You're not being very clear...
According to the diary it looks to be
that Mr. Tachibana won this person
an innocent verdict knowing that
this T.K. committed the crime,
and you knew nothing of it?
I just happened toscome across the letter
when I was clearing the papers out.
Mr. Tachibana got angry
and told me to forget about it
The people from the office have arrived.
We'll go over right now.
HE R SZ & (45)
Ob: N!»
ZEN FEL
I came to get Mr Tachibana's body,
but I was told I couldn't...
umio Fujisawa (45)
Iaw er
Is there something suspicious
about his death?
Umio Fujisawa (495)
Iawyer
Is there something suspicious
about his death?
Well, there were some trivial things
we wanted to check on so.
Where us Mrs. Tachibana?
She's waiting at her residence
with the other members of the family
Where is Sugi...who was it.
You mean Ms. Sugimura?
She's off on Saturdays and Sundays
and seems to have/gone out.
We can't get a hold of her
There it is!
A red baseball cap!
We've got to report this immediately
to Officer Baba!
I'm sorry to be intruding on you
so early in the morning,
but we found what seems to be evidence
This red baseball cap.
Have any of you seen it before?
It's the same color as the one the person
sailing the boat was wearing!
I see...
What about you, Ms. Kamei?
Yes I'm sure it looked like that.
Actually, there is a name on this cap
Please take a look.
Do you have any idea
who thissnam Kumada refers to?
No, not at all.
How about you?
I have no idea.
Hey, Mr. Sakuraba,
isnt Mr. Kumada the one
that Mr. Tachibana
defended about 5 years ago?
The hearing that they had, the same year
you came to Mr. Tachibanass office?
Oh, yes, him?!
And!
Did that person get an innocent verdict?
Yes,
although the circumstances
seemed to be against him,
Mr. Tachibana won him
an innocent verdict
His name was Tatsuya...
I think it was Tatsuya Kumada!
Tatsuya Kumada!
The initials would be...
So, we've got a connection here
with the initials
that were on the letters of blackmail!
This could be...
Although the man called Kumada
was blackmailing Mr. Tachibana,
he was probably being ignored.
Or maybe Mr. Tachibana,
on the contraryatold him
that he would press charges
of blackmail against the guy!
So, he goes all the way to
where Mr. Tachibana is fishing
and forced him to drink sleeping pills,
took off his life jacket and drowned him.
It fits In, Officer Baba!
Okay, Officer Inoki1!
Let's go search for
Kumada as a prime suspect!!
Yes, sir!
But, just think that he's: living In
a place only 25 minutes from the villa!
That makes him even more suspicious.
I guess we've got him!
And how come you're tagging along?!
Because I witnessed the man
wearing the red baseball cap!
Strange
I hear that he is a night owl
who is asleep in the mornings.
The door's not locked.
What?!
Mr. Kumada, we're coming in...
W-What is this?!
The suspect Kumada...
has committed suicide!
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
BET firms CONAN
QGosho Aoyama / Si¥dgakukan
YIN [I TMS
All Rights Reserved
DETECTIVE «NAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
YTV / ms
All,Rights Reserved
Ms Sugimura.
Why do you, who only
came to the office three years ago,
know of the case
that happened 5 years ago?
I hear that your father committed suicide
because of your husband,
didn't he, Mrs. Tachibana?
I hear you've embezzled
quite a large sum of money?
Don't be ridiculous!!
I get it!
So, that's what happened!