With a strong heart
and power of deduction,
And step into the essence
with strong rhythm
Today is part ll of a true suspense story.
Get ready for a surprise,
when you find out who the killer is.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan.
While we were driving along the coast,
our car broke down
and we ended up spending the night
at the villa of a lawyer called Mr. Tachibana.
However, the following day,
right in front of our very eyes,
the boat that Mr. Tachibana was
on capsizes and he drowns to death.
It seems to be that
Mr. Tachibana was killed
nt <<
It seems to be that
Mr Tachibana was killed
1 Z TaD
by a man with the initials 1 .K.
that was also blackmailing him.
It was thought that
the man was Tatsuya Kumada,
a man that Mr. Tachibana had won
an innocent verdict for 5 years ago.
Therefore, we rushed over to his place,
but-what we endedlup seeing was...
Mr. Kumada, we're coming in...
W-What's going on here?!
The suspect Kumada...
has committed suicide!
BAY OF THE REVENGE" PART II
Please back away.
It looks to be he used this chair
to commit suicide
But, this rope is sure tied
in a strange way...
The rope is tied to
the railing of the veranda.
Could it be because if it were tied
the ordinary way to the pillar,
his feet would touch the ground?
Well, there was a loud noise upstairs.
Like something toppling over
Just once though.
About what time was it?
Maybe a little after 7:00 in the evening...
It fits the estimated time of death which
Is thought to be around 6:00 to 7:00pm.
About 7:007
Then I'll be of no help,
because I got back at about 7:15 pm.
I see...
But, that's strange...
When I got home, I heard
Mr Kumada's washing machine running.
Are you sure about that?
Positive.
It sure is strange for one
who is contemplating suicide
to want to wash clothes.
Just as I thought,
this is...
Hey!
What do you think you're doing Look out!
Oh, I'm sorry
Which boat was Mr. Tiachibanasriding inv.
The one to the very right at the end.
I want to go take a look at it.
Hey, hey! Are you investigating
on the case or something?
Yep, I'm a detective.
Well, well, working hard
What is this scratch...
Hey!e-
Did you find something?
Was this scratch always here?
On, Lord, I've seen it now for the first time!
It's still new...
I wonder if Mr. Tachibana or
the police who found the boat did it.
What a bummer...
The boat that was stolen was found,
but the anchor was stolen.
I tell you! Why is all this happening to me?
The anchor?
Yeah,
the one that is used to keep the boat
from drifting away while fishing...
This type of anchor is thrown into the sea.
The one for the big boat over there
was stolen, wire and all.
See,
it was the same \ pe as this one here.
It hasn't been found yet?
I was told it wasn't in the boat
that was found this morning,
nor:anywhere in the vicinity neither.
On top of that, the anchor for the boat
that was found was also gone
I get the picture!
I'm back!
Oh, hu.
Conan! Where were you?
What are you doing
with Mr. Sakuraba, Ran?
I was cleaning!
And Mr. Sakuraba just came back
after taking Johan for aswalk.
Mr. Sakuraba,
the case about Mr. Kumada 5 years ago...
What kind of a case was it?
I cant tell you because it's confidential.
What a childish thing to say!
M-Ms. Sugimura...
Where were you all this time?
On a trip!
I saw the news and I came right back!
I see.
And, is the killer the one called T.K?
Y-Yes
You know about Mr. Tatsuya Kumada?
My, you already know his name?
He used to be an elite working for
a securities company.
But, one of his subordinates, Masahiko
Tsuruta embezzled his client's money.
After this, Tsuruta committed suicide...
However, after Tsuruta's diary was found,
it turned out that Kumada was the one
who had actually embezzled the money.
Kumada was.then arrested for
suspicion of framing a murder.
However, the person living
below Masahiko Tsuruta's room
heard something fall at around 10pm.
But, at that time,
Kumada was at a Karaoke snack shop
gy ~~
His alibi was verified,
and he was released
with no charges pressed against him.
That's...
exactly how it looks this time!
Ms Sugimura,
How is it that you know so much of
the incident that took place 5 years ago,
when it's only been 3 years
since you've entered the company?
I was just checking on who the initials T.K
that were signed on the letters belong to.
I also checked a little
on Mrs.Tachibana too...
I hear that your father committed suicide
because of Tachibana, right,
Mrs Tachibana?
How you must've had a grudge
owards your husband...
So much, as wanting to kill him.
Speak for yourself!
Didn't you use a lot of the money
of the office for personals?
I'll bet you killed my husband
because he found about it, huh?
Don't be ridiculous!!
Well, Doc?
Yeah!
I found out that the address
he was at during the hearing
was in the same prefecture, Chiba.
The family of the late Masahiko Tsuruta
include his mother,
Tamiko and his kid brother, Katsuhiko.
His mother and kid brother?
Granny,
is there a house around here
where a Mr. Masahiko Tsuruta lives?
Masahiko's house.
See, it's right over there.
There is nobody there, though...
Why not?
His mother Tamiko and kid brother
Katsuhiko moved away.
After all, they've been through so much
after what happened...
He was such a smart child
who went to a school in Germany, and yet.
The house won't sell
because it's in a place like this
It seems that they used to come back
to take care of it on and off...
But, since about a year ago,
nobody's come around at all.
Johann...
I OTC.
So, I finally get the picture!
It seems that sleeping pills
of the same substance
as those found in Mr. Tachibana's body
were also found In Kumada's-body
They were also found in the whisky
Ieft in the bottle.
Therefore, it was concluded that,
after killing Mr. Tachibana,
Kumada committed suicide
by taking sleeping pills.
Ghads!
No way!
Comesthis way, this*way.
What's in here?
This file, I wonder what it is?
An account book...
So, the renowned detective
is going to give his famed deduction?
What on earth is there
to deduce at this point?
Well, well, please have a seat everyone.
I will now disclose
the truth of what happened
to Mr. Tachibana
and Mr. Tatsuya Kumada.
The truth?
Hasn't the case been closed?
Are you saying that the conclusion
that we have reached is not correct?
Exactly,
Mr. Tatsuya Kumada was also killed
by the same person
who killed Mr. Tachibana.
And, the killer is here with us!
What on earth are you talking about?!
I will explain it to you right now.
The same sleeping pill was detected
in both the bodies of
Mr. Tachibana and Mr. Kumada.
In other words, after putting
Mr. Tachibana to sleep and killing him,
the killer did the same thing to Mr. Kumada.
Moreover, he set it up to look as if
Mr. Kumada committed suicide.
Is there anyone who could have been
able to do something likejthat?
There are three people
who could've carried it out.
Ms. Yaeko Kamel,
Mr. Yuichi Sakuraba,
and Mr Tachibana, himself.
But, Yaeko was with us
when the boat capsized!
Which means...
W-Wait a minute please!
I was at the office in Tokyo
at that time too...
No, no!
The problem is not where you were
when the boaticapsized!
Preparations to kill Mr. Tachibana
were made so many hours
in advance and completely finished.
All that had to be done was wait
Ju Awhat do you mean, Mr. Mourn?
I see!
You mean the man that we saw
who was wearing the red baseball cap!
he is the killer.
But that was more than two hours
before the boat capsized.
How on earth did he make the boat sink?
All you have to do is think why the killer
committed the crime yesterday.
As you already know,
yesterday was spring tide.
Yes, It was spring tide indeed, and
we did have some difficulty in the search.
Can't you figure It out?
Spring tide is caused
by a great difference in the water level
between low tide and high tide.
That's why the killer
committed the murder yesterday.
Could you give us more details?
The man wearing the red baseball cap
who we saw,
approached Mr. Tachibana's boat,
and pulls the life jacket off
Mr. Tachibana.
Then, he throws the anchor that he had
stolen together with the boat into the sea!
The killer hooks the claw that is tied on
to the end of the rope
onto Mr. Tachibana's boat.
If set up this way,
when the water level rises because of
high tide, the anchor ls pulled and tilts,
and when the boat capsizes,
the claw comes off and sinks into sea...
Mr. Tachibana is thrown into the sea...
and drowns
What a way to commit murder!
The boat rental owner did call to say
that his anchor'had been stolen.
That's why the anchor of the boat
that was stolen was missing?
Right,
that anchor has probably
sunk under the sea.
They should be searching the area
where the accident occurred today, hey!
Yes sir!
I'll ask the station about it!
But, why would someone do
something so cruel like that?
Everything was done to create an alibi.
The killer went through all this
to create an alibi for himself
during the time the boat was capsizing.
Yes, hello!
Mr. Mourn!
They seem to have found the anchor
right below the area
where the boat capsized!
The boat rental owner just verified
the anchor 'a little while ago.
Moreover,
+ they found a claw on the end of the rope.
Let me continue.
The killer then returned to shore,
and left the cap with Kumada s name
in back of the boat,
so that suspicion would focus on him.
According to the investigation's officers,
that cap was Kumada's!
No hair or anything of any other person
was found on it...
The killer musteve used
a similar type of cap for disguise.
The killer probably got
a hold of Kumada s cap
when they saw each other or something.
The killer and Kumada
must've known each other.
As evidence of that,
the killer went to Kumada's residence,
and was able to make him drink whisky
with a sleeping drug in
Then the killer, after standing Kumada's
body up against the sliding door,
wound the rope around his neck.
The rope that was pulled
through the pillar,
was pulled through
the railing of the veranda,
and using this as a point of support,
the killer probably pulled on
the rope with all his might.
The rope was then tied onto the railing of
the veranda and the sliding door opened.
Finally, the killer set the chair in place.
But,
at around 7:00pm when
the person downstairs heard-a- sound,
everyone here has an alibi...
The fact is, the killer does not need
an alibi for that specified time either.
Just what do you mean?!
This is the same trick
as the one Mr. Tatsuya Kumada had used
to kill Mr Masahiko Tsuruta 5 years ago.
What was that?!
The washing machine
that was running after 7:00 o'clock!
The killer tied a string around the spinner
in the center of the washing machine
so that it would be wound
as the washing machine operated.
Then a hoop is made
at one end of the string
and hooked onto the back of the chair.
All that is left to do after that is to set
the timer of the washing machine to 7-00.
When the washing machine starts,
the string is wound,
and the chair falls down.
I'll have them check
the washing machine right away!
Which means that Mr. Tachibana
was Killed at around 1:00pm.
Kumada's estimated time of death
Is between 6:00pm and 7:00pm
So the person who does not
have an alibi before 7:00pm,
that is, around 6:00pm, is the killer.
Let's take you, Mr. Sakuraba,
for example...
You left here around 1:00
and returned after 7:00.
Please wait a minute,
there are many who had a grudge
against Mr. Tachibana!
Did you check all those people already?!
Sakuraba, What did you come to pick up
at the office yesterday?
Moreover, why was it at about the same time
Mr.Tachibana's boat had just capsized?
Mr. Sakuraba,
did you come to get this account book?
So, that you could make it look
as if Ms. Sugimura used the money?!
Why you!
I, I'm sorry...
I was going to adjust the book
with Mr. Tachibana last night
to set you up and make it
Iook like you spent the money
that he:lavishly used. 7
That's why I was relieved to hear that
Mr. Tachibana had passed away.
Mr. Sakuraba!
Just what do you mean
by you felt "relieved"?
I was sick and tired of assisting
Mr. Tachibana's wrongdoings!
He threatened me saying that
if I didn't do as he said,
he would see to it that I wouldn't be able to
function as a lawyer in the future...
I was read. to break down any minute...
Mr. Sakuraba; well hear
the rest of your story at the station...
No! I didn't kill him!
If you resist,
we'll arrest you right here on the spot!
Please believe me!
I'm not the one
who killed Kumada and Mr. Tachibana,
I'm innocent!
That's enough!
Mr. Sakuraba didn't kill anyone...
The one who killed them both...is me!
No!!
Y-Yaeko...
I was waiting for you to confess.
I knew you were not the type of person
who could: frame somebody
and keep silent about it.
Yaeko could ve put sleeping pills
in Mr. Tachibana's thermos at any time.
That day, after we all left,
you disguised yourself as Kumada and
Ieft from the back door.
You then
approached Mr. Tachibana's boat.
Soon later, you witnessed Mr. Tachibana's
boat capsize together with us
When you went shopping at sundown,
you parked the car in
the parking lot of the supermarket,
disguised yourself again, and headed for
Kumada's place.
Isn't that right?
Please take a look at this.
Conanxfound this name.plate in the yard m
of Mr. Masahiko Tsuruta's house...
Johan?!
Yes, if you read it in German
it's read: Johann.
This name plate ls probably one that
your son brought back
from Germany where
he was an exchange student,
isn=t that- right...Mrs. Tamiko Tsuruta?
What?!
You mean Yaeko is. .?
Yes, the mother of Masahiko Tsuruta
who was killed by Kumada!
I should've realized it sooner...
Yesterday, Johan chased the boat
you were riding at the cape .
I'm sure that Johan knew it was you
despite your disguise.
My younger son passed away
Iast year too,
so Johan is the only one left for me now.
I lied saying that he was
a stray and he came here to live with us.
I fought with all of my might in
court, and yet no one recognized me.
I aged all of sudden from:thei
inappropriate sentence of the hearing...
And...
Six months ago, Kumada finally appeared.
I happened to hear about
the trick using the washing machine
from the other side of the door...
Kumada was promising Tachibana
that he'd pay any amount Tachibana
wanted to handle the case.
Tachibana won
Kumada an innocent verdict
despite knowing that
he had killed Masahiko.
I followed Kumada
back to his apartment that day,
and thought up the idea of killing him
and Tachibana
when I saw the red baseball cap
that he forgot here.
And you started
sending letters of blackmail
that looked to have been mailed
from Kumada to Mr. Tachibana...
I've been so scared since yesterday...
But, I'm really relieved now.
You were expecting to get arrested
to begin with, weren't you?
That's why you went ahead
and committed the crime
despite a detective like me being here...
I guess so.
I'm so sorry for all the trouble I caused...
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUC RS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi loka
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi1 Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
in association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
QGosho Aoyama / Sl¥dgakukan
YTV / TMS
All Rights Reserved
Dad! Now what?!
Weird, and I just got it repaired.
When are we ever going
to make it back to Tokyo?!
Please help us!
We just need to get to Tokyo!
Maybe more cars will stop
if I take his place?
Never mind, let's stay here and
watch the ocean a little while longer.
Well, why not...
Hey!! Do something!!
Hey! Ran!
What's wrong!?
Ran!
I remember that something
Iike this happened befor \
When there were a series of
high school 'girls being hit-and-run...