Be strong I say to my heart and
step into the essence with strong rhythm
Show time again
for the Metropolitan Police Department.
One mistake after the other
IS made in this eerie case.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
Oh, hello...
It's me...
I'm sorry, just a while ago...
I guess the battery of
my cell phone ran out on me
Yep, that's right...
I got off the car and am calling
from a phone booth now.
I should be there in another 30 minutes...
Okay then, I'll see you later.
INSPECTOR MEGURE'S
SEALED SECRET" PART I
Look! Look!
What do-you:think.of this?
You're going to give it
as a gift to Mr. Kyogoku, aren't you?
Don't you think it's a bit too cute?
You think so 7?
I think...
he'd look better
in a simple sweater like this...
No, it has to be hand-knitted!
What do you mean
it has to be hand-knitted?
I just thought that a hand-knitted
sweater would be warmer, that's all...
Sonoko. don't tell me that you!
W Well, I kind of wrote in the last letter
to him that I would, you what
I'm knitting a sweater
for someone that I care for...
But, I didn't think that knitting a sweater
took so much patience...
So, you're planning to buy
a ready madehand knitted sweater
And give it to him, making him
think that you knitted it for him!
Well, I can't back off now, can I!
Well . all right.
I give you credit for your courage
of telling the person
that you like how you feel about him
so I won't say a word
about the sweater
I still haven't told Makoto
how I feel about him yet...
but didn't you write him a letter?
That you're knitting it
for the one you care for...
Maybe he'll take it to be
that you have another boyfriend...
That's just it...
That's the point...
If he thinks so, that'll make him
feel a bit flustered, won't it?
Just as he's feeling that way
he receives this parcel, see...
What's this, a parcel from
KY receives the parcel Sonoko?
He opens the parcel slowly, and finds...
It was actually a sweater
I was making for you.
This is my Love; love strategy.
Well, I hope it'works out the way
you want it to, and not theother way.
Makoto is so reticent,
unless I do something like this, I'll
never find out how he feels about me.
Thanks for wornryingrabout me, though...
Besides, I'll need a lot of nerve
and courage to ask him directly
how he feels about me...
B...But, Sonoko...
Ran, how about you?
Do you know how
Shinichi feels about you?
See, see, see see!
You want to know, don't you?
You want to ask him,
don't you? Well?!
L,I guess...
1. guess as a childhood friend...
if I said I didn't care at all, it
ould be a lie, but...
cc 0000
But... but, but
I want to ask him, and yet I don't.
S how I feel right now... F
I hope that's not what
you're thinking dream lover?!
1, am thinking...no such thing!
May I go over to Pops
who is waiting in the parking lot?
Then can you tell dad to go ahead
to the spaghetti shop
behind the department store
and wait for us there?
Hey, hey, how about this one here?
I feel like I listened to girlie talk
that I wasn t supposed to listen to...
what Is that... Talk about dorky!
You can say that again!
I wonder why girls
Iike to waste their time on...
You can say that again...
Wow, look at those legs of hers
Moreover, look at that super mini skirt,
despite the cold
A ball pen ls on the ground
Maybe that woman$
who just came out dropped it?
Oh, we've got to go:give it back to her!
Oh, excuse me, Miss .
Uh, you dropped this
Get him!
Uh, hold it, hold it, hold it
give me a break
You were after a serial killer
who goes after women and kills
them by beating them with an object?...
Right,
Officer Sato acted as decoy,
dressed up like that,
so that we could nab him...
But... the height of the killer
was publicly announced as being about 52
One look should tell you
that I'm not the man...
Oh, well... the way you approached
Officer Sato was so... you know...
Not what you could
call all that normal so...
I felt a bit of danger, you see...
H How rude!
We've got a bit of problem here, though...
Yes.
The only thing the three women
victims have in common is
that they were dressed flashily
when they were attacked...
That's about all we know...
The place of attack is also scattered
here and there
Will you show me
the picture of the girls again?
Oh, yes sir...
The first victim was « oko Mizutani.
One night, two weeks ago,
she was hit from behind while she was
waiting for the light to turn green.
Therefore, she got off her car to complain,
but beaten with a metal bat...
The next one who was attacked
was Ms. Hitomi Endo.
Late at night, 10 days ago,
she was struck with a metal bat as she
came out of the ladies' room of the park...
And, she s Michiko Ishiguro,
who was beaten last night.
She seems to have been struck right
after she came out of the phone booth.
Don't tell me it was that phone booth...
Yeah, that phone booth
that we got a hold of you at.
Fortunately,
all three are in satisfactory condition
but the.only thing common
we can find in all of them
is that they were dressed quite flashily.
They allksay
they have no memory of anyone
having a grudge 'against them either...
Well Mr. Mouri any inspiration?
Well, if ll had to come up with something...
If you were to come up with something
Nd were raised in the jungle...
Well, it's hard to think
that these three are ordinary Japanese...
Wow, how cute!
All of them are super black!
The one in the middle is ultra black!
They're called mountain witch girls
Girls wearing this kind of make-up
are very popular now.
M.Mountain witch'...
Not?! Don't tell me you
don't know about them?!
Don't be ridiculous,mountain witch,right?
Of course I know about them!
Huh? Where's Ran?
Oh:she*said
she had to go¥to the ladies' room,
so to go ahead and wait for her
at the spaghetti shop.
But, if the killer is indiscriminately
attacking*those type of girls
where do we start looking for him...
Right...we havenit-had
this kind of case before either so...
On the contrary... If .remember correctly...
they was a similar case in the past...
A series of high school girls
were hit-and run
Very abhorrent case...
That was way before
I became a police officer...
Let's go back and investigate!
Agh, yes sir!
I'll act as decoy once again...
No! No more decoy!
Let s go back and check
if there are no other things
in common. with the victims once again
Y,Yes sir!
See you Mr. Mourn sorry for the mistake
Oh, no problem...
Hello...Oh, Ran...
What, you don't know where the exit is?
And, where are you now?
What, the basement parking lot?
I don't believe it...
how bad can you getsatidirections...
Sonoko, isn't that ring,
necklace and bracelet
the same ones that the girls
in the pictures were wearing?
Where did you buy it?
I didn't bub, it was given to me
at the department store we just went to.
Something about a Millennium Sale
when I showed my receipt at the exit.
I got to choose any item I wanted for
every 10,000 yen worth of shopping...
Hey, how about it?
They're wearing them!
Although they're only wearing one each,
they're the same accessories
as those that Sonoko has!!
Which means that the three girls...
Were customers at the same
department store!!
Hey, Sonoko
What's the matter? Please answer me
Sonoko
Ran?!
Hey, Ran! What's wrong?!
RanOwhat"s up ./! Answer me!
What,
a blood splattered woman is lying on
the ground of the basement parking lot?!
The victim is Tae Aizawa, 20 years old...
She used to be a salesclerk
at this department store,
but quit a year ago,
She seems to have been
presently unemployed
He finally kills at the 4th attempt...
Then, this was also committed
by the same person...
Since the characteristic of the killer
has not been made public,
and this is the basement parking
of the department store in question...
so there's probably no doubt that
it's the same person.
Then this could be the doings of someone
who has a grudge against
the department store...
Tae! Tael!
Fg Fg Puy Fe
Who is he?
He is her boyfriend
and was supposed to
meet her in the department: store.
Something about his father
being the owner of the department store
Noriyuki
and that he was going to introduce
her to him today
Noriyuki
at the restaurant
he is working as a cook at.
Who Is that woman?
A waitress at the restaurant
he works I hear.
Her name is Yuri Konno.
She was his classmate in university,
3 (24 VY
and she used to give him
advice when he needed it.
(24) Y
Advice?
Mr. Shirakawa's father seems to
have been against him
going with Ms. Aizawa...
Ran,
didn't you see anyone suspicious
before you found the dead body?
There was no such person!
The only person I passed by
was a security guard...
A security guard?
Yes,at the entrance of this parking lot...
A man somewhere in his forties, I think...
Oh, that's me!
I just happened to leave
my post to go to the men s room.
my post to go to the men's room
Yoshio Sadakane (43)
Securitysguard
The killer probably entered
the parking lot during that time...
Yoshio Sadakane (43)
Securityzguard
I'll bet you're the one who did it?
D.Dad!
I hear you working as a security guard
for a rival department store
until 6 months ago.
Don't tell me they asked you to do this
«1» Don't tell me they asked you to do this
Haruyoshi Shirakawa (53)
Owner of Haido Supermarket
for them in order to
give us a bad reputation...
Haruyoshi Shirakawa (53)
Owner of Haido Supermarket
N,No way...
Well, Noriyuki,
I guess this is a good opportunity for you
to go and find yourself a new girlfriend!
Next time go find yourself a nice girl
who has no blemishes to her name!
D. Dad!
Noriyuki
Uh, what did he mean by a girl
with no blemishes to her name?
I think he's talking about
the traffic accident
she caused a year ago in the parking lot...
Traffic accident?
Yes...she ran over a little boy here,
and was fired...
Oh, I heard about:it from
Yumi in the transportation section.
A boy who was waiting for his mother
in this parking lot,
ran out from behind a car
and got run over...
Being a parking lot,
the car wasn't going fast,
but the boy got hit in the wrong place
and died...
I think the boy's name was
Akira Sakurai...
I OTC...
By the way, Noriyuki, do you happen to
know how tall your father is?
A little more than 52"(150 cm.) I think...
And, how about
173 cm...
I'm 144 cm.
I'm 167 cm...
Thattimakes the owner
a possible suspect...
He was capable of knowing that
she'd be coming here too...
Excuse me
did your father come to the restaurant
where you were supposed to
be meeting each other?
No, since he didn't show up
at the promised time,
I had her go check on him
to the parking lot
I see...
D.,Don't tell me that you're suspecting
my father of having killed her?
Oh no...
since a woman, who
was previously: attacked mentioned
the attacker being about 150 cm
we just asked to be sure
A woman who was previously attacked...
Then, is this the doing of that
serial attacker after all?!
WwW, We can't really say
What the hell are you guys doing anyway!
You even know the height of the attacker
and how come you can't arrest him!
If you had only nabbed the attacker
Tae wouldn't have had to die!
Noriyuki...
You, yourthespolice are
to blame for Tae's death!
You police are no good!!
Cut it out, Noriyuki!!
No good
No good...
You police are no good!!
Why are you so surprised?
I'm Saying) Ixll be the bait.
It doesn't work out like in the movies,
does it...
Inspector Megure!
In-Inspector!
Are you all right?
Nothing, it's... nothing...
I'm sorry, Inspector.
Noriyuki's just a bit upset so...
No problem.
He's absolutely right...
h... could we go over to that side
and cool off for a bit...
All right...
I guess I'll get back to work then...
Thank you very much...
You know,
didn't all the three women say
that the attacker was about 150cm tall?
No, the ones who said so, were the first
and third women that were attacked...
The second woman...
was suddenly struck from behind
and was passed out till
a passerby:found her
so she didn't get to see the attacker...
But, there is no mistake
that the attacker is about 150 cm tall.
When we had them come to
the station at a later date
they both said that
the attacker was just about their height...
How tall are th two girls?
The first one is 151 cm
and the third one 153...
We measured them
when they came to headquarters
so there's
no mistake about it.
Hey!
Don't go talking to children about things
you don't have to!
Hey, Ran!
You really saw no one suspicious?
No, I didn't...
I was walking around here for a while
Iooking for the exit but I saw no one...
Isn't,
there something funny, thoug
What's funny?
That woman
Oh, you think so too, Ran?
Don't you think? Right?
There's something strange...
I can't really say what it is but...
There's something...
awfully strange about this woman...
Awfully strange, eh...
Wasn't there something strange
about how the second woman
who was attacked was dressed, too?
This woman was attacked
when she came out of the restroom
In the park after midnight, right?
That's right.
That's the picture that we took
when we went to the scene of the crime...
See...
The restroom in the back?
If a passerby found her,
it means that she was alone, right?
But, she s wearing a man's coat!
Oh, that's my coat,
I put it over her,
because she looked so cold...
Then why was she at the park
at night dressed so lightly?
She said nothing about her jacket
being taken away or anything either...
Come to think of it,
she's been in a state of confusion
ever since the incident
and we haven't been able to really get
anything out of her yet...
You fool!
It's the in thing for young women
nowadays to dress lightly!
But, she was wearing
an outfit with no sleeves...
She was dressed too lightly
for the weather
Maybe she was in a warm place
to begin with
and planning to go right back?
A warm place?
Yes, for example...
Iike in a car or something...
A car!
Come to think of it,
the first and third victims were attacked
when they got out of their cars...
And this fourth incident
happened in a parking lot...
C-Cars are involved in all the cases!
Okay. Officer Takagi,
go check and
confirm this with the second victim!
Yes, sir!
That sort of clears up the suspicion
away fromthe owner, doesn't it...
No, we can't be so sure yet...
Thanks for all the good work
as usual, renowned detective!
Kiyonaga Matsumoto (54)
Superintendent of
Thanks for all the good work
as usual, renowned detective!
Kiyonaga, Matsumoto (54)
the Metropolitan Police Department
S-Superintendent Matsumoto!
Thank you for coming all this way!
Hey, Megure...
the press is out there making a fuss
about this being the beginning
of a series of indiscriminate murders...
Call it a day for now
and come back again tomorrow!
Oh, but, well...
Let's do that, Inspector.
We've already gotten to the point
of knowing that all the victims
were probably riding a car...
If need be,
I'll paint myself black,
ride a car and try again...
I've already told you
that I will not be using decoys anymore!
Please let me stay and
investigate a bit further!
I know I'm close to ettin somewhere!
Besides, I have this feeling that
the killer is still somewhere nearby...
Oh, well...
Inspector Megure...
I hope you're not still...
dragging the you-know-what
case inside of you.
That case that you sealed up
inside that hat of yours...
I would never.
Okay...
Excuse me for the stupid question...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi loka
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE GONAN
C Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
YIN I TMS
All Rights Reserved
DETECTIVE CONAN
C Gosho Avyama / ShogaKukan
YTV / TMS
AllfRightssReserved
Here goes!
Huh, these shoes are too big for her...
That's right, that's the thing!
She wouldn't wear those shoes
with that fashion of hers .
If so, the killer...?!
Hey, isn't anyone around?
Yikes!