Be strong I say to my heart
And step into the essence
with strong rhythm
The contents of the hat will
finally be disclosed.
The mistake that
Inspector Megure had made.
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
We accompanied Sonoko
to the department store
because she wanted to go shopping
However, Pops
gets mixed up in the decoy-investigation
that Inspector Megure and
the others have set up
The Inspector and the others
were in the midst of
Investigating a serial woman
attacker case.
Right at that time,
Ran finds the dead body of a woman
in the basement parking lot
of the department store!
Inspector Megure and the other officers
carry out their investigation but
It seems that Inspector Megure
Is not acting as his usual self...
Superintendent!
Please let me stay and
investigate a bit further!
I know I'm close to ettin somewhere!
Besides, I have this feeling that
the killer is still somewhere nearby...
Well, all right...
Well, all right
Inspector Megure...
I hope you're not still...
dragging the you-know-what case inside of you
That case that you sealed up
inside that hat of yours.
INSPECTOR MEGURE'S
SEALED SECRET" PART II
Mr. Mourn?
Please lend me the key to the car...
I guess it'll take a while longer
so I'm/going to go put the things
in the car and then go to the restroom...
You'd better hurry
because+it"s almost closing time.
Thank you.
Take this too, please.
There it is!
00x0
31-02
This is it over here!
3-02
Ghads, what's with this car anyway.
What a way to park!
I can't even open-the door!
31-02
3051122
There we go!
31-02
Inspector!
Its been confirmed!
And?!
That woman did get off the car after all
and went to theirestroom in the park.
Oh, I see!
I don't understand it...
why would the killer want to go after
hip, fashionable girls who are riding cars?
Or, is he after something else...
Some other thingithat the 4 victims
have in common...
KAZEHDFUET
MPA aE
Toilet Out Of Order
We apologize for the inconvienience
You've gotta be kidding!!
NT @ =r «» °
Toilet Out Of Order
We apologize for the inconvienience
You've gotta be kidding!!
FEAR ZEHMNIULET
125::
Toilet Out Of Order
We apologize for the inconvienience
You've gotta be kidding!!
O,! LO
HER ZEH NILES
FY] = IFS
Toilet Out Of Order
We apologize for the inconvienience
This one's being cleaned too!!
Why don't they clean the restrooms
after the department store is closed.g
The next closest restroom
is on the 8th floor,
I guess I don't jive with restrooms...
Thank you ven much for your patronage.
We will be closing in a few minutes...
Your continued patronage
IS most welcomed.
Oh, no! This can't(be happening...
We're canrying the corpse out.
Hey! Watch her foot!
Oops, sorry!
Huh, this shoe.is;jtoo big for her...
Uh, Ran!
The thing that you were saying
about something being funny...
IS]itA
Right, that's it!
All tanned black and dressed
Iike that, yet...
I mean, you know what is
absolutely outrageous?
I"-If so.
Don't tell me that the killer is. ?!
H-Hey, don't turn the lights off on me!!
I'm still here, you know!!
Hey! Is anybody around!?
High soled boots?
Are you saying that the victim Ms. Aizawa
who was killed in this parking lot
was actually wearing high soled boots?
Yep! Girls who are that dark
and wearing such flashy clothes
would never wear
such regular low heeled slip ons.
Right, Ran?
Why did the killer go out of his way
to change her shoes?
He didn't want anyone to notice.
That he was going around attacking only
drivers who are wearing
high soled shoes!
What?!
The other three victims
were also tanned black
and wearing flashy clothes
when they were attacked.
Which means that it is very likely
that they were also wearing
high soled boots!
Yes, Sir.
Igh soled boots...
When Ms. Aizawa got into
that traffic accident a year ago,
one of the causes of the accident was
that the woman who
stepped on the brakes
was wearin hi h soled boots.
Yumi told me that
the victim couldn't step on the
brakes fast enough because of the shoes.
Is that true?!
1 CO.
The late boys' divorced parents
strongly insisted that it was the reason
but, it wasn't acknowledged after all...
His parents were divorced?
Yes, the reason was
because his father used to get violent
under the influence of alcohol...
If I remember: correctly
he fathers name was...
Sadakane maybe?
Right, right, it was that sort of name!
W-Wait a minute please!
The name of the security guard
that we talked to a while ago
was also Sadakane...
Hey!
Don't tell me the killer is...?
You mean, that securi\ guard!?
Taka I 0 and check on
That case from last year!
Yes, sir!
You guys go and look for the
security guard Sadakane!
Yes, sir!
How'd you ever figure it out?
It was really easy.
Because the killer is after people
W O are wearing 1g soe 00S,Trig
You can't tell if the person is wearing
that kind of shoes from outside,
and the ones attacked were
all customers of this department store...
So, it had to be somebody
who could watch the customers
get in and out of their cars
in this parking lot... The only person that
I could think of as suspicious
was the security guard!
But,
the victims all testified
that the attacker was about 150 cm tall!
That security guard said
he was 167 centimeters!
Ha, ha, ha...
Come on...!
All the women who were attacked
only said that
the attacker was about their height.
So, if the women were wearing boots
that were more than 10 centimeters high,
I know that you already realize that
10 centimeters more have-to
be added on to the killer's height!
I see, we measured their height
when they came to headquarters.
Since they were summoned
for interrogation,
they probably avoided wearing
high soled boots and flashy clothes.
if the killer wanted to avenge
his son's death why didn't
he go directly to her house
rather than ambush her in a place like this?
Did you forget, Mr. Mourn?
The victim is 20 years old, isn't she...
At the time of the accident
he was still under age, wasn't she...
The address of a juvenile
is not publicized...
That's probably why he waited for her
here, where his son was run over
I guess he got agitated
because she didn't show up.
So, he decided to attack women drivers
wearing high soled boots
just to vent out the anger
he had within him...
Inspector! I've got what we need!
That security guard is the father
of the boy who died in the traffic accident
a year ago, after all!
And, where is he now?
W-Well, his car is in this parking lot,
but he's nowhere in sight...
What's up, Ran?
Sonoko's not back yet...
She said that she was going to
take her things to the car,
then go to the restroom, but...
Her things to the car...?!
If I'm not mistaken,
Sonoko was wearing high soled boots...
Hello . ? Oh, Ran?
Huh? Now?
I'm still in the department store
Listen to this...
I mean, I tell you...
I know I was taking my time
in the restroom
but the nerve of them to
urn the lights off on me...
What is it?
Is something the matter? Sonoko?
Oh, no, It's nothing...
I just thought I sensed something funny...
S-She saw me...
She saw me...
She saw my face?!
H-Hey, Sonoko?! Sonoko?!
He's made a mistake!
He's mistaken Sonoko for a driver
wearing high soled boots
because she had the keys to the car
and was putting her things in the car!
What?!
Where did she say she Is now?
She said she is in the department store...
Was the phone cut off?
No, it's still connected but
I hear a computer-like voice
in the distance...
Computer-like voice?
Please choose the frame of your choice.
Push the button after you take a pose!
It's, It's a picture taking machine!
Is there a picture taking machine
in this department store?
Huh? Yes, there is!
I'm sure there were two machines
by the stairs of the restaurant arcade
on the 10th floor
I see!
Even though the lower floors are closed,
the restaurants close late
So, Sonoko must've tried to get down
using the elevator there...
Okay!
Officer Takagi,
you go get the lights turned on!
Officers Megure and Sato,
go around to the top with the elevator,
and the others go from below to the top,
take custody of the girl and
nab the suspect as well!
Yes sir!
Hey! Out of the way! Move!
Inspector, you're really into this case,
aren't you?
They're very similar...
This case is
very similar to
the first case that he handled...
Where is your daughter and
the boy wearing glasses?
There it is!
This is hers!
It's unmistakably Sonoko's cell phone!
The customers at the restaurant arcade
don't seem to have seen Sonoko,
so she must've run into
the department store.
Hey, Takagi!
Can't you get the lights on yet?
You guys are devils!
Moreover...
You're devils pretending to be cute girls,
hile committing crimes...
Devils don't deserve to live!
A black out?!
Damn! Why, at a time like this?!
S-Sonoko...
Sonoko, where are you?
Sonoko!!
Shh! Quiet!
It's the sound of a lot of little things
falling to the ground!
And... grains...
no, something bigger...
I think it's the sound of the pebbles
that are used on the floor of aquariums...
The pet shop is on the 4th floor...
She's on the 4th floor, then!
Let's hurry!
BrllMI-CDXIO7U71PM!
5 COORM-AHAEFRE-BESe0TOT
IEA LEKRERYAADRARD 207
I'm sorry...
All I wanted to do was teach you a lesson.
But,
you saw me, didn't you...
You saw my face...
Sonoko?
Sonoko?!
Range...
nobody's in the pet shop!
Sonoko?!
Strange,
nothing is broken
nor is anything on the floor!
D-Don't tell me that the sound
we just heard was...
You saw... my face, didn't you!
I-Inspector...
Do you feel good, huh?
I'm asking you if you feel good
about hurting people...
You may be thinking that
you are flinging that metal bat of justice
upon young drivers with bad manners
but, unfortunately,
she is just a high school girl
who was putting her things in the car
What you're doing is not for justice
or for the sake of your late son.
It's no more than an act of
unjustified resentment
based on misunderstanding!
You took the lives of people
who had nothing to do with the case
just for your own satisfaction
in order to amuse yourself
and distract yourself from your grief!
Don't you see what you're doing!
A-A-All I wanted was
for that woman to apologize...
For her to wear normal shoes
and apologize to my son up in heaven...
That's really how I felt in the beginning...
It's true...
Sonoko!!
Agh, Ran!
Ran!!
Are you all right?
You're not hurt, are you?
I wasaso scared!
Inspector!
Amazing how you figured out
where she was...
Oh well .
This.léd merhere...
This go stone...
I-Inspector!
Are you all right?
No need to worry.
It's just that the old wound
opened up again...
The old wound that
I was supposed to
have left way back in the past...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshit Tak tans
Haruo Oocawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okad1
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kénjiikodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / stogakukan
YTV / TMS
All Rights Reserved
What
an old wound that
he got from a case in the past?
Yeah...
Megure wears the hat in order to hide
the old wound that he got in the past.
But...
isn't a wound equivalent to
a medal of honor for an officer?
Why should he hide it...
It's been more than 20 years already
Yes,
it was back then, when...
Megure had just become
a police detective...
I take it you all know about
the case of high school girls being
run over, the hit-and-run case...
Oh, yes!
The motive of the criminal was...
the grudge that he held towards
the delinquent high school girls
who blackmailed him for money...
What the criminal did was
catch the girls alone and
run them over with his car.
Totally outrageous...
Back then...
the fad among
delinquent high school girls
was to waer long skirts
below their knees.
He went and ran over
every such girl he saw...
At first...
he just bumped into them and fled,
but his actions eventually escalated
and a victim ended up being killed
Therefore,we warned
the high school girls in the vicini
not to wear skirts like those
when going out.
No more cases were reported
after that, however...
One day,
a high school girl came up saying that
she would like to act as decoy
so that she could avenge
the death of her friend...
Of course we turned her offer down, but...
we had no way of stopping the girl
who had her doubts
about the police too.
Therefore, having no choice
we had Megure watch over her...
The criminal tried to run her
over as well as Megure...
Fortunately,
Inspector Megure remembered
the license plate number of the car.
Although the criminal was caught,
Megure paid a large price in return.
Although Megure got away
with¥a wound on his head
the girl slammed her body and head
hard against the pavement
and by the time we got to the scene,
she was covered with blood
and totally ravaged...
Then, the reason why
the Inspector doesn't take off his hat
IS because...
Yeah, that's right,
because most surely anybody
would ask him
how he got the large wound
on his head if they saw it...
And, each time...
He'd have to recall
the incident from back then'.
That's why Megure sealed off
the wound with his hat...
That old wound packed with
bad memories...
That's why the Inspector was...
so much against the decoy idea...
He didn't want the same thing
to happen again .
Oh, but although
the girl was badly hurt...
she didn't die.
She's still alive!
After all, she's Megure s...
Oh, Superintendent Matsumoto!
You've come to visit too, huh...
Officer Takagi and Shiratori just left...
Midori Megure
Inspector Megure's wife
Oh, so they've also come!
Yes, they've all come
between working hours.
She has a wound on her forehead?
D-Don't tell me that...
Hey, Midori,
will you peel an apple for me?
I will tell you,
he is so spoiled regardless of his age!
I guess I'll go blast him one
so that he shapes up and
gets back to work as soon as possible.
Oh yes By allO'means.\
Come to think of it
I've heard that Inspector Megure's wife
used to be a delinquent before...
Maybe the reason the Inspector
never takes off his hat is because...
He doesn't want to be teased about
his first encounter with his wife...
Hey, what's taking you so long...