Be strong I say to my heart
And step into the essence
trong rhythm
The contents of the hat
will finally be 'disclosed.
Ke that
Inspector Megure had-made.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved with
Conan
THE: DE JECTIVES:COME; TOGETHER!
KUDO VS: THIEF KI
Hl IF ro -
Isn't it rare?
A museum...
Aren't you curious what he looks like?
I'm sure he's a nice man!
Like Harrison Ford... John Reno...
yoe csrao VIII...
I heard he collects famous jewelry from
all over the world and holds exhibitions.
That you get to see
the largest blackypearl in the world.
that is said to bring happiness,
the black pearl called the "Black Star?
303%
studio)
Fao Jrik
WN sz ta-&
steel crows
in the dark of the night...
Still yet beyond... there are two more...
Oops,
Kaito Kuroba (17)
they've even got
an armored vehicle ready...
Kaito Kuroba (17)
they've even got
an armored vehicle ready...
Kaito Kuroba (17)
Cle: OT
the Metroplitan Police Department
They've sure gone all out!
Don't, Kaito...
I have an uncomfortable feeling
about this project...
Konosuke Terai (61)
If you are cornered into a fix like before
methin
should ever happen to'you,
I, as your steward...
wouldn't be able to apologize to him
Ghads! You're always like this
before a big project!
Give me a break,
will you...
Here!
But, Kaito...
Besides, tonight I'm not
the son of Toichi Kurobane
whom you served as steward for...
nor am I Kaito the 8th grader!
I'm the one who
Is the talk of the town right now...
ust a villain...
who's putting on airs...
K-Kaito...
» EKODA HIGH-SCHOOL,
Too easy... way too easy...
EKODA HIGH SCHOOL
Too-Easy... way too easy..."
The next job is duck soup that I could
complete with the tip of my.pinky.."
Female fans entranced by Thief Kid...
are rapidly on the rise!
Talk about just great...
Female fans on the rise, my foot!
Ori (17)
That petty thief!
To me, Aoko,
st a rotten apple of a man
running down the path of hopelessness!
Cool it, don't be angry...
Just because...
your father. that dorky inspector
IS always being undone by him...
It can't be helped, can it?
After all, the Kid is.
ORG...
There!
A great thief that«is impossible to-arrest!
Anyway. as for that Inspector.
He wouldn't be able to arrest the Kid
even if Star Wars were to
come up with a completed version
Oh shush, darn you!
Just because you resemble
the Kid and you?
can perform a little bit of magic...
you-re always stickingsup for him
That guy's seeking nothing
more than self-satisfaction
y exposing what he steals
and then secretly returning it later...
aypretentious goody-goody!
That's the very thing I like about him...
Akako Koizu
er WE
Akako Koizumi
He's just like a mischievous young boy,
so he's cute, isn't he?
Oh. Akako!
Akako!?
D-Don't let him deceive you!
That guy is nothing, but a criminal,
matter how you look at it!
He is a villain!
Besides, you saw it on TV,
what the Kid is after next,
didn't you?!
H... you mean
the old clock tower
in front of the station?
Ri ht!
That belongs to
everyone here in this town!
So, don't youithink
ites terrible of him to steal it?
NCO - Noe
1715... 1 YucosdSSDS dL.
M-Moreover that place is...
That clock tower is...
But, I heard that the clock tower
Keiko M
was going to be moved
somewhere else soon anyway
Keiko
That it was going to be used
Keiko M
as the symbol of some amusement park...
Keiko...
Everybody was saying that
if it was going to be moved elsewhere,
It may as well be taken away by the Kid.
What s not good is not good!
Hey...
I don't know whatiyou're up to. But...
I really think you should call off the job
you're planning to carry out this time!
Listen,
I've been telling you that I am not the Kid!
The old tower that tells time,
when the 20,000 bells sing...
A malevolent man will come flying
from the eastern sky and...
the white sinner shall be perished...
Huh?
Is that some stupid make-believe...
e fortune-telling again?
It's not fortune-telling...
It's a prophecy that has come to me
the devil, Lucifer...
The day that clock sounds its bell for
0,000th time is the night
that you warned
ou'll be carr in out our deed...
Yy 8 Be
Whether you believe me or not
0 you, though...
THE CLOCK TOWER
To all vehicles, helicopters circling the sky
Ginzo Nakamori (41)
Police Inspector
nil 5 Ffifl
T - - B88... 08
and police cars patrolling
the vicinity of the clock tower.
Ginzo Nakamori (41)
Police Inspector
*, ay.
tRITIEH - ak." ab
and police cars patrolling
the vicinity of the clock tower.
Report any sightings of suspicious people
of you who are in charge of
guarding the inside of the museum,
don't let anybody through
without my orders!
Guard the post that you are assigned to
your entire heart and soul!
But, Inspector Nakamori...
I wonder if Kid's really going to show up?
His warning went like this, right?
Saturday night when the moon is full,
at the sound of the bell at midnight
I will appear to take the clock
that soars high above away...
The Thief Kid.
Was thinking that he
would have to use a darn big crane
If he were to take a clock
that large away...
You idiot!
When he says he'll steal something,
It means he will!
The needle of the clock...
This clock tower is one
that my father, who was mayor...
Futoshi Takarada (53)
An owner of the clock tower
By =+ £54 - IF
This clock tower is one
that my father, who was mayor...
Futoshi Takarada (53)
An owner of the clock tower
RT al AO 1
This clock tower is one
that my father, who was mayor...
Dished out a large sum and
asked a famous designer technician
from abroad to make...
short hand of the clock, and
along with the signature of the designer
it has several large diamonds
embedded in it.
It is a highly valued work of art...
He's probably after the diamonds...
why'd you let the owner through?
I'm sorry!
He insisted that he wanted to check out
s of security
with his own eyes so...
I sure hope you checked.thoroughly
ther he is really the owner?
Of course...
Whatever you do...
Please protect it...
from the evil hands of that petty thief
hat sent me that ridiculous letter
with a challen in warnin
Hilly
the dear clock tower that I have
inherited from my late father,
do protect it...
1 CO...
We will, owner...
I'm counting on you.
By the way, Inspector!
I haven't seen Police Superintendent
akuba's son, Saguru
around lately...
Yeah...
he said something about having
some unfinished case to take care of
and went back to London...
We sure could've used his help,
couldn't we...
. You idiot!
Oh, I'm so sorry!
What makes you think
we» can COUHUOH
that costume wearing freak?!
Time after time!
Only 28 minutes and 30 seconds
promised time...
Residing in Ekoda...
27 years old... single
police officer Yoichi Sensul...
I'm going to borrow your
name and face for a while.
Excuse me!
Kid, Kid...
L-Look at the number of onlookers...
Owner, how was it inside?
5 (32)
Wa (32)
r. Takarada
5 (32)
wa (32)
r. Takarada
5 (32)
Perfect!
Wa (32)
r. Takarada
a (32)
5 (32)
Not an ant can get through...
awa (32)
r. Takarada
Not an ant can get through...
B-But...
I wonder if everything is okay
on the amusement park side...
I hear that since it will not make it
in time for the opening,
unless the construction for moving
the clock tower is started tomorrow,
purchase of the clock tower
may be cancelled...
M-Moreover,
if the Kid ever steals the precious stones
that are embedded
in the short hand of the clock,
and if he finds out
that the stones are...
Shh!
We're the only ones who know now
that I have already sold off
the diamonds
and switched them for fake ones...
B-Besides
the price of it has jumped high, now that
everyone knows the Thief Kid is after it
and there won't be
a better time to sell it...
Whether they find out
about the whole thing
after the clock tower
IS moved to its new location
is none of my business...
Besides, it would never be stolen!
How could he ever steal
that enormous clock tower...
In front of all these people...
no matter how great a phantom:thief .
He is appearing at unexpected moments
Din- "\
Ieaving no trace behind...
Don't you dare come here, Thief Kid!
Give it to him, Dad!
Hey! Hey, Aoko!
You:re the only one
saying something like that...
You re.the only:one
saying.-something like that...
--""
I know, but...
By the way, Keiko...did you see Kaito?
By:the way..Keiko... did you see Kaito?
By:the way, Keiko. :. did you see Kaito?
Nope: not at all...
ov J oT
Oh'..right,-he said
he's-going to be watching a magic show
that is;jgoing totbe aired tonight...
he's going to be watching a magic show
that is;going to 'be aired tonight...
2 FF >.
he's 'going to be watching a magic show
that-is" going to be aired tonight. _.
-- = -
Oh...
I guess I'm the only one
who remembers something
so old that happened in the past...
What?!
You witnessed a suspicious looking
Thief Kid-like character while on patrol?!
Yes, sir!
Edsthis
suspicious:looking hat and left!
T-This iswthe Thief Kid:s silkehat-and cape!
Will you wait here a while...
Ye S'S Sirs
Inspector Nakamori, please...
Yes...the silk hat and cape are here...
Yes...yes...it seems so...
Okay! I've got approval
from:the Inspector!!
Willryou go explain the circumstances
back then and:the features of the man
you saw directly to the Inspector who
Is at the top most floor?
Yes, sir!
Kid! Kid!
Duck soup!
Without Hakuba around, it's so easy /
that it's no fun after all...
Here they come...Beniko.
Yes . No doubt about it# It's
that helicopter...
He emits the same transparent
vibe that Kaito emits...
He has the cunning of the devil,
and possesses a keen eye that
sees through the hearts of people...
Who is he?!
Hey! What's going on!?
There us one extra chopper!
Pport
helicopter sent over by headquarters.
Support from headquarters?I don't recall
r somethin like that!
Oh... The Thief Kid's silk hat
I've been informed of you...
But, please show me your police ll.D.
nse, just to be sure...
Yes, of course!
Then...please give me your name,
age and date of birth...
Yoichi Sensui, 27 years old,
born June 2nd!!
Okay . good work!
Inspector Nakamori is,waiting for you
on the top floor!
Yes, sir!
Right, just in case...
give me your driver's license number...
Yes...number 628605-524810!
H-He's the Thief Kid!!
Nab him!
T-This can't be happening?!
WW-What?! You found the Thief Kid
inside the building?!
Yes, sir!! The C and D groups
are pursuing him right now!
Hey...Hey. I hope he's no imposter?!
No, there's no,mistake about it!
After he answered
his name, age and birth date,
I remembered.»was told to ask for
his driver's license,number, and whalah!
His driver's license number. A
Yes, sir!
The boy who was sent over
by headquarters had informed me that...
if the thief is an expert at disguising
himself.as another, he would
probably remember what others
would usually not be able to recall...
A boy, you said?
I repeat!
Please close off the entrance and exit
of the clock 'tower immediately!
Please don't open them
until we instruct you to do so...
He's no more than a mole in a hole
that cannot move now...
D group, Nakamura and Kawada...!
We've lost sight of him
near the 3rd floor toilet...
ase calm down, I'm sure
he is still somewhere near you...
The ventilation hole that is
beyond that toilet...
Aren't the screws removed?
It's been removed...
It's been removed!
Then, he's in there!
Please resume pursuing him!
There he is!! It's him!
Hey ..Hey... Hey...
The inspector sure is sharp today...
Or, is someone helping the inspector out?
But, who could it be?!
Sgt SNNnet Fmt Net net Sug
So, it's you after all!
Just what do you think you're doing,
bringing a kid to a place like this...
I'm the commander of this site!
And, besides you don't belong
in this section!
Well...I'm very sorry...
I promised that I'd let him board
the chopper this once...
So, I thought I may as well bring him
ng while I was at it... Huh...?! H
Inspector! I hate to be rude, but
we've got no time to debate with you...
If you want to arrest the thief,
please follow my orders...
wW-What?ls
He's thrown off after being identified
before having the chance
to execute his plan...
His plan is not going as he expected...
There is no better chance
to capture him, but now!
W-Who are you?!
Whorthe hell are you?!
1 am...
Shinichi Kudo...
A detective...
S-Shinichi... Kudo?!
On... know him. I know him!
A high school detective who solves
mysterious cases one after the other...
Then, you're also in the wrong section!
We're after a thief!
Inspector! He's just a high school student
and belongs to no section...
At any rate! This 1s a job
for the police to handle!
Outsiders just stay put in
that chopper of yours! Understand?!
Inspector Nakamori!
Nakamuira of the D group,
after receiving word from the boy,
discovered the Thief Kid disguised as
a police officer inside the ventilation duct!
They are still pursuing him!
What?!
Nakamura of the D group here!
It seems that our target is trying to exit
from the ventilation duct!
W-What should we do?!
Don't panic...
Your target is already caught
in your grasp!
Please tell me your present location!
Well.)
since I was moving along in the dark,
I'm not so sure of where I am now...
I know that I went up one flight of stairs
rom the 3rd floor and
that this is the 4th floor...
No problem!
The exits of all the 28 ventilation tunnels
there are within the building have
osed off!
Please just keep on pursuing him...
There is no escape route
anymore...
The officers who are blocking off
the exits of the ventilation tunnels
Nn the 4th floor should
get ready to arrest him...
How dare he... giving out orders
n his own again...
This is Nakamura of D group!
I lost sight of him near the exit of the
ventilation duct!
What is your present location?!
Tio 15...
The corridor to the east on the 4th floor!
The target has gotten rid of
IS disguise as an officer
UL, RN
and is fleeing down the stairs!
Tn oN
Please send a support
team over right away...
(Iv 1%
T-T-Thief Kid...
Great work, officer!
Okay! He panicked
and got rid of his disguise as an officer!
Don't let him get away!
But, why does that boy
have so much information
as to the structure of this clock tower?
Of course! Because I sent him the data!
You idiot!
Strange...
For him to remove his disguise
as an officer in the space
that is surrounded by officers
is like a hermit crab disposing of its shell
and roaming within the sea...
o me, that ls incomprehensible...
I-It's time, Inspector Nakamori...
Inspector!
Smoke has burst forth from
the foothold at the construction site!
W-What?!
I-Inspector Nakamori!
The hands of the clock ..are gone?!
What?! They're gone?
Wow!! The Thief Kid 1s really something!
Thief Kid...
I hate you Thief Kid!
Is anything wrong?
It's swaying?
Yeah, you mean this chopper is swaying?
No. Ins ector!
In-Inspector, where are you headed?
I'm going to go up and
check the engine room of the clock!
Could)you please...bring the chopper
closer to the clock tower...
Darn! What the heck is going on anyway?
Anything new?!
N-No
W-What the...
H-Hey, what happened?!
A police officer appeared
from the ventilation duct and...
W-What?!
After spraying something strange at us...
H... He went out from there...
It can't be...
If, If so, he should be clearly visible
T-Thief Kid!
Thief Kid!
It, It's me! Nakamori! I've found the Kid!
He ls...
Inspector Nakamori...
My apologies that I have no time now to
be playing with all of you...
W-What...!
Besides, it seems that you have a joker
who is pretty sharp on your side too...
On our side?!
And, if you're going to summon anybody,
I'd like you to do so after
you have deciphered the code
that has been carved into the...
middle of the face of the clock
Code?
Yes, I'd like you to decipher
before callingranyone...
T-The face of the clock is swaying?!
What is the meaning of this Shinichi?
He»is lighting up the face of the clock
together with the curtain of smoke...
The light is turned off, and
the face of the clock is covered with
a gigantic screen that has been
set up beforehand.
And projected on the screen
IS a film of the hand of the clock
The film is being projected from a
projector that has been assembled onto
a foothold at the construction site...
But, it's so easy to figure that trick out...
That trick...
Is fake!
He syprobably behind he screen
right now removing the diamonds
that are embedded in the
short hand of the clock...
I'm going to borrow this for a while.
Hey! Who is it?!
Darn
With the chopper at such close range...
I can't possibly fly using my hand glider...
What shall I do...? What now?!
H-Hey, Shinichi!
Don't worry! I won't hit anyone...
No! That's not the point. Shinichi!
Now: for the finale of your magic show...
Lets watch the leader
of the troupe appear...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michithiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND) MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
OGosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
YTV [ TMS
All Rights Reserved