Be strong I say to my heart
And step into the essence
with strong rhythm
Finally, the truth of the hat comes out.
The reluctance of Mr. Megure
IS unimaginable.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan.
THE DITECTIVES COME TOGETHER!
KUDO VS. THIEF KID
What?!
Senma died?!
It was rigged so that when you touch
the lights of the car, it would explode.
Oh, no...
Waiting here is just going to get us killed.
Let's split up and go check
If there is really someone else
in this house!
Then maybe we three women
should form a group.
That way we can even
go to the restroom together.
Hey,
By the way, where did that brown haired,
fair skinned young man gov
Beats me...
maybe he's feeding the eagle
that he brought along with him?
What a fancy thing to find here.
There-is a brand new scratch
on the piano cord.
That was probably made
by the claws of the eagle.
It goes to show that the young man
also came and searched this room.
There is something stuck
between the keys of the piano!
Is this the secret code that indicates
the location of the treasure
that he was talking about?!
But why is it mimeographed
on rice paper?
Somebody probably printed
a whole lot of this
when no such things
as copy machines existed yet
and, for some reason,
distributed it to many people.
In other words,
the thing he was referring to,
the story about the tragedy
that occurred here 40 years ago
as well as the secret code
indicating the hidden treasure, the
story created after the tragedy...
it's all a bunch of baloney.
This piano is leaking.
Come to think of it, yes, it is.
This is that young lady's luminol fluid.
Which means that
she s been in this room too.
Hey flimsy mustache, turn off the light!
Quick!
Where is Aki, the maid?
She said she'd be waiting in the corridor
outside the restroom,
but why don't you go check?
Oh, okay.
AKI?
Aa Am?!
There are letters written in blood
on the piano.
Something did happen here
40 years ago after all.
An ace...
Don't tell me that?!
Just as "thought.
So, it was you, after all.
The killer would never risk danger,
such as to ride a car
that has been rigged with a bomb.
In other words, the possible killers are
those who stayed behind...You and me...
Ran and the maid, Akl.
Oh, my, sonny,
that stuff can be dangerous.
It was under the pillow in my room.
Although you!probably put it there
so that you'; could set me up
as the killer later.
Oh, what a coincidence...
I was thinking exactly the same thing.
I made the exact same deduction as you.
G, Gun fire?!
It came from the center tower!
No good...
The bullet's one ri ht throu h his chest.
The stairs?!
Somebody's using the stairs!
A computer...
He said to come here after
we find where the treasure is.
Ms.*S, Sota?!
Take a look!
Fl turn the knob that is on the inside,
a needle is set up to come out.
When the one
who finds the treasure inputs
the location of the treasure
into the computer
and is ready to leave the room,
that person is poisoned to death.
But, where on earth is the killer?!
Don't you play dumb with me!
This woman couldn't have been done in
by a trap she set up herself,
and the maid-and your daughter
are snoozing away in the toilet.
If that gunshot was a fake,
the only two people who. can
commit murder are you and me.
I know It's not me, so it means...
that you're the one, right?
Punish the suspicious.
No offense,
Mr. Sleeping Kogoro...
This can't be happening!
Even gathering the detectives did not
result in a solution after all.
C,Cut off?!
The picture of the hidden camera.
What?!
Somebody is inputting data?!
Who on earth could it be?!
What?!
DOWER IMRT
MOTHER
RIZ7ABDOMMAI
DEER (ARF 7
BOTT AW
(XT 7 ABA
DOWER IIR
flurfiznu
bay - 3 -~
- - QC» Oo
RZ7ABDRMI
OD HE == (ZX ig ( 77
EO TEAL
ec NS
The code of the room
has been deciphered.
DEE (IMT
IO TEXAN
NIT ABORMNK
The code of the room
has been deciphered.
Uflfigfifilff
IX TI XX 7- LN
glen: u
FIT ABORAN
The code of the room
has been deciphered.
DEES (IMR (TF 7
Tio AT
eon u
es I"
The code of the room
has been deciphered.
DEBIT
IO TEE 7 LN
The code of the room
has been deciphered.
DEE = (IMT
cfientu
I'd like to verbally say it directly to you
Ufifiglifllff
I= > O94 bis
fim7AEOfl@I
I'd like to verbally say it directly to you
DIES (IMF 7
WOQTEHAT_W
Sonu
so J"
yo. - vv
I'd like to verbally say it directly to you
DEES (IMRT 7-
Cd TAI xX 72 CU»
Ile UL
I'd like to verbally say it directly to you
wflfi§lifllff
I=] TI XX _7_ CL»
Ce bN7_L
O - \ «)*.
I'd like to verbally say it directly to you
Dias (IE (T7-
I=C]1 TI Xx 7 UL»
Ce oN
* TE - _A
2'- ZVVI
I'd like to verbally say it directly to you
Dias (IEF T
(Ce bN/7_L
F*(37 AB DIRK
I'd like to verbally say it directly to you
DIES (IRE ITT
BOA TE ATW
(Ce oN7T_ UL
so come to the dining roon
Dias IBY
IBEOTEATW
*I127 ABDIFME]
SO come to the dining roon
Digs (IETF 7
Ce NV] I
Can - _AO
so come to the dining rocon
OOBS SS (X88 (FT 7
Iie I
TIT NBDORAN
The 7th detective!
It, It can't be!!!
All the detectives that I invited
should be dead!
There is no such thing as a 7th detective!
Then, who can it be?! Who on earth...
It is difficult to think that
the person who set the bomb to the car
would ride!the 'car unless
it was a suicidal plan...
However, there are exceptions.
That is, in the case
you want to make it look like you
yourself died in the explosion...
Ri ht?
Detective Senma
Yes...before the explosion you...
snuck out of the car,hid in the bushes,
and confirmed the car falling over.
After sneaking back here,
you were watching all of us
from a room somewhere in here
through all the hidden cameras...
Don't be ridiculous...
I got out of the car in the nick of time after
I realized the car was going to explode
I just got back here
Besides, didn't we decide at that time
who was going to ride the car
even before the coins were tossed...
Not really...it was already decided
that you were going to ride the car
even before the coins were tossed...
You set the coin with the head facing up
on the back of your hand
even before you tossed the coin...
You covered your right hand
over your left hand
from above the coin that
you were holding, in order to hide it
and pretended to
catch the coin that you flicked.
You dropped that coin on the ground, then
all you had to do was show the first coin
you put on the back of your hand
No matter how many times
you repeat it, you get heads!
Since you had a 10 yen coin on you
when checking the tea that
Mr Ogami was drinking,
you would've been able to carry this out,
wouldn't you?
The God Forsaken Child!
Are you saying that
the guest who carried out the supper
and killed Mr. Ogami Is me?
Then, tell me.
How did I make only Mr. Ogami take
the cyanide in this dining room,
and just how
was I able to predict the time...
There was no poison in his tea,
Mr. Mouri was sitting in between
Mr. Ogami and me...
Besides, didn't we do rock, paper,
scissors to decide where to sit?
The seating has nothing to do-with it...
Because you had swabbed everybody's
cup with,cyanide beforehand anyway...
You swabbed the cyanidefin the upper
part where the handle joins the cup...
That is the place where
Mr. Ogami's rightthumb tip touches
when he holds his teacup
It is also very close to his nails that
he unconsciously bites when he thinks
He started biting his nails right
after the tape recording of
your altered voice
announced the code of the
hiding place of the treasure
If you gave instructions to the maid
to serve the tea a little before
the tape was to be played...
Mr. Ogami, after hearing about the code,
would start thinking
and you would be able to kill him
alone just as scheduled .
But, back then, I remember that
everyone wiped their dishes
before using them, just to be safe...
True...
It was too careless for a renown
detective, such as Mr. Ogami
But, if he was your partner in planning
the supper then
Being so sure that nothing could ever
happen to him,
it's not hard to understand why he
skipped the safety precautions
that everyone else took
From the time I heard that
Aki had arrived early in the morning,
the Benz was already parked...
I was suspicious of you...
In order for anyone to abandon a Benz
in such an remote mountain area
there had to be someone to ride the Benz
as well as somebody else
to come pick you up.
You would need an accomplice
While I'm at it,
the reason why you went out of your way
to. wait for Mr. Mouri
and make him give you a lift was
Ieave an impression on him
that you don't like cigarettes
in order for it to work out so that only
Mr. Ogami died in the dining room...
If Mr. Ogami were to put a cigarette
in his mouth after grabbing a cyanide
coated cigarette with his fingertips
He would immediately
go to the world beyond
The reason why you chose Aki
to be your maid is because
you found out that she has a
habit of biting her fingernails
by watching her through the hidden
camera during the interview
and you figured that you could kill her
using the same method
that you used to kill
Mr. Ogami at any time.
You killed Mr Ogami,
who was your accomplice, and
made yourself look as if you'd been killed
by someone else,
psychologically cornered
all the detectives that you've invited here
into deciphering the code
and once you found the treasure you
were going to massacre everyone here.
Just like Renya Karasumaru
did 40 years ago!!
I found the name + osuke Senma
at the end of the words
written in blood on the piano
That was probably...
That's my father's name
My father who was an archaeologist was
invited to this Twilight Inn 40 years ago
The story was that a millionaire
who was over 100 years of age
inherited this estate from his mother
found out that there was hidden
treasure in the building.
He wanted someone to find the treasure
for him before his time to lie...
It seemed to be an easy job that paid well
and cash was sent to us
everyday with a letter
so my mother and I were delighted.
But, 6 months later, the letters and
cash suddenly stopped coming.
My father who did not tell us
where he was going,
could not be contacted
ever since that time.
We found out the truth
only after we raised the last letter we got
from my father up to the light...
It was a letter that my father had written
by opening holes using a needle.
The letter was about a code that indicated
the location of the hidden treasure
It said that there were many other
scientists besides my father
who had been summoned to the place
and that Karasumaru,
who was almost at the end of his time,
became impatient and started killing
the scientists within the building
as an example to the others
of what would happen
if they didn't hurry up and find the treasure...
My father had also written that
even if the treasure were to be found
he would not be able to make it out alive.
Did you tell the police about this?
No, I only found out about the letter written
with a needle 20 years later...
And, besides, Renya had already
passed away
and the building was handed over
to someone else...
But, it all, started when I happened
tostalk about this to Ogami 2 years ago...
He went all out and found this place and
started like mad to look for the treasure.
However, he couldn't decipher the code .
He bought this place and had
a large debt because of it.
So, unable to reverse what
had already been done,
he said the following.
Let's gather all the
well-known detectives here
and have them decipher the code!
The bait to get all the detectives to come,
is the Thief Kid!
We'll set him up as the host,
and set up a game
which everyone would have
to stake their lives on!
By making it look as though both
you and me have been killed
part way through the game!
Right! Maybe we should
actually kill the maid?
Once they find out that
they really have to be risking their lives
they have no choice but to get serious!
No problem, we'll just put
all the blame on the Thief Kid!"
Which means the one
who chose that maid was.
Mr. Ogami...
He was delighted saying that he found
a maid with a habit just like his
that he could kill,
just as he would be killed
but I guess he never thought that
he'd be killed in the same way.
Yes he bit his nails at that time
because I had recorded
something he had not expected to hear.
Because he was thinking of killing
the maid after the dinner
But, why did you kill Mr. Ogam?
Because I realized that he had found
the location of the hidden treasure
and was planning to kill everyone
including me
By making it look like we all killed
each other using the guns
that he had set up in all of our rooms...
I had no other choice but to carry things
out the way I did, f I were to stop Ogami
who was obsessed like Karasumaru,
as well as let the detectives continue
to decipher the code.
The result ended up the same as
40 years ago...
The code could not be deciphered
and the tragedy was repeated
I think your father did decipher
the code, don't you?
Don't you think it's strange that there
is only one clock in this large building
the one in the dining room
the sentence at the top of the code
Iookéd- up at the sky ."
Il0okéd- up at the sky...
means when the long hand and
the short hand of the clock
point to the same direction
at the top, 00:00!
So, let's do that by making
the hands of the clock point at 00:00
And the key to solving the rest of the code
Is what your father had left behind
by writing in blood the final ace!
This refers to playing cards in English!
The King, Queen and Jack in the code
are the King, Queen and Jack
of the playing cards!
The treasure is diamond the chalice
is heart and the dagger is spade
In other words, the treasure and the King
the king of diamonds!
The chalice and the Queen
the queen of hearts!
The dagger and the wainnior
the jack of spades!
First you bring the hands
of the clock to 00:00...
then you move the hands of the clock
In accordance to the direction
their faces are turned...
Left 13,
Left 12,
Right 11, then...
The polish has rubbed off
and gold is in view on the inside...
Moreover, this clock
IS heavier than it looks...
I see...the inside of this clock
IS pure gold
to think that my father had to die
for something like that
I guess that's life
So, you promised, Ms. Senma
Tell me the way out of this place!
There is no way out of here to begin with
I was planning to bury my bones here,
you see...
Although Mr. Ogami did believe me
when I told him
that I would tell him
the way after dinner...
Just as I thought
Granny Senma...
What're you going to do about
the only valuable I had on me?
Remember I told you that something
childish like this isn't worth it...
Complain to sonny over there
If you got any gripes
» He's the one who said that
she may tell us the way out
if a child asked to know...
You mean you all pretended to be dead
just so that I would tell you the way out?
Because you were even trying to kill
the ones who figured the code out
We figured that you wouldn't tell us
even if we cornered
you so long as we were alive
Besides, throu h the monitor
even ketchup looks like blood!
But, at least we did right in putting
Ran and Aki to sleep.
This act of bad taste would have been too
harsh on the hearts of young women...
S,Since when did you know
I was the killer?
From the time,
that boy over there made I toss the coin
Back then
you stretched your hand all the way over
to take the coin
that was farthest away from you, right?
That's when it flashed through me
That you didn't want anyone else
to take the 10 yen coin.
If anyone with cyanide on their hands
touch the 10 yen coin,
redox reaction would occur,
and the whole trick would be disclosed!
That's why we all todk you to be the killer
and joined hands right off the bat!
I had seen through the trick
as soon as I saw
Mr. Ogami's nail of his right thumb...
Y ou little brat
So, the problem is...
how do we make it out of here...
My, what's that sound?
Oh, probably the police choppers
that I contacted...
You called them...?
Watson probably took the letter
that I had attached to his anklet
to nanny who was waiting in the car
below the cliff as soon as morning came!
I'm glad that I marked the car with an X
so that he'd be able to tell it
apart from other cars...
Why didn't you tell us sooner!
Talk about having to
put on such a crumby act...
No, that's not only
the sound of choppers...
I hear the sound of something
collapsing too...
D.,Don't tell me that...!
So, The Thief'Kidenever showed up, huh...
Did you want him to?
Oh, not really...
But, granny...
etd 44
The thing about psychologically cornering
us was Ogami's idea, wasn't it?
Why did you pretend to be dead
after you killed him?
I wanted the code that
my father left behind to be deciphered
no matter what the risk...
I wanted to find out in this life time...
I didn't think I could ever have
such renown detectives like you
gather together like this, ever again...
Maybe it was I,
who was obsessed by Renya Karasumaru
G,Granny?!
Shoots!
What?! T Thief Kid?
Hey granny!
I think you're already too old
to rush to your death, huh?
Don't be ridiculous!
I saved you...
What?
As an apology for using your name
to hold the supper...
You would've never been able to escape
the grasp of those two boy
unless I did it this way...
Especially from the little one
that was aiming
a strange looking watch at you!
Oh - so ou knew...
Cigarette...
Kogoro Mouri is a heavy smoker...
You didn't smoke one cigarette
since arriving at the inn, right?
Who are they... anyway?
Lovers... that I most definitely
do not want to encounter, I guess?
How unfortunate.
You came...
Because you were after
Karasumaru's treasure, didn't you?
Yeah, at first maybe, but
I guess not, after all...
It won't fit into the cloth
I carry my stolen goods in...
- V,he walls have collapsed and
gold is showing from inside...
That clock was the switch
to bring the walls down...
Just a would be expected of
a residence owned by Karasumaru
It's worth at least zillions...
I see
Twilight means the time
when the sky glitters yellow at sunset...
It is indeed the Twilight Inn!
WV 7 EPID EEL FRE
MN VT
HER go
12117% TA
Ii 11a
Ms HA
Woes Xk » EMT
INC (FE ND EL pris (Th&
oD HM
IryNasr. mF Ir
14 )d Io
- of 4s
%; YEP WEE
Qomoa GRE VX
+ Bm 27412
IH) 23888 wmmuy Ha. J Him x
fr SE AOL FI Md U bie
TOD {10d
JIQAgd Id I
rR) 7
mOMR
Bret
ARIZ 0
FWDHLD
BF{?
FF Mm Wm
rzfi-rruz.» invert-a nix: in,
Cf o>TWs BANE ED SRARICBRL
» (DIR 1%
Co TID BAMFIZES £2 ARICBL
LE ->TWD BAHT ED £ RRICHL
7, fr [Xe
hs HAN Ls
Fit Fow.a
A=_ra rey
2 Bapires
ir) JAR £5
Jago as
1? x->a>t>fi
TILT Es
TENTH
IZ UL ARD
$I T--ADs 2
HA - ratory
7 AT7 =)
PAT MAT
[.LL70 LL ON DO
ART FHT - RD
WIRTZ A-vaves¥
AZ AMAT
7S 2 Iv
Hw JIN
_S 18 gris;
n staff fin? life
- LU AND
AR IT -A5 0
FT A=artzr¥
AP HXMAT
Nn start in my life
(1%: ¢ dev rev ho,
FINRA
LR 7b (TD
Nn start in my hfe
FFI NRA
FAR Zab (TD
7 a= 1
JE 1)
ase) JA
+. Aye yy
MAY Tr
« LN SS 7
pair
Joy vey J
«YN. Ae
A, > Vo 00 Ye
HIRT
AA En
Is 2 FT I
AAR FIR
Var. agmmoasysy oa.
BF RISE 3
HESHIBL
BE 15 REY XE
252311152
YAPRRITIQFY av.
Il £5152 BE HE 88 Sz IT
TY 72
5 oo SS Iji HERR:
Vine of 4
= 2347 jiii
FAR THE OC NnD 1)
VIDEO}? f
O-XND ATH, DD
5S oZILIR
4 A NN tT-3 ~7J Jb pry Fan 0
PM TY
BART 2 Sr
FL) oj
0 sa Brick
#4 IE Fn
APU RHF
LO5-AD BH Ex
AL, 144 Th
Lah Pg
NPY) ey
so ID TVA AS!
AY 4-947)
Pm AB MM IR
wm 50% 8 IR
mm Cybersound
(GIZA
HIND QIckA
SFL 0F
AY bARA4547)
man SIF 8B IR
mam Cyhersound
(GIZA
t 113 I
- jiOd Yr
RAT) 9 I25
WMBFL-oO LL ASA)
KH BR
ne 4 xX ox
Ba _= FR
44 Hot BO ~
Te > Szer °C ye TC
IT o- J Co 140 - DID/
WB -2 C° FIN BNE
HIT AR TD
mk EFT
MIF ~~ DD CF EASE LDT EL
Po Co FL)
FA -gpath To -Y a
MW Ve
TU kL
Nite
Am oh
wr why) 2
v7 A SS YE
Tl SIRE 0) 1 =
BLNN
MRE 9 - T5354 KL
Judt stale 't» ny lire
FH2 Jr
Rah E
Just sta.¢ fA mybife
FH Jr
Ne lLi-Eg
Um! Where is my real dad 7?
Acchoo
Phew... over here...