Be strong I say to my heart
And step into the essence
with strong rhythm
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan
THE DETECTIVES COME TOGETHER!
KUDO VS THIEF KID
The Thief Kid...
He's an honest guy
The minute his name was mentioned
he showed signs of his identity.
I sensed your piercing,
callous presence...
No doubt about it, he is here...
Inside this house...
I don't know what he's up to, but,
I wonder if he can continue deceiving
the 7 detectives
who are gathered here!
4 Ah WAH
ay, O-
Then,
are you saying that the Thief Kid
is the one who invited us here?
It seems that he gathered the six of us
that have a eputation of being good
detectives hereto compete intellectually.
By staking the treasure that
he had stolen up to now,
as well as our lives...
He's probably watching us
from somewhere this very minute.
I found surveillance cameras
all over this place.
This is an appetizer.
So, the last supper that
he is referring to has finally come.
Excuse me, maid?
Yes?
By any chance did
the master instruct you on
which order to place
the dishes in on the table?
1 CO.
I was told to place the dishes on the table
starting with Mr. Hakuba
and continue on clockwise.
Well,
It just bothered me
that he was calling this the last supper
despite the game having just begun.
There's no poison in the food,
because I'm the one who made it.
But, the forks, knives and spoons,
the wine glasses and tea cups
have been placed
on the table beforehand.
We all seated ourselves according to
where we found our name plates.
I don t-think he Intends to commit murder,
but he may set up
a sinister joke
to test our capabilities.
It may be wiser to wipe
your glass cup and fork
with your own handkerchief before eating.
No doubt about it.
I don't like the idea that things
are being carried out as he planned.
Would you like to do a game of rock,
paper, scissors and change seats then?
B: But, what if someone ill-fatedly
gets the poisoned seat?
That's that, take it as fate,
and cry in the coffin
Oh no...
Boy, that sure was good!
Just-as-expected of:a gourmet detective!
You've really got fantastic talent
for cooking too, don't you?
I went through axalot of training
to satisfi this tongue of mine, so...
It seems we took our imagination
a bit too far...
We can't be too sure yet.
Well, people,
how did you like the last supper
that I prepared for you?
So, here it comes.
I guess it's time for me to talk.
Let me explain why I chose
this place which I dished out a lot for,
as the stage for this game.
First, take a good look,
at the many dishes that are in front of you.
A bird.
There is an image of an eerie bird
with a large beak.
Isn't this a crow?
Then, this is probably...
Have you figured it out?
That's the millionaire who died
a mysterious death a half a century ago.
Renya Karasuma
It's the crest of Renya Karasumaru.
R, Renya Karasumaru?!
Not only the dishes but also...
the doors, floors, railings...
the chess pieces and the playing cards
in the living room
were all specially ordered
and made by his request.
In other words, this is a villa,
which had been built by Karasuma...
or, rather, it used to be a villa...
40 years ago,
a blood-chillin tra ed occurred here.
Until that stormy night...
Being that you are all superb detectives,
you may have already noticed the minute
the remains of the enormous amount
of blood that was splattered and shed.
1 CO...
it was on a certain night 40 years ago,
when this place still retained its beauty.
The prominent figures of the financial
world were invited here,
and a special gathering was held.
It was entitled Memorial for
the late Renya Karasumaru.
He passed away at the age of 99.
But, in actuality, the gathering
was an auction of the various artworks
that Karasumaru had collected
during his lifetime
More than 300 items were auctioned
And, it was scheduled
for a period of three days.
On the 2nd night, that stormy night...
Two men were freezing
and with trembling lips, remarked
that they had lost their way In the storm,
and they would like to
spend the night until the storm subsided.
The host of the auction was hesitant about
Ietting the two stay the night at first, but
the man handed the host
over a small parcel saying
that it was in exchange for
Ietting them stay there
The contents of the parcel seemed to
be something like a cigarette,
and the host smoked it
just as he was told to...
Then,he gradually got merrier and merrier,
and let the two men inside.
The other guests who
were watching were urged
by the two to smoke likewise,
and the whole place
was covered with smoke.
D,Don't tell me that the parcel was...
Marijuana
The guests had a enjoyed a merry,
boisterous time for a while,
but after a while things began to change
A man screamed as if
he had seen the devil,
carried the item that he had
bid for and now owned, and ran...
A woman started crying as if
asking someone for forgiveness
until her tears dried out.
Yet another man,
delightedly poked his arm time and again
with the pen that he was holding.
The guests finally began to snatch
the works of art from each other,
and using auctioned items, such as
Iong swords and jeweled daggers,
started killing each other
The auction grounds had transformed into
a scene of massacre and hell...
The day after the hideous
and nightmarish night,
the two men had disappeared
with the art works and jewelry,
Ieaving 8 dead and as many as
over 10 people comatose behind.
But, why is such a serious crime
not known to the public?!
Probably because among them...
There was a powerful figure of
the financial world,
or maybe a member of the family.
I see...
If the conditions were such that
no one could tell who killed who...
Those involved may have come to
the conclusion that it would be better
to keep the case under cover,
rather than solving it.
It was probably within the calculation
of those men too, wasn't it?
Well, 'this age old story sure does
whet,my appetite.
So, now .
Do you understand why I chose this place
as the stage for the game?
I would like all you detectives to re-enact
the tragedy that occurred here
40 ye rs ago.
That ugly scene of people fighting over
the treasure and killing each other.
Really stupid...
I figure it's too cruel to make you all just
search blindly all throughout this building
so let me give you a hint.
H, Hint?!
When the two travelers
Iooked up at the sky.
A devil descended near the palace.
The king carries the treasure
with him as he flees
The queen collects tears in the chalice
and asks for forgiveness.
The warrior falls dead by
the sword stained with his own blood.
-- - 14
The warrior falls dead by
the sword stained with his own blood
That must be...
Don't you think that these sentences
are more than suited
to describe the competition
of intelligence
staking your lives that is
about to be carried out here?
Don't be ridiculous...
To kill someone, you need to
have some who wants to kill you,
as well as, the will to kill yourself.
Of course, you do not have a choice
and cannot have out of this game.
Because you are all already
under the magic spell that I have chanted.
00008000,y,
when someone among you
Iets out a scream
that is the start of the game
Understand?
The one who finds
the treasure must enter
the location of the treasure
in the computer
that is in the room on the
fourth floor in the center tower.
I will give you half the treasure
as promised,
as well as instructions on
how torget out of here.
M, Mr<Mogi!
Mr Mogi, are you all right?!
Just kidding!
What a bad old man you are, really...
Sorry, sorry...
As a token of my apology, I'm out.
I'm not at all interested in
treasure hunting.
But, how do you intend to get out of here?
Don't worry.
This is not some isolated island
in the middle of the ocean.
I'll get somewhere
if I keep roaming the mountains
See you all later then, detectives!
Hey, mister, it won't work.twice.
22:34 and 51 seconds,
verified breathing stopped.
Judging from the circumstances here,
I think it is impossible
to try to resuscitate him.
What?!
No sign of cyanosis,
in which the lips turn purple, is visible.
And besides, this almond odor is
distinct of hydro cyanic acid gas.
Which means cyanide was
in the tea that he just drank.
'000000000009° 00000
There is no redox reaction.
VP 0000000009° $0900
"8 e8et000000000s0een) ~
I guess it's not the tea...
Then, what on earth happened to him...
Then, what on earth happened to him.
For the sake of Detective Ogami
who has died to make way
for the grand start of this life
risking competition of intelligence,
go search for the treasure
with all your might.
Cut out your stupid talk!
Go search for the treasure
with all your might.
While you are still alive...
A cassette tape...
It seems to be connected to a timer.
A timer?
Were you also instructed on the time
at which to bring the food in?
Yes, in detail, appetizers, soup,
main dish and dessert...
Which means that he wasn't talking
while watching us, but...
The tape was being played.
So, now we, know two things.
That the killer intended to
Kill Mr. Ogami to begin with,
and, that maybe, the killer is among us...
The killer may be among us?!
Take that tape for instance
Somebody in this room could've
recorded the voice beforehand,
and pretended to listen to it
Iike everyone else here, right?
1, That is possible...
And sit in this same dining room
as Mr. Ogami, without us noticing...
he was made to drink the cyanide
and poisoned himself to death.
Right in front of
the very eyes of all 5 of us.
Moreover, from the contents of the tape,
it sure sounds like
the killer knew what time
the victim was going to die too.
The question is, there was no
cyanide compound reaction from the tea
that he was drinking
until just before he died.
Then...
maybe the poison was on
the rim of the cup and not in the tea itself.
because he drank
from the cup two to three times.
But, the criminal that you're referring to is,
the Thief Kid, right?
I've heard that he never kills anyone.
No...
This is the first case in which something like
this has happened, as far as I know.
Well,
talking is not going to get us anywhere.
Shouldn't we o take a look?
To see whether our cars have really
been blown up or not!
I agree.
There could be a car
that was spared from being blown up.
Yeah, the explosion
that we heard a while ago
could've been NM bluff:
The car that I rented...
My Ferarri's done medium too.
My Alfa...
As well as Ogami's:Porsche are all gone!
Is that Benz yours, then?
I had my granny drive me over here.
Strange.
I had Mr Mouri give me a lift here
Who's Benz is that?
I think it s the master's car
When I got here early this morning,
It was already here.
Which means that there is someone else
here besides us, after all.
Could it mean that my car
that is on the other side,
has also been burned.
On the other side...
You mean you didn't park your car here?
because I was instructed to park it
at the backggate
What's the short cut to the back gate?!
Go through the enclosed garden...
Go to the back gate from the kitchen
to the left beyond!
Oh, your car's just fine!
Isn't there something fishy about this car?
That rat probably forgot to set the bomb!
Then, maybe we should go check to see
if the bridge is really gone.
I'll go with you.
I guess I will too.
Me too.
Come now, too many captains
will sink the ship.
True,
We'll end up not with the Phantom Thief
but rather, a Phantom Ship.
Then, why not decide
which detective goes by tossing a coin?
I jus happen to have
exactly 5 coins on me.
My, you're pretty well prepared, little one!
This is a very primitive way
to decide, however.
I guess we've got no choice.
Then, the one who gets heads...
gets to go drive over to the bridge
and check it out.
The ones who are going are me,
Mr Mourn and Mogi, right?
Please be careful, dad!
Don't tell me that.
It couldn't be?!
Come, let's go back inside!
Come on, let's go!
Oh, okay
What a sight...
The bridge is completely drowned.
Hey, granny Senma!
Will you bring the headlights up closer!
I want to look at my feet...
Okay!
Closer, closer,
Closer...
I wonder if the killer will move.
Yeah...
I don't think this is all there is to it.
Ms. SS, Senma!
Ms. Senma!
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER :DESIGNS BY.
Masi1tomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kasfirwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Hioure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Tikatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In associtiomwith
Yomiuri Telec. Sting Corporation