THE DETECTIVES COME TOGETHER!
KUDO VS. THIEF KID
I AW ALA
W-What a guy!
To fall onto the crowd
together with the screen
It s impossible
to find him among that crowd...
Yes...Me ure here
Hey! Megure!!
Are you the one who fired?!
No...I'm not the one who fired...
By the way, Inspector,
didn't he leave a message with you?
He did. something about a code...
Code?
This is Greek to me...
Was a letter like this really carved
in the center of the face of the clock?
Yeah...that's it!
At any rate, that's important evidence...
We've got to have them
postpone moving the clock tower
until the code is deciphered...
I don't need you to tell me that!
Well, I guess all is well...
since the clock tower is safe
and his plan didn't work out...
No...wrong, Inspector Megure...
He left a code on the face of the clock
and left the clock tower
up to the police to take care of...
He took the clock tower away
from the hands of the owner
who was planning to have it moved...
Besides, it's written in the code, see?
You change the katakana characters
to roman characters,
and move the vowels one space
each clockwise and read it...
It says The bell will not toll for you."...
Come to think of it,
I still haven't asked you...
The name of the thief
Oh well...
I guess it doesn't really matter...
Are you waiting for somebody too?
I'm going out with daddy
But, he said he may be busy with work,
so we might not be able to go...
Here you go.
I'm... Kaito Kurobane!
Nice meeting you!!
I'm Kaito Kurobane, nice meeting you!
Kaito!
I wouldn't forget...youuidiot... =»
Kaito...?
Is anything the matter?
Thanks to your remark
I just remembered something!
The clock tower incident,
when I was really in a fix...
And, whatever
became of that clock tower?
Oh, yeah
you don't know about it
Since youymoved*'s¥
Then...it has since been moved over after all...
This is the sound of...
The police investigated afterwards,
and found out that the diamonds
were fake, so the city
bought it for a cheap price...
Okay! Shall we get going then!
His real target is the "Big Jewel."... 4
The jewel in the possession of
the Suzuki Financial Group,
the "Black Star'!
Kaito... m not about to
stop you at this point...
But, Toichi used to always say...
Making contact with a client
IS always a battlefield...
Never be conceited, or take them lightly...
Look into their hearts
and concentrate all your nerves
so that you may look through them.
Give it all the skills you have...
Yet, keep smiling and be gracious.
No matter what happens
neversforget...
you have to put on a poker*face...
right?
K-Kaito...
2 « WY
£544355
I'm back!
You've got mall
Oh no! What is this...
It gives me the creeps...
What's all the fuss about, Ran?
Well, take a look at this .A.see...
Mr. Kogoro Mouri is written in
calligraphic white letters
on a black envelope...
No stamp, no name of sender...
It's probably a new type of
please join us direct mails...
I wonder...
What is it...
$22 1%
in honor of your wisdom,we would like to
invite you to a dinnen:gathering...
5 = BF
se «4%
in honor of your wisdom,we would like to
invite you to a dinner:gathering...
+ & <O
in honor of your wisdom,we would like to
invite you to a dinner.gathering...
ave CT O
in honor of your wisdom,we would like to
invite you to a dinner gathering
Si?-
in honor of your wisdom,we would like to
invite you to a dinner gathering...
<< 5 -
in honor of your wisdom,we would like to
invite you to a dinner-gathering...
invite you to a dinner gathering...
in honor of your wisdom,we would like to
Invite you to a dinner gathering...
<~¥\w
in honor of your wisdom,we would like to
Invite you to a dinner gathering...
invite you to a dinner gathering...
s@\ =
in honor of your wisdom,we would like to
Invite you to a dinner gathering...
See, what did I tell you?
Just what I thought it was...
I'll bet they're just trying to
add some class to their party
by inviting a detective...
I don't think so.
See, because this fell out of the envelope.
XE all
2,000,000 yen is written on it, right?
2...2,000,000 yen?!
Wouldn't it be awfully strange
to send something like this
just for something like that?
And, they don't even know
if you're going to come or not yet...
Hey, Dad...
Isn't the name of the sender
somewhere inside?
Now, what is this?
The Phantom of a God-Forsaken Child...
Oooh, how creepy...
ZANE thrill, k, suspense
7/3 LVI) RH J 1
- +4 -
JLA. WV J) RR J \ -
PAX 3 (CZ 58<
Gill
FLAIR
FL, 705 iE LTL\S
HEBCHBELESICEZTV ApbLh amor
41 CR IC-VIFIUN Jie Z0 CNV VQVJIII" DOD VU LIBTIL es
ce z=meiiicawzcunwrdHn
Lr <<
+ 400m
HIZCHIEH TRAN T -_ADHESKRI
=I & IF 6h 3 FT < - ADDER
a Wg wf 2
S<L I- TO Al _ tt J IT JEG LL & NN - ANN Vals wm T5< 3
F135 DODO
TH love 1s thrill. shock. suspense
HENEENUESZ5 LE LTHRA 2h ICIVL
ammo
LOR PBAXd
» zor
REESE FT TRE
Wei ENE heTs
IBY.) mrp) ) @ 1 TC
Conan, can you check
the tire over on that side?
What's wrong, Dad 7?
Wow! The tire on this side is super flat.
A flat tire?
What a bummer...
There's no spare tire! Darn it!
Hey, Pops.
What is it?!
See, over there...
There's a service station over there!
Wow, talk about lucky...
A Buddha in hell indeed...
Darn, shortcut, my foot!!
How dare that guy at the service station
tell us to use this road...
Uh, Uh, Dad, is this really the right road?
Of course!
He took me into his stand
and sold this really expensive map
that he insisted was very explanatory
of this area too!
If this isn't the right road,
He's going to pay for it!
So, we've finally come out to
a normal looking road...
I guess he wasn't lying
when he said that this was a shortcut!
Because, see, isn't that it
on the Tight hand side?
The place that we're headed for...
It sure is an eerie looking building...
It looks more like Dracula's mansion,
than a Twilight Inn to me.
H-Hey, Dad; are we really going there?
O a place like that...?
You dummy! We've got no choice after
getting an invitation like that, do we?
Besides, there was a 2,000,000 yen
stamp enclosed in the letter too...
B-But. .wasn't there something eerie
written by the sender?
Oh, about the child forsaken
by God thing...
Don't worry about it.
It's just somebody bluffing nonsense!
I wonder...
Let's not go, after all
We've already come this far.
But, what if a Dracula really appears...
Don't be ridiculous!
There is no such thing
as Dracula in Japan!
If there is anything, it would be a... what is
that called? A mountain witch...
M=Mountain witch!
Now, what a way to greet
a woman at a first meeting...
Oh...I'm so sorry...
What are you doing out in a place
Iike this, granny?
Most obviously,
my cute little Fiat stalled on me...
So, I was waiting for someone: to...
Come by...
You folks are going to
the Twilight Inn too, aren't you?
If it's not too much trouble,
would you give me a lift?
Yes, why not. Go ahead
and ride in the back seat.
And, while you're at it,
would you please move my things
from my Fiat into your car?
On, all right...
Thank you so much...
Do we have a while more to go?
We've just got a little more to go,
but, is anything wrong?
I've got to go to the ladies room!
Ah, come on...
Miss?
I guess it's none of my business,
the principal. of*the:elementary school
of our town used to always say...
that people who succeed in life, are those
who never let an opportunity pass them by
Once you let the opportunity pass you by,
thinking that the same sort of
opportunity may come by again,
no matter how long you wait for it
to come by, it never will...
Why didn't you finish
what you wanted to do
when you stopped over
at the service station a while ago?
How did you know, granny?
That we stopped over
at the service station...
Very easy, little one...See, over there...
The empty ashtray and
the still new cigarette butts on the floor
goes to show that
you are a heavy smoker...
Yet, the ashtray us empty...
The only place you could've emptied it
is at the service station
about 10 kilometers away...
A gentleman who is nice enough
to give a strange old lady a lift
would never throw his cigarettes out of
the window of his car
in front of a young lady
Hey, hey, granny...
who on earth are you...?
I am Furuyo Senma
Furuyo Senma (63)
Detective
I am Furuyo Senma
Furuyo Senma (63)
Detective
IX 15
A detective just like you...
Mr. Sleeping Kogoro?
Furuyo Senma (63)
Detective
A detective just like you...
Mr. Sleeping Kogoro?
Furuyo Senma (63)
Detective
A detective just like you...
Mr. Sleeping Kogoro?
Furuyo Senma...
The famous one who solves cases just by
hearing about cases in a comfy chair
Oh come on, flattering an old lady
will not get you anywhere...
So, she's the one...
Well then, I guess I'll keep this
ashtray for now...
Hey, wait!
Even if we get to the inn,
don't ever smoke in front of me!
I hate the smoke of cigarettes...
There's the Twilight Inn right in front of us.
Give. it all you got andsstep:on the:gas!
Uh...
Dad* open. the back, please!
The closer you get to it,
the more it looks like a haunted house...
Dad, I'm going to go on inside!
The ladies room, the ladies room...
Wow! Look at all those fancy cars!
A Mercedes Benz a Ferrari, a Porsche...
It sure is full of dangerous cars...
It's an Alfa Romeo!
Classy!
Hey!
Don't you go touching my girl like that...!
This one's a shrewd that
I finally tamed after 5 years...
I don't want her to get upset
over some strange man touching her
Right, flimsy mustache...
Flimsy mustache?!
Hi there Mogi, it's been a while
You were invited over too?
Hey! Granny Senma
Which means you were invited here too...
Mogi...
Harufumi Mogi (39)
Detective
fig?
Q ay 0
Ix {a
He's Detective Harufumi Mog!
Harufumi Mogi (39)
Detective
Vv 28
IX {a
Harufumi Mogi (39)
Detective
LO ev
- - a> -
321E
Are you all right, though?
I read in the papers that you were shot
by a Mafia in Chicago last week...
I've forgotten something so old...
And? Have you come around
to wanting to get married yet?
You're going to be 40 in three days,
aren't you?
Heck...who knows about the future...
Shmlig
Welcome, Mr. Moqgi...Mr. Mourn...
and Ms. Senma, I believe...
We've been waiting for you...
Please come in...
Oh...Well, this is...
A haunted house?
Please put your umbrellas here...
Hey, you!
Yes, sir! Please excuse me...
I just went to the kitchen, but...
If I remember correctly, he's...
The gourmet detective...
Shukuzen Ogami...
What?!
Shukuzen Ogami (51)
a gourmet detective
$2 {4
What?!
Shukuzen Ogami (51)
a gourmet detective
1% {4
Shukuzen Ogami (51)
a gourmet detective
IR {a
The cook suddenly fell ill and can't come?!
Shukuzen Ogami (51)
a gourmet detective
The cook suddenly fell ill and can't come?!
You've broken your promise!
I've come allthis way
Iooking forward to the dinner!
I, I'm so very sorry...
I've bought all the ingredients
necessary to make dinner, though...
Okay, forget it already!
Lend me your kitchen!
Ill makesdinner!
Gourmet food and murder are treasures
I cherish that uplift
and stimulate my brain cells!
Darn it!
I'm so sorry...
to have kept you waiting
Why did you summon four detectives up
to a remote place
in the mountains like this for?
Well,
we actually invited
six detectives altogether.
Hey, hey,
are you telling me that
there are two more detectives?
1 CO,
another woman and a young man...
Young man.
Don't tell me it's Shinichi?!
No way!
I think it's Heiji
Right?!
Two other detectives were
4 also included in the master's list,
but Mr. Kudo could not be contacted,
and as for Mr. Hattori,
we got a call from his mother saying
that he can't make it
because he's got an exam coming up...
Because those two were cancelled,
the master okayed Mr. Mourn
to bring two members of his family.
And where is this detective lover weirdo?
I have no idea...
since I, myself has never met him yet...
But, you got the list from him, didn't you?
Yes,
I did get this list when I came here
for an interview to be hired as a maid.
But,
it was a very peculiar type of interview.
Peculiar?
Aki Ishihara (23)
a maid
2&Tr +
Yes,
AKi Ishihara (23)
a maid
Xx 1 Fk
Aki Ishihara (23)
a maid
Xx 1 Fk
since it was a high paying job,
Aki Ishihara (23)
a maid
Xx 1 bk
people wanting the position
crowded over here.
AKi Ishihara (23)
a maid
people wanting the position
crowded over here.
When I entered the interview room,
all I saw there was a computer,
an explanation of the dinner,
and a list of the invitees on the desk.
Nobody was in the room.
So, having no choice I started reading
the papers as instructed on the PC,
when I sudden]! heard a noise.
% RA U
Then. I saw the sentence,
FERAL mM
You are hired
on the screen of the computer.
Then,
you don't know why you were hired?
But you must've at least heard his voice?
You did say that he gave you an okay,
didn't you?
Well, all the details were exchanged
by mail using a cell phone.
This sounds really interesting.
The thrill is killing me.
I was already electrified the minute
I saw the strange pattern of that door!
It sure does look strange.
I wonder what it is a pattern of...
Be careful, baby.
If I'm not mistaken, that's probably
the remains of an old blood stain.
What?!
You're joking, aren't you?
No, they re real blood stains.
The remains of blood that had splattered
at just about a 45 degree angle
to the door.
Not only the door
On the wall there are the remains of
blood stains streaming downward.
On the floor,
there are droplet blood stains.
Although they have been wiped away,
there are blood stains soaked here
and there everywhere in this house...
It seems that these blood stains
are not just those of one or two people.
Just as expected of you...
Luminol...
When it is sprayed onto blood stains,
It oxidizes because of
the active oxygen within the blood,
and emits a bluish
purple fluorescent color
You make good deductions.
Ex-coroner...
Ms. Ikumi Soda.
Ikumi Soda (29)
a detective
I'm flattered to hear that,
Ikumi Soda (29)
a detective
boy...
Saguru Hakuba (17)
a detective
I am Saguru Hakuba.
Saguru Hakuba (17)
a detective
Ix (a
Nice to meet you all.
Saguru Hakuba (17)
a detective
Nice to meet you all.
Saguru Hakuba (17)
a detective
Nice to meet you all.
H-Hakuba?
You mean you're
Police Superintendent Hakuba's...
Police Superintendent Hakuba
Is my father indeed,
Mr. Mouri.
A-An eagle?!
Oh, I'm sorry to have scared you.
Whether it was because Watson here
was accompanying me in Britain,
I'm not sure but he has become
very sensitive to the smell of blood.
W-Watson
I'm sure glad
I came all the way back home, though...
After all, here I am standing at the scene
of the tragedy that
has been hidden for ages.
One that I have only heard of as rumors.
I'm here at last after a period of 40 years.
This is more than I could ask for
to awaken my intellectual excitement.
Tragedy
Oh, no...
You're pretty good.
Why, thank you...
How about this,
Mr. Sleeping Kogoro?
All right!
Look, look, I've got a straight!
So, I win again!
She sure is as stron: as ever, I tell ou...
Wait a minute,
Now, let's not cheat, Ran.
See, the Jack to your very left.
You've got one on top of the other,
don't you?
Oh; you ré right.
I'm sorry, I didn't realize it.
They seem to have-been stuck together
from the start, though...
What's wrong, Ran?!
There's blood on the playing card!
Oh my, my! blood has splattered
there too, I see.
Come to think of it, the maid was saying
that the things here are just
as they were at the time of the crime
That practically nothing has been moved.
WwW Which means that something
happened in this room too.
Thank you all for waiting.
Dinner is ready
so please come to the dining room.
The master is waiting for you.
So, the big boss finally
makes his a earance...
I can't wait to see him.
I somehow don't seem
to have an appetite.
Here we are.
Please go on inside.
Hey, hey,
what's with that attire of yours?
I think you've been watching too much TV.
To you all, the distinguished
and famed 6 detectives!
Welcome to the Twilight Inn.
Well then, won't you all take your seats?
Take the dishes out
just like I instructed you to a while ago.
Oh, yes sir...
Now,
the reason why ll invited you all over here,
is because I want you to find the treasure
that I have hidden somewhere in here.
I want you to find
the enormous amount of riches
that I have accumulated over the years
And, risk your lives to do so.
R-Risk our lives?!
What was that sound?!
No need to worry
I just made sure
that you'd be stranded here.
What?!
I am always being chased around
by all of you.
So, I thought I'd experience being the one
to corner you for once.
Besides, I also did away with the bridge
that you crossed to come here,
so even if you had your cars,
you wouldn-t have been able to
makerit out of here anyway.
Of course there is no telephone here,
and the cell phone is
out of range of the signal waves.
So it is impossible to get help
from someone on the outside.
Yes...
half of the treasure,
as well as the solution as to
how to get out of here
will be given only to the one
who finds the treasure.
This is the game...
How do you like the idea?
I just don't take well to people like you
who go around fleeing about
hiding under a mask like that.
Come now,
you can't work on an emp. stomach.
Please enjoy the dinner
to your heart s content, the last supper.
A speaker is attached
to the neck of a mannequin?!
Who...
Who on earth could be doing this?!
My...
A persongasgrenowned as you, Mr. Mouri,
had no idea why you were called here?
It was written in black
and white in the invitation4letter
1 he'Phantomrof a God-Forsaken«Child <<
- The phantom...
The phantom...
That is something
that appears unexpectedly
and has no concrete body.
The word child in the sentence
Is written with the Japanese character *
attached to the left.
So it refers tosthe child of a beast,
because this character is used:o write
words like coltTand puppy in Japanese.
The God forsaken beast
in the New Testament,
refers to the goat that
could not receive the blessings of God.
Therefore, it refers to a baby]goat?
And, of course, a goat is a goat,
but a baby-goat in English is called...
a kid...
W-What?!
Maybe this will make it
easier to understand,
kid the phant wm thief
Kid the phantom thief
Sool
kid the phantom thief
H-Hey,
don t«tell me that...
Don't tell me that...
Right,
He never lets the prey
that he is after escape.
The way he carries out his feat
Is practically like magic.
He is a genius criminal
that confuses the police
with faces and voices
that are as limitless as the stars...
He's the main dish
that we, the detectives, drool to savor...
He's a stuck-up villain
that I would sure like to throw into jail.
He is the only instance so far
that has ever thrown me off...
People who have seen him in the dark
dressed in his white outfit call him...
The Thief Kid!
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS-BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi loka
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshr Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama