With a strong heart
and power of deduction
step into the essence
with strong rhythm.
A beautiful and mysterious lady makes
an appearance in today's episode
An odd request begins the case
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan.
A CLIENT FULL OF LIES PART I
You say, you're looking for someone?
Yes,
There is a person that I really want to see.
Well, I'm so sorry,
but I happen to be tied up just now.
Please, will you help me please?
To tell you the truth,
I'm right near your office already.
If it's okay, I'd like to
at least talk to you...
Kaminari-Boy!
The winner is, Kaminari-Boy!!
He has won the final race
with his graceful legs!
Oh no! I lost again!
He has won the final race
with his graceful legs!
Oh no! I lost again!
Hello, Mr Mourn?
Didn't I already tell you that today I mm...
vo ) NS a
il... yeO,
I guess it won't hurt to hear you out.
I'll be waiting for you.
Come on, do your job!
Dad!
I Know...
What kind of person was the caller?
Some middle aged lady.
She says she's coming over right now!
I'll bet she one of those,
Please, please help me find my first love
type client anyway
I just know it...
Please come in!
I called just a while ago.
My name is llkenami.
Please forgive me for intruding on you
so suddenly like this
An acquaintance of mine
mentioned that you,
Shizuka Ikenami
LE BE
Mr. Mouri would definitely find
the person that I'm looking for
Shizuka Ikenami
IR MR
Mr. Mouri would definitely find
the person that I'm looking for.
Please help me
Please come this way
Talk about beautiful...
Where did dad go?
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting...
mademoiselle...
I was looking through some,papers of
a very difficult case, you see...
Come now, and relax on the sofa,
and calm that pulsatinggheart of yours
before I hear you out.
Ran!
Get us something to drink, will you!
Okay...
Here he goes again...
You re looking for
a Jr. High School classmate.
Yes,
we belonged to the same kendo club.
Couldn't you find his address
on the graduation list?
He moved before graduation,
and the space where his name is
supposed to be is blank
51,08 BIC...
I see...
I've brought a picture of him back
In those days with me.
He's the one In thercenter
holding-the winner's cup.
His name is Shiro Shibata.
Isn't the girl standing next to him?
How embarrassing, but it's me...
It's already been 30 years though.
T, Thirty years ago?!
Don't tell me that you're already over 407?!
Yes,
I will be 42 this year.
But, the boy in the picture
Is still in 8th grade.
Although I think
he may have grown taller 'byinow.
Any hobbies?
Oh, yes...
I don't think he has
any special hobbies though.
No, I mean yours.
I, I like knitting,
and I usual knit sweaters...
My what a nice hobby!
Oh, my mother's hobby Is knitting too!
I'll bet you're good at cooking too?
No, not at all.
See, I cut myself in three places when
I tried to cook after a long while last night.
O Oh well, no big deal!
Shortcomings help make a person
more attractive at:times.
Right, right,
Just like mother!
But I'm full of shortcomings...
That's why I'm still single at this age
What?! You're single?!
Yes...
Well, to leave a beauty like you single,
the guys around you must be blind.
Really, what a fantastic person.
Just like mother,
it's hard to understand the guy
who doesn { give a hoot about her
Ran...
Oh, I'm\sorry...
What's wrong?
Do you have a cold?
Oh, no...
I was born with bronchial problems
I'm, you see, allergic to dust.
I'm sorry,
it must be dusty-heme because
we were cleaning just a while ago...
Let's change places then
I'm sorry...
Picture?
So, you re looking for this Mr Shibata
because you wantsto
get a picture back fromthim?
It s only one picture
that was taken when we won
the semifinals in a summer contest
during our Jr. High School days...
Just the other day, my grandmother
seems to have mistakenly thrown away
the plate we received then.
So, I thought that I'd like to at least
have a picture of it.
But, why does this Mr. Shibata
have that picture?
I was using that picture as a bookmarker
for a book that I borrowed from him,
but I forgot to take the picture
out of the book when I returned it to him.
Then, Mr. Shibata is not your first love
or anything like that?
No, well...
And, do ou have an other clues on him?
Well...
Mr. Mouri, may I take your order?
Oh, coffee for me!
I'll have iced lemon tea.
Reiko...
Reiko?
Who is she?
Oh, no...
He used to call me by that name.
Something about the character
called Reiko,
in the book that I borrowed
from him resembled me.
What would you like, Conan?
Ice coffee for me!
I'll take the same.
All right.
So, where should I start...
The only clues I have are his name,
age and this picture of 30 years ago.
You know what...
Then,
what about asking him for help?
Him...?
I've heard rumors about him.
Also that the high school detective,
ShlnlChl Kudo IS in
and out of your office at times.
Shinichi?!
Isn't that right, sonny?
No, he hasn't come around at all that brat.
He only rings me up once in a while
to say stupid things.
Well, I'm sorry that
I only have stupid things to say.
What a bummer,
to have such rumors going around.
If worse comes to worse,
they may hear about it too.
LWlhhave to keep my deductions
to myself for a while, I guess...
Conan.
What dofyou think, Conan?
Wella ou were about to say
somethingfljust now, weren't you?
What good IS it going to do, asking a brat?
But, he always takes
note of interesting things, doesn't he?
Oh, no, it's nothing.
Something just happened
to cross my mind.
Since he's holding the trophy,
this man won the tournament, right?
Yes.
If he was that strong
when he was in the 8th grade,
I just thought that maybe
he would still be participating
In some tournament even now.
Oh but just thought maybe...
What? He's participating?!
In the Shizuoka Tournament,
among the general contestants,
Mr. Shiro Shibata?
Yes,
yes!
Did you find him?!
Yes!
He seems to be awregular
who always appears in the top ranks!
He seems to be working
as a high school/PE. teacher in Shizuoka.
And is presently residing
with his wife in a condominium.
I'll go rent a car right now.
I'm glad you found him!
Yes, really...
He's been found.
The one she's looking for
has been found,
but, what I can't make out is this lady
who is full of lies.
Almost everything she says is a lie.
I wonder what she is up to.
Could it be that she's hiding her identity?
Hey, hey, come on
don't tell me that this lady is.
Thank you!
It's all thanks to you.
Nobody seems to be home.
I'm sure the couple
has gone out together,
because today Is Sunday.
Why don't we go kill time
somewhere nearby, then?
Wait.
Are you by chance looking for
Mr. Shibata?
Takezo Yoshikawa (47)
JI 1758 (47)
AMMEAD TA
Oh yes...
Please finish what you have to do
as soon as possible,
because he promised to play mahjong
together today at my house.
Oh, but he doesn t seem to be in
It can't be.
I'm sure he's asleep or something.
Seemhesssthome.
This program is brought to you
by the following companies.
It's the sound of the TV.
This program is brought to you
by the following companies.
Ah come on, dozing off with the TV on
without even locking the door.
Hey, -Shibata!
We're going to start pretty soon!
It looks like he was still eating?!
The soup is cold
The rice 1s all dried up and hard
This couldn't be his breakfast
What a waste, the guji looks so good.
Oh, I mean tilefish.
I'm back.
Dear?
Hey, who are all of you?!
Kyoko Shibara (38)
BEE mm O
- T CTY,
Why are you in my house?!
Kyoko Shibara (38)
Bel FF (38)
SERRA 3 A
I'm going to call the police!
Kyoko Shibara (38)
ERIS =A
W We are.
Hey, Shibata?! What's the matter?!
Get a hold of yourself!
Mr. Shibata!
Hey! Get a hold of yourself!
He us holding something In his right hand!
What is it?!
This is?
So, let me verify what you said
Mr. Mouri and his party
came over to Mr. Shibata's house
and pushed the button of the interphone,
but there was no answer.
Just then, Mr. Yoshikawa whom he had
a previous*engagement with came along
and tried turning the knob of the door.
The door was unlocked,
so the five of you came into the room.
Then,
Mrs. Shibata, Mr. Shibata's wife,
who had been out comes back
and runs into Mr Mourn and the others.
After that, at hearing
Mr. Yoshikawa shout you all go to
the living*room+to-check things out
and found Mr Shibata bleeding from
the head and dead.
The estimated time of death us
between dawn and morning today.
Where were you around that time,
Mrs. Shibata?
Oh yes.
I had a golf date
with a friend of mine today,
and my friend came to pick me up.
So, I prepared my husband's breakfast
and left the house before 5:00.
Was Mr. Shibata at home then?
He came home about 03:00
and was fast asleep.
He came home at 03:00?
Y, Yes .
Wywere 'la in: man on .
We were playing mahjong,at my room
that is on the fourth floor.
Just as Mrs. Shibata says
we finished the game around 03:00.
As a matter of fact,
the morning paper was one the table,
About what time is the newspaper delivered?
It comes about 06:00 and I's put inside
the mailbox right outside the front door.
I see.
Which 'means that Mr. Shibata,
got up in the morning,
pulled the newspaper out of the mailbox,
and was in the middle of
eating his breakfast
when someone
who came to the door killed him.
I guess-that's what happened.
How can you tell that
it was when he was eating?
The food on the table IS half eaten
and besides, it's cold and dried up.
Who did this?!
Who killed my husband?!
Well, I don't know yet.
Mr. Mouri, did you notice anything strange
when you entered the room?
Well,
I guess the only thing is
that the TV in the kitchen was on.
What, the TV?!
It was turned off when we got here!
P I tu med-it off because it was noisy.
Besides, I just figuredithat he was
watching TV while eating breakfast.
Maybe
My husband could've been watching
a samurai show
called Kenyuden that starts at 08:00.
MYdhusband records
that program every week
and watches it in the living room.\
He sure does have a lot of them.
Okay, go check out the video deck
In the kitchen!
Yes sir!
I wonder why the ID player is gone.
Because he has a lot of ID software
and yet there is no player.
See, this place here on the shelf is empty!
Morever, there is only one speaker.
True .
Maybe it s out for repair or something,
right Mrs..Shibata?
Oh, as to that my husband...
WwW .,Who cares about that right now!
Hurry up and do what you have to
and let me go!
All right, I'm going to verify your alibi
so could you give me the phone number
of your friend who you went golfing with?
Sure...
And, I'd like to have
the phone numbers of the people
who play mahjong with you too.
What?
She came to pick Mrs. Shibata up
at 05:00 sharp?
Are you sure?
Yes.
She says the radio beeped
the time at the tone.
And she says she dropped
Mrs. Shibata off here a little after 7:00.
A little after 7-00 is
just about the time we got here.
I also checked with the newspaper man,
and he said that he delivered
the papers here around 06:00.
Taking into consideration
that the samurai program this morning
kept recording the video
and the time the-program was aired.
The estimated time of the crime
would probably be
around 08:00 to 45 minutes from then.
Which means that
Mrs Shibata couldn't have done it.
0,of course not!
Then let me ask you this, Mr. Yoshikawa,
I've had my doubts about the way
you've been acting till now,
but would you tell me of your alibi
around 08:00 this morning?
A, At home sleeping.
Is there anyone who can verify that?
No, because ll live alone!
Oh that's right!
I left a message in the answering machine
I said About time you get up
because I'm going to pick you up soon.
A Killer wouldn't leave
such a message behind, would he?
Or, maybe that's the very reason
you left the message?
Wait a minute!
You seem to be suspecting only me
but, what about them?
Although they seem to be
,an acquaintance «of you or something!
They would never commit murder.
He is' KogoroiMouri,
a detective that:I"deeply:respect!
Why, thank you.
Y, You mean that famous...
Sleeping Kogoro!
Yes.
The young. lady with him,
IS his daughter Ran.
The little one is.staying at his place,
and his name is Conan.
And, this beautiful woman here
Is Mrs. Mouri!
Right, Mr. Mourn?
Does it'look that way?
Oh, no way.
My name is lkenami
and I went over to Mr.yMouri's office
to have him look for Mr. Shiro Shibata
who happened to be
an old friend of mine.
I came here because I wanted him
to give me back a picture
that I had mistakenly given
to him about 30 years ago.
A picture?
That picture is probably the picture
that he's holding in his hand!
I took a look at it a while ago.
It cant be...
T This is...
D, Don't tell me that this is...
Yes that's the picture!
That's the picture I was looking for.
Why is Mr. Shibata holding
the picture in his hand.
Maybe, Mr. Mourn,
that is his dying message...
It cant be.
Beautiful Shizuka can't possibly
be involved in any way.
Besides this picture was
kept between the pages of a book!
I can't believed that
it just happened to conveniently be
on the floor where he was struck to death.
What?
Something is squashed
under the stomach of that man.
What is this?
A novel?!
The title us, Raljin No Mon.
bond tell me that this is the book
you were talking about?
Yes, it Is.
That's the book that I borrowed
from Shiro 30 years ago, \
and read, using that picture
as abobkmarker.
Then, don't tell me that the killer is...
Hold it, will you...
Don't you think everything fits in too well?
How can it be that the book
as well as the picture
just happened to be lying on the floor,
so coincidentally?
Come to think of it, there was a strange
phone call the day before yesterday.
A strange phone call?
Well, Mr. Shibata said,
Watch the program
because it's interesting.
That's why I was watching that
samurai movie here in this living room.
Just then, I got a phone call
Right, Mrs. Shibata?
Yes...
The person on the phone
asked my husband something.
He searched for a book,
took it from the shelf,
flipped through the pages and grinned
while remarking, I found it, I found it.
He grinned? And?
Where did your husband put
that book after that?
I'm sure that
he put it on top of the books that
he had piled up in:front of the bookshelf.
They are scattered!
Officer Yokomizo!
Although they are very slight,
there are blood stains in the corridor!
What?!
It seems as though the real scene of
the crime was here in the corridor.
Officer!
Could I take a look at that book?
No no it's
very important evidence!
Besides, this is a ninja book
full of kanji characters.
You're too young to be reading
something like this!
Did you read the book, officer?
Yeah, a long time ago.
Does a person bAthe name of'Reiko
come out in that"book?
A lady with such a fancy name
doesn't appear anywhere in the book!
Not again.
Yet another one.
She's lied again.
What on earth is she up to anyway?
What is there behind all the lies of hers?
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Hioure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi T1katani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutini
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owdga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Te dmitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Kenji Kodim1
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
N dssociitiomwTh
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
OGosho Aoyama / Shegakukaffi
YTV / TMS,
So, Ms llkenami,
please come to the station with me!
I refuse!
The killer ls...
She was here!
She was here before we got here.
Don't tell me that this 1s the remains of!
Isn't it about time you tell us