With a strong heart and
power of deduction,
step into the essence with strong rhythm
Ttoday the case as well as
the lies will be figured out...
the identity of the beautiful client
sure is a surprise
He sees through the one and only'truth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
ith Detective Conan
A beautiful client appears
at the detective office.
Her name is Shizuka Ikenaml.
She comes to ask Pops to look for
her classmate
from her middle school days,
who belonged to the same Kendo club
and whose name is Shiro Shibata.
He was located immediately.
He seemed to be working
as a PE. teacher in Shizuoka.
We set off immediately to his place,
but...
what awaited us there was...
the dead body of Mr. Shiro Shibata,
who had been killed.
He had the picture of Shizuka Ikenaml
gripped firmly in his hands.
What bothers me is
why the client is so full of lies...
Almost everything that she says is
a lie...
What on earth is she hiding...'?
A Client Full of Lies
(Part 2)
Officer Yokomizo!!
We've found a blood
smeared wooden kendo sword
that seems to be the murder weapon
Really?!
Yes, sir!
It was found by the emergency stairs
right beside the front door!
Mrs. Shibata, did you have
a wooden sword in the house?
Oh, yes...on top of that shoe cabinet...
Kyoko Shibata (38)
Wife of Mr. Shiro Shibata
DI - I
EEG-m ix
Kyoko Shibata (38)
Wife of Mr. Shiro Shibata
Simian ix
My husband kept it there
to get rid of persistent solicitors...
Kyoko Shibata (38)
Wife of Mr. Shiro Shibata
£15351': 9e?
It's not there right now, is it?
By the way,
how many phones do you have?
Just two. One in the living room and
one in the bedroom.
We did have one
by the front door before too, though...
I see.--
I got it.
Now I know that
the killer is you, Ms. IkenamnH
the killér is you, Ms IkenamnH
Shizuka lkenami (42)
Shizuka Ikenami (42)
Hey, hey, Officer Yokomizo.
You made sure that he had the picture
by calling him beforehan
And ih order to get it back,
you had already come here this morning.
However, you got into an argument with
him over the picture at the front door,
and on impulse struck him
with the wooden sword
that was on top of the shoe cabinet...
Thinking that you had killed him,
you escaped from the emergency stairs...
But, Mr. Shibata was
still alive at that time
He desperately crawled across the floor
towards the living room phone to get help,
but his body did not move as he willed it.
He sees the book
with your picture between the pages...
He uses whatever strength
that is left within himself and
grabs the picture of the one
who killed him, then dies.
But, it's only a picture...
There must be some secret
nd the picture...!
That's why she came back here again
with you Mr. Moun!
To get the picture back...!
Please come with me to the station,
Ms. Ikenami, will you?
I refuse!
Huh?
Ifsyou want to interrogate me,
please do so after you get an
arrest warrant from the court, will you?
Well...
at this stage when you are lacking
in documents with credible evidence
on which the judge needs to
base his impression of me,
I don't even think it is possible for you
to compel him to issue you
a warrant for my arrest anyway...
Of course, it would be a different story
if Mrs. Shibata there,
intends to file charges against us
for trespassing on private property...
W, What the...
Who the hell is this lady anyway...
Wow, look at his left hand!
It's smeared all over with blood!
E must've touched
the wound on his head.
Strange, though...
there's no blood on
the bandage around his finger...
Come to think of it,
that lady's left hand was also...
Wait a sec...
If so, on his right hand...!
H...Hey!
I see, I get the picture now...
1Hey
That's a no, no!!
So, she's the killer after all...
She came here before we came here...!
To this blood smeared murder scene
But, Ms. Ikenaml...
the victim, Mr Shibata was found dead
with your picture grabbed firmly
in his hand, wasn't he?
I'll have to have you at least explain
what ybur relationship is
with Mr. Shibata,
as well a's why he happened to
have that picture in his possession.
I have explained everything
Mourikalready
Then, come with us to the station and
explain it to us too!
Then, let's do this...
I'll give Mr. Mouri power of
attorney over me.
Huh?
If he says I should go to the station
to be interrogated as a suspect,
I will.
Uh, well...
Well, Mr. Mourl?!
I,~;I'fthink you should at least 90 for
the interrogation...
BUt maybe it's not all that necessary...
Mr. Mourl!!
Uh, well...
Mr. Mourn?!
Mr. Mourl'?!
Hoh-hee...
M, Mr. Mourn?
Ms. Ikenaml,
under these circumstances,
no choice but to be interrogated.
R, Right?!
Only...
not as a suspect but,
as a witness to prove the truth of the case
that I am about to disclose now.
Are you saying that she is not the killer?
No...
If she were the killer,
and if she came here with us again to
get her picture back?
She would've walked into the house
saying that the door was not locked
the minute I rang the door bell and
no one answered...!
If she had come here beforehand and
struck Mr. Shibata to death,
she should've known that
the door wasn't locked!
The only chance she had to
get the picture back was'?
During the short time
between when the body was found to
when the police arrived.
Then, is it you,
Mr. Yoshikawa'? Since you seem
to have known that the door was open
Mr Yoshikawa? Since you seem
Ta keso
A friend of Mr.
back then...
Ta keso
A friend of Mr.
Hun K
Ta keso
A friend of Mr.
Besides,
you're the one who found
the dead body...!
I'll bet you came back to the scene
get rid of something
that you didn't want the police to see.
Rlflb'y...
Yoshikawa is not the killer either.
Huh...?
If the late Mr. Shibata always left
the door open.
It wouldn't be hard to assume that
the door would've been open then too.
Besides, it would be
much too dangerous for Mr. Yoshikawa,
whose alibi around the estimated time of
the killing is not all that Clear,
to set foot again into
the scene of the crime...!
If there was something that
he wanted to come and get that badly,
he would've done so,
first thing...He wouldn't come and get it
almost half a day after the murder...!
He would've known that if he called,
there would be nobody here
except for the dead body.
Moreover, he went out of his way to
stop all of us who were ready to leave...!
If I were the killer,
I would see to it that
the visitors leave first,
then sneak into the house alone.
T,Then, don't tell me that the killer is...
the one who seemingly has
imate aliblv
T,Then, don't tell me that the killer is...
Yes-.
The one who seemingly
has a legitimate alibl...
Mrs. Kyoko Shibata!!
M, Mrs. Shibata-isfithe killer?!
M, Mrs. Shibata, don't tell me that you...
8, But Mr. Mourl...
Mrs. Shibata prepared breakfast and 4
Ieft at 05:00 in the morning, you know?
Why was the paper that was delivered
at 06:00 found on the table, then?
Moreover, she got back here after 7 pm
when a friend of hers dropped her off.
That's just about when you
arrived here, Mr. Mourl...
Who came back after you arrived here,
have moved the morning paper
onto the table?
It's true that I got here after 7 o'clock
This is indeed a very convenient way of
expressing the time, don't you think?
Whether it's 7:05 or 7:10,
we can say after 7:00 pm...
Huh?
Inf other words, Mrs. Shibata could've
got back-r'jfisit b'efere we got here!
W Wait a minute...!
N, are you saying that
the breakfast on the table is...
It's probably what she prepared for him
when he got home
at three in the morning!
D to doWas
put the morning papers beside it
to make it look like breakfast
But, what about that video?
The program that was aired at 08:00
was being recorded
All that needs to'b'é'done is...
to set the pre-set record time to
Iong and you've got it.
So, this is what Mrs. Shibata did...
First, she urged her husband
who came back at 03:00 in the morning
to take a bath or something,
in order to kill time
At just before 05:00,
she tells him that it is his night snack and
makes him eat the food on the table. .!
Then, she calls her husband
while he is eating to the corridor,
and strikes him to death from
behind with the wooden sword...!
She then set the video up,
Iocks the front door and leaves the house
She gets into her friend's car
that is waiting for her
at the main entrance
of the condo at 05:00.
She returns after 7:00 pm
takes the newspaper out
of the door post box,
and puts it on the dining table.
Then she calls the police.
She has a perfect alibl.
I see...
That's way she can make it
Iook like somebody
who had visited had killed her husband
while he was havmg breakfast
at around 08:00 in the morning...
But, when Mrs Shibata returned,
something that
she didn't expect had happened...
Her husband who was supposed to
have been lying in the corridor,
in order to call for help,
crawled all the way over
to the living room!
IUD...
and as she was watching
what had happened,
she gets a phone call.
Don't tell me that it was from me?
Yes, your call saying,
I=Fm going to pickayou'Up soon.
Mrs Shibata who heard the message
on the answer phone got an idea .!
Instead of reporting directly to the police
with the morning paper and food
on the table,
she thought it better to
make somebody else discover the body
and return home later.
That way, it would make her
much less suspicious...
Then, where was Mrs. Shibata till then?
She was probably hiding
behind the door of the, emergency stairs
beside the front door
until Mr. Yoshikawa came...
Although we seemed to have arrived
here earlier than he did...
Mr. Detective,
then what is that picture all about?
Why did Mr. Shibata have her picture
gripped in his hand?
That's a camouflage that
Mrs. Shibata thought-Up to
on the spur of the moment
to divert everyone's- attention...
Camouflage?
First, please look at
her husband's left-héind!
The'p'alm of his hand is smeared with
blood and yet,
there is no bloodVon the bandage
that is wrapped around his ring finger...
Huh?!
Y,You're right!
Then, look at his right hand...
Don't tell me that this is a trace of...
IUD...
when Mrs. Shibata came to
the living room,
Mr. Shibata was already
holding it in his hand!
The marriage ring that is a symbol of
their being husband and wife!
Mrs. Shibata who realized that that
her husband, as not wearing
his marriage ring that
he always wears on his left ring finger,
knew right away that
he was grabbing it in his right hand,
and somehow opened his fist that had
already closed tight
and removed the ring.
But, if she had left things as they were,
his right hand would look
awfully unnatural and stand out...
Therefore, she made him hold
the picture of Ms. Ikenaml
that was between the pages of the book.
I see, so'it could've been
anything if it didn't point at her!
Yes...
she then tried to put theringrb'a'ck
on the ring finger of hisaleft fiahd,
but she couldn't put it back on
because his fingers wereb'ent!
That's why she wrapped a bandage
around his finger!
All to hide
the traces of his marriage ring!
She probably also wrapped
his little finger
so that it wouldn't stand out as much...
Officer Yokomizo, I found it!
The trace of a marriage ring
under the bandage
Okay, take a picture of it right aWay,
will you?
Now, for the ring!
Search every nook and cranny
in this house...
No, that won't be necessary.
I'm sure Mrs. Shibata
still has it on her...
Huh?
I don't think she would hide a ring that
would have a Iuminol reaction
even if the blood were to be wiped off,
somewhere inside the house
fore the police arrived...
Of course she wouldn't hide it
by the emergency stairs either!
E safest thing to do would be
to get rid of it after the police leave...
at's why I'm sure
she still has it with her!!
The dying message that
her husband left behind to indicate that
he was killed by her!!
Fuh...
I guess evil never wins after all...
The evil things that my husband and
Mr. Yoshikawa had been doing
didn't come out in the open and yet...
Don't you think it's unfair?
Huh?
There were gambling playing mahjong!
My husband was playing mahjong and
gambling everyday
Moreover, they were gambling
exorbitant amounts
that would make your eyes pop out!
Thanks to them,
I had to sell off the computer, jewelry,
car, laser disc player and speaker
one after the other...
All because of that detestable game
My husband told me that the next thing
he was selling was my golf clubs...
And, after that he would even
sell off the sword that
my father gave him as a wedding gift...
et's go to the station
so we can hear you out...
Y. Yes...
right after I change clothes.
A sword...?!
Oh no!
D, Don't tell me?!
Agh!
S,Stay away
M, Mrs. Shibata, please calm down!!
I, I'm finished, because I've...
killed somebody.
Mrs. S, Shibata!!
Will you move out of the way?
Huh?
Huh'e'?!
Huh?!
W, What's with you, stay away from me!
Stay away I said
Are you going to kill again?
Huh?
I'm asking if you're still going to kill after
having already killed your husband
I was just going to kill myself.
You idiot!!
There is no such thing as mine or yours
when it comes to life!
It's something very important
that you're not
Those who kill, are all killers and fools
It doesnit make any difference
if it's your own life!!
Don't you ever forget that!
Shall we get goingnthen, officer?
Oh, yes...
8, Before that, Ms. Ikenaml!
Will you please tell me?
The reason why you lied four times...
I can't make out why you, with weak
bronchial tubes, like knitting,
when there is yarn flying
all over the place...
Knowing what kind of fish it is,
Just by looking at slices of it,
goes to show that you like cooking...
Moreover, you are married
but ou're hidin the trace of the
wedding ring that is on your ring finger!!
And, the name Reiko...
Nobody in that ninja novel has-that name!
And, what is the meaning behind
the reason you mumbled
Reiko in the coffee shop?
Not Reiko, but Rei-(cold) ooh-(coffee).
She was probably-"gang to order some
cold coffee, bat decided otherwise...
Because calling iced coffee, rei-co
would give away the fact that
he is from Osaka...
In this day and age, though,
the only people who would talk like that
are mom or middle aged women...
Right, old lady?
H, Hem and Kazuha!
Hey, old lady!
You finished what you had to do, right?
So go on back to Osaka!
Hmm, hey you!
Hey, stop calling her old lady, how rude!
It doesn't matter what I call'her...
because she's my mother!
Whaaaat'?!
What?!
8, She can't be,
because she's not dark skinned
You idiot!
I got my dark skin from grandpa
Oh my God...
Gosho Aoya'ma
Mlchlhlko Suwa
Masahito Yoshloka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
jumch'i lloka
KanjiKashlwabara
Kazunarl KOUChl
Jumchi Mlyashlta
YUIChl ngure
Toshlki lnoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshl Takatam
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushl Aono
Akao Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukuhlro Shlbutam
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashl Nomura
Hironobu Horlkoshl
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshl Kobayashl
EDITOR.
Terumltsu Okada
CHIEF DIRE'CTOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY.
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
n association with
Yomlun Telecastlfig Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
OGosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
All Rights Reserved
What? You came to
check me out?
Yes, that's right...
Every time Heiji is with you,
he seems to get serious wounds, right?
I thought that
maybe you were making him go through
a rigorous training-bf some sort,
saying that he needed it
in order to become a detective.
Even when he came to Osaka,
you didn't drop by
but went st'raight back to Tokyo...
So, I was worried that you may be
a ruthless and callous guy...
Speak for yourself ma.
You didn't even come to
the hospital back then, but you waited
in front of the balloon fish restaurant.
I couldn't let things go by
without checking it out any longer,
and that's why I decided to come...
However, after seeingnyouz
I really got the picture.
That you, Mr. Mouri, you are
a sharp, keen and nice man that
Heiji couldn't help but respect
W, Well, thank you...
I arrangedV'thin'g's b'éforehand
With Shiro by'phone,
and made like I was looking for him.
You saw through my es and
the murder of Shiro that
happened'c'oincidentally too.
You solved it all in no timefat all!!
I'm really sad about
what happened -to Shiro,
but I got back the picture that
I had been Iookihg for...
VVhatalady.
I thought you said
you didn't want the picture back
because it's a picture of an under
classman beating you, and it vexed you,
so you didn't want it back.
Now, I can rest at ease leaving
Heiji and Kézuhauin ydur ha'n'dsl!
Huh? Leave them in my hands...?
Huh?
Huh? YoCumearuthat phone call was;for.real'?
The message went...
The mermaid will kill me... help.
A, A mermaid...
Will kill somebody...?!
That's. . .?!
This crime can be carried out by anyone,
be it a man or a woman.
And, the killer is still somewhere nearby
($1415?)
(sift-SE)