With a strong heart
and power of deduction,
step into the essence with strong rhythm
The legend of a mermaid
starts off the new series.
Heiji, Kazuha, Ran & Conan
work together again.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
THE MERMAID DISAPPEARS-PART I
(THE MYSTERY)
Good grief,
I hope you appreciate what I'm doing...
first you pop up out of the blue
then you tell me
that we've got to go to Fukui on a job
and that's why were on thisicrazy trip...
Oh don't grumble!
I'm paying for this.
what?
So where are we?
What's the name of that island
we're going to?
It's called Bikuni Island,
it's just a tiny island
the locals around here call it...
the island where the mermaid lives...
Bikuni Island
Did you say mermaid?
Yeah.
Bikuni Island
ERIE
They say there's an old lady on that island
! , - ype .
AA ea Ss nmerimal mea.
I've heard about that!
About 3 years ago,
there was a big fuss:about her,
she's an old lady who has lived forever,
Isn't that right?
Yes, that's right.
I decided to come along
because I wanted to learn
the secret of her beauty & longevity!
Oh I/get it!
You want to snare Heiji
with those secrets, eh?
Shh!
Don't talk so loud!
You've got to be kidding me!
I hope you're not going to tell me
our job is to find a mermaid!
It's just the opposite,
there were only 3 lines
in the letter giving us the job...
and the writing was shaky...
This is what it said,
The mermaid will kill me...
help!
A mermaid...
Is going to kill someone?!
Yawn...
Hey, this is serious!
Give me a break,
mermaids only exist in fairy tales,
don't expect me to take you seriously.
I don't. believe they really exist either,
the name in the letter got my attention.
The envelope was addressed to me but
the letter was written to Shinichi Kudo!
You should be thanking me!
It might be somebody from your past,
that's why I brought you along!
did you contact the person
who sent the letter to confirm it?
Yes.
The sender, Saori Kadowaki,
wrote the number for her cellular phone
on the letter!
No one answered after the second time
I called,
but the first time I called someone
answered and hung up immediately.
On that first call though,
I can still hear
the sound coming from
the other side of the receiver...
It was the sound of waves
and a woman moaning...!
It couldn't be...do you think it was her?
Maybe the mermaid already killed her.
What?!
Saori Kadowaki is missing?!
Yes,
it seems she hasn't shown up for work
for the past 3 days.
3 days ago,
that's about when I got the letter.
Her neighbors are saying
that she might have gone
to the main island:on the ship though.
Sir, it's almost time!
Yes, be right there!
Well,-I've got to go prepare for the festival.
Festival...
Today's the day of the "Dugong Festival".
It's the island's annual celebration!
If you:want-to know more about it,
go to the gift shop Saori worked at,
it's right at the corner!
Mermaid amulets... mermaid straps...
wow, they've even got dugong cakes!
This island's really got every
mermaid item in stock.
What's a dugong. anyway?
Well. uh...
It's a mammal that lives in the ocean,
some people say that
that's the model for the mermaid.
They used to live in the southern part
of Japan too, long ago. and it was
believed that their meat was medicinal
and could make you live a long life.
Dugong arrow...
Yes sir.
It's a charm to keep you young forever,
only 3 are given away,
once every year at the "Dugong Festival
Saori was presented with 1 lastyyear
but she said she lost it
and she has been terrified since last week...
She said the mermaid would curse her.
That's hard to believe...a mermaid...
Mermaids do exist.
Why, Naoko.
Naoko Kurtoe (28)
4 I~ )
LWDME Id
OF VJ 170i IP
There's a holy person who gained eternal
Iife after eating the dugong meat
Naoko Kurtoe (28)
2 are
AL TEWODHIE LU IF»
FFT NE WW
There's a holy person who gained eternal
Iife after eating the dugong meat
Naoko Kurtoe (28)
and whoever possesses the dugong arrow
with the holy person's blessed hair tied to it
will also be granted eternal life!
I don't blame her for running away,
who wouldn't be afraid of
the mermaids curse
after losing an arrow that important?
Who was that?
That's Naoko, she & Saori have been
friends since they were children.
And who is this holy person?
She's the star of the festival
as well as the symbol of our island,
she's old lady Shimabukuro!
So tell me, how old is
the old lady anyway?
There's some that say she's a hundred,
some say she's 200...
if you don't believe me, why don't you go
ine for the festival?
The shrine?
The holy person's great
randdaughter. Kimie,
who's also Saori's childhood friend
ERIOOP
I think weisre being given the run around.
Bikuni Shrine
200 years old, that's ridiculous!
My great-grandmother's
exactly 130 years old this year!
Hh EL
My great-grandmother's
exactly 130 years old this year!
Kimie Shimabukuro (27)
LH) cA)
Kimie Shimabukuro (27) /
DH EL
You can check the birth records
that'll prove it!
Kirniefihimabukuro (27) Q;
KM PW
You can check the birth records
that'll prove it!
Good grief.
Just because she's a little older than :40',
most, everyone exaggerates so much. 77
A little older...
She belongs in
the Guinness Book of World Records.
where is this very old lady anyway?
She's in her room,
blessing the arrows to be presented
at today's festival.
Then, you mean,
she really eats dugong meat?!
Huh:
Aha!
Hahahahal,
There's no such things as mermaids!
Heh?
That story's a complete lie!
B, but what about the Dugong Arrow...
My late mother told me
that it was originally a protection amulet
but the people on the island went &
started to call it dugong arrow instead.
You've lost your mother?
» a WD
1 CO.
She was lost{at sea 5 years ago,
along 'with my father.
And it seems my grandparents
were also lost at sea before I was born.
How awful,
you lost your whole family to the sea,
there must be something behind it.
That's nonsense!
Saori and I went to the main island
by boat just recently
and nothing happened.
You went with Saon?
When was that?
4 days ago.
I had a dentist appointment
andfasked her to come with me.
There's no dentists on this island.
Was there anything strange
about her that day?
She was very scared
because she lost the dugong arrow.
She thought the mermaid would curse her.
No matter how hard I tried to convince her
nothing would'happen, she wouldn't listen.
You're so stupid.
She wouldn't listen
because you don't believe in
the holy:ones:powers, isn't that right?
Toshimi?
She's the real thing!
Toshimi Ebihara (27)
BEFRFR (27)
110) Id
Toshimi Ebihara (27)
BEES (27)
WONT ULH
Toshimi Ebihara (27)
BEBFSE (27)
She really ate dugong meat!
Well, actually,
about 3 years ago, the carcass of
a real dugong did wash up.
A dead dugong?!
Oh, wasn't it on television
about 3 years ago?
The media played it up a lot.
You don't know what you're talking about.
You saw it, didn't you?
The bones were crushed in
a very strange way. It was grotesque...
That's enough, Toshimi!
Rokuro.
You shouldn't tell outsiders too much.
Rokuro Fukuyama (28)
If you people are looking for Saori,
RokuroFukuyama (28)
BoE LY
RokurosFukuyama (28)
3¢ 33
ORE LH
why don't you just go to her home?
RokuroFukuyama (28)
3< 33
ERO TE IF
Why don't you just go to her home?
You might learn something if
that drunkard father lets you in, that is...
Nobody seems to be very worried.
That's because Saori fought with
her father a lot and she'd often runaway. 4's
Would you mind taking us
to Saori's home?
I don't mind.
But it'll have to be after the festival.
What do you do at the festival?
Lottery tickets are sold beforehand
and if their numbers match the numbers
my great-grandmother picks,
they get an arrow.
It's like lucky number drawing.
Oh, that's right!
Would you like to try your luck?
An elderly couplessuddenly
cancelled this. morning
so there are 2 extras.
If you say so...
Whether you win or lose,
it's all up to the Gods!
Maybe, you'll be able to obtain eternal
youth and beautydjust like the rumors.
I'm kind of excited.
Me too!
Mikoto Shimabukuro (130)
It's the holy person!
The holy person is making
her appearance!
That's the holy person...
She's so tiny.
It's just an old lady
wearing heavy makeup.
She set fire to the door!
I get it.
The fire burns
the winning number onto the door.
I... don't believe it...
Am I seeing things?
I did it, what luck!!
Oh well...
Ra, Ra, Ra, Ran...
I won!!
You what?!
Attention winners.
The dugong arrows will be
presented to you in an hour.
Please proceed to
the Mermaid's Waterfall!
Now, will the 3 persons
who will receive divine favor,
please; step forward!
Yes!
Here I am!
Where is the other person?
Isn't there anyone else?!
Benzou Kadowaki (52)
PIE FI (52)
SPUN
Here I am.
Benzou Kadowaki (52)
NR #62)
IHR BUY
Benzou Kadowaki (52)
8 ~h<t5
HE #113 (52)
Hehehe...
Benzou Kadowaki (52)
NR £2)
What is this?
That's strange...
I could've sworn that other girl won too.
Yeah...
and I don't see her around here.
At this time, however...
she was already
here at the Mermaids Waterfall.
Show these 3 with the divine light!
Hey. What's that?
What is that?!
That's right...
Iong, black hair wafting...
on a slim body that sways...
it most certainly looked like
a mermaid swimming up
the waterfall,
shiny & blue...
but it was a lifeless body...
To, Toshimi...
Do you think she killed herself?
R was she murdered...
Maybe it's neither...
the rope that's around her neck is
the one that's used to rope off
the dangerous areas along the river.
What did you just say?
- - - 37 am -_
I OCC...
So it happened like this,
it was dark & Toshimi tripped
she grabbed the rope
but the current was too strong
so the nails came loose
and as she fell,
the rope got tangled around her neck!
But don't you think that's strange?
The festival was still going on
around the bottom of the waterfall.
So what did she go into the forest for?
Maybe she was looking for
the mermaid's grave?
What?!
The mermaids grave Is
somewhere in this forest...
on the night of the festival 3 years ago,
a fire burned the shrine's storage house,
that's how
the mermaids bones were found. They
were buried somewhere in this forest.
Yes, I remember she was always talking
about that grave...
Hold on a minute!
You all talk about a mermaid
but how do you know
they were a mermaid's bones?
Well...
all the people on the island said they were
but the policeman from the main land said
the bones were those of
a middle aged woman.
That's a lie!
He said he couldn't be sure if there were
bones from the lower part of her body!
The lower part of her body...?
He main beam from the storage house
burned and fell on the lower part of her body
but when the beam was lifted off,
there were no bones
for where her legs should have been.
Th, that's hard to believe!!!
Thanks to that fact,
the media made a big fuss broadcasting
that a mermaid's body was found.
And our holy person became famous!
But didn't the police say it was a lady?
Yes...
they said probably tourists who didn't
win one of the dugong's arrows
snuck into the storage house
Iooking for an extra arrow
and the fire was caused when the candle
In the storage house was lit.
A year went by and
it was still unidentified
so we went and buried it...
The problem started after that.
Problem?
Grave robbers...
What?
Stupid tourists started coming around
trying to dig up the bones.
It seems they heard that mermaid bones
were the elixir of eternal life.
That's why my great-grandmother
asked someone
to help and they reburied
the bones here secretly.
Who did she ask?
I don't know.
All she said was that it was
someone she trusted very much.
Well, whether it's suicide,
murder or an accident,
we'll continue this conversation
after the police have arrived
and we've taken her body down.
Humph...
If it was murder,
then it's partly Toshimi's fault too,
coming to a place like this
at this time of night.
Aren't you the cold one,
your fiancee just died.
Fiancee?
Our parents arranged that on their own.
I never proposed to her.
Besides, both my father and mother
are no longer alive.
Toshimi!
Toshimi!!
Ioshimi!
Who is:that?
That's Toshimi's father.
Mr. Ebihara,
the head of the fisherman's union.
Dad!!
Uhuh...
did you call the Fukui prefectural police?
They said the seas are too rough
and they won't be able to
come until the water calms down!
You've got .to beikidding.
Hey. lucky:for us!
Huh
The murderer can't get off
the island either.
What do you mean, murderer...
we don't know for sure yet
that she was murdered.
Then take a look at it!
A swim ring?
Heiji & I found it,
It was stuck in the middle of the river
that joins the water from
the waterfall to the ocean!
If Toshimi was knocked unconscious
then she's put on the swim ring and set
afloat, with the rope winding her neck,
she'd end up hanging from the waterfall,
wouldn't she?
We saw Toshimi at the shrine
2 hours before the fireworks went up!
It doesn't take an hour to get
to and from the top of the waterfall...
which means,
anyone could have committed the crime,
man or woman...
and the murderer is still on the island!!
Th, that's terrible.
Don't worry about it!
The murderer will be caught in no time!
When Heiji moves his hat around,
he's turned his switch on!
He's ready to go!
Wow...
But...
you must've fallen in love with him.
I'm no match for you...
we ecome rivas...
Ka, Kazuha...
you're so sweet!
Hey, what're you doing?!
Listen...
if Toshimi was murdered,
you'd better not let that person
out of your sight.
I'm talking about Saori's drunk of a father.
Excuse me,
would you like to go to Saori's home now,
I'll take you-since I promised you earlier.
With him in that condition,
I doubt he'll be much help though.
You may be right.
Alright then...
Huh 7
I'd like to meet the holy person!
Sure,
I don't mind, but?.
Boy this house is old...
#it doesn't look like they're making too
much money from those dugong arrows.
How can you say that?
Those platelets cost 5 yen a piece.
Eh? 5 yen?
The people on this island said the price
has been the same
since they can remember.
There are 108 number platelets
in a huge box
& everyone lines up then pulls one out.
Then the old woman picks
E winning num ers.
What's taking that old lady
so long anyway?
Kimie said she'd tell her
we want to see her
but she might be tired
after today's festival,
so we may not be able to see her...
Huh
What is that sound?
Ah?!
Are you the ones who want to see me?
Without makeup, she looks like a spook.
Uh, excuse me...
we wanted to know
how you picked the winning numbers.
I just pick them randomly.
Once I used the numbers of the horses
that won at the races.
I don't believe this.
So why don't you sell more instead
of being so stingy and selling only 37
That can't be helped...
the hair I tie to the arrow is my own
& ll don't have a whole lot.
Great grandmother!
Your bath is ready!!
Excuse me,
if that's all you came here for,
I'm going to take a bath now & go to bed.
Wait, I'd like to ask.you more...
Alright then, you girlie...
You, the one with your hair tied back.
Who, me?
The dugong's arrow is
really a charm to ward off evil...
if it leaves your body,
evil will overtake you
men will return to the soil
and become heartless demons,
Women will return to the water
and become silent mermaids.
You must never let it leave your person.
Even her voice sounds wrinkly,
\ andsshe's so pale!
She looks like
she could drop dead any minute.
The next day
Ebihara family
ves O
- . - -
"ERE IL EK
See! 3
I'm glad I brought my school uniform
withfme, it's coming to good use.
Arelyou sure this is OK...
Won't they mind having
us show up like this? ¥ .
No problem!
It's a small island, this'll be
) the perfect time to question everybody.
Stop smiling like that!
This is Toshimi's wake!
Oh, sorry...
Kazuha, -
\did you bring the arrow with you?
Yes! I certainly did!
Hun?
It's that drunk...
he's already here.
Why Mr. Mourt,
I'm surprised you all came.
Yes, well...
by the way,
I understand that Mr. Kadowaki
didn't go home last night.
That's right...
But I heard he got into a fight
with a tourist at a bar.
So he was drinking all night, huh?
I don't see Naoko around.
Her name was on the
sign-in sheet though.
Eh? Naoko's here?
She's probably in the restroom!
We'll go check
- [ED
1 CD,
good idea.
Eeek!!
Don't tell me you're afraid of thunder?
No, it's not that...
someone's out there.
Y, you're right!
What's going on?
Oh, Heiji!
Somebody's out there!
Are you sure?!
Isn't that?!
Eeeeceeeeekkkkkk...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
KatsuotOno
CHARACTER DESIGNS; BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
IMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
OGosho Aoyama / Shagakukfi
All Rights Reserved
FF. fish scales?!
You mean the killer's a mermaid?!
Stay close to me.
Eeeek!!
What happened?!
Over there,
a brown haired girl with glasses is...
She's looking straight at us!
1. I don't believe It!
Saon?!
Th, that's impossible!
Idiot!
That's impossible!!!