With a strong mind &
sharp powers of reasoning,
a keen sense of rhythm that enables him
to grasp the inner meaning of the crime.
A keen sense of rhythm that enables him
Today's episode is Part ll of
the story about the mermaid.
Danger creeps up on
the interesting couple.
He sees through to
the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with
the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
G Beach/Los Angeles! agfiedd
The strange letter sent to
Heiji Hattori beckons us and
we come to the island of Bikuni
The Island of Bikuni
but we learn that the sender,
Saori Kadowaki, is missing.
That night, the island is lively
because they are celebrating
the annual Dugong Festival.
The islanders believe that whoever
possesses the dugong arrows blessed
by the Holy Person who gained
eternal life by eating dugong meat
would also be granted eternal life.
But during the festival,
one of Saori's childhood friends,
Toshimi Ebihara
is found hanging
by the neck in the waterfall.
Heiji and I realize this is a murder and
we begin to investigate,
but on the night of Toshimi's wake,
another murder takes place
The Mermaid Disappears
Part ll
I don't think she's been
dead longer than an hour
She was probably strangled
then put in this net...
Naoko Kuroe (28)
TET (28
She was probably strangled
then put in this net...
Naoko Kuroe (28)
RIFT (28)
2EBDOHBEL
IFE\N2UT FIs SE
She was probably strangled
then put in this net...
Naoko Kuroe (28)
RISHT (28)
2RDIOBEL
HOITFVE ER
She was probably strangled
then put in this net...
Naoko Kuroe (28)
SWELL
HFVITFME ER
She was probably strangled
then put in this net...
Naoko Kuroe (28)
-« Xx
L238 (CO)
SWOT LH
HOFWE ER
The footprints on the sand are
from sandals & rubber boots...
Naoko was probably wearing
these sandals,
so the murderer must've been
wearing boots!
How cruel...
Hey, look!
See, doesn't this look like an arrow was
stepped on by sandals?
It's been stepped on by sandals
so Naoko must have stepped on it
after it fell
while she struggled with the murderer...
The killer must've taken the arrow!
Let's follow the boot prints,
that'll lead us to the killer.
You're right...
Hey, these prints...
They look like they go straight
into the ocean...
You're right...
Huh?
There's some shiny things
around the prints...
What are they?
Hmm... these are . '7?
Fish...scales...?
There're 2 or 3 fish scales
on Naoko's body too.
What?
Hey!!
Huh?
What are you people doing there...!
Carrying out an investigation, of course...
We're the Fukui Prefecture Police,
that's OUR job!
Prefecture Police?
You're finally here...
What?!
The killer's footprints disappeared
into the sea?!
Yeah...and left some fish
scales behind too
Did you say fish scales...!?
You're no saying the killer's"...
A mermaid... 1?
How stupid!
Mermaids don't wear rubber boots!
The killer probably approached
from the shoreline and
then went up to the nets where
Naoko was told to wait...
after murdering Naoko,
the killer walked back to the shoreline
and left the scene walking
through the water!
Now I get it...
By the way,
did anyone see Naoko leave the room?
Not me...
she wasn't there when I got there...
Kimie Shimabukuro (27)
Eat Rt
Benzo, what about you?
You signed in right after Naoko,
didn't you?
I didn't see her and nobody was in
the room when I got there...
That means Naoko was the first one
to get here
then she left to go to where
the nets were hung...
Wait a minute,
do you think the same person
who killed Toshimi killed Naoko too?
We don't know that for sure yet
but we do know the killer
took Naoko's arrow...
The dugong's arrow?
O oO nN  7 ER SE Ny FL
DEelore sine aisdp ped
Saori also said that she'd lost her arrow,
do you think...
Yeah...she might already be dead too...
I saw Saori near the Mermaid's waterfall
on the morning of yesterday's festival.
I saw her too.
She was far away and I only caught a glance,
she was in the forest by the waterfall...
Are you absolutely sure it was Saori?
No mistake, she was the only girl
with brown hair and glasses...
And she always wears blue clothes...
Then she must be running
away from something,
Saori Kadowaki
IRTEITHS
that's why she's hiding from everyone!
Saori Kadowaki
Mr. Kadowaki, don't you have any idea
what's hap
Don't ask m
she never told me anything...
ump...
I just hope she hasn'tsturned into
a mermaid like this dead girl...
Mermaid? What do you mean?
Didn't you know?
The legendary nun ate the meat of
the mermaid that was caught in the net...
MM, mermaid...
If the arrow leaves your body,
evil will overtake y
women will return to the water and
become silent mermaids...
Ka, Kazuha...
Never mind that,
Iet's all go look for Saori in the morning!
Kazuka...
Stay close to me .
Hei...
Later that night, the police searched
everyone at the wake looking
for the person who took Naoko's arrow,
the only ones with arrows were Benzo
and Kazuha, who won them at the festival.
Hey Kudo, did you find anything out?
No, nothing...
All I know at this point is,
Toshimi, Naoko & the missing Saori
the powers of the Holy Person who
is said to have eaten mermaid flesh...
Yeah...it's almost abnormal
how much they believed in it...
If we only knew who held what number
at last night's fest:
that's easy.
We have everyone sign the list...
Would you like to come with me now
and take a look at the lis
Of course!
For goodness' sake Dad!
Get a grip on yourself!
I know this is a bad time,
but... did you think about
what we talked about before?
I'm serious, you know...
I can't...
Tloshimi's dea
it wouldn't:be fair to her...
besides, I have my great
grandmother to take care of,
I can't leave this island...
I'm sorry...
Did the 5 of you go to
college together too?
Yes...
We all loved watching movies &
joined the movie club in college
We even made a film about
the legendary n
And it took first place in the film contest,
we were all so
We set our sights on Hollywood!
That's fantastic!
But we all loved this island and
ended up coming back...
who would have dreamed Toshimi &
Naoko would end up like this...
I could have sworn we left them here...
Can't you find them?
No...only the ones for this year
are mis
Maybe that old lady took them?
She would never do that...
Did anyone else know
you kept them there?
Most of the locals knew
I'll go check the other rooms just in case.
I'll help you.
Me too...
Thank you.
Wow, look at these names!
A former Foreign Affairs Minister,
a Chief Secretary of-the Cabinet and
a President of the Bank of Japan!
They all wanted to live
a long life I guess...
Shino Miyano...?
I'm pretty sure...
her real name was something like that...
but it couldn't be...she's not the type to
wish for eternal youth & beauty...
Eceececeeceececeek!!
What happened!?
I saw a brown haired girl with
glasses standing?Oover there...
She was staring at us!
Th, that's impossible...!
Saori was here...!?
Huh? What is this...
Why is this glass cracked!?
Where's Kimie!?
She said she was going to look in
the rebuilt warehouse.
Where is it!?
I'm pretty
she said it was behind the shrine.
She said it was behind the shrine.
Hey, what's that?
It's awfully bright over there!!
It couldn't be!!
The fire continued to burn
throughout the night
just like it did 3 years ago,
it burnt to the ground...
that's right...
it was exactly like the fire 3 years ago...
including the remains of 1 victim...
A burned body!?
It was burned beyond recognition
but it had glasses on it.
You could just barely make out
that it was wearing blue clothing.
It's probably... Saori...
who was missing...
Th, then the girl we saw last night...
Was a gh, ghost
Kimie...where are you, Kimie...
Mikoto Shimabukuro (130)
LR 553 (130)
BOWIE
Mikoto Shimabukuro (130)
B&R IRE 30
HORNE
Mikoto Shimabukuro (130)
Kimie...
Isn't Kimie back yet?
No, she's not .
I'll go stay with the great grandmother...
I'll go too...
Hey Hattori...
didn't Kim.
She went to the dentist recently?
Yeah, she did...
You don't mean...
do you know what you're implying...
Don't fool me...
the same thought passed through
your mind too, didn't
We bot
the same bad feeling about this...
Yes, I see...thank you very much...
What did you find out...1?
They compared Kimie's dental records
with the burn victim's teeth and...
They were a perfect match
How awful...
Kimie's dead...
She... can't be...
I don't believe it!
It's all a lie!!!
I see...
So Kimie's dead...
We're very sorry...
we lost sight of he
for just a few moments...
Another young life has been lost...
and here.l am, still alive at this old age,
I'm-so a
I have a question,
the mermaid's grave that
you asked someone
to help you move into the forest...
who helped you do it?
It won-t do you any good to know...
that person's died before me too...
Hey, Mr. Mouri!
Did you find anything?
Absolutely nothing!
What a complicated case...
we can't even figure out who the killer is,
how can we find a motive for all of this...
On top of that, we don't even know
why Kimie was dressed like Saori...
Well, that was probably to make us think
it was Saori who die
Then the Killer must be Sao...
Or it could be someone who
wants us to think it is.
Huh?
Is that the ocean?
The ocean's right behind us last night...
Kimie told us that . last night...
Well, no matter who the killer is,
one thing is for sure
we've got to find the killer
as soon as possible,
we can't let such a heartless
Killer run f
Dad!
What is it, Ran?
Someone just called Kimie's home,
the caller said something strange!
What do you mean?
The caller said, Thank you for
Ietting me have the arrow.
It was worth the 1,000,000 yen,
my son's operation was a success'.
Someone bought the arrow!?
For 1.000.000 yen!?
ICC...
the caller said that the other morning,
a man who said he worked at the shrine
agreed to sell it as a special favor...
Doesn't that have something
to do with the old couple
who cancelled the morning of the festival?
It probably does...
And so what was the man's name?
I don't know but
he was a big man probably in
his 50's and he had a scruffy beard...
Are you sure...!?
Benzo!
Hey! If it was before the festival,
then that arr
More than likely it was the arrow
Saori said she lo
And luc {for Benzo, he won an arrow
at the festival and on top of that,
the register with all the names got lost...
Something's going on...
Naoko, who was kille
on the day of Toshimi's wake, also
had her arrow stolen...
I'm going to the Ebihara's home
where the wake was held.
Kudo, I mean... Mr Mouri, please
go and check Benzo's place!
Good grief...
Are you sure about that!?
Did you say Benzo left right
after us last night!.
That's right, he looked scared...
I knew it, Benzo was listening to us...
He heard us talking about going
with Kimie to check the register...
So he took a short cut and stole it
before we ar
Then it was probably Benzo who set fire
to the warehouse,
You re probably right...
if Kimie found him hanging around
holding the regist
What are you doing here?
Don't tell me you forgot!
You're the one who told me to stay close!
Oh... that's right...
Besides, since I have an arrow
that's been bless
I'm your good luck charm!
You have nothing to worry about,
if you're in danger, I'll protect you!!
Wow, I'm so lucky...
I'm serious...Heij...
But now that Kimie's dead,
I guess this will b
the last Dugong Festival...
I guess so...
Hey, you!
Can you tell me again which footprints
are yours and which are your friends?
Sure no problem...oops!
Huh? What the
What is it, Heij1?
There are scratches on the back
of this sandal and they're still fresh.
Where are the sandals
Naoko was wearing?
They were taken
the Fukui Police Department.
Kazuha, let me see<your arrow
Eh? Sure...
Perfect match...
These are the sandals that stepped on
the arrow on the sa
which means...
what I thought all along...
I knew it, no one's home!
Hey, what're you people doing here?
Well, uh, we wanted to talk to Benzo,
do you know where he is?
I haven't seen hi
since the wake last night...
What bad timing...
we thought at least we could take
a look at the missing Saori's room...
If you want to get insid
take a look underfthe potted plant
That's where the key is
Let's see now...
Aha, I found it...!
Alright, let's do it!
Are you sure it's alright to
go in without permission?
He won't mind, we'll just have a fast look!
Hey, how did Saori act
just before she disappeared?
She was s
even when the ocean got rough...
she said the mermaid
was going to punish her...
Punish her...?
This is SaOri's room.
Hmmm...
Huh?
What's this bag doing here?
I wonder what's inside
Co, Conan...!
Aspirin, toothbrush...
That's Saor
run away from home set...
But then she usually went to Kimie's
so I heard she kept extra clothes
and a spare pair of glasses there...
So you m
the clothes Kimie was wearing
when she was found in the warehouse,
she could have put them on herself?
Why'd she have to go and do that for...
Maybe to lure the killer out...
Just kidding!
Ha, ha ha...that's ridiculous...
But if Kimie thoug
the killer was after Saori too
and if she saw someone suspicious
hanging around the house
she might have done what Conan said
so that she could catch the Killer...
You're crazy,
Iast night during the fire,
didn't you say you saw someone who
Iooked like Saori in the yard
Is there a picture of Saori in this room?
I think there's a photo album around...
Hey Ran! Is this the girl you saw?
I'm not sure, it was pretty dark...
These pictures,
are they ones from w
you did the film on the legendary nun?
Yes...
Where? Let me see...
Wow, this is something!
It really looks like a mermaid
IS swimming in the ocean...
It really does! This scene
In the storm is so realistic...
Yes, Saori's special effect photography
and Kimie's theatrical makeup techniques
were the main reasons
we won first place...
but 1 year after that,
there really was a storm
and both of Kimie's parents, as well as
mine and Saori's mother were lost at sea.
Not one of us dreamed anything
Iike that would happen.
Huh? Wait a minute...
bank book, cash card, name stamp...
driver's license and passport are here...
But that thing's not here...
I don't understand
It cant be...1?
Hattori here...
Oh, Kudo, it's you...
oh, I mean Mr. Mouri?
I was just about to call you!
The sandal we found in
the Kadowaki's yard
had scratches on it
from stepping on the arrow!
It proves that.on the night of the wake,
the killer went to whe
Naoko was waiting near the nets
and after killing her,
the killer returned to the wake!
The only 2 who could have done
that were Benzo and Rokuro...
But seeing how upset Rokuro
was in the afternoo
I doubt he'd do anything to hurt Kimie...
Which means...
I'm going to tell you my theory now...
Iisten carefully...
Yeah sure, go ahead...
That's ridiculous! It's impossible!!
I don't believe it!!
Hattori...
when we rule out the impossible,
only the truth remains, no matter
how unbelievable it might seem!!
What did you say!?
Inspector!
Our men are in the forest
tracking down Benzo Kadowaki!
Good! Let's go men!
After we catch Benzo,
I'll go to where you are!
Wait for me there!
I don't want to believe it either, Hattorl...
It's a lie! A lie! It can't be true!
You canst make me believe it, Kudo!!
What's that?
Do you smell incense?
You're crazy!
Who'd be burning incense
this deep in the forest. huh?
Is this the mermaid"s grave...?
W, wait a minute...
then this must mean...
Kudo must've been right...
Oh no!
Oh no! The cliff...!
Argh!
KazuhaH!
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junichi hoka
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
OGosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
YTV [TMS
All Rights Reserved
Forgive me:Heij...
Ka, Kazuha...?
Goodbye...
You fool!
The only 2 capable of leaving the wake,
were Benzo and Rokuro!
There's only 1 person who could have
come up with that plansbefore the festival!
That's right, YOU are the killer!!