With a strong mind and
sharp powers of reasoning,
a keen sense of rhythm
that can grasp the crime.
Today the mermaid case is solved
with powers of deduction
w'h'iéh' surpass legend
. He sees through to the one & only truth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Heiji Hattori receives a Strange letter
that prompts us to come to Bikuni Island
BIKUNI ISLAND
What awaited us was
a series of murders revolving around
some dugong arrows
that are said to grant
the bearer eternal youth
Saori Kadowaki, the girl who
wrote the letter is missing,
and her childhood friends
Toshimi Ebihara
and Naoko Kuroe are
murdered one after the other,
and on top of that, the warehouse
belonging to the shrine goes up in flames
and the body of Kimie Shimabukuro is
discovered in the rubble.
Is Saori responsible for the murders?
We go to search her room for clues
and make a startling discovery.
It's like Kudo said after all...
so the murderer's who he said it is...
KazuhaH!
If? I\
The Mermaid Disappears-Part III
E, Heiji...
Hang on...Kazuha...
I'm going to start pulling you up...
Oh n0...
h, the branch...
s going to break...
we'll both fall at this rate...
Forgive me, Heiji...
Iive a long life. ..for me too...
a, Kazuha...
Goodbye...
You foo!
Rokuro Fukuyama (28)
a Fisherman
ism an cam
awn Jba
Mama
Rokuro Fukuyama (28)
a Fisherman
ism fiEB (28)
♪ CDQJH La}
$575
Okay Mr. Detective!
I brought him here just like you told me to
this guy's been running
over the forest...
Benzo Kadowaki (52)
ESaori's fath'ér
$133
Benzo Kadowaki (52)
rSaori's father
#fi(
So where's that kid who speaks with
the Osaka accent?
Oh yeah...l haven'tlSeen him since
we got separated in the forest...
What'?
...Heiji...l don't understand...
hy didn't you let go...
we'll both die if we stay like this.
Let go of my hand...
Ka, Kazuha...
Don t move...
I'll kill you if you move you nut case
Hem...
Hattori, where are you...
Why aren't you here. What're you doing...
Come on already,
how long do we have to wait?
We police officers have
a lot of work to do...
to Shimabukuro (130)
great-grandmother
It's the Holy Person...
Wow...
Why is she here...
Now that all the actors are present,
Iet me begin explaining.
I'm going to give you the truth behind the
3 murders that occurred on this island...
The first murder which involved Toshiml
being hung in the Mermaid's Waterfall...
and the second, of Naoko being
strangled in the nets...
and lastly, the murder of Kimie who was
burned in the warehouse...
The important issue here is
the second murder.
Judging from the evidence,
it appeared as though the killer
walked along the shoreline to get
to & from the scene of the murder, but...
That kidifrom Osaka
explained that already...
Yes, he told me too...
those footprii'nts were put there by the killer
before the murder to throw us off track...
the killer actually went to the scene
during the wake
those fish scales really had me fooled...
the killer dropped
the scales around the footprints
then on Nahoko's clothes
after killing her, that way,
with the scales leading to the water,
the killer made it look
a mermaid was responsible
& that it escaped into the ocean...
And, the only ones who could have left
the wake that night,
were Rokuro & Benzo,
you're the only ones.
Hat...
I don't believe it...
By the way Benzo,
I have a question for you...
on the morning of the festival,
you're the one who sold a dugong arrow
for 1,000,000 yen to
an elderly couple, aren't you?
Ah...that's the arrow my daugh
Saori won the year before...
m her father, I had a right
All that money must've made you greedier
so when you saw that
Toshimi won one this year,
you told her to meet you by the waterfall &
then at the waterfall, you stole her platelet,
set her afloat on the swim ring
so that her neck would get caught.
And as for Nahoko who also won an arrow,
you called her out on the night of
the wake, killed her & took her arrow.
But if the list of names were checked,
everyone would know
Toshimi's platelet was stolen.
So you went to Kimie's home before
we got there to steal the registry, but
Kimie saw you so you locked her
in the warehouse & set fire to it!
This registry that you had
in your possession
when you were arrested proves your guilt!
And we've also found your fingerprints
on the swim ring used in Toshimi's case!
You're mistaken, Benzo's not the killer...
If Benzo was the killer,
he would have burned the registry along
with the warehouse, don't you think?
Besides, everyone
who lived on this island
knew where the registry was kept,
I don't think
he'd have to n'xsh overdo stem Vt.
Another thing, it would have been very
hard for him to call Naoko out...
Nahoko noticed that Toshimi won
an arrow at the festival too,
and she was suspicious of Benzo
who had that winning number...
Alright then, what about the fingerprints
on the swim ringl'?
I'm pretty sure he touched it
when he found it along with
the winning platelet which was
snagged somewhere on the river...
Yeah...the detective's right...
I didn't want people to think I was
the killer just because I just happened
to find the winning platelet,
that's why I stole the registry.
Th'e'fi Roku'ro Fukuyama,
YOU must be the killer!
Hat's ridiculous...
Toshimi was your fiancee, wasn't she?
She would have gone to meet you
at the waterfall with no suspicions...
No, he's not the killer either
What!?
The killer used a swim ring
to kill Toshimi so that
she'd float down the waterfall
without getting caught on anything,
that way,
it would look like an accident, but
being a fisherman,
Rokuro has very strong arms and
Toshimi wasn't very heavy
so it would have very easy for him
to just toss her into the river
He wouldn't have had
to use a swim ring
which would only be left
behind as evidence
But if neither of them is the killer,
then who is?
The killer made it look like
Toshimi's death was an accident
but made no attempt to hide the fact
that Nahoko was murdered.
Do you know what that means?
Well, uh...
no,ldon1.
When Toshimi was killed,
the police didn't arrive right away
because the sea wasj'toonoth,
Normally, the police would have arrived
sometime that night.
And since it was a case of murder,
the investigation would
have been intense,
the killer wouldn't have been able
to move about freely.
The killer didn't want that to happen,
that 3 why it had to look like an accident.
Which means,
the killer planned to kill Nahoko
after Toshimi from the very start!
But no one would have known
Nahoko had won an arrow
until she came forward
That's right.
The killer's motive
wasn't to steal an arrow
nor was it to kill whoever won it.
It was only made to look that way
to mislead the investigation!
That's.
The reason why the killer made it obvious
that Nahoko was murdered was'\
so that everyone's attention was
on the scenerofbthe crime,
- the killer used that time
to carry out the third murder!
The killer planned and executed
each crime very carefully.
It wasn't on a whim.
The only person who could have
prepared everything before the festival is
No, you don't mean...!?
Someone who knew beforehand that
Toshimi & Nahoko had won arrows...
That's right...
YOU are the killer!!
That's right.
The killer is the holy person!
Yes, you
Humph...you've got to be kidding.
How can a 130 year old lady
do those things...?
What if she had an accomplice?
If neither Rokuro nor Benzo
could have killed Nahoko,
then the only other person
who could have done it is...
Kimie!!
That's nonsense...
Kimie was the third victim
But what if it wasn't Kimie
that was in the warehouse?
What!?
Don't you remember,
Kimie 3 dental records and
the burn victim's dental records
were identical
Dad, you were there too weren't you?
When she said she'd gone to the dentist.
Yes, I heard.
She said she went with Saorl!
You don't mean!?
A s rlgm...
it was Saori's teeth that got worked on...
Kimie went with Saori to see the dentist
on the main land
and when Saori wasn't looking,
she took her insurance I.D.
then she insisted
Saori use her I.D. instead .
That's how Saori got her teeth fixed
as Kimie...
Then she killed Saori in the warehouse,
and set it on fire with the body inside,
the dental records led us all
to believe it was Kimie who died
Then the brown haired girl with glasses
we saw in the garden was...
It was Kimie in disguise...
that's who the witnesses saw
on the the morning of the festival too...
it was to make us suspicious
about the body found in the warehouse
and to make Saori look guilty...
But all this is just your theory...
I called the dentist & got verification.
The Kimiekhe worked on
had brown hair and wore glasses
Which means,
Kimie Shimabukuro is still hiding
somewhere on this island,
waiting for an opportunity to escape!
Alright then, I'll have this entire island
searched from top to bottom...
There's no need for that
What'?
Kimie is right here in this room!!
What did you say!?
Where!? Where is she!?
Kimie's here...
I can't believe it...
That can't be...
I don't see her anywhere!
Rokuro told us that
Kimie's talent as a make-up artist
is outstanding...
Yes, that's right...
Are you saying
she's disguised herself as somebody?
This isn't a movie, it wouldn't work
You're right, it would be impossible
to disguise herself perfectly...
but what if
it's someone who doesn't show herself
to others very much...?
And what if the only time
everyone sees her is
at the festival when she has
on very heavy make-up?
Now your choices have been
narrowed down significantly!
Th, that's...
impossible...
B, but, how do you account for
the height difference...
Think back.
Remember the strange corpse you found
when the warehouse burned down
3 years ago...
There were no leg bones
where there should have been...
and the locals said
it was a mermaid's body, yes, that case...
it was probably the body of a woman
who died in the fire with her legs bent...
And tied with rope
made of paper or something
If my theory is right,
that woman was Kimie's
It wasmmy mother...
She carried out the Holy Person's role
that was grandmother's
it was for all the people on the island...
she put her heart into the role...
I feel so sorry for her...
Iook-[What it got her...
You're pretty good, Mr. Detective
I was pretty confident
nobody'd see through this disguise...
It was that time when we found
that the register was missing...
Maybe that old lady took it?
She'd never do that...
I was suspicious about
how quickly and confidently you replied...
I see
But while we were
talking to the Holy Person,
we heard Kimie's voice...
Great-grandmother!
Your bath is ready!
Oh that,
I recorded that on a cassette tape
and then replayed it!
But why, Kimie!?
You 4 were close friends
since you were kids
The words childhood friends mean nothing
when it comes to
avenging my own mother's death...
Do you mean
those three are the ones who set fire
to the warehouse 3 years ago...
IUD...
they were angry
that they didn't win arrows at the festival
and then they got drunk & set it on fire...
Mother was disguised as the Holy Person
and when they saw her
go into the warehouse,
they decided they wanted to see
if she really had eternal life!
. I didn't find out until a week ago,-
when Saori told me,
she was in a panic
because she lost her arrow,
I never dreamed
they could do anything like that.
But I thought your mother disappeared
5 years ago while she-"Was out fishing...
Mother said it would be easier to play
just the Holy person's role all through
instead of playing 2 roles
at the same time...
Then why didn't you admit
the truth after the fire?
Why didn't you tell everyone
the body was your mother....!
Mother called me on her cellular phone
while the flames burned around her...
Kimie...the rest is up to you...
Kimie the rest is up to you...
That's why...l played the Holy Person...
Don't let the Holy Person die
that was what she sand
and yet...
all of mother's devotion...
meant nothing to them.
After Saori lost her arrow
she had the nerve to say...
If you won't give me another arrow,
then tell me
where the mermaid's grave is!
The mermaid bones that the Holy Person
had hidden in the warehouse,
where are they buried!
I want to be like her too.
Like the Holy Person .
To be in perfect condition
after being engulfed in all those flames
I want to live forever!!
I couldn't forgive her
nor Toshimi, nor Naoko...
Getting them to meet me was easy...
when I told them
I'd tell where the grave was
after they won the arrows at the festival,
the eyes of those two
Iit up with excitement...
it was mother's grave...
my mother and I worked so hard
for everyone...
But you two weren't alone...
Ha, Hattorl...!?
I'm pretty sure there were others
who knew what the Holy Person
was up to, isn't that so?
You, old man! I heard you say that
now that Kimie was dead,
there would be no more festivals!
I meant, uh...
I'm sorry, Kimie!
Everyone on the island knew,
except for the younger people...
I, don't believe it .
We also knew that it was your mother
who died in that fire 3 years ago...
After the fire,
we went to tell you that
the festival could be ended, but...
when you came out
dressed like the Holy Person,
we couldn't bring ourselves to tell you...
You see, this is the mermaid's island...
and if you decided
you'd carry out the role...
We decided to keep quiet about it
and help you whenever we could...
We thought we were doing it
for the island, forgive us
Forgive us, Kimie...
We're sorry...
Forgive us...
I don't understand...
Why didn't you say something.
Sooner...
That's right...
you should all have awaken
from this dream sooner...
this dream of gaining eternal life,
it was just a nightmare
Life comes to an end
that's why It's so precnous...
knowing it has an end makes us
work harder to make a good life...
Isn't that right...Kazuha...
The next morning,
all the people on the island
went to the pier to see Kimie off
as the Fukui Police
were taking her to the mainland,
but the sea was rough once again
and the ship took a long time
to leave the port...
It was as if the sea was unwilling
to let go of the young girl
who tried singlehandedly...
to protect the ways of her people
for 3 years...
When I called Saori the first time,
that moan I heard,
that was probably Kimie crying
She was probably crying while looking at
Saori's body in the warehouse...
But what I don't understand is
why Saori sent you a letter
addressed to me
Maybe it was just coincidence?
Why, Mr. Moufl and Hem'.!
Huh?
I know you, aren't you...
That's how we met for the first time,
on that diplomat, Mr. Tsujimura's
murder case...
That's the victim's son,
Takayoshi & his girlfriend, Yukiko...
Long time no see
Did you by chance go to Bikuni Island
because Seen contacted you?
Eh? How did you know that?
Yukiko's from that island
and Saori used to live next door,
she asked Yukiko for some advice...
I see Shinichi didn't come with you...
how disappointing, after I told her
he was the most reliable one...
So it was you!
You were behind that misleading letter...
Now I remember, I did change back
into Shinichi that one time...
By the way,
did something happen on the island?
Weflgtarrived on the island today but
everyone seemed to be in such a rush,
we just decided
to take the next ship back...
maybe it's better if you didn't know...
Why'd you pick today to come?
The festival was 2 days ago, you know
We didn't come for the festival,
we came for the seafood on this island!
It's cheap, delicious
and the scenery's great!
People are starting to talk about it!
I see...
Even without the Dugong Festival,
the island will still attract tourists then...
Guess so...
I just hope their wounds heal quickly...
ORIGINAIJ. COMIC BC!) v KS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Mlchnhlko SuWa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Kat-suo'riOno
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
MasatOm'o Sudb
STORY EDITOR
Iunlchl Iloka
Kan]: Kasfi'lwabara
Kazumrl KOUChl
Jumchl Mlyashlta
Yuu'hl Hugure
TOshlkl [DOUG
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Marsatomo Sudo
Ieotmhl Takatam
Haruo Oogawara
At'sushl Aono
Aklo Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yuklhlro Shlbutam
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashl Nomura
Ieonobu HOl'lkOShl
Takahlsa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshl Kobayashl
EDITOR.
Terumltsu Okada
CHIEF DiRE't'TOR.
Kenji Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
n associatlo'm with
Yomlun Telecas'hng Carporatlon
DETECTIVE CONAN
C Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
YTV / TMS
All Right Reserved
Hey Hem, at me see your scan!
What for?
You know why, come on...
That's the wound of love
Kazuha marked you with
Ran, what aare you saying!
Oh. . .that...
When I got up this monolog
the scar had come off
and it had already healed...
I don't believe it...
I should have stabbed you deeper...
Why you!
But I'm glad it's healed!
Now I won't have to hear you say
that I almost killed you.
Kazuha, wait up!
UUI.
You've just made me more fired up...
I'm never...
Going to let anything happen to that girl...
never...
What an actor...
I see,
ifjthe shop is doing good business.
Then the people running it
have to be there all day working...
and during that time,
the one we're looking for
would be é'lo'h'e'in thefib'flse, hiding...
Why this sounds just like the work of
the League Of the4Red Hairs!
Hcame here to see
the 'palm of the God of Fortune
What is this?!
I don't believe it 3 years old...