With a strong mind
and sharp powers of reasoning,
a keen sense of rhythm that grape
the meaning of the crime,
today's episode is a unique type
of mystery story.
Flourishing business is the entrance
to a criminal case.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in a earance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Mgeles/
Secret of Flourishing Business
Teitan Elementary'Schoolm
tin kin bcfl b': C5
A suspicious man?
Yeah.
Your family has a diner's business, right?
I know! Manpuku Diner's
The shop is dark, dirty
and because everything tastes lousy,
it's always empty!
Oh...I'm sorry.
And: in what way is that man suspicious?
He suddenly came around
2 months ago...
My name is Yuji Kamekura.
Yuji Kamekura (28)
I owe the shop owner
who passed away my gratitude...
Yuji Kamekura (28)
To my deceased husband?
What kind of gratitude?
It's something so great
that I could never express it in words.
So, in order to pay the master back,
I'm wondering if you'd let me stay here
and work for you
as a token of my gratitude, yes.
You mean you want us
to let you live here?!
W,We can't afford hiring anyone!
I'm not asking to be paid!
I just want to pay him back
for what he did for me!!
Please let me!
Okay, I've got to get to work.
So saying,
he forced his way into our house...
But, something is definitely strange!
Because grandpa who passed away,
was stingy and had a bad personality.
He would never do a favor for anybody!
I'm sure that man is up to something.
That's why
I want the Youth Detective Squad
to find out what it is!
Shoots!
L'thought it was going to be
an interesting case,
but it's nothing but a liar trying to freeload.
I smell something super fishy
that may lead to a crime!
Same here!
Idotoo!
Yes, it smells, really smells super fishy.
Ai'?!I
All right!
It's show time
for the Youth Detective Squad!
Give it all'iyouEv'é'lgot;f'.Conan,
Because I unfortunately have
other commitments.
Bye-bye!
Hey, don't walk away like that, no fair, Al!!
What?!
You mean, this is Manpuku Diners?!
So, what?
The shop's) so pretty now}.
Look at all those customers
It's because of that man...
We got'no customers at all again today...
s-usual, Aha, ha...
After all, there are loads of delicious
and nice diners so...
We can't go on like this...
Okay!
I have experience as a cook
so I'll give you special training in cooking!
And, let's renovate the shop
to make it brighter and more Cheerful
Renovate the shop. . .'?
I'll dish out all the cash
Please don't be hesitant
because all I want to
do is repay the favor!
D...the shop started doin
unbelievably good...
What's so suspicious about all that?
He dished out his own money
to renovate the shop
as a token of his gratitude, right?
He's a nice man.
I got it!!
He's going to make good business
and split after taking all the money!
Is that what the man's thinking?!
If he wants to split with the cash,
why should he help the shop
make-money, then steal it?
Wouldn't it be faster for him
,to pick eat-flourishing shop to begin with?
Oh, yeah...
Smell of a crime, my foot...
Hmm'?
Just what does that mean?
What?
Researching newnmenu.
Absolutely off-'limits, Kamekura
The man's in the room from morning
to night thinking up new menus...
He won't even let us in,
saying that it is a secret
til he completes the menu.
Rintaro!
We're busy, so if you're home,
you've got to help!
Come on, say bye-bye to your friends!
I see,
1 I  fr
If the sho ets bus
the members of the family will have to
stay at the shop all day...
In the meantime,
the one who proposed'all this
stays secretly confined to his room...
This sure sounds like the pattern of
TheuRedeeaded  League. . .'?!
It can't be...
I've got it!
I'm sure that this is the pattern
of the Red-Headed League'!
Oh, The Red-Headed League!
What's that?
The Red-Headed League" is
one of the most famous among
the 600 stories of Sherlock Holmes.
A man who sneaks into a shop
as an employee,
gets the shop owner to step out
of the shop by telling a Clever lie.
In the meantime,
he digs a tunnel underground
towards the bank in an attempt to rob it.
It is a masterpiece that describes
a very bold and bizarre crime!
Thanks for the explanation.
Butilid like to add that it was written
more than a hundred years ago.
I wonder where in the world today
you>can find a criminal so patient
who'd dig a tun'nel
in order to steal Valuables...
Huh?
W,What are you:guys doing?
we should be able to hear something.
Stop acting silly.
I'll go check it out for you!
Check it out?
Is he the one...?
What is it, Rintaro?
We're sorry to bother you
when you're busy, but...
you must be the god of fortune
because the minute you came,
the shop is so busy.
I came wanting to see what the palm
of the god of fortune looks like...
The palm of my hand?
Oh! Sure.
Go ahead and take a look at it!
T,This is!
This can't be, hey...
Hey, it was,'wasn't it?
The hand of a criminal?!
That's not what I checked for.
He had a lot of blisters
and calluses on his hand.
It's the hand of one who uses a shovel!
It's hard to believe
but I'm sure he's digging a hole
under the house!
I told you so!
You're fantastic, Mitsuhiko!
Too bad Mitsuhiko got \the credit this time.
But...
can something like this
really be happening...?
The thing is,
where is the tunnel
that he's digging headed towards!
Conan?!
Locc...
The closest bank from Manpuku Diners
is here!
fan
flfimfltttif!
Slfié
mmnmttm
same
But, it's closed.
This bank's been closed down
since a week ago
So, it can't be here.
No...
Nufuh, wrong again!
You seem to have swung at air again,
Conan.
Another place near here
that could be a target would be...
Agh! There's a jewelry shop
It's impossible for any thief
to steél "anything from our shop.
Because this place is protected
by a fail-proof security system,
thanks to a bitter experience in the past!
A bitter experience in the past?
We've been robbed before
of 3 billion yen worth of jewelry
and the robber hasn't been arrested yet...!
A jewel thief...
And the thief hasn't been arrested yet?!
Maybe this could be...?!
When were you robbed?
Next month makes it exactly 5 years ago.
I guess not, then...
A jewel thief...
and a suspicious man who is
secretly digging a hole underground...
This could be
Mitsuhiko'?
Hey. Mitsuhiko,
don't tell met that you're thinking that...
-4".
Mitsuhiko!
Well, I've got to go because I'm busy!
What were you asking her, Mitsuhiko'?
I've solved the mystery!
A man ca 9 I'. GU16 ura IS
the one who stole the jewelry
from that jewelry shop we just went to
5 years ago!
He's the jewel thief?!
Really?
I'm sure my deduction is correct
Aha, ha...l thought so.
But, that deduction's a bit too farfetched!
However, the thief is no dunce!
If he sells the loot immediately,
he'll be caught,
and it would also be too risky
to keep the loot with him right through.
Therefore,
he buried the loot somewhere
right after he stole it, for the time being!
He happened to bury the loot
right under Rintaro's house
that was being re-built back then!
The house was being re-built...?
Oh, so that's what you were asking
the lady a while ago!
Right!
So, Kamekura forced his way
into the house as a live-in employee,
in order to gradually dig out the loot.
Wow, Mitsuhiko, you're awesome!
What a perfect deduction!
I mean, it's not'that much of a big deal.
No need to be shy, renown detective! But,
I was thinking élong the same line too.
Why would he want to dig it out now,
after leaving it buried for 5 years?
Fuh! Don't you get it, Conan?
He was waiting for the statute to expire.
The period of prescription expires
in 5 years.
Which means he can soon
hold his head up high and sell the loot off.
That only goes for criminal cases!
The period of expiration for civil affairs
is 20 years!
Which means
even if he digs it out now,
he won't be able to own the jewelry.
Ha,ha,ha...!
We don't know of such complicated rules.
If we don't know about it,
I'm sure the thief doen't either.
H,Hey...
You're just argumentative by nature,
aren't you Conan.
Mom always tells me
that it's important for people
to accept things without argument.
That's not the point...
Let's go tell the police
that he's actually a jewelry thief!
Don't! There's no evidence!
You'll just end up
embarrassing yourselves!
Shoots, okay.
All we've got to do is
catch him in the act, right!
jiJst what'do you intend to do?
I'm going to set up a trap!!
A trap...?! Hey...
(),
Oh, it's you...
You want to see my palm again?
We know about everything!
W,What'?!
You can't deceive the eyes of
we the Youth Detective Squad!
Good-bye!
Good - bye!
'BU""
Qt? x
G,Good-bye.
So, now all we do is
wait for him to fall for it.
What kind of trap
is that supposed to be
He'll anic etflustered
And commit himself right away, for sure!
Sure!
It's perfect!
Where in the world
woula there be an adfllt
whd'd panic just 'cuz
some grade schooler takes a jab at him
The following morning
What?!
YoUr'fwfiole familylis going{
on a 1 night 2 days hot spring trlp?
Yeah,
Mr. Kamekura suddenly recommended
father and the others to take a trlp!
He said that we should go on 3 mp
and relax
since we haven't had a day of rest
after the shop started getting busy.
And of course
Mr. Kamekura's not going, right?
Right,
he says just our family should go
and enjoy ourselves.
He's making the entire family
Ieave the house
and then is planning
to dig it out all at once!
I'm sure that's it!
Like I told you, Conan,
he fell right for the trap
and started making his move!
It can't be...
Can this really be happening?!
I don't have the slightest idea
what's going on
You seem to be completely lost.
Well,
where in the world are there criminals
that will make moves
Just because they're pushed from behind
by a bunch of grade school kids!
And, there are other things
that I donlt get either,
Iike...
Conan,
Maybe the man you're dealing with is
very different from the criminals
that you've handled so far.
In what way?
He's an unsophisticated person.
It's even harder to understand!
Conan seems to have lost
a lot of confidence.
Yeah, he's so off this time.
I hope he doesn't get sulky
and become a juvenile delinquent!
It's possible.
That doesn't sound good at all...
Temporary Closure
Are you sure
you don't want to come along?
No, because a friend of mine
has been bugging me
to spend the night at his place.
Have a nice trlp!
In the past, going on a trip to a hot spring
was unthinkable, even for a day.
This is all thanks to the business flourishing.
Rather, to Mr. Kamekura.
I'm really glad
that such a good man has come.
Okay, everyone's left!
Now, all we have to do is
wait for Mr. Kamekura to come home!
Are you going to wait one whole night
if he doesn't come back...!
What are you going to tell your parents?
Agh! He's back
So, we go in there when the time is right
and use this key
that I borrowed from Rintaro to go inside,
and catch Kamekura in the act!
Conan, you're not your spirited self.
I've been digging day after day,
but I haven't seen a glimpse of anything...
I shouldn't have buried it so deep
ASH?!
There it is!!
I did it!!
I did it, the loot, the loot!
Wow!
That's it, mister!
Huh?! Whaaaaa!
We have clearly confirmed the jewelry
that had been buried.
I'm sorry.
Oh, uh, well, we're not the police...
Come on, Conan...
Huh? Come on, what?
Aren't you going to thrust your deduction
at the criminal?!
We'll let you have the best part.
Because you had no room
for highlight this time!
I've got nothing to thrust at him!
Come, get on with it!
Give it your best shot, Conan!
Mr. Kamekura,
5 years ago, you broke into a jewelry shop
and stole 3 billion yen worth of jewelry...
Exactly.
See, he admits it.
But, I'm no dunce.
I knew that if I'soldathem off right away,
I would be caught,
I had my eyes fixed
on the re-building construction
that was underway.
I buried the jewelry under the floor
and fled...
Then, I worked day after day
so the police wouldn't suspect me.
I endured everything,
being shouted at, being hit and all.
All my friends
couldn't bear the apprenticeship
and quit one after the other.
But I stuck it out!
Thinking, 5 years...
after 5 years the 3 billion yen worth
of jewelry will be mine...
This was what had't'ept me going
through all the tough times.
And, finally the 5 years that I've waited
for all this time had come!
I just couldn't wait till the time expired,
I just had to dig it up as soon as possible!
You figured that if you worked here
as a live-in employee,
you'd have the chance to dig it out...
But, it didn't go that easily...
Since there were no customers,
the shop was always slow
and the members of the family were
always rolling around on the floor.
If this keeps up you'll never get around
to digging up the loot...
Having no other choice,
you renovated the shop
with the money you had saved working,
taught them the cooking
that you had learned
under apprenticeship,
and by making business flourish,
you succeeded in
chasing the entire family
out of the living room.
You were finally able to work
on digging up the jewelry
that you buried.
Isn't that right, Mr. Yuji Kamekura?
It's exactly as you say.
Ithoughtso!
Our deduction was right on the ball!
I just can't figure it out, please tell me!
Why did you rush to dig it up,
Just because
a bunch of grade school kids
pushed you from behind?!
I'm really chicken...
Even if you're only inf grade school,
the minute I heard that you guys were
the detective squad, I got scared...
I see.
What's there to be afraid of!
An adult being afraid of a detective squad
of a bunch of kids!!
If you had thought up sending them off
to a hot spring trlp,
why didn't you carry it out
in the first place!
Huh?
It would've been faster, cheaper
and easier
if you just gave them a voucher for 3 mp
and send the whole family off,
than to go out of your way,
dish cash out of your own pocket,
renovate the shop, and help it flourish
Oh, that's true.
That's right!
I guess so, now that you mentioned it.
You guess so...
It never even dawned on me...
What...?!
I guess the case is closed...
Al?!
Convinced?
Didn't I tell you that
the person you're dealing with this time
is unsophisticated.
They've come. I called them...
I wonder if they'll award us
with the Tokyo Police Commissioner Award?
It would be nice if they did.
Sure would.
I'm pretty sure they will.
After all, you've carried out
fantastic good deed, eheh, heh...
You do?
I hate this...
I don't feel a least bit good
even after the case is solved...
I hate it!!!
Gosho Aoya'ma
PRODUCERS
Mlchlhlko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
K1t'su05Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
MasatO'i'fi'n Sudo
STORY EDITOR.
Jun'lchl lloka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashlwabara
K'lzunan Kouchl
Jumchl Mlyashlta
YUIChl Hugure
Toshlkl Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Misatomo Sudo
Hirotoshl Takatam
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushl Aono
Akuo Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yuk'lhlro Shlbutanl
Takashl Nomura
Ieonobu Horlkoshl
Takahlsa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashl
EDITOR.
Terumltsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]! Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomlurl Teleca'stmg CO'rpora'tlon
DETECTIVE CONAN
OGosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
YTV / TMS
All Right Reserved
We received a letter offathanks award
.from the police
for cooperating in the arrest
of a jewelry'thief
Just before his duration of prescription
was about to expire...
We did it, didn't we!
It was really easy this time!
Uh, I've got something
I'd like to tell you guys.
HUD.
Not all the criminals are going to be
a fool like this one, you know!
It's dangerous just barging in,
Just us kids!
Be more careful next time, understand!
HUD?
You sure don't sound like your usual self,
Conan!
Conan, so you're that vexed
that we got the upper hand this time?
Genta! Don't talk like that
because Conan is hurt!
Conan, cheer up.
I'm so sorry, Conan. That's a good boy...
You idiot!!
I'm a specialist-of. decent crimes
where brains clash against brains
and em spams.
H, He's dead.