With a strong mind & sharp powers
of reasoning,
a keen sense of rhythm that enables one
to grasp the inner meaning of the crime
He sees through the one & only tnuth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Battle Game Trap- Part I
Aha!
Oh no!!
This IS great
Now "know why this one's your favorite,
Sonbko
See, I told you!
And it's far from our school
so nobody knows about it
Hahaha.
Oh, look!
There's a wedding version too!
I don't believe it...
it wasn't here yesterday...
Let's have a look!
Wow...
Gee, 'I"'think this-'T'one's so cute'! (g
Why don't the 3 of us
get our pictures taken here?
Eh!?
Oh no...wait, wait, just wait a minute!
Uh, maybe it would be better to take
separate pictures sometimes,
you know, for a change of pace
Sonoko
Confess Sonoko,
you're going to write a letter
to Mr. Kyogoku
and stick your picture on it, arenit you?
Why just a few days ago,
Mr. Arade was reading
a fan letter from one of the girls
and he asked if sticking your photo
onto the letters was the current trend...
Uh, listen, Ran...
I think you're about the only one
ho isn't doing it...
Really?
Boy! Mr Arade has it rough doesn't he...
He thought he could just relax
when he was relieved
as coach for the basketball team,
but now
he's in charge of the drama club...
But I guess that can't be helped,
since that handsome Shinichi's
not around anymore,
all the girls are chasing Mr. Arade...
That's not completely true.
Jody, the new English teacher
is pretty popular too!
Only among the guys though
She's always wearing such se\ Clothes
and excreting pheromone,
I think
she thinks Japanese men are idiots!
Haha. . .look who's talking,
you always wear clothes
that show your belly button...
But she explains everything simply
and she's easy to understand!
She's just too serious, she's no fun!
She's always so quiet and proper,
after class, when we ask her
to join us for refreshments,
she always turns us down...
She acts like
she's a very well bred daughter
of some blue blood family...
I mean, she's the first American I know,
I expected her to be more outgoing and...
Hey! Come on!!
You're Miss Jody,
our teacher aren't you...
What are you doing in a place like this...
Oh! Miss Mouri & Miss SUZUKI!
Eh? A teacher?
Hey! Isn't that Teitan High's uniform?
Which means you're
a high school teacher?
Oh for goodness sakes!
No, no, you've made a mistake!
What!?
You've been coming here
every day after school!'?
You, Miss Jody!?
Yes!
The games here in Japan are
so very beautiful & exciting!
Of course the games that come to the US
from Japan are very popular too!
Jody Santemillion (28)
English Txe'a'éher
Of course the games that come to the US
from Japan are very popular too!
Jody Santemillion (28)
English 'Iieacher
JdTfl'V/Ji'J/J/ KO}
There's always such a long, long line,
I never get to play!
That's why I became an English teacher
That way,
I can play the newest games everyday!
She, she's a gamer...
You, you mean; yourle'ssons,
they're so textbook because...
Yes!
Because if I make a mistake & get fired,
it'd be, The End!
It's very, very hard for foreigners
to get jobs in Japan
That's why you mustn't tell anyone
I was here!
Please keep it as our secret!
OK, but you sure looked good!
That's right!
You reminded me of Billy the Kid!
If you think that was neat,
want to try another great game?
It's the most popular fighting game
in town now!
Hmm, I've never heard of this one...
Me too...
Just sit, go on!
First, put the headgear on
Insert a coin & stand by!
Play character" is beginner level
HUN?
What the...
Hey!
Are you ready?
When the right punch comes in lightly, go!
Oh, OK!
Ready. . .Go!!
Yikes!
O'C'ST!
Ouch, that hurt!
Ram?
That's right,
this is a virtual reality fighting game,
the player actually feels the damage!
Is it too much for a girl to handle?
Eeek! Ran, no, come on!
Go forward!
Oh come on!
You Win!
You did it!
She may not look it,
but Ran won first place in the State karate
championship tournament!
Oh! Champ
I§,ll"kill you!
What's this?
Someone's entered the game
But why, how?
Another player...
Another player's challenging you...
Eh'? I don't believe it...
Be careful
He is terrific.
He's beatable though...
Fight
Wha, what the...
You lose!
Now that you've lost,
why don't you just get out of chair,
That gold seat
Kengo Bitou (21)
Unemployed
is reserved for me & me alone...
Kengo Bitou (21)
Unemployed
What are you talking about!'?
Ran!
Stay in that seat & try again,
it's payback, it's payback!
You're just wasting your time...
Eh!?
Besides the punch & kick mode,
he can manipulate all 4 control buttons
and create an undefeatable attack.
Today's the first time
you've ever tried the game,
Hitoshi Dejima (22)
Store Worker
you don't stand a chance of winning
Hitoshi Dejima (22)
Store Worker
Hmmmm
Hmmm
Hurry up!
What's taking you so long?
Yes sir, this seat's built just for me!
What a creep,
who is he anyway?
He's known as The Shisa of Beika
and it's gone to his head(
but he's just your neighborhood hoodlum.
He's been getting cockier lately
ToshitSuguaEmori (141)
Taxi Driver
2:1,
Toshitsugu Emori (41)
Tax: Driver
sway-ma?
& making things hard for the rest of us...
Toshitsugu Emori (41)
Taxi Driver
973-'335
Oh, and by the way miss...
your moves are bug
It may be called fighting,
but it's only a game
you don"t need strength.
See, watch him.
His movements are small,
he doesn't even look like he s fighting,
does he?
Uh, you were watching?
You watched us fight?
That's right,
on that big monitor...
There's usually a tape playing on it,
but when a challenge is made,
the game's shown.
I figure the only person
who can beat him...
Haido City's invincible...
Lutus from Haldo...
I'm the only one, right?
Takayasu Shimizu (30)
Game Magazine Writer
wk 51? (30)
7-14323549
Takayasu Shimizu (30)
Game Magazine Writer
Elk Efi (30)
1.1313549
Takayasu Shlmizu (30)
Game Magazine Writer
bin-£549
Takayasu Shimizu (30)
Game Magazine Writer
57K 331? (30)
Nub/w I
Yo, I've been waiting for you, brother!
Let's continue our fight
Give me a second...
Iet me smoke a cigarette first
Miss Jody, éome on,.
Let's get out of this place
Why?
She's right,
this isn't the only game arcade...
Alright but this racing game!
Let me do it one more time!
Good rief...
Goodness...
Wow, you're good!
Do it!!
I bet you're going to be the high scorer!
Phew...
she's a true blue gamer all right...
Fight?!
Those 2 have started to fight!
Forget about those two...
But it looks...
What a barrage...
Wow...
Eh? Who's winning?
There's no hit point gauge on that thing...
I think the more damage you suffer,
the bluer your face gets...
The guy who beat me is winning so far .
Hmmm
Wow.
Again...
Wow...
Down!
Wow,
that special combination rheélly'did the job.
That Lutus from Haido's not so hot.
I don't think he can get up...
he's gonna deliver the finishing touch
before he gets up...
Hey, what's he doing...
He's got to finish him off quick,
time's running out!
Wham?
Oh brother what a dummy
It would've been an easy win
if he'd finished him off right then...
Hey...
something's wrong...
dead.
He died while playing a game?
Are you sure about that?
Oh yes
We were all watching their game
on the monitor...
He was on the verge of winning
and then all of a sudden,
hegstopped attacking.
And when we looked...
The man working the character
had stopped too, eh...
The deceased vs Kengo BRO,
21 years old,
presently unemployed
He is by nature quite rude
and his reputation at this arcade
isn't good.
I see,
so he was a man with many enemies...
Miss Mouri, do you know this man?
Yes...
he's my father's former boss...
Huh?
Oh, this is our school's English teacher!
English teacher?
Yes!
My name is Jody Santemillion!
( Lim'rpleas'ed» to meet you!
My name is Jozo Megure!
I am a Japanese policyman!
Policy?
Not policyman!
Policeman!
Po, poleeecemaan?
No,no,no.
Policeman, OK?
Pholeecemyan...
Uh, Inspector...
Ahem,
yes, the question is
why did he die during the game?
'Co...
We questioned the other customers,
no one noticed anyone suspicious
wandering around.
And it doesn't appear like Mr. Bito drank
or ate anything while he was playing,
so that rules out suicide...
what's with this et-u an we
It Iodks'like
something from a science fiction movie.
It's a virtual reality game...
The damage'i'nfllic't'ed by your opponent
shows on screen
and at the' same time,
the player feels it too.
The player feels the damage?
And on top of that,
if your opponent hits
or lekS you from over the guards,
the other player feels a slight sensation
in the arm or leg
so it seems like you're actually in a fight...
Hey waitfta minute, yo'ui'd'on't mean
that's what killed him...
The damage was too much,
he couldn't take it
h, no...
That would never happen.
All you feel is a Ilght vibration.
You know, like the vibration mode
on those cellular phones.
You can't kill someone
with only that much, can you?
And who are you?
I'm the guy that fellow
was playing against just before he died.
I thought I'd better come over before
you make me out to be the murderer...
Besides, I don't like to admit this but
I'm the one who was taking the beating.
I only got a couple of punches in.
And I was even chewing gum
to help my rhythmn, but it didn't help.
Is that true?
Yes...it did seem like
he was taking the brunt of the beating...
Hmm...
then what could have killed him...
Yes ..and there doesn't
seem to be any wound...
Maybe it was poison!
See, this man looks like he died of
suffocation,
but it doesn't look like he was strangled!
It would have to be poison, wouldn't it?
But Conan, this man died
while he was playing a game
and there's no indication he ate
or drank anything
Now, if he had been poisoned
before the game,
he would have looked sick or
at least felt sick, isn't that right?
Did you notice anything like that?
Uh, no
I didn't notice anything...
Just before that game, he was very
actively giving Ran a good beating...
But if you put the poison
in a syringe & inject it...
Hahaha.
If som'eéh'e tried to do that,
he would have gotten angry & yelled.
And th'e 'other customers
would Have heard "that...
Hmmmm, you're-right...
Hmmmm, you're right...
Of course I am!
But Inspector, have you forgotten?
ThlS is a game arcade, isn't it'?
All the machines are off now
& everything's quiet, but usually
the place is filled with all kinds of sounds,
it's so noisy,
you can't even hear yourself talk!
And this man's arms & legs
are attached to the machine,
I don't think he could have moved
very well.
And these arcades are kept kind of dark
so that the screens are easier to see...
I see,
the victim was practically unprotected &
even if he yelled,
all the noise would have drowned
out his voice...
And in the dark room,
with most of the other customers
watching the monitor,
is would be possible to poison him...
All right then, let's have the body taken
to the coroner's for an autopsy!
Our first objective is to
determine the cause offideath!
Yes sir!
Uh huh...
Now to narrow down the list of suspects,
It s going to be qunte a job,
finding the killer among the nearly
30 people who were here.
I know who went close
to the man who died!
We were sitting right next to him
until just before he died,
we were watching Miss Jody do that
racing game.
Right?
Yes...
And then? Who went close to him...
That boy who works here!
And that tall boy!
And including the 4 of us, that makes 6...
Isn't that right, Miss Jody?
Yes, but this little boy isn't the only one
who was watching everything!
Eh'?
He's the other one...
A security camera
By chance, would everything be on that
camera?
Uh, sure...
Then can we Viewflm'xght aw av
along with the 6 others?
Of course...
Right away!
Follow me...
Will you all please come along?
What's that?
What 3 making this sound?
It sounds like something metal is hitting
something...
Luke it's rubbing something...
What Is it!?
Here it is! Around here.
The victim took his seat at about...
See, there we are getting
chased out of our seats
Isn't that you, Mr. Dejima?
What were you doing?
I was collecting the money
from the machines.
I see
Oh? Now it's Mr. Shimizu...you two
seem to be having a conversation...
What were you talking about?
Before the game, I wanted to see
if I could get him to tell me his strategy...
but it was no use.
What's this?
What d he crouch for & pick up?
I dropped my lighter &
was just picking it up.
And then the game started...
Uh, Inspector!
Mr. Dejima is...
He's holding something in his hand?
A Video?
Is that what it is?
Yes, it was such a great game,
Ithoughtrdtapeit
Hey, don't I know you from some place?
No, you're probably mistaken.
Wow, you're right,
it really is something.
The blows keep coming.
Huh?
Ran, it looks like you & your friends
Ieft the racing game partway through.
Yes, the fight was so exciting,
we started to watch that.
What you're saying is,
Miss Jody & the victim were left alone...
But I was very busy playing the game.
I di'dnit even notice everyone-he'd left!
But still,
unless someone verifies your story...
It's true, Miss Jody never left her game!
Whpn we ran up to the body,
she had just reached the goal &
her score was the highest écore'tef/er!
I"IICI'I"DI,'IC.ILD III LIIC LAUGH...
that racing game's not easy
no one can score the highest score
unlessfltheyfi'concentrate &
keepatheirih'a'hds on the wheel.
Hmm...then who killed him...
Hey, what is this!
This man who just came out
from behind the victim...
Who In the world is that guy"?
Oh isn't that the man
who'awas playing mahjong?
Yes!
That's the man who was bad mouthing
the man who died!
What!?
Bring this man here right now!!
Yes sir!!
Judg'i'nO'*'ifi'om the condition of the body,
I'm posntl e he was poisoned...
That makes that? p'érsfion
the most suspicious...
and I'm sure there is evidence inside that.
Now about the needle
or hypodermic syringe...
nothing like that was on the floor...
I doubt the killer would still
be holding on to it...
Where...
where did the killer hide the weapon...
Gosho Aoya'ma
PRODUCERS.
Muchlhlko Suwa
M'asahlto Yoshloka
BAGKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STQRY EDITOR
Jumchl lloka
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunan Kouchl
Jumchl Mlyashlta
YUIChl Hloure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Ieotoshl Takatanl
Haruo Oogawara
A'tsushl Aono
A'klO Kawamura
Takashl Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yuklhlro Shlbutanl
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashl Nomura
Huronobu Horlkoshl
Takahlsa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshu Kobayashu
EDITOR
Terumltsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY.
TMS Efi'te'rtalnment, Ltd
m association with
Yomiuri Telecastl'rrg Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
OGoshoAoyama / Shogakukan
YTV / TMS
All Rights Reserved
The poison was injected
under Bito's arm, right?
I don't think he'd let me stick him.
That was a great story but it's a trap,
IHNelady
That girl playing the racing game
next to Bito was the only one, wasn't she?
Inspector, haven't you noticed?
That strange sound he makes
when he walks...
(ffifi)
LII: