With a strong mind & sharp powers
of reasoning,
a keen sense of rhythm that enables one
to grasp the inner meaning of the crime.
He sees through the one & only truth.
A child in a earance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Ng Beach/m 'TTgeles/San Die
thAngeleslsarf legd
Ran, Sonoko & I were at a game arcede
getting our photo sticker's made,
that's when we run into
Jody Santemillion, an English teacher
at Teitan High School,
deeply engrossed in a shooting game.
At her insistence,
Ran is set to compete in a fighting game
against a skilled gamer
named Kengo Bito
who beats her in no time at all.
But during the game
with his next opponent,
Mr. Bito ends up getting killed!
There are 4 suspects.
Mr. Bito's opponent, Takakazu Shimizu,
the game arcade attendant,
Hisashi Dejima,
a taxi driver, Toshitsugu Emorl,
and Jody Santemillion.
Ju'dgihgfifnom the Eondiition of the body,
I'm positive he was poisoned...
Which means,
that person is the most suspicious.
And the evidence is probably in there.
All that leaves is the needle or
hypodermic syringe...
nothing like that Was on the-floor...
and I doubt the killer would still
be hanging on to something like that...
Where...
where'd the killer hide
the murder weapon!?
I was picking up a 100 yen coin...
I was going to go get a can of coffee
from the vending machine in the back
Toshitsugu Emori (41)
Taxi Cab Driver
5&2!».
bu dropped the come. on the floor...
Toshitsugu Emori (41)
Taxi Cab Driver
5h!!-
979-1535
bun dropped the come. on the floor...
Sure, he was a creep but I respected
his skills as a gamer.
Oh, surex ou did...
he saw you make a mistake
when you played that racing game
and he made a fool out you
in front of everybody.
Is that true?
It sure is!
Takayasu Shimizu (30)
Game Magazine Writer
It sure is!
Takayasu Shimizu (30)
Game Magazine Writer
37x ERG)
Lxfifi'i 49
He yelled out You'd better not get in
this guy's cab unless you want to die!
Takayasu Shimizu (30)
Game Magazme Writer
'U 157
fix EfiGO)
He yelled out You'd better not get in
this guy's cab unless you want to die!
Humph!
Well, you had a stronger motive
to kill him!
After all, that guy was your precious
baby sister's boyfriend...
His sister's boyfriend?
They were living together,
or you could say, he was living off of her...
but I guess he can't complain,
he's her brother
and he's a gamer too,
jUSt like that guy was...
And kid, what about you?
You wanted him out of the way too,
didn't you?
What do you mean?
Up until 6 months ago, that kid was called
Hitoshi Deshima (22)
Arcade Attendant
The Battler of Beika, he had a pretty
good reputation himself as a gamer.
Hitoshi Deshima (22)
Arcade Attendant
The Battler of Beika, he had a pretty
good reputation himself as a gamer.
That was until that guy came along &
thrashed him,
then he dropped out of sight
Who would've thought he'd
change his hairstyle
and start working part time
in a game arcade...
Inspector!
They found poison in the victim's blood!
What!?
The name of the poison is tetrodotoxin!
The point of e'n'tn was the inside of
his upper righ'tiriarm
and it appears the penetration
went up to the artery
Te, tetrodotoxin, that's...
Puffer fish poison!!
Tetrodotoxin, commonly called TTX.
0.5-1 mg would cause instant death,
that's 11500th the amount needed
for a deadly dose of potassium cyanide,
it's a crazy poison...
it is found in most puffer fish.
But when ingested by mouth,
the symptoms progress slowly
and the rate of survival is quite high.
When directly introduced unto the
bloodstream, paralysis sets in quickly
The End"...
M, Miss Jody?
My friend, who's a doctor told me!
Jody Santemillion (28)
English Teacher
My friend, who's a doctor told me!
Jody Santemillion (28)
English Teacher
1374-3756 JZ"! (28)
fiflfifiéalfiafi
When I was coming to Japan,
I was warned about eating puffer fish!
Jody Santemillion (28)
English Teacher
737446355 YD Km
MC, C5 Au 88:5 b
Hififiifiliflgfli
When I was coming to Japan,
I was warned about eating puffer fish!
Jody Santemillion (28)
English Teacher
I knew it...
Now to find where the weapon is hidden...
At any rate,
Iet's go back to the scene of the crime
and go over everything one more time!
Ye ism!
I hope you'll all cooperate!
Sune...
Huh?
There it is again...it's that sound...
What could it be...
Hey, the shoe lace on your left shoe
is coming loose!
Oh, thanks kid...
it's dangerous, you could've tripped
That's who it is...
that's who killed Mr. Bito...
the distinct features of these arcades
were used to commit the murder...
But oneithing bothers me...
Why'd that person deliberately do that
in front of the police...
Conan...
What's the matter, Conan?
Come on, hurry!
Oh, yeah!
PW'! U" ll H1! H
Inspector!
We've searched this floor
from top to bottom
but we haven't come up with anything
needle like
that could've been the weapon.
Hmm...
according to the video from
the security camera,
none of the suspects left this floor
until the police arrived...
Chances are high the killer still has
the weapon, don't you think?
Yes...
We'll be taking you all into
another room for a body check.
Humph!
I'll answer all of your questions,
anything you want,
but don't you think you're making
a mistake by suspecting me?
He died while playing against me.
I didn't have a chance to poison hum.
Well that goes for me too.
I went up to Mr. Bito
before the game started to collect
the coins in the machine, that's all...
If you're going to do a body check,
you should check Mr. Emorl,
during the game,
he was close to the machine when
he was picking up the coin he dropped.
Only that lady was next to Mr. Bito
playing her racing game
Hey wait a minute!
What are you talking about!
Miss'Jody was playing the game the
whole time, she couldn't have stopped!
Right?
Right!
No mistake about it!
Besides,
the inspection of the scene just now
proved that, didn't it?
When you're sitting here
See!
Your hands don't reach the chair
next to you!
I don't think she could have done it, but...
Hmm .
Let me say something now.
The poison was injected
under Bito's right arm, wasn't it?
Ircame up from his left side,
I couldn't have done it, now could I'?
Everybody just calm down.
This is just a formalix ,
so please cooperate...
Sonoko, what's wrong?
Good grief, how disappointing
Inspector Megure, what's up with you...
Huh?
WThe killer's right in front of you,
smiling & you haven't caught on yet...
Wham?
The poison's point of entry was
the inside of his upper right arm.
As Mr Emori himself pointed out,
he couldn't have done it because the only
time he came in contact with the victim,
he was on the left.
We can also cross Mr. Dejima out
since he came in contact with the victim
before the game started
and after that the victim was seen
talking to Mr. Shimizu
And of course,
Miss Jody was busy playing her game
and we were on the opposite side
of the victim,
so none of us could have done it either...
Then that only leaves...
That's right.
Only 1 person remains...
You're the only one who could've done it!!
"Fih'at '3 fight.
on'h 1 pférgson remains...
You're the onl. one who could've done it!
Takayasu Shimizu...
You're the only one!
Haha.
Younglady,
do you know what you're saying...
you watched the video, didn't you?
You saw me getting beaten in the game
How could I have poisoned him
in the midst of all that?
Heh heh...
no use acting innocent.
You'll see how easy it is when
we demonstrate!
What!?
Ran & Detective Takagl!
I hate to ask but will you play that game?
Huh?
The answer will come to you right away
when you do it
NARNING-
ALL RIGHT RESERVED:No PART OF THIS VIDEO GAME
Y BE REPRODUCED OR TRANSMITTED BY ANY
MEANS, ELECTRON KL, PHOTOGOPVING
MINING-
q r100": no.
V BE REPRODUCED OK TRANSHII It!) BY ANY
Are you going to allow this?
Is the police going to take orders
from a young girl?
Well, you may not know it
bUthonoko 3 pretty sharp...
It's starting!
Fight!
Wow, that girl's getting a total beating
Hey Takagi, go easy on her.
Oh no!
Oh oh...the irl's had it...
Poor thing1
Ta,. Takagl!
I know how much you hate to lose but
don't you'think you went overboard here,
just a little too much?
Sonoko told me to tell Detective Takagl
what to do
She said he would be the girl character
and that he had to blindfold himself
with his necktie
and not do an thin durin the ame,
just go limp!
Then the one controlling
the male character was.
It was me!
Sonoko told me to...
Isn't that ri ht, Conan?
Yup!
You mean!?
That's right...
preconceived notion...
Everyone would assume Ran .,
would be the female character
and Detective Takagi the male, correct?
But it was actually the opposite...
jUSt like it was before...
Mr. Bito is Beika's Shisa"
Mr.Shimizu is Haido's Lutus",
everyone assumed
they'd use their own characters.
And on top of that,
this game has no hit point gauge
so no one can tell who is which character
Just by watching the monitor...
Nobody would notice if they switched
Are you saying Mr. Site was killed
before the game started...
IUD...
Mr. Shimizu had already injected him
and he was either dead
or the poison was just starting to take
effect & he was semi-conscious
Tetrodotoxin causes paralysis...
even if Mr. Bito was
alive during the game,
it would have been difficult for him
to sit up straight.
But if that were the case,
someone was bound
to notice something was wrong...
No, that's not necessarily true!
I let my body 90 limp but everytime
I took a hit,
my arms & legs would move a little
so unless
someone was watching very closely,
it would look like I was playing the game!
And besides, these guards would keep
his body propped up
so he wouldn't fall.
This is how Mr. Shimizu did it!
Before the game starts
he goes up to Mr. BRO
and injects him with the poison,
while Mr Bito is struggling,
he finishes the game he's in the midst of.
And then starts the new game with
the new character,
hrs. character, Lutus'.!
Then all he has to do is
go to another machine
and enter the game as Mr. Bito's
character, Shisa & he's set!
Then you deliver a series of blows
to an unmoving opponent
and everyone thinks
you're getting beat up, right?
But why didn'tche deliver-the finishing
blow at the end of the game?
Because if he had & someone
ran up to MrBito,
they (3 see the words You Lose
on his machine when in fact he had won.
If they ended in a draw, Draw would
appear on the screen!
And in a draw,
the game comes to an immediate end!
The character Mr. Bito used
would remain unknown...
What about the weapon?
If what you're saying ls true, girlie,
it should be around some place,
shouldn't it?
Where's the needle or syringe?
That's why we're going to do
a body check...
Humph!
Search all you want but if you don't find it,
you're going to be in
a whole lot of trouble...
Of course we won't find it!
You don't have the weapon
on you anymore...
but, I bet you didn't notice...
A certain something has been
following you around...
What do you mean!?
Mr. Dejima, could/you please come here?
Why, sure...
What is it?
That's fine, you can go back...
Okay.
What was that all about?
Didn't you notice It, Inspector?
Every time he takes a step,
you can hear a strange sound,
Iike metal scratching something...
What!?
Huh?
You mean it's on the bottom of his shoe?
Yes...Mr. Shimizu,
put the used needle inside a cigarette
then stuck some gum to it
and then put it on top of
the gum wrapping paper
and left it on the floor.
Someone would step on it while they were
watching the game on the monitor
and then the evidence would be carried
to another location, that was the idea!
And it was done,
when he bent down to pick up
the lighter he dropped...
If the cigarette is flattened, you wouldn't
really notice if when you stepped on it
And even if you did notice
you'd just think it was rubbish
& throw it in the trash bin.
I suppose we'll just have to rely on
Mr. Shimizu's good conscience
to see whether he wiped the poison off
the needle before he got rid of it...
Heh heh...
He prepared the cigarette trick
before the crime...
probably in the toilet of this arcade.
All he had to do was roll up the paper
& put it into the box of cigarettes
then when he took it out,
it wouldn't look suspicious...
I see.
So if we find Mr. Shimizu's fingerprints
on this cigarette or paper,
then we'll have the proof we need...
Humph!
I must commend you,
that was one terrific story...
but unfortunatel irlie, this is a tra
Take a look!
Both the gum & the cigarette
aren't my brand
Let me see!
Sure...
I'm sure somebody's trying to frame me!
We. a we known fact the chew on
gum during the game to keep rhythmn,
it was even written in a magazine...
Check if you don't believe me,
you're not going to find
my fingerprint on anything!
Aha...now I understand!
That's what bothered me all along
I couldn't understand why you would
chew gum in front of the police
when you used gum to hide the weapon!
I'll bet you used someone else's gum
and cigarette from the ashtrays
in this arcade.
You chewed gum so that just in case
the needle was found,
you could use the excuse you just used.
You used the preconceived notion
th'atsnoicriminal would
deliberately incriminate himself,
to your own advantage...
But wouldn't his fingerprints be left
behind when her-injected the victim?
No, if the needle was placed
between his fingers,
it would be possible to commit the crime
& not leave any finger or palmprint!
That's right!
If you were to push the bottom of the
cigarette box, the cigarette would come up
and you could take it out
between your fingers without
getting your fingerprint on it.
But. . .what about a com?
Mr. Dejima'? Could you please open up
the coin box on that machine?
Yes ma'am...
There should be two 100 yen coins
in there if his story is true, right?
Because before Mr. Bito
started the game,
Mr. Dejima had collected
the coins already...
But I'm sure you'll find 3 coins in there!
Hey! She's right
There's 3 in here!
You're right...
1 of them is-the coin Mr. Bito put in
to start the game...
another will be Detective Takagi's,
he just finished his game...
& the last one is the coin the killer put in
when he started the camouflage game.
Ll f-
That's right...
Mr. Shimizu,
your fingerprints should be all over that
100 yen coin.
But we won't know until
we have it analyzed...
Sure we do...
the coins were collected
before Mr. Shimizu got here...
He probably thought
it wouldn't pose a problem
if a coin with his fingerprint was found
in a mountain of other coins...
Anothe'rrthing', unless he wore gloves,
he wouldn't be able to drop the coin in
without getting his fingerprint on it...
You'll find them...
my fingerprints are on it...
I had a tight grip on it
when I dropped it in...
That's because I intended that
to be my last game...
Your last game?
Yeah...
I intended to bid farewell to these games
as well as to that guy...
it was for my sister's sake,
she's in the hospital, almost blind...
Almost blind?
Do you now how she got that way?
Vitamin A deficiency due to malnutrition...
Haha.
Can you imagine, in this day & age...
That guy's gambling debts were so high
and my sister was working like crazy
this past month
trying to repay those debts,
she hardly ate anything...
But after an he put [her through,
she still refused to break up with him...
I don't know how\ ou could Have played
games with someone like that.
He told me that
if I won just 1 game against him,
he'd leave my sister alone.
I pratioed & got good enough
to be called Lutus of Haido, but...
I just couldn't beat him...
so you-killed him?
IUD...
but you know, Inspector...l regret it now...
That unbeatable character
he controlled, Shisa,
I destroyed my chance
to beat it with my own hands...
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Mlchlhlko Suwa 4
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER-DESIGNS BY.
Ma 53 tomb Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Jumchu lloka
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunan Kouchl
Junlchl Mlyashlta
YUIChl ngure
Toshikl lnoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hurotoshl Takatam
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
AklO Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yuklhlro Shlbutam
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashl Nomura
Ieonobu HDruk'oshu
Takahlsa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashl
EDITOR
Terumltsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY.
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
m assocnatlon with
Yomlurl Teleca'stmg Corporation
OGosho Aoyama / Shggakuka'n
All Rights Reserved
Oh! Sonoko, you were terrific, good job!!
Sonoko, you were great!
You were just like Kate Martinelli!!
Kate, who?
Oh that, famous female police officer
in the United States...
It's true,
even Shinichi would've been impressed!
ShiniChl?
Ah, the boy who appeared
at the school festival!
He is so cool!
Oh I wouldn't say that...
all he thinks of is solving crimes...
Well Miss Jody, we go this way...
Good night, Miss Jody!
Bye bye, see you tomorrow at school!
Bye bye, cool guy...
Yes, that's right...
A lot happened...
You were right,
I don't think I ll be bored
I think I've got one of our targets...
Yes...
he's changed his appearance &
going to school as if nothing happened...
Hehehe.
Isn't that funny?
Little Mister target...
That's right...
Rotten apple...
Shall I turn him into a rotten apple...
Hahaha
Oh dear?
When Dad came by last week,
di'd'nét he tell you?
My father's actually Kogoro Mourl,
he's a private detective.
I am so sorry! Is it broken?
No, mine is OK.
No, mine is OK
Thefi'fifiét sound just now .
(ma)