With a strong mind and
sharp powers of reasoning
a keen sense of rhythm
that enables one to grasp
the in'ner me'anin'g of the crime.
A seemingly impossible crime
Gaga (mum 3 grunting u iflplhi'iimi») (orzin'nlsx
The case is solved.w,he,n the
deduction is Iaié on the line.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child ifiappearance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
(mica)
Murder at the Pottery Making Class
Part I
Hey Ran, look
Is "Tada!
Don't tell me you've sgrted
taking karate lessons?
Good grief, take a closer look!
Can't you read?
It says Kyogoku Makoto.
I was just kidding!
Isn't this the tea cup you
made in thefj'p'ottery class
you've started going to?
For goodness sakes .
But Sonoko .
Are you going to give this to him?
Isn t this a little small?
I know, th'at one's mine!
The one «or Ma'koto...
Rightfi'here!
It's huge"
But why's your name on it?
The answer's so"obvious!
The man I loveais in a
country far, far away...
The. Only way I can make him remember me 'is
through those far. spaced
telephone calls
And that"s Where
this tea cup handrfi'éde by
Sonoko comes in!
He won't be able to forget me with this.
Now will he 2
But Sonoko,
didn't you send him
a sweater before?
The one you bought at the store...
Oh...thét. I changed my mind-av
Huh?
You were right Ran.
NS not fight to cheat.
And besides. no matter how hard
I work on a sweater,
he can only use it in the winter...
But take a tea cup.
He can use it every day, right?
Well, that's true
Besides, I guess I'm worried...
Makoto's very kind.
I'm afraid some gi'rl-will
' come along and
take advantage of'him...
For instance...
there could be a lonely widow who's
Just lost her beloved husband
and Makoto says something kind
to comfort her
and she ends up stalking him...
What a cruel person...
To widow such a beautiful
woman as yourself
order to pay for his sins...
Young detective...
My lady...
If it pleases you.
You may cry inside my arms...
No, you mustn't...
But young detective. ..I...l...
Madam.
Ran?
What's'the matter; Ran...?
Hey Sc'moko! Didn't you say you
were going to
that pottery class every Sunday?
Uh, yes...why'?
What is it? Are you interested in it?
Well, yes, a little...
Three Weeks Later...
Hmm. Ayou'fie
pretty good for a beginner...
Uh Mr Mmo
Muneyuki Min'o (62)
Pottery. 'lieacher
Too. bad though.
Those letters ép'diled that cup...
Muneyuki Mino (62)
Potter. Preacher
Potter. Treacher
what does it mean anywayq.
Muneyuki Mine (62)
Potter. L'l'reacher
Well. uh. it doesn't
eally mean anything...
I see, well, keep up the good work!
Come on. what was it?
What did you write?
It's a secret, top secret!
You didn't by chance write
I Love ShinichV/did you?
Of course I didn't
All right then, let me see it!
Little boy, what are you doing here?
I'm not doing anything!
Did you come with somebody?
Attention everyone!
Does anyone know this child?
C, Conanl?
Why did you come here?
Don't tell me you followed us here!
Uncle Kogoro asked me to come here
and check on things...
That's strange...dad came here
Iast week to look around.
Uh, I mean, I mean...
Aha. I get it!
It was Shinichl!
I'll bet he's here because Shinichi
asked him to Che"? up on us!
He wants to make sure you're
not fooling around on him!
F, fooling around!?
No, you're wrong'!
Shiniohi wouldn't do
anything that stupid
That's the face of' someone
who's been paid off!
How muchid,-he,pay,you?
100 yen? 200 yen?
What a cheap skate...
Ités no problem.
He's come all this way,
Kikuyo Kasama (29)
Pottery Teachgr's Assistant
Potteryfieachgr's Assistant
How about it little boy.
Do you want to making something?
Kikuyo Kasama (29).
Potter" Ieacher's Assistant
ssssss
Is that all right, sir?
Fine, I'll demonstrate how to do it!
My goodness!
Have you met the famous Kikuemon?
Famous P
Yes!
His students taught me their techniques
and about color and things!
Isn't that right, Ran?
Now I understand. I knew you kids
picked up too fast for beginners!
I really envy you! You're friends with
a living National Treasure!
Well. not exactl .
He asked to see my father...
But they were there.
A murder took place
and Rah's father did
a brilliant job solving'it, didn't he?
He solved it, you mean
Oh my! Didn't my father tell you
when he Was here last week?
The truth is. my father's name is
Kogoro Mouri. He 5 a private detective.
Yes. I've heardiof him.
Isn'thét'called Sleeping Kogoro"?
How exciting!
Boy, things are 'lively here today, huh?
Oh, M6too, you're back!
I just got in.
I'll go change and help you, father.
Motoo Mine (31)
Company Emp'loyee
Yes, sure. . .thank you
What? Life insurance!'?
He made you take-one out?
Yeah. . smy father-in-law was
pestering me to sign up,
he said just in case somethinghhap'pens
Good grief...l heard that at~<one time
he was a talented potter
and everyone thought he'd be -a
new leader in the field,
but ever since his daughter
died in that accident,
he's changed and now
he's just an old drunk.
That likes to play with mud...
Aren't you being terribly cold
to your late. beloved
wife and her father...
Beloved my foot!
I was-going tmdivorce her as soon
as I got my hands on as much money
as I could from selling
the things the old man made}
but she went and! aiédi on me,
just lik'eithat'n-'i.
Don't let it bothér you] '0 much...
Mr. Minds not young.
He won't live much Ibnger.
Yeah when he; dies.
Let's fold up this operation
and open our own place...
If we sell the p'i'éces
in the warehouse,
IJ-m sure they'll
bring 'a'- good price
By the way. who's
the benefactor on that policy?
You; of course.
You've always been my woman.
In the past and even now.
Oh Hm so happy'.!
Q Them ou wonfitumind
dying to repay my debts?
VVlly... Idlllb'l!
Mr. Mino...
Kikuyo, here you are...
I'm going to go check the kiln,
take care of the
studentséfor me.
Yes sirs
Isn't this a new necktie?
Yes. Kikuyo gave it to me
Iast night for my birthday...
I told her I didn't look good in beige
That's not true...
I thunk 11 looks ven nice
wound your neck
Come'? on Ran!» Let me' see it!
I said no!
Everybody's going to see it anyway
when it gets'fired up!
I am so sorry, is it broken?
No, mine's OK...
When What was that sound just now?
Didn'hit come
from the storage mom?
I'm going to go have a look.
Okay...
I just want you to know.
If you 'look at it,
we're no longer friends'
Oh all right...
Mr Minol?
Oh. uh ..my hand slipped
and I dropped a plate...
Thanks. would you mind
finishing 'Up here?
Of course not.
Ouch!
Is something wrong?
It seems like something
was mixed in with the soil...
I guess it was a piece of
the plate I cracked
it must've been on my clothes
I'll go get the first aid kit!
Do you know where New
Why yes, it's on the upper/night Shelf
in the storage. room!
Then bring it right away...
Ohdfi'flgdodness sakes...
please be '-'ca refu I;-
to a potter. hands are
most important...
Is there something on my face?
No, it's nothing- .
By the way. I haven't
seen M0100 around...
Now that you mention it.
Neither have I
Hey, Motoo!!
Memo!
He wasn't by the kilns eithen...
How strange
This storage room's
the only place we haven't looked...
Hejwouldmt be in here. t
The only plac'e you could
hide in here is in that cabinet
Besides,
I'opened it just a little while ago
to get the first aid kit
and he wasn't inside...
The cabinet
a Biece of cloth...is sticking out
from under the cabinet dbor.
Isn't it one of the aprons
you use in class?
You're, right. . .'it's the sam'é pattern
as the ones we're weaning...
Good grief. this is like the ostrich
hiding it's head but leaving
its body in plain sight,
come on out; the gamefls oven!
M'otoo
Ibw AA
I1lopenit
Mo. Motool? What's wrong. Motoo?
Motool? Motool?
Snap out of it!!
Wake up. Motom'?
Someone call an amb'YIance, quick!
All right
And I think it'd be better
to call the police too...
Hurry!!!
Yes sir!
Motoo! Motoo!
The strangulation victim is Motoo Mino,
31 years old, a white collar worker...
Was he a student of this
pottery makingaclass too?
No, he lived-here.
He was married to my daughter
who died 2 years ago.
I see . my condolences
My name is Muneyuki Mino.
I run this pottery making class.
She's my assistant, Kikuyo Kasama.
Plgfise'tell me what the victim did
after he got home...
He got-home around 5 PM
as usual, then he said
he was going "to change into an apron
and help me in the class...
but some time passed and
he still hadn't
shown up so we all went to look for him,
isn't that right. Kikuyo?
Yes...
this storage room was the only place
we hadn't looked...
and then Mr Mino
opened the {cabinet...
And his body .
Motoo's body...oh...
, INS émaz'ing- that you found him there,
you weren't playing hide and seek,
who would've thought
a person would be inside there...
It was so obvious!
The apr6n was sticking out!
Isn't that right, Ran?
Apron?
It was sticking out!
Part of the apron he was
wearin'giwas sticking out
from under the door!
Do you know how long
it was like that?
No, I don't...
I remember now...
it wasn't sticking out
when we were
d fining up the broken plate!
What do you mean?
I accidentally dropped a plate
in front of that cabinet...
the students heard
the sound and came running,
I asked t 'é'mito clean it up for me.
I gugss I dropped it right after
Motoo left the storage room
after changing into.his apron...
Eh? You and the victim were
in here together?
Yes...the aprons are kept
in this cabinet...
that's why he always changed in here.
See. his jacket's
hanging ri'g'ht over there.
There's several overalls
hanging next to his jacket.
What are these'?
Those are also for the students' use!
When making large pots and such,
an apronfiiSn't big enough
to" protect their clothing...
I see...but I wonder
what the victim was doing in here?
Actually, while I wag looking for Kikuyo,
I hfi'ppened to finfl W'ér herewith Motoo.
IS that true?
Well, yes.
I was helping Him change.
Then Mr. Mine came in and
he asked me to look after the class
because he was going to the kiln.
And then what did you do?
I did as I was told.
I went back to the classroom...
And so Mr. Mina,
you were hef'e'with the victim alone,
is that correct?
Now-"wait just a minute, officer!
You're not implying that
I killed him, are you?
Like I already told you,
Motoo left the room
BEFORE, broke the plate!
If I'd killed him and} hid his
body~in the cabinet,
5 the Students would have
noticed the apron sticking out
from under the dodr when
they were cleaning up!
Perhaps the apron got stuck
when you came back
and Cheék'edbthe'bod'y'after
the students had finished cleaning up.
I don't think so!
While we were cleaning up.
Mr Mino went to the kiln,
and when we finished cleaning up
and Went back to the classroom,
Mr Mine was already there
After that. he was always beside
Conan working on something.
Isn't that right, OOnan?
Conan?
Uh, yes...
Mr. Mino was with us the whole time
until we found Motoo's body,
he couldn't possibly have
put the body in the cabinet.
I see...
So it must have gone like this,
after youuall had cleaned
up the broken fil'ate,
the killé'hcalledsthe victim
to this storage room and killed him,
or. the murder could have
taken place somewhere else
and the body brought back
hege when noone was looking
I just remembered! Maybe Kikuyo
saw the killer's face...
I cut my finger while I was working and
and Kikuyo came to the storage room
to getnthe first aid kit.
That was just before we began
our search for Motoo
so I just thought that maybe...
Did you see anyone? \
No, no one...
Where is the first aid kit kept?
On the upper right shelf of that cabinet.
What so you're saying
you opened the cabinet?
Yes-fl did but there was nobody inside...
That's the truth
Inspector!
After examining the victim's neck,
I've determined
the victim was strangled
with this necktie
we found around his neck.
Hmm. but that is strange...
Why did the killer tie
the necktie around the neck?
How awful. Kikuyo gave that
necktie to him for his birthday...
I, I didn't (givé that (cs-him!
You didn't?
He told me you did though...
What is the meaning of this?
Well. uh...he said he didn't know
where it came from,
he found it in his bag
along with 251 birthday card.
He really believed it was from me,
he thought I was
just too shy to admit it
Now that you mention it, he was
mumbling something when he
walked out of the storage room.
Huh?
Something about money
turning peop'le in'to monsters
and that his birthday- had just come but
he would be eaten by a monster...
Eaten by a monster?
Truth is. officer.
I want to tell you about that...
All right Takagl.
Check up on that right away!
Yes sir!
Uh. excuse me.
Do you have-Ha" pen or something?
Mine's run out of ink...
6? course .
I'll go get one!
I'm sure there's some in the classroom
Aren't those scissbrs?
FiLdn't the man from the crime lab
ask for a pen?
Oh, yes...you're so right
And will you take a look at that.
/ that's my cup! It's almost finished!
See?
Oh...you really like pottery making.
Don't you?
Yup I love lt
Besudes\
I want- to finish this upibecause
I don't want to be like
that man who died
and leave things.half£'aone!
Half done?
You mean you didnit notice?
His shirt sleeves were rolled up
but the length was different!
You know what it looks like?
It 'I'do'ks like he was attacked
whlle he was
chai'n'ging into his apron and
helping I'n class.
B. but young man.
Maybeqon'e sleeve got pulled down
while he struggled with the killer
Oh, that's right!
Then the killer must've
pulled his necktie tool
His necktie?
Yes, his necktie pin was really low!
And the button hole
was stretched out too!
But maybe the necktie pin
Wasre? little too low...
Maybe he likes putting it there.
And maybe it's his style to wear shirts
with different length sleeves...
But!sir. you like both the left
and right evenly, don't you?
I mean when Mr. Motoo fell out,
you were stan'aing on the left
but you deliberately went around
td the right side and yelled!
You actually wanted to fix the length of
his sleeve, didn't you.
Also. his apron was sticking out
from the right'side of the door
and it would've been natural
to open just the right side
but you opened both sides
at the same time...
Yes. I guess you're right.
I like things even...
I'm finished!
My tea cup! Pretty good, huh?
Yes, that's really quite good...
but you knowyoung man,
it appears as if
you're worriéd'f'éboutsomething...
you're either'hidihg' some deep.
Dark-secret or
debating about
something important...
I'm right. aren't I?
The soul never lies...
You're very good...
I think you should take care...
Of your own affairs
before meddling in other people's...
But...this is the cup YOU made, sir.
What!?
Whilst-You were busy
Ibdking through the desk,
I put you "5 Here!
L-thought for sure you'd~c'atch on!
And! ifthis is your tea cup...
the'fi'.'Y.O.U.,'must be hiding something'. .'.
Mr; Mino, sir, Whatfare you hiding?
Tell me...
ORIGINM! COMIC BONOKS BL.
(m s h 0 Aoyfrm a
PRODUCERS.
Mich/lulu) Sum) /
Masahno Yoshmka
MGKGROU'ND MUSIC
kmsuo Ono
CHARACTERDESICNS HY.
Masatnmo Sudo
510 EDITOR
Ium'dn Iloka
§CRIPTS BY.
Kan]: defllwabdra
Kazunan KOUChl
Iumchl Mlyashlta
hmhl Hugure
Toshlkl lnuue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Mmatnmo Sudo
Ientnsht leatam
Harm) Gaga u am
Atsush'l Aono
Nun Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yuluhlrn Shlbumm
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashl Nomura
Huronobu Honkoshu
Talcahisa Owa'ga
RECORDING DIRH TOR
Imtsuyoshl Knhayashl
EDITOR.
Terumltsn Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR?
Ken]! kndima
Plea/nu 15m,
TM 5 Enter moment, ltd.
In 85.4; run.) on WW II)
Yomlun Teleca'Sfm'g Cbrporatmn
OGosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
All Rights Reserved
PREVIEW
WAhere can'il'find the evidence
Oh, sorry kid!
PREVIEW
Necktie...
Why, this is!
PREVIEW
Miss Kikuyo. it seems you owe
101,000,000 yen.
PREVIEW
Well. yes . I found
a nice condominium and
PREVIEW
I've finally foufid it!
Proof only a professional potter
would I'eavevbehind!
PREVIEW