With a strong mmd
and sharp powers of reasoning
a keen sense of rhythm that enables one
to grasp the inner meaning of the crime
A strange murder takes place
at a pottery making making class,
the words on a tea cup
also poses a mystery
He sees through
the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the LG) of an adult,
no 0339113 left unsolved
with Det'ectiv'e Conan
ong Beach/Les Angef
Ran decides to go to the pottery
méking class Sonoko is'ffg'oing to,
and I g'b tea check up on her.
Muneyuki Mino (62)
Potter
Muneyuki Mine (62)
Rotter
ODD.
9&1! 5&2 (62)
£5 Wu tr
The instructor of the pottery;making
class Vs, MU'heyuki Mino,
Muneyuki Mino (62)
Potter
'fii
Kikuyo Kasama (29)
Potter's Assnstant
£20333?
and his assistant is Kikuyo Kasama.
Kikuyo Kasama (29)
Potter's Assistant
Kuwyo Kasama (29?
Butler's Assistant
III! fife
$20)?
Later, Mr. Mi'nbffs adopted son-in-law,
Memo, comes back from work.
Motoo Mme (31)
Mr. Mino's adopted son-in-law
Motoo Mine (31)
But he suddenly disappears.
Isn't this the apron you use for class?
I know who the killer is but...
I'm. finished!
Huh?
It's my tea cup!
Pretty good, huh?
Year-that's really qUite-good,
but you know, young man,
it appears you're
worried about something,
you're either hiding some deep,
dark secret or debating
about something important...
I'm- right, aren't I?
The: soil never lies.
Youlr'e'fyvery good, sir!
I think you should take
care of your own affairs
before meddling in other people's...
this is the cup YOU made
While you Were busy
Iooking through the desk,
I put yours over here!
I thought for sure you'd'catch on!
And if this is your cup
then YOU must be hiding something...
Mr Mino, sin, what are you hiding?
Murder at the Pottery Making Class
This...kid...
Uh...
Did you find a pen?
Yes-where. .
Use this...
Thank you...
and may I also use this desk?
By all means.
I appreciate this...
Now please go back to the storage room
where the inspector is waiting...
All right.
Nb doubt about it.-...
Mr. Mino is the murderer...
I've pretty much figured out
hisfalibi trick an
while I was checkingth 1b0dy.
He hid the evidence...
I saw him pick up those scissors,
that means the evidence
is still somewhere
it's got to be some place,
but if I can'-t fund ht...
Darn, isn't there something'el's'e'?
Something that the killer's missed...
Oh, thanks kid.
A necktie
Yes, this is it!!
Rvefoundifl
I've finallafound it,
you overlooked a piecelolf evudence
only a professional potter would
Ieave behind!
Inspector Megure!!
I've confirmed the details!
Give it to me!
And that's not the only thing I learned...
I see, debts eh
Miss Kasama
it seems you have debts
totalling 10,0005000 yen
Yes, [1 die»...
I found this great condominium.
What about it?
Nothing,
I just thought it was in'ter'e's'ting
The late Mr. Motoo just took out
an insurance policy last week
and the premium was
for exactly 10,000,000 yen,
payable to you
The timing just seemed so perfect...
On top of that,
just before Mr. Motoo's body was
discovered in the cabinet,
ou had come to at the first aid kit
from that very cabinet.
If you weren't the murdener
you surely would have seen
his body in there...
I already told you
I opened the cabinet
but nobody was inside]!
Besides,
it didn't take me more than a minute
to go get the first aid kit and return!
There's no way I could kill someone
and hide their body in the cabinet.
According to everyone's testimony,
'when Mr. Minggot hunt.
You volunteered to get the first aid kit
What if you had alneady put
Motoo's body in the cabinet
You «didn't want his body
to be discovered yet so
you went to gét the first aid kit yourself.
But when ybu opened the cabinet,
his apron slid out and
got caught in the door,
maybe thz'at's what happened
Th. that's absurd!
I'm not a murderer...
Don't lie, Kikuyo...
I saw you
I came in here looking for you
I saw you choking Motoo's neck!
Is that true?
It she said shejwas
helping Motoo change but...
that's not what it looked like...
I, I was just playing...
You can tell us about it
down at the station...
Now just hold on a minute officer
What's wrong, Inspector?
You know,
everytime we start to
walk out with the suspect,
a strange voice stops us,
It goes, Furiyaa or Oops"; likedhat...
Oh, you're talking about Kogoro Mourl.
Well. you can rest assured.
He's not here today!
Oh, that's right...
Funya
nyalala
Sonoko, what's the matter?
I just remembered, this girl does it too
Inspector Mequre.
You've done it again, I'm so bored...
How dare you!
Didn't you notice it?
The victim Motoo's
sleeves were rolled up
but the lengths weren't the same!
Doesn't that seem like
he was attacked while
he was working in the class?
And if that's the case,
then the killer could only
be that person, don't you think?
Who are you talking about?
You don't mean...
1 (es
that person who
came into this storage room
while Kikuyo was
helping Motoo change
then forced her to return to {We class
Ieaving him alone with the victim...
that person is
Muneyuki Mino!
Yes you are the murderer
Hahaha Sonoko!
We noticed the thing
about his sleeves but
Mr Mino has an alin
According to Ran's testimony
when Mr Mino left
the storage room earlier today,
the apron wasn't sticking out like it was
when they discovered the body
And he was with all of you
the entire time later that day, wasn't he?
Besides, just before
the body was discovered,
Kikuyo had come
and opened tHe cabinet!
We're not sure she's
actually the killer yet
but she should have screamed
if he was inside,
wouldn't that be thé natural thing to do?
That is, if She didn't kill him.
And unless Mr. Mine was a magician,
there isn't any way he could have
put the body in the cabinet
without using his hands.
Isn't that right?
No. actually,
he did use magic...
Mr. Mino used Ran and
Kikuyo as assistants
and made Motofu's body
appear in the cabinet
after making it seem like
he wasn't inside!
Kikuyo and I were assistants?!
The proof of the pudding
is in the eating!
You'll know what I mean
when we reenact it. /
Let's see.
Officer Takagi.
Will you be my assistant?
Wan"?
Who, me?
Take 'a good look people!.
What you see before you is
a simple cabinet with nothing rigged...
Hahaha.
Please check and make sure
nothing is sticking out of the cabinet!
Uh. - .eVerything's clear...
All right then,
please open the door on the right side.
It's opened
You've checked and
made" sure nothing is inside?
Uh: yes...
I didn't notice anything unusual
GAEI
A piece of cloth is sticking out
from under the the cabinet?
That's strange.
That cloth wasn't here before
So-that's how it was done!
I'VE on the inside of the doorl!
That's right!
I asked Conan and
the man from the crime lab
to stick that handkerchief there.
I'm almost certain Mr. Mino
taped the end of the apron
to the inside of of the
accordion style door's right side
then closed the door while
pushing the end of the apron inside!
Then,
when someone opens the door,
the apron will be pulled out,
and when the door is closed again,
the apron would stick out.
What I'm saying is,
Mr. Mino deliberately cracked
the plate in front of the cabinet
so that Ran would see that
there was nothing sticking out from
underneath when she was cleaning up,
then he made Kikuyo
go get the first aid kit
telling her he had hurt his hand,
when she opened
the door to theflsabinet,
the apron came loose and
got caught under the door.
I see!
That way it would look like
there was nobody in the cabinet
when Ran was cleaning up
the broken plate and
as if someone had put it in there later.
B but
if Kikuyo had noticed the apron
when closing the door,
after getting the first aid kit.
I don't thifik'she would look
down when closing thé door,
not knowing that there was an
injured person Waiting for her!
Hmm...
so where was the body all that time?
When the door was opened,
the body fell out
that means the body was probably
Ieaning againstithe door
Kikuyo had to have seen it
when she got the fist am km!
I think we'll know the answer when
we open the door one more time.
But this time,
open both doors at the same time...
Both sides at the same time?
Whal'?
A mop'?
This wasn't in there
the last time I opened it Up!
How'd you do the?
It's a simple trick! /
I tied some string to the top of the mop,
then made a knot at the end of the string.
Next. I passed the string through the
hanger bar on the right side shelf
and hung the mop so it leaned forward,
then I passed the string through the
opening above the door on the left side,
pulled it so that the knot would get caught
when the door closed
and that kept it in place!
That way,
even when the door
on the right is opened,
the mop is hidden by the joint,
when both doors are
opened at the same time,
the knot. which is
the stopper comes loose
and the mop falls out!
The mop is Motoo,
the string is his necktie,
and the knot in the string...
You've got to be kidding...
hlS tie p'in!!
That's right!
When you look at the tie
around Motoo's neck,
you'll see for yourself, it' so obvious!
The reason his tie pin was
so attached so low was,
it was adjusted to
accommodate this trick,
the hole the tie pin
made was big proving
Motoo's weight. stretched it out!
B, but
but wouldn't someone notice if
the end of the neckties Were sticking out
from above the left door?
Not if you were to roll it up and
stuff it into the space in the door!
Then when-did-he retrieve
the piece of apron?
When the police arrived,
we did nit fi rid-anything
Iike that in the cabinet.
Besides,
he discovered Motoo's body
when all you students Were present,
didn't he?
He couldn't have retrieved it
with all of you watchihg...
He certainly could!
When Motoo fell out of the cabinet,
Mr. Mino moved to
the right side, bent down
and while he pretended
to be trying to rouse him,
he opened the right door fully and
used his body to hide the apron
sticking out from under the door
then if he tore It tape and all,
no one would notice it, would they?
Ucc,
when the door is partially open,
the apron is hidden by the
V shape joint on the inside and
when {the door (is opened fUllYp
it sticks out from the left side, doesn't it?
Mr. Mino tore that
and hid it in his pocket!
Yes, see what you mean
Then we'd find that piece of cloth
if we search his pockets...
Humph, this is absurd...
Take a look
as you can 899.
I don't have such a thing?!
What is this, Sonoko'?
He probably hid it
in the toilet or some place
before the police arrived
while I waé checking the body.
In the toilet?
Conan saw Mr. Mino looking for scissors
so he probably meant
to cut it into little pieces
and flush it (Pawn the toilet.
Takagi, check it out!
Yes sir!
it doesn't matter what and where
you find it. I'm not guilty...
No one actually saw me hiding anything
Besides,
anyone could have rigged
the trick that girl just explained!
You're right
even if we do find the piece of apron,
the moment it left your'person,
it lost it's weight as
evidence against you...
But unfortunately Mr Mina...
there's solid evidence remaining
that incriminates you...
Eh'?
It's on the back of the tie
that was tied around Motoo's neck.
These look like!
Scratch marksl?
That's right
it's from the soil that's embedded
in Mr. Mino's fingertips...
it's not unthinkable for those
scrat'éh marks to be there
Mr Mine was making
a tea cup with Conan
and judging from the
position of the tie pin,
the neck tie was just barely long enough
to keep the body suspended
The only way he could avoid getting his
fingerprints on the tie pin
while pulling the body up
and getting the tie pin over the door.
Was to grip the necktie tightly...
Mr. Mino, you made 2 mistakes!
Firstl, you didn't use gloves...
and second,
you chose to use that necktie
to pull the body up...
If you had used gloves,
you could have looped the tie pin
with your fingers and pulled the body up
and if you had used string
with a knot instead of"the=f'ne'cktie,
you wouldn't have made
those scratch marks.
Putting gloves on makes it seem as if
I were touching something dirty...
My lét'éi'daughter gave that tie to him,
it-'gwas a symbolaof her love for him...
it was for Christmas.
Then.
The birthday card and that tie
he found in his bag yesterday...
It was from me,
I knew he'd assume it was from you...
I was determined to use it to show him
the grief my daughter felt...
And I wanted you to take all the blame...
I started to suspect the
relationship between you two
when my daughter was struck by
the truck and died, 2 years ago...
It was 3 days after Ohristmas...
me whens was over
and I was cleaning her room.
That's when I found it.
The necktie was crumpled and
thrown in the trash bin, box and all
I thought he did it my mistake so
I rushed to the airport to give it to him,
I expected to see a man grieving over
the recent loss of his beloved wife
waiting sadly for his flight to
take him to his work assignment...
the man I saw at the
airport wasn't a man
who had recently lost
e woman he loved...
what I saw was a fraud,
he was holding you and
you two were laughing
and enjoying yourselves...
That's when I knew,
my daughter wasnit hit by the car,
she found out about you two
so she threw herself in front of the car.
Killing herself].
hoWjdid you know this
necktie was for Motoo?
Maybe she was
going to give it to you...
I knew...
after all, she.
She told me .
Beige?
Isn't that color rather plain for Motoo?
It doesn't matter!
I like beige and besides,
I want him to be a little more like you!
Beige is the color of the soil!
That's your color, isn't it, dad?
Iguassu
you could say
it-.-'was- a father's I'n'tt'iiti'on...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS B)
705,10 Aoyffi'na
PRODUCERS.
Michlhlko Suua
Masahlto Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Misuo Ono
CHARACTER-DESIGNS IT.
M'lsalomo Sudo
5 TOR y ED? TOR
Iumchl Iloka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan}! Kasfilwabara
Kazunan KOUChI
Jumchl Mlyashlh
YUIChl ngure
Tos'hlkl lnoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshl Take) tan:
Haruo Ooghwara
AtsUshl AOHO
Aldo Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yuklhlro Shlbutam
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashu Nomura
Huronobu Horlkoshl
Takahlsa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshl Kobayashl
EDITOR
Terumltsu Okada
CHIEF DIREZ-it-TOR
JK('fljiKOdfi'ma
Phonwcm "Y.
TMSTnte'rt'TmmenL Ltd.
m assocmtlomwffm
Yommn Telecfiflhv Carpnrmon
OGosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
YTV / TMS
All Rights Reserved
hnee days later
You got a letter from Kyogokul?
Then why're you so sad, Sonoko?
Take a look at this picture!
He thought you made him a vase...
I guess
you could say I vested" my time...
sadjoke
Ran. did you send
yours to you know who"?
Didn't you have your friend the living
national treasure fire yours up for you?
Well, no...
I don't think I did it right.
That's why I didn't send it...
I think they're all gone...
Hey Conan.
Huh?
I hate to ask but could you go
get the bag of chips on my desk?
Okie dokie
What's this?
It's a chopstick holder...
It looks familiar...
Mystery maniac is a complete foo?
I get it now,
So thus is the tea cup Ran made
I understand why she couldn't send
a silly tea cup like thus...
I'll be waiting for you "
Conan, what are you doing?
Hurry up, we're. waiting!
Oh, yeah,.'éo'ming!
Conan looks so happy!
Kind of creepy, isn't it...
PREVIEW
Eh? \
I'm surelof it!
PREVIEW
One of these 3
is part of their gang
PREVIEW
But did the gang find out?
How did théyjkhon
I was acting suspic'ib'u's?
PREVIEW
9A NA
(mm)
(QM)
v Next episode
(mm)
Mysterious Passenger -Part I
(mam