With a strong mind and sharp powers
of reasoning, a keen sense of rhythm
that enables one to grasp
the inner meaning of the crime.
Today's episode occurs
inside afbuxis filledkwithadanger.
Ai'is acting strange.
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult.
No case is left un's'olve'd
with Detective Conan.
Dld you see that? He Just left
The client left with a happy face...
He doesn't realize
that was his last drink...
Isn't that right, bro...
Bro?
Oh, so that diva's up next?
Every time I hear her sing.
It sends shivers down my spine.
And shells good-looking too...
She's your type, isn't she...
Dry, martinis for you two
compliments of the diva.
Well, well, well...that's mighty kind of her.
Aw...
What's the meaning of this?
Huh?
I asked you what the heck you're doing.
I already know all about you!
Belmot!
I'm just Kid'dingllflP
It was a joke...a joke
It was a joke . a joke
Belmot
Ib-'E/h
Don't get so angry
Belmot
JbEyh
I was just teasing the guys
who have the hots'for th§t diva.
That's all...
Sure, but are you sure this is OK?
I mean you're a famous actress.
What if someone saw you with us...
Don't worry about it...
everyone's attention is
on the diva who's up next...
Neversmind that,
did you find what you were looking for?
We'll...
not exactly what I was looking for, but...
What are you looking for anyway?
Don't you think it's
about time you tell us
where you're at and
what you're doing...
Hah, no use asking...
this woman never reveals her secrets...
You just don't understand, do you...
A secret makes a woman'a woman...
A woman becomes beautiful
when she has secrets to hide...
You make me sick...
Never mind about me.
What about you?
Did you find that little kitten
that got away-from you?
No...
But it%?won't be Iong'before I do...
my nose can sniff out
a traitor wherever they are...
and when I db.
I'll Show them what real fear IS...
I'll teach both of them.
Her and that boyfriend of hers...
Mysterious Passenger-Part I"
Next stop...Beika 3rd chome
front of the Kodama
Products main building...
Next stop. . .Beika 3rd chome,
front of the Kodama
Product's main building...
Hey Professor
are you sure you're up to ski?
It's his own fault...
I told him to stop because
he-would catch a cold but};
he stayed up all night watching
those How to Ski"
tapes for image training);
I guess you're right...
I'm in charge of you kids!
I've got to set a good example
But when we get there,
you've got keep still
and Stay in bed at the lodge.
Like they say. the beginning
of a cold is the most crucial time...
You'd better not push
yourself and go outside!
Uh uh...
Aw, come on...
I can't tell who the kid is...
Next stop. . .In front of Beika Park.
N'éxt stop ..In front of Beika Park.
Hey!
The passengers are boarding now.
Please stay in your seats.
Yes sir!
Oh my
you look like you're
about to die from boredom...
you look very sad since you won't
be able to see her for a long time...
Huh?
Or could it be...
That you're sad because you won't
be-able to see those guys?
You're nuts.
These passengers have
nothing to do with me.
Who'd be crazy enough to want to run
into those guys in a small bus like this?
Especially with
all these kldS on board...
Is he one of those men in black?!
No he isn't.
I can tell, they have a smell
it's an unpleasant smell. only those
who're in the organization give it off...
You don't smell funnfl.
Will you stop kidding around?
But if you have that sixth sense,
what happened with Bisco...
Well. I had my suspicions
Then why didn't you say something?
I wasn't absolutely sure...
I had a feeling there was one more.
That's right...
someone worse than Bisco...
I felt an aura
that made my skin prickle...
Ku,Kudou
chan'ge'seats with me and hide me...
Please!
Ha, Haibara...
Look! It's Mr. 'A'r'aid'e'u
I didn't expect to see
all of you on this bus too
We took our physical examination
at school yesterday!
Yes, I know
Hey,
Mr. Mamie, what happened to you?
I just remembered
you werenlt'there yesterday.
Hey. are you on a date, sir?
Uh, no,
she's a teacher at Teitan High School.
I'm the 'school doctor there.
Hi boys and girls!
Oh! You're that cool kid.
So we meet againh!
Do you know her?
Uh, yes...
she teaches English
at Ran's high school
My name is Jody Santemillion!
I'm on a date with Dr. 'Araide.
We're going to the Ueno Art Museum.
Uh, no,
we met at the bus stop
quite coincidentally.
You shouldn't embarrass a lady!
It wouldn't be good for rumors
to go around school about us.
Isn't that right?
Oh, yes'
That would be a problem!
Hey look
Look at those two...
we're not even there yet
and they're already in their ski suits!
They probably can't wait...
But I know how they feel.
I do I00!
Good grief. why is he putting
his goggles on in the bus...
Why don't we change too?
Don't you remember...
we sent our bags on ahead...
Ohfl. that's/right!
Genta, you're so forgetful.
Nobody move
Move and you're dead
Wh, what is this?
It's them'!
Nobody move!
Move and you're dead!
Wh, what's going on?!
Are they hijacking the bus?!
What is this?!
What the?!
Don't you have ears
I told you to shut up!!
Hey?!
Yes?
First off, let's close the front doors
Yes, sir...
Next. let's change the destination
sign to read Not in Service
Yes, sir!!
Now then...
Iet's get this bus moving!
Just drive through the city!!
Yes sir!!
Hurry up
Listen
If, we when we stop for a red light.
Wan you 0 ca your company.
Yes sir
Good...
Ou're all being smart...
now I want all of you
to get your cellular phones
out and hand them over to me...
Don't try to hide them...
if you do. I'll make it so you
never make another pho'ne call.
Th, this' is W-707...Kobayashl,
W 707 Kobayashl
Liste'. we're being...
We've just hijacked
your company's bus]!
We only want 1 thing!
We want the release of
Kunio Yajima who's in prison
Tell the cops that if they don't do it,
we'll kill 1 passenger every hour!
We'll call you back in 20 minutes!
Get things settled by them!
Kunio Yajima...
one-of the members of a gang
{of robbers, last monttp,
they made a bomb and
tried tb'rob a j'ewelry store...
The leader of'the gang.
Kunio Yajima was the only one caught
the other three are still at large
I'm'sure Yajirna
was once a jewelry broker...
gent...
I'll bet the rest of the gang donft know
what to do with the jewels they stole
and they haven't gotten rid of them yet
so they're trying to break their 6083 out...
or maybe only the boss knows
where the jewels are and
they're trying to get him out/
of jail so they can get to it.
Hey, you!
Hurry It up
Oh, sorry...
Shuichi Akai
(Passenger)
Shuichi Aka:
I don't have a cellular phone...
Shuichi Akal
(Passenger)
I don't have a cellular phone...
Sheesh, what a dork...
Hey, old man, you
What's that in your ear?!
It's a...a hearing aid...
Yasuhiko Machida
(Passenger)
I...IL got hurt when I was young...
Yasuhiko Machida
(Passenger)
th..that's why I...
Yasuhiko Machida
(Passenger)
Hey you!
Stop that, it's noisy!
No-canhel'b\gum chewing's noisy...
You guys' re wasting
your time doing this,
Miharu Tomino
(Passenger)
you're going to get caught anyway...
Miharu Tomino
(Passenger)
M5Q~M
I think you should give it up
and make a run for it
OK, I get you
I'll shut up...
Yeah.
Yeah
That's what you should've
done from the start .
Whwwhat happened?!
Are you okay?
Yeah,fine...
Why you...
Jo...Jody...
Oh sorry!!
Oh forget it. get back to your seat!
It's very, very exciting
Goodrgrief, is thisifteacher for real. . ._
Anyway...
while those guys are over there,
I've get,to contact Inspector Megure
on my earring shaped transmitter to let
him know what's going on in this bus.'...
What are you doing!'?
Why you...little brat...
Try something like that again
you're really going to get it
Oops, almost forgot...
I'm going to hang onto this...
Rats he tooktmy phone...
dnan! Are you alright...
That's strange. . .1
he came straight for me.
But I'm sure he couldn't see me.
I was hiding behind the Seat...
that must mean...
another one from their
gang's on this bus...
It must be one of those three since they
could see what I was doing.
But how'd he let him know?!
HoW'd-he let him know where I Was.
How'd he do it without
anybody noticing...
This is Seton
The hijacked bus is presently
heading towards Takaido!
Travelling at a Speed of
approximately 50 kilometers
This is Takagi, we're in position E!
The hijacked,bus has
jUSt come into View
There are two suspects on board!
Both are in ski suits!
If can't make out their faces because
they have hats and goggles on
It appearSLboth suspects arexarmed! ,
What should we do, Inspector! I
The bus-might pass-that way again!
Hold your positions!!
Yes, sir!
Damn!
If both of them have guns,
then we have to move carefully...
Inspector!
The bosses upstairs
jUSt gave their orders!
First prioritx is for the safe
release of the passengers!
The prisoner, Kunio Yajima,
is going to be released
per the hijackers request...
I guess we have no other choice...
as it seems the hijackers have
alr'eady fired 2 shots in the bus
if the 're part of that
gang 0 jewelry robbers,
an explosives professional
might be in there too...
If they detonate some bombs in the city.
We're going to have
a disaster on our hands...
But still.
They're trapped like rats in there!
It appeans that the bus is just moving
through the streets randomly...
No, they have some kind of plan...
They intend to lose
the police and escape...
They've got a plan
So they've agreed to release him, eh?
All right then. tell Yajima when
he's released to call us back in 1 hour!
As soon as we know
he's in a safe place,
we'll let the passengers go.
Th lee of them first
Listen carefully!
Don't db anything stupid!
YilZes'!
Two ski bags in a row...on the floor...
they couldn't be, could they
What the...
You againl?
If you're not afraid of dying...
Then I'll be glad to oblige
Hey! Little kid stand up
Co Conan!
Stop that
He's just a little boy being...
being mischievous!
Besides. you're getting what
you asked for
If you hurt even one passenger.
Your plan's not going to go smoothly.
You've got some nerve
You young punk...
Stop that!
If the bullet misses & hits
that thing". then what?
Oh, uh
OK you guys.
Get back to your seats, now!
Yes, OK...
You said that if that thing" got hit...
NAha, I knew it! These bags...
Are there bombs in them?!
I still don't know what these guys are
going to do with these, but now...
I do know for sure that one of those
three in the back3'fpart of their gang
and he's telling them about me.
I've got to find 'out
somehow who it is,
Otherwise, there'll be nothing I Can do...
Hey Haibara, do you have any ideas?
Huh?!
What? What is this?
His choking pressure...
It's that same overwhelming
feeling I got before...
He's here... that guy's...on this bus"
Is it one of the men in black?
Are they after me?
Or is it just a coincidence?
If my identity is blown now ..if they
realize I betrayed the organization.
Then Doctor Agasa and
all the others on this bus
everyone .will be killed...
so will he, of course...that's for sure...
Please. . .oh please...
Don't let them see me
msho Aoyé'ma
PRODUCERS
Muchlhlko Suua
Masahito Yeshloka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Kw {51107 Ono
CHARACTER DE§TGNS~4§Y.
Mamm'h'm Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Iunuhl Iloka
SCRIPTS BY.
KanjiKasfilwabara
Kazun'arl KOUChI
JUHIChl Mlyashlta
YUIChl Hloure
Tos'hlkl lnoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hurotoshl Takatam
Haruo Oog'awara
Atsushl Aono
Alan Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yuklhlro Shlbutam
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashu Nomura
Ieonobu Honkoshl
Talfihlsa Owagh
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshu Kobayashl
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
611151 01125611111.
dKCfljiKodfrma
Phonwcm "Y.
TMSTnte'rtnmmont, Ltd.
m accormtlomflwnh
Yomlun Telecastmv COrporatlon
OGosho Aoyama / Shogakukafn
All Rights Reserved
PREVIEW
No. it can't be...
it can't be...is he in here?
PREVIEW
here on this bus...
somebody from the organization...
PREVIEW
Listen. when the bus comes out of the
tunnel, that's when we act
PREVIEW
I've always known there was no place
for me. I'm a fool, aren't I sis...
PREVIEW