Everqdnekidestiny gives us
meme itoflthefi'hystery.
The most puzzlinq"case
becomes transparently clear.
Today's case occurs
in a regular condominium.
There's a twist to the strange accident.
He sees through the one & only truth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan.
Ng ngs Angeles/San Diego
Ai H'aibara and I board a bus
With Doctor Agasa
and the Youth Detective Squad
on our way to get in!
Some Spring skiing.
On the way
Mr. Araide and Miss Jody
also board the bus
and Haibara suddenly becomes
cared she's just not herself...
Just then,
two men wearing ski suits
board the bus
and hijack it!
I hide and try to contact thevpo'lice But...
Why you
Iittle brat...
You little brat!
Try something like that again
and you're really going to get it!
Rats!
He took my'phone...
Conan!I Are you alright?
That's strange. . .1
he came straight/for me...
but I'm sure he couldn't see me.
I was hiding behind the seat...
that must mean...
another one from their
gang is on this bus...
It must be one of those three
since they could see what I was doing
But how'd he do it?
How'd he letmim kn'ow
where I was?
How'd he do
without anybody noticing?
Mysterious Passenger, Part II!
Hey Haibara.
Do you have any ideas?
Huh?!
Don't do anything foolish, Mr. Cool!
Huh?
You II get your chance soon!
You don't havgto be so scared
What's your name,
Iittle red riding hood?
she's
Jazz;
fiTfi 515A,
WhatF'6ur 'r'f five; 34
iii-Ti 15mm
Iittlem'ed'Tiding'l'ifide 7.7.1
A stranger,
we just happen to be
sitting next to each other!
She's really scared,
SO {WIN we S 10C! ( eave'Wer a one...
I'm sorry
You over there
What're you doing over there!'?
Miss Jody!
Please don't upset them!
Oh, okay!
$7219
et's talk about it later...
eah, sure.
don't tell me...
it can't be, someone's here?
Here, on this bus...
someone from the organization?
But for. now,
wé'verfgot to find out who
these hijacker-is partner is.
I've got to figure out
who it is and take care of mm, for now,
the organization is,
the least of my worries...
and those three are very suspicious.
The most suspicious one is...
the guy who has the opportunity
to signal h'i'm, by sound...
the guy who'é's'abeen coughing
Shuichi Akai
(Passenger)
that guy...
Shu'mm Aka
(Passenger)
ifs???
Shmcm Aka
(Passenger)
ii???
But then...
Doctor Agasa is also coughing}.
There's not too much difference
in the sound of their coughs}.
Anduif the signal's sound,
then that woman chewing gum
is also a suspect...
Miharu Tomino
(Passenger)
but the coughing sound is louder...
Miharu Tomino
(Passengen)
Those guys were by
the driver's seat that time...
they wouldn't be abletto/hear her
chewing gum from there'../.
That leaves that guy
with the hearing aid
If that hearing aid were
a wireless'microphone,
a wireless microphone.
Asuhiko Machida
(Passenger)
If that hearing aid were
a wireless microphone,
asuhiko Machida
(Passenger)
IBIS £3
asuhiko Machida
(Passenger)
he'd be able to whisper
essage,but.
Asuhiko Machida
(Passenger)
neither of the hijackers
don't have anything in their ear
besides, if he said something,
the other 2 beside him
would've heard him...
The only thing those hijackers are
also checking is that back mirror...
Hey, old man!!
Eh? ,
Wh Yre you messing with
It's..uh..only...cough medicine...
Againvn...
They've been signaled again.
Rats!
How's it being done...
How're they being signaled?!
We've been waiting
for your ca"ll Mr. Yajima!
We? HoW'ére'thmgs on your end...
No problem...
I lost the cops...
Alright then,
we'll meet at the usual place
3 days from today...
Okay driver,
get on the expressway
then the Chuo freeway!
Yes sir!!
Whén you get to the Kobotoke Tunnel,
drop your speed .
Don't worry about anything...
We'll release the passengers ,
just like you told us to...
Hey!
You with the glasses
and...that guy in the back coughing!
You two. . get up here
What're you doing, hurry up...
You better do it, it's for your own good.
Aha...so that's how you did it
and now I know
who your other partner is...
And you intend to
get away from this bus.
A notebook?
Djo you have lipstick?"
Now to use this badge and
get those guys to
(3&0; Mama»
GENE-$2
hat can you d6,with-1 lipstick.
(5 "(IE U? Who
(DEEP-zit
It $55,231.11
Show Me your magic...
I Eat?
_J J'IJ(
Cool guy
Sato here...
the bus is presently
on the Chuo Freeway heading
for the Otsuki direction!
W'eireralm'ost a't
the-'Kobotoke Tunnel! 'a
Continue tailing them!
Don'tf. lose them?!
Yes, sir!
Listen carefully!
The bus is nearly out of gas!!
I'm certain
the hijackers will release thcee'jof
the passengers as promised
when they stop for gas!
Contact the Yamanashl
Prefecture! Police and
ask them to place officers
at all parking areas
the bus mi ht sto at!!
Yes sir!!
When the door opens,
we'll rush in, that's the best scenario
Inspector!
The bus is slowing down!
Wham?
The bus is now
entering Kobotoke Tunnel!
Okay you two!
Put these ski suits on
and sit on the floor!
And don't forget these hats and goggles!
You're going to change places with us
for awhile and buy us some time...
We're going to disguise ourselves
as 2 of the released passengers
and make our getaway and
you're going to buy us time to do that...
Don't worry. the other
passengers will testify later
that you're not the hijackers...
And whether our escape
is successful or not,
depends on you. driver!
It's all in your hands]!
When we get off the bus,
drive away and draw
the police's attention to the bus!
And to make sure
you follow our orders,
we're going to take 1 hostage with us...
That woman in the back chewing gum!
You, come here!
When we get to the end of the tunnel.
I'll ive ou the Si nal to s eed u
after the cop car following us is
out of sight. you stop the bus!
After we get off,
keep going until you run out of gas
That's if you want this girl to stay alive
Yes, I'll do it!
No, that's wrong...
she's no hostage...
She's one of them!!
I was right...
after the 3 of them leave the bus
they're going to detonate
the bomb in these bags
killing us all so we can't
testify as to what happened.
That's right...
they're going to be
under police protection
because everyone will think
they were really passengers
they're going to make-up a story
bout the whole thing.
And the police probably think
there were only 2 hijackers.
So if they say there was a struggle
between the passengers
and the hijackers,
the police will believe
that something happened
and the bomb went off
killing everyone...
Which means
the homes of Mr. Name and the guy
with the cold will be found
wearing ski suits and the police will
think that they were the hijackers
They made them change in the tunnel
so that they couldn't be
seen from the outside but
this darkness will work for me too...
Huh?
Is that our badge?
Co, Conan!?
Ears! Ears!
Listen!
Do exactly what I'm about to tell you!
Don't worry!
The inside of the bus is dark and
they're so sure their plan is
going to work, their guard is down...
The moment the bus
comes out of the tunnel...
that's when we make our move!
Okay! Speed up!!
Okay!
Don't try anything stupid...
Just do what we tell you
and you won't get killed'...
What a -lié'r. "5.
Huh"?
I know you're going to kill us...
Isn't that why you're
Ietting us see your face?
Listen everybody,
if we don't do something.
They're going to kill us...
with this bomb
Why you little brat!
I'll shut you up"
No idiot! Don't shoot
Huh 2
hams that refigrafim....
Hurry!
Uni'?
8, stop!?
This way mister!
Mitsuhiko, don't let go!
You don't have to tell me!
H that hurts...
Why you...
I\'/lr'.1 Araide!
Grabxboth that lady's érmsl!
Her wristwatch is
is they-device thatlll set off the bomb!!
Kid-f, you just made a big mistake.
I'm so sorry!
We braked so suddenly.
I lost my balance
8, stop that
Hey, what gives?
He trigger's...
You're so stupid
Dldnitlyou know that
the safety on that type of gun Ioc'lZs
when you pull the hammer back lightly
nd stop it halfway
You shquld have at least studied
that before. you attempted to use it...
Wh, what the?
Who the heck are you anyway!?
$715 nu Mb
It's a big secret.
FiiBfla<§L\b
I'm sorry, I can't tell you--...
fiiffl'tmub
First QbQ
% hflth
A secret makes a woman, a woman...
321355 J'é':
blurb b
A secret makes a woman, a woman...
7&3th b
You surrender, huh
h no--
Oh no...
We've got to get away
from here, right now...
When the bus skidded.
My wristwatch must've hit somethi'hg.
The bomb's been activated!
There's less than
a minute before it explodes!
Are you serious!
Inspector!
The bus's in the Koboto'ke Tunnel area.
They've come to a sudden stop
and now there's no movement!
What should we do?
Should we storm the bus?
Wait for your backup to arrive.
Co, Conan!?
What happened?
The bomb those hijackers
brought on the bus is
going to go off
in less than 20 seconds
What I?
We've go to do something...
I'll stop thé cars at the tunnel.
Chiba, yo'u'go to the other lane!
You other men.
Help the passengers out of the bus!
Ye's ma'am!!
MEW Where's N? I
I don't see her...
No, she couldn't be
It's not possible, she's...
That-is right.
This is the best way...
Even if wene saved,
I'd probably run into that person"
when the police question us...
If I were to disappear right now,
then there'd be nothing, left to link
those guys with the ofgénization.
I've always known that but...
I knew that from the moment
I ran away from the organization.
There'd never be a place
I'm such a fool...
I really am a fool...
aren't I, sis...
Co, Conanr
Conan
She's hurt!
Can you take her with Doctor Aqasa
and the others to a hospital?
I can answer all the
police's questions by myself!
Oh: I guess so...
There!
Don't run away Haibara...
From your destiny...
Don't run away...
Get to the hospital, quickly
Oh, yes
Oh, cool kid!!!
Breaking the window like that
and rescuing the girl
was so James Bond!
Miss Jody. yoi'J're more
Iike Agent 007 than me!
You tripped the hijacker
and pretended to apologize.
But actually. you put the safety on.
On that gun, didn't you?
Oh, yes!
It went exactly like in the movies!
Haha. . .~.oh\come on
you're very bright!
How did you know
she was part of their gang?
T Was the bubbles...
Bubbles?
She was chewing bubble gum
that's how she was
signaling the hijackers
which passenger
was acting suspicious .
The bubble would break and
the hand she used to pull
the gum off with would show
what side and the number
of fingers she used.
Would show which seat
that passenger was in.
Then how did you know
her wristwatch would set off the bomb?
She was wearing a watch
that had stopped at 1:00.
That made me suspicious
I'm so mad though!
Their boss got away!
Don't worry.
The police wouldn't let
a dangerous man like that
out of prison so easily.
Not without a plan!
I'm sure he'll be captured right away!
Attention all passengers!
We have some
questions to ask all of you,
please get into the cars!
We've got to go too...
You're pretty messed up...
are you sure you're alright?
\I'm fine, no problem!
Ouch.
I knew it! You've been hurt badly
You're a very reckless boy...
r. Name...
Youlcan answer their questions
after you've been treated
Oh, alright.
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
(ms/10 Aoyfirn
PRODUCERS.
Machlhlko Suua
Masahito «Yodnoka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Nahuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
sham EDITOR.
Iumchl lloka
SCRIPTS BY.
KanjiKasfl'lwabara
Kazunaril KOUChI
Jumdn Mlyashlta
YUIChl ngure
TOS'hlkl lnoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Hlfbtoshl T1katam
HJI'UO Oog'awara
~HSU§I1IAOI10
Aldo Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yuluhlro . hlbuldnl
DIRECTORS or PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takath Nomura
Ieonobu Horlkoshl
Tahhisa Owa'ga
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshi Kobayashn
EDITOR.
Terumltsu Okada
CHIEF DIRE'Cm'R.
Ken]: Kudfinm
PkODWCEfi'W.
TMS Fnte'rtammcnt, Ltd.
In summation n llh
Yomiun TelecistmU Corporation
fiETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
YTV / ms
All I; t Réserved
doesithur
You're bleeding 8 lot from your leg.
I'm alright...
that isn't my blood..--
That's right...
this is his blood...
he put it on me so that
I'd be taken away from there...
it seems youéve repaid your debt to me,
waven't you, Kudo.
Please get it qunckly!
Unable to continue search
as unforeseen situation has occurred.
The target did not show
We will resume
investigatiomin a few days...
Overt
PREVIEW
It looks like he fell from
is own apartment...
PREVIEW
Did he slip whil'é going-Jo
and from the veranda?
PREVIEW
Hmm.
I think the door bell's broken...
PREVIEW
Mr. Yoshimura's
death wasn't an accident!
PREVIEW
He was murdered
- Next episode is
Was it-Murdemor an Accident?"