Even one's destiny gives us a clue
to the mystery.
The most puzzling case becomes
transparently clear.
Today 3 case occurs
in a regular condominium.
There's a twist to the strange accident.
He sees through the one & only truth.
A child in appearance with the IQ.
Of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
Was it Murder or an Accident?
Good grief,
Ran says she's going to see a move
so she dumps
Conan on me!
Think of me as your lucky charm.
What do you mean?
Well, every time you solve a case,
I'm always with you.
You're cra «!
It was all just coincidence!
May I help you?
Huh?
Are you Mr. Mourl?
Yes...
you must be Mr. Ueda!
Please sit down.
Thank you...
Oh, I'm sorry my cigarette
does it bother you?
Yes...
Hot coffee please.
Yes, right away.
Actually, it's about a colleague of mine,
Dr. Yoshimura,
George Ueda
(Doctor)
FIEBIEXISEFD
we both work at the same
university hospital...
George Ueda
(Doctor)
U Pu n
- Mammal!
Are the prank calls still; coming?
Theyx'se'em to-getting wo'rs'e.
At first, a threatening letter arrived, then
But lately, threatening telephone calls
have been coming in
When he goes out, he's followed, he's
become a nervous wreck.
I'm so worried he might commit
a terrible medical mistake.
I don't blame you for worrying.
Dr. Yoshimura says he doesn't
Understand What it's all about either.
I want to hire you to look.for the
culprit and find out why he's doing this.
I understand.
You can leave it to Kogoro Moun!
First off,
I think it would help
if I spoke to the victim, Mr. Yoshimura
and got all the details from his personally.
I'm going to see if that Dr. Yoshimura
is in his room
Hello, Yoshimura'? It's me!
He was In his room. I'll take you there...
This is the place; Mr. Mourl...
Yoshimura lives in the corner
unit on the 5th floor.
Shall we go up?
Gggggh
What was that just now?!
This way!!
Hey Conan
What in the world
Why this is!
Sir! Call an ambulance!
Uh. . .right!
Yoshimura!!
What did you say?!
Tr]?!
Yes, this is Mr. Yoshimura,
Mitsuo Yoshimura
(Doctor)
Yes, this is Mr. Yoshimura,
Mitsuo Yoshimura
(Doctor)
$155555 (25)
. FiDBABBID
Mitsuo Yoshimura!
Mitsuo Yoshimura
(Doctor)
$155596 (25)
U. c flu u b
-§DBABEW
Mltsuo Yoshlmura
(Doctor)
in awe (25)
be e urea u I
IIBEXEB'I'E
Yoshimura!!
Hey Yoshimura, snap out of it!
Yoshimura!
Yoshimura!!!
What does this mean...
The deceased is Mitsuo Yoshimura,
A 25 year old male
He was employed as a doctor
at the city's medical university
The key to his apartment was
found in his pocket
So Mr. Mouri, you were
hired by Mr. Yoshimura
And just happened to witness
the accident, is that right?
IUD...
according to his friend Mr. Ueda
Mr. Yoshimura was
apparently being threatened
I see!
Mr. Yoshimura's apartment
Is on the 5th floor
it's the unit at the extreme end
I guess he fell from his own apartment
We'll be going to his apartment now!
We may be able to
determine how he fell.
I know it's your job but we really
appreciate your cooperation
It's really no problem
Ryoji Hara
The situation being as it is...
VUJBVQIQA
I'm so sorry about Mr Yoshimura
What oes?
No one's here either
For secufl \ Reasons»
we've programmed the elevator
To stop on every floor at night...
I see, but it must be very
irritating when you're in a hurry.
It us
That's why the late Mr. Yoshimura always
used the emergency stairs
Of the warehouse on the next
building when he was in a hurry.
The stairs on the building next door?
He's right
The distance between his apartment
And the warehouse stairwell
is perfectly jumpable...
I warned him several
times he shouldn't but...
5th floor...
Excuse me, officer
Would it be alright if I changed?
My apartment's on the next floor
If you need me for something
I think it'll be alright,
When you're done changing, please
come to Mr. Yoshimura's apartment
I most certainly will
It's May but this year's pretty chilly.
You're so right...
A glass of whiskey & water...
It looks like he was drinking alone.
It seems he didn't feel safe
anywhere else...
Besides the hospital where he
worked & this apartment.
Now that you mention it, recently...
Some very suspicious looking
en were following him around...
They'd go to his apartment in the
middle of the night sometimes.
According to Mr. Ueda
The threatening phone calls came at
all hours, there was no pattern.
Hmmmm
Why it's...
Is the veranda Mr. Yoshimura
always used to get in & out?
Yes, that's right.
Mr. Yoshimura kept a pair of sandals
Here all the time & came &
went through here...
I warned him against it many times...
Inspector...
The apartment was locked & his key
was found in his pocket!
On top of that, the lights...
In the room were all on & there're
no signs of a struggle!
It appears the death was accidental,
A result of Mr. Yoshimura's
carelessness.
That theory does appear very credible...
A sandal...?!
How'd it get way over there.
Wait a minute...
It's not the roof...
Which means...
See...
Thank you very much.
Rats, so it was a prank call.
Hey
This door bell's not working...
Mr. Uedal- Mr. Ueda!
Yes?
Excuse me,
I'm so thirsty,
May I have some water?
Oh, sure
No problem...Come on in.
Thanks!
Wait here, sit wherever you want
Thank you
You know Mr. Ueda,
a flower delivery man was just here...
Yes,
I think someone~played a prank on them.
Really?...
What's the matter, kid?
You shouldn't be up there, it's dangerous!
Come back here.
Oh alright.
Here's some juice
Thank you
After you finish that,
Iet's both go to where
Mr. M'ouri is waiting.
Okay!
Mr Ueda, are you hot?
You're perspiring so much.
I perspire easily.
I'm going to the restroom,
why don't you finish your drink.
Okay.
I wonder what left that mark...
What is this...
Hey r!
There's another other there...
and over there too.
On the bed...
table & sofa too...
I see,
now I understand!
What do you think you're doing?
Eh...!? Uh...
I forgot something in
the room downstairs,
I'm'going to get it!
Good grief...
Hey!
You shouldn't do that,
we're still checking the scene.
I'm sorry!
Actually, I came here to give you a
message from Mr. Mourn...
From Mr. Mourl'?
He said...
Uh huh, yes, yes...
Yes, I understand!
I'll go right away,
but you must t touch
anything in this apartment.
Okay!
I knew it...!
There's no mistake about it...!
Mr. Yoshimurals death
wasn't an accident!
He was murdered
I regret having to say this,
but as Mr. Mouri deduced,
it appears Mr. Yoshimura's
death was an accident.
For some reason,
when he tried to jump from his
veranda to the warehouse,
he must have tripped.
How unfortunate
and just when you were
coming to see him...
Mr. Ueda,
didn't you call him & tell him
we were on our way?
Yes...
Then I wonder why he would go 'out'?
Children shouldn't butt in!
If you're going to bother us,
you can wait outside!
Oh alright.
I guess I have no choice...
I'll have to put him to sleep for awhile...
Uh oh...
Huh?
What's wrong, Mourl'?
Inspector,
I think it's too soon to leave.
What?!
There are several suspicious
details that need clearing up,
before we dismiss this as
a simple accidental death.
Mr. Yoshimu [81:5 apartment was locked
but the door chain wasn't on...
don't you think that it's strange for
a man who was being threatened...
Yes, that's true...
Another thing,
if he was sitting in his living room having
a drink just prior to falling to his death,
isn't it strange that
all the ice was melted?
Hey Mourl
what are you trying to say?
Mr. Yoshimura wasn't
in his apartment when he fell.
That's ridiculous!
Théfimwhere do you think he was?
The key to that question
is Mr. Yoshimura's sandal.
His sandal?
On the victim's foot
He wore sandals on his left foot
But his right was bare.
The missing side,
was on the roof of the warehouse
next door & pretty far in too.
Even if he'd tripped while trying
to jump to the emergency stairs,
I doubt the sandal would fly all
the way to condominium roof there,
he'd have had to fall from
above the 5th floor.
I'd guess the roof!
But the door to the roof was locked!
Are you sure!?
Then that means...
If it wasn't from the roof,
then there's only one
other place I can think of...
You're not implying...
I am. Inspector,
Mr. Yoshimura didn't fall from
his apartment on the 5th floor,
he fell from this
apartment on the 6th floor!
Mr Ueda...
You caused it to happen, didn't you!
Th, that's absolutely absurd
Detective Chiba, will you help me?
Sure.
First, move the television
to the corner of the room
Is this alright?
Fine!
Next, move the table to the center of
the room & put the chairs on both sides
And finally,
move that bed against the wall.
Mouri, hold it right there
A bed's too heavy to move...
Just you wait & see...
Cl]...!
Eh...!?
This bed has casters so it's easy to move
Now Inspector,
Iook at this room carefully,
Haven't you seen this
exact same setting somewhere before?
Everything's set up like
Mr YoshirfiUra's,ap'artment; #501
Mr. Ueda rearranged his
apartment in this manner,
He made Mr. Yoshimura
think thus was his apartment
But Mr. Mourl,
the furniture's not the same!
That's right,
but If you were to wake up In dark,
you wouldn't notice right away that
you were m someone else's place.
That's how,
you got Mr. Yoshimura to
fall to his death from the window.
Just a minute!
When Yoshimura fell,
I was with you, Mr. Mouri, remember?
That's right...
you used me as your alibl.
But if I were with you,
how did I make Yoshimura fall,
tell me that?
You knew Mr. Yoshimura had a habit of
using the warehouses emergency stairs,
so you used this fact to stage your trick!
You were probably drinking with
Mr. Yoshimura in his apartment,
drugged him with something that
Could snap hin out of quickly,
jUSt in case something happened.
Something weak like
a sleep inducing drug.
After he fell asleep, you carried him
to this apartment & put him on the bed.
Mr. Yoshimura was mentally distraught,
you fooled him into thinking
he was in his own apartment,
then you left him there & came
to meet us at the coffee shop,
where you called him telling him that the
men threatening him were coming for him
And that he should get away from there!
And you had an accomplice.
Are you saying he had help?
Inspector Megure
This man has something to tell us.
My nameais Umemoto, I'm a florist.
Inspector Megure,
this is the accomplice...
Although he didn't realize
that he was aiding a murder.
Mr. Umemoto,
please tell everyone
what you did here tonight
Alright,
I received an order for flowers
to be delivered to Mr. Ueda in unit 601,
of this condominium tonight at 7 PM.
To this apartment?
Yes, I arrived at 7 and I'd been told,
that the buzzer was out of order
so I should knock when I arrived.
I did as I was instructed & pounded
on the door but no one answered.
So what did you do?
Well, there was nothing I could do,
so I made my other
deliveries & came back again,
That gentleman over there came to the
door & said that he didn't place any order.
Inspector Megure
Now do you understand?
Mr. Ueda's call scared Mr. Yoshimura,
then Mr. Umemoto the florist's timing
is perfect when he knocks on the door...
Mr. Yoshimura thinks it
is the men who are after him.
So he tries to jump to the
next building like he always does,
But, he's on the
6th floor & he doesn't make it...
he falls straight down.
That's ridiculous,
you have some imagination!
The reason you held
Mr Yoshimura up was,
to give yourself an excuse to go back to
your apartment rearrange the furniture.
That's why you said you wanted to
change out of your bloodied sweater.
The reason why you were perspiring
when Conan went to your place,
was you d been moving
the furniture all by yourself.
That's a lie! Can you prove any of this?
You want proof?
We have proof,
When you were in the coffee shop,
you said you didn't smoke Cigarettes.
And yet there're
cigarettes & an ashtray right there
Mr. Yoshimura's a smoker,
just in case he woke up
before time & wanted a cigarette,
you didn't want him wandering
around looking for an ashtray,
because that would make
him realize he wasn't in his own place.
That's why you
brought-one from his' place.
Mr. Yoshimura brought this
himself when he came to visit!
It doesn't prove anything
Inspector, please check the
incoming calls on that telephone.
Let's see now...
A call came in at 7:15...
Mourl,
the number is from a cellular phone.
It's probably Mr. Ueda's number...
it's the call he made
from the coffee shop
Oh, I see!
Hey, hold on just one minute!
I called my apartment
by mistake that time...
Oh really,
then why is your call to Mr. Yoshimura
recorded on his telephone
How did you confirm that
Mr. Yoshimura was in the apartment?
You must ve been positive that;
you wouldn't be suspected,
since you were with us all along,
you thought his death would bewritten
off as a simple accident, didn t you.
That's why you didn't think
we'd ever Check his telephone.
Is that true, Mr. Ueda'?
The truth is,
I bought some stock & lost a lot of money,
Just when I needed money,
Y'oshimura came to me
with a no fail proposition.
His plan was that I'd steal drugs
from the university & he'd sell them...
Sol did like he said, I got my
share of the money & that tided me over,
but then he said that if I didn't do it again,
he threatened to tell
the university about me...
I was afraid I'd be dragged in too deep
so I started planning how to get rid of him
Just about the same time,
I heard that he was being threatened
by some bad business partners,
so I decided to use that.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Muchnhuko Suwa
Masahlto Yoshloka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Ka'tsfii') Ono
CHARACTER DE§IGNS BY
Mas'atom'o Sudo
STORY EDITOR
Junlchl Iloka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazun'an Kouchl
Jumchl Mlyashlta
YUIChl ngure
TOShlkl lnoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS.
Masatomo Sudo
Ieotoshl Takatam
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushn Aono
Aklo Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yuklhlro Sh'butam
Takashl Nomura
Ieonobu Horlkoshl
Takahlsa Owaga
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshl Kobayashl
EDITOR.
Terumltsu Okada
CHIEF DIRE'C'TOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY.
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
m association With
Yomlurl Telecasting Corporation
OGosho Aoyama / Shogakukan
YTV / TMS
Case solved, eh?
Uncle, listen, you sneezed earlier
too, are you catching a cold?
No, my nose is just itchy, that 3 all...
As for you,
you'd better not catch
a cold & cause us trouble.
I wouldn't talk...
IjUSt remembered Conan!
Come with me tomorrow too!
Eh? You're working tomorrow too?
You are such 3 Too.!
Somehow whenever
you're with me, I have luck!!
I feel like I could win
big at the horse races!!
Like that will ever happen!
Smoke from the incinerator!
What's that?
That's strange,
there were 2 blue
cushions the last time I looked
there's one more now...
What's the meaning of this?
(mg)