Even destiny serves as
emulate deduction.
And the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case
Three cute doggies
and four fishy breeders.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with
the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
Ong hlLos Angeles/San Diego
If!»
The Nonvanishing Evidence Part I
Wow~~How cute
He's a male Shiba Dog.
What's his name?
Te ruya Kan'oh
(Son of Dr. Agasa's Friend)
Arthur!
Teruya K'anoh
Son of Dr. A asa'xs Emend
fiffliQE/KOQ
Teruya K'anoh
(Son of Dr. Agasa's Friend)
fiflz'tOJZEAwE?
We named him after
Sir Arthur Conan Doyle,
Teruya AK'anoh
(Son of Dr. Agasa's Friend)
fimtofiAmn
the creator the renowned detective,
Sherlock Holmes!
Teruya Kanoh
(Son of DJ]. Agasais Eniend)
fifliOEACDE-s-
the creator the renowned detective,
Sherlock Holmes!
If he joins up with Conan,
it'll be the start of the world's
greatest detective agency, won't it!
Hey, hey, me join up with a dog?
Sounds good!
It's a very cute girlish concept!
You're too picky.
All right, all right.
Well, it's been 10 year
since I've been here
and this town has really changed.
Did you find the new parking lot?
That area resembles a we-like pattern
and is very complicated...
Ai navigated 'me using the map
sol didn't get lost.
Hey, Arthur, stop it, will you!
Strange, he rarely gets excited
and barks like this...
Um, Doc...
Huh?
Didn't you touch a dog
before you came here....?
Moreover,
a male dog
that is larger than this Shiba dog.
Y,Yeah,
together with An,
I saw a Doberman that a friend of mine
brought along with him this morning...
But, why?!
You had dog hair on your slacks.
Moreover, dogs are able to tell the
size and sex of another dog by smell.
Among male dogs,
when they find that there is
another dog bigger than themselves,
a sense of enmity is aroused at times.
Besudes,
you and Ai came over to this gate once,
were told by Mr Kanoh
to go park your car again,
and then came back, right?
Therefore,
Arthur got the mistaken impression
that you and Ai are his owner's enemy,
because despite
being shooed away once,
you came back again.
Oh...is that why
You're not too bright, are you?
You seem to resemble,
Conan when it comes to being
slightly absentminded, don't you?
Hey. hey...
Well, I guess it can't be helped,
because his mistaken impression is
due to his natural behavior as a dog.
Dangerous people
who are not of his kind...
In my case...
maybe he's not all that mistaken...
H,Hey .Al...
Just kidding!
And, one more thing
There is one other
reason why Arthur barks...
Huh?
It's your voice when
you hold Arthur down
Yoshio Tsunashima
You're too soft!
Yoshuo Tsunashnma
Yoshio Tsunashima
When you scold him
you've got to be stern.
Yoshio Tsunashima
8 Bl» fl
Otherwise, the dog will think you,
the master is cheering him on.
Yoshio Tsunashima
Otherwise, the dog will think you,
the master is cheering him on.
So, keep that it mind, will you.
Y,Yes, sir.
Who is he?
He is Mr. Tsunashima
who I met at the Dog Lovers Club!
He's here for the same
reason as you are, Dr. Agasa!
Wow~how nice!
Oooh-ucomb'.
This plane is mine!
This doll for me!
This antique hour-glass is for me then
But, are you sure you don't mind?
They look so expenswe...
Of course not...
Those are just objects that,
my grandfather bought and collected
as a pastime While traveling abroad...
Although all three of us in
the family have no interest in antiques,
we wouldn't feel right
selling his things off either, so...
Therefore, both my parents decided,
to give them away to our acquaintances...
Come to think of it,
where are they. . .?
They've both gone over to the new house,
that was just built and are getting
ready to move, so they're not here...
I'm going to be moving to
England because of work,
so my parents are going
to move to the country,
where my father's
youfi'ben bro'th'éflives...
That's why,
I'm trying to clear all kinds
of things out of this house!
Oh...
The only thing I'm going to
take with me to England is Arthur,
all that my parents will
be taking with them"is...
my mother's dear dog, Doyle here.
It's a Papillon!
If there's an Arthur and 8 Doyle,
There must be 3 Conan too?
My father had a dog named Conan,
but it med of an mess 2 years ago.
I...see...
But, no problem,
because we've got Conan with us.
Just what do you mean, Ayuml...
But, the name Papillon
is sure a funny name...
Papillon means butterfly in French!
They were really hailed by
the Imperial Court of
France in the 16th Century.
It is said that Marie Antoinette
also owned a pet Papillon.
A fine coat of fur indeed!
It's no surprise that he was
awarded the championship award!
Championship award?
He just happened to win the award at
the contest my mother entered in.
Well, this dog is fine dog indeed
that there were people asking to by him
for a million yen on the spot.
A,A million yen-LA
Really,
what a gracious and refined dog he is.
He is so much like the spoiled, selfish
and beheaded Queen of France...
M, Ms. Tosabayashl?
Aki Tosabayashu
The front door was open
Aki Tosabayashl
ifZEfi/ =F (39)
so I took the liberty of letting
myself in
Aki Tosabayashl
because you mother told me that she'd
give me anything I want.
As for this living room the only thing that
I'm interested in is that large flower vase.
You people can go help yourselves
for all I care.
No offense,
but I'm going to hunt around on my own.
Is;she';'a member of
your dog lovers club too?
IUD...
she wasn't like that before, though...
Phooey.
She's jus't all sul _\ because her dog lost
to Doyle at the contest!
Oh, no, no...!
I can't have that lady claiming the clock
in the Japanese room
that I reserved for myself!
I'll have to stick a note on that clock
noting that it's already reserved...
Hey! Why don t you get yourself
something too, An?
HUN!
I say we should take this opportunity to
go help ourselves!
There are a lot of interesting things here!
I guess so...
Maybe I should takenDfiSer...
Huh?
Because if I am put to the guillotine
and diéappgarkéym'ist like Marie...
don't you think this dog will come after me
and jump iritbAheFrS'ein'e
as did, her dog?
Ri ht?
Hey, hey, come on...
S,She sure is quite an odd girl,
isn't she...
Oh, yes, sort of...
Hey, Shinichl,
can't you cheer her up a bit!
I really had a hard time bringing Al,
who refused leave the house
after that bus incident, you know...
Strange...
after the incident,
I called her on the phone and told
her not to worry since no suspicious
or unidentified people
came up during'fiolice interrogation.
But, the way she's freaked out,
is not normal.
She even refuses to eat.
She doesn't seem to be sleeping much
at night either...
The only thing I can say for sure now
is that
even if there were any men on that bus,
who were members of the men ir'fgblé'Ck,
it was mere coincidence
and not because
they knew of her existence)...
It's been 10 days since then alneady.
If it weren't a coincidence,
we would've been killed by now...
Including you and them too,
because you were all there tob...
What the...?!
Hey, hey, not again, you guys...
Mr. Agasa, if you find something
you want, please feel free to take it too!
0,Oh, I guess so...
Oh...then...
I guess I'll take this stereo.
Agh, I'm sorry
Somebody has already reserved that...
Huh?
A,Arthur'?!
No, you can't come/U'p'=f wtth
dirty feet like that
H,Hey!
What is it Arthur?
AHéy!
All right, all right,
I get the message, so let go of me,
Arthur!
What is It, of all things...
Oh...
I'm sorry...
I pushed the door bell many times,
but it seems to be broken...
Shino Hasukl
Arthur was nice enough to go
and get you...
Shino Hasukl
so, please don't scold him.
Oh, no,
I'm very sorry for not knowing
you had come...
(30 can; and play with-Arthur
Wow, they really get along, don't they!
A Shetland Sheep Dog!
Yes,
her name's Christie!
I see
the King and Queen in a detective story...
By chance, is she the one...
who reserved that stereo set'?
Yes...
I thought it'd be a good gift to give to
my younger brother
in celebration df his enrollment
into high school.
If you ask me, the sooner you separate
the two dogs, the better.
Huh?
You can't sell cross breed babies
for a high price!
Needless worry,
because Arthur is going to be leaving
for England soon,
right Kanoh'?
Yes...
Agh...
I wonder what's got unto Doyle?
It's his snack time...
What ?!
My grandfather liked dogs a lot too.
My mother, in an attempt to Show
Doyle to late grandfather,
used to feed Doyle snacks in front of
the Buddhist altar in the Japanese room...
And, Doyle acquired the habit of doing
so ever since.
So, when the clock in the Japanese room
strikes 12:00 noon,
he runs over to the room,
sits on the cushion and waits
A cushion?!
Yes,
Doyle loves the blue cushion,
so he bring it in front of the altar himself.
But, doesn't the clock ring
at 00:00 midnight too?
What happens if Doyle mistakenly brings
the cushion then?
That's no problem
because we asked the clock maker
to fix the clock
so that it would only ring at 12:00 noon...
Are you sure you don't mind me taking
such a precious clock with me?
IUD...
because mother also mentioned that
it's about time we stop pampering Doyle
and start feeding him only twice a day,
in the morning and at night.
Oh, I guess it's all right then...
Go ahead and look through that space.
Doyle is sitting there, isn't he?
On the blue cushion...
Doyle's not there...
The blue cushion is not out either...
Huh?
Maybe he couldn't pull out
the blue cushions
because there in
between the brown ones?
No, because he usually pulls
the blue cushion out
from under the others with
his mouth and puts it on the floor...
Strange. .I wonder where,;.heT~-Went...'?
Anyway, let's split up and look for him!
What if he's stucktsome
place and cannot come out!
Yes...
Doyle
Where are you 7!
Come out here, Doyle!!
Doyle
He's nowhere intsight.
Uh, did you find him?
No, we didn't!
We even looked in the bath tub
Arthur's barking!!
Christie's barking too!
The back yard!
Let's go!!
S,Smoke is coming out of the incmerator!
We've stopped using that
incinerator long time ago...
D,Don't tell me that...?!!
Shoes?!
It can t be...It can't be...
A c,collar'?!
D,Don't tell me that's...
Doyle's...
It can't be...It can't be...
Doyle...
Doyle! Doyle!
Doyle
Don't worry...
What?!
Only this collar was burned...
There was no dead body
of a dog in the incinerator...
By the way,
is this really Doyle's collar?
I didn't see anything just a while ago...
Y,Yeah...
It's usually covered with
his fur and is not visible...
It's burnt black, but I'm sure of
the color and the print on it...
Grandpa bought this collar,
in France for the Papillon,
that he used to own.
It's very old...
Please take a look over here!!
Hun /
The lock of the back door is open!
Oh yes, really...
Isee...
The one who took Doyle away,
fled from this back gate...
But, why?
Why'was the collar in the ifibinerator?
The one who took Doyle
away took off the collar
so that it would be hard
to tell one Papillon from the other.
Besides, that collar was a
unique collar with decoration on it...
I don't think so.
HUM.
Because why would somebody who
steals a dog and'is in a rush to flee
go out of the way to burn a
collar which is covered under the fur
that can't be seen and leave
traces of how he or she escaped?!
I'm sure that the one who did it
wanted to make it look like
he or she fled outside of the premises!
Which means that Doyle is still...
Yeah...It's most likely that Doyle is
being hidden somewhere in this house!
H,Hey, does that mean...
Don't tell me that the person who
hid Doyle is still in this house...
Hey, hey, don't tell me
that you suspect us?
Oh, no, but...
But, if it's as that boy's says,
we already have a
definite idea of who did it...
Look over there.
Those ladies shoes
Those are mine... .Why'?!
Come on, let's not play dumb!
Aren't those your shoes that you
brought from the front entrance?
N,No.
That can't be
The criminal would never leave
shoes out like that, and besides,
if someone is seen carrying
their shoes in the house,
anyone would deem that
person to be acting suspicious...
Ms. Hasuki, you've been here more
than one or two times, haven't you?
T,That's right...
If so, that you could've
trained Christie to bring your
shoes from the front entrance to here,
then back to the front
entrance again, right?
That's r,ridiculous'?!
Anyway, let's go
and look for Doyle again!
We'll go with him,
so...why don't you three go and
search for Doyle together, Doc!
0, Okay...
But, Conan, how are
we going to look for the dog?
We've looked practically all
over the house just a while ago!
That's why this time we donét'search
for places where dog might hide,
but we look for places where
humans would hide them!
That'.s night! Let's('ave Arthur help us!
Don't you get it...?!
His nose! Knows!
We'll make him help us by using the
best weapon he has, which is his nose!
A dog's nose is a 100x more capable
of sniffing out smell than that of humans!
So, if we make Arthur sniff Doyle s smell,
I'm sure he will help us find him!
Here it Is!
The cushion used in Doyle's bed!
Come on Arthur!
But...he's not a police dog...
But, it may work!
Because father used to play around
with Arthur doing things like this.
I think he's found him!!
He's going into the Japanese room!
Doyle is in there, then!!
Huh?
A blue cushion?
Come to think of it, Doyle likes
blue cushions too, doesn't he?
Do dogs Ilke blue?
HUN (
That's strange...
just a while ago there were only
two blue cushions.
Counting the one that Arthur
brought our, makes three blue cushions...
One extra cushion...
What does this all mean...
Maybe he can't do it, after all...?
Uh, did Arthur ever do
something like hide shoes?
No, he once did the opposite, though...
It was back when
Arthur was still a puppy...
When I stood up, Arthur, thinking
that I was going to take him for a walk,
would rush over to the front door,
take my shoes out of the shoe
cabinet and bringing it to me...
But, once he found out that it wasn't
always the case, he stopped doing it.
But, that's fantastic
Arthur is no ordinary dog, after all!!
Go ahead and sniff
Doyle's smell once more!
Oh! There he goes!
But, he's stopped in
front of the living room...
He looks to be thinking.
Oh...he's walking again.
He's heading for the front entrance!
Huh'? He's gone outside...
Maybe Doyle was taken outside!!
Oh, come on, all he's doing
is frolicking with Christie.
Maybe he's just tired
of searching already!
I,I guess it can't be helped
Uh...is there any place that Doyle
usually hides whenhe's scolded?
Huh?
Maybe when the person
removed the collar by force,
Doyle got scared and hid
somewhere on his own?
Hmm~~Arthur used to
hide under my bed a lot.
Under the bed?
Yeah, when I first got Doyle,
I used scold Arthur 3 lot...
When I was hugging Doyle
as a puppy in the living room,
Arthur used to get jealous and tear the
cushion in the living room apart...
They get along now, though...
Oh...l wonder where Doyle
is hiding though.
Poor thing if he's
trembling in fright somewhere...
Right.
The people who are looking for you,
are bound to find you one day.
There 3 nothing tougher
than to live in terror hiding...
Hey!
That's enough! What are you all
sulky about?
No...
I'm just trying to tell an optimist
with no real strategy prepared,
of the dangerous situation involved
here...
I don't know for what reason,
but what I know for sure is that
one of their men were on that bus!
If they even had the slightest
notion of'my identity back then,
me, you and everyone else...
Don't worry about it! I can assure
you that you haven't been identified...
Why?! How can you be so sure?!
Just as you can sniff
them out, I just know!
I can tell when someone has
a threatening air about them.
I guess you could call it
the intuition of a detective.
Well, if I were able to tell who
possesses this threatening air,
I wouldn't have problems...
But, I know for sure that no such
person was on board that bus.
That is, the person that is making
you feel threatened...
What's with that look on your face...
Do you despise detectives or what?
No, I'm just totally bored!
Oh, I see...
Let me recall once again...
back when Doyle disappeared...
Doyle, at the chime of the
clock which struck 12:00,
headed for the Japanese room
where he could get his snack,
and disappeared from our view...
After that...
we all followed Mr. Kanoh who went into
the kitchen to get the cheese snack...
Then we went to the Japanese room
and found that Doyle was not there.
So, we split up and looked all
over the house for Doyle...
This is approximately how
the layout 'ofthe house is...
We don't really know
who searched where yet...
But, where on earth did
the person hide Doyle...
And how in the world is that person
planning to carry Doyle out of here?!
Omcmfiwcowc BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODU ERS
Michlh'lko 50wa
Masahito Yoshioka
Katsuo Ono
Masatomo udo
Junlchl hoka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan Kashuwabara
Kazunan Kouchn
Jumchl Mlyashlta
YUIChl Hloure
Toshlkflnoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
sMasatomo Sudo
Hirotoshl Takatam
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takafhl Hyodo
RT DIRECTER:
Wklhlro Shlbutam
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashl Nomura
Ieonobu Horlkoshl
Takahlsa Ogawa
REC RDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshl Kobaxashl
EDITOR.
Terumltsu Okada
Ken]: Kbdama
R6DUCED
TMS Entertainment, Ltd
In association With
YOmlUl'I Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan - Y'W - TMS
All Rights Reserved
Want a sec when I looked a while ago.
Hmm~what's this cotton like thing?
It looks like some sort of chemical fiber.
What is the matter Conan?
Was Doyle burnt In there after all .g
see... That's what the person used...
T,Thls IS the sound of...
The sound of the wall
clock in the Japanese room...