Even destiny serves as
a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces through
the most mysterious case.
Champion dog Doyle disappears.
The real faces of the breeders
are revealed.
He sees through the one and only truth
A Child in
appearance with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
We visited the residence of
Teruya Kanoh, a friend of Dr. Agasa
whotinyited us over
because-he wanted to give away
things he didn't need to his friends,
before moving to England.
At his house, we meet his friends
Mr. Yoshio Tsunashima,
Ms. Aki Tosasbayashl,
and Ms. Shino Hasukl.
Amidst the exchange of
various complicated feelings,
one of the Papillons,
named Doyle disappears out of the blue!
Moreover,
the burnt black piece of Doyle's collar,
that has been cut with a knife is found
in the incinerator!
D,Don't tell me that's...
Doyle s...
No...It can't be...
No ..It can't be...
Huh?
That's strange...
JUSt a while ago
there were only blue cushions.
Counting the one that Arthur brought oVer,
makes three blue cushions...
One extra cushion...
What does this all mean...
The Non-Vanishing Evidence Part II
Doyle,
at the chime of the clock
which struck 1200 noon,
headed for the Japanese room
here he could get his snack
and disappeared from our view...
After that.
We all followed Mr Kanoh who went into
the kitchen to get the cheese snack
Then
we went to the Japanese room
and found that that Doyle was not there.
So, we split up
and looked all over the house for Doyle...
This is approximately
how the layout of the house is
We don't ream know
who searched where yet...
But,
where on earth
did the person hide Doyle..
And,
how in the world is that person
planning to carry Doyle out of here?!
Looks like your time to
prepare to move IS running out.
Yes. . .that's ok.
Move?
you said that you're giving us
the things you don't need
because you're going to be moving away
but can we take the things we want,
home with us today?
Y,Yeah...sure...
Are all the other people going to take
their things home with them today too?
N04.
I'm going to be sending Mr. Tsunashima's
clock to his residence tomorrow.
Ms. Hasuki's stereo will be sent to
her house 10 days later,
which will be the day before I move...
I never use any of the stuff,
so I told them
that I could send the goods right away,
but they both came today
because I happened to find
more antui'ques in the closet
and they wanted to take a look.
Debl ll
ayashl
As for Ms. Tosabayashi who showed up
out of the blue today,
ayashl
Judging from her personality and all,
Jdebl ll
I'm sure she's going to take
that flower vase home with her today...
That flower vase
if I remember correctly was
in the living room!
Don't tell me that...!
Doyle is in that...
Of course not...
A living creature couldn't possibly
be hidden in a stereo
that is supposed to be shipped out
10 days from now, either...
The wall clock in the Japanese room...
It's impossible to hide a dog
in there either...
HUD.
That clock is 5 minutes slow...
HUN?
Strange...
after it was repaired,
it was always accurate...
Wait a sec...
Wheml looked a while ago .
What's this cotton like thing?
It looks like some sort of chemical fiber...
Hey,
Iet me see it...
This is...
That glittering cotton was
on the blue cushion
that Arthur was holding too...
W Wait a sec...
Come to think of it, I've seen this
some place too...
T,The incinerator
What's the matter Conan?
Was Doyle burned in there, after all?
When I saw it a while ago,
I just thought it was plain trash,
but this is definitely glass wool!
It's sound absorption material
I see...
so, that's what the person used
Uh, Conan!
I've figured out where Doyle is hidden,
as well as how and why.
I've also figured out who did it too!!
It's this late already...
I've got to get going home.
Me too,
since I've ot to start
getting dinner ready...
P,Please wait
Well, I guess you were just unlucky.
I suggest you forget about that doggie.
0 Oh. no...
T,This is the sound of...
The clock in the Japanese room...
It's only supposed to ring at 12:00 noon...
What's going on?!
C,Conan'?!
It worked. Conan!
We'll go get things ready
in the living room, then!
Okay!
Get things ready?
We're going to try an experiment!
To see if the person
who hid Doyle could really do so
without being seen by anyone.
How foolish,
when we haven't even found Doyle yet...
Of course,
the star of the experiment is...
Doyle, here!!
Huh?!
«DoyleH
You found him!!
I'm glad
Okay,
Iet's start the experiment then.
Doyle disappeared from our sight...
from the corridor
in front of the front entrance...
Darn,
the dog's been found,
soianthatenough!
I don't have time to be fooling around
With a child's detectivesggame either.
Well, well...
Okay, Mitsuhiko, you can start!
R0 er!
N,Not again...
Yes, first Doyle...
after hearing the chlme of the clock,
headed for the Japanese roo'm
where he usually gets his cheese snack.
In the meantime, we went to the kitchen
before going to the Japanese room.
Right?
Y Yeah...
Then, where do you think Doyle is now?
This is ridiculous!
If he was given his snack as usual
in the Japanese room...
Where else would he be,
but the Japanese room...
He's not here...
Besides,
the sound of the chime
did not come from this room...
Oh, really.
W,What is going on...
The sound of the clock came from
thus Ilving room!
The living room...?
D,Don't tell me that's...
From the speaker of the stereo?!
IUD.
We rung the chime of the clock
a while ago, recorded it,
and played it on this stereo.
I used the tape recorder that was
in your room, brother!
Which means that Doyle, was lured to
the living room by the sound of the clock.
Just the sound won't do.
The cushion's got to be there too.
Cushion?
Remember,
you said that Doyle pulls out his own
cushion at snack time.
But,
the blue cushion that Doyle likes was
in the Japanese room just a while ago...
Doyle doesn't necessarily like
blue cushions!
A dog's ear can hear
four times that of humans,
its sense of smell is
far more superior than that of humans.
But its eyes can hardly tell
one color from the other
That's why Doyle always pulled out
the cushion
which had his smell on it at snack time,
and that cushion just happened to
be blue.
In other words,
Doyle was not waiting in the Japanese
room at 12:00 noon.
He was trained to think that
if he waited on the cushion
near the sound of the chime of the clock,
he could get his snack!
So,,
the person who schemed this took
advantage of Doyle's habit
and lured him out to the living room!
The cushion that Doyle always used had
bite marks oniit,
so it was also easy for the person
to tell~it apart!
But,
I came here to living room right away with
Mr. Tsunashima to look for Doyle,
but saw neither the
cushion nor the dog...
Ngnt/
R,Rlght...
There's a good place to hide Doyle...
Huh?
Look,
here behind the stereo
Behind the speaker
The person peeled off
the sound absorption material
that was stuck on to the inside of
the speaker beforehand.
Then the person put Doyle's cushion
in the space that was made,
and put the cheese on the cushion.
Of course the right speaker was rigged
so no sound came out from it...
And the left speaker was rigged
so that the sound of the clock that was
recorded beforehand would come out of it.
Doyle,
Iured by the smell of
the cushion and cheese,
as well as the sound of the clock,
went into the right speaker
where the back board was open.
In other words, he was lured inside!
If so. wouldn't he come out
after eating the cheese. ?
He was put to sleep with a sleeping pill
that was burled inside the cheese!
I wonder if it would work out
that smoothly...
Back then, the clock in the
Japanese room indicated 12:00 noon,
so the real chime should've been
ringing too...
I don't think it rang.
Because.
It was 12:00 midnight!
Huh?
That clock is made to ring
only at 12:00 noon.
If the hands of the clock
are moved up 12 hours,
the chime won't ring!
But, who would do something like that?!
Who else?
Hulk!
It can't be anyone else but
Ms. Hasuki who was going
to take this stereo with her, can it?
It, It can't be...
She was probably going to put
that doggie in the speaker and steal it.
0,Oh hofiifjlf'awoul "never. . .
W,Wait,
Ms. Hasuki would never do
a thing like that...
But, her shoes were
in the yard by the incinerator too.
But...
Ms. Hasuki IS not the one!
Ms. Hasuki is not the one!
What IS this boy talking about?
Because that stereo was going to
be sent out on Saturday, right?
No one would look a live dog in a
place like that!
If it's not Ms. Hasukl,
why would the dog have been
inside the speaker of the stereo...
The person who did it,
didn't want to steal Doyle,
but rather, just wanted Doyle
to disappear for a while.
Disappear for a while?
It maybe a blind spot, but if
the back board of the speaker is removed,
it would easily be noticed.
That's one of the places
anyone would look when searching...
Right...
That's why the person came first thing,
0 IS Mng room,
replaced the back board and hid Doyle...
Isn't that right, Mr. Tsunashima'?!
Since you said that you came here first
thing to look for Doyle,
it would've been easy for you to pretend
that you were searching
behind the speaker
and replace the back board, right?
Come to thunk of It, you said that
you looked behind the speaker and
didn't come over this side, didn't you?
H Hey...
I'm sure that .
you heard about Doyle's snacking habit
from Mr. Kanoh's parents.
As well as about the
stereo not being used much
And when you came to
this house before...
You peeled off the sound absorption
material behind the speaker
and had prepared a place to hide
Doyle beforehand!
All you had to say was that
the speaker didn't sound good to pretend
that you were trying to fix it.
Then nobody would suspect you.
If you were around when Doyle was
eating his snack
you could record
the sound of the chime too...
You put the tape and cushion
behind the stereo...
when Ms. Hasuki came before 1200,
and we were all gathered
at the front entrance
You then pretended to look for Doyle
and went around behind the speaker.
You removed the collar from Doyle,
who was asleep...
retrieved the cushion
and replaced the back board...
You then put the cushion back
into the Japanese room.
You returned the hands of the clock
that were moved up in time,
back to the accurate time.
You then burned the collar
in the incinerator
and left the back door open.
Because you wanted
everyone to think that
someone who snuck
into the house took Doyle
and fled from the back door!
I see...
It seems that you wanted to
burn the sound absorption material that
you peeled off in the incinerator but...
That's glass wool that is also used
as a heat insulator...
Most of it was left in the incinerator
without being burned!
I see,
that's why
when we made Arthur look for Doyle,
he brought the cushion
from the Japanese room...
Because it was Doyle s cushion
that was replaced.
But, why wasn't Arthur able to tell...
That Doyle was inside the speaker...
He knew but he couldn't go inside,
Because this room was a place
where he was scolded.v'ery harshly
in the past, and had bad memories about.
Oh...
But, sonny,
I gain nothing from hiding Doyle
inside the speaker...
What you wanted was not Doyle,
but this, that was on his collar,
right?
This gem stone...
This is quite an expensive item that...
Mr. Kanoh grandfather had bought
in France.
And, where did you find that?
Behind the pendulum of the wall clock
in the Japanese room!
When I looked at that clock at 12:00,
the time was accurate.
But, when I looked at 15:00,
it was off 3 minutes,
and when I looked at 17:00
it was off 5 minutes
The clock continued to delay
one minute an hour...
That's how I found out
there was something attached
behind the pendulum,
as well as the person who attached it
was the one who was to take
the clock home, Mr. Tsunashima.
And, that person is you!!
Darn!!
Mr. Tsunashlma'!
Darn...
Stop it, Arthur, don't!
You could never hit a dog
because you like dogs, don t you
That's why you didn't kill Doyle, right?
You didn't screw the back board
of the speaker back on
because you wanted Doyle to
be able to leave
when he woke up, right?
That's right, isn't it, Conan?
But, Mr. Tsunashima, why...?
Money...
I wanted money to take care of my dogs
that multiplied beyond expectation...
If so, you could've sold your dogs
anél redfi'ced'fithe'fido'g'sé'thatWESu fiw'ned'.!
The dogs that I have at home are mostly
mixed breeds that have been abandoned.
Selling them is out of the question.
There is nobody
who is willing to take them.
The only path left for them is.
To starve to death or be killed by drugs...
They only have one in two choices
Mr. Tsunashi'ma...
Mr. Tsunashima...
Here...
Huh?
You may have it...
No...but...
I'm not giving It to you...
I'm giving it to the dogs
that are at your house...
Mr Kanoh...
I'm so sorry...
No problem...
I'm sure m late randfather would
be more than happy to have you take it...
ORIGINAL 3 COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gas 0 Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michthlko Sum?
Masahlto Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER'DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo udo
(if! "r rid
Jumchl lloka
Gina us;?
Jumchl hoka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan Kashnwabara
Kazunarl KOUChI
Junlchl Mlyashlta
Ymchl ngure
TOShlkl Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
sMasatomo Sudo
Hirotoshl Takatanl
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushl Aono
Aldo Kan amura
Taka "hi Hy )do
{Kl UIKEL UK
thlhlro Shlbutanl
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashl Nomura
Ieonobu Horlkoshl
Takahlsa Ogawa
REC RDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kob'ayashl
EJTJR
Terumltsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kédama
TMS Entertainment, UH.
m assocuatlon mth
Yomiur: Telecasting corporation
Gosho Abyarfia / Shogakukan - YTV - TMS
All Rights Reserved
How audacious can you get!\
I feel sorry for the dogs that are.owned by
someone who cannot handle them!
Come now...
after all, he did promise
that he'll make sure
the number of dogs
he owns won't increase...
Arthur and Christie were both great,
weren't they!
They were like police dogs
when they cornered Mr. Tsunashima
who tried to flee
It's instinct!
All I'Ah'th'fi'rA-did was go after the person
Who pushed his master,
and Christie is a sheep dog to begin with.
Shetland Sheep Dogs are brought up to
bring sheep
that have gone astray from the flock,
back into the flock...
They have the habit of going around
and stopping anything
that suddenly runs off!
Talk about a wet blanket!
I can t figure out why...
Ms. Hasuki's shoes were on the ground
near the incinerator...
He's the one responsible.
Hide here a while, will you...
What're you doing , Conan?
Hey!! Arthur'!
Since when did you start doing
a thing like that?!
Hey, Arthur Are you listening to me?!
C 07.7
Arthur
I wonder if he doesn't Ilke me anymore?
No he just wants you to stay here
forever,
right, Arthur!
Remember, you said a while ago
that Arthur would bring your shoes
when he thought you were going to
flake him for a walk?
That's why Arthur came to think
that humans cannot go outside
unless they wear shoes!
He tried to hide your shoes
so that you wouldn't be able to
go home with Christie who he really likes!
Is that right.
But, don't worry, Arthur...
Christie and I have also ended up
having to go to
London just like your master .
Huh?
WhiCh means...
Yes...
that is what I came to tell you today!
Which means that
you're going to get married after all?
This calls for a celebration.
Congratulations, both of you!!
Congratulations
We've got to have a celebratory party
before the move, then...
Silly d'og...
Don't worry,
nobody s angry at you anymore...
All right
We were all worried about you!
Because you looked to be
so blue recently .
That's why we were trying to think up
a plan to cheer you up!
So, I'm not counted in?
Because you're always arguing with Al.
LRight, right.
Oh, okay .
You did it, Arthur!
Good work!
Right, you should always keep smiling
Iike that...
Huh?
As long as you're wearing
that facial expression
you look nothing but a child.
You look far from an old lady
approaching her 90 s that way!
Nah, only joke!
How rude!
I'm only 84.
Why .Why
is he lying on the ground
in such an unnatural posnion?
Uh, take a good look.
The wine bottles on the very top of
the low shelf are toppled...
But, nothing's wrong with the wine bottles
on the shelves on this side!
I've found conclusive evidence
I'm sure the criminal still has it!
The Locked Wine Cellar"