Even destiny serves
as a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces through
the most mysteriqus case.
Today's stage takes place
in a wine Cellar.
Aged wme IS the key to the crime.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
The Locked Wine Cellar"
what a wonderful collection
you have indeed
How pleasing to the eye!
so you're quite knowledgeable
about wine, Mr. M0url!
Oh, well, sort of...
Well,
Shohei Kusaka
(President of Finance Institution)
ha Nu
310005 A la, WSJVB
3:1!!an flR
jUSt as expected of a renowned detective,
to know of this collection
ShoheiKusaka
(President of Finance Institution)
as «u
an! IL Ii
Oh no~~~it's nothing like that...
This collection of labels is one that
a noble family of Europe had collected
over a long period of years
0,Oh...
Mr. Mouri seems to have done it.
I guess we won't be having wine
for a while then.
Huh?
Won't be haying-wine for a while...'?
Your father just...
complimented the collection, right?
Takeo
Then what happens is...
As if a switch is turned on,
he won't stop bragging
about the collection.
Jokichi Tonomura
(Sommelier)
5 we» 35
9M"! IE (om
Mouri is going to be stuck thére
for a while.
Jokichi Tonomura
(Sommelier)
UJEJ to
5441 IEMO)
0,Oh.
In other words, he's a wine freak...
Yukari Takano
(Art Gallery Owner)
Well,
Yukari Takano
(Art Gallery Owner)
(38)
.m3'-fl
all he does is repeat the same dialog
over and over.
Yukari Takano
(Art Gallery Owner)
BB 'ts D (38)
In?! - ♪
This is the gem of the whole collection
that is very hard to get a hold of...",
Iike so...
This is Moselle wine, a superb article
that is very hard to get a hold of.
0,Oh...
Most people get fed up with his boasting
and avoid coming to this party...
Your father was given
a handkerchief like this, wasn't he?
Yes.
He received a handkerchief with his
initials from Mrs. Kusaka a while ago.
Oh, so he did after all.
Everybody Kusaka takes a
Iiking to, gets one.
See, I got one too...
But, the worse is yet to come...
He's going to ke'ep inviting you
to come to his parties.
Well,
I advise you to tell your father
never to borrow money from Kusaka.
If he does, he won't be able. to
turn down attending the party
So, you've all borrowed money
from Mr. Kusaka'?
Oh w,well that's...
Hey, Conan!
You sure hit a sore spot, sonny...
You're absolutely right.
All three of us owe Kusaka money.
Mr. Nonaka borrowed money
for gambling...
Ms. Takano, for management funds
for the art gallery that she runs...
And me, for money to train myse'lnf
as a sommelier...
Oh, what are you all talking about?
Toshiko Kusaka
(Shohei's'Wife)
E'FR'FGJ!
Oh, what are you all talking about?
Toshiko. Kusaka
(Shohei's wife)
$3410)!
Toshiko Kusaka
(Shohei's wife)
FR-410)!
You all seem to be enjoying
the conversation
ToshikoKusaka
(Shohei's wife)
5mm 3
B'FR'FG)!
You all seem to be enjoying
the conversation...
Toshiko Kusaka
(Shohei's wife)
E'FH-'Fm!
You all seem to be enjoying
the conversation...
Toshiko Kusaka
(Shohei's wife)
E'FRSFGJ!
we were just talking about how nice it is
to come to Mr. Kusaka's party
because we'get drink fine wine here.
1My-
my husband would be so happy
to hear that.
By the way, Mrs. Kusaka
what do you say
we begin wine tasting soon?
He's so absorbed in Mr. Mouri that...
it seems he's forgotten about us...
All right,
I'll go tell him right now.
Please do so
That's right!
Now that you're here, let me show you
my wine cellar in the basement!
Huh?!
Oh, well...
I've got my best wines put awayitherew
Ah, dear...
Hmm?
Tahe other guests are waiting for you
0 tor-start wine tasting.
Oh, no!
I had completely forgotten!
Thank God...
Hi, everybody,
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting
I thought the party was going to end
the way things were going.
Pardon me for my rudeness.
Right! What do you say that we...
change plans for Wine tasting
and have Mr. Tonomura, the sommelier
pick out the right wine?
well, it does sound interesting, but...
If he's a sommelier it's only natural
that he chooses all the wines correctly.
Well,
if Mr. Kusaka sugge'St's so, he must have,
some very secret item in his possession;
It is only natural for asommelier
to get the names of the wines right,
but If he misses, he loses face.
Therefore, there's got to be some merit
for going through this...
Okay, then let's do this.
If'Mr. Tonomuna gets all the wines right,
I'll take on the you know what" thing...
I 366,
I guess I'll just have to do it then...
3 Okay, everyone, please enjoy yourselves
to your heart's content.
Here goes
Let me see...
Good wine...
This is Solaia
from the Toscana district in Italy...
Just as expected of you.
fWZIé
Oooh...
jUSt as expected of you Mr. Tonomura...
There's far more to go,
he's just warming up...
this is very rare wine indeed!
Chateau Latour, isn't it?
Moreover of 1965...
Well, utterly fantastic!
He sure is a true sommelier!
It's as if he knew what wines were going
to be given to him!
Not really, everything so far requires only
a beginner sommelier's knowledge.
Oh, well. well...
I'm so scary
that all the wine I have offered
you to taste so far were all for beginners
Let me give you
the best of my collection then!
Well, well,
so he rushes off to hlS pride
and joy wine cellar.
I feel a bit sorry for him.
H'éjUst getting
a taste of his own medicine.
Why don't we take
a short break, everyone?
I'm a bit pooped myself.
I'm going to get
a bit of fresh air and sober up
I guess I'll go to the restroom...
Boy, was I nervous, weren't you?
Yep.
Hmm~~~I can't tell at all...
Uh~~~Mr. Moun'?
Yes?
Don't you think Mr. Kusaka is taking
a bit too long?
Some 40 minutes have past
since he's gone...
Huh?
Has it been that long already...?
Uh, did you mention my husband...?
Oh, Mrs. Kusaka,
it's been 40 minutes since your husband
went down to the wine cellar
and he hasn't come back yet.
My--
I wonder what he's doing,
making his guests wait like this?
I'm so sorry, I go get him right away.
Mrs. Kusaka, let me go wuth you.
After all, something may have happened
Thank you, please do...
Hey, wait Conan!
Please be careful,
because the stairs is quite steep.
Y,Yes...
D,Dear?!
Whatff'saWrongyJ'.!
Mr. KusakaH
Mr. Kusaka!!
Are you all right?! Mr. Kusaka!!
Mrs. Kusaka,
where's the key to this room?!
here it is...
Mr. Mouri, how is my husband...
Mrs. Kusaka, please call the police.
Your husband's been killed!
Mrs. Kusa'ka
Mrs. Kusaka, please get
a hold of yourself!
Mrs KusakaH
Why...
Why is he lying
in such an unnatural position.
Why.
The victim IS Shohei Kusaka, age 52.
He is the man of this house and.
Runs a financial institution.
The cause of death is suffocation
due to strangulation by the rope
that was found around his neck
Can you explain the circumstances
when you found the body?
Yes, sir.
Since Mr. Kusaka did not come back
from the wine cellar for quite a while,
I came here to check on him
together with Mrs. Kusaka...
Then we found him lying on his back
on the floor...
And, what about the door, was it locked?
Yes.
Inspector!
Mrs. Kusaka told me that these are
the keys that Mr. Kusaka had on him
They are the key to the wine cellar
and to the house...
The door of the wine cellar auto locks,
and the only ones who had both keys
were Mr. and Mrs. Kusaka.
She's says there are no other spare keys.
So, the door auto locks...
Mr. Tome, How's the window over there?
Nothing here.
There is dust accumulated
on the dust shelf
and there are no traces of anyone
having broken in from outside...
Besides, as you can see, the handle
on this wmdow is on the inside,
it would be extremely difficult to open
and Close the window from the outside.
\ LsTIWTIM
Moreover, look there.
That's an alarm system,
so if the window is forced open, the alarm
system is set to go off immediately.
The switch to that alarm system is this.
When you push the switch of the remote
control that is attached to the keys.
The alarm system is turned off
and the window can be opened.
And, when the window is closed again,
the alarm system switches back on
Isee...
It'd be imposs'iblegor the killer
to go in and our of that window...
If so,
we can narrow down the killer quite a bit,
can't we, Inspector?
I mean, the killer is an acquaintance
of Mr. Kusaka.
The person probably had Mr. Kusaka
himself open the door
and came into the wine cellar,
then, committed the murder...
Wine bottles were probably cracked
and lying around Mr. Kusaka
beause the killer and Mr. Kusaka had
a fist fight or something?
Most likely!
But, wouldn't that be sort of strange too?
Because, look over there.
The wine bottles all fell only
from the very top of this low shelf,
and nothing's wrong with
the wine bottles on this side.
If they really had-a fist fight
in a clustered place like this,
wouldn't everythin'g be more messed up?
I see...that's true...
Just coincidence!
What are these traceswon the floor...
The two traces seem to
have been made by
rubbing something strongly
against the floor
Inspector, let's go take a look at
the back of the house
If there are no traces of anyone
having come in from the back door,
Wait a sec...
If there are no traces of anyone
having come in from the back door,
somebody that is in this house
has got to be the killer.
Maybe...
somebody that is in thus house
has got to be the killer.
Maybe...
There are no traces of the back door
having been broken into.
Maybe a spare key was secretly made...
Oh, I think that IS unthinkable.
What do you mean?
The keys of this house are
all special electronic keys.
An electronic key IS not something
that you can easily have made
in a hardware store in town.
You can't make a spare unless
you place an order to the manufacturer
Now,
it's pretty much definite that the killer is
someone who is within the premises!
Hmm!
Where are the people of this house
and the guests?
Yes,
I have xthem waiting in the living room!
Okay,
Iet's go hear them out.
Hey, Conan
Just what do you think
you're doing up there?!
Oh, um, -w-;well,
practicing the horizontal bar.
What?
Inspector
What's the matter, Chiba?
We got a report from the identification
officers just now saying that
they found two pairs of finger prints
other than that of the Kusaka's
on the door of the wine cellar
One was that of Yukari Takano,
a guest at the party.
And the other one of Jokichi Tonomura!
What?!
Okay, let's go to the living room}!
Yes, sir!
Take care of Conan, will you,
Officer Chiba!
Yes, sir!
What?!
Um, Officer Chiba.
What is it, Conan...?
Um...
I haven't heard that something like
that has been found.
Have you heard anything Mr Tome?
NC»,
I haven't heard of any such report.
I've found conclusive evidence
The killer still had the stuff,
not being able to throw it away
W,What?!
Are you saying
that the killer is among us?!
Please give us a decent explanation
Inspector!
I'm saying that judging
from the circumstances at the scene,
it is most likely that someone
in this house had committed the murder.
That goes for you two in particular,
Mr Tonomura and Ms. Takano!
The fingerprints of you two were found
on the door of the wine cellar.
H,Hey, hold it there, will you.
I did go to the wine cellar!
To ask him to loan me more money.
But, I didn't go inside!
How about you, Ms. Takano?
I went to the wine cellar to ask him to
extend the period of
which to repay my loan,
but I didn't go inside either!
And, young. Nonaka?
Huh?
After Mr. Kusaka left the room,
I was strolling around the yard.
So, I haven't gone to the wine cellar.
I DUE
Where were you, Mrs. Kusaka?
I was in the kitchen right through;
In order to go to the wine cellar;
I had to come through this living (room .
where Mr. Mouri and everyone else wereao
I was seated at the table of
the living room all the while,
but Mrs. Kusaka never left
the living I'oom!
Hey,pbps.
I found something strange
in the wine cellar...
Something strange?
Hey, Conan...where is it?
That strange stuff. . .?
I'd like you to call my lawyer
Right!
I won't say a word till then?!
Well, well, let's not get all excited...
EXCUSE me for a moment...
Hello, Megure here.
What?! you've-fig'Ured
out Who the killer is?!
Well. everyone, let me explain...
How this ruthless
murder was committed...
and disclosed who did it too!!
Just a while ago, I mentioned that
the killer is among the three people here.
There is no doubt about that!
What?!
First, the two whose
fingerprints were found on the door...
Mr. Tonomura and Ms. Takano...
However, they are not the killers!
Hey, then are you
saying that the killer is not here?
No, no. The killer is here.
H,Here, then...
Yes!...Mr. Nonaka,
The killer is you!
W,Wait. I was in the yard at that time.
I didn't even go near the wine cellar!
Shall we replay the situation then?
First, you went around to the backyard,
and knocked on the
window of the wine cellar.
Oh, I forgot to mention the role of the
killer will be played by Officer Chiba
Then Mr. Kusaku turned off the
alarm system and opened the window...
Officer Takagu!
Y,Yes sir!
Please play the role of the vnctim...
Yes, sir...
Mr. Nonaka, then you lured
Mr. Kusaku out into the yard.
Saying something like you
would explain what trick
Mr. Tonomura used
during the wine tasting
Mr. Nonaka, you killed Mr. Kusaku in
the backyard when he was off guard...
Then you went around to the backdoor,
Iocked the door with the keys you took,
and then put the keys
back into the victim's pocket.
Wait, Mr. Mouri, then how did
he put Mr. Kusaku into the wine cellar?
Even if he were to throw
him in from the window,
wouldn't it be impossible to
Iie him down in the center of the cellar?
He used the clothes rack pole!
The clothes rack pole?
Mr. Nonaka lined two poles up together
and laid the dead body on it like so.
He pulled the pole
through Mr. Kusaku's belt
to keep the space between
the poles from widening.
Then he pushed the
poles through the window...
and if you tilt the angle...
II DUE
The wine'abottles broke when Mr. Kusaku's
Iegs knocked them off the shelf!
Finally the pole is pulled out...
It, It is similar to the time
Mr. Kusaku was found,
what about the window ?
He hooked a narrow wire or
something on the tab of the window
then pulled on it with all his might.
It closed
In this way/, it is
possible to lie Mr. Kusaku
on the floor between the shelves
without coming into the wine cellar.
That's all a bunch of baloney
Do you have evidence,
where's the proof
Would you be so kind to show
me your handkerchief?
The one with your initials
on them that Mr. Kusaku gave you
When Mr Kusaku was
dropped, some wine bottles broke
Wine would then naturally
splatter onto the poles.
But, no wine was found on the poles!
That's because you wiped off the wine to
hide your trick of having used the poles!
Since you didn't expect
the wine bottles to break,
you wiped it off with
the handkerchief you had!
I'm sure you still have it with you,
because if you threw it away,
it would be obvious that it's yours!
N, No!
He's, He's to blame
He lends money and demands
ridiculously high interest.
Then, when it becomes
inconvenient for him,
he demands that you pay
him back the next day!
You've got to be kidding
I've got employees to feed too!
That's why I did for the
sake of everyone else!!
You foo!
No matter what your
reasons are, murder is murder!
You can't look away from
the fact that you took someone's life!!
Think deeply about it!!
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
MIChlhlkO Suwa
Masahnto Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
MasatOmo  udo
Jumchl lloka
SCRIPTS BY
Kafll Kashlwabara
Kazunan KOUChI
Jumchl Mlyashlta
Yuuchn Hagure
Toshlla (Inoue
ANIMATION DIR CTORS
iMasatomo Sudo
Hirotoshl Takatam
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Aldo Kawamura
Takafi'hl Hyodo
RT DIR CT'ORc
hikihlro Shlbutam
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashl Nomura
Ieonobu Horlkoshl
Takahlsa Ogawa
REC RDING DIRECJOR
Katsuyoshl Kobfiyashl
EDITOR,
Terumltsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: KOdama
RODUCED
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
m association mth
Yomlun Telecasting corporation
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan  YTV - TMS
All nghts Reserved
Very nice job, Mr. Mourl!
Y,Yes good job...
Yeah you .'too.
Mr. Mouri, I'll make it up
to you one of these days...
Ient him something?
Oh, well...
Yeah, you can take your
time paying me back!
80 Sorry Officer Takagl!
Ran, could you please
take a picture of us two?
Oh geez. Here goes!
What?! W,Wait
Madoka, this is Mourn!
Where and in what
condition is the body?!