Even td'est-inyF-serves
as a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
Today's episode takes place in
Shirahama of Southern Kishu
Thea-footprints of crime
on a white sand beach.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan
«if» NA.
South Kishu White
Sand Beach Mystery Tour Par
Shlrahama Station
fiO<fl
Here!
There on 0
Dad! Let's go check out
souvenirs at the waiting room!
We~don't have to go look
for souvenirs just yet, do we?
Wow! How cute!!
Look, look, it's Sour Boy
Kishu is a region famous for sour plums!
I'm going to buy some on my way home
What's so cute about a
sour looking guy like this?!
You can say that again...
So, where to?
Here.
Hmm. . Nanboukumakusunokl . . . .?
No, it's read
Minakatakumagusu Memorial Hall...!
NO, lit's'read
Minakatakumagusu Memorial Hall
No, CW sTead
Minakatakumagusu Memorial Hall...!
Minakatakumagusu Memorial Hall
Fia'safimsaffie
He's a world famous botanist who
was born In Wakayama Prefecture,
especially known for his
research of plants and fungl!
Oh~~such a great
res'earcher existed, eh...
I'd advise you to study
a bit before traveling...
fififiém
Minakata Kumagusu Memorial Hall
Why don't you stop by for a meal here?
The crawfish here is good
What do you think, dad?
It's still too early...
Let's go check out
the memorial hall first...
Minakatakumagusu
Memorial Hall Entrance
un<a er Q Ohfiolflba
fifififififiafifiélfl
The road's closed on this side...
This way, Conan
Okay!
Minakatakumagusu Memorial Hall
Shirahama
Wow, the sand is-Ireally fine and white
I wonder-"Whyfltis so white?
I once heard that the
secret of its whiteness
is due to the 90 lo silicate quartz sand!
Well,
He sure is knowledgeable of trivials...
I want to take this sand home!!
You know,
Iike lill it up in a bottle
Iike the star sand and take it with me.
What girlish taste you got...
You were looking
at a weird looking key holder
back at the station too, weren't you
The one with sour pickled plums
attached to it!
But, it's so cute
You fool! Only brats like things like that!
Brats...
Excuse me, but aren't you Mr. Mourl?
Huh'. Yes.
I thought so...!
I'm a fan of yours!
This is awesome!
I'd like to take pictures of you
Do yoU"know him, Kota'?
Wow! What a beauty
He's the renowned detective that
you're all familiar with, Mr. Kogoro Mourn!
What?
WBW!
Ran, could you take a picture of
both of us together?
Here goes.
By the way, did you come here
to investigate a case or something?
it's just a plain sightseeing tour
We drew a winning raffle
at the shopping arcade.
You be quiet!!
Are you all students?
Yes, we're seniors
at Naniwa Medical University.
Oh~~~so, you're doctors in the making!
Oh, let me introduce everyone, then.
The girl who is next to you
is the queen of our group, Maki Shinjo!
Is the queen of our group, Maki Shinjo!
Mam Sh'm'm
is the queen of our group, Maki Shinjo!
Mam Sh'm'p
Élb'JBA 4 L1 3:
Céh-(JBK q LIE:
Come on, out it out, Kota.
Mam Sh'm'p
Élh'JBx Q I-jil:
Next to her, is the stud Tatsuhiko Yura.
Tl'ats'fjh'iko'Yu na
This is our Madonna, Madoka Mitsun.
Madoka Mitsun
14:32:73 (21)
uluoax 4-21:
Madoka Mitsw
#5813 (21)
JZIQDISX 41-1
How do you do?
Madaka Mitsui
Flaunt \
EICDBX 4 .$
She is our whiz kid, Kanako Mihara.
Kanako Mihara
muse-5?
She is our whiz kid, Kanako Mihara.
Kanako Mihara
2E7]??? (21)
El'bEX 4.5
Nice to meet you.
Kanako Mihara
siflflfi? (21)
Dir-t
KICDEX 4 Ii
And, I'm the clown of the group, Kota Fuji
Kota Fuju
And, I'm the down of the group, Kota FUN!
Kota Fuji
Faith-455
The three here belong to the art club,
and sinc'elMaki suggested that
we take a nature sketching trlp,
we've all decided to come.
I guess you could call it
a pastime for Ms. Little Richie.
Talk about grateffjif} 'i't'eélly...
She paid for the hotel, train tickets
and rent-a-car fee as well.
Yura! You've got no class,
talking like that!!
It's okay
I broke up with her because I didn't like
jUSt what she's doing for all of us now!
I mean, she spends several 100 thousand
yen a month just on cosmetics
She has them sent from Paris every time
a new productligo'eéi~abh{the» market. . .!
On the contrary,
Madoké'fl1 h'a'sf'n'o fn'oheyu like me
and doesn't look down on me...!
Her childishness is a fly
I'rifithéét'ii fitme'rftse-fthou g h _
Well, aren't you lucky having found
yourself a cutie-pie to go around with...
It doesn't bother me a bit.
Hey, hey...
Hmm...
I'm thins .
Can you go get me something to drink,
Kanako?
No, way!
Go get it yourself!
I've decided to not listen to
your beck and calls anymore!
Kanako.
It's true that thanks to you,
during our high school days
since you taught me math
that wasn't my cup of tea,
I made it into college!
I really appreciate
whaifwou *d idlfoijimedthen!
But,
will you stop bossing me around harping
on how grateful I should be to you!
I didn't mean to be bossing you around...
Break it u oka
We've all come on this trip together,
so why don't we just all go ahead
and have a good time
I'll go get the drinks...
Right,
maybe I'll have Kota do things for me
instead of Kanako from now on.
Huh...?
I wonder who it was that fainted
during practical dissection practice
and was saved by me?
something like that happened to you?
Come on, Mam,
you promised that \
you'd keep that a secret...
Well, I'm going to get the drinks,
so hde'fin.
Mr. Mouri, whatoare your plans?
U'Fuh...
We're going to the Shirahama Energy
Land, right over there
Then, we'll be going to
the undersea observation tower.
Then, we'll go around to Sandanbekl
and finally watch the sunset
from Senjojikl.
What about tomorrow?
We've thinking of going to
Adventure World from morning...
Woul'dl ou like to
come along with us, Makl'?
Because we have other plans...
And, where are you staying?
At the Shinyuzaki Hotel.
I see
Dad, we'd better get going...
Huh...?
Yeah, I guess so...
I guess we'll be going then.
Oh, have a nice trlp .
Please enjoy yourselves.
Those people, you can't tell if they're
getting along or not, can you?
Yeah,
well when you're young, anything goes...
Sandanbeklf
Wow~~~it's amazing!
Sandanbekl
It's really a bold sheer cliff!
It seems that we can go way
over that snde.
I'm not going!
No darn way!!
Okay, why don't we go tour
the caves then!
It-seems we=canwgo~down~ using
the elevator from of a temple that building.
And, after that we get to watch
the sunset at Senjojiki, right?
Yep! I'm sure that
it'll be super beautiful...!
Senjojikl
What a scenic masterpiece
I'm sure glad we came.
Yeah,
it was worth coming,
if only to see this sunset
Mr Mourn
Maw.!
Did you all come to watch the sunset too?
Yes,
because we haven't seen
the view of the sunset here yet.
By the way, Mr. Mourl,
do you like to drink?
Yes! Very~~~much!!
If so,
why not stop over at Toretore Market
before going to
Adventure World tomorrow?
Toretore Market. . .?
Aside from fresh seafood
they have a whole line of
A+ locally brewed sake.
Locally brewed sake!
You can send it home
by courier service too.
I've also written the bus route
to the market from Shinyuzaku.
There is a bus stop called Bus Depot
near Tdrettore Market.
There is no bus that goes directly from
Toretore Market to Adventure World,
and you'll have to get off once at
Shirahama, but it shouldn't take that long.
Thank you so much for all your kindness!
We'll visit there for sure!
Goodbye, then.
Thank you so much
for all your thoughtfulness!
Thank you so very much!
It seemed as if Maki came
all the way here
jUSt to give us information
about the market, didn't it?
I guess she's just a kind person
Following Day
7,171 wzmm
Shinaham'a
Sandanbekl
Adventure World
J FN'Jiv-U-lb
Toretore Market
The bus for Adventure World is bus #3.
The next bus to
Adventure World is at 10:15.
We still have about 20 minutes to go.
Maybe we should go walking
around the area.
What's wrong, Conan?
I felt like someone was watching.me.
I guess it's just my imagination though.
If you want it so badly,
why don't; ouifbuy, it now?
Uh-uh, it's okay
Let's go take a look
in the souvenir shop outside too.
Letl's gofiConan
Hey, we've only got 7 to 8 minutes left,
so we'd better get going.
Uh, would youamin'd'"
if I stop over at the store of the station?
Huh?
We don't have time, you know.
Hurry it up, okay!
So, you're going to buy it after all.
Not again...
Itis just as if I...
someone is watching me...
This please.
Thank you very much.
H'eyfihurgy Lip-=,, th'efibus is')'goingi to leave!
Hmm...
Only one more left. . ?
Somebody else beside Ran is buying it...
Thank you very much.
Makn!
Huh?!
Thanks again
Be careful!
Conan, that bus is headed
for Sandanbeku!
Adventure World
Wow~~~Nice shot!
There, Conan, wave your hand.
I, I'm fine...
He's only a kid and yet he's embarrassed.
Why, it's you, Mr Mourl!
I didn't think that I'd run into you here.
Oh, you're ah...
Fuji!
Kota Fun!
So: you've come here...
Is everyone else here too?
three went out to sketch from morning,
and Maki was saying that she was
going to go driving until sundown.
I saw her around 10:00 sharp
at Shirahama Station!
Oh, I see ?
Really...
Hey, over that side!
Let's go see!
That's a laptop, right?
Do you always carry it around with you?
Yeah
that's why Yura call me a computer freak.
Huh?
What Was that...?
Oh, excuse me...
Hello...
What?!
Clam down and tell me again, Madoka!
What?...Maki is dead?!
What...?
H,Hey!!
HLJHeyu
Madoka, this is Mourfl!
Where and under what
circumstance is she?!
In the bushes at Sandanbekl...
Stabbed in the chest with a knife...
Sandanbekl 7
That suspicious looking silhouetted figure
was on board the bus to Sandanbekl...
Darn!!
We're all headed that way,
including Mr. MOUI'I!
You called the police already, didn't you?
Did you tell Yura and Kanako already...?
Not yet .?
Okay! I'll Inform them, then!
Hey»,
Didn't we just go pass
the entrance of Sandanbekl?
Madoka is more inside
This way!
Madoka!
Where is Makl'?
0,over there in 'the bushes.
One stab right into her chest...
She probably died on the spot.
Maki's wallet is nowhere in sight...
This is most likely to be
310389 of murder-robbery...
Theme are no signs" bf any struggle
in the area.
If so,
the murderer could've been
an acquaintance...
Hmm. ?
Strange...?
If I remember correctly,
Maki's key holder had...
the key for the rent-a-car on it too .
Does that mean that the killer took it along
and fled with the car...?
But...what's with this key holder then...?
Huh...?!
What is it?
Work gloves...?
Why does she have work gloves on her?
Haven't I told you time and again
not to mess around the scene of a crime
I'm sorry!
Let's wait for the police to come
for further investigation.
OUCh~~~it hurts
Ouch-Wu hurts
Hmm...?
This sand is...
Huh...?
This is...?
Thank you for wanting
I am Ohura mm the Wakayama
Prefectural Police Department.
How do you do?
I'm Ando, from the Shirahama East
Police Station.
How do you do?
I am honored to be able to work with you,
the renowned detective, Mr. Mourl,
on this case.
Please do give us
precise advice if need be.
Well,
cooperating with the police is
the duty of any civilian!
I'll help in whatever way I can!
Let me introduce you
to the friends of the victim, then.
This Kota Fuji, who rushed over
here together with us
from Adventure World, Kota Fuji
She is Kanako Mlhara who came over
here from En'getsu Island
She is the one who first found
the body, Madoka Mitsuu
And he is Tatsuhiko Yura who came
here from Shirahama.
Ms. Madoka Mitsfll,
please tell us 'the circumstanc'e'sfnvvh'en
you found the body of ME. MékilfiShinjoi,
I heard Beethoven playing.
What?!
Beethoven. . .?
I was sketching
on the far end of Sandanbekl...
I heard the melody of
a cell phone ringing behind me...
So I went towards the bushes
where the music was coming from...
I didn't know what to do,
so I called Mr Fuji right away.
I see that Maki was lying
on the ground fairly close to you.
Nevertheless, you didn't realize
that a crime was being committed?
I was faced in the opposite direction
and the sound of the waves was
pretty loud .
But, you heard the melody
of the cell phone!
W,Well.
It's only natural.
Electronic sounds like those of cell phone
are made to be audible.
Hmm...well, I guess so...
Officer Ando,
please give us a report on the autopsy
Yes, sir!
The cause of death is shock
by a stab wound.
There are fit) traces of the conpse
having been moved after death,
and the estimated time of death,
in other words the time the murder is
thought to have been committed is,
judging from the condition of the body
between 9:00 to 11:00 this morning.
I'm sure the time the murder was
committed can be
narrowed down a bit more!
What?!
We ran into Maki at Shirahama Station.
It was about 10:10 when we saw her!
What?!
Are you sure it was about 1010?
After bowing to us,
she left immediately in her car.
We were going to get on the 10:15 bus
headed for Adventure World,
so I'm sure there's no mistake!
Officer Ando!
How long does it take to get from
Shirahama Station to Sandanbeki by car?
Well...
since it's the tour season now,
it should take less than 15 minutes.
Let's say it takes about 14 minutes,
so she arrives at Sandanbeki about 10:24.
If she parks the car in the alley
closest to the scene of the crime,
it would take her 2 minutes to get there...!
If we assume she was killed immediately,
the time the murder was committed,
no matter how early,
would be around 10:26!
Yeah
Which means that the time
the murder had been committed
is narrowed down to
approximately 34 minutes!!
By the way,
Maki'swallet seems to have disappeared
from among her personal effects.
Justsa few minutes ago,
the car that the victim was thought to
have been driving was found
near Sansho Shrine
about 3 kilometers away from here.
And an empty wallet was found
inside the car!
It's Maki's!
So, we've already gotten to
the bottom of this case...
Wait!
So, we've already gotten to
the bottom of this case...
Wait
Was the key of the car found?
the key was in the ignition of the car.
Um, did you only receive
one key from the rent-a-car shop?
I think so.
I don't think they normally give you
two keys, do they?
This is a case of murder-robbery!
After the killer attacked Makl,
the killer stole the car and fled on it,
and abandoned it near Sansho Shrine!
No...murder-robbery is probably
Just camouflage...
It's most likely that this murder was
committed by an acquaintance of hers...!
If so.
The murderer is among the people here...!
RIGINKL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho onama
PRODUCERS
MIChlhlkO Suwa
Masahlto Yoshmka
Katsuo Ono
(HDUU UIIU
Masatomo; udo
flu sf if}
Jumchn lloka
ST'ORX EDITOR
jumchl lloka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kafil Kashlwabara
Kazunan KOUChI
Jumchn Mnyashlta
Ymchl Hloure
Toshika Inoue
ANIMATION DIR CTORS
iMasatomo Sudo
Hurotoshi Takatam
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Aldo Kawamura
Takasm Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR:
Yuk'lhtro Shnbutam
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashl Nomura
Ieonobu Horlkoshl
Takahlsa Ogawa
EC RDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshl Kobaxashl
If)!
Terumltsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kédama
TMS Entertainment, 1.56.
In association with
Yomlurl Telecasting corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan - Y'W  TMS
All Rights Reserved
You're the one with the problem.
It was unfortunate that
Maki witnessed you.
So, you killed her to make sure that
she wouldn't leak your secret...
Shirahama in South Kishu
You're the killer?!