Even destiny serves
as a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
This is the first time Conan is handling
a case like this.
XWere you able to enjoy his facial
expressions as well as his deductions?
He sees through the one and only truth.
IvAfichil'd-in-eappearanc'e
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
We set off on a trip to Whitevsandeeach
in Wakayama prefecture.
Despite having a feeling
that somebody was watching us,
we continued sightseeing .
Later
we find out that one of the five
Naniwa University students
that we met the prevnous day,
Mam Sh'mm was found dead
at Sandanbekl.
Among her belongings,
her wallet and her car key are missing.
In the pocket of her top,
she has working gloves.
Also,
what is the meaning of the tiny bottle
and the Sour Boy easel?
What looks to be murder-robbery
is firobably camouflage...!
Possibilities of this being a murder
committed by an acquaintance is high.
If so
the murderer is among the people here!
South Kishu White Sand Beach
Mystery Tour Part II
Okay everyone,
please tell us where and what you were
doing from 10:26 in the morning to 11:00.
Just what do you mean by that!
Do you suspect us?
No, we're just verifying things...!
I was sketching at White Sand Beach...
TatsumkUYUra
Since there were a lot of tourists,
it shouldn't be hard to verify.
In your case, Ms. MItSUI...
since you were so near
the scene of the crime,
your alibi may not help you much.
But we do there sketching right through?
IUD.
Any witnesses?
I'U...
I don't like to be watched
what I'm sketching...
Madoka MitSUI
3313 kl! CZ
aroma-st
Madoka Mitsuu
#§¢n(
that's why I had them show me a place
where there were not too many people.
Who told you of this place?
Makl did.
She seems to have come to
White Sand Beach many times,
so she knew this place very well.
Uh, Ms. Mihara.
I was a restaurant near Engetsu island...
from about 10:30 to 12:00.
Oh, the parking lot where a woman was
standing calling out to the customers.
The shop where Engetsu Island
is in view, right?
Yes, that's right .
At first, I was sketching in the vacant lot
where Marine Palace used to be...
Right inside the tunnel
from the Memorial hall.
A funnel?
Back there,. eh...
Maki was the one who told you about
the vacant lot wh'arejMa'rine Palace
used to be too, right?
LRight...
Because I didn't want to be bothered
But somehow I didn't feel like drawing,
so I went to drink a cup of coffee
to refresh myself
and ended up eating lunch there...
draw much did you?
Nope, not at all.
I was sketching at the beach
from afternoon.
You mean the one on the way
to the Memorial hall?
But from there you can only get
a side view of Engetsu lslahd, can'; you?
Why didn't you sketch
mom the mo \ . area
where you could get
a frontal view of Engetsu Island?
I didn't want to draw anything
that resembled picture postcards.
That's what art is all about!
Don't ask such silly questions
By the way, Ms. Mihara,
we found in
Ms. Maki Shinjo's caller ID records
that you were the last person
to have called her.
Yes, I called her,
wondering how she was...
But, since she didn't answer, I hung up.
And now, Mr Pu.
I was at Adventure World...
from 10:26 to about 11:00...
I think I was watching the Marine show.
Do you have any witnesses?
I didn't run into anyone,
but I took a picture
using my digital camera.
Would you like me to connect it
to the TV set?
What?
You mean you can do something like
that with a digital camera?
This is the picture
that Maki sent me this morning.
She sent it first to Kanako, Yura
and-Madoka, then me, in that order.
and Madoka, then me, in that order.
After this,
I took several more pictures
inside Adventure World...
Then I watched the seal, dolphin, and
Orca shows that were 30 minutes each.
Oh, see, from here.
It's the show that we saw, isn't it?
Yep!
We saw the one from 11-00.
Then, we just missed each other.
Huh...?
Ooops, that's it!
But, could there be a possibility that
he took the next Orca and Dolphin show?
Just what do you mean by that?
In other words, if he takes a picture of
the seal show from 9:30 to 10:00,
and then"'takes
the next dolphin show from 11:30,
it would serve as his alibu
from 10:00 to 11:30.
I see!
I don't think so.
What?!
I think that's an Interesting deduction,
but she's not the same woman we saw.
Oh, you're right.
The person we saw had braids.
Which means that
Mr. Fuji has a perfect alibl
But why didn't you take Ia picture of
the Cree Shbw untilm 3:1 5
after taking theaOncéerhow before 11 :00'?
The next picture is the one that you took
when you saw us at 1315, isn't it?
Dlsn'ta-strange
that you didn't take any pictures
for a period of
more than 2 hours and 15 minutes?
T,That's because I was riding
Jet coasters, having meals
besides I had nothing
that I wanted to take during that time!
I tell you, cut out your stupid questions!
Please let me copy your pictures
on your driver's license
so I can go verify what you just testified.
I'm pretty sure...
that my intuition is correct...
If so,
what with the pictures
taken by the digital camera. '?
Wait a sec...
A laptop...?
Maybe...
May I go outside for a while?
Okay, but keep away
from dangerous places.
Okay.
Nun-l...n:,
Adventure World
'7-Jbl~
Um, I left just a while ago,
but may I go back in again?
My father is inside.
Okay,
I guess-you didn't get your hand stamped
when you went out
What?!
A stamp...?
Okay,
I got a hold of one evidence!
What?! Down with a fever?
RI ht,
that's why we're so busy.
Justaslthoughtu!
Why did Maki go to Sandanbekl
where Madoka was
after she saw us at Shirahama Station?
Moreoven the greatest mystery yet is
that I still can-it figure out
who kill'éd Makl...!
Just one more timé!I;Oneef'mOne? time!
Please let me ride
the Adventure Coaster, okay!!
My goodnessh:
Will you promise to study
when we" get home?
I will I will I promise
Okay then, just one m'oiez'time!
All right
That boy's not going to study for beans...!
Hsee,
so that's what happened.
Ifso,
everything's been solved...!
No doubt about it...!
That person's the killer!
I'm sure that person's the killer,
but I have no proof...!
Oh, goodness!
Hmm...
Today is r'eally'hot,
and it's -a'l'tea'dy1thi's4time of day!
I see...
This was a blind spot for men!)
I've found conclusive evidence
Hey, aren't you the boy
staying with Mr Mourl'?
Oh, officer.
Why are you here?
Did you come to verify
the time_o,f the=Marine-Show too?
Yeah just to be sure...
Mr. Mouri was saying that he wa'nte'dyou
to check on something elser-loo.
What?!
Mr Mouri said so...?
First of all, Mr. Yura
was witnessed sketching right
through from about 09:00 to after 11:00
by the life guard who was
on duty at the beach park.
Next, as for Ms. Mihara,
we were able to get testimony
from the people at the restaurant.
The problem is you, Mr. Fuji
What?!
We questioned the Cree trainer
and found out
that the same members have been
on duty all day today.
Nevertheless, a person
that was not even there today
was taken on your digital camera!
Well, that's because.
Mr. Fuji.
You left Adventure World once,
didn't you?
No use lying about it,
because all we have to do is use
this black light to disclose that you did!
What is that?
Come on, Mr. Mourn,
Iet's cut out that horse play
You're the one who told us to check on it.
Huh?!
Please go ahead
Please show me your right hand.
Some letters have appeared?!
Mr. Fuji,
the mark is stamped on your hand
for those who want to re-enter
when you leave
Adventure World temporarily.
I'm sorry...
The pictures I just showed you were the
edited version of the ones that I had taken
when I came to Adventure World before.
I edited them with my laptop
Oh, and just why did you do
something like that...?
W'el la.
You're going steady
with Madoka, right, Mr Fuji?!
What'?«!&
What a thing to say, Conan?!
Madoka is...
Mr Fuji
you left Adventure World about 09:50
to see Madoka
who was at Sandanbeki, didn't you
And you stopped over
at Shirahama Station on the way, right?
Uh,sonny,
Why would he go frorfi Adventure World
to Shirahama Station
that is in the opposite direction
from Sandanbeh...
He went to buy the key holder
that Madoka wanted.
See, the one that is on that bag.
Sour Boy that is only sold
at the shop at the station...
That's when you saw Mam,
fight, Mr Fun?
What's why...
I was really surprised back then...
I didn't think I would run into her
in the place like that...
Makl!
Thanks again
To top things off,
I run into all of you too, Mr. Mourn...
I didn't want anybody to find out
that I was going with Madoka...
Especially when it came to
Man and Yura...
I knew!
What?!
That's why I went to see Madoka
part way too.
What?!
I got to Sandanbeki a little before 12:00...
But,
you weren't there,
and that key holder was hanging
from the easel .
We were having lunch then.
I sensed right away
that you were with Fujn.
That's Whyfyou threw down
the bottle with sand in it, right?
Huh?
The sand of White Sand Beach?
You got it for me .?
Because I sand
that I wanted to take it home?
So, you found it eh sonny...
Cracked jUSt Ilke my broken heart...
Why 'did you keep something
so important hidden?!
Well, let's calm down
a bit here, Mr Mourl...
Which means you took
those pictures with your digital camera
just so that you could show your friends
that you had an alibi of
no elng wn a o a -
Yes, almost as if I were playing a game...
I'm really sorry.
But, how'd you figure it out, Conan?
How'd you find out
that I was gonng with her?
Because you were the very first person
that Madoka called
to report what had happened to Man
when it would've been more natural for
her to call Mr Yura, right?
Besides, when we got to Sandanbekl,
you knew where Madoka was sketching.
That's why I thought
maybe you had already seen her today.
Oh, I see...
No!!
Huh?
Mam happened to see you
together with Madoka...
so in order to contain the secret
you decided to shut her up!
Southern White Sand Beach
Hmm'?!
What seems to be the matter, Mr Mourl?
Agh! Don't tell me that...!
This is the much rumored about,
Sleeping Kogoro pose!
Now,
Mr. Fuji has absolutely nothing to do
with the incident that had happened.
What?
He's not involved?!
The main point of this case is
that there was a switch of
the main characters part way.
The victim of the murder
Which was supposed to have be'e'h
Madoka had also switched to Makl!
Let me explain...
First of all»
Mam, who was angrycat Madoka
3 mg , . er overaaway,
hated her and schemed to kill her
Maki was scheming to kill me ?
And, she chose Sandanbekn
as the place to carry out her plan.
However,
since Maki had a motive to kill,
she decuded to make herself an allbl.
She let that person pretend to be her
and made her do something that caught
the eyes of people at Shirahama Station.
D,Does that mean
she had an accomplice?!
Right
Maki who ran into us
at Sh'irahama Station
thought of setting up us as wntnesses.
That's why
Maki asked us for our schedule.
She set it up so that we would arrive
at Shirahama Station at 10:00 today.
However,
Maki's accomplice had other plans.
Other plans ?!
That plan was to switch Maki's alibl
and kill her!
Wait, dad!
Then the Maki that we'saw
at Shirahama Station at about 10:10 was...
Yeah, an ir'fiposter!
The imposter wore a wig, hat,
sunglasses and even make-up
jUSt like Maki's...!
And this imposter had probably already
killed Maki at around 09:25 at Sandanbekl
before coming to Shirahama Station!
Whaaaat?
35 minutes before we met her...?
W,Who is that imposter anyway,
Mr. Mourn'?
A person who was trusted enough
to be asked to be an accomplice
in committing the murder...
as well as disguise herself
to look just like Makl.
There iS'Ohly one'ppe'rsonsamon'g athe four
that is. capable of'fib'ifig-thiS! I
Yes? Ms. Kanako Miyahara!!
Only you could've done it!!
But, Mr Mourl!
Kanako already told Maki yesterday that
she would not listen to Maki anymore!
Mam tom her to say
so that the police wouldn't suspect
h'er safiinfi
that Kanako was only making up an alibi
because she was forced to say
what she did.
This mooning, after Makiwdropped
everyone off at their destination,
she returned to Engetsu Island,
and made Kanako get into her car.
Kanako disguised herself
as Maki as they drove along.
According to Maku's plan,
she was supposed to get off
atuthexinner alley of Sandanbekl
which after, Kanako drives to
Shirahama Station.
Then after her alibi was established,
Makl was supposed to kl Madoka.
I see!
That's why there were working gloves
in Maki Shinjo'si'rj'a'cket
Right!
She was going to use them
when committing the crime!
However,
Maki's plan suddenly shatters to pieces.
After committing the murder,
Kanako took Maki's knife and wallet.
She did this to make it
Iook like a murder-robbery...!
She then speeds along
and arrived at Shirahama Station
a little before we got there
Then, she observed us
and waited for
the right time to appear before us
Which means that
when Conan said that he felt
as if he was being watched .
Right!
It was Kanako!
After that you...
Made us witness Maki around 10.10
Then you went to Sanjo Shrine, while at
the same flme gem'n'g me of the emdence,
You then abandoned the car
and went-lback» to Engetsu Island:
Please wait!
Do you have any grounds
for saying all of this?
Of course!
Although you mentioned
not wanting be bothered by others,
you went out of your way
to choose a beach
where there were
a lot of tourists and began sketching.
Fearing the estimated time of death
being extended to a later time,
you called Maki on her cell phone to
make Madoka realize as soon as possible
that Maki was lying dead on the ground
That's only forced interpretation!
If you insist that I'm the killer,
show me proof!!
If I'm not mistaken,
Mam was us'm make-u that
she ordered «from Paris, wasn't she?
Huh?
You may have been able to get
a hold of the clothes
that Mam wore,
or the bags she carried, in Japan
but, as for the characteristic color lipstick
that she used,
you could find no substitute here!
Nd your saliva was foun
on that lipstick.
The saliva of the person
who used it last, you...!
Moreover,
Maki's lipstick that
you could not wipe off completely
IS still on your lips...
Under Mr. Mouri's orders,
we have already received
the results of the forensic analysis of
Ms. Maki Shlnjo's lipstick.
Would you like me-to explain
in detail on saliva and blood type?
No, thank you...
I am aware of that
amount of medical knowledge too.
When did you figure out
that I was the killer...?
It took me quite a while
to put my fingers on you.
Only, I did have a hunch
that it was one of you.
But, when I found the key holder
near the deadbbody...
Key holder?
Mam had the key of the rent-a-car
attached to the key holder together
with her house keys, didn't she?
But the key of the rented car was
missing from that key holder.
That's because Mam...
Yes,
a robber would've taken
the key holder and all
because Maki's key holder was not
the hook type key holder,
but the coil type that is harder
to remove the key from.
80, I'm sure that Mam gave you
the key to the car
after she removed it from the key holder...
You're a great man, Mr. MOUI'I,
Just as expected of you.
I've completely lost...
But, Kanako, why did you ?
Entered the university illegally.
Huh...?!
I asked Maki's father to get me in...
After I got in,
Makifthreatene'd to disclose
what happened if I didn't listen to her...
That's Why I kept following
her orders all this time...
fl wantéfid tbitb'e -'fl'r'eedhm
from Mam.
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
MIChlhlkO Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER-DESIGNS BY
Masatomof 'uflo
STORY EDITOR.
Jumchl Iloka
SCRIPTS BY
KafijiKashlwabara
Kazunan KOUChI
Junlchl Mlyashlta
YUIChl ngure
TOShlkl Inoue
ANIMATION DIREfi-TORS
iMasatomo Sudo
Hurotoshl Takatam
Haruo Oogawara
AtSUShl Aono
Akio Kawamura
Taka'hi Hyodo
ART DIRE from
Yuk'lhlro Shlbutam
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashl Nomura
Huronobu HOrlk05hl
Takahlsa Ogawa
REC RDING DIRECJOR
Katsuyoshi Kob'as ash:
erumltsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kbdama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, 113.
In association with
Yomlurl Telecasting no'rporatlon
OGosho Ao'yafna '7-Shogakukan ° YTV ° TMS
All Rights Reserved
I guess we'll be able to get back
to Tokyo by tonight somehow.
Yes,
it's goodbye to White Sand Beach too...
I'm so sleepy that I can't stand it...
Then, have some of this.
A pickled plum.
Sour
Sour Ha
I'm awake!!
Only if this could also awaken
your talent as a detective...
Ray, okay!
I've arrived!
Oh, Ricardo not there.
Left, left!
Huh?
Hey, wait!
II.IIC D...
the journalist we just a while ago?!