Even destiny serves
as a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
Wis case takes place in Osaka.
He sees through the Cher-and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the ll.Q. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
Huh?
A party for a restaurant's opening?
Yeah, that's right .
Actually, it was my mom
and dad that got invited,
but they both came down with a cold
and said they can't go,
so I thought I'd invite you guys...
I mean, after all,
three famous athletes from America
are opening a restaurant here in Japan,
everyone here's so excited!
Hey, listen.
What is ity
About the party, where's it going to be)?
Over here, of course!
In Osaka, where else!!!
I pass!
Whoa that was fast.
Come on, just for a little while...
Sorry, but I've got research
to do back here
I'm back!
Oh, uh, welcom back, Ran.
Who are you talking to?
Uh, Doctor Agasa
He's repairing
some earring mobile phones for me
What's the matter?
Did somebody come back?
If this is a bad time,
you want me to call you back later?
No, never mind-itis-all right.
.You'sureyy
Anyway, don't turn-me down so fast!
You're going to be able to
see famous athletes in the flesh!
There's pro boxer Ricardo Balera,
Mike Norwood the Major Leaguer
and...
FA AA
(BI%R)
HA AA
(BIER)
The 3K's Incident in Osaka" Part I
Look at that they're all here!!
Theres Mai Kuraki,
Miho Komatsu
Two Mix
ar 4 then, the love of my life...
Yoko Okino!
Don't talk so loud dad!
You're being. so obvious...
And what about you? You brought
an.autographfboard with you...
Are you sure it's all right, Kazuha...
I'm mean there's so many
famous people here
and we weren't officially invited,
should we be here at all .
Don't worry about it!
Besides, your dad's a famous person too!
I wonder .
I have a bigger problem than that...
Has Heiji done something?
He's been acting strange...
What do you mean
He was whispering to someone
on the telephone
and he said Are you alone now?
Are you sure no one's caught on?
and If this is a bad time, you want me
to call back later? things like that...
You don't mean...
I do, he's having an affair!
that Heiji. I'm sure he's been taken in
by some stranger.
Maybe he's told her to come here. I
that was me, he was talking
to me on the phone...
Oh, it's finally starting...
Ladies E... 14 rt ILI I J INrl 0
thank you for waiting.
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you for waiting
It is my honor to introduce
the three stars of tonight s party
who also happen to be the owners 1)
of this World Restaurant K3!1
First. the undefeated former
world middle weight champion!
Ricardo Balera
Mr. Ricardo Balera!
JhlhlTL15 (36)
xxZOMoY
Ricardo Balera
JAIL ILLS (36)
sxx 70MoOY
Next the pitcher who received
the 160 kilometer Cy Young trophy.
Mr. Mike Norwood!!
Mike Norwood
45+)-9 x (RN)
Jo-U-7
and the mansfearfully known
as Europe s steel stronghold,
the famous goalkeeper
Mr. Ray Curtis!
Mr Ray Curtis!
Ray Curtis
Jovy h-a%
Le -h=F42X (37)
oY sh A
Ray Curtis
QYvuoh-A
QY yn-A 1
This is great!!
It's the real things!!
Well? aren't you glad you came?
Yeah
And now I'd like to ask
these three men some questions!
Why did you decide to
open a restaurant in Japan?
The reason is. to the three of us,
Japan is our second home!
Wow, he speaks Japanese...
My wife,
as well as Mike's...
IS Japanese!
And as for Ricardo,
-- He's. crazy about ninjas and samurais!
By the way,
about the K in the restaurant's name,
I imagine it stands for king, doesn't;it?
No, no
you're mistaken
The first K stands for knock out.
It's the K from K.O.
The second K is for strike out.
K for strike out!
The third K is for goal keeper.
It's the K in keeper!
I DUB.
Haven't you forgotten a other one, Ray?!
I OC.
You know, right...?
It's a Japanese word
that describes perfectly men
Iike you who are smeared with scandal...
Ed McCay
INyo4 (48)
L.A he BB Lo»
wits
K for "kitanai (dirty)
Ed McCay
IN 4 (48)
49% Bl n=
Ed McCay
ho (48)
15; ll I ai
C CElm DOW Va.
BITE or
HULYHLL KN SDE EOBL» SLOW?
As you can see, I'm a guest here,
I had an invitation...
I don't know who sent it to me,
but I really appreciated it...
because I just love sushi.
Who the heck is he...
He's as well known AmericanO
He's a reporter that's made
a nameffor himself
by writing about scandals that
famous athletes are involved in.
Most.of.it's made up,
but'he.writes so vaguely, #
even if he's taken to court,
he's-hardly ever charged... #
Uh huh...
I guess you should
be careful then huh, Heiji.
What do you mean by that?
Gee, I wonder
Uh, let's move things along now
and start with the question and answer
portion of the presentation
Is there anyone in the audience
who would like to ask
these gentlemen a question?
Don't be TV come on up...
I have one!
A brave young lady
has her hand raised!
Please come up on to the stage.
Ra, Ran...
All right young lady, ask away!
Well, uh...
It's not really a question,
I have a favor to ask...
Mr. Curtis! May I have your autograph!!
What's she doing...
You, won't do it?
No. no!
They re not autographing anything today
Okay, it's okay!
I'll do it as a special favor for this young
Iady for brightening up this party, again!
Oh thank you so much!
All right how about if I sign
one of my uniforms?
Really, will you do that for me?!
No,.you;can't do that.
Those are;forithe, lottery...
Don't worry about it!
There's still three left!
BB. but...
Oh. if you don't mind
could you write in this name...
Okay! What's your name, young lady?
Um, er, not my name...
Shinichi
Could you please sign it "To Shinichi ?
Is he your boyfriend?
Oh no, it's nothing like that.
Oh. she remembered
that I'm Ray's fan...
You better give her a call later.
Yeah. .you don't have to tell me...
Isn't it strange though?
What do you mean?
The goal keeper usually wears number 1,
why is his number 87
Ray was originally a mid-fielder!
But during the Woinld Cup Series,
both goal keepers were thrown out of
the game and the team was in a bind,
so Ray had ngschoice
but to go in as a keeper...
He performed super saves
one after the other
and the team managed
to come in second place!
From then on,
even when he was a goal keeper
for a league in Spain in the Serie A,
he kept the number 8!
And he's continued wearing it even now
when he's in the Major League Soccer!
I see .
Then answer me this...
What about the number 99? 7
He's-a pitcher, isn't he?
Isnt that too big a number?
That stands for 99 miles.
In Japan, it's equivalent to 160 kilometers!
His goal was to pitch balls that fast,
that's why he wore the number 99!
And what about the number 47?
See, it's written on the boxing gloves
along with the signature!
That's because Ricardo always scored
a KO win in the 4th round.
So he added the 4
along with his signature
Ah. I didn't know that
You should've done your research
before you got here!
Well excuse me.
Telephone numbers interested me
more than uniform numbers...
What's wrong with you?
You keep mentioning that!
You figure it out!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
You,did this for some guy who's %
gallivanting who knows where...
That's my business, not yours.
Oh yes!
It's for you, Conan!
Jd on 4
It's a ticket for the special game.
Ray will be playing
in tomorrow at Nagai Stadium!
He gave it to me
just now but it's a secret!
You will go, won't you?
Of course I'll go!!
That was generous.
But I had to agree to their one condition.
Here, look at this...
A transceiver?
They said they want to surprise everyone!
Ray, it's okay I'm here!!
No, Ricardo, that's the wrong place
Left, to the left!
Oh, I get it now,
they're trying toiform the: letter K
bysturning 'on the lights
in the hotel roomstabove the restaurant
before the hotel opens!
When the guests
come out of the restaurant,
they re really going to be surprised!!
But they don't have to do it themselves...
They thought it up themselves,
that's why they want to do it on their own!
Uh huh.
If even one of them is seen outside,
it would cause quite a commotion,
that's why they wanted us to stand outside
and see if the letter is formed right!
Ran? Are the lights I'm supposed to
turn on all on already?
Oh, the end part of the last row
of the vis stillloff
Okay! I'm going right now!
Mike, open the curtains, open them.
Okay?
Okay!
Ricardo, you're good too!
Ran. it is on?
Let's seed.
Yes, it's on!
All right!
The K is completed!
The window
And there were gunshots too
FAT?
ESL?
Hey¥fwait!
Kazuha! Tell those three
not to leave the rooms!
Hey! Wait up!
That's the room!
Yes!
This is the guy,
he's that reporter from the party!
He must've been shot with this gun!
Huh?
He's holding something in this left hand...
What the...
ab, belt?
The window
And there were gunshots too...
Hey, wait!
Kazuha! Tell those three
not to leave the rooms!
That's the room!
Yes!
This is the guy,
he's that reporter from the party!
He must've been shot with this gun!
Huh?
He's holding something in this left hand...
What the...
ab, belt?
The victim is an American
Iiving in Chicago
He's a reporter,
name Ed McKay, 48 years old.
He was shot in the chest
and died almost immediately.
Inspector Otaki
EAT OE
The weapon used was
a Smith & Wesson revolver.
There are signs of a slight struggle,
so he must have.been alive
for a short time after being shot...
Heiji. do you know
what time you heard the shot?
Sure...
I'm sure it was a little past 8:05 PM.
AKazuha and the rest of us
were outside the Ih otel when we heard itd
and we saw the window crack
so I'm pretty sure about it!
What do you Mean, outside the hotel...
where you ledOing the party so soon?
No, no!
Those threeftguys
asked us to do them a favor.
They asked us to check to see
if the lights in the hotel
formed the letter K
Iike they planned!
Those three?
Of course.
They own the K3 restaurant...
Ricardo Balera, former pro boxer,
major leaguer Mike Norwood,
and pro soccer player, Ray Curtis.
And by chance, were they the ones
who turned the lights on too?
Yeah, that's right!
Ra was in charge of 5,
the first and second rows,
Mike was in charge of 4,
the third and fourth rows
and Ricardo was in charge of the two
on the very top fifth row!
So that means its possible for
those three to have committed the murder.
It sure is possible.
Especially since it seems;
they all didn't like that reporter
But they couldn't have done it.
Huh?
This room is in the center
of the second row. isn't it?
When the shot was fired,
the three of them were in different rooms!
Isn't right, Ran?
Uh huh
Do you which.rooms:they were in?
I'm positive Mike was in the room
directly above this' one.
He opened the curtains
that were partially drawn.
Right after that,
Ricardo turned off the light
in the second room from the left
on the top floor
which he'd turned on by mistake...
and right after that,
Ray turned on the light in the room
on the right of the very bottom
which he'd forgotten to turn on...
Just when we thought
the letter K was complete,
we heard the gun shots
and the window shattered.
Did you see
the three of them at that time?
No}:
but only 5 seconds had past
since Mike opened the curtains
and Ray poked his head out the window.
And it was only about 3,seconds later
that we heard the gunshots.
And right after that,
all three of them looked outside
and asked what was going .on...
Then who is the Killer...
Mabe it was
one of the guests at the party?
What?!
Remember, when Heiji and I got here,
the place-was crowded
with people already!
I'm sure the killer was hiding
in one of the rooms close by
and got away
in the midst of the commotion!
But: if that's true 4
then all the party guestsfare suspects
and it's going to take a lot of time
of question all of them
Hey, what's this?
Look, look at this guy's left hand
He's holding on to something!
A belt?!
And look at this man's finger
on his right hands
His baby and ring fingers are bent!
Do you think he and the killer were playing
janken (paper. rock & scissors game)?
Conan!!
Hey Hell
are you thinking what I'm thinking?
Yeah...l think that as he was dying,
he tried to leave a clue through the belt
and the shape of his hand...
it's his dying message!!
But you don't know for sure that he was
indicating the belt is the clue, right?
He might have meant his pants,
he might have wanted to remove
his pants and show something!
Fool!
If he meant his pants, he'd put
his hand on the edge of his pants
if he meant to take his belt off, he'd have
put his fingers on the edge of belt, right?
I don't think any guy would clutch his belt
Iike that if he wanted to take it off...
All right then I'll take this as a hint
and keep it in mind
when I question all the guests who's been
waiting in the restaurant downstairs...
No...that won't be necessary!
Huh?
I've figured it out!
The Killer is one of thoseithree...
the belt... that 'sf right
only one who has fought bravely has
the honor of wearing it around his waist,
it proves he is a champion...
which means the killer is former middle
weight champion, Ricardo Baleral!
So what do the fingers mean?
If Ricardo always knocked out
his opponent in the fourth round,
shouldn't his fingers indicate four?
All right then it's Ray,
the pro soccer player!
He's played in 3 countries,
Italy, Spain and America,
and always led his team to victory...
Ray also played.in a premier league
in England and they became champions
Oh, I see...
no «ee
maybe it doesn't mean 3, maybe
it has something to do with baseball...
you know, when the pitcher
throws his pitch,
he holds the ball
with three fingers, doesn't he?
That's it!
The Killer is #
major leaguer Mike, it's settled!
«ou don't know anything about baseball!
Mike's team never won a championship
and even if they did you don't get
championship belts in baseball!
And that goes for soccer too!
Hmm.
The key to this case
is the fingers on his right hand
and the "white band"
gripped by his left hand
I guess we're going to
have to solve this puzzle first...
Band?
Oh? Don't some people
ireferto-a belt as a band?
The only people:who do are old fogeys...
Bands three band. .three...
Band three
bandthree!!
That's it, he meant
someone named Bandthreel!
All right!
Locate the guest named Bandthree
and:the-case will be solved!!
Hey. Hew
are ou that's the famous
Sleeping Kogoro™?
I know what you mean,
I think he's a little drunk tonight...
Well,
I guess we don't have a choice, let's
forget about the dying message for now...
Shall we start testing
everyone for powder burns?
I guess you're right,
we'll start with the guests waiting
INthe restaurant downstairs
And of course those three men
waiting in the room...
Okay, next...
Um, excuse me.
Yes?
Is your name Bandthree, by any chance?
No, it isnt!
Oh, pardon me...
Well? Did anybody
test positive, Inspector Otaki?
No, not yet...
How about those three?
We tested them first
but they all,came out negative...
Did you do a body check?
Yeah...we did a simple body check but..\
those managers they have
they've been giving us a hard time...
But never mind that
is«it true what Mr. Mouri said.
Did 'those three really hate that reporter?
Yeah, seems that way
Ricardo was suspected
of throwing a bout
and forced to retire
while he was unbeaten...
Ray was thrown out of the European,
Ieague on suspicions of drug use...
Mike got divorced
because he was having an affair
but he's married to a Japanese girl now
and they seem to
be getting along just fine.
And all of their problems were caused by
th murdered
reporter's unsubstantiated articles!
But Hem,
how do you know
they were unsubstantiated?
They took him to court and won!
They proved they weren't
involved in the scandals.
,» &
I DUB...
That's why I don't think
they had any motive for killing him!
I think you're right
Come on, Kudo
What's with you...
you're acting kind of strange...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER: DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
Junichi hioka
SCRIPTS BY
Kaflj1 Kashiwabara
Kazunari kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Hieure
Toshiki-Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
gMasatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatan:
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
TakaShi Hyodo
VT DIRECTOR.
Yuifhiro Shibutam
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshr Kobffish:
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]! KOdJma
PRC DUCED BY.
IMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoynrn": / Shogakukan - YTV - TMS
All Rights Reserved
None of those threejcould have
committed the crimesin-that span of time.
Hey Kudo
you're acting strange...
You don't know what, yousre talking about!
Tha ss not possible!
I'll prove it to you just you wait! =
Someone in the restaurant:did. say
band" and "geta." (wooden sandals)!
That reporter Ed knew a lot about Japan!