. Yo --
- -- ~
bo. : RR
1 CO...
4  » \
193-1
IV Ias J!
Yi), 00 itm
W/UWUWNWD ) -
Huh
,
Huh?
CHIT 1d Dr.
ANAK 7
Hey?
Well,
Yeah...
Wait...
Kudo...
Yeah...
& Ah Kl
EA Kl
Au KI
IT Jt
RA Iqpp=- )-7]
But boy,
Darn it!!
And then,
AIwo- )-7]
AIv=- J-7]
Please...
I guess...
Which is...
No way...
2, RAR?
Oh...them,
you did it
A favor?
Didn't you?
I wonder...
Th, this is a
it so"much...
then shot.
Ray Curtis
Hey, Kudo
Ray Cu tis.
After that,
oN VY ZR] 170) Dla CV CU)
Uh, well, but.
Ray Curtis
I don't know.
That's right...
Now I get it .
I just noticed,
against you...
It's the truth!
set things up
that means...
they'll be fine!
My shoes?
It's SO Ironic
oY Jh-AF
Ray Curtis!!
No case is left
of the letter KI
(51%)
DISH
So why then...
if I shot the gun,
But still, Heiji...
doing here +»
You think so?
Was shouting
Refers to band.
RT Bo
And of coursen
Heilji's House
In exchange...
I When he finds
They sure do...
Let me explain,
You're lousy...
IPOs
they should be
PIT ITI ALLNS ET TILDYY WT LRT MINUS...
which means...
Mike Norwood
Be careful Ran,
Thatisaright...
ET Jul uy
Mike Norwood
Ricardo Balera
Cau IR)
Mike Norwood
Ricardo Balera
Wait a minute...
Mike Norwood
Isn't that right?
So I came up with
Turn yourself in...
he could operate
You know Kudo,
Ky DK
LyoTeU=tEDH I?
LA D-5T12R (37)
I heard the words
I dBN't think so...
that with one arm...
Isn't that fight?
There at that time,
Inspector Otaki?
You didn't find any
That's ridiculous!
I'm sure Mike said
49:)-9.% (AV)
Inspector Otaki?
It flies out radially,
7494-9» (35)
v19:/=9b (35)
Junichi hoka
instead of the left
Kitsuo Ono
That's right... Ray...
to be lit up second,
Atsushi Aono
been a slow runner...
They never check
and claim you were
Ran, you were. luc «
that my body was
Then, you rushed to
No, you're wrong!
That mop then pull it,
Yuich1 Hioure
and get to that room
A favor from. ou-—
FREE FF AL
This is a bad joke!
Was called off too.
I checked the room
under an alias name,
JAIN IKLLS (36)
What'd you say?!
the other. set back,
it was the only way...
All that's left to do is,
For your information,
you have to explain.
When it's turned on.
Gun shots ring out!!
MOAT Ts
All Rights Reserved
Ray turned himself in
'to worry about, Ran...
a great fan of yours
that I want you meet...
JHIN-IL135 (36)
Toshiki Inoue
I bet you could do this
It's such a small thing,
and take the mop out.
For him to have done it
I had to rely on drugs...
Answer mel! .Ray!!
As a clue to deduction
that will be the truth...
Ken]: Khdanm
That's the kind of shot
in association with
Akio Kawamura
It<s Ed, he's telling us
A child in appearance
What's the matter...?
Before firing the gun.
Thanks for the warning.
Band" for the number 8.
With this crime scene!
Even destiny serves,
it would've looked like
Ran said so herself.
When you came out of
with the l.Q. of an-adult,
Iosing my wife Keiko,
they're spare clothes
PRODUCERS.
Will be very, very sad...
I really appreciate it
Maybe it's a.spare?
One of the symbols is
Iikes about this game
Something's not right
It's just a mop, isn't it?
That's not the only thing
some powder does too.
And whatever remains,
This is how you dosit!
Iooked out the window
Gosho Aoyama
Michihiko Suwa
NE Tr -ILICLWND AF
But you know little boy,
He didn't have it on him
Come on, answer me...
because that person is
hevopened the curtains...
Kazunari kouchi
I changed them just now
, we 'came to Osaka to
Ray Curtis, was known
I hate to disappoint you,
tossed the gun away...
before the light went on
for him to run up the stairs
Ray. you're the only one
from the view outside,
under the souvenir table
RT DIRECTOR.
Since Ray suffers from
gMVa~atomo Sudo
or any scratch marks left
you're acting strange...
But I didn't find/any trace
It shouldn't be a problem.
Taka$hi Hyodo
Haruo Oocawara
with your eyes closed...
A plan to get back at Ed...
Is "more than enough time.
If the curtains in the room
Something's wren
I fueled his suspicions
Takashi Nomura
It's just a matter of time...
Helping with the case?
It: shouldn't be a.problem¥
It shouldn't be agproblem.
Spoke fluent Japanese
Terumitsu Okada
You're right, it out of place .
The reason addicts don't
I'm not going to do that...
PRC DUCED BY.
STORY EDITOR.
After turning the lights on.
There's someone waiting
When we ran into the room
MOHLeE Ve ITO lilies 0 zen
In the case of a revolver,
Masalomo Suflo
And since my agent took
fixed your pants and shirt
and I'd sell him information
Do you think it's because
you think it's possible?
I'll prove it, just you wait!!
Without running into you...
on the first floor all the time!
I'm sure about it, this time!
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
they teach in high school...
it's probably some!jokes...
in the bathroom was wet...
in their muscles and joints
you were there all along...
but the more I looked into it
As you walked up to him,
and it wasn't in the room...
Hirotoshr Takatani
And there wasn't any sign
had been shot to death!!
If you were to tie a string to
remove what can't be done
named Ricardo Balera,
in the hotel laundry by now!
Mike worked on. first thing,
Oh for goodness sakes...
In this order. three seconds
stop using drugs is partly
Maybe Conan's the same
Takahisa Ogawa
All you do, is kick the ball!
The crime in that time span!
And Ricardo has always
And for your information,
you've forgotten one thing.
There, the set up is ready!
I'll go polish my shoes now...
4 Hey Kudo, what is that...?
Wereialready.left open,
it's pretty much impossible
<_it'll fall onto the shoes too!!
And the gun shot was heard.
I forgot to mention, the towel
you had turned the lights on
and wait for him t Ycome out...
QIf the gun's an automatic,
What about.your shoes?
Reporter named Ed McKay .
When the string was pulled.
And wait for him to come out...
I told him to meet me in Japan
that's when I figured it out...
when the cartridge flies out,
the inside of the:clothes.
Junichi Mivashita
What's the matter, Ray?
From the string being pulled...
It looks like you had nothing
and kick it down the stairs...
you went to the second room,
HO2EBRAV INDENT
Then put your jacket back on
and the light of truth-/pierces
That newspaper reporter Ed
Upon Heiji Hattori's request,
Those two said they'd like to
there's going to be so many
a former professional boxer
jd like you to do me a favor...
If you haven't changed them,
the switches fromOfar away...
The position of Ed's finger on
Yukfhiro Shibutans
you wouldn't test positive...
you WERE wearing shoes
After all, you had to make sure
and he'll start to hate soccer .
And rigged it so it would open
to have committed the murder
Yawning and pain in the joints
Europe's steel stronghold...
There was also an extra ball
being eaten away by drugs...
It's absolutely impossible!!!
Are signs of drug withdrawal.
The right end of the first row...
The left hand clutching the belt
which you'd injured long ago,
It was his dying message!!
Bomb inside. Do not touch'!?
This room in fr rit of the stairs.
About Ray's drug addiction...
DETECTIVE CONAN
the 5S on the lower second!row
If you took your jacket off and
you can't pin anything on me.
Band" and "wooden sandals"!
On the skin washed off easily...
Because I perspired so much."
What are you talking about...?
And went upstairs with the gun
Los Angel s/San Diego
He was indicating Ray Curtis
It'sia very simple setup.
prio YE HOS HT ULTEHE
After just a couple of trial runs,
Masahito Yoshioka
Hironobu Horikoshi
Kaffj1 Kashiwabara
those three guys could onl use
it should show powder residue.
In the party hall, it was deflated.
You brought it to her attention
You don't have to worry so-much.
When the police did the test,
The sliding door is propped up
the barrel being the center point...
Three men own the restaurant
vow S5RXEEIT
while being somewhere else...
before looking out the window
and pretended to be surprised
Isn't that what you said Kudo...
You kicked the ball accurately...
What's the matter with you...
Weren't you the one who said.
And he knew a lot about Japan!
What are you talking about...?
They'd have to knock on the door
unsolved with Detective Conan.
Where did Conan and Heiji go?
Something the least bit wrong,
I found more and more evidence
whose number is 8, was his killer.
The lights on in the second room.
Since the hotel's not open yet,
where the gun shots came from,
After you knocked on his door,
you spoke into the transceiver,
You should've been able to stop
for scoring goals on free kicks
could also have done it, however
to the Osaka Prefecture Police.
But he was;looking forward to
But you canst prove I put it there...
I had my agent hang on to for me.
When you shot him, weren't you?
You could also turn the light off,
to kick the ball, knock on Ed's door
He could've opened the curtains
Everything he wrote was a lie
What are YOU talking about!
A mop in a hotel's'guest room?
These stairs to get to each floor...
Ieft the field, never t Nréturn again...
If Conan's anything like Shinichi,
and the sliding door is lifted up,
then kicked the ball, didn't you?
ELLEN S SL ELTH
but the evidence you mentioned,
which turned the light on in the room
Escort on the Shinkansen" Part I
Like the newspaper article said,
and professional soccer player
to kick the ball, knock on Ed's door
then kicked the ball, didn't yéu?
And is undergoing rehabilitation.
"Don't know what everybody»
the same time he opened the door.
Ray's not going to be playing?!
Whom I loved more than anything...
IMS Entertainment, Ltd.
When they go into withdrawal.
So when'd you figure it out, boy...
Goal keeper, uniform number 8...
and told her that you were heading
and by the time the victim let them in,
Mike's injured his Achilles tendon
The 3K's Incident in Osaka" Part ll
You probably knocked on the door
The person who is working there
your so called super plays were...
closest to the scene of the murder
turning the light off on the fifth floor
You probably knocked on the door
the toilet holding-your right knee
Any other time, if the witnesses to
You washed your face and hands,
other great players in that game...
The sliding door is.proppediup
because they can't stand the pain
Have I missed something? ..Ray...
Are yousserious, did he really say
the scene of the murder was on the
your plan went something like this...
of the sleeve and maybe the pants.
After you turned on the first light,
It would've been impossible for me
I set off to prove you were innocent
I should, have powder residue on me.
The same goes for Mike who was
I know it had something to do with
went into the toilet right after you
Katsuyoshi Kobdyshi
the room Ed was waiting in, shot him
turned your shirt and pants inside out
I started using drugs AFTER that...
but it would have taken 10 seconds
[4But while we were in the midst of
they're probably sticking close to
The tip of the mop handle is placed in
deflate the ball and hide it in your shirt
First, you leave the door wide open
A prisoner's being transported!
What's this deflated{soccer ball
through the most mysterious case.
Then...to forget the grief I. felt over,
came out and found it in the trash bin.
I heard it in some restaurant once...
If I'm arrested, my fans and my family
but if he used what he always does,
I I OKs like something happened!
The elevators weren't operating...
All the rooms are set up the same and
Conan's disappointing suspect...
the murderer will be caught in no time!
I believe that would be solid proof...
helping them with their secret plan,
Out of the three, Ray was in the room
This shirt as well as these pants,
you'd had hidden and the soccer ball
or a sukiyaki restaurant. one of those.
Even a kid like me managed to do it...
EU 'RDING DIRECTOR.
It would take:more than 3 seconds
This is the time to solve the incident.
000 B LulAngeles/San Diegé
You set this up in the room 'scheduled
and at almostithe same time, kill the
Inspetor Otaki helping with the case...
Take the soccer ball you've prepared
and while you were waiting in the room,
gun powder residue on them, did you?
Barely three seconds had passed
attend a restaurant's opening party.
Then remove the closet's sliding door
It wouldn't have been possible for him
the lights switches are all in this spot.
In the position the light switch will be
his right hand is in a sushi eating form
who could have committed the murder!
That string had been tied to the curtain
knowing Ran was outside watching,
and ran back down.stairs into the room,
you got yours before this happened!
I guess you knew gun powder residue
a chronic articular ailment in his left knee.
Lights on and off is to press the switch...
Then turned on the lights on in the third,
that means there was-an extra one...
Isn't that when you used this needle to
Of course, you deliberately didn't turn}
Detective? Can we leave already?
Opening the curtains on the third floor...
he'll do a complete turnaround and hate
I'm asking you to turn yourself in, Ray...
that the wiring was rigged in any way...
until the door to the hotel room is locked
so that I have an excuse for the police...
then you kicked the ball down the stairs
The other two might not be able to do it
which means Ricardo. who said he was
confirmed the light had been turned out
is where my wife was born and raised...
to do what you said in such a:short time.
Major League pitcher, Mike Norwood,
between the sliding door and the switch,
we found that an American newspaper
in the room you were just in at the hotel
And it seems like the only way to turn the
go back to the hotel and take 'a shower!
A tempura restaurant, a sushi restaurant
None of the three could have committed
with this method, you cangturn the lights
that would take another five seconds...
in the position the lightiswitch: will be
O Gosho Aoyamn / Shogakukan * YTV *= TMS
second floor, which you were in charge of.
In sushi restaurants, the employees use
and lured him here to Japan because this
After all, Heija Hattori's hot on the case!
Thanks to this murder, the party's ruined.
To do what you said in suchta;short time.
He wasn't goingito-the game in Nagai?
A crime had shaky alibis like these guys.
SO youican hide it just about anywhere...
He sees through the one and only truth.
They look like real brothers, don't they?
Even if they could've made it to the room,
you went to the stairs and kicked the ball
If he tied string to the edge of the curtain
a code of symbols only they understand.
The lights you were supposed to turn on,
by the gun shot giving us the impression, ,
but it caused my wife to commit suicide
The lottery for the autographed souvenirs
during your career-assa mid-fielder, you,
fig Beach/Los Angeles/Qfii DIQD
we'vergot¥a lot to worry about:though...
No matter how you look at it, it's impossible!
Reporter in the room on the second floor,
The murder weapon's already been found,
that thing, he's a little childish in that way.
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
you'd have been the first to suspect them!
Fourth and fifth rooms on the second floor.
Wm-fl eerhlkn" Itnrsr PrerJSFfi Drepr;
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
they only checked the area around the cuffs
on the first floor:onfromithe, second floor
RIGINKL*COMIC BOOKS BY.
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
ERE L_EN