Even-destiny serves
as a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
Today's stage is on the Bullet train.
There is another locked room
in an already locked room
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
HA AA
(51%)
Escort on the Shinkansen" Part I
Shin-Osaka Station
LA 88 Tr Aw
FT 2 Bz BR
Al canitidecide which...
Hey, hey...
Isn't that your cell phone?
What...?
I wonder who it is...
No ID?
Could that be a Ion -awaited call from
your sweetie Shinichi?
What?!
Come on! Pick up and answer!
He'll hang up if you don't sooner!
I don't have to answer a call from
somebody who won't identify himself.
Don't be so shy! Come on!
I know! Three's a crowd! I'm leaving!
Hello, hello?
What...! Shinichi!
Shinich ?
Shinichi!!!
What do you mean it's been a while?
Hey, Ran's dad!
I know what's bugging you!
Why should I?
Oooh! Bull's-eye!
Like I told you...
I have no way of contacting you...
But...
But then, how did you know
I am in Osaka?
Hattori called me and told me...!
you're in contact with him all this time.
But, but... Just a coincidence!!
You know the K-3 event...
There was that event right?
Let me see...
which one should I pick...?
Well,
I don't need any lunch,
so what about newspaper A
Why, you just bought one a while ago!
What happened. Ran...?
Well, then Shinichi...
Do you know about that casey
You mean...
I saw the news In the morning...
That case about Ray Curtis...
I couldn't believe it...
Kudo .
Well well And so... Shinichi
To tells ou the truth... lsasked him...
Maybe you're thinking of...
The uniform that Ray autograph?
Yeah...
I heard about it in a phone call
That wasn't necessary.
But...
Sorry, but I want you to keep it
until I get home.
No matter what happened,
Ray on the ?fieldlis"my hero forever.
Thank you. Ran.
Well, then,
there's something I need to check into...
There's something, Shinichi...
What?
Don't you want to know...
how Shinichi feels about you?
What's up?
Do y,you...
Go Ran! Say it!
Shinichi...
Shinichi. about me...
Shin Osaka Station
Track No. 26
Nozomi No. 56 departing
at 14-26 for Too
at 14:26 for Tokyo
No-smoking cars are Number
1, 2, 3 and 5 through 9...
I can hear the Shinkansen arriving.
No-smoking cars are Number
1, 2, 3 and 5 through 9...
Yes.
No-smoking cars are Number
1, 2, 3 and 5 through 9...
Then, I'll call you when I have the time.
No-smoking cars are Number
1, 2, 3 and 5 through 9...
Well... okay...
No-smoking cars are Number
1, 2, 3 and 5 through 9...
Hey, there...
No-smoking cars are Number
1, 2, 3 and 5 through 9...
Wait, wait...
the conversation hasn't done yet...
Wait, wait
For your information, all cars are
for the passengers with seat reservation.
Wait, wait
the conversation hasn't done yet...
For your information, all cars are
for the passengers with seat reservation.
Stop...
He hung up.
I can't stop him.
He's too busy...
Oh, Kazuha...
Oh, it's you, Heiji...
What's that fuss about?
It was a phone call from Shinichi.
The line went dead
when she was about to get to the point.
No! Not really!
What point?
Yeah.
They were in the middle of
a sweet conversation.
Huh...
Then he must have
chickened out by hanging up...
What?
You know,
he's a wimp.
Track No. 6
Wait till I get you...
No. 164.bound for To vo:are going
to leave.
Wait till I get you...
No. 164 bound for Tokyo are going
to leave.
Nagoya
No. 164 bound for To (0 are:going
to.leave.
The doors will close,
Ran, listen to me
Don't beat around the bush.
So please step aside...
Ran, listen to me.
Don't beat aroundythe bush.
So 'please step aside...
so please step aside...
Give it to him straight!
Okay...
A fast ball ight at the center!
Hit the bull's-eye!
What s going on, Ran?
Are you planning to play baseball?
Well yes, sort of...
Don't throw straight into the bull's-eye.
I think you should sound out
strategy with a curveball...
No, wait
What!?
Mr. Mourn!
Officer Takagi!
What!!
Youwsre transporting a crime suspect!
Turn it down Mr Mount...
I'm sorry, Takagi...
What about the guy...what did he do?
His name ls Senzo Ogura.
A narcotics dealer.
We were about to arrest him in Tokyo,
but he made a narrow escape...
We organizedra dragnet in
the Kansai region, and he fell into it.
Senzo Ogura
We organized a dragnet in
the Kansai region, and he fell into it.
Yes, I remember reading it
in the newspaper...f
That such a guy is being transferred
from Osaka to the Police Agency.
If I remember correctly,
a huge supply of narcotics were found
in his home in Tokyo.
1 CO...
That's why we're hoping that
he'll confess the name of his boss.
Coffee...
What did you say?
I want to drink some coffee.
Boy, you are troublesome.
Takagi can you go get one?
Uh...Yes.
But we can only get you cold coffee.
I don't want you spilling hot coffee
over us to try to escape...
Huh...
I wonder if I have small change...
Here it is
It's a ticket to
the Ichizo Sanada Magic Illusion show!
Wow! Are you going to see it?
Yes, on my next-day off.
I didn't know you were interested in that!
Well...
To tell you the truth, Yumi
in the Traffic Control Section asked me
because she had an extra ticket.
Huh...
Yumi did?
1.1 told her I'm not really interested.
Well, Takagi!
1 TO...
That might be a good idea. Why not?
Let me know
if you catch the trick behind it!
Well...
How about this?
You casually tell Miwako that
I asked you out...
What?!
If she turns pale,
that means she has a thing for you...
If she turns pale...
A straightforward pitch isn't going to
work on a girl like Miwako.
Try sounding out with a curveball!
Get it?
What is it with you?
What? Well...lim going...
We'll be returning to our seats.
Okay. See you later!
Who's going to catch MY curveball...?
We should see Mt. Fuji soon...
Huh?
Looks like something happened...
What's wrong?
Has something happened?
First things first, I'll check the restroom.
You staylhere.
Okay.
Excuse me! Let me through!
It's here.
Contains Bomb. Do not touch!"
When did you find this?
A passenger found this just a while ago
I think it hasn't been very long.
I see.
Thanks.
It seems people are gathering over there
There must be something going on.
You must be kidding.
Huh?
I think I'll go and check.
Wait! Stop!
No! It's dangerous...
Sit still!
Hey, Officer...
I need to go to the restroom.
What?
I've been trying to wait
until we get to Tokyo, but I can't anymore.
Then, wait till Officer Sato returns.
I'm telling you because I can't anymore...
It's okay by me if I do it here.
No way!
Darn it!
I'm sorry about that.
Where are you heading, Officer Takagi?
The bathroom!
Did you find something...? Officer?
Do you hear something?
Yes.
I hear clock ticking...
What?!
Anyway,
we must have
the passengers evacuate from the car.
Tell the driver to stop the train...
III!
Bet
It was just a hoax.
I'd like to speak to
the person who found this bag...
Hey!
Are you done?
Don't rush me, officer!
I've only got one hand free!
That's a problem in itself...
Darn it...
By the way, I heard you say something...
that you are going to make me
confess the boss's name.
I'm sorry to tell you that it's impossible...
Huh?
Because this bird won't be
singing any more.
What's on on!
What's this!!
How did you get the knife...?
I need to call Ms. Sa
Oh, no!
I'm out of ran e in a tunnel!
Darn it!
I'll be back right away!
I'll be back... Stay there...
What did you say!!
The suspect in the restroom?
He had a knife stabbed in the abdomen.
Why?!
He shouldn't be in possession of a knife!
I know, but...
But, when I opened the door,
he was splattered with blood...
Anyway, please come!
All right!
Officer Sato, ittS'here!
Gone? The knife is gone!
What?)-
It's too late...
He already died.
That's impossible
Strange...
There is something fishy here...!
What!!
The suspect killed himself
during transport! -
Fool!!
What have you to been doing!
Well... starting from the beginning
I took the suspect to the bathroom.
Suddenly, he began to suffer.
When I opened the door, he had a knife
in his abdomen and he was bloody.
That is why, I went to report to
Officer Sato to receive orders.
I locked the handcuff
on the handbar in the bathroom.
I had him confined inside
the bathroom to call Officer Sato.
Although he was injured,
I believed that it is dangerous
to have a suspect
in possession of a weapon to
be left abandoned inside the car.
When I returned with Officer Sato,
he had pulled out
the knife and was bleeding.
Anyway,
I will be heading to Tokyo Station with
the medical examiner and forensic team.
Don't let anybody
inside until we get there.
Yes, Sir!
A police officer making
the mistake of allowing
a suspect to
commit suicide during transport...
That's a scandal.
This means reprimand
or a pay cut or even suspension...
No. no...
It might mean a dishonorable discharge
Poor Officer Takagi!
What are you saying? Officer Sato, you're
speaking as it it's no concern of yours.
Hello Takagi speaking!
Hi, it's me. Yum.
It's you, Yum...
How was it? You know
Well
You know what! Operation Ticket Chase!
Did it succeed?
Was Miwako jealous? How did she react?
Come on and tell me! I'm dying to hear!
I'm not in the mood to talk about that!
Don't call me about such matters!!
It bombed as expected...
What did Yumi say?
It was nothing...
Is that so...
But, the problem is
the knife used to kill himself...
Yes...he is not a magician...
It's impossible for a suspect to
hide and carry a knife during transport
without the police officers knowing...
He's not a magician!
Without the police officers knowing...
DNis man is a samurai!
What?
Look at the knife on the floor!
Look at how it is on the floor.
The blade is looking upward...
and he was holding it this way...?
This means that this man was
holding the knife...
This away to pull it out ike a samurai.
Takagi... How did the suspect hold
the knife when he stabbed himself?
Of course, in reverse,
it's easier to hold that way.
Reverse when stabbing,
and normal when pulling...
that's weird...
Does that mean that someone else
had pulled the knife?
That's impossible...
Talking about weird...
this blood as funny, too.
What?
Look, the blood splattered all over
the man and the blood on the knife.
It is wiggling like jelly.
But, the blood on his hand is
not hard yet and is liquid like water...
Does that mean that
what is on his hand is not blood?
But, but the color
Iooks so much like blood...
Might be heparin...
He...heparin?
ITO...
It may have been mixed with blood.
You mean, that anti-coagulant?
Yes...
Usually, blood begins to clot over time,
making it difficult to transport.
If blood is mixed with Heparin
and sealed tight in bag,
it is possible to bring it in
on the train to use as fake blood.
If it means fake blood, then...
Yes!
If somebody had concealed
the fake blood and knife in here
this IS truly...
Murder!
ORIG! RIOCOMIC "BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
NdlSUO UHV
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
NILSUO UIIU
Masatomo wudo
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kali Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIR CTORS
gMasatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takahi Hyodo
A 7 DIRECT OR¢
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
EC RDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyosh: Koba; ash:
DI TOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kbdama
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting sorporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
OGosho Aoyama / Shogakukan * YTV *» TMS
All Rights Reserved
We were framed...
Something is stuck on
to his blood smeared hands.
Willzall three of you bring me
that newspaper then?
And Mr. Tokuyama, please don't forget,
the can coffee that you bought then too.
The killer said something strange too...
That person .