Even destiny serves
as a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces
throughsthe most mysterious case.
The "Hope" in the case
comes with Tokyo approaching.
What us to be with the two police officers?
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the 1. Q. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan
On board the Shinkansen from Osaka,
we run into Officers Sato and Takagi
escortin Ta suspect
However, a bomb scare happens
inside the train.
Officer Sato heads for the location
Meanwhile,
the-suspectithe Officers arefescorting
decides he wants to go to a restroom.
Reluctantly, Officer Takagi takes him
to the john without his backup...
There,
the suspect tries to commit suicide!
However,
Escort on the Shinkansen" Part ll
Yes,
This is undisputedly a murder case!
Murder!?
Yes...
First, the culprit set up a bomb scare
in the train car at the back...
I was forced to go there.
In no way that Officer Takagi
will not suspect,
The culprit sent a message to Ogura,
telling him to go to the restroom
in the train car ahead of him.
Ogura was made to pretend to
commit suicide
with the knife and fake blood
hid in inside the toilet!
That way, Officer Takagi will remove
his handcuffs to call me.
When Officer Takagi left,
the culprit who was hiding...
Immediately went to the toilet
And, killed Ogura!
But, but... the knife was stabbed deep
I looked inside the john to check
before Ogura entered.
I didn't see any knife or fake blood.
Probably
the knife didn't have
any blade from the handle!
It must have been a fake knife!
The hiding place was probably...
The rack behind
this diaper-changing table.
There must have beemfake blood
and knife here with a memo.
With the table raised, it can't be found.
What memo?
A memo describing
a fake plan to dupe Ogura.
What!
The memo must have said,
I planted a bomb.
Use the fake blood and knife
and pretend to commit suicide.
When the cop is gone...
I will cut the handcuffs lose and
Iet you escape when the bomb explodes.
But, why did you call Sato
on 'the cell phone?
WwW, Well...
Right at that moment, we were
in a tunnel, and the cell phone didn't...
Yes,
There must have been a watch with the
memo, and the memo must have said.
Take action when the train enters
Shintanna Tunnel...
We've been framed...
But, with all this blood, the culprit must
have a lot of blood on him as well.
You're right...
People will notice if you go back
with blood all over you...
In Ran"s car...
Did you find somebody like that?
Oh, yes!
After Officer Takagi took
the suspect to the restroom,
I was watching the door.
But, only Officer Takagi returned...
the culprit left Car #3 and headed toward
Car #13, toward the head of the train.
That'll makes him hard to find!
What's this?
Something inside his bloody hand...
Something attaches...
So, that's'it... The culpritiused this for...
Ouch
I told! you to watch himl's
Oh, yes...
But, how could the culprit send
the message 'Go to the toilet?" to Ogura,
without Officer Takagi noticing?
Hey, Officer Takagi!
Y. Yes.
After I went to the back car
of the Shinkansen,
did you see anybody suspicious?
No one in particular .
After you left, I think two or three
passengers passed by our seats.
Who were they?
Do you remember their faces?
Well...it was just for a very short time...
I remember!
What!?
Only three passed by the aisle.
Two men were holding newspapers and
another man carried a can of coffee.
Those three, do you think
you can identified them?
Yes!
What!
Inside the: restroom,
a man was killed...
Then, why do we have to
be interrogated by police! Huh?
Well... because just before
the man left for the restroom,
you three passed by the seats.
We suspect that one of you had
signaled this man to go to the restroom.
If you don't mind,
we would like to know why
you had passed by his seat at that time
My seat was four rows behind you.
Tatsuro Ilwakuni
SE =EBB (47)
My seat was four rows behind you.
Tatsuro lwakuni
When I heard the noise
In the car behind me getting louder,
I moved to the car ahead of me because
I wanted to listen to the radio
I DUE.
How about you?
Well...
Norio Tokuyama
I bought a can of coffee from a vending
machine and was returning to my seat.
Norio Tokuyama
I bought a can of coffee from a vending
machine and was returning to my seat.
At that time, I heard that there was
a bomb In one of the restrooms...
I never thought that somebody got killed.
The next p
I got scared about the bomb
and moved to the train car ahead
Akira Akashi
I got scared about the bomb
and moved to the train car ahead
I have been told that Mr. Akashi
and Mr. llwakuni were both holding
newspapers in your hands
when you passed by...
Yes.
Yes, I did, too.
Talking about newspapers,
this guy was reading one, too. Right?
Well... yes...
Then, could all three of you
bring the newspapers?
What?
Also... don't forget to bring
the can of coffee Mr. Tokuyama.
So, all three of them boarded
the train at Shin Osaka Station...
and=beforesboarding, you bought
newspapers at the kiosk on the platform.
Mr. lwakuni had Keiba7
Tokuyama had the morning edition of
Maicho Shimbun and a can of coffee.
Mr. Akashi got Nichiuri Sports.
None of these newspapers have
the words "toilet" orérestroom"
written in large letters.
None of them have holes
or traces of blood...
The same is true for the can.
There is no way a message
to go to the toilet can be sent.
What...? Wait...
This must be...
What!? A man stabbed himself
while sitting on the toilet!?
Isn't that supposed to be suicide?
Well... that was a hoax
to try to deceive us.
When we returned,
the knife had been removed.
The blade of the knife
was pointed the strange way.
Then...
Because it was hard to remove the knife,
he may have tried to stand up and
pull it out with both hands?
Ah...
He is right!
If he had pulled out the knife
standing up,
you'll never know
which way the knife will turn!!
You mean to tell me
that you suspect us just because of that!?
Well...
Anyway: ll'refuse to remain
after the train arrives in Tokyo!!
Me, too!
Same here!
Mr. Mouwurt...
What is it?
Do you remember what you bought at
the platform kiosk in Shin Osaka Station?
Well... Let's see...
There's "Keiba 7"
Nichiuri Sports" and canned coffee...
And I think, two packs of cigarettes.
What's that has to do with this?
Well... nothing...
My hunch is right.
The culprit said something strange...
That person
How he made Ogura
come to the restroom
How he killed him...
I got it all!
Even something that you missed!y ,~
Suicide, of course! It was suicide, alright!
If it is not murder,
we have nothing/totdo with it!
Well...
There's nothing more to talk about...!
Thank you very much for
boarding the Nozomi...
We are now arriving at
the terminal Tokyo Station.
It's time to leave, bye...
I'm leaving too, I need to pack my things
But... Wait...
We're in trouble...
getting our man killed on the train,
and if we let the killer go...
we're seriously in trouble.
Especially you, Takagi,
having been by his side...
You're really gonna get it!
Well, not to worry!
If you get fired, you can become...
* My assistant at the detective office...
Mr... Mour:...?
Well, just a fleeting thought...
make you my assistant... just
What's that?
Whether or not I will hire you as assistant
depends on whether you go through with
your job as police officer...
I need you to see the man behind you...
You fulfill your duty
and arrest the man as the murderer
Do you mean that...?
You found the murderer!?
The problem was...
how the culprit communicated
the message to go to the toilet
without Officer Takagi noticing.
This is where attention is directed to...
When the three suspects
passed by Ogura...
Carrying newspapers and a can of coffee.
Do you get it, Officer Takagi?
There you see the characters
suggesting the toilet...
But where?!
Where can I find such characters?
There... can't you see that!
Tithe characters suggesting toilet...
The letters WC, meaning "water closet...
in there...
Officer Takagi!!
You mean to tell me...
The World Cup?!
1<o...
He carried the newspaper
to make the headline clear to see...
When he passed by Ogura's seat,
He pointed to the letters WC
to tell him to go to the toilet.
Isn't that night...
It. was the man carrying
this sports newspaper...
Mr. Akira Akashi?!
What?
You must be kidding...
Don't try to make me the culprit
just for carrying a sports newspaper...
You're right...
Associating the toilet with the letters WC
appears to be a bit unconvincing in logic.
That is why Mr. Akashi placed the bag
in the toilet cubicle in the bomb scare.
He made the train personnel report this
to the police:officer right in front of him
in order to emphasize
the word "toilet" to Ogura!
If he points to the letters W
and then points to the car ahead of him,
Without saying a single word,
Ogura will most certainly go to the toilet
in the car ahead of him...
Probably...
Mr. Akashi was watching Officer Takagi
buy the tickets at the station on that day...
Boarded the same Shinkansen train
and executed his plot to Kill...
Stop playing with me...
Oh! I'm sorry!
I thought you were asleep...
oc...
I have heard of you before,
but it was my first time seeing
Sleeping Kogoro" in action.
Sleeping Kogoro?!
You mean the famous detective?
Huh!
I don't care what kind of sleeper he is,
but there is no proof that I'm the killer
and you accuse me of the murder...
It is murder...
the knife we found
inside the toilet was very unnatural...
Did you hear what I said before?
He tried to pull out the knife but couldn't.
So, he stood up
and pulled it out with both hands.
Well, well... why do you have to stand up
to pull out the knife with both hands?
Are you fool?
You need to stand up to
reach for the knife with your left...
TOO.
certainly... Ogura was chained to
the handbar at that time
and could not have used both hands
unless he stood up...
What is strange... is that...
you have never seen the site of
the murder... why do you know?
J, Just my imagination!!
When the man stabbed himself,
I heard that the police officer went to
call the other officer...
Sol imagined that the handcuffs
were chained to the handbar .
Well...
how did you know that
the man had been in handcuffs?
When I pass by the seat of
this police officer
that man was sitting beside him
with both hands covered with cloth!!
Then...
how did you know that
the victim was the same man?
WwW .,Well just from
the course of developments...
Anyway, if you have so much to
complain about me, show me the proof!!
Did you find my fingerprints
on the weapon?
Do you see blood on my body?
Of course, there's no blood on you!
You have the victim hold the newspaper.
And then, you stabbed him
through the newspaper...
The proof is seen
in the bloody right hand of the victim.
A newspaper article was printed on
the palm of his right hand,
since he was grabbing
onto the newspaper.
So, I see... that way,
the killer won't get blood on his clothes.
What are you saying...
There is no hole or blood
on my newspaper!
That's why you bought two copies?
What!?
The same Nichiuri Sports that I bought
at the station, right, Conan?
See?
This is the same newspaper you have!
What proof is there
that I bought two copies?
Look. Look!
This newspaper looks strange!
Look, the newspaper that Uncle bought
and a newspaper that you bought...
They looks similar,
but the words are different!
You're right!
The headline on Father's copy says.
World Cup Hero Arrested,
but here, it say
World Cup Hero Interrogated.
That's the difference between newspapers
sold at stations and those sold elsewhere.
Unlike newspapers sold at convenience
stores or delivered to homes,
Newspapers sold at railway stations
are delivered late.
That's why, they can switch headlines
at the last minute.
Because this is big news,
the headlines for newspapers.sold
at stations had been replaced.
Then... The newspaper
that Mr Akashishad...?
He must have bought it
at a convenience store...
It must have been very convenient to. «
get Ogura to go to the toilet
He probably bought another
copy of the newspaper
while he waited for him to arrive
at the station...
To use to keep blood
for soiling his clothes...
He bought the same sports newspaper,
just in case people suspect him for not
having the newspaper after the murder.
No!! I just bought the same newspaper
because I found the difference
in headlines interesting.
Then show me the Nichirui Sports copy
that you bought at the station.
It. it's...
I bet it's been flushed away
in one of the toilets on the train.
We'll find out
when we check the septic tanks.
Thank you for boarding the Shinkansen...
Darn it!
I'm not gonna let you get away!
You...
Now! You can't get away!!
That was fantastic, Officer Takagi!
Fast ball...that was the solution...
What did you say?
Oh... nothing...
Immediately after that,
Inspector Megure who had been waiting
in To + 0 Station arrested the killer...
and he was taken away
to the Police Agency...
The motive of the murder was
to seal the lips of the victim
regarding that drug trade route.
Ironically, the killer confessed,
and the route was uncovered and
destroyed successfully by the police
Thanks to this contribution, officers Sato
and Takagi managed not to get fired...
And Officer Takagi escaped the fate of
becoming Uncle's assistant...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gos 0 Aoyama
PRODU ERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
Katsuo Ono
BACK ROUND MUSIC.
K Ysuo Ono
Masafomo" 1150
Yid>Satonio scuaduao
Junichi hioka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kaflji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
yMasatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akfo Kawamura
Taka*hi Hyodo
A T DIRE TORe
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
REC RDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
DI TOR .
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Kenji K6dama
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting sorporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan * YTV * TMS
All Rights Reserved
And.
A pay cut! We got a pay cut!
On top of the measly pay
we are getting in the first place...
Isn't that horrible?
Take it easy.
Actually, a pay cut affects
promotion, doesn't it?
True, true...
Don't take it too hard!
You're a girl and you can always find
a way out through marriage.
I'm not interested in marriage.
I want to work for peace
and security of the people of Tokyo.
Actually the problem is Takagi.
He's never gonna make it beyond the
post of deputy Inspector until retirement...
By the way...
Huh?
What's going on with him, Officer Takag:.
You like him?
What?
&x BB En
& BB Uh
What?!
What's that surprise on your face?
As a veteran officer in the same section,
I must know about my colleagues.
VN EN... YES...
So...what do you feel about him?
Do you like him or not?
Are you in love?
Not... really...
I knew it!
He looked excited receiving
a ticket from you! Poor boy...
You shouldn't be teasing a boy like him.
You should find a right person.
Well... Okay...
Miwako... has fallen!
She's fallen for Operation Ticket Chase.
I'd better call the other half of
the pay cut pair about the good news.
You should find a right person
Huh!
Why should I be doing this...
this waste of time!
Thank you very much
for taking your time for coming here...
Don't take it too hard! You can make it up
with another successful arrest!
Officer Takagi!! What's with you!
Straighten up!
Straighten up...?
Were-going-after-thexcase-on 4th-St...!
Yes...
Officer-Satoiis~astenergeticras-ever...
Shezalso~got-a pay-cut.
Something-nice: must-have
happenedtto her...
Genta, what happened with you?
I'm afraid...
A killer is after me
Anyway explainjtoius!
Why would anyone want to kill you!?