Even destiny serves
as a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
The star of the show today, is Genta
Like you know he's not all that reliable,
so let's all helpthim.out.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Teitan Elementary School
TW Rh LED 5 TD
WA ZNER
Let's eat!
TeitamElementaryiSchool-l-
TW A LED Bo &3
WHA FER
Listen, everybody!
Don 1 be picky and chew well
when you eat!!
Yes!!
What is this...
I tell you, eating from a lunch plate
in high school...
I feel like crying...
Oh, I sort of like this.
Hun 7
When I was in the States
I used to eat alone in the cafeteria...
That's wh eatin to ether with ever bod
Iike this is interesting and very enjoyable
Well, I felt nostalgic
the first few time too, but...
Oh, Mitsuhiko, you're not eating
your carrots again!
Oh, I'm going to eat them
all together at once later...
There«are guys like him
who push the food they don't like.aside.
And, they are those who brag
about how fast they can eat too
Well, in this class the guy
who just can't help but do so is
'did it I'm number AY!
I was sure it was going to be Genta...
Ms. Kobayashi,
I don't feel well so may I go to
the infirmary and rest a while?
- 7 -»
Huh?
What?!
Whaaaaat 211
Genta's Misfortune
We've got a case here!
Genta has virtually
not touched his food at all!!
I wonder if he's on a diet?
No way, he's too fond of eating...
Come to think of it,
Genta hasn't been playing with us
the past 2 to 3 days, has he?
Even after school, he'd go home
ahead of us, all by himself...
Maybe he's being bullied by the seniors...
Don't be ridiculous,
Genta's not the type to be bullied,
and even if he were, it would be safer
for him to go home with us, wouldn't it?
Maybe he s got problems at home...
Huh?
Maybe somebody in his family
Is seriously ill
or maybe their having
all out quarrels everyday.
=f that's th€¥case though, it's not
something that-we can do anything about.
OO. Oh no
No such thing is happening!
M,Ms. Kobayashi...
His parents are healthy and well,
managing a liquor store!!
I went to visit Genta's house yesterday
because I was wornnied too...
But it is true he is afraid of something.
They told me thatthe would pull
the covers over himself
as soon as he got home and tremble.
But, what is he afraid of anyway?
Well, no matter how many times
I ask him, he won't tell me.
All he says is, It's nothing.
Maybe he'll tell you people!
When you find out what it is,
will you please tell me about it too?
Okay...
Wait, Genta!
What are you sneaking around for?
Oh, are you training to
become a ninja or something?
I see!
You're on a diet, that's why you didn't eat
Iunch, so that you could get into shape.
R.Right!
I saw a real cool Ninja movie
the other day so...
Don't be ridiculous!
Why would a guy like that
be trembling under covers?
Uylit.
Lull bet you dreamt that
you were being slashed
by some blood smeared samurai warrior,
and running around from
an illusionan enemy of some sort.
Dream, no way!! I really
You really?
You really, what?
1.1... .to tell the truth...
My life is being sought after by a killer!!
K,Killer?!
Stop joking, Gentah
There's no way that a killer would
come after a grade school student!
She's right.
After all, he's not me nor you...
Hey...
I was stupid to have told
you guys about it...
Hey, wait...
Genta, please tell us
more in detail about it!
I won't laugh at you anymore so...
I heard strange footsteps
when I was walking along the road
under the railroad track...
It was pitch dark
that I couldn't see the guy,
but when I stopped he stopped
and when ll ran he ran...
It was most likely your own footsteps
echoing off the wall of the road...
That's not all!!
I was pushed off the stairs of
the pedestrian crossing,
and even last night, a motor bike ran
a traffic light and came right for me...
It was probably only coincidence,
mere coincidence!
It was no coincidence!!
Because that guy...
The guy...
Huh?
What a large screw...
Dangerous...
I wonder where it came falling from?
T,The neon sign of the department store...
1.I'm sure the bolt was old
and it fell off coincidentally...
This:is just a bad day: Ymerely bad day!
Genta, maybe you'd better
go get exorcised...
No... It's neither a bad day,
nor a coincidence.
Huh?
Look,
there are traces of the wiring
having been cut by a knife...
It was cut beforehand,
so that when the bolt is loosened and
the neon sign falls it doesn't get stuck.
If so.
It would fall indiscriminately
on anyone who walks below the sign...
0 It seems that the target was set
Take a look at this!
Isn't this the Kamen Yaiba toy
that Genta is always looking at?
Which means that...
Yeah...
It seems that just as Genta says,
somebody is after his life...
There seems to be no doubt about it...
Genta, tell me more in detail about this...
Abo why you're being targeted!
O Okay
Whaaat?!
You saw a serial purse snatcher?!
Yousrmean you saw
that purse snatcher who's been attacking
only aged people and women
In this area recently?!
Yeah...
He looked ju 'Mike the wanted poster
composite drawing at the police station.
Did you tell the police?
Yeah,
about a week later...
Because when I first saw him
there was no composite drawing posted.
I remembered that I saw the purse
snatcher after I swaw the wanted poster,
but I forgot where I saw him.
But, I found the young man who
saw the purse snatcher together with me!
Saw him together with you?
Yeah...
About 5 days ago, there was a purse
snatching incident near my house,
so I went to look.
Then, I found the blonde guy
who was standing beside me
when the purse snatching incident
happened among the onlookers!!
And, what happened after that?
Of course, I took that young man to
the police that was over there!
But that young man said, I don't know
the boy nor the purse snatcher.
Are you sure you saw the purse snatcher
together with that man?
Yeah...
When I saw the purse snatcher, it
seemed that man was sitting next to me.
So I was sure that he saw him too...
What do you mean by it seemed...
I was sort of sleepy then,
so . I just happened to notice
that the man was beside me!
What about the purse snatcher then?
He may have been around
and he may have not
People usually get sleepy,
when they are in a movie theater...
Or, in a train...
Judging from what Genta is saying,
it seems that
the purse snatcher is after him...
Gosh...
and why didn't you tell the police
that somebody was after your life?
1.1 got a phone call.
I'll kill you if you tell anybody about me!
I'll kill your friends family
and everybody around you..." He said!!
That's why you didn't.
say anything till now
Yeah...
But, we do have a problem...
If he hasayour phone: number,
he probably knows your address too...
Yeah...
If we rush over to the police,
the culprit may«mistakenly thin 4
that Genta recalled something,
and God knows what the culprit will do...
He could be watching us here
in this shop right this minute...
What?!
- Ww. ~
And, don't you remember anything else
that could serve as a clue
to finding the culprit?
I told the police officer too, but he was
smoking a cigarette with his left hand!
Which means that
the culprit is left-handed!
Uh. He was wearing
a strange looking T-shirt...
A black T-shirt with a white skeleton on it.
Like that! Like that!
He was wearing
the same T shirt as that one!!
Excuse me, sir!
Huh?
Are you the man
who is after Genta's life?!
Huh?
His face is totally different...
What?!
Illl
What do you guys want with me...?
Besides the T-shirt of the man
I saw had 202 on it, not 1999!
Uh, do you remember
where you bought that T-shirt?
Huh?
Oh... a clothes store
in front of the station called Bones!
Thank you, sir.
0,Oh, okay...
Okay, let's go check out that shop then.
Yes, that skeleton T-shirt is...
an original item of ours!
But, I wonder if we had
anything that said 202"?
What other kinds of T-shirts
did you have?
1999, HELP, ESCAPE,
all with some kind of pleading; message.
Remember in the year 1999, people made
a fuss because of that prophecy, right?
We pushed our luck
and starting making those Ti-'shirts!
Did you notice anyone suspicious among
the people who bought that T-shirt?
I wonder
It was quite some time ago, sol don't
remember the faces of the customers.
Found no
If you could only remember
where you saw the culprit, Genta...
Wasn't it in a movie theater
or on the train 2?
No. . because smoking
Is not allowed in those places...
What about a family restaurant, then?
I'm sure that's it!
You probably were full and got sleepy!
But that guy wasn't eating anything.
I wasustaringaat him for a while,
but all he did was glare
at the newspaper and smoke cigarettes...
How come you can remember all that
and still cannot remember
where you saw him?
I don't know why...
But, how strange...
If you stare at someone like that
it's most likely to get scolded...
Did you get scolded.
3 Nope... besides, my eyes never met his.
I see... so, that's what it was...
The 202 skeleton shirt...
Left handed.
And a place where you don't get scolded
for staring at somebody for a long time.
Genta, I've figured it out.
The place where you
witnessed the culprit!!
Hey, Genta.
It was at a glasses shop, right?
Huh?
The place where you saw
the purse snatcher!
You said that you didn't get scolded even
when you kept on staring at him, right?
WY. Yeah...
If the culprit had taken off his glasses
to have his glasses cleaned,
he wouldn't be able to tell
If somebody were looking at him
because everything would
be blurred, right?
B.But, Conan, I never went to
an eyeglasses shop...
You've gotta be kidding!
Because look over there...
Huh?
You're totally wrong!
Huh? Really?
I thought I had it all figured out.
I guess that's it for the Holmes
of this century then.
Well, well, it's only human
to make mistakes.
Don't get depressed!
I'll see you all, then...
Let me know if you recall anything, okay!
Okay!
I wonder where it was that
you saw the culprit, though, Genta.
A place where you don't get
scolded for staring
and some place that makes you sleepy.
Maybe it's at school?
Because Genta's always sleeping!
If such a person came to school,
we would surely have seen him too!!
That's true...
Hey! Will you wait a sec. right here!
Huh?
My god...
You sure love to eat, don't you.
You're going to get fat!
Who cares, I can't help eating what I like.
You've got ice cream
on your cheek, Genta!
Huh.
What's the matter?
Did you remember something?
NW .No, not really...
Please be careful
on your way home, okay!
Bye!
3 skewers with green'onions.-
and chicken and 4 liver please.
Okay!
I think I'm a little hungry.
But, you just ate ice cream a while ago!
It's French food!!
Hey, hold your horses!
It's only a little ways more to home.
Red, white and blue...
What about the French flag?
Hey, Ayumi, doesn't red, white and blue
Iook familiar?
I wonder...
but, Conan is always wearing a red
bow-tie, a white shirt and a blue jacket...
D.Don't tell me that
the purse snatcher you saw was...
Don't be silly. Conan would never
do something like snatch purses.
I don't know why but the colors red, white
and blue are spinning inside my head.
Oh...
I'll see you around, Genta!
Go straight home, okay!
Yeah...
If you get any fatter than you are now,
you'll be the laughingstock of the pigs.
Shut up!
Darn that Ayumi... All she can ever
say is fatso, fatso...
I'm not all that fat...
Hmm /
Agh!!
I got it!! It was over there!!
The 7th floor of the station building...
In front of the elevator...
Agh, that elevator!!
Wait a sec!!
What floor, s nny?
SS. Seventh floor please
Hey, sonny!
T,The blonde man...
I'm sorry aboutilast time...
It seemed to have slippedOmy mind...
I remember now! The place where
I saw the purse snatcher with you!!
Don't talk so loud...
He may be looking from somewhere, right?
Don't tell me that he came after you too...
Yeah, I just remembered a while ago too.
I thought it'd be better to see
if both our stories match
before we head off to the police.
Right, let's go to the men's room
where nobody will come around...
No doubt about it!
Huh?
1,This guy.
What«d
I'm sure he wrote the name Someda
on the customer's list...
Huns
Who are you...?
If you get funny,
you're really going to get it...
Left handed, with a 202 skeleton T-shirt...
With thestestimon that Genta ave,
it's no surprise that the police couldn't
make out who the culprit was...
Because Genta was watching
your reflection in the mirror!
Y,You guys are the kids 4
that were around a while ago.
Right...
Genta didn't get scolded
for staring at you
because he was looking at
your reflection through the mirror...
In other words, the 202 that was reflected
in the mirror was actually SOS!
You're not left handed,
but actually right handed!
A place that Genta would go, where there
IS a mirror, and moreover, get you sleepy.
Where else would it be
but a barber, right?
And, Genta mistakenly thought
that he saw and the culprit...
IS because you dyed your hair blonde
while he was asleep.
The man with glasses
and black hair turns blonde.
Since your clothes were
covered under the cloth
and you were seated next to Genta.
That's why he thought
you were another person.
What is this kid talking about?
And he doesn't even have proof.
A witness is standing right behind you!
The barber who dyed your hair!
You were lucky
because he hates to watch TV.
And, there were no posters
with composite'drawings of you
along the road where he used to walk.
You may have thought that
you could easily commit the next crime
by simply dyeing your hair back to black,
and that you'd never get caught but...
Your fingerprints were left on the bag
that you previously attempted
to snatch and failed.
If the fingerprints match your fingerprints,
now you have no way out, do you?
T, Then what?
You mean this kid was going
all over town because...
I wanted to lure you over here!
The ice cream that was
on his mouth was shaving foam
that you use when shaving your face.
The French flag that is red, white and
blue is the spinning pole of the barber!
And the reflection on the glass window
was the mirror!
, Everything ended up
reminding him of a barber!
We had Genta pretend 1
that he recalled the barber...
so that the blonde-haired man you would
follow him and walk into our trap.
You've gotta be kidding!!
What do you think you're doing you?!
You're a fool.
Do you really think I'd walk all over town
just to lure you out here?!
What?!
Right...
While Genta was making you
run around town and buying time...
we 'calleduthe cops!
Therefore, the purse snatcher
was arrested
The case was solved just like that
Wow, but Conan, you really
gave it to that guy, didn't you?
Are you really a grade schooler?
LI just copied the police officer
that I saw on a TV drama!
I see.
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko uwa
Masahito Yoshioka
4 . .
Nditd>UU UITHTY
Katsuo Ono
CHARACT R DESIGNS BY
Masatomo udo
Junichi hoka
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashlwabiara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS Pp
gMasatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani!
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
rF ~ » o> »
ART DIKECU TUK.
Yuhfhiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
EC RDING DIRECFOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
Tor?
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kédama
TMS Entertainment, Id.
In association ith
Yomiuri Telecasting eorporation
O Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan * YTV * TMS
All Rights Reserved
The Youth Detective 'Squad does it again!
Genta, I think you're sleeping
a bit too much!
You were asleep all the time the man
was getting his hair dyed blonde!
The barber told me
that he didn't wake me
because I seem to
be sleeping so soundly.
Well, but they do say,
children who sleep well grow fast.
Aren't you glad that the culprit was
not left handed
and right handed just like you assumed...
Huh?
Well,
I guess if it were them, I guess they
would've come after me instead of Genta.
So, I guess it wasn't them...
H,Hey, don't tell me you're talking about.
If you didn't know,
you'd better remember this well.
Gin is left-handed too.
What?!
1, This is...?)!
He probably wanted to
Iook inside the briefcase.
Because see, the key is
still inside the key hole.
A curse...