Even destiny serves.
Asa clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces through
the most mysterious case.
Kogoro's imposter finally appears.
The real Kogoro is surprised
This sure is a tough case.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Ng Beach/Los-Angeles/San Diego
ng Beach/Los Angeles/San Diego
ngB8 Los Angeles/San Deg
0 Beaclill gs ngeles/San Diego
on eri oc farrind en Dir
Welcome Master Detective
We are honored
I didn't notice at all.
ME 3 BR (58)
BBL Da tN, Le Uh
SERIE EA
I didn't notice at all.
Yoshino Onda
(The master of Aoi-ya hotel)
_lH BEG
I had been told last night
«oshino Onda
(The masterof Aoi-ya hotel)
BBULPO Ox Le LA
'Qfifill 2A
a you wl e arriving
in a company of three.
Yoshino Onda
(The master of Aoi-ya hotel)
SBP Dz W LB LA
SEMRSRAR EA
that you will be arriving
in a company of three.
I arrived early because the case was
closed quicker than I expected.
By the way, do you have it?
This is the briefcase I told you about.
Of course, I have not seen the inside
for five years.
In fact, I couldn't because it is locked...
Not to worry.
I think I can manage.
E... Excuse me...
Can't you open it here?
Don't worry.
I will let you know as soon as
the mystery is solved...
by Kogoro Mourn.
It!» NA.
The Kogoro Impersonator " Part I
The air is so clean, it's delicious!
It's lovely being in the bosom of nature.
Darn...
Why did we have to get off the cab
and walk*the rest of the way?
Why not?
The inn is ri ht out there
when we get out of this forest.
We still have a lot of time
before our appointment...
I wanted to get there to immerse
myself in the spa!
By the way, why don't you do something
about the sunglasses?
It makes you look suspicious!
Dimwit!e
How can the) great, detectiyegsh'0v§i}up
with a mosquito bite:onfthereyelid? af
And, there may be female admirers
waiting for me at the inn!
I don't want to look bad...
Pathetic...
Who put this rock here!!
What's that?
It's a "jizo" statue...
It must have fallen In
some sort of an accident.
Let's put it upright.
Oh, no, no, don't!
If you do that, a curse might fall on you!
What?
Oh, no!
Oh, my!
It-s the great detective Kogoro Mourl,
who barely escaped
being arrested thellastitime...
Well, hold it...
The klutz at Gunma Police...
What are you doing here?
I have business at the Aociyaf : okan,
just ahead from here.
Uh...
Is it related to the case of
the unidentified man in the red jacket?
Actually, I'm also
on my way to Aoiya Ryokan.
The body was found around here,
in this Kashiragami Forest...
Kashiragami is the name of a god
who causes headaches.
People with worries on their mind
who go deep into the forest are...
captivated by the forest
and never come back.
This forest is famous for suicide.
S,Suicide!?
Yes!
The statue that you were
about to set upright was
the "Forward Fallen Jizo"
that appeases the spirits.
It is said that making
it upright invites misfortune.
That's why it is left that way
for very long time.
Since were all heading to the:same place,
I'll take you all by car.
Oh... no... my daughter wants to
walk in the forest...
But... your daughter is already in the car.
Oh my...
So, the body found was
that of an employee at Aoiya Ryokan?
Yes.
The body was found during a hunt
for wild edible plants...
But, there was something wrong
with the body.
What-was wrong with it?
We found car keys
but no driver's license...
Cigarettes without lighter or matches...
The man supposedly died in summer
but was wearing a sweater...
How do you know he died in summer?
The evidence was found
In the knapsack he was carrying.
A package of milk and a bun
with product life expiring
exactly 4 years ago on July12.
This had been verified our receipt from
a nearby convenience store
where they had been purchased
Both milk and the bun had been
squashedfand ruined on impact
when the body hit the ground.
Hit the ground?
The body had a noose on its neck,
and there was a broken. branch nearby,
to which the rope was tied.
Most probably, the man: hung:himself,
and the branch broke later.
That appears to make it suicide.
Yes. That is why I am planning to
ask the employee
who 'discovered the body to find
the reason for the questions we have.
Why are you going:there, Mr. Mouri?
Well, this man in the red jacket
reportedly saw the owner of the inn.
What!? When was that?
He said that was around
October five years ago...
I have been told that this man
showed up at the inn suddenly
and told the owner this...
I will pay ¥100,000 for you to keep
this briefcase and the envelope..."
He said, "I'll come back to get it
one year later, no matter what."
An briefcase and envelope?
Yeah.
He told the owner to give him back the
briefcase if he personally shows up
and to hand anybody else
who shows up the envelope.
Although there's no proof
the man in the red jacket
and the body found are
one in the same person...
The man reported emphasized
not to forget the red jacket and long hair
so probably, it ls the same man.
In the end, it appears he did not show up.
Come to think of it,
the dead man had long hair
So, this is what you think happened.
The man deposited the briefcase
with the inn owner five years ago
and said he will return to pick it up
no matter what.
Roughly one year later in summer,
he killed himself on his way to pick it up.
The guy is a fool.
He cannot get it if he's dead.
That's why I've been:asked
by 'the owner to solve this:mystery!
He had been paid not to report it to the police.
That's why he didn't tell anybody.
IS that s
Excuse me.
So, nobody came to claim
the briefcase?
Actually, a man who claimed to be
his' proxy showed up the next day,
the man in the red jacket
deposited the case.
He was a strange man, bearded,
wearing a hat and sunglasses.
Although the owner could not decide
right away, as he was directed to do,
he decided to hand
the envelope to the man,
And then?
The man opened the envelope
right on the spot, and read the memo.
He appeared angry
and tore up the memo
And threw it away in the trash can in the
Iobby. He left and never returned again
What did the memo say?
The owner was curious
and collected the pieces
When he glued them together, he saw
seven letters written hastily in blood,
I will curse you to your death!
Goodness, that's why
I told you not to come.
But.
Don't worry!
Uncle Kogoro will solve the mystery
as soon as he gets to see
what's inside the case.
Well, yes .
And what's inside...
It might be the man's long hair...
"hate the pandemonium you stir up
Welcome to Aoiya.
I'll park your car in our parking are
Masao Jimbo
Xx TBE 2X \
Oh... thanks.
It's a great looking inn!
Why, is this your first time here?
You just said a while ago
you're going to ask an employee again.
A Thelastiti "XY 4d'him
to come 'overito our station.
Oh, Officer Yamamura!
He's the one who found the body.
Is that so...
Yes, I was shocked.
Eiji Urakaw
I never expected to see
a person dead there.
Ell Urakawa
All BR (37)
BREE tf
He was nearly completely skeletonize
Eiji Urakawa
DO xLH
HI... I» (37)
He was nearly completely skeletoniz
Eiji Urakawa
HO Aw I
LWP Dz ruLedt2ed
I- 0;». --1_-_,A4\\I1
Were you the only one
who found the body?
Oh... yes.
Excuse me, do you always go
picking plants all by yourself?
Well,
Mr. Jimbo, the owner Mr. Onda and I take
turns when picking plants in the forest.
However, I have
the highest percentage of finding bodies.
I have the knack to feel
the presence of dead bodies in the air.
Is that so...
In fact, it's usually my turn after our trip.
I had no choice...
What does that mean?
Every year before summer vacation,
the inn is closed for all employees
to participate in a group tour.
You see, the entrance to the forest
is right in front of the inn.
That is why
more people commit suicide at that time,
when there are less people
around here to be watching.
If it is suicide, I have nothing to do.
Hey, isn't this person in sunglasses
a police detective, too?
Oh, no, this is...
I am proud to present to you
the great:detective...
You must be
the assistant of Mr. Kogoro Mourn!
No, no... he is in fact...
Mr. Motuiri has already arrived
and is already waiting in his room.
What?!
You said
that Kogoro Mouri is already:ihere?!
Yes, three hours earlier.
Then, what about the briefcase?
He brought it up tothis room.
He is such a nice person he gave out
autographs to all the employees.
Please don't soilgit.
I'm planning to get it framed.
Where is he now?
He's in Room 209.
I'm going to give him a piece of my mind!
Wait, Ran.
What?
You know,
in the old Japanese samurai movies.
That delectable scene in which the
genuine one confronts the impersonator.
Bearing*the unbearable,
suffering the insufferable
When that impersonator begins
his chintzy detective show...
I enter and show my genius as sleuth,
sweeping the crowd off their feet!
What kind of plan is that! How foolish!
Officer Yamamura,
you'd better tell him that!
That...
That sounds likeva great idea!!
Brilliant, isn't«it?
Please let me in on that!
Leave me out!
Excuse me, but can I have your names?
Our names?
Mitsuemon of Echigo
I'm just a plain old man
Yes you are. My Master.
Huh?
Yes, and give me the cheapest room!
Yes, Sir.
Excuse me!
Your daughter appears to have left
her cell phone inside the car.
Isn't this your daughter's?
Thank you, I'm obliged
Your gesture is appreciated!
Shall we be on our way?
Then, my aide Suke-san, shall we take
a bath and have a drink later?
Ah... no... I do appreciate,
but I am on duty.
He says he's Mitsuemon of Echigo.
Absolutely great!
No, no... that was nothing...
This away, you can do away
with the impersonator.
We'll be able to see
his detective show tonight.
How disgusting!
The show doesn't appear to be starting...
Tihatis.why-I"'told you. We should
have been talking to him earlier!
That impersonator might have
escaped already!
No... it seems nobody left the inn.
If he's not doing it,
it'sshigh time we go pay him a visit.
Hey! Are you there? Phony!
Hey! Come out!
He doesn't come out...
Hey, it's all dark in here!
Hide being under covers
because you can't solve the mystery!?
Wake up!
The real Kogoro Mouri is here...
What's this!?
This... is...
Here you are! Officer!
What's the matter?
Everything is the matter!
Detective Mouri has been found
In his room, hanging from his neck!
What?!
Anyway, you have to.come
in a hurry, too!!
What?!
Mr. Mouri!! How can this be...!
In my tears, your face looks distorted...
But, why did you do
something foolish like this...
Sleeping Kogoro has gone
to sleep for'eternity...
You overdid your joke!!
What is this silly talk?
What?!
We haven't allowed anyone into this area.
You'd better call your colleagues at
Gunma Police,
as well as the forensic team!
A...a ghost!
What!? A phony?
SO you are the real...
That man impersonated
Mr Kogoro Mouri.
This is the real detective,
the great Kogoro Mourn.
I knew it! I knew your face...
from somewhere...
Please forgive our blunder.
I had never seen your face...
But why did he pretend to be Mr. Moun?
He probably wanted to see what's inside
Look, the key is still in the keyhole.
True, let's look inside.
Huh?
What in the...
Sports papers?
Akagi-maru?
Isn't Akagi-maru that sumo-wrestler who
retired 4 years ago
after sustaining serious injury;.
Look closely!
This paper features the September
sumo tournament fiveiyears ago!
That was when
he 'drewymedia; attention for winning for
the first time in 18 years.
But why is it here...
Hey, there's something under
the newspaper.
Look, somethin 'What looks like
black yarn...
For God's Sake...
It's only a bundle of hairpacked
IN newspaper.
B-but... the hair is long!!
I hope.
It's not the curse of the longhaired man
in the red jacket
who died for years ago.
JIf a curse can kill people,
the police and we detectives are
out of business!
Well... umm...
this is what happened!
Five years ago,
two men had a wager.
Over what will happen to an athlete
one year from then
The two men were...
the long-haired man in the red jacket,
whose body was discovered
sometime ago,
And the other, the bearded man
who claimed to be me
and was found hanging by
his neck over there.
And the professional athlete is
Akagi mar...
who enjoyed the peak of his career
five years ago!
The longhaired man told the
bearded man...
My answer is in here.
I will place this in the care of the inn
owner and give you the key.
I will place this in the care of the
Inn owner and give you the key.
Then, who's the bearded man
with the hat...
who came as pro « of the
Ionghaired man...?
He probably was the bearded man.
The memo with the writing,
I will curse you to death,...
Was probably a threat to kill,
if he breaks the promise and
comes earlier.
B-but...
The sports papers in the case
what's got to do with the answer?
Remember,
there was one more thing in it-hair.
When a sumo w estler cuts his hair...
That means-retirement!
You got it.
However Akagizmaru won the
Nagoya tournament,
just before he suffered the
fatal injury...
and was promoted to the rank of ozeki.
The wager probably involved
a large amount of money...
Believing that the wrestler is not likely
to retire, the longhaired man...
Committed suicide
before arriving at the inn.
But, why would this man
commit suicide?
Because the prediction made by
the longhaired man was right.
When he learned that
the longhaired man died for years ago,
he wanted to know
what was inside the briefcase.
He heard that the owner of the inn had
solicited my services over this case...
He pretended to be Kogoro Mourn
and was able to check
what was inside the case. However...
The prediction turned out right.
He was driven by the sense of guilt of...
Causing the long:zhaired man to
kill:himself years ago over the wager,
He hung himself with his belt
To kill himself as well.
What wonderful brainwork!!
You exceed your reputation!
Of course, you're right!
No one gets killed with a curse
In this age of science and technology!
IT IS a curse!
What?!
Here, look at this carefully
The length of hair is not equal,
some are permed and some are dyed
In addition, it's slightly wet...
If all this hair had been wet for five years,
don't you think it's a curse?
This is not the curse of
the longhaired man!!
It is the evil spirit of a hippie
who has long-dyed and permed hair!!
Not again.
By the way,
your hair was wet a while ago
right, Ran?
Well, of course!
I just had a bath!
Don't be so nosy!
Bath?
But you just told me
that you weren't able to take a bath
when you went to the bathhouse
in the early evening...
That time, there was a sign at the door,
saying it was closed for cleaning!!
Talking about being wet,
the tatami mat at the entrance
out this room was a bit wet-wasn't it?
Well... yes...
Are the baths cleaned
in the early evening in this inn?
No... no.
The baths are cleaned usually
in the middle of the night.
That means that...
someone in the inn...
Hung up the sign in front of the women's
bathhouse, to keep people away.
In order to collect
a large amount of women's hair
from the drain to bring it here...
Placing the bundle between
the newspapers in the briefcase,
orchestrating to appear that it was
the curse of the longhaired man...
Possibly to distract
the police investigation.
En<... oh, no---itsamust mea
Yes... this is murder!!
The tatami mat was wet probably...
Because the culprit went into
the bathhouse in a hurry in socks...
And the culprit knows where the
CLOSED FOR CLEANING" sign is.
That means,
the culprit is among the employees.
Yes... this is murder...
The culprit probably...
Is the person with ties to the longhaired
man who died four years ago.
The nagging point is
the strange circumstances
under which his body was discovered...
Car keys were found,
but no driver's license...
Cigarettes were found,
but no lighter or matches...
And, he was wearing a sweater
when it was summer .
Most probably,
the longhaired man didn't kill himself.
That was the murder, too.
Someone had tampered with
the body for some special purpose...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
Katsuo Ono
BACKGROUND MUSIC
NAISUO UITU
Masatomo Sudo
Junichi hoka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kaflji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichr Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
sMasatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akfo aewamura
Taka hi Hyodo
ART Dues from
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobaa ash:
2) Jar
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Kenji Kodama
TMS Entertainment, 140
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting sorporation
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan * YTV * TMS
All Rights Reserved
How childish.
I can't see how anybody can do
omething so embarrassing...
Well, I'm so sorry that I'm childish!
I have seals on mine too!!
Huh...?
The person who found that...
H,How did you know?!
Just as I thought.
He's the killer!!
(£24)
Next. Conan is...