Even destiny serves
as.a:clue to.deduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
Conan; Kogoro-and Officer Yamamura
The briefcase is the link
over time and space.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the ll.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
To answer a client's call to solve
the mystery of the briefcase,
we headed to the inn Aoiya Ryokan
with Detective Yamamura.
A man wearing a red jacket was
found dead in the Toshin Forest.
Strangely, the man was wearing
a sweater in the middle of summer.
Car keys and cigarettes
were found on him,
but without
his driver's license or matches.
The briefcase in question was entrusted
to the innkeeper five years ago
by a long-haired man
wearing a red jacket.
The man who is posing to be Kogoro
finally came to get it...
The case contained five-year-old sports
newspaper and a bundle of long hair!
Kogoro impersonator" Part II
Nn... you mean... this
Yes It must be murder!!
And the culprit knew where
the "CLOSED FOR CLEANING" sign is...
The culprit is among the employees...
From left, "Eiji Urakawa," "Yoshiro Onda"
and "Masao Jimbo."
The culprit is probably...
a person with ties to the long-haired man
who committed suicide four years ago!
And probably the long-haired man
didn't commit suicide at all...
Someone must have tampered with
the body for some special purpose...!
But who? And why...?
Mr. Yamamura!
I found a cell phone.
Huh?
It was in the jacket of the victim.
I found one phone number
in its memory bank.
Would you like to try?
Yes, yes... Of course!
Tatsuo! Is that your.
What happened to that
gold mine of yours?
Let me know when you
get your hands on it!
Oh, yes,
I got a call from your landlord
He says he won't extend the contract
and he'll have to evict you
if you don't pay the rent.
Hey, are you listening to me?
Uh...
Oh, got a customer!
Call me back later!
He hung up.
He mentioned something
about a gold mine...
And he said that the contract can't be
extended unless the rent is paid...
Extend!?
Anyway,
we found that the name of the victim
is" Tratsuo Morn.
It's one step forward in solving the case
Huh?
How did you know
his last name is "Morn"?
We only heard his first name is
Tatsuoffiover the phone
Look!
The phone has aname label on it!
Phooey!
Using a name label like a little kid...
How immature!
Sorry for being immature!
II have one on mine, too!
What!?
You're okay 'cause you're still a kid!
Wait.
That means the murderer is...
Uh... Officer...
Can you give me more details about
what the long haired man had on him?
Huh?
You already asked that before.
That he had receipt for milk and bun
he bought 4 years ago!
Well... see...
Then, would you like to see the photos?
Photos?
I came to the inn today
to ask about these photos.
This is the front and back of the
crushed milk package...
The crushed bun and cigarettes
The convenience:store; eceipt
found in his wallet...
The July 10 date of the receipt...
it is the date of the tour
the employees went, right?
Uh... yes.
Yes! That was it!!
Now I see it!
What the culprit wanted!
Hey, Officer...
What?
Did you, by any chance, find a dead body
in the Kashiragami Forest
after the employee trip of this
in four years ago?
Yes, we found one,
near the fallen Jizo statue
Was the person who found it...
By any chance...
Why... why did you know that?!
I knew it.
He must be the one!
And, the sports newspapers there is
the map where something is hidden.
What I need now is proof...
If I'm right,
There must be some here...
On that shogi board and...
And the table...
Traces of the culprit...
Yes!
I found it!
Hey. kid!
You're not allowed to go in there!
I've been asked by Uncle Kogorou!
I was told to look at the table and
the board very closely...
Detective: Mouri told: your.
Yes, and...
I was also told to take a close look
at the light in this room.
The light?
He says it is the key
in running down the culprit!
Anyway, the estimated time of death
is between 4 p.m. and 5 p.m. today!
That time, the culprit placed the
CLOSED FOR CLEANING sign
and collected long hairs in the bathroom.
He took it to the room...
And tried to divert our attention
by making...
it look like a curse of
the long-haired man!
If only the employees of the inn
know where the sign is,
we have just about found the culprit!
I want all of the employees here now!
We want to interview each one
about the early evening hours today...
Wait, officer.
Can't employees be excluded
who have never seen:or heard about
the man who died 4 years ago?
What?
Weren't you all here when the man
deposited the case five years ago?
Well...
I received the case
from the man in his room...
He was hired four years ago in spring...
And I just told the employees-that
I have asked Detective Mouri to come to
check the case left with me 5 years ago...
I never mentioned it came from
the long-haired man...
I see.
So, the relationship between
the case and the long-haired man...
was not known by others... Master!
Hey... not me I didn't kill...
If I am the one,
I won't keep it for five years.
I would have pried it open.
And isn't it puzzling?
Such an important case contained
only old:newspaper...
The culprit probably took away
something wrapped in newspaper and...
has already gone far away from here...
Unless this newspaper has some
special meaning...
You're right.
Hey!
What does "Front- 3 mean?
Huh?
See that?
I see "Front-5" written before the name
of the tournament champion Akagimaru.
That means he ranked No. 5 among
the "East - Maegashira" wrestlers.
What's "Maegashira"?
Doesdit have to do with
Kashiragami Forest?
What relation, dummy!
How about with the fallen Jizo statue?
Absolutely not!
Maegashiratvis...
A sumo wrestler ranking behind the
grand champion Yokozuna,
champion Ozeki, and the sekiwake
and komusubi ranks...
No. 5 means he ranks No. 5 among
the Maegashira wrestlers.
Okay...
Then, Akagimaru must have won
the tournament
when he wasn't especially strong
because he was very cautious!
Cautious?
Because. look!
Akagimaru fell in the hole only once!
Huh?
This means that the sumo wrestler
fell in a hole, right?
It says "push-down" below
that black circle...
That's not a hole!
It's a symbol for loss!
It means that he lost the match
on the 8th day of the tournament!
So, it doesn't mean he took
eight steps and fell in a hole!
Anyway, I want you to call
all the employees for questioning.
Of course, we won't make any exceptions!
So, you don't have anyone In particular
who can corroborate
what you were doing during those hours.
11<o .
Okay.
Next, please.
Excuse me.
Will it be long?
I want to start cleaning up.
I have to prepare for breakfast
tomorrow morning.
Can't I leave early?
0... That's not possible
So, I've questioned every oneiof'them=s. 8
Most of you don't have alibi as to
your whereabouts between 4 and Sp m
Of course!
My employees work without interruption.
I don't have in my employ anybody
monitoring and clocking others at work!
I'm impressed...
Officer Yamamura!
Did you see Conan and my father
somewhere?
No...
Yes, Yamamura speaking.
What! Mr. Mourn...
Yes... yes... All right.
Excuse me... my father...?
Well...um...
He went to ask neighbors
around the area
and was taken under police custody
for suspicious behavior.
He's at a police station.
What!!
Looks like Conan is with him.
Anyway, I will go to
pick him up at the station.
So, stay here and wait in this room!
Okay...
Um... How about us?
Uh... You can all go to sleep now...
We will hold a more thorough
Investigation on a later date!
Bye!!
Rocks...
It can't be...
What?
I guess you've been looking for this,
Mr. Jimbo...
or should I say...
the man behind the 100 million yen
blackmail case!
What!?
I found as soon as we checked through
the serial numbers of the bills.
The money was extorted from a candy
manufacturer by two men five yearss ago.
One of them being you, and the other...
The long-haired man who had
the briefcase kept by the innkeeper.
And the sports paper pointed
to the location of the money.
Akagimaru who made the headlines
was East Maegashira No. 5!
Maegashira, literally meaning front head,
was the key suggesting
the fallen statue in the forest.
Walk east five steps from the statue...
You take 8 steps from there according to
Akagimaru's win/loss record.
If you dig the spot there, you're
expected to find a pot filled with money!!
Right? Mr. Moun?
The long-haired man put
the newspaper inside the case...
and gave it to the innkeeper for storage.
He did it because he was aware...
That you might kill him to get
the entire fortune.
Well, it was quite natural for him
to notice that.
He probably was responsible for
carrying the money.
And he was told meet in this forest,
a well known suicide spot...
This is corroborated by the fact that
he included a memo in the briefcase.
A message damning him if he should Kill
and come to take the money alone.
Sure enough,
you killed him in this forest,
making it look like suicide...
and appeared in the inn
with confidence...
Hiding your face with a hat,
glasses andrbeard...
However, what you got was
a memo cursing you to death...
You couldn't give up and decided to
Investigate by working for the inn.
Time passed, and the body of
the long-haired man was found.
This led to your discovery that
the innkeeper kept the case for 5 years
and has requested me
to conduct an investigation.
You hired the man to pose as me
and get the case before I do.
You intended to get what was inside,
but found it contained only
old sports newspaper...
The man who expected to get his share
of the money right there got angry.
Threatening you to tell the real Kogorou
Mouri to arrive later everything
if he doesn't get his money.
You had no choice but to kill him and
Ieft the mystery for me to solve.
The best proof is the fact that you have
come here to find the money.
Let's go to the police station.
What are you talking about?
I was just inspired by the newspaper
and came here.
I thought that I may be able to help
the investigation if I find something.
Get off it...
In fact, the long-haired man died
four years ago on July 10.
At that time, I was on the empoyee's trip.
No! He was not killed four years ago.
That was in fall five years ago!
Immediately after he deposited
the briefcase at the inn!
You planted the milk, cigarettes, bun and
the convenience store receipt later!!
You did it to mislead us
regarding time of death
and to make sure you have an alibi!
The milk package and receipt came
from another suicide case you found
after the employee trip 4 years ago!
That is why the long-haired man was
wearing a sweather
and had cigarettes
but not lighter or matches!
You removed
the driver's license from him
because the license was soon to expire.
Your alibi will not work if the body had
driver's license that expired a year earlier.
You placed the bundle of hair
In the newspaper because...
you wanted to direct
police attention to the fact
that the person who killed the impostor is
Iinked to the long-haired man,
and make the police think you're not
a suspect because of the receipt.
We know everything you planned!
Then, how do you know that the milk
package and receipt were placed later?
Huh?
The man may have actually had them
with him, right?
Well, that's
The straw!
The milk package did not have
a straw attached to it.
That is proof that milk was refilled
In the package,
the lid sealed with glue again
and placed beside the body.
No one puts an opened package of milk
inside a knapsack.
Y-yes, yes... That's right!
Then, did you see it?
Did you see me kill the long-haired man?
Certainly,
it happened too long ago to determine
whether you committed that murder...
However, we have proof that you killed
the man who posed as me!
What?!
To carry a body and hang it
from a high place,
the person carrying it
must reach as high as the ceiling.
What the killer used to reach that high
was the shogi board and the desk.
Of course, he had to take off his socks
in order not to ship.
I heard from the forensics people.
There are footprints found on them.
What will happen if we checked
the prints against yours?
I did use them as a stool!
When I changed the light bulbs
in the room.
If you check the light bulb,
my fingerprints should be there...
Yes, surprisingly,
we found your fingerprints!
Under a thick layer of dust!
They probably were there for
a long period of time!
Still, your footprints were there,
suggesting that you were the killer!
I've never heard of an inn
that does not wipe desks
until a thick layer of dust
collects on the light bulb!
Mr. Jimbo,
Iet us all stop this...
Let's not tamper with time...
Why?
Why did you know it was me...?
You told us.
In the lobby, when you delivered
my daughter's cell phone.
That time, you gave it to me
without hesitation although
Officer Yamamura was there,
someone you had never met before.
You told me, " Is this your daughter's?
What about that?
I saw the name seal that said RAN
MOURI pasted on the cell phone...
Yes, that's right.
You knew me the moment you saw me.
That I am the real Kogorou Mouri.
RIGINALRCOMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
Masatomo ufo
STORY EDITOR.
Unic I I1Ohd
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIREG TORS Pp
sMasatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
TakaShi Hyodo
ART DIRECT(ORe
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
UITURe
erumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: hbdama
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting sorporation
O Gosho Aoyama /:Shogakukan * YTV * TMS
All Rights Reserved
I was really excited!
To see the great
Sleeping Kogorou" in action!
I can only recall up
Conan tried to drag me into the forest.
I was astounded when you phoned me
instructions to go to the forest
for a sleuth performance!
Dad,
why did the people at the inn call me
Miss Echigo?
Never mind.
Huh?
Hey!
Thank you!
Is this the way to Aolya, « okan?
We're trying to get there to see
the detective Mr. Kogorou Mourn!
Yeah!
We got off the bus here
but don't know how to get there...
Yeah!
Oh! You don't need to do that...
What a coincidence!
We were just on our way back there!
Do you want a ride?
Yes, of course! Is it really OK?
No big deal. Come on!
Great!
Thank you so much!
By the way, what's your name?
Huh? Me?Huh? Me?
Let's say I'm just a "man of the world"
goingfby the name of Kingoro Toyama.
He never learns...
Don't be silly!
I've just started drinking!
A gun?
What is that...
It's right on target.
This is undoubtedly the weapon.
It was impossible. for people at the party
to shoot when the shot was heard...