Even destiny serves
as a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
Twice around a unique house in a day.
An unexpected solution
to an unexpected trick.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the l.Q of an adult,
No case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
Nishiizu
Ce. Lo
- me am
Well, the Inspector insisted that
I ride this, so I borrowed it from him.
I was luc +!
I figure what actually happened
was something like this...
So... I implore you, Inspector Megure!!
Will you please. ?
I guess not, after all...
What ?
In, Inspector Megure?!
Thank you so very much,
Inspector Megure!!
I'm pretty sure you forced your way
through borrowing:this;car...
and+you call this luc « ?
It's raining cats and dogs
I can't even get a view of Mt. Fuji...
Y.You think so...?
By the way, how much longer
do we have to go, dad?
It's about time we get there, but...
Oh, isn't that it?
The Gunshot at Sunflower Manor
It took quite a while to get here after
the building came into view, didn't it!
Yeah, the rain stopped.
Mr. Mourn...
O Oh... Yes!
We've been waiting for you, Mr. Mou
Ryuichiro Kanazawa
(An Architect)
I'm very familiar with
all your great deductions
Ryuichiro Kanazawa
(An Architect)
TOLLS 33
= RM-E 32)
I'm very familiar with
all your great deductions
through the articles in the papers
I've read about you in the papers too,
famous architect,
Mr. RyuichirmKanazawa.
I hear you've received
another award just recently too.
Un, let me see... what was it called?
The International Competition at
the Shanghai Modern Art Museum.
Sensei... Your guests?
They are Hayashida and Amamor.
Makoto Hayashida
I'm Makoto Hayashida.
Masaya Amamori
I'm Masaya Amamori.
Masaya Amamo
S <a»
Keep your cool now, this person here is
none other than Mr. Kogoro Mouri.
Mr. Kogoro Mourn...
You mean that famous...?
I am the renowned
detective Kogoro Mourn.
I wish you'd stop addressing yourself
as renowned detective.
A stalker?
Yes,
pictures like these have been sent
to me since 3 months ago.
H... You're in every picture
Hmm?
The first thing we have to do is
find out who is doing this.
Do you have any idea?
Not at all...
Please think carefully.
What I presume from years of
my experience is that the stalker is...
very likely someone you know.
What?!
For example...
7:00 pm
Is the award ceremony
day after tomorrow?
It's going to be at a hotel in Shanghai
Shanghai?!
Are you all going too?
No, we're going to stay behind
and watch the house.
Right? Amamor.
Yeah, I guess...
By the way, Ran
what do you think of this building?
It sure is a different looking building.
You think so too, don't you?
Sensei designed
this building personally too,
but it's of good taste, don't you think?
Huh?! I had a feeling
he building moved just now...
It's really moving
The 2nd floor moves once
around every 12 hours.
We call it the Sunflower Manor.
Oh... how interesting!
But, why was it made to rotate?
Beats me... I wonder why...?
I guess I'll ask Sensei one of these days.
There's no reason.
Mitsuko Kanazawa
(Ryuichiro's wife)
His architecture is nothing more tha
crowd pleasing bluff!
Mitsuko Kanazawa
(Ryuichiro's wife)
HERO
Mitsuko Kanazawa
(Ryuichiro's wife)
7:10 pm
By the time you return,
I'm sure everything will be solved.
I hope so.
Mr. Mouri, was it?
Oh... Yes!
Mr Mouri...
Could I also ask you a favor?
Would you... would you please
Investigate his background?
As for my payment to you,
if I I get to divorce him successfully,
Iet's divide the consolation money
between you and me.
Mitsuko, that's enough!
Wasted and boozed out like that, can
you get on the plane tomorrow or what!
Why don't you go to
the awards ceremony alone?
Or, do you intend to go with the stalker?
Now, that's enough!
You're the one
that's already done enough.
You seem to be concerned
over a stalker or what not,
but aren't you the one
who brought it upon yourself?
Like your ex-girlfriends and such.
Hayashida!!
Y Yes, sir?!
All you've been eating so far is meat.
1 CO...
You can never come up with designs
with a taste of originality to them
because of your unbalanced
eating habits.
7:20 pm
Where do you think you're going?
I'm still talking to you.
7:20 pm
I'm just going to get some beer
from the refrigerator!
Why don't stop picking on
people weaker than you?
If you keep it up, you'll be bitten by
your supposedly faithful dog one; day.
Right, Mr Amamori?
I'll go get some charcoal.
7:25 pm
Will you watch the meat
so that it won t get over cooked?
7:25 pm
Will you watch the meat
so that it won't get over cooked?
Okay.
Mr. Mourn!
This dressing goes good with that salad.
But it saysyolive oil o
Oh, I'm sorry.
I used what bottle I had available,
but the dressing is what I just made
a while ago. It's my own original dressing.
You don't have to use
any of the dressing.
Besides, her taste is not
what you can call normal.
My... that's just what YOU think.
Sensei!
It's 7:29. There's only 1 minuterto:go.
Oh, that's right. Take care of things
for me here, will you then.
Uh, Mr. Amamori, where did
Mr. Kanazawa leave for?
To watch the Chinese Language
Course on TV.
He's all excited about giving his, speech
in Chinese at the awards ceremony.
No matter how busy he is recently,
he checks the program out real time.
It's just a snobbish hobby.
7:35 pm
Let me see,
where's my beer...
Have a cold one...
Thank you.
Come on, dad!
Haven't you already had enough?
Come off it,
I'm not the least bit drunk yet...
WwW, What was that?
Sensei!!
The door's locked from the inside!
Is there a spare key?
Most likely not.
I guess we have no choice
but to break the door down, then.
I'll go get an axe!
7:40 pm
Sensei...?
Sensei?
What seems to be the matter, Sensei?
Is something wrong?
Ran, turn on the lights!!
Sensei...?
S,Sensei!!
The victim is architect,
Ryuichiro Kanazawa.
It seems that Mr. Kanazawa always
sits here whenever he watches TV.
He died on the spot
after being shot in the head.
Officer Yokomizo
'YUM
fill
Iv Bi
Officer Yokomizo
&¥ bw UL
Le BRAUN
And the murder weapon seems to b
nowhere in this room.
Officer Yokomizo
LP BALL
And the murder weapon seems to b
nowhere in this room.
Officer Yokomizo
And the murder weapon seems to b
nowhere in this room.
The windows are all locked
from the inside...
A locked room murder case!
There is a mark of a bullet having pierced
through the window here.
Which means
the sniper shot the gun from...
Shot the gun from?!
Shot the gun from...
uh, I wonder where?
Mr. Mount!
This is no time to be joking!
Hey, hey! This room is
really something, you know!
I was told that it rotates
once around every 12 hours!
RR. Rotates?
I see!
It s 8:35 now, so
the gunshot wawheénd an hour ago.
If we move back the line
that ties the position of the victim
and the hole on the window an hour,
in other words,
move back an an le of 30 de rees.
That's it!!!
I wonder what that is?
That thing that is on
the decoration of that building.
Could it be o
There're none, after all...
What's up?
Well, there are no footprints around
the pine where the rifle was fixed on.
There were quite a few between the shed
and the party hall, though.
Between 6:00 to 6:30 this evening,
it was heavy raining.
Which means,
nobody went near the tree
where the gun was fixed onto after 6:30.
If so, just how did the sniper fire?
At any rate, go find the owner of
the rifle on the double!
Yes, sir!
MM. Mr. Moun!
The rifle is wet,
So, it must've been placed there
before the sudden shower, after all.
Bingo.
I'm sure this is the murder weapon.
The problem is after the gun was fired,
where did the sniper go.
Don't tell me the sniper took
a dive into the sea.
But, the beach is right below, so it'd
be impossible to jump right into the sea.
Hmm? Mr Mourn!
This is a fishing line...!
The tip of the string...
What's with this line?
It's covered with mud...
There's mud on the trigger too!
A weight!
I see!!! I got it.
The fact is this...
This sniper knew that the victim would
be watching TV in the study,
calculated the time when
the bullet would strike its target.
Then, at the time of the crime, pulled the
weight at the tip of the fish line from here.
If so, the sniper would not have to go into
the villa, and fleeing would not be difficult.
Do you think that the sniper is
someone from outside?
But, if the sniper knew
what the victim was going to do...
Officer Yokomizo.
The victim was being hassled
by a heinous stalker lately.
Which means that
the stalker is the sniper?
I guess it would be most reasonable
to come to that conclusion.
It's true that unlike the usual Pops,
his deductions have been correct so far.
It's impossible for the people who were
at the party hall at the time of the gunshot,
to have fired the gun.
But, why is this so intricately designed?
Wait a sec.?! There was mud on
both the fishing line and the rifle.
The sudden shower would've
washed the mud of clean.
What on earth is going on?
Was it rigged to hide something else?
If so, what could it be...?
Officer Yokomizo!
The rifle seems to have been
the personal possession of the victim.
The owner of the rifle had filed
a robbery report for the rifle last week.
I see.
The substance that was on the decoration
of the outer wall of the 2nd floor was...
oil after all.
Okay, .l would like you all to tell me
what, ou were doing today!
Uh-6:40,
Right after arriving here, Mr. Mouri went
up to the 2nd floor with Mr. Kanazawa.
Conan, Ran, Mr. Hayashida
and Mr. Amamori...
were all in the backyard, right?
And, Mrs. Kanazawa, you were...
I was drinking brandy in the kitchen.
I went outside after 7:00.
The»party began at 7:10, and
Mr. Mouri and Mr. Kanazawa join in.
At 7:20, Mr. Hayashida, you went to
the kitchen to get some beer.
You were gone for about 5 minutes.
Yes sir.
Mr. Amamori, you left to go
get some charcoal
just as Mr. Hayashida was
coming back from the kitchen.
You were gone for about 4 minutes.
At 7:29, Mr. Kanazawa
goes upstairs alone in order to watch TV.
After that I left to go to the bathroom at
7:30 and was gone for about 5 minutes.
I heard the gunshot as soon as I got back.
Let me verify things once more.
At the time the gunshot was heard
everyone that was at the party was here?
Yeah, that's why none of us here
could ve shot the gun.
I've more or less fi ured out the trick...
But, the problem is who did it...
This is...!
Uh, officer,
there's something on the ground
Oh, Thank you!
And, Mr. Mouri says he wants you
to check on something.
The diameter of the build
IS 20 meters,
the distance from the building to the tree
where the rifle was set up is 10 meters.
And the length of the fishing line
that is left on therrifle is...
precisely 10 meters and 2 centimeters.
Thank you!
I've figured it out!!
That person's the sniper!!
Conan
That kid, where is he hiding anyway?
Hey, Dad!
This is no time to be resting.
Help me look for Conan!
I've found him!
I'm over here!
Conan!!
And I've also figured out the who did it.
Huh?
Ran, will you please
gather everyone here?
Mr. Mouri!
You've figured out who did it?
I thought you said just a while ago that
the sniper was someone from outside.
Please forget what I said back then.
But, it's true that the trigger
could be pulled
if the fishing line is pulled
from below the cliff.
Because the sniper wanted to
confuse everyone
by making it look like someone from
the outside committed the crime.
But, the sniper didn't realize that mud
would adhere to the trigger.
If it rains, mud was
supposed to wash off clean.
That is, the rifle was fired in another way.
And the one who was
capable carrying it out...
In other words, the sniper is here.
What?!
I shall show youright now how, the rifle
was fired without anyone attending to it.
May I ask you to help me,
Officer Yokomizo?
Y...Yes, Sir...
Please roll the paper up tight.
Then connect the cylinders
with double-stick tape and make a rod.
After that, stick the double-stick tape
on the tip of the rod.
What is this double-stick for?
Oh! That reminds me,
I found this on the ground!
It,It's the same!
You mean this is the sniper's...?
When everything is ready,
will you please look at the ground?
This was found by the trigger...
Please hook that on to the tip of the rod.
Then lift the rod towards the building.
The fishing line that is attached to
the pine tree lifts up.
When it is pulled taut, the weight that
is attached to the other end of the line...
I see, that's why there was mud
on the fishing line...
Now, please look at
the top of the building.
The top? Did you say the top?
The decoration on the 2nd floor?
Yes. The sniper hooked
the fishing line on it.
The weight is gradually pulled up...
And eventually puts pressure
on the trigger...
Of course,
the sniper was extremely careful
and applied oil to the decoration so that
the fishing line would slide smoothly.
The sniper probably placed
tissue paper or something
that was soaked in oil
at the tip of the newspaper.
The oil was most likely applied just
before the fishing line was hooked up.
It probably took at most
one to two minutes.
And, Mr. Mourn!
Just who is it? The sniper...
The sniper is you, Mr. Amamori!
At 7:25,
you went out to the backyard saying that
you were going to get some charcoal
You pulled up the fishing line that you
had hidden under the soil beforehand,
and got it ready...
Then, you came back to the party site
as if nothing had happened
With the rod made of
newspaper taken apart
and charcoal wrapped in it.
Because of the length of the fishing line,
the time the fishing line could be hooked
onto the building was only 10 minutes.
In other words,
the only one who could've done this was
the person who left the site of the party
from the time the gunshot was heard
at 7:35 to just before that at 7:25.
And you're the only one I can think of.
You all do not know the real...
the real . uichiro Kanazawa.
I'm the one who designed
the Shanghai Modern Museum!
I stole your design?
Don't be ridiculous!
Do you have proof?
I've always respected you Sensei!
I'll just warn you about one thing.
You don't seem to
be aware of where you stand.
That design gained public attention
because it was announced
under my name.
If you want to stay here
watch your mouth.
At that time, I swore to myself...
That I would never let him go to
the awards ceremony.
Then, were you the one
that was stalking him?
Es... I made up an imaginary stalker
Everything went as planned... Mr. Mour.
Other than the fact
that you showed up today.
ORIGINALO COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito "Yoshi Ira
Katsuo Ono
Natd>uuv uiiv
' 0) . 09
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi hoka
STORY EDITOR
SCRIPTS BY.
Kan]: Kashrwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS DP
gMasatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Taka™h1 Hyodo
ART DIREC ORe¢
Yuithiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECJOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
[DITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
IMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan * YTV *« TMS
All Rights Reserved
What's up, Ran?
After this case,
I don't know if I can trust those
who people call geniuses anymore.
Which means you can't trust me either?
Huh?
The other genius, Kogoro Mouri is in fact,
a totally different person...
How do you like that?
You know yourself more than you realize!
What are you doing here?
R,Ran. ?
I see! The beach that
Doc was talking about was here!
Y,Yep.
Um, don't you think it's strange,
Officer Yokomizo™!
He drowned and yet his clothes
and body are full of scratches.
And besides,
why is he wrapped in the net?