Even destiny serves
as a clue to- deduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
It's summer and hot!
Time to go to the seal!
At a beach, an incident is awaiting us.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
I'm bored...
We came all the way to Izu resort
But, I canst swim the way
I want with this body.
I really want my original body back.
Oh, my'.
Are you OK, little boy?
Ah...I'm fine...
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Bye bye!
Take care!
All right, I guess I'll make do
with this bodysfor a while
Hey you, Conan!
Play seriously!
Conan!IDOn=t~foljget*you;re in!
Yeah=mnight...
Well, let's start again!
Please, count to thirty properly!
Which on Yof the two do you like?
Huh?
Come-on'! Don't hold out! You were
enticed by their bodies, weren't you?
That's silly! Who cares?
But the young woman behind me
wearing the blue striped swimsuit
IS a a different story
I see.
You double exposed her body line
against the body line of you know who...
and were daydreaming about it, right?
Cut it out!
Hey, is it you, Conan?
What're you doing here?
Ra...Ran!
Hey, why is the snot-nose kid here?
I don't know.
I remember that Ran said
she would go away with Sonoko.
Aha! This is the beach
the doctor was talking about.
Yeah.
Oh, no. We're always caught up in some
incident every time as we take this kids
That's why we didn't bring him this time
Calm dow!
I think the more the merrier, right?
Yeah!!
The Mystery Caught In the Net Part I
Hey! It's no use running away!
Here goes!!
Ouch!
Well, do you give up yet?
Darn it! I'll beat you next time.
You re a strong player, Sonoko!
No, she is not, but she's just a bully who
enjoys -pickington younger kids.
Huh? Where's Ran?
While you were getting
the ball that drifted off,
she went up to the shore with Conan.
Haibara said she's a little tired,
so Ran went with her!
But she said she'd come back again
after taking a little rest.
High body temperature,
dry skin with no sweating.
And contracted pupils, a flushed face
But her pulse Is strong and rapid.
Shes got heal stroke.
The ™ we better bring. her
back to the hotel quickly.
She's all right
In case of moderate heat stroke like this
just resting in the shade,
coolingdthegneck, the chest and
the under-arms with wet towels will do.
Doctor!
I asked a shop worker for ice and water.
Oh thank you!!
How Is she now?
Well, her temperature is going down,
d sol think she will be fine.
Oh, great!
Please don't hesitate to let me know
next time if you feel sick, ok?
I'll go back to the beach
where everyone is then.
Okay!
Oh, boy I'm impressed by her insight!
Yeah, She was the first to notice
something wrong with Haibara.
But Al, you sort of brought it
upon yourself too.
Just sitting there without
even going into the water
If you felt tired you should have rested
with Dr. Agasa under the beach parasol.
Right.
I didn't want to feel
as if I were running away.
Huh?
You mean running away from sharks?
There is no sharks in this area!
Not from sharks.
But from dolphins...
Yeah, the dolphins, one of
the most popular animals in the sea
The mean sharks that fled from the dark,
cold bottom of the sea,
they are no match for the dolphins.
Hey, what are you talking about?
The dolphins? Aren't the sharks
stronger than the dolphins.
Please leave me alone. You exhaust me.
What...?
Hey, what do you think you're doing!?
If you bump into people around,
somebody may get serious injury.
What's wrong?
This boat was abandoned on the beach,
and the sea isn't rough at all, so
no big deal as long as we hold it steady!
Hey, Sonoko!
I'm so sorry. We'll put it back
where we found it right now.
Heck!
Hey, Noboru, don't talk so loud
Yuuta...
Can't you see that
the other customers look surprised?
He's so upset now because he jus
got dumped by his girl friend!
Noboru Shimojo
Don't be ridiculous!!
I am the one who dumped her!
Noboru Shimojo
Mm BE
Well put the boat back then.
Oh, but we're the ones who took it out so.
Never mind.
It's also a part of our jobs
as Life Guards to clean up the beach.
Uh... you're Life Guards...
I assumed you're fishermen,
but I guess it was my imagination
Well, unskilled fishermen who cannot
should just go back on shore
Giichi Aramaki
JR bl
and work part time jobs picking up
garbage on the beach to support your
Giichi Aramaki
FEE PE - (51)
MN ED
Says you! We cannot fish
because of YOU!!
Stop it, Noboru...
So, Mr. Aramaki, as we decided before,
we'll meet in Tong-Poo
in the Queens Hotel at 8 o'clock tonight.
We'll be waiting for you...
Don't turn tail and run away from us!!
Of course, I'll go. Just you wait and see!
Hey, Ran... I think the restaurant
we booked was...
Chinese restaurant ,Tong-Poo...
Oh, dear, Doctor, I didn't know
you were here?
Yeah, well...we're staying at this hotel.
Let's have dinner together!
Won't you sit down here with us?
Oh, yes!
Huh? Where's AI?
She's sleeping in her room now.
She says she isn't hungry,
so she doesn't want dinner.
Oh...
Oh what's this?
You seem to care deeply for
that brown-headed girl, don't you?
I just wanted to talk to her...
I've barely spoken to her.
When our eyes meet,
she always looks away from me...
I wonder if she doesn't like me?
No! That's not true!
Oh, really?
Because Ms Haibara was telling Conan...
Aren't you lucky
that Ran's got great buttocks.
Hey, Conan, just what is this all about?!
D,Don't get me wrong!
Al said that of her own initiative.
Huh? Isn't having great buttocks
supposed to be a compliment?
Some type of buttercups?
No, she doesn't like being buttered up.
I see, it's not about butts...
Hey, hey, didn't she say
anything about me?
She said you are wild.
Oh, well
Aren't you happy?
She's saying you're wild, isn't she?
Aren't you the girls and kids
that we met on the beach this afternoon?
Hey, do you have the time?
My watch has stopped.
ILS 7.1<£...
Darn it. I came too early.
All right,
I think a fight's about to start soon.
So, let's order quickly and eat!
It's not a fight.
We're just gonna teach a rule.
A rule?
Yeah
A rule about the law of nature that
should not be broken.
Oh, no.
He draws a seine everywhere and
takes whatever he can get his hands on.
Yeah . we try to limit our fish catches...
And we are also doing fish farming
We're not going to tolerate
him who came from elsewhere
doing everything his way... No
So tonight, we're gonna teach Aramaki
how long it takes to restore
the over-fished sea to its original state!!
Can't you control him?
I guess we can't...
There are regulations concerning fishing,
but they exist in name only around here.
So, in other words,
he gets to take all he wants.
Hey! Yuuta! You're late!
It's 8 o'clock sharp.
You're here too early, Noboru.
Huh? Where's Nobutsugu?
Didn't he come with you?
I got a call from Nobutsugu saying
he'd be late
because he's going to visit
his father's grave before coming here.
Oh, yeah, today is the day our father died.
Our fathers?
Yeah... our fathers... All of them died
eight years ago due to a storm.
Well, they were happy to die
in the sea as they were fishermen
You don't mince your words, do you girl?
They hit it off well together.
Hey, Sonoko! That's rude, you know?
What? Who cares?
Hey, come on...
Well, well...
but it's true that,
despite knowing the storm was imminent,
our fathers ventured to sea to fish.
No! It was not because the storm...
Nobutsugu Nezu
Our fathers' boat was sunken
by that person!!
Nobutsugu Nezu
DS OD
RA BR 2R(3D)
Nobutsugu Nezu
That Aramaki"s pirate ship!!
-» 13
RAE BRD)
Hey! Nobutsugu,
You're still talking like that?!
How rude!
Anyway, where's that 'Pirate'?
He should be here by now!
It's already 8:40.
I guess he forgot about us
and already fell asleep.
You gotta be kidding.
All right, I'm going to wake him up!
You'd be lucky to get him. I called him
up a little while ago but he didn't answer.
Hello?
D.Did he answer?
The call went through
but there's no answer
I only hear a strange sound.
A strange sound?
T, This is...
The sound of waves!?
He hung up!!
Come to think of it...
This beach is a shortcut from
Aramaki's house to this hotel, isn't it?
Yeah, I know... but,
Now at high water,
nobody can take the beach route, I think.
Don't tell me...
He is enjoying night fishing,
while keeping us waiting.
It's not likely
OK then, why don't we go there
after getting sober.
Oh, yeah
I see, this person, Mr.Aramaki and
all three of you had arranged to meet
at the Chinese restaurant, "Tong-Poo
in that Queens hotel at 8 o'clock tonight.
Ye ¥he didn't appear
at the expected time...
And an hour and a half
after the appointed time, around 9:30,
when you came here to check up on him,
Mr. Aramaki's drowned body, wrapped
in the net, was washed up ashore.
Is this right!
Y.Yeah.
Hey, you're getting too close to me!
We are not telling a lie!
Oh, I'm sorry
You know,
it's well known that you local fishermen
and this Mr. Aramaki were on bad terms.
So, I thought that
you three could've drowned him here
and pretended that you found his body.
What are you talking about.!
They're telling you the truth!
Oh, aren't you Sonoko and Ran?
We heard them confirming
their appointment with
the man who passed away,
on the beach today.
Right, Ran?
Yeah...
And, it's also true that
they came to the Chinese restaurant!
See, I told you so!
It's true, but all three of them
came separately to the restaurant...
Oh, Dr. Agasa?!
That thin young man
came at ten after seven!
The plump young guy
came at 8 o'clock!!!
The tanned young man
came around 8:40, I think.!
Those kids don't look like you at all.
No, they are kids from the neighborhood.
Their parents asked me to take them
on a trip during summer vacation.
So, Umm... Don't tell me that Conan and
the precocious little girl, are also here.
On, Al is at the hotel now, but Conan is...
Look over there...
Oh, my!!!
Hey, you! Stop that!
You're not allowed to touch it!
You know what? Don't you think
it's stange, Officer Yokomizo.
What?
Look! He drowned but his body is
full of scratches and his clothes are torn.
And why is he wrapped in the net?
Well, the murderer tried to
make him drown,
binding his arms and legs with the net.
And scratches...
Maybe he fought with the murderer...
Hey, the police will take it from here.
Your help is not necessary!!
All right, send the body for post-mortem.
Yes, sir!!
Uh... can we go now?
We have to prepare to
go fishing tomorrow.
No, you can't!
I have something else to ask you yet!
Are you still suspecting us?
We already told you! All three of us had
been waiting for him at the restaurant!!
Yeah,
but It seems more probable that he had
already killed before the appointed time.
And I don't really understand
why you came thisbeach to find him!
It's the call...
We waited for him until after 8p.m,
but he didn't show up at all,
so I called his cell phone
to ask him to come over.
He just hung up without saying anything,
but ll heard the sounds of waves
in the background.
The sounds of waves?
Yeah, that's why
we came here to look for him.
Because this beach is a shortcut
from his house to that hotel.
I also called him once,
while I was waiting alone at "Tong-Poo."
And called a second time
after Yuuta came.
Oh, which reminds me, I also called him
once before I went to the restaurant
because I wasn't sure
that he was going to show up
Oh, really?
Yeah, I heard the phone ring
but ll couldn't get him on the cell phone.
If you still doubt us, why don't you check
his cell phone to see who called him!
Officer Yokomizo. We found a cell phone
that was caught in the net.
It seems to have dropped
from his clothes. What should we do?
Can I take a look at it?
Check it carefully!
Mine should be listed after Yuuta's.
Hmm... according to the records,
Mr. Yoshizawa called at 7:02.
Mr. Shimojo called three times
at 7:47, 8:03 and 8.18...
And then Mr. Nezu called once at 8:41.
It shows that he only answered your call,
exactly as you told me.
Which means that the person
who took the call was
Mr. Aramaki himself or the murderer.
But then why didn't he take
Mr. Yoshizawa and Mr. Simojo's calls?
How should we know?!
Now you know that
we didn't kill him, right?!!
It s true...
If the one who pressed
the button to take the call was
Mr. Aramaki himself or the murderer,
it would be almost impossible for any of
these three persons here to kill him...
But I also think it is highly unlikely
that the murderer would take a call.
And if Mr. Aramaki himself took the call,
why didn't he take the calls from Mr.
Yoshizawa and Mr. Simojo. It's strange.
And if he took the call to ask for help
while being attacked by the murderer,
then why did he hang up
the phone without a word.
Hey! Look!
Isn't that the boat,
which we were sailing on this afternoon?
Yeah, it sure is
Hey you, go retrieve the boat right now!
The boat may have
something to do with this case!
Yes, sir!
Darn it!
That reminds me of the day
when our fathers died.
Well, their ship drifted back to
this beach at that time, just like that boat.
Yeah... without her crew
and with the big hole in the hull...
Anyway, no amount of grieving
is gonna bring them back.
So, let's just forget it, Nobutsugu.
Hey, you! What are you doing? Hurry up!!
Y.Yes, sir!
Why don't you stop barking orders
and go help him.
Oh, well, that's not my job but my men's.
Hey, don't tell me you can't swim!
Oh! how could you become an officer
without knowing how. to swim?
Your hair looks a lot like corals
but can't ou swim?
A coral?
There is a sake bottle
and a sandal in the boat
The pooled water in the bottom
of the boat is seawater, I think.
This is...
A button at the bottom of the boat?!
Hey, if I remember right,
the dead body is...
Yes... the corpse was wearing
only one sandal,
and a button was missing from his shirt!
I see...
The murderer must've made Mr.
Aramaki drunk and put him on this boat.
Then wrapped him in the net, threw him
overboard and drowned him.
About the scratches on his body...
Perhaps he got them when he struggled
with the murderer on the boat.
But that seems somehow unnatural to me.
Huh?
If I were a murderer, .liwouldn't leave
evidence like this just lying around,
I would throw them into the sea...
Don't you know that you shouldn't throw
the garbage into the sea!
It's environmental destruction!!
Huh... Didn't I tell you that's only
if I were the murderer...
Oh, no, Conan! Are you the murderer?!
No, no... I was thinking from
the murderer's side...
Oh, which side? The good or the bad?
Dr. A asa...
please keep an eye on these kids!!
Hey, ulricer!
Can we start going?
Oh... Not yet...
Then hurry up and find out
his estimated time of death!!
Without that information,
we can't figure anything out either...
We are working on it, now...
Hey! Don't dump garbage into the seal!
A tin can...?
Oh my...
Ouch!
E... Are you all righ
Yeah... I just felt
something prick my hand.
Be careful!
There are many seashells
Iying around here!
S Seashells...
Um, sir! Were there scratches
on the victim's cell phone?
Huh? Oh, yeah, it was badly scratched...
Look!
Now I've got it! So, that's what happened.
Yell find it unlikely that the murderer
would bet on such a coincidence.
So, he must have used a trick of
some kind... What is his true intention?
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
Katsuo Ono
BACKGROUND MUSIC
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Ktsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo 'wudo
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY.
Kaflj1 Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS @
sMasatomo Sudo
Hirotoshr Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takas 1 Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR.
Yukihiro shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
EC RDING DIRECJOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
2) Ia
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kbdama
PRODUCED BY.
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting Corporation
O Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan * YTV * TMS
All Rights Reserved
I've figured it out!
The trick the killer used to
drown that man!!
What?!
Whaaaat I"
I see, that's what happened...
That's why that remark was made...
No doubt about it!
That person s the killer!!