Even destiny serves
a ta clie to deduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
A tangled net murder case on the beach.
The two girls also come to
terms with each other today.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
We came to visit
the ocean-of lzu-onc Yagain:
Ran and the others got acquainted with
Yuuta Yoshizawa,
Noboru Shimojo,
and Giichi Yoshizawa at the beach.
But there was a somewhat
dark atmosphere.
That night, we coincidentally ran into
Mr. Shimojo, Mr. Yoshizawa and
their friend, Nobutsugu Nezu.
The three seem to have been waiting
for Mr. Aramaki.
Yet, at that time...
Mr. Aramaki was ruthlessly being washed
up to shore, a sorry sight and dead.
The Mystery Caught in the Net Part ll
Everybody is late.
Okay, I got it! Keep at it!
Yes, sir!
Officer Yokomizo!
I've figured it out!!
Uh... what did you figure out?
The trick that the killer used to
drown that man!
Huh?
» \Wihat?!
What }
What's the reaction of
yours supposed to mean...
Huh? Oh... so how did the killer do it?
That boat that was drifting IS a fake!
The real trick is very simple and clear!
The killer made the man drunk,
wrapped him up in a net
then threw him out on the beach!
High tide comes
and the man is rendered helpless,
not being able to move, and drowns.
So the killer didn't have to be
at the scene of the crime to do it!
Wow!! Sonoko, you're a genius!!
I am, aren't I?
Uh... I don't mean to be a wet blanket,
but that's impossible.
Huh?
Because even at high tide,
not all at once instantaneously,
water can only increase
several centimeters at a time.
If the waves touch the body
and the water gradually increases,
no matter what the case,
the victim would've awaken.
Besides the victim was only tangled
in the net and not tied up or anything.
He could've gotten up
and avoided the waves.
He could've escaped on all fours to
a place out of range from the waves.
But, if he were given some strong
sleeping pill or something,
it would be a different story of course
We haven't got any such report
from the coroner yet, though...
Well then, what about this?
The killer was holding him down with the
net covered over the man till he drowned!
How about 1t?!
There's no trick involved there.
Shoots! No good either.
S.Sonoko...
I see... So, that's what it is.
That's why that person did
something so weird...
I'm sure that he's the killer!
Noboru Shimojo
Moreover, he hasn't realized yet...
sm He
Noboru Shimojo
that the trick that he used in
an attempt to hide his crime...
Nobutsugu Nezu
is actually working against him
and revealing what he did...
Yuuta Yoshizawa
Hey! Come on, that's enough!
Even all the on lookers have left already!
We said all we have to say,
and if there's nothing more, I'm leaving!
Oh, please wait. Just a little while more!
I want to talk to you. Just a bit...
Um, Sonoko...
you can't think of anything that has to
do with the murder anymore, can you?
So, let's go back to the hotel.
I guess so...
D.Don't tell me...
Is something dawning on you?
Like always?!
I guess it's just a plain old mosquito bite
Shinichi, it seems that the investigation's
not going to see much progress for now,
so why don't we get going too...
Come on, what good is it
going to do us to head on back?
When Detective Agasa's got to start
explaining the truth of the case!
Then, you mean, don't tell me that...
Yeah, I've figured the case out.
I know who drowned Mr. Aramaki on this
beach and the trick he used to carry it out.
I'm waiting for Mitsuhiko and the others to
bring me the tools to explain about this,
so when they come back,
move your lips like always and match it
to my voice through the voice changer.
Huh? It's not here...
Oh no, I forgot the voice changer
in the hotel room...
Oh no.
Here you are...
Huh?
AGRA.
Just as I thought...
Thank you.
It's amazing how you figured out
we were here...
You were taking so long to come back,
so I asked the person at the hotel,
whether there was a murder or
something that happened near the beach.
I'm so sorry,
you completely slipped my mind...
Uh, where is everybody else?
Oh . they're...
Heeeeey!
Conan!
We found it!
He e, a'large shell!
A dead starfish!
Here! I asked the people living around
here to lend me a basin and bucket!
What are you going to use all this for?
Just wait and see!
Please give me a break, will you, officer.
Just when are we going to
get to leave anyway?
Like I said,
just a little while more until Mr. Aramaki's
estimated time of death is determined.
Ghads! Just how long more
is it oin to take?
It doesn't take this long to wait for things
Iike this in detective dramas on TV!
Besides, isn't it impossible
for us to have killed him?!
When we called his cell phone at 8:40
someone answered and hung up
right away, you know.
You've got the call received record
for that call,
and all three of us were at the Chinese
restaurant of that hotel at that time
If you insist on suspecting us,
give us an explanation, will you!
How on earth was the phone
that was tangled up in the net together
with Aramaki taken from such a distance!
It's the waves...
Huh?
See, look!
That empty can...
Is just like Mr. Aramaki
who was washed up to shore, isn't it?
Mr. Aramaki was washed up to shore...
I see, he rolled!
Mr. Aramaki who was washed up to shore
rolled on the beach pushed by the waves!
That's so obvious! So what about it?
He rolled along and the switch of the cell
phone that was caught in the same net
was pushed by a shell
or something that was also in the net!
With the next roll, the switch was pushed
again and the phone was disconnected.
As proof of that,
the cell phone that was found together
with Mr. Aramaki was full of scratches.
The same went for his clothes and body.
No doubt about it!
The phone connected
when you called him Mr. Nezu,
not because someone pushed the button,
but because when Mr. Aramaki
rolled around,
the button of the cell phone just
happened to be pushed!
In other words, if the killer could predict
that the body would roll on the beach,
the killer didn't have to be here
to connect and disconnect the phone.
But, wasn't that just a coincidence?
Huh?
Maybe the body rolling on the beach
could've been predicted,
but how could the button of
the cell be pushed
at exactly the same time
that Nobutsugu happened to call him?
Wouldn't that have been impossible...
I guess so...
But, your alibi that was based on, so
the phone call is no good now...
If so, why don t you tell them to hurry up
and check on the estimated time of death!
Hello?
What?! You've got
the victim's estimated time of death?!
Ont!
Okay, great!!
How was it?
Well, you see...
Hey! Cut out the whispering,
but hurry and tell us!
You know now what time
Aramaki died, don't you?!
Yes, now we know!
According to Mr. Aramaki's
estimated time of death,
the alibis of all three of you are voided.
That is, all three of you
remain to be suspects!!
WwW What?!
Then, when did he die!?
If*you don't tell us what you know,
how can we be convinced!
I got to the Chinese restaurant after 7:00!
Yuuta got there at 8-00 sharp!
And, Shinji got there around 8:40!
It takes 10 minutes
from here to the restaurant
Nobutsugu visited his father's grave
before coming to the restaurant
so I'm sure that somebody
from the temple saw him!
Come on! Tell us!
What time did that guy die!
If that time was when we couldn't be here,
we couldn't have committed the crime.
Not really...
It can be done without being here...
If this trick is used!
1 , 1 TICK... IVIT. AaSAa...
Just what are you doing?
Preparing to explain the trick...
as I'm sure you all can understand.
Tithe sand in this 'basin is...
of course the sand of this beach.
This starfish is the victim, Mr. Aramaki!
And the water in this bucket is
the water at high tide!
O.on...
Okay, back down everyone.
Okay!
First, you should make a hole in the sand
One just big enough so that the body of
a person lying down would fit inside!
Then, Mr. Aramaki who is drunk,
wasted and asleep
is placed into that hole
with a net wrapped around him.
Oh, Dr. Agasa.
Unfortunately, that won't work.
You want to explain that the body is
wrapped in the net so it cannot pull free,
then you wait for high tide and wait for
the victim to drown on his own, right?
But, that's impossible!
Because Officer Yokomizo
just finished explaining that
despite a high tide, there is no way
that the water would suddenly increase,
so the victim would realize
that he's drowning and would flee.
How about if I use this!
A shell 7?
You put and press this onto the victim,
then if high tide comes.
Hmm - I guess so...
If a person is wrapped in a net
and has something like that put on him
he wouldn't be able to escape even if
he did realized that high tide was coming.
But, if so, the large rock would've been
found on his body when he was found!
Was there anything like that around?
No, there wasn't.
Right, if it were a plain rock,
it would've just been left on him...
but if that weight looked
something like this shell...
See what happens...
It floated up!!
But, wait!
Where did you find such a large
and convenient shell...
D.Don't tell me!
It's; that.boats.!
Yes, the killer got Mr. Aramaki drunk...
MILT vwiapplily Hin up 11 uic 11,
he was placed inside the hole
that was dug in the sand,
and this boat was placed
on top of him as weight!
This way, even if he did realize
that water was covering him,
it would be impossible for him
to get up and he would drown!
After the water level
Increases even more,
the boat floats drifts away
from Mr. Aramaki...
You were waiting for that time to come at
the Chinese restaurant, weren't you?
Mr. Noboru Shimojo!!
And, everything worked out
as you planned!
H,Hey, Noboru...
Don't tell me you...
M,Mr. Shimojo, you...
Am I doing okay?
Yeah, you're doing great.
Just keep on matching your lips.
But, what about thesliquoribottle,
sandals and button that:were in the "boat.
With those things in the boat,
it would look like Mr Aramaki
were put on board the boat,
but no one would even think that
he was being locked up under the boat.
Moreover, the sea water that
accumulated at the bottom of the boat
made it even heavier.
(It-was all planned to make it
harder for Mr. Aramaki to escape.
It is true that from what you said just now,
it is possible to
commit the crime without being here.
But, how did you come to the conclusion
that I'm the one who did it?
You knew the order of the incoming call
history of his cell phone, didn't you?
That your name is listed
next to Mr. Yoshizawa's.
That's because he said that he called
before coming to the Chinese restaurant.
Mr. Yoshizawa came at 8:00 sharp.
You made the first phone call at 7:47.
How did you know that Mr. Yoshizawa
called Mr. Aramaki before you did?
S,So that's because...
You knew that Mr. Yoshizawa called
Mr. Aramaki's cell phone!
You heard the call come in
when you were setting up the boat trick
that I just finished explaining!
I See.
Just what are you talking about? You're
just making an irresponsible remark!
I mean, so you're saying
that I'm the killer
just because I made a mistake
in the order of the received calls list!
There's no proof that I carried out the
trick that you explained just now either!
It could be that somebody
just got him drunk,
wrapped him up in a net
and dropped him into the ocean.
Right, Mr. Agasa...
there is no proof that
Mr. Shimojo committed the murder...
There is no such thing.
What we have are all proof that
are advantageous to you...
Huh?
That's right!
The only evidence that you have now is
that I was far awayjin that Chinese
restaurant at the time the guy died!!
Who can testify that for you?
Huh?
Aren't you one of
the witnesses for that too!
Oh? At what point of time
are you referring to?
I've become a bit forgetful recently so...
Why you...
You were there too; weren't you?!
Right by me, at the Chinese restaurant!
At about 8:00 when he died!!
Wait a second, Mr. Shimojo?
Huh?
How do you know that Mr. Aramaki's
time of death is about 8:00?
I heard you whispering
among yourselves a while ago!
That's strange
The estimated time of death
that was reported to me,
was from 6:00 when Mr. Aramaki
was found dead to 9:00.
D,Don't say anything wrong!
I'm sure you can get
the details of his death, can't you,
postmortem rigidity and death spots.
Absolutely.
The estimated time of death
Is usually assumed by signs of
& postmortem rigidity, death spots
and rectal temperatures,
but that is, if the body is laid to rest
in one place at constant temperature.
In Mr. Aramaki's case, his body tossed
about by the waves and spun around.
Gravity
In this case, the blood accumulates at
the bottom of the body because of gravity,
and it becomes impossible
to judge by death spots...
The muscles that become rigid
are difficult to set in place...
Due to constant covering with waves,
the speed of rectal temperature
decrease becomes abnormal.
Therefore, its impossible to
estimate an accurate time of death.
In other words, nobody including the
police know what time Mr. Aramaki died.
But if you are the killer that set it up
so that he would drown at that time,
of course you would know!!
Noboru!
Don't tell me
you did it for our fathers...
Yeah... Thank me for it.
Because I conjured up all the courage
within me to kill the bastard Aramaki
who killed our fathers 8 years ago!!
8 years ago, wasn't that
an accident th "Happened
because the men set out on their boat
despite knowing that there was a storm.
Our fathers didn't just sail out
to prove how macho they were.
Aramaki ignored the report of
an oncoming storm and sailed out,
so our fathers went out
after him to call him back
Aramaki lost control of the wheels
because of the high waves,
and not only did he crash into
the boat of our fathers,
but also he left our fathers
who were thrown out into the sea to die,
and went back to shore alone!!
I asked a timid mate
that was on board his boat at that time,
so there's no mistake about it!!
Then, why didn't you take
him to the police?!
He disappeared out of the blue...
What?!
I asked Aramaki about him, and that guy,
without a tinge of guilt, wise cracked...
Do you know
how a perfect crime is committed?
You set sail with another person,
and when you're out at sea,
you push the other guy off the boat...
The body won't be found
and there are no witnesses either...
How about it? It's simple, right?
Which means that
Aramaki killed that man too...
But, you didn't need to kill him, did you?
Now, you're just as guilty as he is...
Just what do you mean by that...
I avenged the death of our fathers,
for you guys too, you know?!
After I sacrificed myself,
went out of my way to conjure up courage
and pass judgment on that guy
all by myself, what's your right...
What right do you have
talking to me like that!!
N,No way.
Ran...
No way...
The word courage is to be used to
conjure up feelings of justice...
It should never be used to
justify taking someone's life.
The killer, who was rendered speechless
at Ran"s remark,
was escorted silently to the
Shizuoka Prefectural Police Department.
He wore a calm and sad smile
on his face as he was being taken away.
ORIGINALOCOMIC "BOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
Katsuo no
BA XGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo (no
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo wudo
reser rid
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kan]: Kashlwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Hioure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIR CTORS
gMasatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio awamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR.
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kodama
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecastine Corporation
Gosho Aoyama./ Shogakukan * YTV * TMS
All Rights Reserved
Maybe I stuck my nose In too far...
Nope, you did just great.
You really surprised me!
I just thought that was
what Shinichi might've said.
Are you in the mood for
Iove or something?
Courage...
Is a word to be used to conjure up...
feelings of justice...
I Mm... 'Al Haibara.
Nice to meet you...
Nice to meet you, too .
Um, neither your money nor
your credit cards have been stolen.
All the documents have to do with
the village head's work
and are all dated today!
Something bothers me...
Something's fishy...