Even destiny serves as a clue to, deduction
and the light of truth pierces through
the most mysterious case.
Afrpension in the highlands
at:the end of summer.
An impossible crime
involving a one-path road.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in
appearance with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
Alibi of the Healing Forest
Thank you for coming all this way to
an inconvenient place like this.
This is the only road there is,
that will take you topour pension.
This is the onl road there is,
that will take you torour pension.
Shiro Murakami
tum 477573-7
This is the onl road there is,
that will take you topour pension.
We should be there
In the next 10 minutes,
so please bear with me a while longer.
Sure!
Is ititrue that
you are running the pension
together with your brother?
Oh, no.
I just help my older brother
at the pension
Kinji Tateshiba
x eh UL
5% fi fl(27)
during the summer.
Kinji Tateshiba
«oh UL
BE 7 Se
during the summer.
H~~~I see...
Come to think of it, Shiro!
We're, going to be delivering
watermelon to dad, aren't we?
Isn't our priority,
to see:our guests off first?
Are we going to stop over somewhere?
If so, then...
I would like to go to the restroom...
Yes, of course.
It's right over there across the bridge...
Oh, that's just great!
Oh come on dad,
you're drinking too much!!
Ryuzo Murakami
Ded ¥3
I feel just great!!
Oh!!! Well, well,
this is indeed a fine vase!!
Ehem!!
Are you a ceramic artist,
village head?
I'm just doing it to kill time
because I live alone.
But, I got hurt yesterday
and can't do a thing today!
Oh, that's right!
Father,
this was taken from our field.
I hope you like it
Phooey!
Are you trying to humor me?
Father,
Shiro's doing no such thing!
You too!!
Despite my strongly going against
him marrying into his wife's famil, ,
he went along and did so!!
Listen, Shiro!
I have no intention of lending you money!
Take that and et out of here!
I'm sorry you had to see
something so unsightly.
I'm very sorry.
Nah...
I guess he just happened to be
in a bad mood today.
No...
he's always like that.
On top of being stubborn,
his way of thinking is old fashioned.
Hello!
Hi"there: Alo!
Making your rounds
collecting payment?
I was going to,
Aiko Misawa
R EF (25)
Bic eSELIZDULVA
FLEECE AR
Aiko Misawa
R EF (25)
mzobibwrauv»
but I forgot to bring the ledger.
Aiko Misawa
R BE 7 (25)
3 edRL\DLA
but I forgot to bring the ledger.
Would you like me
to pay for-fourusdnwgadvance? .
Thanks,
but I'll come: to.collect it-next time,
because I'd like to be
meticulous with money matters.
Ho-hum!!
How do you do, Aiko?
I am Kogoro Mouri a private detective
I'm planning to spend the night here,
and my room Is. ..um, let me see...
Oh, I'm sorry
I've got to make deliveries,
so if you will excuse me!
Eh, heh, heh...
The beauty of the healing forest...
$Agh!!
My hat!!
Agh, be carefull!
Dont go. into. .thérriver
because it's dangerous!!
I'll go get it for you
Thank" God!
I've .got it: Miss)
Than X ouso, much
I'm sure glad you didne sget wet!
But, your slacks got wet, Mr Murakami...
No problem.
But, more than that,
now everybody knows that
I can't swim, ha, ha...
See you, then.
We're going to go
pick mountain vegetables for dinner.
The part-timer inside will
take care of thingsffor, ou
Thank you!
Here's your additional order.
Than you always!!
Is a tour group spending the night here
or something today?
Oh, well sort of...
Haah
There's no more beer~~~Beer!!
Uuuugyaaah!
Oh dad.
How dare he get drunk and sack out...
Mr. Murakami,
did you pick mountain vegetables?
Huh?!
Yes... well sort of.
I remembered
that I had something to do
so I came back early.
Oh, but please rest assured.
My younger brother's taking care of
gathering the mountain vegetables
I\-§I%F~v
Now, where is this now?
Heh, heh, heh...
I tell you- dad!
Yawn! Mouri Detective Office.
What did you say...
What?
The village head had been killed?!
I'm back
Yes! I understand,
I'll be right over, yes.
oji Midonikawa
You're Mr. Kogoro Mouri!
Oji Midorikawa
I'm Midorikawa who is stationed here.
I £ (Ga)
Good work.
I'd like to see the murder site!
Yes, sir!
This way please!!!
F.,Father!
A paper knife...
so this is the murder weapon...
R.M... initials?
It's the belongings of the village head.
Judging from the looks of the corpse,
the killer was in the study
and probably stabbed
the village head from the front!
Since the papers were scattered,
does that mean that the
killer was looking for something?
Hmm...
About the method of entry,
aside from the front entrance,
all the other places
are locked from the inside.
Hmm...
Aiko,
please give us the details of
when you found the village head.
Yes, sir!
If I remembericorrectly,
at about 5 minutes to 4,
I came here to collect payment for milk.
I had him stamp this notebook back then.
And after that?
On my way to Shiro's pension,
I heard someone scream,
so came back here immediately...
and found the village head...
And, what time did you hear the scream?
Four o'clock
I was in the middle of making
my round.ofapatrol...
I arrived at the village head's house
a while after Aiko,
which was about 5 minutes after 4:00.
Which means,
he was killed only within a few minutes
after Aiko left his house...!
In other words,
the killer seems to have been here
when Aiko came to collect the money.
Huh?!
Um, his money and credit cards
haven't been stolen.
Besides, the things on his desk
just seem to have fallen on the floor,
that it doesn { seem 10 be a robbery case.
Ouch!
I tell you,
don't touch things without permission!!
It seems that
the killer came to see the village head,
encountered a problem
and impulsively stabbed him...!
By the way,
where were you two at 4:00 sharp?
Oh, I was already back at the pension.
I was probably
walking along the one path road.
Can someone prove that for you?
Well
At around 4:10
when Mr. Murakami got a call from Aiko,
he was already here at the pension!
And, Mr. Tateshiba came back
while Mr. Murakami was on the phone.
Ri ht!
And, besides...
Why would we want to kill father...
It takes at least an hour to get
from father's house
to this pension here on foot.
If by car it only takes about 5 minutes,
but back then I went out on foot.
The car was parked
at the pension right through.
Any other way of transportation?
There is no other way...
There's only one road to the pension
besides it's a dead end street.
Precipitous mountains
surround the path...!
That means
it would be impossible
to return to the pension
from the village head's house
in 10 minutes!!
Whew...
Which means that the killer is Aiko?!
Judging from the wound,
the killer would havebeen splattered
with a large amount of blood.
I see!!!
In other words,
it would've been impossible
for anyone here to commit the crime.
The culprit is most likely a third party,
who broke in to steal something
and ended. up committing a murder.
Whew...
Something's not right .
Something...
Will you show me that notebook?
Huh? You mean this?
Sure, sonny.
All the papers are dated today,
and have to do
with the village head's work!!
But...
Why...?
Mr. Mourn!
Is it all right
if we go back to the pension once?
I don't see why not.
Huh?
The clay has decreased.
The village head whose hand was hurt
couldn't have used the clay
Besides,
the rope that was on top is also gone...
I get it!!
What's up, Pops?!
Mr. Mourn!
Dad!
It's nothing,
I just figured out who the killer is!!
The killer is among us!!
But...
you just finished saying a while ago that
it would be impossible for anyone here
to commit the crime...
As far as Aiko is concerned,
she was immediately deleted
from the list of suspects.
The killer would've had to
get rid of the clothes
that was splattered with blood.
But, she did not change clothes,
nor did she have time
to get rid of the blood
that would've splattered on her
Whew...
Shiro and Kinji have
both changed clothes...
We both changed clothes
because we got dirty
picking mountain vegetables.
Either way,
if one of the two were to be the Killer,
how was he able to
get back to the pension in 10 minutes?
He went down the river!!
If go downstream the Tsunakawa
that flows near
the village heads house and the pension
well, it'd be possible to come back
to the pension in 2 to 3 minutes.
But,
there is no scaffold in that area
where you can tie a boat to!
No there is none
Moreover, since this was
murder committed on impulse,
no boat was prepared beforehand either!
Are you saying
that the killer swam down the river?
Then,
I'm counted out because I can't swim!
Huh?!
1, Then did Kinj did wt?
DD. Don't be ridiculous!
Well, let me finish
Most probably after the killer killed
the village head on impulse,
he snapped back to himself
and realized that
a lot of blood had splattered on him.
Therefore, he figured
he had to get out of the village head's
residence as soon as possible
and wash off the blood from himself
The method he thought of,
was to use the clay and rope
that was left on the dirt floor!
The clay and rope...
but: how?
First the killer takes off his slacks
that was splattered with blood.
He then washed his slacks lightly
at the water basin of the dirt floor,
taking the clay and rope with him.
He then,
turned his wet slacks inside out,
smearing clay
on the inside of his slacks.
He turns his slacks right side out again,
then tied the hem of each side
of his slacks with the rope.
Next,
he holds the waist part of the slacks,
filling it with air...
Then,
he jumps off the bridge into the river.
The slacks that inflated served as a float,
and the killer headed downstream...
Like a child usual plays
when taking a bath
by filling the towel up with air.
It's the same principle
Clay keeps water from entering
the slacks through the seams!
All the killer had to do was
Ieave the rest up to the flow...
Then he would reach the bank of the river
beside the pension!
Almost all the blood that's splattered
on his slacks would wash off too!
After arriving,
the killer quickly changes clothes
and appears before us
as if nothing had happened.
which one of them is the killer?
Before that, Aiko!
Yes?
We will be taking
that notebook as evidence,
so please collect
what you have to from Mr. Murakami.
Why,
at a time like this...
Could you stamp it then...
It seems that youyve realized
what I'm trying to get at.
That notebook,
Mr Murakami is the very thing
that is evidence of you being the killer!!
Please closely compare the stamps
of Ryuzo and Shiro.
Their stamps are interchanged!
What!!
Look!
\ UZO's seat up to last month is
stamped nicely but,
this month
a part of the outer circle is chipped off.
Youire right!
Shiro's is,
until last month,
the outer circle of the stamp
Is chipped off, but
the stamp for this month is
perfectly rounded with no chips.
I see!
Taking a good look,
it's obvious that
the two stamps are interchanged!
Right!
In other words, Shiro,
that serves as infallible evidence
that you were at the village head's house
when the murder took place!
Shiro visited the village head's house
bringing his own seal with him,
but got into an argument
with the village head.
Since the stamps
of both men are involved,
they must've argued on money matters.
Then, one of them threw the papers
that were on the desk onto the floor,
and this was
when their stamps interchanged.
It did not interchange today!
I'm sure it was the other day...
That's highly unlikely!
The stamps were interchanged today
just before Aiko came here.
The papers
that are scattered on the floor
are all stamped
with today's date on them.
Moreover,
that stamp is exactly the same
as the one the village had been
using up to last month.
In other words,
out of all the things he stamped
his seal on today,
the only time hexstamped a different seal
IS when Aiko came to collect payment.
He He probably stamped
a different seal just today...
Being that he holds
an important position as the village head,
he would never suddenly change his seal.
Besides, whether the seal is real or fake,
as well as the fingerprints on the seal
can easily be verified.
T, This could never serve as evidence...
Mr. Murakami...
Conan told me
that before you went
mountain vegetable picking,
you stamped your seal for the liquor man
who came to make delivery.
If we check which seal that was, then...
It s not true, is it, Shiro?
Why!
Why would you have to kill father!
Say something, Shiro!
Tell me that it's not true!
Father... hated me...
I was always being compared with
my brother who excelled in everything...
Shiro...
Financial woes
because of sluggish economy...
I needed money badly
so I went to ask him for financial aid .
Please father!!
At least...at least...be my warranter...
Enough!
When I say I can't, I can't!
Hello, village head,
it's sure hot today too, isn't it?
You're still there brooding!
You're nothing but trouble!!
You should have left this house
instead of Kinji!
That one phrase...
triggered all the anger
I felt towards father and I exploded...
And,
I quickly wiped
my fingerprints off the knife,
picked up the IOU and the seal
and left the room...
The rest is
just as Mr Mouri had explained...
SS. Shiro...
Shiro,
Though it was a trick,
you thought out a way to go downstream,
despite not being,ableitoiswim.
Therefore, don't you think
that there may have been
there was another way around the
ill feelings you had against your father?
Whether you make an effort to find a way
or not, is what divides fate
ORIGIN Y~COMIC BOOKS BY
osho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
Masatomo Sudd
STORY EDIT R
Junichy liokd
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kas/Twabira
Kazunaii Kouchu
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichr Higure
Tos! 1ki Inoue
TION DIREC
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi1 Takatani
Harup Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR.
Yukihiro Shibut mi
DIRECTORS OF PH TQOURAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hiron bu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Ken]: Kvdamau
PRODLC ID BY
TMS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association With
Yomiuri T lecasting <orporition
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama /*Shogakukan * YTV * TNS
&fl Rights Reserved
This is supposed to be
a Healing Forest and yet...
Is pops up?
He's sulky and just pretending to sleep!
He's upset because Aiko
didn t come to see him off!
She can't help it 'cuz
she's working today and then...
Mr. Mouri!
Mr. Mourn!
Conan! Ran!!
It's Aiko!!
Ms Aiko!
My beautiful Aiko
Please come again for
a relaxing tour again someday
I'll give you my word that
I'll come again someday
The only thing that can
heal me is your smile}
We've awakened a sleeping child