Even destiny serves
as a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces through
the most mysterious case.
Today Yoko's appearing.
Long time no see!
Even TV idols have a lot of worries...
He sees through the onesand only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an duit,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Beach/Los Angeles/San Diego
ng Beach/Los ngeles/San Diego
each/Los Angeles/8an Diego
Iee O on /f arlitr Cen Bier
No Precio «+ Ante ieedSen Diego
Los Ange! -s/San Diego
L-O-V-E
!] love Yoko
Cutie Yo-Ko
YAAY!
Oh, boy, don't you get tired of watching
the same video over and over
again during the day?
That's enough!
Oh, no!
Why not!
I have so little work to do anyway...
But you have a lot of mail!
It may be a job offer.
I will look through them later,
I so.just: leave them
somewhere around, 0.K.?
You don't have any work to do,
and neither are you motivated...
Let's see,
the electricity bill and
an invitation to give a lecture...
Oh, my...
This letter is from Yoko!
What!
It's an invitation to a party!
Great!
An engagement party
will be held at her friend's house!
How wonderful!
Engage, engagement?
It's her friend who got engaged and
asked her to arrange to meet
the renowned Detective Mr. Mouwuri...
You're going to the...
engagement...
ENGAGEMENT..engagement...
He's in a world of his own...
The Secrets of Pop Stars Part
Well, Thank you Yoko!
It is a great pleasure to be invited
to the engagement party
of your best friend.
He pleasure is mine...
Yoko Okino (TV Idol)
AE3-1 (22)
PAIL
Thank you for coming
on such short notice.
Yoko Okino (TV Idol)
14153-3 (22)
I'm sorry to have surprised you,
by inviting you out of the blue...
Yoko Okino (TV Idol)
AEFI -13 (22)
I'm sorry to have surprised you,
by inviting you out of the blue...
NO! Not at all!
You re, right!
YOU were the one who was sadly
mistaken and terribly disappointed!
So? Who is she?
Your engaged friend?
You will see her soon
All of you know her very well!
Do I know the person well?
Hi, Yoko!
H, dear...
You really brought him here...
The renowned Detective...Kogoro Mourli
You...l guess,
you are cast as the Detective, Samoniu...
Osamu Kenzaki!
Osamu Kenzaki (Actor)
Shh!
So, then,
you're Yoko's engaged friend?
Well, actually, no...
I am her future husband-to be.
Yoko's best friend is my future bride...
Anyway, I think it's really
great that you brought
the renowned Detective, Mourn, to us.
She'll sure be delighted to meet him!
In fact, she doesn't know
that Mr Mouri is here yet...
I wanted to surprise her.
OK, let's go to see her surprised look...
There's no answer at all...
But, everyone should
already be here by now...
Gosh!
The door ls unlocked...
Nuts!!
I'm really sorry, Mr. Mouri...
How embarrassing...And you
e all the way out here...I.
h... Don't worry about it
Being struck by a famous
actress like you... will be
something special to look back on...
I'm recently being hassled by a stalker...
Kaoru Kusano (Actress)
I saw a strange man looking through
the peep hole of the door,
Kaoru Kusano (Actress)
I saw a strange man looking through
the peep hole of the door,
so I couldn't help striking at you...
If you are his admirer or fan, you
should have known his face?
I can't believe it...
Well then, Yoko's friend
who got engaged to Mr. Kenzaki is...
The formal wedding ceremony
will be this coming spring!
It's still off-the-records to the media...
Oh, that reminds me, Kaoru co-starred
with Mr. Kenzaki in Detective, Samonji.
That's right!
We brought them both here to
celebrate and tease them,
while watching the
TV program being aired tonight.
Yuki Takeno (Celebrity)
a - TI
RIFE
The perfect couple...
Yuki Takeno (Celebrity)
E851% (22)
RIFE
Wow... Yuki Takeno!!
Gee... Your nails, I think, are
a little bit too flashy, Yuku...
Cool, huh? These false nails...
Ah, but it's a pity...
Yoko Okino...
Yuki Takeno
and Kaoru Kusano
One more person,
and all four would be present.
How regrettable indeed...
Oh, did someone call me?
TERUMI!!!
Well, well you have
turned out quite nicely...
Terumi Hoshino (Actress)
Well, Yoko told me
t I had to come, so...
Terumi Hoshino (Actress)
BE EX (23)
Um...am I interrupting?
If so, I can leave...
Terumi Hoshino (Actress)
Um...am I interrupting?
If so, I can leave...
Come, come...
Now the four Earth Ladies have
gathered here again after a long recess.
Earth Ladies?
U may not know, but...
Kaoru for the fragrant
field of sweet grass!
Yuki Takeno is for white snow
covering the high mountain!
Terumi Hoshino is for the
glittering stars in heaven!
And Yoko Okino is for the sparkling
waves of the blue sea!
So, all four of them together
are called Earth Ladies'!
That's figures...
Each of thenames stands for
a superb view of the earth...
Yeah, but Earth Ladies broke up because
of a quarrel between Terumi and Kaoru...
So, only Yoko continued on as a singer.
Anyway, I was surprised that...
Kaoru, the youngest of the four of us,
turned out to be the first to get married.
Actually, so did I!
I thought Terumi would be the first
to get married and settle down!
Hey, I thought you once said
something about your loved one?
Yes, yes, tell us what happened to your
relationship with the guy?
Did you confess your love to him?
Not really.
Besides, it's much easier to
Iove him from a distance.
That way I can keep him in my
heart as my ideal man.
You know , like some people say,
Marriage is the tomb of love and trust.
Hey, just what do you mean by that?
Terumi! How dare you...
but who is that old man with the kid?
Oh, yeah...Are you
Kenzaki's brother or something?
It's about time
Detective SAMONJI will be starting.
Atsushi Makuma
(Kaoru's Manager)
Don't you want to watch it?
Atsushi Makuma
(Kaoru's Manager)
WMOIR-I%
Atsushi Makuma
(Kaoru's Manager)
MO R- Iv
Il pass it up...
In the meantime,
I'm going to take a bath.
Just tell me when.it's over.
But...umm...
As the food's getting cold,
I'd like to have dinner together now...
Please don't bug me!
I said PASS! Don't make me say
the same thing over and over again!
When will you get off telling me
what to do? Huh, a loser like you!!
I'm sorry
Wait! Kaoru
She hast changed at all...
She's always embarrassed
to watch the programs she stars on,
with other people...
Just as we planned...
Hey!
Are you really going to do it?
Of course! That's why we invited you!
Do what?
We'll be waiting for you
in the living room...
Yoko, why don't you go first, and change
Into your costume in the restroom?
That's none other than the costume that
the Earth Ladies
wore at the time they debuted!
I SCC.
When Kaoru comes
out of the bathroom...
Yep!
Three of us are going to
celebrate her engagement by \
wearing these costumes and
singing our debut song...
It's so embarrassing
to wear this costume, though...
Oh! Great!
It looks nice! Lovely Yoko! WOW!
You're just too much! You know that?
Thank you for waiting!!
Tah-Dah!
Ugh!
Do you really wanna do it?
Well then, next I'll go get rejuvenated!
Hey, Yuki. Hurry up.
I also have to change into...
Hey, let's all write a few lines each...
in celebration of Kaoruissengagement.
I wish you much love and happiness...
OK...
Here you go!
OK then, next, Terumi...
Don't mind me, I think I'll pass...
It's a good opportunity to make
peace with Kaoru, I think.
OK, OK. I'll write something...
Hey...
Did Kaoru really want to see Pops?
Yeah, as she said,
weirdo follows her around...
She wants him to
find out who the man is...
Once she moves in with me, she won't
be troubled by the man anymore?
Yeah!
Oh that's a message card?
Yeah, we're all
writing our comments on the card.
All right, then
I'll go get transform myself...
Look! What is this?
I express-my 'condolences.
Terumi Hoshino
I express:my,; condolences.
I express my condolences.
And she stubs out her cigarette on it...
I express my;condolences.
Terumi Hoshino
I express my condolences
and she stubs out her cigarette on it...
ust what Terumi would do...
If Terumi dares to do that,
hen I can do this...
With a loving kiss!!
Hey! Manager,
why don't you write something to her?
No, um, I...
C'mon You donst have to be modest...
Well, now, you can write anything,
comments, complaints,
whatever you like.
Please...
Oh, I'm sorn , you don't have to
if you really don't want to...
No, I'm just glad...
Here, I changed clothes.
Wow! It fits you just right!
Then, I'll go call Kaoru...
What's wrong with him?
I have no idea
Hey!
None of you watched my drama
seriously, so none of you really care!
Whoa! Calm down.
It finished rewinding...
OK, well just wait for Kaoru to come.
Huh? Where is she?
Well,
1, I tried calling her many times...
but...she didn't answer...
She may have become dizzy or
fainted in the bathroom...
Then, Mr. Kenzaki,
you should go check it out...
I think she's just sulky and
Iocked herself in the bathroom.
Huh?
There are bloodstains...
Ieading to the entrance.
Shoots.
Kaoru!
Now please come out from there...
Everyone is waiting for you!
Mr. Kenzaki, open the door!
What!
Now!
Kaoru! I'm coming in!
Kaoru?...
KAORU!!!
Ka, Kaoru!?
What ha ened?
How did this all come about?
She still has a pulse!
We must get her to the hospital
immediately. Her life depends on it!
Hurry!
Hey! What happened!
I heard someone shouting something...
Ka,Kaoru!?
Hey! Kaoru!! Are you all right!
Kaoru!!!
RAN! Call the ambulance!
Yes!
Ah~The victim is Ms. Kaoru Kusano,
20 years old.
Room number 1 on the 28th floor...
A 20-year-old living
alone in this luxury condo...
Some rich kid or something?
Huns
You don t know, Inspector?
The Earth ladies?
Earth what? What's that?
Oh, yes.
We're the police.
Please...
We're coming...
Oh. I'm sorry...
I must have the wrong room...
Oh! Inspector Megure.
We've been waiting for you!
Yahoo! Lots of TV celebs!
I see...Now let me ask
you one more time,
You three women were invited to
Ms. Kusano's engagement party...
And while she was in the bathroom,
you, one by one, changed into your
costumes in the rest room, to surprise her.
Ms. Okino, Ms. Takeno and
Ms. Hoshino in that order
And when three of you finished changing,
the manager, Mr. Makuma
went to the bathroom
to call her but there was no answer...
Next, her fiancee, Mr. Kenzaki
went to call her and
opened the door of the bathroom.
You found Ms. Kusano leaning on
the edge of the bath tub
and bleeding from the neck, right?
Yes...
And once AGAIN,
just like the devil had planned it,
at the scene of the crime, I run into
Ah...Don't be like that...
I just happened to be invited here
by Ms. Okino...It's just a coincidence.
It is not a mere coincidence but a
meaningful coincidence.
Or maybe better said, mere curse!
And?2Where:is: the victim,
Ms. Kusano now?
She's been transported to
Haido Hospital by ambulance...
We haven't heard from Mr Makuma,
who accompanied her to the hospital,
so, we don't know how she is now.
Kaoru...Is she going to die? Oh..,no...
Alri ht, Alri ht... I'll oo call the hos ital...
I'll go with you...
My dad often goes to see
the doctor at this hospital
because of his diabetes...
So I know the number...
Really? Great! Thanks...
And about the person
who cut her neck...
Do you think that the killer is
someone in this very room?
No way!
But, people often say that
the first finder of the body
IS the most suspicious...
Hey Hey ..l don't have
any reason to kill Kaoru
and when I found her in the bathroom,
that kid with glasses was with me!
Besides, he's the one who told me
to open the door of
e bath room to begin with.
Is that right?
Yeah! Because
there was blood dripping from
the hall into the entrance
And when I opened the entrance door,
I found that stuff lying there...so...
A rain jacket, work gloves with holes...
an eye dropper and a handkerchief.
We found them outside the front door,
so we laid them aside
before the ambulance came.
The rain jacket and gloves
are covered with blood.
This must be the clothes
that the criminal was wearing.
It's slight, but there's
a lipstick stain .on-the handke chief
If someone filled
this bottle withlanesthetic and
and he or she used
the anesthetic soaked handkerchief
to put her to sleep
before committing the murder...
But...who did it to Kaoru?
It's outrageous!
It's the stalker! He did to her!
The stalker scared her,
playing spoo « dingdong Dash.
Ding-Dong...?
It's a trick of ringing the front doorbell
and then running away...
But it's not just a joke, it's a crime...
A strange note was always left
outside the front door...
It said, I'll come again
I'll come next time and
I'll come even if ll die
It got worse and worse over time
That creepy piece of paper
typed with a word processor!
I see...
That's why Ms. Kusano tried to hit me
out of blue when I rang the bell.
Was the door
Iocked at the time of the murder?
It was open...
There were lots of people here so
she may have felt safe
and left the door unlocked.
So, the stalker found the door left open,
went'inside the room,
came across Ms. Kusano
who had just come out
after taking a bath...
Then, because Ms Kusano
saw the stalker's face,
the stalker put her to sleep with medicine
and slashed her throat with a weapon...
The bloody rain jacket and
work gloves were disposed
of because they were too conspicuous
and would attract negative attention...
Then the killer fled...
Alright, Takagt!
Start poking around the condo,
Iooking for clues!
The criminal wore a rain jacket
on a day that wasn't raining.
There's got to be a witness...
Yes, Sir!
But I don't think anyone saw that person
because the person's very cautious.
Very cautious?
Well, if you were wearing
a bloody rain jacket,
you would step on the blood
that drips from the jacket, right?
But when I saw It,
there were no traces of footprints
at the bloody entrance.
This means that the criminal tried to avoid
stepping on the blood
whenirunning away.
That, That's right...
Eh? That's odd...
if the criminal saw
many shoes in the entrance way,
why did that cautious person
come into a room with so many people?
Inspector!
What if the criminal deliberately
walked with the rain jacket in hand
to make the blood drip
down on the hallway,
and then tossed them over outside,
in order to make it look like
he/she ran outside?
- La .
and if Ms Kusano was
acquainted with the aggressor,
the person could
call her without alerting her.
If she defenselessly comes
out from the bathtub,
then it wouldn't be difficult
to make her smell the medicine
and put her to sleep at the door...
Hey, wait!
You mean the murderer is...
could be one of us...
Is that right? Detective...
Terumi!
That's true...
The restroom that was used
as a changing room is between
the living room and the bathroom
Each of us would have had
a chance to commit the murder...
Even you...
Even so, Yoko couldn't have...
While she was changing,
we were waiting in front of the restroom
and after that, we went back
to the living room with Yoko.
Then I'm also clean...
When I found her, I was with this kid.
Yeah!
First when Kaoru went to the bathroom,
you very kindly accompanied her...
You couldn't have killed her...
Huh? You walked to
the bathroom with her?
Umm, yes
So, you had the chance to
attack her then?
OK, first, let me ask each of you...
But before that,
aren't you forgetting to do something?
Huh?
The deadly weapon...
The knife that was used
to cut Kaoru's throat.
If It's found in our belongings or indoors,
the criminal's among us...
Otherwise, the criminal
came from outside...
It's hard to think that,
after committing the murder,
a criminal from outside would
hide the weapon somewhere
in this condo at the risk of
being witnessed by one of us.
The criminal may have
wiped the blood from the knife,
and the hemoglobin of the blood
may be invisible to the naked eye...
But, luminol solution can detect
the small amount of
hemoglobin in the blood
It's not something you
can hide after all, right?
You're right...
Umm...what?
What on earth is she?
ORIGIN I~COMIC BOOKS BY
osho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS -BY.
Masatomo Sudo
Junichr Lika
Junichi lioka
kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Joshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Harup Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
ID! TOR
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodamay
PRODUC D BY
TMS Entertainment, Lid.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecasting +orporation
DE TE LIT! VFCONAN
Gosho Aoyama /.Shogakukan * YTV « TMS
fl Rights Reserved
PREVIEW
Oh, it's a picture...
What?!
PREVIEW
Kaoru...
D.Don't tell me that Kaoru...?!
PREVIEW
Maybe it's about time you let it all out?
The real meaning of
this engagement party...
PREVIEW
The real meaning?
Huh... Oh, well...
PREVIEW
Don't tell me she was
planning to die to begin with...