Even destiny serves
as a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
Misunderstanding and
compassion as a storm clears the air,
today's incident helps strengthen
the bond of friendship.
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Ms. Yoko Okino invites us to
the engagement party of her friend.
Yoko Okino (TV Idol)
Yoko and her friend, Kaoru Kusano,
AF 3-1 (22)
are both ex-members of a
pop group, called Earth Ladies.
Kaoru Kusano (Actress)
are both ex-members of a
pop group, called Earth Ladies.
We get to the party, where we see
other ex-members of Earth Ladies',
Yuki Takeno (TV Celebrity)
WFIU
Yuki Takeno and
Yuki Takeno (TV Celebrity)
IWFSL/h
IWFSUL/b
Terumi Hoshino, who were also invited...
Terumi Hoshino (Actresss)
ste . -
BE KEE (23)
But Kaoru, while taking a bath,
Is attacked by someone
The Secret of Pop Stars Part ill
But before that
aren't you forgetting something?
Huns
The deadly weapon...
the knife that was used
to cut Kaoru's throat
If it is found in our belongings or indoors,
it means that the criminal ls among us...
Otherwise, the criminal
came from outside...
But it's very unlikely, because
after committing the murder,
a criminal from outside
wouldn't hide the weapon
somewhere in this condo at the risk
of being witnessed by one of us.
Even though the criminal wiped
the blood from the knife,
and hemoglobin of the blood
Is invisible to the naked eye...
Iuminol solution can detect
the small amount of hemoglobin
In the blood that has been removed.
It's not something
you can hide after all, right?
You're right...
You know very well...
I'm hooked on detective
novels thanks to someone...
Ok, Takagi, you body check Mr. Kenzaki
and you police women
search those ladies...
The rest of you split up to
search for the weapon!!
Yes, sir!
But Inspector,
if Mr. Makuma, who is
accompanying her to the hospital,
were the murderer,
the weapon would already...
Shoot!
You don't have to worry about it...
I asked the paramedics to call here
if he were to act strangely...
You, you're a good boy!
Next, Ms. Takeno, please...
Ah, yes...
Hey, was Ms Takeno a regular
on Detective, Samonji"?
Yeah...
She played a role
of an annoying journalist
who followed Detective Samonj.
But she canceled her appearance on
the drama because of her father's illness,
so her role went to Kaoru...Actually,
Terumi's name first came up for the role,
but thanks to Mr. Maguma's push,
Kaoru got the role.
A little while ago,
she called Mr. Maguma a loser...
Mr. Makuma was also a would-be actor
and he belonged to
the same studio as us...
But he gave up his dream early on
and became her manager.
Nonetheless,
and contrary to what she said before,
Kaoru thought highly of him and
expressed her regret over his decision,
saying he gave up too soon,
he just doesn't have courage
Hmm...
-_- -—
I OTC.
That no weapon was found...
No...
We couldn't find it anywhere, the room,
the drain pipe, or their belongings.
Did you check their
fashion accessories too?
1 To...
Ms. Takeno's false nails
and Ms. Hoshino's earrings.
We even checked Mr. Kenzaki's choker
but there was no luminol reaction.
About Mr. Ma uma oin to the hos ital?
Investigator said that
that he had looked into
Mr. Maguma's glasses but no results.
And until our detectives
got to the hospital,
he was sitting depressed
and gloomy on the chair.
I thunk it is very unlikely that
he would try to get rid of
the weapon In question...
Umm...
So, it appears that the criminal
took the weapon outside. then.
We're driven back to the theory that
it was done by someone from outside.
No, maybe not...
The culprit wouldn't have known
that Ms. Kusano was taking a bath.
So, who would dare to
commit a bold crime like that...
It would be too daring and too risky
if the stranger just
walked inside and tried to kill her.
I think it was an inside job,
and the weapon must
be hidden somewhere
in this apartment right now...
But where is the weapon?
Inspector!
There's a bugging device in
a stuffed animal in her bedroom!
What!?
And there re signs of
someone having
ummaged in the drawers
So, the criminal had known from the
outside that Ms. Kusano was engaged,
or even that she was in the bathroom.
If the perpetrator is her fanatic fan,
it would be possible that
the culprit aggressively
attacked Ms. Kusano
and took something away
to remember her by.
Then call her office immediately,
and ask if she had
a stalker-like fan like that.
Yes, Sir.
This is the bedroom...
That is the drawer
they were talking about...
This is the drawer that was searched...
There are some pen and scissors...
This is the drawer of clothes
and accessories
mm... This has been lef auntouched...
HUM Pi a.
This picture
Hey!
Don't do that!... You're violating privacy...
I'm sorry...
Girls have secrets that they don't want
anyone to know about.
Even though sometimes it could be
foolish to keep a secret.
That picture, put it back in
the drawer at the lower left
She will be troubled if she can't find it.
Oh, yeah...
OK, Into the drawer...at the lower left...
KEN - 75» /
Tihates why...
I've solved the mystery about
the weapon used by the criminal...
Now how would the culprit
try to erase the evidence!!
Anyway...
as long as the murder
weapon isn't found indoors,
the crime may have been committed
by someone from outside.
Maybe this was
the work of an obsessed fan...
Yieah .
Now all we can do is hope
and pray that Ms. Kusano,
who was taken to the hospital
gets better...She may have
at least seen the criminal...
He. .Hello...Oh, yes...
I'm a friend of Ms. Kusano
Yes...
H Kaoru...
Yo.,Yoko?
What's wrong?
It's from the hospital, isn't it?
WwW, W Wait!
Don't tell me that Kaoru...
Don't worry!
The operation has been a great success!
They said she will come
to in a few hours!
Oh, that's great!
Thank goodness!
Then you had better go to her now,
Mr. Kenzaki...
She needs you, her future husband...
Yeah...
But, Is it okay because
I heard that hospital is being thronged
by journalists who smelt trouble...
So, I'll go later.
I don't want to cause trouble
to other patients at the hospital,
and I don't want this to be blown
all out of proportion
by the media with misinterpretations .
Misinterpretations?
Now why don't you tell everyone else?
Eh...
The real reason for
this engagement party...
The real reason?
Oh well, that...umm...
ell, actually... well...
That's too bad...
Things didn't go as planned.
as it"you?
The criminal who slashed
at her throat in the bathroom...
Hey, kid...
I'm sorry to say this,
you are acting like a detective,
but there's no weapon here...
That deadly dammed thing
that cut her throat!
Listen, kid.
The police searched everywhere
in this room but found nothing,
and I didn't have it on me either...
If you insist that I'm the one,
tell me where the weapon is ?
I don't know where it is now,
but I can tell you
what it is! It's something long,
attached to the tip of your finger!
Oh, you mean these fake nails?
1111 S0Ity... 11He police
have already checked these nails but...
No, the fake nails are a camouflage!
Huh?
It's the thing that you're hiding
under your fake nails.
It's very hard, second only to teeth,
and can be used as a weapon
to slit the opponent's throat...
Your real nails that
are as sharp as a fine knife!
You probably used the thumbnail
of your right hand as a weapon
because it is the thickest
and easiest to use.
Before the crime you put
the fake nail on your thumb nail
And you used your real nail as a weapon.
And you cut off the bloody nail afterward.
Then you again
put the fake nail back on...
No one would think that
you had a long nail on your thumb
So that's why you used
the work glove with holes, right?
You let only the thumb nail
out of the glove,
and covered yourself with the rain jacket,
to avoid getting your clothes stained
by the blood of the victim.
The only reason blood
was dripped on the floor,
the rain jacket was thrown out
dripped on the floor,
and the gloves were outside
the entrance door is...
in order to make it look like
the work of an outsider...
The work of the stalker you made up!
Yuki... And you're also the one
who left the strange notes
behind the door and
also sent the stuffed toy
with a bugging device, right?
Oh, I'm sorry
Oh, I'm sorry...
well... That's right,
The weapon was a fingernail.
But if so,
there should be some tool
to cut the nail here somewhere
So, that's why you were in the drawer
where there were some pens
and a pair of scissors...
because you just wanted
to get her nail clipper...
But unfortunately,
there was no nail clipper...
Perhaps, Ms. Kusano shaped and trimmed
her finger and toe nails with
a nail file before her nails grew long.
Well,
if I'm the murderer, I could just
have cut off the nail with scissors...
No, you wouldn't
because you knew that
the police would first notice the scissors
that is capable of slashing the throat.
If you cut off your blood stained nail,
they would soon find out...
On the other hand,
you thought a nail clipper
wouldn't be checked by the police...
But, you didn't bring one because
you didn't want
to have such evidence on you.
And moreover,
because you knew all personal items
belonging to the suspects
would be checked closely.
Tell me...how I cut my nail not
being able to find a nail clipper?
I have already told you...
your nail is very hard only second to...
your teeth...
After biting the nail into bits,
you drained it down the sink somewhere
Doing so, even if bits
of the nail are found,
they wouldnat look like a weapon.
I have PROOF that you did that!
Look! Your lipstick mark on the card.
I didn't think much of it at the time
but as time went on,
a part of it turned brownish...
If this is Ms. Kusano's blood that
got on your nail at theltime of the crime,
and that smeared on to your lips
when you bit off the nail...
This is concrete evidence that...
W, without it,
she will attest the truth of all...
that I called her from outside
when she was taking a bath
and that I made her sniff something
when she went out of the bathroom.
WwW: what!
Did she drink something before
I came in here?
I love..um...ll loved him...l
Ioved Mr Kenzaki...
ever since we performed together.
But both my role and Kenzaki
were taken away from me by Kaoru...
No, you're wrong .
So when I said Congratulations
and you know what she said?
It's just a gimmick,
a gimmick to make a topic out of it.
See, he's kinda cute, it's good enough...
It surprised me...
that my jealousy drove
me to commit the crime...
Fatal misunderstanding!
The real reason why Kaoru
got engaged with Mr Kenzaki is...
How stupid I am!
If I only cut a little deeper...
but when I saw her face...
I couldn't kill her.
I couldn't do it...
he ls my friend...
I'm glad that Kaoru...
didn't die...really...
What, what did she drink?
Her face is pale,
breaking into cold sweat
pulse racing, and hands shaking...
aving jitters...
My dad often goes to see a doctor
at the hospital because of his diabetes...
Hypoglycemiants
Medicine for people with diabetes
if a normal person takes it,
their blood sugar level will drop too low
and so the pill is very likely to be fatal!!
If she had prepared it in advance
she may have been planning
to kill herself all along!!
Gotcha!
I won't let you die!
Just because of a misunderstanding...
hat's too sad...
I will not let you die!!
Kaoru...
I'm sorry...Kaoru
I'm so sorry
Kaoru...
Ka, Kaoru...
Are you awake yet?
Where am I?
Haido hospital...
You have been sleeping
for two whole days now!
You're so silly...
You mistook your daddy's
medicine for a vitamin pill.
Huh?
Well,
I'm gonna call Terumi and
tell her that Yukihas finally come to...
Oh...
Well,
Kaoru...
All right!
I told the police in
detail about what happened...
that the person who
attacked me in the bathroom was
a short fat middle aged woman...
Huh?
I just kind of tentatively said that
the criminal was a middle;aged woman...
I don't want to be thought that
some stalker old man
saw me naked, so...
But,
but...It was me...
Well, I will thankfully accept
this scar on my neck
as a punishment
for deceiving you without
considering your feelings at all...
Were you deceiving me?
Yeah...
That engagement party
thing was all a hoax,
a complete fabrication
that Mr. Kenzaki and I made up...
to help somebody make a decision...
Remember,
I used to say that my dream
was to suddenly get married at 20,
ust: like Yukiko Kudo...
Yeah...
And, and...
Now that dream has just come true!!!
Shazzam!!
Look at the morning paper today!
He finally made up his mind!
Do you, do you STILL like him,
that geek guy?
Oh, Shut up!
He sure doesnst-have-guts,;. 1.
But he still has good points.
He announced 'his-feelings for me
in front of the journalists and cameras.
She is the one I love,
I don't want to lose her!
He said that about me...
Really...
Actually, a lot of things happened but...
I think it was meaningful
to carry out my plan,
despite Terumi s objection.
What!
Terumi also knew about the plan!
Oh, in fact, we,
we, Terumi and I weren't
on bad terms with each other...
That fight was
a fake fight to disband our group
because we thought
if we had continued the group,
we would have gotten all messed up
I knew you and Yoko
wanted to continue the group...
So, we were hiding
the real reason from you...I'm sorry...
I see.
You pretended to be fighting
in order to hide it from me.
Then what did she mean
when she wrote,
I express my condolences
on that card...
Oh, that kid told me,
that the painful remarks from her
meant that
our plan has failed miserably...
That kid?
Onan, you know...
Mr. Mori must have
trained him very well!
When Mr. Kenzaki
carried me out of the bathtub,
Conan saw that he got bashful,
covering my body with a towel,
and realized that
he wasn't my fiancee...
Then, judging from
the picture of Makuma and me,
and Terumi's words and deeds,
he asked me: directly if I like him a lot.
He is also the one
who put sugar in your mouth
as a stop-gap measure when
you collapsed with
the effect of the medicine.
That boy...
And so, what will you do now?
I mean, about Mr. Kenzaki!
If you still insist on hesitating,
TerumiPayWaKe him away from you!
Huh?
Why?
This is also what Conan was saying!
The reason why Terumi
IS now hooked on mystery novels is
probably because she likes Mr. Kenzaki
playing the role of"Detective, Samonji.
Unfortunately, that is wrong.
I heard Terumi dumped
Mr. Kenzaki before.
On, really .
So who is her ideal guy now?
I don't know, but...
it would not surprise me at all
if Terumi has a younger lover...
ORIGIN I~COMIC BOOKS BY
'who Aoyama
PRODUCERS
; ICHI NIKO NUwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
Iasatomo<Sodb
mat - rm
STORY EDITOR.
Junichi 1 kas
CRIPTS BY.
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Jumchir Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoupe
ANIMATION DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yiakihiro Shibutani
DIR CTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
TakashiiNomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa @gawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
KenjnKfidamfl
TAS Entertainment, Ltd.
In association 'with
Yomiuri Tecistine <orporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
2 Gosho Aoyama /'Shogakukan * YTV = TMS
Ail Rights Reserved
OK, the next part is
you push your struggling x
opponent into the corner.
Terumi,
we'll count on you to act
the cool female Shogi player,
as usual!
1 CO.
Oh, don't you know...
that:you have already lost thezgame...
In my point of view, the game ended
twenty eight turns ago...
when you moved "Gin".
"1 Tau
Terumi acts like a detective
rather than a Shogi player...
In order to*win a brilliantsvictory
there's only one move to make...
his is the truth...
Certainly...
Boy oh boy...
PREVIEW
on"t tell Mm Lihat.
onan...!
PREVIEW
No good, he's dead already!
He's bleeding from the head,
ft means he's . .
PREVIEW
What's.... this...7?
piece of chocolate...
PREVIEW
Tragedy at OK Ranch