Even.destiny serves
as a clue tosdeduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
The name of the stage isYOK Ranch.
A single combat unfolds
betweenicrime and.deduction
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Wow~~~1! it feels so good!
Doesn't it, doesn't it!
There's nothing better than nature!
But, Dad, why did you
suddenly decide to come driving?
Well-1 wonder why...
Um, we passed here before, didn't we?
Huh?
Uh~~~Oh, yeah?
Uh~~~~We're here now.
We came this way,
and when to this way, so...
Let me check!
Where are we headed for?
WwW, Well
Hey Dad pull over to the side»
Fy Fag Par ae
That's it!
Wait for me!
OKUSU Ranch?!
Tragedy at OK Ranch
OKUSU-Ranch
Well, well, you were a great help.
Thanks to you
I was able to make it here in time!
Oh, no problem
Hiroto Ninomiya
(ranch employee)
After all, we haven't had
people come visit us for a long tim
Hiroto Ninomiya
(ranch employee)
&#% 03 DE
BALIALAATLILW
7248 TE We PR
Hiroto Ninomiya
(ranch employee)
#% 03 DE
BA<LSDLeDEEDLWN,
-- eo
TX 490 AL WE JN
It's a ranch for horses...
So, Pops just brought us along
so he could enjoy his horses!
I just thought that
I'd let you have your fill of nature!
Go home!!
Get out of here right this minute!
You don't have to tell me to leave, I w
Kanenari Mochizuki
(President of real estate agency)
BA FAK (46)
Sh &ZDdlTADMVLe Load
THE= HR
You don't have to tell me to leave, I w
Kanenari Mochizuki
(President of real estate agency)
55R 0158b
2A Mit (46)
3 EI3BANNLe LeBad
"WEI {I
because I'm busy too, you know
Kanenari Mochizuki
(President of real estate agency)
858008D
2A FMA (46)
$& EDBAMALY LeB2D
FEST ER
Just make sure that you don't goof on
the timing of selling this place!
Well
I'm sorry about the scene just now...
Welcome to OK Ranch!
Tomoyuki, Okusu (Ranch owner)
vv £6 be
I am Okusu, the owner of this ranch
Tomoyuki Okusu (Ranch owner)
¥y &6 be
OK Ranch?
The name of the ranch is taken fro
the first two letters of my last name,
OK Ranch
Nothing's been okay
around here recently though...
OK Ranch
Oh, that's right.
Here, sonny,
would you like some chocolate?
It's good!
Chocolate, eh...
No. thank you.
There!
Wow, fantastic!
Oh, I'm sorry I'm late
I am your guide, Takeuchi.
Sanae Takeuchi
(Ranch employee)
MR BEE)
<L23Led EEL
& oF - -
18 EX £2
Sanae Takeuchi
(Ranch employee)
TAR 8B & (21)
CL L£DL oD ETL DLA
138 LE 3
Nice to meet you all!
Sanae Takeuchi
(Ranch employee)
MAR 23)
LL2OLd EIN
Sanae Takeuchi
(Ranch employee)
TAR 282D
ILL EIN
IRLEMM
All the horses that are owned, are out
because it's horse racing
season right now...
I wonder if you'll be able to
see any horses you know?
Oh, isn't this horse Madam Leap?
Yes! She's a stock mare!
I made a lot of money off her in the past.
How nostalgic.
Thank you for all the cash
you brought in back then.
Gee, you don't look too well
She experienced still birth,
and is not able to have anymore babies...
Oh, I see...poor thing
The racing stable over there
is used for bringing up colts.
It's not in use right now,
but if you'd like to see it...
Hi, Sanae, guests?
Y. Yes...
Hi there!
Good work, take care of
Madam Leap for me today, will you.
He is Motoo Sugiyama, sir,
the guy that I've taken care of
ever since he used to be a jockey!
Ever since he used to be a jockey!
Motoo Sugiyama
(Farrier)
ever since he used to be a jockey!
Motoo Sugiyama
(Farrier)
Z< it IBM
He is currently one of the most
sought after farriers of the times.
Motoo Sugiyama
(Farrier)
O && 8
WIT I
Motoo Sugiyama
(Farrier)
O && 8
Wl BAND
Farrier
A blacksmith, you know,
a professional at making horseshoe
Horses that live along with human beings
go through rigorous exercise.
Therefore, their hooves get scraped
That's why they need horseshoes.
But, with the horsesho
their hooves stay OK.
Therefore, they periodically
ake off the horseshoe...
And shave off the outgrown hoof.
Then, in order to match
the hoof that has been shaved,
a new horseshoe
is put in place of the old one.
Ha, ha, ha, you sure
are knowledgeable, sir.
Ms. Takeuchi is
not going to have anything to do.
Oh no, it's just that
I've heard a little about it before...
The new horseshoe is heated in flames,
then shaped to match
the hoof of the horse.
The hooves of horses
are all shaped differently.
That goes all four
hooves of one horse too!
Oh...Is that so .
Are you all right, Conan?
Eheh, heh, heh!
Well, I'll bet you're glad
that we came, aren t you?!
Yep.
Madame Leap!!
Oh Mr. Ninomiya, Madame Leap is
Ah...I know!!
What s wrong?!
Madame Leap has run loose!
Whoah~~whoa calm down...
It's the first time that
something like this ever happened
Good girl... Calm down!!
Blood?!
Don t'tellvme 'that?!
Conan!
Mr. Sugiyama?!
Sugiyama!! €
No good, he's already dead!
He's bleeding from his head,
which means, he may have been
kicked by Madame Leap.
OO. Oh no!
That can't be!
At any rate, please call the police!
O,on, that's right
Please tie Madame Leap
to the wash place or something!
Y,Yes Sir.
What's this?...
A piece of chocolate...
Its right hind leg
seems to be wounded
Unreal!
The nail isn't hammeredsin*right!
The shape of
the horseshoe doesn't match...
Why would Mr: Sugiyama
do something terrible like this?
But, wait a sec...-maybe...
Conan!
It s.dangerous!
IV 'mysonry.
Okay, okay...calm down...
Maybe giving her something
to drink will help.
Hey, Ran there was tea left in
the thermos bottle, wasn't there?
No, not tea!
Huh?
Although tea does
not affect humans much,
it is a very strong stimulant for horses!
Tea is a stimulant...?!
Maybe this Is not an accident...!!
There's no doubt about it.
He was kicked by the horse.
See!
The traces of him being kicked
the mark of the horseshoe
is left right here.
But, just to be safe,
I think it would be better to double check
whether the horseshoe
matches that of the horse...
Hmm?
Excuse me, but
may I have your name please?
Oh, pardon me...
I'm a detective soll...
I am Kogoro Mourn.
Huh?! You mean that famous...?!
Please excuse me for my rudeness.
But, since this is an accident,
I guess your deductions
won't be necessary...
I guess so.
By the way, what is going to
become of Madame Leap?
Well...
If it is a violent horse maybe
it would be better to get rid of it...
OO. Oh no!!!
Mr. Sugiyama's to blame!
He deserved to die!!!
Sanae?!
You mean, you don't like Mm Sugiyama?
Huh .
What do you mean
by he deserved to die?
Uh, Mr. Mourn, let me explain...
It was when I went out
to town to buy some things last night...
Huh? ..That car
Isn't that Mr. Sugiyama's car?
Hey he's?!
Sugiyama was meeting Mochizuki
who was trying to buy up this ranch.
Okusu is still wrapped up in making colts.
Oh-That's nice to know,
and I hope he fails again If he does,
this time for sure he'll go bankrupt
Which means you're
going to do that again?
Yeah! I'm counting on you, Sugiyama
Sugiyama was betraying Mr. Okusu,
the one who saved him, for money!
Sugiyama came along,
before we had a chance
to tell Mr Okusu about it...
In other words,
Mr. Sugiyama, through orders of
Mr Mochizuki was obstructing
the horse rom becoming pregnant
so that the ranch
would fall into a financial rut.
Right.
Producing horses cost
an enormous amount of money...!
If a horse as unable to have colts,
that itself is a great loss!
Which means that Madame Leap
got messed up in the ugly
dispute between humans...
How errible!
But, I wonder if that would
make the horse take revenge?
Because if it did, it would be the same
as the humans
who are doing those things!
That horse looks sad,
ut has nice eyes...
Hey! You stay out of this, kid!
I'm sorry
Conan!!
1.I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Huhv. Your pants are wet.
Oh, I was cleaning the stalls
and splashed water on myself.
I'm sorry, did I get you wet?
Nope, I'm okay.
I'm pretty sure that this case will be
processed as an accident...
Thank you so much.
Um, officer,
don't you have to take the horseshoe that
Is the murder weapon with you?
Huh?
Isn't the evidence going to be collected
and taken to the police station?
Yeah... but...
If the horseshoe needs to be
removed I'll do it now
I used to do all the works
in the past too, you know...
Back then, I hadino money
to hire a specialist so
I still don't...
I guess I'm in the samfiboat even now...
Iease put it in this bag...
Okay, I've removed it...
Okay, everything s done
Good girl, for sticking it-out...
Huh. there's blood
on the back of this horseshoe too!
Huh?
He's right!
There's a lot of blood smeared on it...
That's strange...
Just as If thought...
I've figured eve "thing out now!
The killer as well as
how the crime was committed!
No matter how strong
the horse isgit's:difficult for
blood to find its way
all the way behind the horseshoe...
If so, there is only
one possible answer...
Blood was smeared
onto the horseshoe beforehand?!
Most likely,
what happened then was...!
Oh, but wait
that's Madame Leap's blood.
Huh?
See take a look.
The nail's been hammered in sloppily
that the veins have been damaged.
I tell you, that Sugiyama
just did a really sloppy job.
With a job like that done on it,
it's not surprising
that the horse go wild...
gn runydri
gh...Funyah
Dad?
MM. Mr Mourn,
IS anything wrong?
No, it's just that
I've figured out who killed Mr. Sugiyama.
Huh?!
But, I thought this was an accident...?
No, it is none other than homicide!
Conan, show everyone
the you know what!
Es, sir!
Here it is.
This is what I picked up
at that wash place
This is chocolate.
But, what about this...?
If tea is a stimulant to horses,
wouldn't chocolate do the same?
E, Exactly,
a substance called
the obromine is in chocolate.
There is someone
who gave chocolate to Madame Leap!
No way! Who could've
done something so terrible!
Mr. Okusu,
what did you do with the chocolate
that you offered Conan
at the front desk a while ago?
Huh? Oh, that, well...
I left it back in my office
If ll remember correctly,
I think you put it away
In your pocket back then?
D.Don't tell me that Mr. Okusu
used chocolate
to excite Madame Leap...
But, how can we tell
whether Madame Leap
ate the chocolate or not...
A simple urine test would do.
Besides,
if the chocolate is
checked for fingerprints
we can even conclude
who gave it to the horse!
There is no need for that.
I gave Madame Leap the chocolate!
O,Oh, no?!...
Why?!
Why did you do such a thing?!
Although I understand
that you may have hated Mr. Sugiyama,
how could you even think of
making Madame Leap kill Mr. Sugiyama...
Hold it, Sanae,
Madame Leap is not the one
who killed Mr. Sugiyama
The one who killed Mr. Sugiyama is
the one who put a horseshoe
that did not fit
onto the right hind hoof of Madame Leap!
What?!
Which means that Mr Sugiyama
wasn't the one who put it on?
Of course not!
If'a professional is
to do an amateurish job like that,
even if it's to get on someone's nerves,
he would lose his job on the spot!
And besides,
the blood that was smeared on the back
of the horseshoe was Mr. Sugiyama's.
The killer probably struck the back of his
head with a brand new horseshoe!
Then,
not knowing what to do
with the blood smeared horseshoe,
the killer hurriedly
put it on Madame Leap...
You would never do
a sloppy job like that
no matter how much of
a rush you were in, right, Mr. Okusu?!
Could it have,been
the guy called Mochizuki,
who maybe got:into
a dispute-with Stigiyama...?
That is unthinkable,
because it would be much easier for him
to take the evidence along with him
and walk out of here
before he is witnessed by anyone,
than to go out of his way
to make it look like an accident.
Besides,.if he had planned
the murder.beforehand,
he would have planned
everything out more carefully.
Then, who did it...7?
Just as Sanae had pointed out,
Mr. Okusu would
never do such a sloppy job.
But, judging from the fact
that he wanted to remove
the horseshoe as soon as possible
he must've known about the
abnormal horseshoe at an early stage.
In order words,
he figured out somehow from the
situation at the scene, who the killer was,
and in order to protect the killer,
gave Madame Leap the chocolate.
Then, went back to the main house
and waited for
Madame Leap to go berserk
He wanted us,
the guests, to hear the commotion.
A person that Mr. Okusu
would want to protect
enough to even risk giving chocolate
to beloved Madame Leap
Sanae was with us all the way,
so she couldn't have
committed the murder...
So, that leaves us
with no other choice than you...
Mr. Ninomiya!
Well?!
No!!
Your slacks seems to have been wet,
but, maybe if we check
Iuminol reaction will appear?
Becausea'ou struggled to
fit the blood smeared horseshoe,
that was the murder weapon,
onto the hoof of the horse,
despite it still not being shaped
to fit the hoof of the horse yet.
Getting soiled by dirt happens
everyday on the ranch, but...
if it's the blood of the victim,
you'd have to wash it off, wouldn't you?
I didn't mean to kill him...
I really didn't mean to...
But, I just couldn't forgive him!
Not being able to bear it,
I pressed Sugiyama for an answer
as to what we saw last night...
Then, he said that he would kill me.
He insisted that he could simply make it
Iook like the horse had an accident.
Then, he snickered.
While we were struggling...
Sugiyama died...
No matter if I was not myself
when everything happened,
it is a fact that I tried
to put the blame on Madame Leap...
And I'm the very one
who should know more than anyone else
how despising it is
to put the blame on-a-horse...
Mr. Okusu...
I'm sorry...1...Il...
I'm the one
who needs to apologize to you.
Huh?
I sort of had an idea
as to what Sugiyama was doing.
I kept it from you
because I thought that
if I let word out of it to you,
who has a strong sense of justice,
the problem would be
blown out of proportion.
I should have told you about it somehow,
if things were going to turn out this way...
I'm so sorry, Ninomiya...
Mr Ninomiya...Mr. Okusu...
Every person is responsible
for compensating
for the crimes that he has committed...
No matter how much
you protect the culprit
or try to cover up
the crime that has been committed,
doing so is not a solution
to thegproblem at all...
And, it doesn't matter
what reasons may have existed
for committing the crime.
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
osho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
Jun chi I1 "ha
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kou hi
Junichi Mivashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMA IDN DIRECTORS
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECT R
Yulilirp hibctord
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
TakashitNomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RE -ORDING DIRE TOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama,
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainme: 1, Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecastine Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama /*Shogakukan * YTV * TMS
#11 Rights Reserved
2-0611
Go for it!
The black and green caps!
Cheer them on!
Go for it! 2~6!!
Now we know he's not off
only when he makes deductions...
Price of the-kid is 10 billion yen...
Clown...
This is...!
Will you lend me this picture, gramps!
I promise I'll give it back to you!!
In other words...
If I can figure outiwhere this is,
I would be able to locate
the place Akio is being confined...
What's up, Ayumi?