Evenidestiny, serves
as;a.cluetofdeduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
Today's mystery involves
the Youth Detective League.
The picturesa.child draws holds
the key to the case.
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Just as expected of you,
this is a terrible picture, Genta!
Hey; come on, talk for yourself Mitsuhiko!
Say what you Like!
A man's value is not to be judged
by the picture he draws!
You're right!
But, people who can draw nicely
are admirable and I really respect them.
1. guess so...
Maybe I'll think of commuting to
art class starting tomorrow
Oh, count me in too!
Really I tell you...
Jukichi Sakai
RARE =A»
RC AVBOITNED O La
RR =I
I wonder what he's doing?
What a weird man!
I smell a crime.
What? What? What?
M,Money?!
T,Talk about a large sum of money too!!
That's...maybe?
Hold it, mister!!
Why do you have all that money.
Are you a thief?
N.,No! I'm...
Get him!
Oooh... TI
Wait, you guys
Let me go! The boy...
The boy will... be killed!
What does it mean?
J, Just as I thought!!
The Kidnapper in the Picture
My hunch was right after all...
Right... it was a kidnap case!!
The one who was kidnapped is
Akio Tsubakuro, age 5,
Akio Tsubakuro, age 5
Kenzo Tsubakuro
The one who was kidnapped is
Akio Tsubakuro, age '5,
Kenzo Tsubakuro
the grandchild of Kenzo Tsubakuro, t
head of the Tsubakuro Jinancial Gro
Kenzo I subakuro
In TT
EE = tw
the grandchild of Kenzo Tsubakuro, t
head of the Tsubakuro Financial Gro
Akio Tsubakuro
He likes to draw pictures...
And the bunch of bills were ransom
moeny for Akio who had been kidnapped.
All right, then Mr. Tsubakuro,
will you please explain the details.
Get out of here...
Mr. Tsubakuro...
What's this?
It's a picture that Akio drew,
that was sent here from the kidnapper.
When did you receive it?
About noon yesterday...
It was in the mail box
together with the blakmail...
I see...
And that's the blackmail...
Price of your child,-10 billion yen... Clown"
Wow~~! How many servings of eel
over rice can you eat with that amount?
Ah, come on, Genta!
But, the money we just saw a while ago,
was far from 10 billion yen.
That money was just to display
whether they really had the will
to pay the ransom amount or not.
I'm sure that the kidnapper
back then was...
Yep, I'm sure, right!!
Y,Yes...that's right...
Hey, hey, I appreciate you
reporting the case to the police,
but from here,
we the police will take care of things
So, go and hurry on home!!
What 211
Inspector! You the police
are also going home!
B,But, Mr. Tsubakuro...
Akio is my precious one and only grandson
that my son and his wife :had left behind
after they died of
a traffic accident last year
If anything happens to him,
I wouldn't be able to face up to them...
I understand how you feel,
Mr. Tsubakuro, but...
The moment of contact with
the kidnapper when the ransom money is
to be exchanged for the kidnapped
Is the best time to arrest the kidnapper!
10 billion yen is quite heavy to carry,
therefore, the kidnapper...
No!!
I don't care whether
the kidnapper is caught or not!
Ado lidon't want to endanger Akio's life!
Besides, I have no intention to
give the kidnapper the money!
Huh?!
Just what do you mean?
This was In the mail box this morning...
Account where the money
IS to be transferred to
Swiss Fontvelle Bank...
S,. Swiss Bank?!
Inspector, we'd better order
stop payment
or ask the bank to tell us
who the account belongs to...
It's no use.
What?
Switzerland ls a bank nation.
If things go that easily,
the existence of the banks
In Switzerland would-lose their meaning.
Oh.Oh god...
I hate to say so...
But, it's just as the boy says.
No matter what the case,
they are no exceptions.
But if by doing so Akio
IS going to come back safe...
So, please!! Leave!
Mr. Tsubakuro...
Then...
This is...
A perfect crime?!
Um, Inspector.
Don't tell me that
you gave up on ie inves iga ion.
Of course!
As long as Mr. Tsubakuro
wants it that way,
we can't involve ourselves
in his paying the ransom.
However, being the police, we can let
such a ruthless crime go unchecked!!
Which means that as soon as the ransom
Is paid and Akio is returned safely,
you're going to start
an all out investigation, right?
Exactly!
But, even if the ransom is paid, there is
no guarantee that Akio will returned safely.
Oh, Akio really likes to draw, doesn't he...
This is...!!
What's up, Conan?
Conan?
Mr. Tsubakuro! Will you please show me
Akio s picture one more time!
Just as I thought, it's here too!!
Oh! That's Akio's habit.
Habit?
When he draws a picture,
he draws whatever
catches his attention as his signature.
Whatever catches his attention?
Come to think of it, I think I've seen
the same thing somewhere before.
Really? Where?
Hmm -1 wonder where it was
Oh! That's right.
When I went to South Beika Kindergarten
where Akio goes to,
I was shown a picture that he drew.
South Beika Kindergarten, I got it!
Mr. Tsubakuro, please lend me
this picture, I'll bring it right back!!
H,Hey, sonny...
Excuse me!
Do you want anything, sonny...
I would like to have a look at the picture
that Akio Tsubakuro had drawn.
Akio's drawing?
The one that Akio's grandfather looked
as is probably this picture posted here.
There!! This is the one!!
Um, teacher,
where did Akio draw this picture?
No doubt about it. That signature is
the same as the one that Akio drew.
Moreover, the one that was sent over is
what he drew in confinement.
Which means .
If I can figure out where this is, I'll be
able to find where Akio is being confined.
Ut... the problem is...
Conan!!
Just what do you think
you're doing, Conan?!
It's not fair leaving us out, you know!!
LI... didn't mean to...
Don't play dumb with us!!
I'll bet you're planning
rescue Akio all by yourself!!
We'll help you out.
D.Don't be rididulous!
We're dealing with
a kidnapper, you know!!
We can never tell what kind of danger
we may be encountering
But!
Take a look at this picture,
Akio looks:so happy!
Yes.
He's enjoying watching TV
with the kidnapper and laughing.
Yes, thisfis Kamen Yaiba, isn't it.
Yeah!
As far as this picture goes,
If we're going to rescue him, it's now!!
Yep!
Conan, that's what
you were thinking too, right?!
You guys...
Besides: this is a case
that we brought attention to!!
Right,.right!!
Okay!
But, only until we find
the place he's confined in.
After that, we leave everything
in the hands of the police!
Hmm -his signature...
Hmm -~-his signature...
I see...
But, what is it he drew here?
A spaceman?
Isn't this a chimney
attached to some building?
No I'm sure it's a spaceman!
What makes you think
he can see a spaceman from here?
But, there's no chimney
IN view from here either...
Well, that's true...
This is no time to be arguing!
It doesn't matter
whether it's a chimney or a building...
Iet's split up and look for the thing
that looks like this signature.
Okay!
There it is!!
Huh?!
Really, Ayumi!
Look isn't that it?!
A water supply tower... But ,.
It sort of looks like it...
And kind of doesn't look like it
I'm surer*that's it!
Really?
How can you be so sure?
Look, what do you see in the foreground
of that water supply tower?
A clock. ?
A park?
Yeah...
So, what!
A park is not included in his signature...!
Take a good look.
There's something that looks like eyeballs
in the middle of the signature, isn't there?
There's somethingithat looks like eyeballs
True.
Definitely...
How would you see if the water supply
tower and clock overlap on each other?
Right, The thing that looked like eyeballs
on the signature was that clock!
Which means that Akio is
in the water supply tower?
No, he s at a place where he sees
the. water supply tower and clock overlap
I see!
Let's go to the water supply tower, then!
Maybe we can see where Akio is!
Okay, let's go!!
How is it, Conan?
Yeah...
That place in view over there is
the park with the clock...
The eyeball of Akio's signature is drawn
so that it fits right into
the center of water supply tower...
In other words...
Although there may be slight differences,
Akio is most likely confined
somew ere wi in IS range.
Holy cow! Talk about a lot of houses...
It s hard to tell from here, after all.
If we all split up and search,
I'm sure we'll find him in not time at all!
Okay! Let's give it a try!
If you see any suspicious
person or house,
use your badge and call immediately
Don't ever attempt to go after
the kidnapper alone
or even think of attempting to
rescue Akio on your own!
How was it?
There were quite a few
suspicious looking places, but...
There was nothing all that conclusive
of any one of those places...
There are too many places yet, to really
narrow down the place of confinement.
Hey, wheres Ayumi?
Huns
Huh?
We were all supposed to meet
at the park at 5:00.
Yes! This is Ayumi!
Ayumi! Where are you?
Oh! Conan.
I figured Akio might be hungry, so I was
shopping at a convenience store.
Ah, come 01!
It's way past the promised time,
you know!
I'm sorry
I'll be right there$
so wait for me just a while more, okay...
Huh?
A clowns mask!
Huh? What did you just say?
I couldn't hear you too well?!
Ayumi? Is anything wrong?
What's up,. um?
I've found a suspicious looking person!
A suspicious person?
The kidnapper?
I'm not sure yet, but the clown
that Akio drew was wearing
a triangular hat with a star on it,
and had greemhair.
It was holding the remote controller
with its left hand, wasn't it!
Wait a sec!
Yep, It's exactly as she says.
No doubt about it!
It means that the kidnapper is
Ieft-handed, right?!
Ayumi, don't do anything rash!
Listen to me, will you.
Oh, wait!!
Ayumi?!
I've found him! I'm sure
he's the one who kidnapped Akio!!
I'm going to go after him!!
D,Don't, Ayumi!
It's dangerous, Ayumi!!
Answer us, Ayumi!
I'll be fine!
But, I don't want the kidnapper to find
me out, so I'll contact you all later, over!
S,She cut us off...?!
Ayumi... 7?!
Ayumi
Darn it! How could she...
Hey, Conan...
How long are we going to wait here
for Ayumi to get in touch with us...?
If anything should ever happen
to Ayumi, it's all our fault.
I get it! Can't you track where Ayumi is
with that glasses of yours?
Gentar I can't...
Agasa is fixing
my tracking glasses for me now...
Sitting here doinggnothing
isn't going to get us anywhere.
Look where?!
It's Ayumi!
Hello, Ayumi?!
Hi, sonny, I'll bet you're hungry?
I bought you some sandwiches.
And crayons and drawing paper too...
Thank you, Mr. Clown!
While you were out shopping,
I drew a lot of pictures, Mr. Clown.
Oh, yeah! Good for you!
W, Who is it?!
Who are you?
Akio! You'll be all right now,
because we've all come to save you!!
Who are you?!
How did you come here?!
Hold it!
That's it!
Hey hey! Kidnapper! We Detective Boys
are taking you on!
Give yourself in quietly!
Right!!
Darn it!
Come, kid!
Mitsuhiko, there he goes!
You're not getting away!!
Conan!
Here you go!!
We did it!
Akio!
Are you all right, Akio!
I'm all right...
Akio!! I'm so glad,
really glad that you're safe!!
We did it, didn't we, Conan!
Our strategy worked.
Yeah!
A great victory once again
for the Detective Boys!
ORIGINAY~COMIC BOOKS BY
osho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS "BY
Masato Sudo
mega
STORY E 1TGR
Junichr lioka
S aRIPTS BY.
Kani Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Much: Hlgure
Joshiki Inoue
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsush1 Aono
Akio Kawamuri
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR.
Yikilro Shil-tani
DIRECTORS OF-PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING REG-TOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Kenji Kodama%
PRODUCED BY:
TMS Entertainment. Ltd.
In 1ssociation with
Yomiuri Telecastine Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan * YTV TMS
#11 Rights Reserved
After that, Inspector Megure
and the other officers who got our report
came to the scene and
arrested the kidnapper.
But, as for us...
You fool!
Just as expected we were
bawled out by Inspector Megure
Bye, bye, big sister!
Thank you, big brothers
of the Detective Boys!
Ye, bye
Let's hang out next time, Akio!!
Bye bye 1)!
He said thank you...
It sure feels good to be thanked.
Wow, Akio sure draws well after all.
Where, let's take a look.
Conan!!
W, What?!
Wait up, Conan!
How dare you take
the frosting and the cake again!
How come things turn out this way 1"
Mail?
Thief!! Somebody stop him!
He went into the alley!
Don't let him get away!
We are police! You can't get away!
What the . there's three of them?
(BIE)