Even destiny serves
as a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
Those two have our complete attention,
a wager between two adults
causes the case to expand.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Hey, Miwako!
Hmm?
An officer of the renowned Metropolitan
Police Department First Division
Is lying around during the day with
her mouth full of tangerines, watching TV.
Give me a break, it's my day off.
It won't hurt to take it easy, will it...
Here, then!
Not again! Pictures of
my marriage mate candidates.
If you've got time to be loafing around,
Iook through them, will you.
No way!
I'm sick and tired of looking at pictures
because I've got to look through
bloody pictures of autopsies all the time.
How did you ever end up
turning into such a tomboy?
It's all my fault...
I raised you giving you too much freedom.
I couldn't possibly face up
to your father, who died on duty
and is watching over us from the heavens.
Okay then!
But, I'm just merely going to
meet them, all right!
My, just as would be expected
of my daughter!
You have the same taste
as I when it comes to men.
Love Story
at Police Headquarters-4" Part I
What?!
Officer Sato is going to meet
a marriage mate candidate?!
Right!
I'm sure that Miwako is
all dressed up by now
and meeting that man right now...
Um, and just who is that man...?
Miwako doesn't know either...
Because she told me
she chose the picture without
even looking inside the envelope.
You mean she's meeting a man
she doesn t even know the looks of?!
No problem, though!
He's a man that decided to meet a woman
officer who is in active duty, right?
I'm sure he's a very independent and
reliable, square middle aged man...
Japanese Restaurant
Minatorou"
Hey, hey, hey!
Japanese Restaurant
Minatorou"
Hey, hey, hey!!
10 minutes have already gone by
since the promised time of meeting!
A man who has the nerve to keep a lady
waiting couldn't be worth much anyway!
I'mVtleaving!!
No big deal, he's only 10 minutes late yet.
Ms. Sato?
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting.
I am Isokichi Kamei, please
remember me from here on after.
W~~What, What's thi
Is this old man supposed to
be my marriage candidate?!
No! He's the butler!
Well, since this meeting
popped up so suddenly...
The Mr. and Mrs. are on a trip abroad,
SO sire asked to
come along in their place.
Sire?
Hi, I'm so sorry!
I took a while tr in to choose flowers
that would suit you, Ms Sato...
Oh no, I shouldn't call you
Ms. Sato today, but rather...
would it be all right for me
to call you Miwako?
S,Shiratori?!
Long time no see, Mother dear...
Hello
WwW. what? why?
Just what are you talking about!
You chose him yourself, didn't you?
Huh?!
Being attracted to a police officer,
no doubt you're my daughter after all.
You mean no one in the 1st Division
knows about her meeting 'today?
Officer Takagi doesn't either, then?
G@ No. She said that she would never agree
to going out with the man anyway,
and is embarrassed,
so she was keeping it a secret...
Besides, Miwako is quite popular
with the guys
that if the word goes out,
it may cause a commotion.
But, what if the man
she is seeing wants to marry her...
No problem! Because it's all worked out
that she gets out of there
when the time is right!
Nobody would ever want:to.marry
a woman who splits the scene saying
that she has to go cover a case, right?
But, who's going to do that?
You silly thing.
Who else but Officer Takagi?!
I'm going to mail him on his cellular
with the message, "Miwako's In trouble!
Lie saying that a criminal case has come
up and take her away from where she is!
I'm sure that he'll going bursting in with
a face that you've never seen before!!
You witch...
He may just confess how he feels for her,
if situation pushes him to do so.
Hey, why don't we go there too!
But, It's pretty far from here...
Why don't you give us a lift there,
Yumi, then?!
I can't because I'm still on duty...
What are you all doing here...
Dr. Araide!
Lucky!
Huh?
But, what an honor.
To think that you chose me from among
the number of candidates that you have.
So, like I've been saying
it was sheer coincidence!
The picture that I chose without
even looking at happened to be you!
Oh, come on, Miwako, saying something
Iike that to hide your embarrassment.
I rather prefer... that it was a coincidence.
Because it would mean
that your beautiful fingers were
guided to my picture by some work of God.
I feel that it was a work of fate.
R,Right...
Splendid, Sire!
I can't possibly tell him that
I picked his picture up with my toes
I wonder if Yumi's really
going:to carry out what we planned. 3
I'll send my kid brother over,
so hang in there.
She promised saying so, but, I wonder...
I wonder who she means by kid brother?
Are you all right? You've been sneezing
quite a bit, Officer Takag:.
Yeah...
Yes, Takagi here.
Oh, Officer Takagi?
Did you read the mail I sent you?
Mail?
Robber!!
Someone, please catch him
Okay, let's go after him, Officer Chiba!!
Yes, sir!
Hello, Officer Takagi?
Hey, are you listening?
Hey, Officer Takagi!
E,Excuse me, we're the police.
Please let us through!
Oh, thereahe is! That's him!!
He went into the alley!
Don't let him get away!!
Are you all right, Mister?
Did you see someone wearing a helmet?
The guy rammed into me and
ran towards the restroom of the park.
Oh, Officer Takagi!
Here are) helmet, a coat,
a bag and gloves...
No: doubt about it,
the man who robbed the convenience
store is inside the public restroom.
Police! No use trying to flee any farther!
Come out quietly, will you!!
Hey, hey, what's with all the fuss...
Hiroshi Zama
2J)-9
What do you want...
Eiko Koshimizu
WwW, What would the police want to with
Yasuo Kamieda
1, Three people?
These are the three people
who were using the restroom
Well?
Can you make out who bumped into you?
Not really...because my glasses fell off
when the person bumped into me,
so couldn't see very well
since my vision was blurred...
Any little thing will do!
Please tell me what you remember!
Well, the person was taller than me...
She was a girl wearing
blue clothes under her coat!
Ms. Koshimizu is a only woman,
but the clothes she's wearing is black.
What do I know!
That's all I remember!
O,Oh...
Hey! I don't have any idea
what's going on, but...
If we have nothing to do with
what's going on, can we head on home?
I've got other commitments after this so.
P.Please wait!
You may leave only after we finish
questioning the other witnesses!
What 21
S,Shiratori... Don't tell me that he's
the one from the police department?!
Yes, he's in the Tsuru Room
together with Ms. Sato.
Which means that the man
Officer Sato is meeting is...
Inspector Shirator?!
Uh... would you like me to
take them a message?
Uh, well, no, we're...
We were asked by the families of the two
to bring them an interesting gift.
It's going to take some time to prepare,
so will you please let us use
the room next to the Tsuru Room?
Yes... sure,
since it ust so ha ens to be vacant.
Thank you, Miss.
Please wait a while then.
I'm very sorry to trouble you
That kid is pretty sharp...
My, how delicious!!
We had our chef come over
to cook for us here,
so that you could taste the kind of meal
that we eat at the Shiratori residence,
and had him make
these exquisite Japanese dishes!
Sire had informed us that Miwako
does not care much for French cuisine so.
Oh? Did you have food
that you didn't like?
Hey, Miwako?
Huh?
Uh, yes.
Uh, excuse me!
Is there anyone who-witnessed the robber
in this convenience store a while ago?
Hey, Officer!
Wouldn't it be faster for you to ask
the employee of the convenience store?
We already did!
She said the robber stuck out a knife and
showed a paper, said Give me the cash,
so the only thing she remembers
IS the helmet and coat.
Hopeless case...
Darn it... give me a break...
Uh, officer?
I can tell you how tall the robber was!
The person who was wearing
a helmet and a coat, right?
I was watching through
the window of the shop, but...
I saw the person's head
sticking out of the throng of people,
so I think the person's height
was about 180 centimeters...
180 centimeters would be
the tallest of the three, Mr. Zama.
Come to think of it,
he was wearing a blue sweater.
Oh and when the person's coat
flipped over a bit I saw the color green!
Not blue?
No, I'm positive that it was green!
Were able to tell if it was
a man or a woman?
With a height of 180 centimeters
wouldn't it be a man?
I see...
Hey, Officer!
Yes?
That coffee shop owner was bragging
that he looked at the robber close.
RR. Really?!
Yeah, I sure saw him!
The weirdo wearing a helmet
who went running off!
It was when I was getting the samples
of the lunchtime menu out.
Can you give me
the characteristics of that person?
I'm not sure if the person
was a man or woman,
but the height was
about 170 centimeters!
The person had a coat over black clothes!
B.Black... did you say...
About 170 centimeters
would be Mr. Kamieda.
But he is wearing green colored sweater.
Hey hey, what's going on?
Well, I guess we'll excuse
ourselves for a while then.
You two take your time
and talk things out together.
Ney, ney... yum...
When is she coming to pick me up?!
I see.
So someone is supposed to come rescue, I
the beautiful princess from
the hands of the evil prince?
D.D.Don't be ridiculous!
Just what are you talking about!
Okay, let's do this.
If Officer Takagi comes to get you,
I shall gracefully back down.
But, if he chickens out and
doesn't show up, you will be my wife.
Huh? Why is it Officer Takagi?
Why not?
It's just a joke! A joke!
I just wanted to see you look troubled.
All right then...
Huh?
It's a deal!
What 21
H,Hey, Officer Takagi,
just what-is going on?
The testimony of the witnesses
don't match...
There were three witnesses
in all, weren't there».
Yeah... all three of them remembered
the characteristics of the robber very well.
The man who bumped into the robber said
that it was a woman wearing blue clothes.
The High School girl who was watching
through the window of a shop said,
that the robber was more than 180
centimeters tall, wearing green clothes,
and most probably a male.
And the owner of the coffee shop insisted
that the robber was about 170
centimeters, wearing black clothes.
All three witnesses had something
absolutely different to say.
V.,Very true...
I don't believe they told a lie.
Yeah.
Shall we begin interrogating
the three suspects then?
Yeah...
What do you mean, it's a deal.
Are you sure you know
what you're talking about?
Yes, I do.
If Officer Takagi comes here to get me,
then this meeting for possible marriage
is called off immediately, right!
If he doesn't show up,
I marry you and become your wife.
Instead of waiting without a time limit,
Iet's set the limit at sundown,
what do you say?
Hey, hey... you've gotta be joking,
Officer Sato.
Things are starting to sound
really interesting, don't you think?
But, what if Officer Takagi
doesn't show up?
It could be that Officer Sato is
after a Cinderella story, you know.
Inspector Shiratori is after all
the son.of'a... coon
that attends most of the parties
held at my house, so.
I thought that Officer Sato and Officer
Takagi really got along well though...
Well, she went as far as
to say what she did
So, I think she thinks
that the odds are in her favor.
Okay. So, it's all right with you then?
Yes! I will not go back on my word!
Right, right, it's Officer Takagi.
I'm sure that he's the one that's going to
pick me up that Yumi was talking about!
S...l just know he'll com
I'm sure?
My name is Yasuo Kamieda.
I teach at a prep school.
I stopped over at that restroom
on my way to a book store nearby,
where I was planning to by a book.
I'm Hiroshi Zama, a part-time worker.
I just happened to use that restroom
on my way back from band practice!
I'm Eiko Koshimizu. I work at an office!
I was taking a walk when I suddenly
came down with a stomach ache.
So I went to that restroom.
Now that I've said all
I have to say, let me go!
It's already after 2:00!
Huh? You're wearing two wristwatches?
My boyfriend's abroad,
so I'm wearing a wristwatch showing
the time of the country he's in too!
It's notanice calling him
at a ridiculous time, is it?
Back in Jr. High School, a teacher
told me to wear two wristwatches too.
Because I was always tardy for class!
Hey, mister!! What's so funny?!
Uh, well, I always tell my students
at prep school
to take off their watches during class,
so I just thought what a difference...
You mean the wristwatches
of the students?
Yes, because I want them to concentrate
on the lessons without thinking of time.
I also removed clocks of the classroom
as thinking out other things to help them.
By the way, about the band
you just mentioned Mr. Zama?
Oh, I'm playing in the band
with my high school friends.
A visual type band!
When I play in the band,
I dress like a woman.
I may not look it, but I get a lot of calls
from my fans and I'm pretty popular too.
OO. Oh... I see...
Oh, talking about phone calls, there
was a call for you from Yumi a while ago.
She said for you
to read the mail she sent you.
I'll bet she wants to go singing
at a Karaoke or something again.
Little does she know of
the predicament I'm In...
Oh... a convenience store robbery.
Oh, no, I just had something
I wanted to ask Officer Takag:.
Please tell him to give it
his best shot then, Inspector Megure
H,Hey... What's this about a
convenience store robbery?!
Wasn't Officer Takagi supposed to
be checking ona case today?
After he finished checking on the case,
he seems to have run into
the convenience store robbery case.
It seems he's already narrowed the
suspects downto three people, though.
It seems the testimony of
the witnesses are a bit various
What do you mean various?
There's only one suspect, isn't there?!
Well, I don't have the slightest idea.
Okay, I'll contact
Officer Takagi myself, then...
It's against the rule for you
to call him from your side.
It's much too disadvantageous for me.
Well, I'm sure everything
will turn out all right.
He'll rush over here as soon as
he arrests the convenience store robber.
Or, maybe you don't believe he will?
It... It's not that .
Then again, if a police officer abandons
the case in the midst of an investigation,
and shows up in a place like this,
he'll have to go through
disciplinary action
taken against him
for violating duty regulations.
If I remember correctly, he went through
a pay cut once before, didn't he?
If he has the guts to
show up here knowing
that he may have to undergo
disciplinary action for the second time,
1 Il admit that
he's been¥aiman- about the whole thing.
The situation doesn't look too good,
does it?!
Oh come on, we can't just do nothing...!
Quiet...!
I've got to go to the restroom.
He "Officer!
Just how long to you intend to
keep us locked up in this car?
The sun's going to set!
Oh, so just a little while longer...
Oh, hello, is that Yumi?
My hands are tied just yet and...
This is Shinichi Kudo
What?!
Conan asked me to give you a call...
WwW, what did Conan ask you to do?
Please check your cell phone mail
and take note of the situation
that you're in now.
But, the only mail I got today
was from Yum...
Miwako is In trouble!
Resue her from Minatoro where she is
holding a marrige meeting...
Ms. Sato is meeting her husband to be?!
So, you haven't read the mail, have you?
But, don't worry, please calm down.
There's still a lot of time
to go till sundown,
and the place she's meeting him is
in the neighboring town, Haidocho.
1.1 sundown?
Officer Sato agreed to the terms
that her husband to be stuck out at her.
If you don't solve the case
by sundown and go to get her,
she's going to have to accept
her partner's marriage proposal.
Please give me the details of the case...
Officer Takagi?
Officer Takagi, can you hear me?
I DUE.
All three suspects testified totally
differing characteristics of the robber?
How interesting.
In, Interesting, Shinichi...
First of all, I'll go to that coffee shop
and talk to Mr Mamehara, the owner.
ORIGIN LL COMIC BOOKS BY
(~osho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sudo
ao er
Junichi1317ka
Junichi loka
SCRIPTS BY
Kan]: Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Hioure
Toshiki Inoue
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
Ken]: Kodamfi?
PRO UCED.BY
TMS Eitertainment, Ltd.
In 1ssociation with
Yomiuri delecastine sorporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Abyama /*Shogakuka'n - YTV - TMS
#1 Rights Reserved
40 minutes left to sundown.
I've got to hurry, otherwise, Ms. Sato will../
If Takagi doesn't make it in time
and I win the bet,
as proof, please give me a kiss of pledge.
I see!! So that's what it was!!
Shall we get started...
With that pledge you know what thing...