Even destiny serves as a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
What became of the two detectives?
As the evening grows, will their love fade?
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult,
No case is left
unsolved with Detective Conan.
We learn from Yumi,
Officer Sato's colleague
that Officer Sato is going to be meeting
a marriage candidate
who she has never met before.
No problem!
Because it's all worked
out that she gets out of there
when the time is right!
But, who's going to do that?
You silly thing.
Who else but Officer Takagi?!
I'm going to mail him on his cellular,
Miwako's in trouble!"
Lie that a criminal case has come up
and take her away from where she is!
I'm sure that he'll go bursting in
with a face that you've never seen before!
You witch...
When we arrive really interested
and curious at Mizutozakura...
What?!
S,Shiratori... Don't tell me...
that he's the one
from the police department?!
he is meeting with Ms. Sato in there
Which means that
the man Officer Sato is meeting. is...
Shiratori?
Robber!
Somedody, get him!
At that time, officer Takagi met
a robber at a convenience store.
He ran after a criminal and
hunted him down at a restroom in the park.
However, there were three suspects.
Besides he hasn't been able
to-clear whichswas a criminal,
because everyone testified differently.
Oh, so just a little while longer...
My hands are tied just yet and...
Uh, it's me...
This is Shinichi Kudo
What?!
Conan asked me to give you a call...
WW.,What did Conan ask you to do?
Please check your cell phone mail
and take note
of the situation that you're in now.
But, the only mail
I got today was from Yumi...
O,Officer Sato is
meeting a marriage candidate?!
So, you haven't read the mail, have you?
But, don't worry please calm down
There's still a lot of time
to go till sundown,
and the place she's meeting him
Is in the neighboring town, Haidocho...
T,Till sundown?
Officer Sato agreed to the terms
that her proposed husband suggested.
If you don't solve the case
by sundown and go to get her,
she's going to have to accept
her partner's marriage proposal.
Please give me the details of the case.
Officer Takagi?
Officer Takagi, can you hear me?
Hey. +
Love Story at Police Headquarters-4-
Part ll
I have the three suspects
that were in the restroom in the park
where the robber fled into with me...
Of the three, two are men.
One of them is Mr. Hiroshi Zama,
21 years old, a part-time worker.
Hiroshi Zama
2J-5
He is about 180 centimeters tall,
Hiroshi Zama
2J)-5
IS wearing a blue sweater
and pierced earrings...
Hiroshi Zama
IS wearing a blue sweater
and pierced earrings...
The other man is
Yasuo Kameida, 32 years old.
Yasuo Kamieda
EH QQGZ)
He is a prep school teacher
and about 170 centimeters tall.
Yasuo Kamieda
or 55
He is a prep school teacher
and about 170 centimeters tall.
He is wearing
a green sweater and glasses.
The last one is a woman
called Ms. Eiko Koshimizu.
Eiko Koshimizu
AK WRF (28)
She is 28 years old
and works in an office.
Eiko Koshimizu
wWN J \
She is about 160 centimeters tall,
Eiko Koshimizu
#2 JK BR F (28)
She is about 160 centimeters tall,
IS wearing black clothes
and wears two wristwatches.
When the robber broke
into the convenience store,
the outfit the robber had
on were a helmet, a coat, and gloves.
The robber stuck out a knife
and showed the employee a paper
with the words, Give me money.
The robber is still unidentified.
There is no doubt
that the robber disposed of the coat
and ran into the restroom in the park...
But, the trouble is that the testimony
of the witnesses all differ...
The old man who bumped into
the robber in front of the park says,
She was a woman wearing blue clothes.
The girl who was watching
through the window of a shop says,
The head of the robber stuck out
from among the throng of people,
so the robber who is about
180 centimeters tall is most likely a man.
And from under the coat,
she saw the color green
As for the owner of the coffee shop,
he said when he was outside the shop
he saw the robber who was on the run.
He says that the robber
was about 170 centimeters
and wearing black clothes under the coat.
I see.
All three suspects testified totally
differing characteristic %of/the robber?
How interesting!
In. Interesting, Shinichi...
First of all, I'll go to that coffee shop
and talk to Mr. Mamehara, the owner.
Huh?
Why do you know the owner's name...?
I've known him from before
Hey, officer, what's up?
Did you arrest the robber?
Ah... Not yet...
Take the owner outside.
Huh?
Hurry!!
H,Hey!
Where are you taking me?
Let's talk inside the shop.
1.I'm sorry, please come with me...
WwW, What's with you...
Y,Your glasses are sunglasses?!
I'm pretty sure,
that the sunglasses that the owner
IS wearing have photochromic lens
that change color for about 15 seconds
when he goes outside
and is exposed to ultraviolet rays
The owner as I know him,
doesn't wear glasses,
so I thought that it may be possible.
I'm wearing these glasses just for show.
I decided to wear them
just for fun only recently.
I completely forgot about them.
Which means
that the robber s clothes that you saw
may have looked darker
than the actual color
because of the change in the color
of the lens of your glasses?
0,Oh,
but about the robber being
about 170 centimeters is a fact.
But...
another witness says that the robber
was about 180 centimeters.
The shop that the girl said
she saw the robber through the window,
where is it?
About 100 meters from
this coffee shop, back store.
In the direction of
the convenience store.
Oh...over there.
Then, please go to where the shop is.
If I remember correctly,
she said she saw the head of
the robber above the throng of people?
Yeah...
That street...
Ieads from the entrance of the subway to
the bus stop, so depending on the time,
It becomes congested with people.
If a throng of people
come heading in your direction,
how would you try to
make it through, Officer Takagi?
How...
I would try to avoid them
as much as possible...
If you feel that doing so will not get you
through the crowd fast enough, so what?
Well, then I'drhave no choice but to...
give up running along the sidewalk
part way and run along the curb stone...
II get it!
The girl witnessed
the robber running along the curb stone,
and mistook the robber's height as
being over 180 centimeters!!
A puzzle...
AqZiQZGW puzzle, Officer Taka'g'l...
Although the pieces may look scattered
and mismatching...
if you rotate them and look at them
from a different angle,
they will surely fit in perfectly
The mismatching pieces
of testimony that the witnesses
give us are indispensable pieces
that we need to complete the puzzle
Conan's sure taking his time, isn't he?
Oh, I guess I'll go check on him, then.
I wonder if Conan ate something bad...
I made toast and sunny side ups
for breakfast today...
nd for lunch...
I'm pretty sure I've seen
that person once before...
My, so it wasn't the right person after all?
I've seen that person
somewhere before...
The only person left is the old man
who says he ran into the robber...
According to my deduction,
the testimony of
that old man is the most decisive...
Uh, Shinichi.
1 CO.
Why?
How is it you know so much...
Well, that's...
Conan?
Oh no! It's Ran!!
Conan, are you all right?
Oh, so will you please talk to
that old man once more!
Then, you'll be able to narrow the robber
down to just one person!
Huh? Hey, wait...
If I remember correctly
the old man testified
that the robber was a woman
wearing blue clothes under her coat.
But, Mr. Zama is the one
who is the one wearing blue clothes...
0,Oh, yes, it's his pierced earrings!!
The old man saw the earrings
and thought it was a woman...
but when they bumped into
each other the robber
should still have been wearing
the helmet...
He couldn't have seen the robber's face...
Then, why did he think
the robber was a woman...?
Darn.
Only 40 minutes to sundown...
I've-got to hurry,
or else Ms. Sato will have to...
Watch...
Come to think of it, that person...
I see!
That's what it was!!
I've got it!!
I've figured out who the robber is!!
The sun has set quite a bit.
Oh yes, I guess so...
Ms. Sato...
It's not that I don't trust you, but...
If Officer Takagi fails to make it
here in time,
I d like some proof of it
Proof?
As proof of it,
I'd like you to give me a kiss
as a pledge of your promise
Huh?!
A kiss of pledge...
Me and you?
Yes,
you don't mind, do you?
Because if Officer Takagi
doesn't come here by sundown,
we're going to get married anyway, so...
You promised not to go back
on your word, didn't you?
Y, Yes,
of course...
Come on, what's keeping you.
Officer Takagu...
Hurry up and arrest the robber, will you!!
Oh, Officer Takagqu...
Did you find out anything new?
No, not at all...
The testimonies of the witnesses
are still all different
as far as the robber is concerned...
A woman wearing a blue dress,
a man wearing green clothes
that is more than 180 centimeters tall...
or a person wearing black clothes
that is about 170 centimeters...
That's no help...
We can't possibly narrow down
the suspect to one person
with what we've got now...
I guess I'll take my time...
Because after all it's still before 3:00 yet
So, I've still got lots of time...
Hey, hey,
just what are you talking about?!
Your watch must be broken.
It's already 4:30...
Huh?
So, it was you after all, wasn't it?
O,Officer Takagi...
The owner of the coffee shop said that
the robber was wearing black clothes
because he had glasses
with photochromic lens on!
And the girl said
the robber was more than 180 meters tall
because the robber in order to avoid
the crowd ran along the curbstone...
Aside from the testimonies
black clothes
and "more than 180 centimeters,
when.matching.
The testimonies of the two,
the robber is said to have been about
170 centimeters
and wearing green clothes.
In other words, Mr. Kamieda...
you're the one who did it!!
B,But
the old man who bumped into the robber
said the robber
was a woman wearing blue clothes.
Yes.
But, at that time,
it had completely slipped my mind
that the witness was an elderly man!!
Please look, Miwako...
What a beautiful sunset...
20 more minutes
to go till the sun completely sets...
Officer Takagqi...
Officer Takagu...
Officer Takagi...
Officer TA-KA-GI I
1, 1 get it, the old man!!
Elderly men in Japan
sometimes say blue when
they actually mean the color green!
Yeah.
Elderly people in Japan
used to say blue regardless of whether
they meant indigo, light blue or green!
After recalling that
Mr. Kamieda was a prep school teacher,
an idea raced through my mind.
He mentioned
that he tried to devise ways of
not making the students worry
about the passage
of time during his classes...
So, I figured that it could be
that he had the face
of his wristwatch turned towards the inner
part of his wrist rather than outward,
where only he himself
could see what time it was...
(am am.
1 See,
so the old man
mistook the robber as being a woman
because the face of the robber's
wristwatch was on the inner side
of the wrist than the outer.
Yeah.
He probably always used to wear
his wristwatch in this fashion
because it was too much trouble
to keep changing the position of
his wristwatch for every class.
In other words,
the testimony of
the witnesses all point to the fact
that you are the one
who robbed the convenience store,
Mr. Kamieda!!
Aaaagh. .Aaagh...
A little less than 10 minutes to go...
I guess I've won the bet...
Please don't wear such a dreadful look...
I'm not going to force you
to marry me right away,
not until you're perfectly ready to accept.
I'm willing to wait as long as
you want me to.
Huh?
I don't to make an enemy out of you
I'm always on your side.
Inspector Shiratori...
The phone...
Oh, Officer Sato?
Takagi here!
I just arrested
the convenience store robber!
The place you're at
Is pretty near from here,
so I'll be over in about 5 minutes.
Okay,
hurry up and come get me then, will you!!
Really, I tell you...
U,Uh...
May I ask you a question
before I head on there?
What?
Why me?
Huh?
Why did you believe in a person
Iike me and...
agree to bet on something so important
that would affect your whole life?
Because I was positive
that you would come get me!
Does it bug you?
U,Uh well...
you see, that's...
M,Maybe...
you...
WwW ,Well, you...
See...
I thought that you like. .me...
The robber got away!!
Hey, freeze!!
Come on, Officer Takagi!
Oh, but...
I don't have time left!
Officer Takag:.
Which means more to you,
the convenience:store robber or me?!
Huh?
Go after him, Takagi!!
Y.Yes!!
Are you sure it's okay?
If he goes after the robber now,
there's no way he'll make it in time...
Well, if so,
I guess I'll have to resign to the fact that
it was destined to turn out this way...
It could be that the heavens punished me
for getting Officer Takagi involved in
this bet without his permission.
But, a bet's a bet!
Why don't we hurry up
nd get on with it then...
with that pledge or whatevers...
16:56 suspect arrested... Heave, heave...
1, I...wanted money...
I needed severance money
to give to a woman
who persistently hung around me
uuugh...
U...uuugh...
Ghads...
I've come quite a distance
from Minatorou...
I would never be able to make it
there now
Officer Takagi!
You did it, Officer Takaq:...
Nah...
I goofed and let go
of who I really wanted to catch
Hey, so what's the matter?
Hurry up and get on with it.
I'm all ready and set!
Ready and set...
But, your face says you don't want to...
Don't worry, Miwako.
Let's just stay this way for a while
and calm down a bit...
After all,
there is nothing to keep us
apart anymore anyway...
They're finally going to kiss.
L,I'll go stop them!
W What are you talking about?!
Um, Mr. Niide...
Hmm?
Will you please come...
I'll take him to the station,
so you go on ahead Officer Takagt!
You're an officer, aren't you?
If so,
than do what an officer is expected to do
and pursue your target until the last!!
Takagi!!
Okay.
The sun will completely set soon.
Have you calmed down?
Yes...
What is it, Conan?
Um...
never realized .
888...
come to mean so much:to me...
Huh?
H,Hey .
H. Hey...
Hold it!
Im really a crummy officer
realizing something like this only now...
I guess this is just
what I need to forget the whole deal
Bye, bye, Takagqi.
Assistant.Inspector Miwako Sato!
I'm sorry to bother you
when you're off duty,
but we've ot a case
and I hope you'll come to back us up?
O, Officer Takagi?
He's come!
Officer Takag:!!
Bad timing!
Officer Takagi!!
Officer Takagi?
Huh?
Cc. Conan?
Oh...Officer Takagi...
Officer Takagi just went running down
the corridor to the entrance...
Ghads, I tell you!
Oh, Miwako
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
osho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
Masat » "Sd
STORY EDITOR.
Junichr oka
510 Y EDITOR
Junichi lioka
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari.Kouchi
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIR CTORS OF PHOTQLRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi: Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kfldamav
PRODU ED BY
TVS entertainment, Ltd.
In association with
YOITIIUH Télena§tanév mrporwtmn
DETE «JIVE CONAN
Gosho Aoyama ; Shogakukan * YTV TMS
#11 Rights Reserved
No good...
The sun has completely set...
I couldn't make it in time...
Police Sergeant Takagt!
Huh?
What the hell are you doing?!
Hurry up, get in!!
O, Officer Sato...
You've got a case on your hands,
haven't you?
Oh, yes.
I couldn't help wanting to help out...
I mean those two are so awkward
at things like this,
just like some other twosome
I'm really familiar with...
I feel real bad for having done this to
Inspector Shiratori, though...
Mr. Ushikubo passed away?!
What?!
There's blood on his fingertip...
Besides,
it looks like he touched something...
Hmm?
Why on earth did that person?