Even.destiny serves as a clue to deduction % °
and the light of truth pierces through
the most mysterious case.
Another travel mystery for our fans,
the puzzle is hidden in the beautiful scenery.
He sees through the one and only truth
a child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
Ahhhh!
For goodness sakes dad, it's still morning
and you're already drinking...
What's wrong with that,
after all, My ticket was the winning ticket
at the shopping arcade lottery...
I know, you had the lucky ticket and that's
why we're able to take another trip
Iike this, isn't that what you want to say!
We've heard it so many times already,
right, Conan?
Uh huh!
That's right sir,
you're real lucky at lotteries.
Not just at lotteries, at everything!
Gar harharharhar...
Hahaha...
You think it'll go all right?
I mean he's the one
who made all the arrangements.
Don't worry,
Conan's very mature for his age.
As for you dad, you're drinking too much!
Uh...
Oh all right...
THE LINKED POETRY INCIDENT
at TAMATSUKURI in MATSUE-PART I
This Matsue city,
Matsue Castle
is famous for its castle.)
is famous for its castle...
and for Lake Shiny...
Lake Shiny
I hear the Lake Shinji Shitchin's
worth trying.
Lake Shin
ded. 7
I hear the Lake Shinji Shitchin's
worth trying.
The castle's shrine
hat's shitchin...
the castle's shrine
Ha far ah
the castle s shrine
It refers to the sea bass,
SEE Ea.
Japanese ice fish, pond smelt,
fresh water clam,
moroge shrimp,carp and eel,"
the seven delicacies caught in this lake.
Collectively, they're called shitchin.
Yakumo Koizumi's former residence
Matsue also boasts Lafcadio Hearn
known as Yakumo Koizumi.
Yakumo Koizumi's former residence
Matsue also boasts Lafcadio Hearn
known as Yakumo Koizumi
Yakumo Koizumi, you mean
the author of Kwaidan?
most people are familiar with
Mimi nashi hoichi
and Yuki Onna'.
And,
there's a spooky story based in Matsue,
do you want to hear it, Ran?
Uh, well...maybe another time...
Matsue hot springs "Kosuikan
Mr. Kogoro Mourn.
Mr Kogoro Mourn
one of our staff
will show you to your room,
please wait over there for a while.
We serve all our guest
green tea and sweets...
Thanks.
Wow...
It's the lake!
How wonderful, you have
such a great view of the lake from here.
We'll be able to see them digging
for clams tomorrow morning!
Speaking of clam digging,
I believe
Basho composed a poem about it...
Shijimi tori futami ni wakare
yuku aki zo...
something like that.
Ph .hee hee hee...
Mr Shiina, that's rude...
But madam...
I hate to correct you.
But I believe it was hamaguri clam,
not shijimi.
Fa...
hamagur?
Yes.
Actually, the poem reads,
Hamaguri no futami ni wakare
yuku aki zo...
And just so you know, he wrote that
at the last point of Okunohosomichi,
at Ogaki.
Ahaha...
You know your literature...
Matsue ranks high alongside
Kyoto and Kanazawa
for its Japanese sweets.
Osaka, our hometown's
got to work harder at it...
He's Takumi Yagisawa.
He runs a Japanese confectionery shop
in Osaka.
Takumi Yagisawa
NMFEE =A
It's no big deal,
Takumi Yagisawa
"took over the business from my fath
NMFTE EA
I see...
so you're the junior president.
They sure look good.
I'm helping myself!
Me too.
But don't forget...
Brush your teeth after you eat them!
Uh, of course...
He's Ryosuke Shiina...
Ryosuke Shiina
DED Tl
a superb dentist
Ryosuke Shiina
At your service!
And over there is...
Mizuki Kawaguchi
Mizuki Kawaguchi...
one of my students,
she also works in the library.
Mizuki Kawaguchi
Did\you say student, so you must be...
Oh forgive me,
I forgot to introduce myself...
Reiko Ando
my name is Reiko Ando,
I do research at a junior college
Reiko Ando
in Osaka in the Japanese
Literature Department.
Reiko Ando
in Osaka in the Japanese
Literature Department.
For goodness sakes, you're an expert!
We're members of a
renga group from Osaka,
we came to Matsue on
a poetry composing trip
You don t say...
Our other member is over there talking,
that's Gozo Ushikubo, he's an investor.
Gozo Ushikubo
Which means the price of
this stock will keep rising!
Gozo Ushikubo
I see...
My name is Kogoro Mouri,
I'm a private investigator from Tokyo.
Eh!?
Kogoro Mourn?
What!
Kogoro Mouri, you mean you're that...
Famous private detective!?
Oh yes,hahaha...
Does that mean,
that famous private detectives
make a lot of money?
Well, not exactly...
Yes, but you...
Excuse me,
my name is Tomonaga,
I work for Naniwa Securities
at their Okayama branch.
Previously on another job,
Mr. Ushikubo and...
Hey you,
isn't it time you left!?
Oh, uh yes, you're right...
I enjoy poetry too
and I sometimes compose my own.
I'd like to join you one day...
well, Mr. Mourn,
I hope you have a nice visit.
Humph!
Oh,excuse me, madam,
what is that big book?
Oh, you mean this?
This is called
Dictionary of What Things are Called
We use it when we're composing poetry.
Would you like to look through it?
1 CO.
Wow, it-looks very interesting.
Hey, look at these shoes!
See,
they look just like Mr. Shiina's shoes!
They're trekking shoes all right...
but then,
those are for professionals,
mine's just an imitation...
Those shoes of yours are so fancy,
they look pretty expensive
how can you afford them, you're broke.
Garharharharhar...
By the way, Mr. Mourn,
why don't you join us for dinner?
That's a great idea.
We'll get to hear stories from
Japan's greatest detective first hand,
what a rare opportunity!
Ja...Japan's greatest?
Deheh heh...
Well, how can I refuse then,
I accept your invitation!
Gar harharhar
Hah...
Don't you just love these hot springs...
yeah...
Me too...
It feels so good,
my body feels like
it's turning into melted chocolate...
Exactly...
Excuse me, Mr. Yagisawa...
Yes?
What is that renga
you were all talking about back there?
How can I explain...
simply put,
it's a kind of game where several people
compose poems and link them together.
For example, Conan,
you compose a 57-5 haiku, okay?
The next person
would add another 7-7 poem to it...
Then another person
would add another 5-7-5 poem to it...
and so forth,
Iinking one poem to the other.
Is it different from haiku?
The first 5-7-5.
Is called hokku. But...
I suppose you could consider it haiku,
after all,
It would contain the season word...
I see...
What kind of poem do you like,
Mr. Yagisawa?
I like poems that are humorous.
What about you Mr. Shiina?
Huh?
Who me?
Let's see...
My favorite poems are those with feeling,
Iike how a father feels for his daughter...
pardon me for asking,
but do you have children, Mr. Shiina...?
I have a daughter...
but my wife took her when she left me...
Oh, gee...I'm sorry to hear that...
I don't blame her though,
it was all my fault,
I was over my head in debt...
{ - iy. wally.
I...
Thank you for listening!
That was wonderful, Mr. Yagisawa!!
Here you go Mr. Mouri, drink up.
Well, that's mighty nice of you...
By the way,
have you made plans for tomorrow?
Oh, that's right,
I was meaning to ask...
Conan,
have you ever heard of Yaegaki Shrine?
Ms. Ando told me
about it while we were in the bath,
why don't we go there tomorrow?
Uh, tomorrow: mo ning,
we're going to
the Tiffany Garden Museum of Art,
then In the afternoon...
Yaegaki Shrine, eh...
I believe It houses the god of marriage...
It's famous for it's Mirror Lake
fortune telling, isn't that right.
Eh? Oh, yes...
Well then we'll have to go there too...
except for Mr. Ushikubo,
the four of us are single...
But,
Ran already has someone special,
don't you?
There's a bus that goes to Yaegaki Shrine
from the Matsue Onsen station
in the morning...
you can always go to
the art museum in the afternoon...
h all right then...
that's what we'll do.
Good grief,
Iook at those two, all goo-goo eyed.
Now, now...
Ms Ando, listen...
Yes?
Don't you think
it's about time we picked the location
where we're going to compose
our first poem?
1 CO,
you're right...
Shiina...
yes.
The first place
for the poem composition?
We're going to pick
where we're to go to compose
the hokku portion of the poem.
Oh...
I remember, hokku is the 5-7-5 haiku
that starts the linked poem.
Yes,
the rule is to compose the poem
describing the scene in front of you.
Oh, I nearly forgot.
This is for you, Mr. Mouri
It's an-introduction to linked poetry,-
I wrote it.
There's a picture of us inside too.
Hmm...
I see,
you're all here...
There, I'm finished!
Mizuki,
can you get me my hat, it's over there?
Okey.
Here you are.
Thank you.
All right then,
Mr. Ushikubo, you first
Okey...
Next, we'll go according to age,
SO It's me.
Let's see...
The closest one is
Here we are...
All right, everyone read your slips.
Matsue Castle.
Mine is Gessho Temple.
Shiominawate.
Which means,
I'm at the art museum...
All right then,
we'll leave the hotel
at 9:00 tomorrow morning
then return by 11:30.
When everyone gets back,
we'll move to Tamatsukuri Spa
nd link the poems...
Oh no!
Is something the matter?
No, it's just that I wear contact lenses
and my eyes dry very easily
so I need my prescription eye drops .
Oh, here they are.
I'm such a scatter brain,
I forget where I leave it all the time.
Humph!
If it's so important,
you should always carry a spare!
I always carry an extra one in my bag...
On, that's right,
I have to make a phone call!
Well isn't he the busy fellow...
He's probably just found another victim.
Huh?
His motive for joining our group,
was artiall to et our mone
He's really a louse!
Listen up, Yagisawa!
You're the one
who can't afford to lose your business!
Get it all ready by next week, or else.
Pay back what you owe.
Or you'll lose your business,
understand!
Yes, I know...
Yaegaki Shrine
\EiSmht
Mirror Lake
Hmm...
MirrorslLake
It says that if the paper doesn't sink 1
within fifteen minutes,
Mirror Lake
you'll find the love of your life.
And if it sinks close to you,
it means that the person
you're looking for is close by.
Let's try-it...
That's why I didn't want
to bring her here...
Ran.
I don't know how it's going to turn out...
but .
Sorry to keep you waiting Conan!
What a cute puppy.
Uh huh...
Ran...
Huh?
Shall we go?
Okey!
Hello.
Oh,it's you dad.
Uh huh...
uh what?
Mr. Ushikubo's dead!
What!?
Karamete no koguchi Park
2 FEZ
It's Mr. Ushikubo...
I'm certain of it.
I see, so it is...
By the looks of it,
he's been beaten to death.
He was hit on the back
of the head several times.
With a hard, blunt object.
Officer Hirose
Huh?
Oh, you're not by any chance!
Officer Hirose
Oh, you're not by any chance!?
My name's Mouri, I'm a private detective.
It looks like Mr. Ushikubo
tried to protect his head
with his left hand when he was attacked...
That's how his watch was cracked...
10105...
I'm pretty sure we can assume
that's the time of the attack.
1 CO.
And about the victim's right hand...
His index finger is extended
Iike he was pointing to something.
Hum...
Bamboo huh...
It could be a dying message...
Could be...
There's blood on the tip of his finger!
And it looks like
he touched something with it...
There's no blood here...
One of the pages has been ripped out!
Ah, Autumn: is:full I suffice to say,
my lifexhas no sorrow...
Ouch!
Don't touch the evidence!!
Matsue police station
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Officer Yasugi
I'm Yasugi
from the Shimane Prefectural Polic
Officer Yasugi
rm Yasugi
from the Shimane Prefectural Polic
Of fiber Tlsubakl
And this is my assistant,
Officer Tsubaki.
Officer Tsubaki
And this is my assistant,
Officer Tsubaki.
Hey, where'd that kid go?
And beside him is Officer Hirose
of the Matsue Police Station...
Hey, where'd that kid go?
And beside him is Officer Hirose
of the Matsue Police Station...
I don't know
he was asking everybody questions
and then he ran off somewhere...
Good grief...
the reason
I asked all of you to come here is
I need to know where you were all at
when Mr. Ushikubo was killed,
which is approximately 10:05.
What are you insinuating!?
From what Mr. Mouri tells me,
you all had a motive
for killing Mr. Ushikubo.
Everything's bound to come out
sooner or later,
so I think it's better
for everyone to just tell the truth.
All right then,
I was
at the Tiffany Garden Museum of Art.
1 went there to write a poem...
Tiffany Garden Museum of Art
There's a piece called Shika no Mad
I wrote a poem while I was looking att t.
Tiffany Garden Museum of Art
Even the Gods will gather
and gaze upon Deer's Window...
Yes,
I do remember him
I'm sure that
person was bending over by the hedges
beside the fountain
in the English garden,
something about having dropped
some coins
Do you remember the time?
I'm sure it was a little past 11.
Thank you!
Huh?
What are these marks?
I was at Gessho Temple at that time.
You probably know
there's huge statue of a turtle there, right?
CO...
Gessho Temple
I spotted a praying mantis by that stat
To the huge turtle a mantis
does raise its ax in reverence forsooth,
Is what I wrote
The time was almost 10:05 on the dot.
Yes, I remember,
he stood in front of that statue
for a long time thinking...
Do you remember what time it was?
I'm sure It was 11:00.
19680...
I was looking at the samurai residences
at Shiominawate...
I was there from about 10:00 until 11...
samurai residences at Shiominawate
I don't have any witnesses,
but I sat in the rest area
thinking up a poem.
Samurai residences at Shiominawate
And did you come up with something?
Yes...
Soft and gently where the sun shines
down upon autumn leaves dance...
This is it...
I don't understand!
From the rest area,
these plants would hide
the autumn leaves from view!
I went for a stroll along the lake
and then went to
the Prefectural Art Museum...
but ll didn't write a poem...
Why not?
Because, on this outing,
I had each of them
write a poem and then
refectural Art Museum
Prefectural Art Museum
I was going to select which one
to use for the start of the linked poe
Prefectural Art Museum
I was going to select which one
to use for the start of the linked poe
No one remembers seeing Ms. Ando...
That's right, that memo pad...
There was stock information written in it...
The page that was torn out,
something must've been written on it
while that person was talking to him!!
Yes, Mr. Ushikubo seemed quite happy.
He jotted it down in his notebook...
I see, thank you very much!
Yes,
no Ml have all the information!
Hmm...
not one of you has a solid alibi it seems...
By the way,
have you found the murder weapon?
We're still searching the area.
And we'll also search the places
you all went to,
so please don't leave Matsue
until I say you can.
All right. 4
I'd like to continue
our linked poetrn session
as a tribute to the late Mr. Ushikubo,
what do you all think...
That's a good idea,
Iet's do it!
The linked poetry session, eh...
What!?
Me join their group!?
Yeah!
You're sharp,
you'd be able to figure out
who the killer is just by watching them
Well, sure, but...
That's a great idea!!
Please do it!
Yeah, okay...
I'm absolutely positive
one of those four killed him...
and we're going to find out
at that poetry session!!
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY
osho Aoyama
PRODUCERS
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY.
Masatomo Sud
Junichi 1 "ka
Junichi hhoka
Kanji Kashiwabara
Kazunari Kouchi
Junichi Miyas 114
Yuich1 Hioure
oshiki Inoue
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
'Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY
Takashi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHI FF DIRECTOR
Kenji Kodama,
PRODUCED BY
TMS Latertainment, Ltd.
Tn 1ssociation with
Yomiuri Telecastine Corporation
DETE IVE CONAN
Gosho AbyémaykShogakukan - YTV - TM
Ail Rights Reserved
Here goes!
XR Catching-the thief will prove to all
that Pam a great detective.
Hannin wo agete miseruto meitantel
All nght, I'm next...
What the future holds
for us god alone knows for certain.
Iki tsuku saki wa kami nomizo shiru
Mr. Yagisawa.
Here
I found it in the lobby just now...