Even destiny serves. as a clue to deduction,
and thetight of truth:pierces through ~*
the most mysterious case.
The Matsue mystery is solved today.
There are so many secrets in the lake.
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the I°Q-"of an adult
with Detective Conan.
Matsue castle
One autumn day
the three of us take a trip to
Matsue city in Shimane prefecture
and at Matsue Spa,
we meet a group of five people
who have come to compose
what is called renku , or linked verses.
The nextiday.
One of their members,
Mr. GozosUshikubo is found murdered
on the Matsue Castle grounds.
His index finger seems to be
pointing to something
and we must find out
what his-dying message is...
I'm positive one of them is the Killer...
and the poetry reading
WI FGVGH WIOI IS.
THE LINKED POETRY INCIDENT
AT TAMATSUKURI IN MATSUE-PART II
Tamatsukuri Spa=
Our haiku gathering will now begin
Tamatsukuri Spa
Tamatsukuri Shirosuna Inn
j P',
RROD LE TR Bx rh
FEB IREE
There will be a total of fourteen poen
this time for our renku composition.
Tamatsukuri Shirosuna Inn
ZT DOA L'S Fx OD& DA
FEIREE
There will be a total of fourteen poen
this time for our renku composition...
Also,
to make it easier for Mr. Mourn,
who is a beginner,
we'll do it with a word game style,
using the last syllable of
the previous word to start the new verse.
A word game? 'Really?
Yes.
There are only a few rules
you have to follow,
other than that.
It's pretty much anything goes.
First,
Reiko Ando
we start with a 5-7-5 poem
for the opening
Reiko Ando
wily 70 ¢
then follow with a 7-7 poem
then another 5-7-5 and so forth.
Reiko Ando
3 OW oo
0 STE RY
then follow with a 7-7 poem
then-another 5-7-5 and so forth.
However,
you have to-be. careful
not to add on to the poem two poen
before yours which is called "uchikos
BIT (
After that,
Ryosuke Shiina
75TH
all you have to do is include
the four seasons
Ryosuke Shiina
FIT (
In some of the fourteen poems.
Ryosuke Shiina
AIT (
in some of the fourteen poems.
In between, we'll include one poem
referring to the moon,
Takumi Yagisawa
NAR 1532)
TOE XA
three love poems
Takumi Yagisawa
NAR T5132)
three love poems
the thirteenth poem will refer to flowe
Mizuki Kawaguchi
NO» >= (27)
Catrh UL La
And the closing poem, will be a poe
about Spring bringing it to a happy en
Mizuki Kawaguchi
nina (27)
& Lari LL La
1 SR 0
and the closing poem, will be a poe!
About Spring bringing it to a happy en
that's all you have to remember.
Uh, sure.»
Oh wow!
Are you sure you can handle it...
Well, let's just start and see.
First: the opening poem,
the.poems you all wrote...
Mr. Shiina's' is
Even. the gods will gather
and gaze upon Deer's Window.
Kamigami mo tsudoi termiru ya
Shika no Mado
Mr. Yagisawa's is,
To the huge turtle a mantis does raise
ax in reverence forsooth.
Oogame Ni kamakiri ga kama furiage te .
Mizuki's is,
Softsand gently.where the sun shine
downrautumn leaves dance.
Yawaraka ki hi ataru hou e momiji mau
and now Mr. Ushikubo's poem,
Ah. Autumn is full I suffice to say,
my life has no sorrow.
AKi taka shi wa ga jinsei ni urei nashi
I think they are all good poems, but...
since this session is dedicated
to Mr. Ushikubo,
I'd like to use his poem as the opener.
We agree.
All right then,
will someone: follow withthe waki"...
Jh, what's a "waki...
It's the second poem.
Like the "hokku",
it contains reference to the season.
Within the silence
I hear a nut falling from the tree.
Shizukasa no naka ima konomi otsu
That's very good.
You interpreted the opener very cleverly.
All right then why don't you go next,
Mr Yagisawa.
Okay.
I wonder if dad will be able to do it.
Hmm...
The guy's about as boorish as can be...
Under the moonlight Dracula
does come to me joining me in vers
Tsukiakari tsugi wa dorakyura
tsukékUshi te"
That's quite amusing.
The use of Dracula,
a very radical character is
very stimulating...
Is that.kind of poem:allowed?
Yes,
for the:third. poem
you can.let-yourself go.
Let your imagination go wild.
Let the imagination...go wild???
Mizuki. it's your turn
Okay.
That text I see there
seems to be made in Japan.
Tekisuto wa meido in Japan
Oh. I think it'd be better to use the word
textbook instead of text.
It's all right if you have an extra syllable.
Okay.
Hmm...
Mr. Mouri!
Y. yes!
Would.you:like:to:give it a try?
Use the last syllablerof the last word
so yourll have to start with a
Pan or:hans word.
Huh!?
All right. I'll try it!!
Hmmm...
Here goes!
Catching the killer will prove to all
that I am a great detective.
Hannin wo age te miseru to meitanter
W: well... what. do:you think?
Et's see.
Great-detective,and .Dracula do
seem to belong to the same realm
whiCh.would bring us
back to the uchikoshi but...
I guess.it's all night.
Phew...
Now it's my turn...
What the future holds for us
god alone knows:for:certain.
IKitsuku saki-wa kami nomi zo shiru
Hem?
Bravo, Ms Ando.
You've subtly challenged the detective.
won't be so easy?
All right then. I'll go next.
U', ru, ru. ru...
Done!
Human-like 'monkey. your face
does remind me. of the girl next to m
Ruijin en:okao ga niteru tonari no ko
Tee heel
Funny, isn't it!
The 7th syllable. O is the main point.
1? What does he mean?
Mr. Yagisawa...
Here...
I found it in the lobby just now.
Oh brother.
I must have dropped it again.
Thank you.
Don't mention it.
See...
You're all so very good!
How's it going. Mr. Mouri?
Well, uh...not very good actually.
3 more poems to go...
we've got to do something soon.
Hey. Miss Mizuki.
Didn't you say you wrote the first poem
while you were looking
at the autumn leaves
at the rest area in the grounds
of the samurai residence
Why...yes...
That's strange.
I went there just a little while ago.
But I couldn't see the leaves
from the rest area.
Is that true. Conan?
Yes!
Oh, uh, ma be...
I saw the autumn leaves
in another location...
Another location?
Where was that?
Uh...well...uh...
Is Mizuki the killer?
If she isn't,
why did she lie like that?
This poem...could it be?
That means she's doing it
for that person...
but,
what did that dying message mean...?
Heh...
so that's what it meant.
But why'd that person
do something like this...
I've got it!
Now I understand!!
Orders from Mr. Mouri for me!?
Yes,
He said not to tell Detective Yasurai,
and he wants you
to investigate something.
All right!
I understand!
If my deduction is correct,
that person is the killer!!
I've got it!
Wh. what do you mean?
I know what
Mr. Ushikubo's dying message is.
He wasn't pointing to the bamboo.
He was pointing to
something beyond that.
? Something beyond the bamboo?
Past the shrubs around the walk way.
And past Horikawa...
That's right!
It's the site of the samurai homes
where Ms Mizuki
went to compose her poem.
Which means you.
Ms Mizuki,
Oil) ad;IreD> Te I er...
Th, that's not true...
Hey Ms. Mizuki!
The 10th poem here, it's a love poem,
Isn't it?
And a one sided one a \that.
Il]/
And another thing. Mr. Yagisawa,
during dinner, you were whistling,
weren you.
Oh...uh huh...
So that's what it is!
Mizuki's in love with Yagisawa!
Fl sees.
So that's why last night. she...
? What about last night?
Mr. Ushikubo said something cruel
to-Mr. Yagisawa last-night.
Ms. Mizuki was watching them
and she looked very worried.
Whoa. wait just a minute.
Are you saying
Oh I get it! Now I understand!!
Ms. Mizuki,
are you trying to protect'Mr. Yagisawa?
Fi What do you mean by that, Mr. Mouri!?
I mean that she was concerned
about whatihappened between
Mr Ushikubo and Mr. Yagisawa last night,
so she changed her plans
and went to Matsue Castle
to see Mr. Ushikubo.
when she got there. she saw...
No. you're wrong!
I saw no such thing!
All I saw was...
Saw what's.
Mizuki...
Mizuki,
I think it'd be better if you told the truth.
But Ms. Ando!
I agree with her.
Oh: I'm sorry if I:sounded.cocky.
if you really do love him .
If you really think he's special...
at first, I had planned to go
to Gessho Temple,
not Matsue Castle...
But I was worried about Mr Yagisawa
the bus going to Matsue Castle
passed-by-and I saw
Mr. Yagisawa in it.
So I'headed:for-Matsué Castle right away
when I got to the walk way,
Mr Ushikubo was already dead.
And...
And at his fingertip. I found...
After that,
I rushed back to the samurai residences
and sat in the rest area
until I calmed down.
Then when it was time
to come back here.to the hotel, I did.
Hey. wait a minute.
Sure, it's true I went to the castle!
But I didn't kill him,
and I didn't go to the walk way either!
Then what part of the castle
did you go to?
To the Shiroyama Inari shrine.
That's where there's a lot of
fox statues. right?
That's where Mr. Ushikubo»
told me to meetéhim
About 30 minutes
after I got to Gessho Temple,
I got an e-mail
from Mr. Ushikubo on my cellular.
It said Come to the Inari shrine
at Matsue Castle right now
It was about:10:05
when I got to the shrine.
I waited about fifteen minutes
but he never showed up,
so I tried calling his cellular
but there was no answer.
There was nothing I could do
so I went back to Gessho Temple,
and composed the poem
about the big turtle.
Then why was your eye medicine
at the scene of the crime?
I don't know...
I'm telling you the truth detective!
If you don't believe me,
check Mr. Ushikubo's cellular.
We've already checked
all the data-on his.cellular.
But there's, no record of
any message to you like you claim!
Th, that's impossible...
How-about his spare cellular?
Mt. Ushikubo said
he always carried a spare in his bag.
We checkedFall his belonging
but there was only one cellular.
Mr. Yagisawal!
You stole Mr. Ushikubo's spare cellular
and sent yourself that message,
didn't you?
No, that's not true!!
Detective Yasugi!
We-found the murder weapon!
What?
We found it in the Ictus pond
at Gessho Temple.
The nightstick was wrapped
in this raincoat,
and the blood on it matched the victimes.
And this raincoat,
Yagisawa!?
That settles it.
Th, that's impossible...
Come on!
You can tell us all about it at the station!
D. detective!
It wasn't me.
You're making a big mistake!
Mr. Yagisawa!
Oh boy. what a poetry composing trip
this has turned into.
Yes...
Lets end today's session...
Good idea.
Excuse me.
I have a poem Id like to contribute.
You're starting with chi next aren't you?
Rm finished!
Yummy chocolate candy hurry
and give me some now.
\ Chiyocoleeto kashi hayaku chodai
NO. mo. No!
That's not what you call a renku!
Not true!
You associated chocolate
candy with ant trail. didn't you?
That's a very amusing
poem befitting a child.
The next one should be a
flower poem. Mr. Shiina., you do it.
Come on! Make a poem starting with I
Make it a pretty one!
All right then!
There!.
Perhaps one fine day together
with my daughter flowery temple.
Itsunohika musume to
futari hananotera
What do you think?
How strange.
It's really strange.
That's the poem Mr. Mouri
read to me just a little while ago See?
Look!!
When did you write that, dad?
Well, uh, I uh...
Ma tsu..e
Ta... ma... tsukuri!
Dad?
the truth is. I didn't write that poem.
Mr. Tomonaga the man
we met in the lobby yesterday
from the brokerage firm wrote it.
Mr. Ushikubo had written it
down in his memo pad
Mr. Shiina...
You were convinced Mr. Ushikubo
came up with it himself. weren't you.
He was such a cruel man,
you couldn't forgive him
for writing such a beautiful poem...
that's why you tore it out of
his memo pad, didn't you.
After you killed him!!
Boom
Your poems had secret messages
n them, didn't they...
The seventh syllable
in the seventh poem,
and the eleventh syllable
in th )eleventh poem
I'm the killer
that was your challenge to me...
You secretly put messages in your poems
mocking both the police and me,
you must have been enjoying yourself.
Judging from your personality.
Given the right conditions
I knew you would use the poem
you stole from Mr. Ushikubo...
I had you pegged.
Because
this is the kind of poem you like...
My favorite poems are
those with feeling
Like how a father feels for his daughter.
The conditions were perfect.
Then when Mr. Yagisawa was
taken away as the suspect in the murder,
The thirteenth poem was a flower poem
so I composed: the previous
poem setting 'things up for you.
So that's why you told Conan
to do the twelfth poem...
That's right...
and just as I'd figured
you used Mr. Ushikubo's poem...
because you were so sure you'd won...
Haha...
the secret message
in the poems was just a joke.
And about that poem,
Mr. Ushikubo showed it to me last night.
Besides. I have an alibi.
An alibi?
That's right.
I just remembered that at about 10:05
I saw a female attendant
at therart museum.
She give a lost boy back to his mother.
Oh that,
you could have set up a video camera
below the hedges there
and then seen it on the tape.
Conan found marks
Ieft behind by a tripod.
When you got
to the art museum this morning.
You set a video camera up
underneath the hedges.
Then you sent an e-mail to Mr. Yagisawa
with Mr. Ushikubo's spare cellular,
which you had stolen beforehand
then you went to Matsue Castle
and killed Mr. Ushikubo.
After that.
You put Mr. Yagisawa's eye medicine
by Mr. Ushikubo's finger.
Went to Gessho Temple to get rid
of the raincoat and murder weapon
then went back
to the art museum: for: the video
then came back to hotel
pretending like nothing happened.
That's a very interesting story. Mr. Mour.
I hate to disappoint you though...
I have the evidence to prove it.
It's Mr. Ushikubo's dying message.
He wasn't pointing
to the bamboo or the samurai residence.
He was making the number 1.
So what's that supposed to mean...
Ran,
what's the first poem in renku called?
Ho, hokku...
Now Detective Tsubaki.
Give us the results from the lab.
Yes sir! w
This is Mr. Shiina's shoe.
The left front hook
on the left shoe,
is where we found a bloody fingerprint,
which matched Mr. UshikubO's right
index finger and it was his blood!
He was telling us to check
your shoe in his dying message!
You were probably
so engrossed with his:memo pad
you didn't notice he touched
your shoe, did you.
I give up Mr. Mour.
You're right
I killed him...
But...
What made you suspicious of me?
The first thing I found strange was
Iast night's drawing of lots.
Usually.
The person who makes the lots draws last
but you went second.
INT AL,
we'll go according to age. so it's me.
You rigged the drawing
so that Mr. Ushikubo would pick a place
that would make killing him easy
and your place would be faraway
giving you an excellent alibi...
Hah...
you're sharp.
No wonder you're the country's
best private detective.
So your motive for killing
Mr. Ushikubojwas...
I couldn't forgive him for lying
and cheating us out of our money
But that doesn't give you
the right to pass sentence on him...
Yes.
I know that...
I know that very well
I know only god can
pass judgement on him...
I guess the god of Izumo brought you
here to teach that to me. huh
ORIGIN 1 COMIC BOOKS BY
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
Mashito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER:DE 1GNS BY
Masatomo Sudo
STORY EDITCR.
Junichi 11cka
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji :Kashiwaiira
Ki1zunr1 Kouchi
Junichr Miyashita
Yuichi Hioure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIMATION DIRECTORS @Qb
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi T1kitani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Tak1sht Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Erumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken]: Kodufilfl
PRODUCED BY
TMS Entertainment. Ltd.
In association with
Yomiuri Telecastine Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Gosho Abyama hshoqaKukan - YTV - TMS
an Rights Reserved
I'm so happy for them...
Magatama
It looks like Mr. Yagisawa
feels the same for Mizuki...
Magatama
It certainly does...
By the way, Ms. Reiko.
The renku's still short one poem.
All right then,
this one will express
my gratitude to Mr. Mouri
and how I feel about Matsue...
Infamous Lafcadio Hearn
miles brightly and Spring arrives
Rafucadeo Haan hohoende haru
Oh that's a wonderful poem.
Isn't it dad!
Lafcalio?
It's Lafcadio Hearn!
Yakumo Koizumi!
Koizumya. oh,
Hahhhhh
Ah hah...
at this rate,
Infamous Lafcadio Hearn
annoyed by you, he springs up
Rafucadeo han akirete haru
would be more appropriate...
Why you do think that thief
chose this old shrine?
I mean, even if he did get
the offering box open,
it doesn't look like there'd be
too much inside. right?
Wh. what happened!?
I wonder...
if that's what it was,
it would explain why it had to be
that place