Even destiny serves
as a clue to deduction
and the light of truth pierces
through the most mysterious case.
Even if you put a lot of money
in the offertory-box,
your prayer won't be answered
if it's for no good
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance with the l1.Q.
of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
At 2:05 AM.
In the middle of the night,
when everyone was fast asleep...
the earth shook violently.
LJ oS =
sect
«Pe 45
Yawn...
Iast night's earthquake was a big one...
Huh
WH. 'What in the world ?
Hey you,
are you all right?
Huh?
The bell...?
Last night's earthquake
must have caused the bell to fall
Nd hit him on the head.
Huh
Someone was trying to break into
the offertory box...
Ah hah!
It must have been this fellow...
Strange Punishment"
Someone tried to steal the offerings?!
Yes,
this morning at Teitan Shrine.
I bet he's really going to be punished.
Listen,
why don't we go and catch the guy!
I'm not finished,
the thief's already been caught...
Eh!?
What do you mean?
Aw shucks...
thenrhe was arrested
by the police, just likefthat .
So you should always-listen to
the whole story Genta.
I guess coincidences
Iike that do happen, huh...
The earthquake struck
while he was trying to steal the money.
Then the "garan garan fell on his head...
nd he got knocked out...
What's 1 s5gara Ygaran'?
Good grief Conan,
that's what they call the shrine bell
didn't you know that?
Don't tell me you didn't even know that.
I don't knowaanybody who says that...
Heaven certainly punished him,
that's why you shouldn't do bad things.
He certainly was an unlucky; thief,
wasn't he?
Yeah, what a loser
Hey. Conan...
Conan?
Why do you think thief chose
this small shrine?
Huh?
What do you mean?
Just look at this place...
hat am I going do...
there's no money for the repairs...
Even if he managed to get
the offertory box open,
it doesn'tylook like there'd be
much inside, does it?
I see what you mean...
I'd understand him trying to rob
Beika Shrine,
a lot more people go to pray there.
Maybe he didn't know
about Beika Shrine.
That's right,
I bet he's from some place far away!
Let's forget about it.
There might be other cases to solve
because of the earthquake!
You're right,
there might be other people
who need our help!
Then we)shouldn't let them down!
Alright)'-
Iet the youth detective league
get to work!!
Let's go!!
Wh, what was that?!
A scream?
Ta, Takeo?!
What's the matter?
Talk to me Takeo!
Takeo!
Takeoisdon't die!
WEG IR
Takeo!!
Genta, call an ambulance!
Okay!
Hang on, Takeo.
Takeo!
I see.
SO you two are getting married
next month.
Yes,
he and I were supposed to go to
our "nakodo's' home today ™
but he didn't arrive
when he said he would
and I tried calling him several time
but there was no answer, that's wh
So you came here
because you were worried...
Yes,
when I got here. he was on the floor
and I was so scared.
How is your head?
Luckily
I suffered jus Va Minor concussion
and the x-rays show no brain damage.
I see...
Then
I'd like to get all the details
Mr. Takenaka.
Please tell me about the attack.
Of course.
I had a meetinghto attend last night
so I got back late, lit was about 2:30 A.M.
after the earthquake.
Oh brother...
what a mess...
That earthquake sure shook things up
this is terrible.
Hey. who're you!!
Stop!!
You're not getting away!
Argh!
Ugh It
Ugh oh...
Oh no.
This can't be happening. is he dead...
I don't believe this!
C..come back here...
you're the saying he ran away
because he thought he killed you?,
Probably...
but I was only knocked unconscious.
What a panicky fellow.
That's the second loser today.
You're so right.
And was there anything stolen?
The 200,000 en
I had in the chest was taken
All he took was the cash?
Yes.
This is going to be difficult...
cash is hard to trace...
Excuse me
does that mean heswon't be caught?
Dont worry. You can rest at ease!
If we find his fingerprints,
he's as good as caught!
He was wearing gloves...
I guess
I'll stant questioning the neighbors first...
Hello Mr. Takag:.
SO it's you, Otani,
what're you doing here?
We're going over the crime scene.
At Teitan Shrine over there.
Oh yes,
I heard about that's
Offertory thief, eh
Rokusuke Urasawa
If Il\ I\TIU \UUI
that's the stupid thief.
He does look stupid.
You shouldn't say such things,
it's not nice.
His name's Urasawa, he lives
on 4th chome just down the street.
4th chome?
He's a real coward
but he just won't stop stealing.
He's been arrested twice
before for breaking and entering.
I guess we've both got
unpleasant work to do
I'm working on a burglary
Huh?
Is something wrong?
Oh, uh...no...
seeings as they've got Tékagu
from the head office on the case.
I'm sure you'll get it
wrapped up in no time.
Well. I've got to be going.
I'll see you later.
I hope he's right...
Huh?!
Uh, yes,
well I'd better go look for witnesses!
I'd really like to help
Detective Takagi solve the case.
Especially since I heard he messed up
Iast time and was punished
Don't worry,
this case is simple, there's no trick to it
isn't that right...
Conan...
Conan?
What are you doing Conan!
I knew it, something's fishy.
What's fishy?
That offertory thief Urasawa...
take a good look at this map.
4th chome is right next to Beika Shrine.
He lives sO close and yet he chose
to rob Teitan Shrine
which farther away and not as popular
it's just not logical, is it?
Who cares about that.
He got punished by heaven for
trying to steal from that old shrine,
so what's the big deal
Punished by heaven?
1jhe~'garanrgaran'.
ey usSua yeon a you now,
even in arrearthquake
I wonder...
if you think about it that way.
Then that'll be reason
enough to choose that place.
And if that is the case...
Where're you going?!
It should be here...
If my theony is right.
It should be somewhere
between there and Tieitan«Shrine!!
What's the matter Conan.
Why dosyou run off like
that all of a sudden?
If found it!
Conan!
Is that what I think it is. 7?
Yes.
Probably.
I'm pretty sure.
They belong.to. whoever: attacked
Mr Takenaka.
Good work Conan! Bravo!
We've got to let
Detective Takagi know right away!
Yes, let's go!
But the money's not here...
and I doubt he has it on him...
See.
Its in there!
Come on-sir hurry, please...
I was going to put some money in
but I threw my favorite badge
in by mistake!
All right. I understand...
I'll get it open soon.
Oh my!!! v
Wh. what in the world?!
There it is!
Thank you very much, sir.
Look at all that, aren't you luck sir!
Th. there's $6 much money in here...
this has never happened before...
What happened, Detective Takagi? *
Yes, there's no mistake about it.
That money was stolen
from Mr. Takenaka's home.
His fingerprints were on them.
I knew it.
And we also found fingerprints
from somebody very unexpected on them.
Who are you talking about?
Urasawa.
That offertory thief is.
So thattmeans he stole money!
What a bad guy.
Waittjust 2 minute, Genta!
Huh
Mr. Takenaka was attacked
at about 2:30, isn't that right?
Yes.
Huh?
But the earthquake was at 2-15, wasn't it?
That's right...
Then at 2:30, that man must have been
unconscious at the shrine by then.
That's right!
The=garan garan hit him on the head
and he should have been
unconscious by then!
That's right...
it's not possible for an unconscious
person to be breaking into another place...
I don't understand it at all...
I just can't figure it out...
I thought it was just a simple burglary...
Detective Takagu...
Detective Takagi, excuse me...
Huh?
Why don't you.ask
Inspector Megure to help you?
I think that would be best...
You...you've got to be kidding.
I can handle a case like this myself,
just you watch!
But...
What do you think, Conan?
Hey? Conan?
Conan?
Yes, Takagi here...
Inspector Megure!
Uh, well,
truth is, Inspector Megure...
I don't want to hear any feeble excuses!
Otani called me just now
and gave me all the details...
Listen Takag:...
This is where you show us
what you can do
don't lose your confidence!
But Inspector Megure
You're a top notch detective.
You just lack self-confidence, that's all
elf confidence...?
That 's/ right
Self confidence!
You) can solve this case. I Khow you can!
Jake pride in yourself Detective Trakagit!
Yes sir!
Good! I'll be waiting to:hear * *
the good news from you!!-«
Inspector Megure!!
Thank:you very much.sir!!
Hey what happened to Detective Takagi?
He's so happy all of a sudden.
He just got a call from Inspector Megure!
He told Detective Takagi to do his best.
You don't say...
Hey Detective Takagi, listen.
What is it?
Are you sure that guy Urasawa
got knocked unconscious at 2:15?
What are you talking about!
That's when the earthquake occurred,
right?
That's when the garan garan
fell and hit him on the head...
But nobody saw it happen, right?
You're right...
we've just got his word for it...
Ah hah!!
That's right...
Okay!
Let's find out what Urasawa was doing
at around the time of the attack!
was the one who attacked Mr. Trakenaka!
Okay!
Urasawa hated to work
Urasawa's apartment
Urasawa's-apartment
RADIX
and he was completely broke.
SO he decided to steal some money...
he walked around looking for
a place to break into...
And then.
He decided to break into
Mr. Takenaka's place...
I wonder why he chose
this house though...
there's so many other houses
around here.
Ho knows...
It was probably
because nobody was home.
But if it was in the middle of the night
iewouecnt NOW ile 1@ ousewasempy
or if everyone was asleep. would he?
Well, that's...
{ He probably just took a chance.
That's right,
who cares about that anyway.
0. it is important...
he must have had a reason...
He must have.
He's right
there's got to be a good reason for it...
I don't get it...
how did Urasawa know no one
was home in Mr. Takenaka's house...
Come on Detective Takagi. think...
Did something happen
in that house at that time...
no. that can't be right, no one was home,
nothing could have happened.
Wait a minute
That's it!
The earthquake!!
Huh
The earthquake occurred just when
Urasawa was passing by the house!
The strong earthquake occurred
in the middle of the night.
It would've woken éverybedy up.
They would have been scared
and turned on their lights.
But only Mr. Takenaka's home
remained dark...
And realizing no one was home,
he broke in...
But while he was looking for
things to steal,
Mr Takenaka came home...
Oh brother...
hat a mess...
did that earthquake do this...
Good grief...
Wh, who's there?!
Come back here!!
You're not getting away!
Aught!
U...uuuu...
1. I don't believe this...is he dead...
this can't be happening!
Urasawa thought he killed Mr. Takenaka,
he panicked and ran away.
He had to find a place to get rid of
the mask and gloves in aJhurry!
He sees the garbage collection area,
so he throws them away there.
So that they wouldn't be found.
Criminals are very nervous
at times like that, aren't they?
I'm-pretty sure they are.
He's actually a very timid man.
And although
he just made the wrong assumption,
thinking he committed murder...
He must have been in a panic.
He knew that the police
would get-high and low
for him now that the charge was murder,
and he didnrt have an alibi...
Alibi?
Alibi...
I'm pretty sure he would have thought...
if only I could come up with an alibi!
That's right!!
GS $ 10 BIN 8 sa3ft
That'sswhen Urasawa.found..it!
He saw the bell on the ground!!
And he decided to make himself
Iook like an offering thief,
he staged it.
What I'm trying to say is.
His goal wasn't to steal the money,
itfwas to get caught trying to stealing it.
That way he'd have an alibi
for the time Mr. Takenaka was killed!
I get it!
Detective Takagi. that was brilliant!
See. you can do it if you try!
But...
Why did he put the money
he worked so hard to steal,
inside the offertory box?
He didn't have a choice.
No one would believe
[he was an offertory thief
if he had 200.000 yen in his pocket.
Oh, I get it...
And besides. maybe...
I just killed somebody.
But I don't want to stay in prison
for who knows how long.
Please,
oh please God.
Please help me!!
Maybe he prayed to God for help.
Prayed to God-7?
It's possible!
She's right, he might have.
It just goes to prove
how: desperate he was.
And then he...
It went exactly like you said...
Detective Takagi!
What you're saying Urasawa
is that you tried to hide one crime
by committing another crime, is that it?
Other people would think
the same thing wouldn't they?
I mean it's much better to be arrested
for something small like minor theft
than to be arrested
for something big like murder...
don't you think...?
You idiot!!
Sorry.
Listen to me Urasawa...
There's no such thing
as a small crime or a big crime!
A crime is a crime and
the perpetrator shall always be punshed!!
Yes, you're right...
I'm sorry...
ORIGINAL COMIC BOOKS BY.
Goshp Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
ICh111 0 uw?
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER ESIGNS*BY.
MasatohiflSufio
STORY EDITOR.
[UNICEF Imlm
SCRIPTS BY
Kanji Kashiwalara
Kizunari Kouchy
Junichi Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
ANIM TION DIRECTORS &
Misatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi Takatani
Harup Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR.
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Tak1sht Nomur
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Kenji Kodam Ty
PRODUCED BY,
TMS [ntertainment, Ltd.
In 1ssociation with
Yomiuri Telecastine Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Go§hoAoyama/eshogakukan - YTV - TMS
&.! Rights Reserved
Hey Takagi!
Inspector Megure!
I hear you did a good job
solving the case.
Inspector Megure!
I've gained a lot of confidence
from this experience,
I know I can do my job well!!
I. I'm glad:to hear that...
I owe 1t}all to you,
you always encouraged me!!
Huh???
I'll be seeing you InspectoriMegure!
Excuse me!!!
What was that 4
Takagi talking about anyway,
I don't get it...
Don't be shy, you thoughtful boss you.
It's not bad.
Hey.
Do you think that guy forgot all about us
and went to go eat with his friend?
I don't believe it
No. I don't think he forgot.
Most likely...
he got himself mixed up in something...
VEG.
Look at this strap!!
Eh!?
Next case is...