Even destiny serves as a clue'to deduction
and the light of truth pierces through
the most mysterious case.
Today's case is a very strange kidnapping.
Understanding English is very hard.
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the: I=Q.of:antadult,.
No case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
With
NAT QPS
Boy what a terrific shew!
The animals were $0 cute.
That white lion's act was especially good!
Well. that lion is the!star of the show...
Oh and look!
That lion's also on this«strap!
I really like that!!
Cute. isn't it... .before the show started,
Ail and I saw it at the souvenir shop
so we both bought one, didn't wel!
Oh. uh huh.
Oh. uh huh...
Oh real"
T&idn't think you liked things like that...
Well
I'think it's a whole lot healthier
than someone who reads bloody
mysteries day in and day out without fail...
Don't you think?
Just leave me alone...
Hum?
Who's.that guy
surrounded by:all those, people... . 4)
Huh 2?
He's the man
who sponsors the animal show
that's Randy Hawk!
He's from Oklahoma,
a southern state in the United States.
He struck it rich in oil and
he started collecting animals as a hobby,
but then his son Paul and daughter Annie
also becam. interested in animals
and now they take
their animal show all over the world.
That's right!
See...
His picture's on the last page
of the pamphlet.
Recently. his hobby is travelling
around the world with Kits show.
and going to the zoo in each country... ¢
According to him,
he says. We've been cowboys
AY NN  Ll NN ° OC «Ny No
OT yeneiduon>. O we prote It ourselves
that's why he doesn't take bodyguards
with him when he travels
I heard him say it on television!
He speaks Japanese very 'well...
Mr Hawk!!!
Could we have a comment please...
Mr. Hawk! Mr. Hawk!
You've made a mistake...
My name isn't Hawk...
Oh come on, you can't fodl us...
Is it true that you're donating
half the Pp oceeds of your show
to zoos all overt e world?
You haven't been toe Japan
in three years, how does it feel?
Please say something!! Mr. Hawk!!
Mr. Hawk!? Mr. Hawk!'?
I can't answer all your questions
at the same time!
BES KRToEMIIC
TREADS AN
[THE MAN FROM CHICAGO-PART I]
My oh my...
he doesn't look anything
Iike a tough cowboy now...
Oh who cares...good for him...
I have to hide and look behind
my shoulder all the time
because I can't afford a bodyguard.
He 'brought this upon himself:
AW come on...
Don't be like that. let's go help him out
that cowboy looks like
he was raised in high-society
and surrounded by a herd of cows,
he doesn't know what to do...
Listen...
I've been trying to tell you that I...
Oh there you are! Uncle Thomas!
Uncle Thomas?
He's not Mr. Hawk?
No...
He's a friend.of my grandfather's,
he's an English teacher.
Yes, that's right.
Come on, let's go Uncle Thomas!
You promised we were all going
to have lunch at a restaurant!
Come on...hurry!!
Thank you veryimuch!
You kids were a big help!!
I get mistaken.for Mr. Hawk a lot
but I've never been
in that Kind of situation before!
en you s 10U ¢ ¢ 1sguise yourse
when you go out...
That would just make things worse!
Do you like Paul and Annie's
animal show that much...
Oh yes!
Their show is the best!
And besides
huh?
I wanted this so badly.
That's why I came all the way to Japan!
Oh. we bought that one too!
But that strap's popular around-the world,
It's sold everywhere...
you didn't have to come to Japan for it...
No. no... look at the back of the strap!
It says In Japan'. doesn't it?
This istthe only place you can get-it!
SO it's a collector's it
However...
that incident back there was
very, very unfortunate!!
I didn't get to meet my friend,
we were supposed
to meet after the show!
Did you happen to see
a man with long hair?
I don't think sO...
After all. that. place was packed...
Oh...
and you're very astute...
how did you-know he wasn't Mr. Hawk...
It's the way he talked...
The way he talked?
What!?
Mister,
back there you pronounced
the word can't as count, didn't you?
That's the Queen English...
If you came from a long line of cowboys,
then there's no way a man from the South
would have an English accent
it just seemed unnatural!
Now that you mention it,
the Mr. Hawk I saw on TV had
a strong Southern draw!
And spoke rather loudly...
I looked at the picture
in the pamphlet very carefully
and saw it was completely different!
But then
I don't blame the Japanese reporters
for making that mistake...
Like Westerners can't tell
one Oriental from the other.
We Orientals can't tell
one Westerner from another
if they have the same hair
and skin coloring...
FL OCGa<
RE HEERSIPN
How perceptive of you!
SULLY
Vie Dad
REIMER
SULLY
£& VL O0a<
RUHR INEN
My name us James Black!
My name is James Black!
IXALKX-TS ID
James Black
ITA IX-TovD
IxAILX "TS v2
What's yours?
James Black
IXTALX TS ID
Conan Edogawa...
I'm a private investigator!
Conan... Edogawa?
Private investigator?
Conan's not the only one!
We all belong to the same group!
That's right!
(Fell
Oh!! Sherlock Holmes!
Then you kids must be
the Baker Street Irregulars!!
Ho, Holmes used some kids
who lived on Baker Street
to gather information for him,
that's what they were called!
Ewe .
I was born on Baker Street.
I know!
Let's have a celebration
in honor of my meeting up
with the Baker Street Irregulars!
I'll treat you to a superb lunch
at a great restaurant I know.
Wow!
Did you come by car?
NrCSo
but there's so many people
I don't think there's room for you...
No problem!
We'll use the van I rented!!
I'll bring it around. please wait here! )
But unlike lunch,
my driving isn't very good!
You'll have to drive!
Driving cars with the handles
on the right is most difficult!
Mister,
what do you mean
you can-t drive right handed Icars...
Does that mean
you're not living in England now?
That's right!!
I was born in London...
but I was raised in Chicago...
AMRD Lyre
The windy @I
where AliCapone stormed...
FIND
The windy city
where Al Capone stormed...
MRD LIell/g
Hey»
don't you feel something about that guy?
No. not really...
I see...
guess it's all right then...
Excuse me sir...
We're with the police...
IS this your car?
Y, yes...
this is the car I'm renting...
I see
Actually, this is a stolen vehicle.
Oh not!
It was reported stolen a week ago...
Could you tell us where you rented it
and give us:the details...
We'd also like your name and the name
of the hotel you're staying at...
Rather than stand here
in the middle of the street,
Why. don:tjwe go to the police car
on the other side of the alley...
Do you mind?
We won't take up too much of your time...
Huh?
What's the matter!? *
please get in...
Oh...
I just remembered
I have friends waiting for me!
May I go-and tell them I'll be late?
Huh!)
Get in...
What!?
Shut up and get in the car!!
Huh!?
What is it?
The guy dropped something...
It's just a strap...
Okey! Let's get going.
All right!
Ouch!
Look what you did. I cut my finger...
Good grief...
what a bother.
Y. you men...
You're not really police offiers,
are you?
Be quiet...
You're just a cowboy wanna be
that:come into a lot of money...
No. you're wrong!!
I. I'm not...
You made your money by whipping
poor defenseless animals...
We just want you to share it with us...
That's strange...
40 minutes...have gone by already...
He's so lété...
I wonder what-he's doing...
I'm so hungry.
Ome on,
Doctor Agasa an wait here,
the rest of us will go check on him!
Good idea.
Thére aren't that many parking lots
(around here in walking distance...
Ail, come with us!
Okey
Sure...
I wonder if this is the place...
Mr. Black! Mr. Black!!
Hey, .are you in here?
Oh...we're-not looking for-cats...
Mr Black!
"Found it!
I'm sure this is it!
This is his car.
ee eres as u ec ion
by the driver's seat...
But...there's nobody inside.
The door was left open...
the key are still inside...
Hey you guys!
You looking for somebody?
If it's the foreigner with the beard,
he was going to get inside the car
but went that way
with two guys wearing coats!!
Ehh!?
Hum?
Oh!? Hey Conan!!
Conan.
Rat's the matter?
Hey! Did you find him?
Co. Conan?
it's @ lion Strap, isn't it...?
I wonder if it's Mr.Black's...
If it is .
This is where he probably got
into another car...
He did say he was suqpbssédl to mes'? I
a friend .didn't he...
do you think that guy forgot all about us
and went to go eat with his friend?
I don't believe it.
No, I don't think he forgot.
Pn my
Most likely...
He got himself mixed up in something...
Look at this strap!
Eh!?
The P & A have been smeared
with blood.
Maybe
he was trying .to leave us a mesage
because he thought we might come
to look for him...
don't, ou think so?
Ehh!?
Th, that's terrible!!
We've got to call police...
She's right!
But...
what?
Don't get it.
Why the P & A...
It was so easy!
Now all we've got:to:do.is
see how much this moneybag's
son and daughter will dish out for him...
I'm thinking 5 million at least...
After all this guy has
SO Much money to spare
he gives it away to all kinds of zoos...
Oh well...
we can thank you
for fixing this car up to look:like
areal cop car not to mention...
Mr. Hawk here...
Who thinks he's some tough cowboy
and wonders around without
a bodyguard to protect him
You've made a mistake!!
I'm not Hawk!!
My name's James Black!!
You've got the wrong man!!
James?
First a cowboy. now; you're
an English secret agent?
Huh 2
No. not!
Oh, you mean James Bond!!
Never mind...
That's not important.
I just want you to keep your mouth shut
until we get to our hideout...
heh...
Mr. 007...
Just you watch...
how we snatch the ransom...
our plan's beautiful...
RIZLVOE
I don't want to see...
RrrLyoRx
I don't want to see.
SET LYE
I don't want to see...
WILDE
'Plat?
how you play out your plan.
How?!you play out your plan. .
2]: FAI». oELY
BAD FEHL OILY
What. Ni?
Pay attention
I've been trying to explain...
he's a foreigner and
he has glasses and beard...
he's teen involved
In some accident or something!
He might have been
kidnapped or something!!
But boys...
you didn't actually see him
being kidnapped. did you?
Besides...
There are a lot of foreigners
with beards and glasses.
We wouldn't know where to begin...
It would be easier...
if you had a picture or something...
I've got a picture!
Hum.»
If you need a picture!
Here!
This is how he looks!"
this is Randy Hawk!
If this is the guy. he's safe!
I just heard him talking on the radio...
No. you don't undersrand!
James Black looks just like Randy Hawk!!
Listen...
was tr at radio program a live broadcast?
Yes,
that's right...ll think he's still on...
vy) .
Es, more wan I ey...
Pat's not good...
if the men kiddnapped Mr.Black
thinking he was Randy Hawk,
they'd probably listen to
the radio program
he Wa supposed to be on,
wouldn't they?
Oh no!
Then they're bound to find out the truth...
after they find out
they've got the wrong man...
they'll probably kill him...
Hey. wait a minute!!
What is this!?
And I'd like all of you
to continue supporting Paul and Annie...
and of course, me, Randy Hawk.
Whyss Randy Hawk
on a livefradio show!!
Th, then WW the helllrehyou-h!
That's what I've been trying to tell you...
you've got the wrong Person...
Oh No! Now what!
Aw come on!
What're we going to do?
The guy's seen our faces!
All we gottado is Kill him!!
That's alll!
Don't do it!
What do you intend to do,
drive all over town
with a bloody corpse in the car?
We'll blow his brains out like...
We planned when we got
to-the mountains in Gunma...
and after his grave's been dug...
we'll figure out another plan...
okey?
NO big deal...
we'll just do like we planned
we won't get caught...
the cops have noidea who we are
and besides...
they wouldn't have a clue
as to why some foreigner
would get kidnapped.
ORIGIN 1 COMIC BOOKS BY
Goshp Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CHARACTER DESIGNS BY
Masatomo Studd
STORY EDITOR.
Jumchiligka.
SGRIPTO BY
Kanji Kashiwabar
Kazunari Kouchi
Jumchir Miyashits
Yuichr Hioure
Toshikl Inoue
ION DIR
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshi1 Takatani
Harup Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIRECTOR.
Yukihiro Shbutini
DIRECTORS OF PHOTOGRAPHY.
Takishi Nomura
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Kenji KOdarmay
PRODUCED BY
TMS E=tertainment, Ltd.
In association Cath
Yomiuri Télecastine Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
Goshb Abyama / Shoqakukan - YTV - TMS
all Rights Rcsorvpd
Listen,
doesn't something strike you as odd?
What're you trying to say?
I feel something
Iike something's calling me
We've got to get this guy's on scene
investigation done by sun down...
Good work! Ayumi!
I've figured it out...
1 know where MmiBlack is!