The heart contains mysteries,
stars and snow-sparkle for the two
Ayumi:s-idea breaks the code
who is the person full of mystery?
He sees through to the one
and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the 1<Q. of an adult.
Ne case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Gosho Aoyama / Shogakukan ° YTV TMS
All Righte Reserved
The gang and I went tossee
Paul and Annie's Animal Show"
After tH SW
we went outside and saw.
A man named James Black
in trouble having been mistaken for
someone else so we went to his rescue.
Later.
Mr. Black went to get his Car
to take us to a restaurant
but he simply disappeared...
Ieaving behind his blood stained strap.
[THE MAN FROM CHICAGO-PART II)
P. PEA?
Uh...
what does ittmean? Id
It-was on the ground.
Hm sure it's a message from Mr. Black
telling us about the kidnappers!
Look!
There's blood on the P
and the & and the A
Well, first things first
We'll take back to the station
and check to. see if it's real blood...
Come back to the policelbox tomorrow!
H, he...
Rats...
If we only knew
what he meant by that P & A
Maybe he. meant P & A together,
to make pa...
Maybe he meant the-name of a shop?
You know, like panya (bakery)!
NO...
If he was in trouble and
he wanted to get pa across.
He'd have smeared blood
on the "Pa" in Paul.
I think we should think of
the P and the A separately...
Hmm...P and A. P and A...
Pink and ..Aka(red)
Pro wrestling, anman
(breadifilled with beanfjam)...
Personal computer. access...
Pistol and assassin...
Come on.
Maybe Ne meant panking area!! ,
Ah. a parking lot!!
Yeah.
But: we don't know which parking lot!
Wait until I finish...
maybe he was trying to tell us
he left a clue at the parking lot
his car was parked «~
Yes...
I thought the same thing so I checked
the place out but I didin't find anything.
Oh, I see...
Rats .
Just can figure it out.
Ikguess we don't have any other choice
except to ask around this neighborhood
with he assumption
they're still in the area!
All right!
Let's all split up and ask around
the neighborhood
, to see if anyone saw two men take
a foreigner. a way!
If youslearn something.
- Contact the others with your badge!!
Okay!
oh oh...
What's wrong. Ayumi?
I can't find my badge.
You're kidding
Maybe you) droppe I it some place.
I don't understand...
it was here when
I showed it Mr. Black.
Oh. Sherlock Holmes!
I think Mr Black
might still have my badge!
Eh!?
Are you sure!?
Yes,
pretty sure...
Then the transmitter built inside it...
will give us his location...
e There they are! O
16kilomaters
north-north east from here...
they're mo ing north along Temuzu Rivers
and Ikumo Highway
judging by the speed,
they're in a can...
They're in a car?
On the Ikumo Highway?
Heading north...?
All set...
now that we know that much...
What!?
Are you serious...
you want me to put up a roadblock on
Ikumo Highway at the Saitama border!?
You're asking the me to do
E IMpossiH» eé .anan.
I can't order a roadblock on
unsubstantiated information. like that...
But that man might get killed
iffyou don't
@h. uh. but nonetheless
Hey!?
Conan. is that your.
This is Sato...
there was a.t affic accident %
in that area just now
and Yumi is handling the traffic...
I can ask her to check
for-suspicious cars.
That shouldn'tre any problem!!
Height, 180...
an American of English descent about
50 to 60 years old, beard and glasses...
Look for the car he's in, right?
Got it!
I'll tell her to stop the car if she sees it...
The kidnappers might be armed?
Yes...okey.
Don't worry!
Takagi'and I will.go there right now!
Et? MM, me too?
What's the big deal!
We'veigot nothing to do
untilPlater tonight...
I besides. whenever:.that kid gets involved,
things. get interesting...
Okay!
We're Reading there too,
Doctor Agasa.
Please bring the car around!
After all, we're the only ones
who can identify Mr. Black!
All right, I,understand!
Listen,
doesn't something strike you as odd?
Mr-Black was brought here through
the alley by two men...
and then transferred into another car...
it would mean he had to cut himself
on the finger and leave the blood code
while he was walking through the alley,
isnt that right?
Yes...
I guess so the man must
have threatened him with a gun
While TO was in the parkiing lot
he must've put the blood on the strap
when they weren't watching.
Or maybe...
he went with them willingly knowing
full well they were up to no good
and left us that message...
What're you trying to say?
I feel something.
Like something's calling me...
Aren't you over reacting?
I hope you're right...
Hey: 166)
Did you see that!?
Did yo Wsee who was driving that car!!
No...
it went by too fast.
Oh...
A foreigner...
a foreigner...
Iet's see
A foreigner...
Excuse me...
Yes?
I hate to ask O
buticould you let us:through?
We've got to get this guy on the scene
investigation done by sundowm...
Sow-you're working a case...
Yes...nothing major.
The guy's small time,
he wrecked his girlfriend's house,
that's all...
No problem! Go on ahead!
We really appreciate this...
Where was I!!
Look for a foreigner.
a foreigner...
What!?
You didn't see them...?
Are you sure!? 4
You know he's a foreigner?
Yes...
I didn't see a single foreigner...
What do) you think happened, Conan?
/henexs the car now?
They're on the move
about 8 kilometers from here
but my batteries are running low...
I don't get it though
how'd they get past this ma? blocld?
If that guy's got one of our badges.
All we have to do is ask hinnyYwhere he) is,
The kidnappers will hear us beeping him!
I guess we have to figure out
what that P & A means...
There's a possibility that it's referring
to where they're headed.
I've got it!! Parfait and anmitsu (jelly like
dessert). so maybe a restaurant!
How about perm and afro
referring to a beauty salon!
Can't you guys think
a little more seriously!
How about this then!
Let's Tae
pelican and ashika (seal) for zoo!?
You know
since rr. ac I es animas.
You're wrong!
If he meant zoo.
He'd have put blood on the word animal
on the title Animal Show...
Aha 1!
So that's whalit La ven
Nice going Ayumi!
Eh!?
I figured (Rout...
I know where Mr. Black is!!
Eh!?
The kidnappers are...
in a police car!?
I. I don't believe it. it can't be...
It's true, it's true!
If we don't go after them before it
get dark, we'll lose them!
Yumi!
What happned?
Did you get the kidnappers
Conan was telling us about?
So...wheresare the kidnappers?
Well, uh...
they're saying that
the)men are in a car...
What!?
Uh, huh!
A police car!?
That's right!
The message Mr.Black for us,
the PP & A" it stands for police car!
I still don't understand...
why does P & A stand for police car?
Take the and symbol (&),
spell it out and connect to the P & Al
Let's see PP & A...
PP. AND. A...
P.AN DA?
That's it, panda!!
Aha! A police car is black and white!
The same as a panda! I get it...
Conan, you're so smart!!
I see what you mean...
there are some police officers in Japan
that refer to the police cars as pandas
didn't you say the victim is
an American ofiEnglish descent?
It's: hard to imagine a foreigner
would know
argon Japanese police officers use...
And besides..t doesn't necessarily
have-to-be a police car,
it could be a round,
white car withblack tires and rims
that would make you.think of
a panda tooywouldnst ite
Maybe...
IN ac. xa wou ¢ re more panca
Iike to a foreigner than a police car
No. the victim James Black
was raised in London, that's why
he would visualize a panda!
A long time ago.
Police cars in England were
painted black and white too!
In 1965. the police department in
Lancaster, England was the first to paint
black and white and
they gave them the nickname panda.
The nickname stuck and in England, +
police cars are known as pandas'g.
The word panda car is
ven listed-in-the English.dictionary!
I don't think the younger generation
would know that though. but
Mr James's generation would immediately
associate police car with panda!
What generation are you, anyway?
Uh, just remembered.
I let-a-police cargo
through-without checking-it...
Bull don't think there was
a foreigner inside...
The officer in the car!!
Didn't he seem strange?
Let's see...
there were two detectives,
the suspect was in the back seat
sitting between them,
his head was covered with a coat...
That's them!!
That was so easy! So easy!!
We:re right on schedule
we'll be: deep in the mountains
of Gunma by nightfall!
You were right,
your plan's working out perfect...
We can't let our guard down yet...
Didnst you think it was.strange?
That female cop was
just supposed to be directing traffic
but she looked into each and every car.
Hey. you :don't think...
the cops are already on:to us...
There's nothing to worry about.
We've got a hostage...
We've got to be prepared for anything
SO keep your gun"pressed«to
this guys throat...
and if they set up another
roadblock or something...
We're going to crash-our way through.
Uh, Sato
we re going to be in big trouble...
We've entered Saitama prefecture!
We've already asked the Saitama police
to set Up a roadblock...
we don't have to keep going after them...
Aren't you worried. Trakagi?
Yumi's checked that police car once.
They might have figured out already
that their cover's been blown
so they might use their hostage as a
shield and break through the roadblock...
another thing. when Yumi looked inside,
she said the hostage didn't move at all...
so there's a high possibility
the kidnappers are armed!
At a minute...
If they have guns and
they see a roadblock,
they might start shooting at everything in
sight...the city's going to be in a panic!!
That's why I've been trying to think
up a plan where we can surround
the kidnappers without them knowing
and then take them in...
but then we'd need a miracle...
No. I think there's a way!
Conan?
The kids detective badge?
Sorry! I put it in your car
when you weren't looking!
And where are you now?
Abouti500 meters behind -that:car!
So what:re-we going to do?I've got
a great plan, do you want to try it?
The only thing is. this plan'll work only
if a lot of other police officers go along.
With. my crazy idea...
Good grief. what's the matter with me,
what am I doing way out here...
Yumi? You following me?
Yes. I am...do I have a choice...
I mean. I made a mistake and
Iet those kidnappers get away-
Yumi, weren't you in
charge of all the arrangements
when we had that get together with
the Saitama police the other time?
Yes. I was...
Another red light.
On't get impatient...
just drive normally and we won't draw
any attention to ourselves...
we'll be safe once it gets dark...
Oh crap, it:sithecops!!
I guess they:refon.totus!!
Come on!! Get going!!
We'll make a run for it,
we'll use him as a cover!!
Yeah, okay!!
Help me sail!
Wh. what's going on?!
Officer
Please help us!!
Um. excuse me!
Rm Takagi from headquarters!
Please help us apprehend that kidnapper!!
Sh. donstmake a sound...
All right.
We'll go along with them for a little while
then turn off into a side road
when the coast's clear!
Got you!
Good they fell for it!!
Well? Is it working?
Uh...just fine! It's going justine!
Don't worry about it...
Get ready...
We're going to;turn into a
side roadfsoon...
Hey!! Why re you going so slow?
They're going to get away!
If you can't turn left, turn into the right!
There's another one onthe right...
Allright then we'll go back!!
Slow down and then back up...
It's no good...
there's another one behind us too...
Wh, what?!
Oh man! We re-completely
surrounded by cops!!
Oh man! We're completely
surrounded by cops!!!
Nice going, Irregulars...
or should I say Holmes...
Damn the cops. they set us up!.
Humph, never mind!!
We've got a hostage!!!
It's no use
when someone gives the signal...
all the cars will stop at once...
LvotWC TL -FEDNT
By the time the kidnappers
regain their balance
Put your hands up!!
Ill?
Your method was a little rough
but it worked out perf ct...
You're a real cool guy...
I want to thank,all of you!
You really helped us out!
Don't mention it! This was an easy job!
By the way, about our next get together...
I'll handle it!!
I'll round up all the pretty
single ones from headquarters.
I don't care,
as long as Miss Sato's there...
Me too.
Hey. Yumi?
Where's the victim. James Black?
He was right here just awhile ago...
where'd he go?
I knew something was
strange about that guy...
He disappeared before
the police could¢question him. =
I just "now there's something behind this.
You think sof
He seemed like a pretty nice guy to me...
Only his name struck me as odd...
His name?
You don't mean because it was Black?
No...James...
Really?
There's James Bond, James Dean...
I.get-a=pretty good image
from that name...
Professor James Moriarty...
The Napoleon of the criminal world.
Holmes' arch rival,
Professor Moriarty.
James is his first name!
I guess only a Sherlockian
ould think of that though...
After all, James is a common name!
Es, suppose so...
Something else bothers me
more though
The man who was
Iooking at us from that car...
he was one of the passengers
on the bus that got hijacked...
I'm positive
he said his name was Sryichi Akaiwhe 1
he was questioned by the police...
ORIGINAI~SCOMIC BOOKS BY.
Gosho Aoyama
PRODUCERS.
Michihiko Suwa
Masahito Yoshioka
BACKGROUND MUSIC.
Katsuo Ono
CITARNAUITLN DLOTWUINOYD 1 ,,
Masatoinofiudb;
STORY EDIT( R.
Junichi hdka
CRIPTS BY.
A I Kashiwabara
Advunari Kouchi
u chit Miyashita
Yuichi Higure
Toshiki Inoue
TION DIREC
Masatomo Sudo
Hirotoshir Takatani
Haruo Oogawara
Atsushi Aono
Akio Kawamura
Takashi Hyodo
ART DIR LL TOR
Yukihiro Shibutani
DIRECTORS OF PH TQOLRAPHY.
Takishi Nomuri
Hironobu Horikoshi
Takahisa Ogawa
RECORDING DIRECTOR.
Katsuyoshi Kobayashi
EDITOR.
Terumitsu Okada
CHIEF DIRECTOR.
Ken) Kodam
PRODLIC LP BY.
TMS Effertainment, Ltd.
Mn association with
Yomiuri Yelecastino Corporation
DETECTIVE CONAN
GosHwAoyama /4Shogakukan - YTV - TMS
All Rights Reserved
That was something...
Leaving a code like that
when you were taken by surprise...
When'd you realize
they weren't real cops?
When they spoke to me in Japanese,
it was as if they knew I understood.
If they were detectives
and if they knew I was a foreigner
who could speak Japanese.
Then they'd have confirmed
my name in the very beginning.
That's what tipped me off...
I thought they knew who I really was
but were pretending not to,
that's what made me suspicious...
Oh well, it seems it: was
a case of mistaken identity though...
But what a surprise.
I never thought you'd cut off
your long hair.
Want to change my luck...
My girlfriend keeps leaving me...
Is that so?
You went out of your way
to get me here.
So does that mean you have a
chance of getting back with her?
Sort of...
I want to get back AT her.
For dumping me...
I want her to cry-tears,of blood™...
Why's there blood here?
Wow...there'll be no sleep tonight,
the mystery's got to b Solved...
So that's the answer, incredible!
The next case
takes place in a mysterious restaurant.