Heart, contains, myster.
Starsrand¥snow:sparkie'for'the-two.
Naniwa is the stage for
a tag team match of Conan and Heiji
He sees through the one and. only truth,
a child in appearance with the I.Q. of an«adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
OSAKA DOUBLE MYSTERY
THE NANIWA SWORDSMAN AND
HIDEYOSHI TOYOTOMI'S CASTLE
Naniwa Chuo Gymnasium
Ried kui
Strike to the mask match is over!!
/Nice going That's 3 wins and 1 draw,
he qualifies for the preliminaries!!
Wow: all the members on
Kano High SThoolrs team this year is strong
they're undefeated so far
in the group competition!
Mrs. Hattori! Bonst get all worked upp
until. you're seen.our captain!
Hell's gottentstronger than a demon!
Oh. is HeijiKaiho High's captain...?
He doesn't tell us anything at home.
Kaiho High School team captain,
come forward!
Yes sirll
Eh.2?! That's not Heiji!
Isn't that him over there?
Over there... surrounded by all those girls
and talking up a storm...
Hey, Haijil!
What the heck are you doing,
goofing off over here for!!
The match has already started!
You've\got to hurry!
You're pale...
Huh?
Uh. hello...
I know you, you're a sophomore,
aren't you?!
Heiji asked to cover for him.
He said that we probably wouldn't need him
until the semi-finals
so he told me to put his gear-on
and just intimidate the other team
But Heiji's so popular
so all the girls flock around me
when they see his name on the uniform
So where did Hey go?
I think he-went to the toilet
alssaw him-heading-toward
the other building
Iisten up,
I'm going to tell you one more timc
Annex
To(get to the
Naniwa Chuo Gymnasium,
Annex
To get to the
Naniwa Chuo Gymnasium,
take the bus headed for Tojir
and get off at the 7th stop.
If you don't know which bus, ask the dr -r.
Ask them which gymnasium is holding
the Kinki Kendo Competition that
Heiji Hattori's competing in. they'll know!
Yeah okay. I. got it.
I'm not a little kid,
you don't have to keep reminding me!
Oh, sorry
You look like a little kid so I forget...
Just don't call me anymore!
I'm havingta hard time getting away
from-Ranyand the old man!
And another thing. we're going to Osaka
cause you invited us to a tetchiri dinner
since we didn't get to eat it the last time
or the time before that at your place....!
The only reason we're going to
watch you compete'is. it's on the same day!
You always give me the cold treatment.
By the way,
this bullet train just left the station
sO it'll be past 2-00 when we get there...!
Won't your match.be over by then?
Don't worry about it!
The semi-finals don't start until 2:00pm.!
You'll make it in time for the finals!
Oh. 4 okay...
So I'll be waiting to see you!
Kazuha?!
What are you doing in there?
That's what I'd like to ask you!
This"is the men's toilet. you know!
Oh really. I didn't notice that!
I thought it was a hiding place for cowards
who didn't want to compete.
I'm planning my moves!
So-that I can beat that guy in the finals!
B that-guy. are you talking about
that-guy that looks just like Kudo...?
That's right! Okita
from Senshin High School in Kyoto.
Last year, he got me with jabs to the neck,
I'm going to pay him back
for this scar behind my ear!
Just because he beat you before,
don't you think you're being kind of snea ?
Don't be stupid! He didn't beat me!
I got cut on the neck
when I dod - ed the 'ab,
and when it wouldn't stop bleeding,
t @ doctor stopped the match.
Besides, the guy skipped
the first and second match,
he was sleeping behind the gym
and then he took me on!
You-don't have to worry about him,
you can: beat him!
You brought your luc « charm. didn't you?
That's not the only reason I skipped
the first and second matches though...
Truth is...it's my right hand...
remember what happened on Bikuni Island...
It's so itchy, it's driving me crazy!
I can't concentrate on the match!
Oh. 1s that so? Fine!
I'm going to have a talk with your mother.
And have herbeat
some heart and soul into you!
Mom's here?
Hey, Kazuha. wait!
What's the matter with you?!
You idiot!!
O.--that wasn't me...
Did you say you can't compete because
yourhave-azhangover?!
I couldn't help it.
Atsushi Tarumi
The company that informally
promised to hire me went bankrup
ARR T Arn
AtSUsHi Tarumi
I was so floored. I had to have a drin
AtSUshi Tarumi
You blockhead! You should have thou t
about the consequences!!
Mineo @motani
Let's all settle down...there's still
over an hour left in the competition...
NbfiyuéfiDogdchu
Let's all settle down...there's still
over an hour left in the competition...
He's right. .let's all calm down
and come up with a plan!
Takashi Kotegawa
He's right...let's all calm down
and come up with a plan!
I'll tell everybody about you know what...
What did you say?!
Unlike the rest of you
who allthave jobs waiting,
Irve got nothing to lose!
I don't know what you're talking about,
but...
if you don't want to compete, then
we'll just have to send in one of the seniors
although they aren't as good as you.
We can't have the whole team
be embarrassed just because of you
we can't have the whole team
Masamichi Hakamada
be embarrassed just because of you
For a guy who stole another guy's girlfriend,
you sure talk big!!
You're a fool...
she made up her own mind to leave you.
I didn't steal her away.
Listen you, I think you'd better sober up
and start thinking about
how to get rid of that chip on your shoulder,
and what you're going to do
with the rest of your life
I'm going to Kill you...
What're you doing Heiji? Come on. hurry!
Yeah, okay...
Chest jab, point!!
Yes!! Good move!!
Hey. I can't find Tarumi anywhere!
Maybe he went home?
You guys go look around there.
Okay
Hey! Why aren't you paying attention
to the match!!!
Go and score those points fast...
Make it to the best four!
Annex
Did you find him?
Pl aE
No, he wasn't in the toilet
or the fencing hall!
Pl eE
No, he wasnst in the toilet
or the fencing hall!
Anncx
No. he wasn't in the toilet
or the fencing hall!
Oid you look in"the storage room?
No. not yet...
ute he-wouldnst be here insthe middle of
he; competition...
Ta, Tarumi...?!
How horrible!!
Somebody, get an ambulance!
@kay., I'll go call for the ambulance!
@Omotani, you go to the police box
and get the police!!
Then I'll go back to the gym
and tell Hakamata about this...
Okay! Go quick and bring him back here!!
Okay!
Yahoo! We're in the best 41!
I think wescan win the championship!
Ta, Tarumi's deads...?! Are you sure!
Pretty sure... couldn't tell if he was
breathing but 'he was covered with blood!
Where is he?
Who the heck are you?
I asked you where he is!!
What is this? There's nothingOin here...
That's strange...we found him-here,
Ieaning against this vaulting horse...
What kind of doll is this?
I think it's a doll you use to practice
Iife saving techniques on.
Yes...you know,
Iike mouth to mouth resuscitation...
Are you sure
you didn't mistake this doll for your friend?
That's ridiculous... .!
Hey! Police is here!!
The ambulance will-be here
inf about 10-minutes.
FWe. can't find Tarumi!
Hat did you say...?!
You don't think
Tarumi pulled a:fast one on us, do you?
What?!
Let's split up and look for Tarumi!
If this is some kind of joke,
I'm going tot ach him a lesson!!!
Excuse me...
Are you from Shinnai THiversity?
Yeah, that's right, what is it...?
A call-just camesin to the recept on desk
from a strange man
he said to tell the guys from Shinnai
University who are in the storage room now,
to go to the locker room beside the pool
It's got to be Tarumi...!
That sneak!
Let's go check it out.
Shower room
Ta. Trarumi...
Is this for real?!
He's really dead...
I don't believe it...
The body in the storage room
IS moved to the locker room beside
the pool while no one is watching...
Dees that mean someone moved it?
But if you were: carrying
a body as bloody as that,
someones, bound to notice...
there's -a team from some school
sitting around the doorway
in the annex having their lunch...
So how in the world...??
Hey. Heij!
What're you doing?
You haven-t even eaten your lunch!
There's less than an hour left
before-the semi-finals?
Shut up!
I'm on a case! There's been a murder
in the locker room over there!!
Are you serious.e
But I don't understand something
sO ll can't concentrate on the match!
Then maybe you should ask Kudo for advice
Are they coming here, aren't they?
That's right, Kudo\. .!
I'll just give him a call...
Kudo would be able to solve the case
\in-no-time.
You don't have to-lose any sleep over it!
Let Kudo handle the investigation,
you get back to the match. come on!
Listen. Kazuhar!
Don't you dare tell Kudo abéut the murder!
Don't forget what I said!
Heiji?!
Kudo won't get here for
another hour and a half .!
I've got to solve this case by then!!
You've got rice on yourself again...
Murder case?!
Then you mean, Hattori's...
That's right!
He said he doesn't have time to compete,
he's running around looking for clues!
What're we going to do?!
The semi-finals are going to start already!!
We don't-have a choice
we've got tq take the championship
without-that Heiji.
Then we'll break that darn
mystery fool's nose in half!
Excuse fine. . .we1'relthe ones 14
who're going to be in the match...
You're positive he's one of your team mates?
Yes, thatgs right... his name's Tarumi.)
we re classmates at the same university.
The killer must have put him
under the hot shower
to mask the time, of death...
oh well, it's plain to see that
the murder Weapon is this sword.
As soon as we find. out who it belongs to,
we.ll have the killer...
You're wrong-about that, Inspector Otaki.
The fast draw instructor
brought it to the competition
because he was going to put
on a demonstration using areal sword...
somebody probably saw it left
in the dressing room,
stole it and used it to commit the murder.
Heiji, what're you doing here?
Can't you tell by looking at me?
I'm competing!
Oh, today's the day of the big competition
between Kinki's high school
and college teams...
so do you have any idea
who stole this sword?
Sort of.
The killer's somebody who comes
to this competition a lot
and knows about
the fast draw demonstration,
that person alse knows
the layout of the place,
the gym. the annex and the locker room
Which means,
the killer is somebody just like you guys!
I understand the part about having to know
about the demonstration
and stealing the Sword
but what does knowing about the gym
and annex and locker room
have to do with-anything?
Because if the killer didn't know
the locations of these places,
it wouldn't be possible to move Mr. Tarumi
from the annex to this locker room
without being seen.
What bothers me is,
not why he was moved but how...
Because when it happened,
there was a group of people
sitting in front of the annex
eating their lunch,
it would've been impossible for them
not to notice
a man covered with blood
being carried out...
unless of course, after you guys
found Mr. Tarumi in the storage room
the last one to leave the place
very cleverly managed to carry him out...
Doryou guys rememben what:happened?
The first one to leave was Kotegawa here...
He:;said "he was going to call an ambulance
Then I left!
Kotegawa told me to go to
the police box-and get the police...
So than means. Mr. Doguchu.
You were the last to leave, weren't you!
But I left right away to get Hakamata
who was in the gym.
How do I know you'rexnot lying?
I said Irwas going. didn't. 1?
Tow Ye
Yeah...
Besides, Doguchi wasn't the last one
to leave, it was me!
What?! »
I knew we needed the ambulance
as soon as possible
so when I saw a group of high school
students hanging around the entrance,
I borrowed their cell phone.
But the person I was talking to asked me to
describe the injured person's condition
so I went back and described
Tarumi's condition
of course, there was nobody else around.
As soon as I was finished,
I went back to return the cell jphone
then I headed for the police box.
Is that the truth?
Yes it is, he came to the police box!
I'm not good at explaining things
so I was relieved he came.
And how long did it take to go from the annex
to the police box then back again ;,
There's a big intersection
in front of the police box
and we:got stuck at the light...
I think it took about 14 to 15 minutes.
Didryou say 14 to 15-minutes?
Don't you think that's strange. Mr. Doguchi?
Mr..Omotani and Mr. Kotegawa came back
with the police right after we arrived
The gym is-right by the annex,
don't you think it took an unusually long time
to get Mr. Hakamata
He probably had a hard time finding me.
The place was filled with guys
wearing the-saméikind of outfits.
This means,
you also had some unaccounted time!
I don:t"Care if youssuspect us
but can you tell me-one-thing first?
Explain how you can get Tarumi,
who was in that condition,
out of the storage room in the annex
into the locker room without being seen?
Yeah. that's right!
If you can't explain that,
then you can't prove we're guilty!
Don't make up stories.
Well Detective, we're going to see
Tarumi's mother
and téll 'her what happened today...
Hey Hakamata, you're the only one
without a sash, why's that...?
"Thought I brought it with me
but I guess I lost it.
Oh well; it looks like we're going to
forfeit the match
so I guess I won't be needing it anyway...
Speaking of match, Heij,
how did you do today?
Didryou win? Or did you lose...?
Heiji...?
Hit on the forearm, 1 point!!
Way. to go! We scored!!!
All we"vefgot to do is hang in there
until it's time and then we're in the finals!'!
Hat's right We don't need Hey
to win the championship!
Tihrnustito. the neck, 1 point!
4 to 1, the match goes to
Kyoto Senshin High School!!
Kyoto Senshin High School...?!
It's Okita. just like Heiji said...!
This is not good!
Without Heiji. we don't stand a chance....!!
The windows behind the annex don't open
and the ones in the front are too noticeable...
The front door is only,way...
But te carry him to the locker room
beside the pool
I'd have to pass the-front of the gym
where there were a'lot of people....!
It's impossible...!
Somebody's bound to notice a man
covered with blood being carried past them!
Kudo's going to be here
in less than 10 minutes...!
Hey you! Wait up!
You just came out of the annex, didn't you!
What were you doing?
I only went to the toilet.
Sorry but there's something
I want to ask you!
What is it?.
Before Mr. Tarumi was killed,
I heard him say
I'll tell everybody about you know what
what was that about?
How would I know...! I don't know anything!!
All ri htth n
is the girl Mr. Tarumi and Mr. Hakamata
were fightihg about here today?
Of course not!
After that incident,
Haori quit managing the kendo team!
That incident? What do you mean?
Did you see Okita's thrust?
Yeah. you can kill somebody with that one.
Hey. come back!
Hey? That's the guy...
He's running again like he was
when we were eating lunch.
What?
Where you guys eating lunch
around the door to the annex?
Yeah, that was us.
There were 3 weird college students,
they asked to borrow a cell phone,
and then they brought the police
and other people, it was a circus.
All right then,
after those 3 left the annex.
Did any suspicious person go in there?
Yeah, there was one guy!
You!
Dummy! Before me!
There was one suspicious guy
that came out of the annex.
What?!
He was cagrying somebody else's
gear in a bag.
How could you tell it wasn't his?
That was easy!
He was carrying the bag while he was
wearing his mask and protective gear.
So that's how he did it, a gear bag...!
If you put the body in there and carried it out,
nobody would get suspicious...!
Mr Hakamata's the only one
would could've done it...!
He killed Mr. Tammi beforehand and
hid the body in the storage room,
and while he has the others
Iooking for Mr. Tarumi,
he goes back to the storage room and after
the other three find the body and go for help,
he puts Mr. Tarumi in the gear bag and
sneaks toward the locker room...
No, that's not possible...!
Even if you were hiding in that storage room
there's no guarantee
somebody would look in there
besides, it was just coincidence that
all three of them left the storage room
If someone decided to remain,
then he wouldn't be able to come out...
Hey!
You better watch yourself kid or
you're going to be in a whole lot of trouble.
I hear you've been asking about Haori too.
You «already told him?
Of course-he-did!
Doguchi and me go way back...
whenever"-he.:s-in-trouble.
He always comes to tell.me,
we made a pact when we wereilittle kids.
You're way off course
suspecting him though...
he's a coward,
he can't stand the sight of blood.
What?
Listen carefully!
Don't be a pest!
Hello?
Hattori, it's me!
Kudo it's you...where are you? On the bus?
No. old man Kogoro didn't want to
wait for the bus so we got on a cab.
Oh, all right, take your time!
In fact, why don't you get off and
have a bowl! of noodles or something,
maybe even walk around
and do some sightseeing!
Don't be stupid
we already told the driver where to go,
we're on our way there.
By the way, you're in the finals, aren't you?
Hey Hattori... you there?
Hey guys! Do you know about the life
saving dolls in the storage room?
Sure, because we came here
a lot to practice...
How many dolls do they have in there?
Two...one skinny one and one big one
That's it!!
Isn't he Hattori from Kaiho High?
What's he doing here?
The finals are starting already...
If my theory's right,
it should be here...!
It should still be here
in this storage room...
I knew it...! This is what the killer
used to move the body...!
Heiji! Heiji, where are you!
That fool! Where the heck is he?
Kazuhal
We're here to root for Heiji!
Ran!
Is HattorPs-team in the finals'?
Yes! And it's starting soon
but Heiji*s gone,off somewhere
I just: knowshe's running,around trying
to solve the murder that just happened
MM. murder. 2?
Original Comic Books By
GOSH!) AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
IUNIEHFIIOKA
Scripts By
KAN}! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JONICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Cf Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
» 5  , 2
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJI KBD WA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in 1ssocration with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION