The heart contains mysteries,
stars and snow sparkle for the two.
He sees through the.one and only truth,
a child in appearance with thed.Q. of ah-adult,
No case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan.
OSAKA DOUBLE MYSTERY
THE NANIWA SWORDSMAN AND
HIDEYOSHI TOYOTOMI'S CASTLE
You know Heiji
you keep talking about a killer...
but this doesn't look like anything else
except suicide...
All right, take a look at this!
Look on Ms. Katagiri's right side...
it's faint because it's wet
but you can still see it...
there are 2 or 3 strange marks...
Hey, you're right!
'Fihereislii strange marks here...!
And there're all the same...!
Isnt"that.blood?
Yes, probably from the victim...
From the victim...?
That's right...
Ms. Katagiri died from a blow to the head,
but she didn't get it when she fell and hit
her head on the bridge girder,
someone might have hit her on the head
with something hard
causing blood to splatter onto the killer...
And the blood got on her when the
killer picked her up...!
What I'm saying is.
When Kazuha and Ran saw her on the
bridge, she was already dead
Another thing, the figure you saw.suddenly
burst into flames and fell into the moat,
that's why you came to the wrong
conclusion and assumed it was a suicide!
B. but...
when she burst into flames, it looked
Iike she was struggling in pain...
Yes. that's right.
She was definitely alive!
That's what you THOUGHT you saw!
It was very dark,
you didn't get a good look. did you?
Es; but...
Well anyway, those guys seem
suspicious to me...!
I've got to find those three guys
who were on the same tour
as the 2 deceased people
and question them. .!
Are you talking about us?
We came back right awaypyjust like you
told us to and noticed the big commotion
It looks like the crowd's getting bigger...
What happened here. .?
En?! I don't believe it
Ms. Katagiri fell from the bridge
while burning up?!
From this Gokuraku Bridge?
But why commit suicide
by setting yourself on fire?
It hasn't been officially declared
a suicide yet...
That's why we need you to answer
few questions...
first off. you fellows and Ms. Katagin
! left this area, where did you go
and what were you doing
efore coming back...
I went to get something to eat
at a small restauranttnear here...
I did the same...
Only I went to a different restaurant...
1. I went back to the hotel in Nanayari
where we're all staying and
changed my clothes
So you were with Ms. Katagiri,
weren't you?
Yes, until we got back to the hotel...
I'd known something like would happen.
I should have stayed
with her the whole time
But why did Mr. Kato and Ms. Katagiri
choose fire...?
It's almost as if someone.ordered
them to do...
Ordered...?
That reminds me; Mr. Wakisaka.
You were playing the role of Nobunaga.
Weren't, ou...
Uh, yes...
That means,
if you ordered them to do something.
They'd have to obey, wouldn't they...
Well in that case.
Fukushima who could assume
Nébunaga's role for 3 minutes
could also have done it too...
What?!
I played leyasu so that leaves me
out of the picturef...
So one of you must have done it...
Their duty was to entertain Nobunaga,
not to take orders!
Besides. no one would obey an order
to set themselves on fire...
And another thing.
Ms. Katagiri played Nene, that was
just a supervisory role!!!
Also, when the firsttmember of
our party died,
we wouldn't be so callous as
to continue our role playing game!
S...l see what you mean.
Inspector Otaki!
We've found another piece of pottery on
Ms. Katagiri's body!"O
What. again
I wonder why they all had
pieces of pottery like this...
Oh. and we found this photo:too...
Huh...?
The your 1 couple in the right corner...
isn't that Mr Kato and Ms. Katagiri=...?
You're right.
So they knew each other from before...
But who are the other 3 people...?
Why that's Hirano!
Here, that's him...
You're right. she looks really young but
I think thatfit's him...
And who's this Hirano character?
He planned this tour...
We got all together because of
Hirano's home page...
he suggested we all goon atrip...
He came up with the idea of
the role playing game too!
Unfortunately though, just before
we were leaving on the trip,
something important came up and
he couldn't make it...
I see,
so the man planned this trip resulting
In strange deaths, isn't in attendance...
Are you absolutely sure Ms: Katagiri
didn't commit suicide?!
Il... we can't say for sure just ye
Well if the killer is using this tour
to commit murders,
the first thing we should do is
talk to Mr. Hirano
All you have to do is access "Legend of
the Lord:of Gold" home page... 1
That's him...
When Ms. Katagiri burned and
fell from the bridge,
that's who the suspicious person
behind Ran and Kazuha was...
s... I thought so t
but there's something
I don't understand...
The killer called Ms. Katagiri
out to the bridge. killed her
then tied a rope around her
and propped her against the railing
and waited in the distance for someone
to come by. when the moment was right,
the killer pulled the rope and she fell
into the moat, that set up is easy.
But to set her on fire at just the right time
and make it look like she was writhing
in pain as she fell,
that's not as easy thing to do...
Another thing bothers me too.
That strange blood stain on her side...
I'm pretty sure that's from blood
that was on a zipper...
But...
none of those three wore clothes
with a zipper...
There has to be a reason
the killer would go to the trouble of
changing into that kind of outfit
then calling Ms. Katagiri
out to the bridge...
And I know what it is...
Yeah.
Now we know why the killer wore
a special outfit that has a zipper...
The question now is,
who used that trick...
Well, anyone of those 3 could have...
Come on Heiji, let's go already!
It's getting windier too...
Eeek!
My umbrella. .!
Hey Hattor:...!
I think we...
I think we made a big mistake...
Oh my umbrellas ruined...
Well what do you except, it was just a
cheapy thing we picked up at that store...
Hey? Where's Heij...
He took Conan and
went off somewhere...
they probably figured out
who the killer is...
Eh?!
He was positively glowing
Tiheyscouldn't havelgone. so far,
but I don't see them...
It's no use!
Only one of them's at the hotel...!
The other two havenitjreturned yet!
There might be another murder. .!
After the first and second cases
are investigated thoroughly,
the trick is bound to be exposed...!
So the Killer's got to finish the job
by tonight . 1
Where could they have gone...!
Over there! That's Mr. Kasuyal!!
It doesn't look like
he's heading back to the hotel
It looks like he's going to finish things...
kay! I'll let the police know...
If the police come, there's bound to
be a commotion and he might get away
Let's you and me open this one up
on our own...!
I'm talking about the door to the truth...!
Hattori. where're you going!
That old man went into a suspicious
Iooking warehouse...
Hattori...don't you feel something?
I get this weird feeling
we're being watched .
Hey. what're you doing?
We're going in!
Hey...!
It's so dark I can't see a thing...
! He's over there...
It looks like he's going up...
Kudo, that tranquilizer you've got
in your watch, get it ready!
Yeah, I know
Ugu ?!
Ey Kudo, what's wrong...
Need to go to the toilet?
Oh no...I'm going to lose sight of him
I don't get moving...
Listen Kudo, when you finish using the
toilet, catch up with me right away!
Hattori is giving us a tour of
Osaka Castle
when we meet up with a tour group
who are fansfof Hideyoshi Toyotomi.
One of their members.
Mr. Kato burst into flames
on the roof of the tower and fell off
Written on the scroll he ad on him,
was the word dragon and the
drawing of a gourd,
They indicated
where the treasure of Hideyoshi,
the so called Lord of gold, was hidden
And before Mr. Kato's death was ruled
a suicide or murder,
another death occurs, right in front of
Ran and Kazuha!
Ms. Katagiri died
after setting herself on fire
and falling off the Gokuraku Bridge.
Hattori and I noticed the strange blood
stain on her clothes
and realized that this was a murder
Later, we followed Mr. Kasuya
Into a suspicious looking warehouse.
11 He's over there...
It looks like he's going up...
Kudo, that tranquilizer you've got
in your watch, get it ready!
Yeah, I know
USU?!
ey Kudo, what's wrong...
Need to go to the toilet?
Oh no...I'm going to lose sight of him
I don't get moving...
Listen Kudo, when you finish using the
toilet, catch up with me right away!
Hey. sorry to make you wait...
Wakisaka
No problem...
id you bring it with you...
It's over there... inside that box...
I see, good!
But there's so much stuff in here
and it's so dark
I can't make anything out...
I put a flashlight on the side of the box,
why don't you use it
here it is...!
Use that and you'll be able to find
what you're looking for...
The tiger scroll...
I wouldn't turn it on if I were you...
You'll be burnt to a crisp if you do...
Just like Mr. Kato on
saka Castle's tower...
Isn't that right, Mr. Wakisaka...
You mean both Ms Katagiri and
Mr Kato were
That's right.
Mr Wakisaka killed them. .!
He used the same trick he used on you
he lured the three of you out by saying
hat he'd found the tiger scroll...
It was easy with Mr. Kato...
all he had to do was tell him that
he hid the scroll under one of the tiles
on the roof of the tower...
in order to climb out on the roof,
you'd avoid going in the afternoon
when a lot of people would be around
and wait until night...
Going out there at night is fine but,
without a light, you wouldn't be able to
tell which tile it was under...
Mr. Kato had no other choice,
so he took the lighter he had out and
Iit it so he could look around,
and he saw a flashlight just lying there
s if waiting to be found...!
Mr. Wakisaka had left it there earlier.
It was rigged to explode
when it was switched on!
I see...
SO you're saying Mr. Kato chose to use
the flashlight which was handier
but when he turned it on. it exploded...
That's right.
The flashlight exploded into tiny pieces
and the lighter with his fingerprints on
was left on the roof,
making it look like he set himself on fire
That would explain the dry mark
that was left under the lighter....!
You wouldn't get that kind of mark
unless you put a lighter
on a round shaped mark,
besides, we found a burnt battery on the
ground near the castle
But how did he kill Ms. Katagiri...?
According to the girls who witnessed it.
When she set herself on fire,
there was no one else around
and she was writhing in pain,
as she fell into the moat...
And all she had in her hand
as a lighter...
Suicide is the only conclusion...
I don't blame you for thinking like that...
But it wasn't her that set herself on fire
and fell into the moat...
It was Mr. Wakisaka!
Wh. what...?!
After the crowdsthat was gathered
near the tower left
and people walking around thinned out
around the bridge, he...
called her out after making her
change into a coat...
then he killed her by striking her
with a hard object,
then he threw her into the moat.
Her body floated on the water
and he poured kerosene on her,
setting the stage...
All he had to do was wait for someone to
pass the bridge then set fire to his coat,
and pretend to writhe in pain
dropping the lighter into the moat
the lighter would set fire to Ms. Katagiri's
body floating in the moat
After that, he jumped into the moat
and dove underwater,
the only thing visible would be Ms.
Katagiri's body burning in the water....!
What you're saying is, even when her
body was lifted obit of the water
and examined, the injury on her head
which was the actual-cause of her death,
would appear to have been a result
of her hitting her head on the girder
because the witnesses would testify
that she set fire to herself
and fell from the bridge...!
That's right.
But it only went as smoothly as it did
because those girls happened
to pass by at just the right moment,
if a lot of time had passed
before anyone had Walked by.
The time of death would be off,
wouldn't it?
Not really,
because Mr. Wakisaka had already
prepared a witness
it was mere coincidence that Kazuha
and Ran saw what happened first,
it appears the intended witness
ran away from the scene though...
You don't mean that it was...
It was Mr. Fukushima. .!
He didn't know anything
about the incident
but when he heard
a burning body fell into the moat,
he immediately said it was suicide...!
Think about it,
if someone were going to commit suicide
by setting themselves on fire,
they wouldn't jump into water,
it would put the fire out...
It would be natural to assume 4
that you'd jump into the water
only if someone else set fire to you,.
Isn't that right
What he said proves that he witnessed
her jumping into the moat
after setting herself on fire...
Judging by the events of the day,
all 2 person would have 10 do is
disguise their voice;
pretending to be the police
and call him out to the bridge,
he would have gone there right away I
But it's awfully strange...
Mr. Wakisakas hair and clothes
weren't all that wet.
And if by chance something went wrong.
He could have been seriously burned...
He was wearing a dry suit
under his coat over his clothes...!
If he wear to put the hood on
before setting fire to himself,
he wouldn't get burned,
and neither his hair
or his clothes would get wet
so he could swim underwater.
Until he got far away from the bridge
then climb up the stone wall,
and after he hid
the dry suit and coat somewhere
he went and joined the crowd
SO as not to draw suspicion to himself...
Incidentally, both the flammable fleece
Mr. Kato wore, and
Ms. Katagiri's coat were given to them
y you, isn't that right...
You probably told them
that it would be easy for them
to spot each other
when they snuck off to meet in secret...
Did you Know there was blood
on Ms. Katagiri's coat,
her blood splattered on your clothes
and then you got it on her...
It got on her when you carried her...
they were shaped
Iike the zipper on a dry suit
and the edge of that badge
you have on your chest...
Which means,
that if we were to check that
Nobunaga badge you're wearing.
We'll have the proof to nail you!!
But why did he want to
kill me and the other two...?
You three weren't-the only ones...
he killed the man
who planned this trip. Mr. Hirano too...!
Basked a professor? I know
to access Mr. Hirano's home page,
he founder. Hirano had been putting
new entries on a daily basis
but-he-stopped:-3=weekstago...
Remember that burnt body
they found in the outer moat recently,
hat was probably
Yeah, that's right...
I killed them,
Hirano, Kato and Katagiri...
in dedication to my grandfather Masakiyo
who loved Hideyoshi
and was killed for it...
Your grandfather?!
Ou saw the picture didn't you...?
The old man in the middle holding
the scroll open was my grandfather...
He always used to tell me...
About the scroll he'd found...!
And about the clues
to Hideyoshi's treasure...
He told me he wantedr
to give up looking for the treasure
and donate the scroll to the country,
but that the others didn't agree
and they began to argue about it...
Then 13 years ago.
He told us he was going to Osaka
to try and convince
the others to agree with him,
and he never came back...
You mean the burnt body they found
in the moat 13 years ago
Was my grandfather,
he was killed by his partners...
Grandfather found
that piece of pottery along with the scroll
but he didn't tell the others about it...
That photo was the only clue
I had as to who his partners were
so I had a hard time finding:them...
And I never imagined-that-one of them
would change how they looked...
You mean that old man on the left is...?!
That's me...
Something happened
and I had to change my appearance...
That Ms Katagiri seemed to suspect
that I was a member
of their former group.
I don't care what happens to me
but are you going to
kill Mr. Wakisaka too?
You'll never find out
where the treasure is!
I assume you haven't brought
the tiger scroll with you #%
I've already found out
where Mr. Wakisaka lives
I'll just tear his house apart...!
Both of you move to the back, quickly!
Pick up that flashlight and turn it on
I'm going to have
you two fall to the ground...!
It's going to look like
the killer and the teenage detective
fell to their deaths
while engulfed in flames...!
By the way.
Before you die, answer my question...
How did you figure out
Mr. Wakisaka was the killer...!
Anyone could have used
that trick you just explained....!
What tipped you off?
Humph!
Why should I tell you!
It was the umbrella!
In his last moments,
Mr. Kato grabbed hold of an umbrella,
it was his dying message,
he was indicating Nobunaga's standard,
the golden umbrella
That's how he knew
Mr. Wakisaka was the killer!
Why you little brat,
when'd you get up there 7?!
Get down here!
Or I'll fill your friend here with holes!
No! Don't come down there!
I guess I don't have a choice...
You idiot!
Humph...what a good little boy...
Y. you're Heizo Hattorir'!
OD, dad?!
You may 've changed
how you looked 13 years ago
but it seems like you can't change that
sick voice or that warped personality!
You're under arrest
for possession of an illegal weapon!
And for attempted murder .!
Also for the 5 robbery-murders
you committed
because you failed to find the treasure...
You're going to pay for what you did!!
Robbery murders...?
I don't know what you're talking about...!
No use pretending!
We've get your voice on tape.
On the spur ofithe moment,
the victim recorded it
on his answering machine,
and we've also got your handprint
on the telephone
when you Ming it up!!
There's no"sympathy'for
those-whorturn-against their friends!
If you don t want to get hurt...
Come along quiet like and
Iet us put these cuffs on you!!!
And so the case
that:spannedf3 years...
was personally solved by the head
of Osaka's prefectural police
while we watched in wonder
it all happened in a blink of an eye...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.