The heart contains mysteries,
stars and snow sparkle for the two.
Naniwa is the stage for
a tag team match of Conan and Heiji
He sees. through the.one and. only truth,
a child in appearance with the.l.Q. of an-adult,
No case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan.
OSAKA DOUBLE MYSTERY
THE NANIWA SWORDSMAN AND
HIDEYOSHI TOYOTOMI'S CASTLE
Yes! that's it! This is my wallet!
You're very-luc +
I figured you might be coming back
right away
so I kept it here instead.of giving it
to the police!
It's a veryiprecibus wallet. isn't.it?
It was-filled with amulets
It sure is! Thank you so much. ma-am!
You mean you had more than
1 amulet in there?
I bought a charm to chase away evil'too!
So that we wouldn't be involved in
another case
and have it ruin your visit to Osaka
Iike last time...
How sweet....!
What?!
A burning man fell from the tower?!
Areryou sure about:that?,
eah the police are there and
everything's going crazy!
It didn't work. none of them...
I guess not...
Inspector OtakHyou sure are busy...
Two murders two days straight...
ell, it's my job...
It's amazing though,
how did you know the victim's
name was Yuji Kato...
I looked on his badge...
Is badge...
you mean the crest on his chest?
That's Hideyoshi's crest,
he Goshichi paulownia...!
As soon as I saw it I knew he was the
Hideyoshi character from their group
$0 I had them come and identify the body!
What do you mean. Hideyoshi character?
As part of the tours entertainment.
We have each member act as a famous
person from the Warring States period
and also have aspenalty game
For instance, I'm Mitsuhide and
yasu...
Wakisaka is Nobunaga and
IS Nene...
and Kato over there was Hideyoshi...
I see: that sure sounds like a lot of fun...
« But I don't understand how you could
Iose track of
one of your tour members and
him end up like this...
Uh, well...
He disappeared so suddenly and
we were looking for him all this time...
He was wearing a flashy fleece outfit
so we figured we could spot him
right away...
Who'd have thought he'd fall from
there in a ball of fire...
By the way. can you think of a reason why
» Mr. Kato would commit suicide?
Uh, no. I don't have the slightest idea...
How do you know it was suicide?
First off it's raining so hard. no one
would go out there on the roof!
And then he:was wearing clothes made of
fleece, which is very flammable...!
That proves he went out on the roof
himself and set himself on fire!
Uh, huh...
but, you sure do come across a lot of
urders, don't you...
maybe you're cursed or something?
Not really,
the Chief of Police's son comes across
them more often...
Eh? Is Heiji here too?
Yes. He and Conan went inside the
castle just a little while ago...
Hey Kudo, be careful, it's slippery up there
because of the rain!
Ow embarrassing...
I feel like a trained monkey...
Did you find something!?
There's a lot of teeny tiny pieces of
omething up here...
It's a lighter
Could this be the lighter he used...
It doesn't make sense though...
why Is it here...
Eh...?
Hat's this mark...
just don't believe it...
why would Kato commit suicide...
I don't believe it either...
he was really looking forward to
coming to Osaka...
I guess you nevergknow what people are
really thinking about...
Maybe he'd planned all along
to commit suicide here
in the land ofiHideyoshi Toyotomu...
All we have to do is find what he used to
set himself on fire with
Right... That's all we need to find...
We found it!
It was_.on.the roof of the tower...
it's a highter!
Why isn't that the lighter Kate had?
Yes. I think it is
That settles it, it was a suicide!
I wouldn't be too sure about that!
Eh...?
The cover. on this lighter was closed...!
Do you think someone committing suicide
would. take the time to close the cSver?
But Heiji...
maybe the cover closed when
he dropped it...
If that were the case we should have
found it further down theiroof...
Besides, it looked like something else was
there before the lighter was put down...
What do you mean, something else..7?7
When we found the lighter, there was a
dry spot in a strange shape under it...
not a rectangle shape like this lighter,
twas a nice fan shape...
I'm pretty sure something round was put
there before it started to rain...
after the rain started, that round thing
was replaced with the lighter...
Isn't that right. kid...
# Yup!
But Heiji, what was that thing...?
What do you think that round thing was...
Beatsime:.ilthaven:t'figured that.out yet...
Bull think it has something 10 do with the
Iittle chips.all over the place...
Inspector Otaki! We've laid out all of the
victim's personal belongings out
Wallet, watch and cellular phone...
Keys. cigarettes
and a piece of something...
Huh...? A scroll...
What in the world...?
Only the word dragon is on this thing...
And what is this from
It looks like piece of pottery...
Hmm? That piece .
Hmm? That piece...
Isn't-<itspossible that piece is theisame \
as the ones they found )
on-the 6ther burned bodies?
My dad and your father were-«talking
about it in the car last night...
there were 2 other burned bodies. one
was found in the inner moat 13 years ago
and the other was found just recently
in the outer moat,
both victims had pieces of pottery that
Iooked the same.
And I heard them say that the one they
found recently had 848 written on iti:
848+? What does that mean...?'" +
No one was really sure
but it seems that those pieces
J are a part of some kind of treasure
Treasure...?
I'm not making it up!
They were whispering
ke 'it was a secret...!
They said something about huge fortune
the great man left behind...!
Did you say huge fortune?!
Are you sure you're not making
all of this up...
Hey Hattori
Huh
Look at this piece of pottery...
There's shiny stuff stuck on
the inside of it .
Hey...isn't that gold?
Think so Lou ws not much -
so I don t-think it's much of a trea tire...
Boy. I just don't understand this case...!
It's a mysterious enough that Mr. Kato
Ieft the tour and went up the roof
but it's even harder to explain
why he suddenly burst into flames...
And the biggest question...
Why Mr. Kato grabbed
the.umbrella... just before he died...!!
Umbrella could refer to rain.
And rain makes me think of
the Ryuko rock
right here at Osaka Castle...
What's that?
You mean you don't know...?
Here at Osaka Castle,?
standing on both sides of
the Sakura Gate, protecting the tow
Sakura Gate Ryuko Rocks
we have rocks called*Ryuko Rocks...!
That's what they've been called
since long ago because
it's said that when it rains, the figures 4
of-a dragon and tiger:appear on them
Rain.
Rain...
Hmm...
Let me borrow that for awhile!
Hey?!
What's going on?!
That's evidence!
Ahaha...
her:story might just be true...
Yeah, there's still a possibility it could
e hidden somewhere...
the treasure of Hideyoshi, the man
alled Lord of Gold"...
Is somewhere: in Osaka Castle...
1, treasure.
Hideyoshi's treasure...
Yeah, it's me...
Don't make a move yet...!
It doesn't look like the copsil be
Ieaving soon.
Don't worry about it!
The thing we want's right in. front of me!
Make sure you've got everything.ready...!
What?! You know what the treasure
Hideyoshi left is?!
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm pretty sure about it...!
The clue is the piece of pottery
Mr. Kato had...
take a good leek at it,
there's just a little bit:here and there
but you .can see that
there's gold stuck on the inside
You're right...
But how do you knew there's a lot of
treasure just by looking at this piece...
Now. put it together with this scroll that v
Mr. Kato had and look again carefully!
But this scroll only has the word, dragon
on the upper right hand written-on it...
What is this...?!
Several sheets of paper were pasted
over the word that was written there...
It's just like the Ryuko Rocks,at
Osaka Castle,
when you wet the paper,
the word underneath appears....!
Yes but most of the words have been
burnt and you can't read them...
And what about this?
What's this drawing on the left?
Isn't that a gourd?
I The gourd is the symbol I
on Hideyoshi's flag. it's his standard!
Eh?!
So is that mean that piece might have
come from pottery shaped like a gourd?
And are you saying
that it was filled with gold?
But according to this diagram,
It was about 1 shaku high...
which is only about 30 centimeters...
No matter how much money
you stuffed in it,
it's so small,
it wouldn't add up to much...
Did you forget?
I 1:8 been said that whenever General
Hideyoshi won a battle,
he:added a small gourd and that's how
'his golden standard was created...
The bottle gourds....!!
Bottle gourds, you mean?!
It. it can't be...?!
That's right...
if there were 1,000 of the same thing.
That would be some treasure...!
And if you were to consider the history
behind it, it would be priceless...!
The burnt body
13 years ago had a piece,
so did the other recent body
and now Mr. Kato, it could mea that
maybe:.they-were after the treasure...
but they were killed by someone who.
Wanted it all for themselves...
I don't understand though...
how did the Chief of Police
and your father know
that it:-meant a huge treasure just
y looking at the 2 pieces...
They hadn't seen the scroll yet...
They probably knew
by looking at the shape...
The piece my father
was looking at in the car,
Iooked like it came from the
top of the gourd
and he said the words 848 was
written on it...
I ORB
848 is a number between 1 and 1,000...
, If both of the pieces had gold stuck to
them on the inside,
that theory might be correct...
But that sounds like a fairy tale...
B. but it isn't entirely impossible...!
It's been said that even after Hideyoshi
died, leyasu was intimidated by him
because of all the gold and silver he'd
stored in Osaka Castle...!
There's a legend that when Hideyoshi
wanted to purify the water in the well,
he put a huge amount of gold in the
Kinmeisui directly in front of the tower!
Even if that's true, what makes you. think,
this is refers to hidden treasure...?
For all you know, this scroll ¢ould just
be a blueprint...
Stupid!
Hiding gold in pottery and layering
sheets of paper!over the scroll is
the proof someone deliberately wanted
to hide something...!
That scroll's the dragons chapter..!
WCrmeans st $ sO O:-VIOUS...
About the tiger...
If that scroll with the dragon is like
the Ryuko Rock
and the drawing of a gourd appeared
when it got wet...
then there should be a scroll with
a tiger somewhere too....!
And what's more.
There's 2 high possibility that scroll will
show us where the gourds are hidden...!
Isn't that right...? Heij:...
Isnt'that: right... 7? Heiji...
M£ Mr. Toyama. sir... 7?!
Wh. what brings you here...?
I gave himfa call!
The prefecture! police's main
headquarters is fight over there!
J Huh?
It seemed to be linked to a case
dad was involved in before,
besides if I didn't do something like this,
you'd never tear yourself away
from this place. would you Hep!
She's gone and butted in again...
Kazuha's right, let us take care of this...
Yes, listen to him"
I know a real nice place in the Shimbashi
direction of Osaka Castle!
Let's have dinner there!
Be:quiet!!
Someone.died rightlin front of our eyes
how can you stuff your face...
I mean, have dinner...
it wouldn't feel right, would it...
So. you should just forget about me
do have dinner with Ran.
Won't mind Ka ..Xazuha...
To heck with you. .!
Let's go Ran!
We'll just go without them!
WwW. wait a minute Kazuha...
Come on, quick, let's go!
It's a super delicious Italian restaurant!
Excuse me, would it be-all right if we got
something to eat too?
We havenst had\anything to eat
since lunch
My clothes got wet from the rain so
I'm going to the hotel first and-change...
Uh, wait...
We'll be right back...
the hotel we're staying in is close by
All right then but don't be long!
That voice... it can't be...
Hey Otaki...
Yes sir!
Listen
Yes sir, I understand!
I'll tell my men right away!
Rr Be careful!
Yes sir!
Heizo... it's me...
You did. it for Heiji; didn't you...?
Calling your father like that...
E 1 bide'?
You knew your father was deeply
involved in that case
so you figured if you called him in
he'd fill Heiji in with all the information
he'd be dying to know...
But you didnit want him to catch on
SO you used that tone with him
So, what if I did... I love seeing it...
I love seeing how his face glows
whenever he solves a case...
I'm such a fool, aren't I...
Yes. a major fool!
A major fool?!
And so am I...
It's sO frustrating. but there's something
so wonderful about Shinichi
when he gets like that...
Uh huh...
Oh, but-.only when he gets like
thatsthough
Isn't that night Conan, you agree
don't you...
Oh no, I forgot to bring Conan along!
Sot Is
You're right...
Hey Hattori
Take a look at this. I found something
strange in a strange place.
A battery...?
All a minute...
if that came from when Mr. Kato
burned up...
ght... it was no suicide.
It was murder...!
Don't worry about it!
Heiji and your father are with him
and besides, there are a lot of police
around here...!
Nothing's going to happen...
The victim's name is Maho Katagiri...
a member of that tour...
according to Kazuha,
her coat caught on fire and she fell
into the moat as if she were collapsing...
but the cause of death is
a blow to the back of her dead...
She probably got it when she fell,
I think she hit her head
n the girder over there...
Was it suicide?
It looks that way, at least for now...
Are you sure she wasn't holding anything
else beside the lighter?
Yes. I'm sure, that's how it looked to me.
Was there anybody neariher?
NO not near her but...
There was somebody near the bridge's
entrance. wasn't there?
Yes...
That's it!
That's who set her on fire!
I don't think it was possible though...
that person was on the same side
as we were...
I definitely think it was suicide though...
Don't be stupid!
No way it was suicide!
There's got to be something here!
Something to prove it was murder!
There has t » bel!
There has to be!!
S. stop that Heiji!!
D. dad...?!
Heiji, stop acting like
you know everything...!
Don't you understand...?
Do you know
how much-trouble you cause
every time you meddle
IN police matters
Calm down sir!
Heiji's just trying to solve the crime
in his own way...
oops. sorry...
Mr. Mouri, that may be how you see it.
But when it comes to this kid, you don't
call his methods police work...!
He's a pest...!
People flatter him
by calling him a high school detective
and that's given him a swollen ego,
he interferes with our investigations
by handling the evidence
and the victim's bodies
all because it's his hobby...
he's nothing more than
a crime scene assaulter...!
To prove my point, look around 2«people
have died right in front of'his eyes
and he hasn't done anything to stop it!
He was so sure
that nothing else would happen
because the police had the area covered!
Actually...you could say
we were just as much at fault...
at any rate...
Meddlesome amateurs should leave....!
Get-out of my sight, immediately!!
S, sir...!
S. sir...
You're being too hard on him
Otaki... 4
Did you forget?
I told you to follow thatfguy, didn't I...?
Oh, that's right!
No wonder the Chief's so... 4
es.:. that's his way of showing
he cares about his son:...!
Otaki, are these both murders?
Uh, no...
Regarding Mr. Katoés case.
He fell from the tower as he burned
and we found a lighter on the roof with
he victim's fingerprints on it...
As for Ms. Katagiri, she lit the fire on
herself and fell into the moat.
Kazuha herself witnessed this...
there are several things
we can't explain
but I'm almost certain
there were both suicides...
If that's the case, then 2 or 3 men should
be enough of cover the work here...
Toyama, lets got.!
The police have
more important work to do,
we can't spend so much time
on a case as minor as this...
Ch, Chief...!
Heizo...
1... you can't be thinking.
Aw, don't look so disappointed Heir.
The Chief's probably angry
because 2 people died
SO close to headquarters...
Still, he didn't have to hit him...
Maybe it's all the killer's fault...
Remember, the story
Aboutgyour dad, driving us home and
they were talking about some pottery...
Well, there's a continuation to that...!
They said it was possible that when the
burnt body was found 13 years ago
there was a rash of armed burglaries
and that the burglar might
unexpectedly be discovered...
Armed burglaries?
Yes, there were 5 consecutive incidents
7 people were killed and
the vicious killer is still on the loose...
Are you saying that
Hattori's father thinks the killer in these
recent cases is the same person...
Aha, now I get it...
Heizo didn't want to put his son.in danger
sO he acted coldly to distance V
him from the case,
that's so touching...
it makes me want to cry...
I Yeah... it makes me want to cry too...
Who'd have thought
my old man would go soft like that...!
He. Hew... .?
I don't take orders very well....!
If I get pushed. I push back...!
I'm going to solve the case and shove
the killer right up my father's nose
Ha. haha, haha...!!
What he's saying is he's more stupid
ham obedient...
but that's strange...
You'd think that being his father,
he would know what his son wouldn't
give up so easily...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KAS O ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I1OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASQIIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animi1tion Directors
MA ATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TA AHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
4  44
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJIKOD WA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION