The heart contains mysteries,
stars and snow sparkle for the two.
Naniwa is the stage for
a tag team match of Conan and Heiji
He sees throligh the one and. only truth,
a child in appearance with the IQ. of an-adult
No case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan
OSAKA DOUBLE MYSTERY
THE NANIWA SWORDSMAN AND
HIDEYOSHI TOYOTOMI'S CASTLE
The question is, who the killer is and
how Mr. Tarumi was moved!
We know how
Heh?
One of mysmen just questioned
some of the kids
that were hanging around
the entrance:to.the annex
and it seems theyssaw the killer
A suspicious character came out of here
wearing a mask and protective gear
carrying a gear bag...
A mask, protective gear and
a gedtrbag...?
I see! The killer put
. » ~~
arumi Iinsice ye gear rag
and wore a mask to cover his face so no one
would recognize him when he walked out!
When did that-guy
wearing the mask come:out?
It seems it was after the
3 left-the<annex: after finding the body
So it: means that the person who moved
the body was not one.of the 3 who found it...
That's right...the killer was
probably hiding in the storage room
when the 3 came in
and found Mr. Tarumfs body.
He didn't think the body would be found
SO SOON, SO he moved it here
Excuse me Inspector Otaki\, r
but did Heiji come here?
Yes...he was here for awhile
but he rushed off for some place
It's no use...
No matter what you do,
you can't make it look like
Mr. Tarumi was killed in this storage room...
Mr. Kotegawal!
That's right...
this isn't where Mr. Tarumi was killed...!
He was killed in the
Iocker room beside the pool
After you fellows found Mr. Tarumi's body.
Mr. Omotani and Mr. Doguchi left
You alone came back
and told him to go to the locker room,
that's where you killed him...
Isn't that right...?
How stupid...it was pure coincidence that
they left the storage room!
If someone had stayed behind,
I wouldn't have been able to come back and
do what you claim I did, now would I?
No. it was No coincidence....!
All you had to do was tell Mr. Omotani to
go get the police
to guarantee no one would be left
You knew Mr. Doguchfs personality.
Whenever something happened,
he always reported it to
Mr Hakamata and besides,
he can't stand the sight of blood...
You knew he wouldn't touch the body,
that he'd immediately
go to find Mr. Hakamata...!
You gave Mr. Tarumi liquor
Iaced with sleep inducers
then you put redgpaint on him
to make him appear dead,
no one would think he was alive!
This storage room is dark so the
red paint would look like real blood!
Humph.
There were a lot of people in front of
the annex, if somebody covered with
red paint came out of here,don't you think
some one was bound to notice?
Yes, they did...
they saw a suspicious character
wearing a mask
and protective gear come out of
the annex carrying a gear bag!
Aw come on,
I hope you're not saying that
at was Tarumi...?
What makes you think
he'd dress himself up like that to go to the
Iocker room just because I told him to.
It wasn't just what you said...
If you were shown something like this
while you were groggy.
You could be talked into doing anything....!
He:said I'm going to kill you*=+?!
Mr. Tarumi was always saying that?
Yes, it seems he had a grudge
against Mr. Hakamata
the other team members, told me that
So that means
there's a possibility Mr. Hakamata killed
Mr. Tarumi instead!
Hhmm
No. that's wrong....!
The killer probably took advantage of
Mr Tarumws anger...
That's right,
when you came back here alone,
you put the Japanese sword in
Mr. Tarumi's hand.
Woke him up and showed him the doll you'd
hidden inside the vaulting horse beforehand.
Then you probably said this to him...!
What in the world have you done!!!
Mr. Tarumi hated Mr. Hakamata and
he was still in a groggy state of mind...
So he didn't notice that it was just the doll
used to teach life saving techniques
wearing Mr. Hakamata's uniform...!
That's why he thought the red paint on his
chest guard was Mr. Hakamata's blood
and that he'd killed him
hile he was drunk...!
That's when you probably told him that
you'd let him get away
before the police arrived
so he should put the mask on
and sneak into the locker room
beside the pool and hide there
And you also suggested he change out of
his bloody clothes, put on the protective gear
and put the sword into the bag
for the bamboo sword.
Then told him to take them with him,
didn't you!
You put the extra clothes and
protective gear in the gear bag
and had it hidden it in the storage room...!
That's so it would appear like
someone else besides you
carried the body out of the
storage room wearing a mask...!
Then you took a short cut to the
Iocker room
and waited for Mr. Tarumi to arrive
and then you killed him for real...
After-that. you washed the paint off of
his body in the shower
put the mask and protective gear
in the gear bag.
And after you hid them somewhere,
you went to the police box
where you'd sent Mr. Omotani!
That's when you did it. right?
That's when you got Mr. Tarumi's blood
on the towel you're holding now...
When you went to get the doll from
inside the vaulting horse,
you decided to smear his blood on it
so that it'd look like he really was
killed here, isn't that right?
That bloody towel in your hand proves that
you killed him!!
Humph...
If you know so much then
you probably know why I did it...
I called the college you go to and
checked up on you...
I found out that last year, one of the
new members of your kendo team
Iost consciousness during practice and
died...!
The college claimed
it was an accident but the truth is...
That's right,
we were initiating the new members,
Tarumi didn't know his own strength,
e overdid it...
Hakamata was officiator but
e was absent that day...
This is what Tarumi said...
Sure I'm the one who did it
but everyone present here today and
the manager is just as guilty....!
If anyone talks,
I'm taking everybody down with me
So you decided to shut him up
so he couldn't ruin it for all of you
since this is a important phase in your lives
being as you've all got jobs lined up!
Humph, I guess you know everything...
but seeing as you aren't armed,
you didn't know about this, did you...
The fast draw demonstrator had
a partner...
naturally, when I went into the demonstrator's
dressing room to steal the sword,
I'd already...
taken a few
practice swings with itl!
Enh?!
A'strange man called and told you
come to the locker room...?
R. really
Uh. yes...
and when they all arrived. they found
Mi Tarumi had been moved here
The reason the killer called to give
Mr. Tarumi's location was.
He didn't want the storage room
to be searched...
which means, there's something
he doesn't want found still inside...
Hey. where is the storage room?
It's in the annex next to the gym, why...?
Show me!
Whoa, slow down...
@Oonan, where are you going?
Don't be a fool!
You won't be able to get away with it
this time if you kill me here!
I'm not worried!
The police"ll assume it's the same Killer
and since they've already decided
I couldn't have moved Tarumi's body,
they won't even suspect me...
I've already figured everything out!!
Wha?!
You picked the wrong guy to fight with
hat the...?
Hattori...?!
I donstibelieve it.
You're that high school kid that
shocked everybody by beating
the entire Osaka Police" Department's team,
and they're all well trained...
That's right...but you realized it too late...
Yuranosuke
Yo! Good to see you!
He. Heiji...?!
Well Otakl_ lhll létfouftake MT-from here
You can count on me!
Best of luc «to you too Heiji!
I almost forgot!
The match. the.match!
We: can't waste our time
standing around here. .!
Think it's already over...
Oh well. it couldn't be helped...!
We lost the championship but
solved the case....!
Right!
Huhhhh?
Hens Heirs turn...
This is delicious!
It's the best!
Of course it is!
No one makes better tetchiri than
my mom!
Huh
Look at that, she fell asleep without
taking a single bite
It's all your fault!
Sheiwas. running all over the place
Iooking for you!
Well it couldn't be helped.
I had to solve that murder, didn't ll...
You can tell he's the son of the
@€hief of Police!
He solved the case in no time!
Thank you
This kid solves cases purely on intuition,
he's just playing detective.
He doesn't even come close to being
a real detective like you Mr. Mourn
So what's that supposed to mean...
that Kudo's better than me too?