The heart contains mysteries
stars and snow sparkle for the two.
The confrontation of this couple,
what's going to happen in the court...
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
Thank you so much for everything.
It's all thanks to you.
Oh, no, it's nothing, no problem...
I will.
guess so.
Goodbye then.
Goodbye, take care.
Mother!
I'm not the one who worn, he did.
I'm sorry Ran, you waited quite a while, didn’t you?
So, Conan suggested that we’ll have you take us to a great meal.
Hey!
The thing is,
What!
Ms. Kisaki,
the car's ready for you outside.
Thank you.
Right, Ms. Kuriyama,
would you please take Ran and Conan to eat something good after this?
Yes, I was planning on going to see you in the near future.
Reiko Kujo
Oh...
So, she's the famous Madonna of the prosecutor's squad...
I'm really looking forward to meeting you in court, Ms. Kisaki.
Take it easy on me, okay.
Goodbye, then.
That's all about to end now.
I'm going to teach her how failure tastes..
BATTLE IN COURT KISAKI VS KOGORO
PART 1
Ms. Kuriyama,
what kind of case did Ran’s mother take on?
Huh?
Do you remember the case about a month ago,
where a corpse of a man was found at a construction site in Haido-cho?
The victim was an office worker called Tsuyoshi Hirasawa.
Tsuyoshi Hirasawa.
It was found that he was hit on the head with a steel pipe
that was found at the site and died...
and,
A suspect emerged from a car key
that was found at the site...
And, he’s the one that Ms. Kisaki will be defending this time...
Well, the thing is,
three fears ago the victim, Mr. Hirasawa, who was drunk,
aceid.eni^ijy pushed
Mr. Usamni ®ff the stairs...
The boy, Masaki, hit his head hard, and died because of the incident...
Haw terrible..
*• *• »
Hirasawa was mo.st naturally chargée for involuntWÿ manslaughter
but at the time of the incident, being that he was drunk,
a suspended sentence was passed..
That's absurd?!
He killed a person and he doesn’t have to go to jail?!
Give me back Masaki!
Give me back my Masaki!
in order to aven&e death of his son...
And, what is Mr. Usami saying to this?
Well., have your remembered anything .fince then?
• • •
nothing..
.I *	9*
Shuji w^srannj
No... nothing..
Shuji iU)$Ta mi
Okay, then let me start from the beginning and ask you again..
you got into an argument with thè victim at a Japanese pub called "Yamazen."
The problem is after that.
The point is where and what you were doing during that time!
I don't care how trivial,
if you remember anything I’d like you to tell me about it.
B,ÿ.tJjH\ way, about your wife,
I cÿn’t get a holcjl^h^ no matterPl^e.w many îirn^s I tW@gfïjJriiW.
She ha's? nothing to do^wijh this!
Why not?
I'm sure she's worried about you.
She hates me.
Ms. Kisaki
Ms. Kuriyama
Well? Find anything?
According to the police, it should be somewhere around here...
Oh, mother, over here!
Ran? What brings you here..
Uh, isn’t this the shop you're looking for?
Is this the shop of the victim's wife?
Mimasu, written “beautiful seat
What an unusual name..
Masako Kamoda
I've already forgotten all about him.
I've heard of why you got a divorce.
But, Ms. Kameda,
It s your fault that Masaki died.
Every time he got drunk he would repeat saying so..
I understand how you feel,
However, your husband is in a very tough situation right now
Please cooperate with us to help him and talk to us...
I don’t want to recall a thing about him.
The construction site where the incident took place is near here, isn’t it?
If there is something that you know about the night the incident happened...
I know
If that's all you want to talk about, please leave.
Hello.
Iflutn:
What are you guys doing in a place like this?
Talk for yourself.
I just came to take a light shot like always.
;Z..do you know them?
Uhife..do you know them?
I'll come again some other time!
Does he come here often?
Mh...
That night? Are you referring to the night of the incident?
Do you kmôw soînêtHiihg abouti
Do you krgjwi sofnêthîng abouti matjn^idje^t^?
Usami came here.
Mr. Usami came here?
Yes..
Ms. Kisaki!
Do you remember what time Mr. Usami came here?
No... I don't..
But, Mr. Mouri may remember.
You h^ean, him?
You mean, him?
Thank you so much for remembering.
It’s not that I tried to remember for Usami’s sake.
I'm home!
Dad!
It's ü^ne ©Pwir busines
Ugh!
You hav7en't changed) at all.
Phooey! It's none of your business?
You smell like alcohol. ..
Here goes gagffi^t beam attack!
Haaaah!
Do you remember that murder case
that occurred at the construction site at Haido-cho?
Come to think of it, yeah..
You were at the pub called Mimasu that night, weren’t you?
Here, drink some coffee and clear your head.
That's just great.
That’s just great.
Do you remember him?
I‘v^s§ë.n this guy...I m sure... at Mimasu. ..
Well.
Mr. Mouri, you have a phone call. Mr. Mouri.
Huh?
Hello?
I can’t hear too well in the shop
Oops.
What's this? You don’t believe me?
That’s not what I’m saying.
A renown detective does not forget a fsrée he en«c secs!
but when I finished taking the phene eaiI and returned to the shop,
Darn....!
Darn..
Are you done with your call?
O.Oh....
He’s an old acquaintance....
Oh.
Well, I guess I better be going....
Oh come on, why don’t you take it easy a while longer, Mr. Mouri.
Okay.
I guess I’ll take another shot, then!
when I left the shop after him.
Do you remember about what time that person came to the shop?
21:25.
So, if Mr. Usami came to the shop at 21:25 he has an alibi!!
That's only ifwye whaLKogow i§ teJÜ® «fis. ..
That's ornly if£wê eajnjê&àfït ©h what Kogp'rio ïs tclHrJÿ iFs. ..
Wlna'fs
Are	what< l-’îffii saying?
'©fi W WfntXming LOtto WiOi?
iBWl Wy W Wking
Ofi ggwrse !l Wï.u Wê7ë; drinking ’IFtWWêj W^you?
I’m back..
Welcome back, mom.
You've both come here, I see.
Hello, Ms. Kisaki.
Hello, Conan.
I was going to bring dad here too, but he ran away....
Ms. Kisaki.
did the defendant remember that he w^iïïfîto his wife’s s.hop?
All he keeps on saying is
Which means that there is no way to make up for the time he lost
The timme heJest?
After looking at the time schedule of this case,
Conan is making weird remarks.
F l@’tfes£roughly 15 minutes to go 'from the pubfto ftlimasu.
H lt£tà’tfes£r0ughly 15 minutes to go "from the pubffe ftlirnasu.
csjrpughly 15 minutes rôm the pubrt0 Mimasu.
So, 4®) irajjnù^j is yna^^urifed for....
So, 4.© li yna^Zguiifed for....
kS@l|rT7 ___
So, 40	for....
I was just wondering what he would want to do for 40 minutes with a person
that he hates to the point of wanting to murder him....
Oh, and it's about Mr. Mouri..
No need to worry about him..
Yes..
Even if his attorney were to insist on his alibi,
But, Kogoro Mouri is also on their list of witnesses....
If I'm not mistaken, Kogoro Mouri is Attorney Kisaki’s husband, isn't he?
Yes, although they're not living with each other right now........
This is getting to be quite interesting....
Make sure you testify for mom's sake, okay!
Like I’ve been telling you,
Oh, boy...
Here, have some oden.
Thank you.
Huh.Thëré-
That's called lidako andjt seems that
Yeah! It's really delicious!!
Answer it. will you, Mama
Here you are.
Nnnah.
Yes, Wîîâîs it?
Yes, heliw, yyî^js it?
Yes>
Wis it?
Right, so that it doesn't get dirty.
Wa'ft a s'e’c?- ff/ s'Ç». .
Hey, you guys.
Hurry, and go on home!
Who cares. Kids time is over. It’s adult time!
Okay, hurry on and go on home!
Dad!
How rude.
What's the matter, Conan?
I wonder if the call he just got was from her?
She was, if I remember correctly... the prosecutor....
Yoh! I've been waiting for you!!
I wonder what she wants with dad?
Beats me..
We will now begin the first trial
of defendant Shinji Usami .
Is this all the witness the prosecutor submitted?
Yes, it's more or less what we expected.
we intend to file charges for homicide.
A real trial really can get you nervous, can't it?
Yeah..
We will begin questioning the witness now.
Your honor.
Before starting,
Mr. Kogoro Mouri
What's going on, Ms. Kisaki?
Does the defense have anything to say?
As you think proper is fine..
We shall summon Mr. Kogoro Mouri as witness then!
If so, then, she .may just win this trial
Looks really bad, Ms. Kisaki! !