The heart contains mysteries,
stars and snow sparkle for the two
The tension in the courtroom is rising.
What will happen-to: pop's:family
and the couple's case?
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance with
the I.Q. of an adult,
the IQ. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan.
Attorney Er Kisaki, Ran's mother accepts
to defend the suspect of a murder case
that is in the charge of Reiko Kujo, who is
also known as the Madonna prosecutor.
Of all things the one who has the key
to the alibi of defendant Usami
who was charged with murder, is Pops!
And worse yet,
he was summoned to court-as-a
witness for the prosecutor!
Battle in Court Kisaki vs. Kogoro Part 2
the Tokyo District Court
Ed exd 38.
RT ih KR
Mr. Mourn
Where and what were you doing
on the night the incident happened?
I was drinking sake at the restaurant
called Mimasu located in Haido city
At there, you drunk 2 cups of Sake,
And you fell asleep on the counter
of the bar.
That's right.
Reiko Kujyo
CD FLL Ce
hk BF (33)
Do you remember what time you got 7?
Reiko Kujyo
NE BF (33)
It was 21:25.
How did you find out what time it was?
I got a call on my cell phone
just as I was dozing off,
so the shopkeeper woke me up.
When I looked the watch on my
cell phone showed 21:25.
And were there any other:customers
at that time?
I was there alone, but
since the reception of my cell phone
wasn't too good,
I was heading outside,
when a man came as I was going out.
Do you remember how he looked?
Of course!
Of course! It's that man over there
HI DnlnjiLJSEIFTWI!
nt Shinji Usami!
Shinji Usami
2 LAL
FEET (40)
Shin Usami
& LA I
FER (AD)
What does this all mean?
Why would the prosecution want to prove
he alibi of the defendant?...
I don't know
I'm sure she's up to something though...
I was surprised because he took the
witness stand for the prosecutor,
but dad is on mom's side after all.
Eah, I guess so...
for now, that is...
That's all for now.
You may cross-examine the
witness now counsel.
Thank you, sir.
All right. Mr. Mouri
do you remember until around what time
the suspect Mr. Usami was at Mimasu?
I'm sure he was there for 30 minutes,
so I think he stayed till about 22:00...
In other words,
the suspect was at Mimasu
from 21:30 to 22:00, the hours that the
victim is estimated to have been killed?
Well, I guess so.
That will be all.
Alll -
Which means that the witness...
our honor...
May I ask one last question, your honor?
Granted.
Thank you.
Mr. Mourn,
you stated a while ago
that you were awakened
by the owner of Mimasu
fter you doze off...
1 Oo.
Then, where was your cell phone
at that time?
Here it comes!
Of course it was inside the
inner pocket of my coat
that was on the clothes rack
inside the counter...
Which means that it would've been
possible for someone to fool around with
the time display of your cell phone
while you were asleep...
Let's say
for example the owner of the 'shop...
No way.
Objection your honor!!
The remark.the prosecutor
just made is mere speculation!
Prosecutor please base your
remarks only on facts.
Yes, sir...
Your honor,
I would like to call on another witness,
the former wife of the defendant
as well as the owner of restaurant Mimasu,
Mrs. Masako Kameda.
He got us...
NM. Ms. Kisaki...
It's my mistake for being
overly concerned about his alibi
and failing to check into the details...
What on earth is going on, Conan?
So long as the cell phone wasn't
in Pops hand AN
the defendant's alibi is invalid.
In other words,
someone could've fooled around with the
watch of his cell phone,
call Pops at any time, then wake him up,
to make him confirm what time it is...
Next, all that has to be done is
change the time back again
when Pops takes his eyes off
the cell phone again.
It is possible for the owner of
Mimasu to do that.
ight...
Your mom, just like you
was already under the impression that the
two were not on good terms with each other
so Ms. Kisaki didn't even think that
the owner of Mimasu
would cooperate in establishing
an alibi for the defendant...
Rs..Masako Kameda...
On the night of the incident
(38)
didn't you change the time on the
cell phone of Mr. Kogoro Mourn?
(38)
didn't you change the time on the
cell phone of Mr. Kogoro Mourn?
Well?
By the way if lie under oath,
you: could be accused of perjury...
Masako?!
T's just as...
It's just as you say, prosecutor...
Then, you admit to having changed the
time on Mr. Mouri's cell phone?
Yes...
What time was it actually
when the defendant Usami came to your
shop as Mr. Mouri wentwout?
I moved the clock 30 minutes so
I think it was about 21:55.
Your honor,
the scene of the crime and the shop of the
witness is only about 10 minutes on foot,
which means the defendant had more than
enough time to carry out the crime.
El; 3)
Would the defense like to question
the witness?
Just one question.
Masako
When I asked you to talk to me
before this trial,
If ll remember correctly, I'm sure you said
you hated the defendant.
So why would you take on such a task
as making up and alibi for him?
Don't know...
That will be all.
Tokyo Prison
E823 85 La
h, Mr. Usami...
Tokyo Prison
EWES DOD B85 LL &
1-7 I
Is what your wife testified in court true?
Ow strange, though...
If you asked your wife to make up an alibi
for you why didn't you use it...?
As I've already told you,
you've got to tell me the whole truth...
Otherwise
I can't go on defending you anymore!
I don't need anyone to defend me
anymore...
Just what are you talking about?!
I'm the one who killed Hirasawa! O
Just hurry up and shove me into
jail or whatevers!!
Yes, Mouri Detective Office
Oh, Officer Takagi.
And [ how] was it?
Yeah...yeah
and what about Usami's cur ent address?
Pops...
Yea h-mmO kayfllfibtflit.
IHiiadAl IRS 10 Ccveiliylulnlimniliy.
I~llrtreat-yourtorardrnin AlaterO=Byerthen.
Conan, I'm going to go out for a while.
tT RULES
Police report on the Hirasawa case...
I thought so...
I'm back.
Huh?
Conan, where s dad?
Hey, Conan!
Ako in his stomach?...
What's this. ..7?
Hey; Conan!
Usami's Condominium
EEDA
where shall I start...?
Pops.
Eheh, heh, heh...
C,Conan?! How come you're here?!
Ran told me to keep an eye on you
so the prosecutor doesn't take
advantage of you again.
Ghads, she's ot to learn to
trust her father a bit more...
Don't you got messing the place
around too much!
Yes, sir!
So, he's Masaki
What's this?
This is the match of Mimasu...
Why would something like this be here...?
Um, Pops was there an ashtray
In this room?
Huh?
Come to think of I Ohhaven't seen any
Usami probabl doesn't smoke.
But, look there's a match box here.
Huh?
This is the match box of Mimasu...
If so, it's not odd that it's here.
But, wasn't he on bad terms with his wife?
Then why...
Married couples go through a lot of
complicated feelings,
although it may be hard for a kid like
you to understand.
Really
This is...
Xcuse me...
Is there iidako in the oden today too?
H, hi, sonny...
1 CO.
After all, it's one of the specialties of
this shop, sol can't do without it.
Do you like it, sonny?
Yep, because it's so delicious!
Oh...all right, then I'll give you some.
All right! Thank you!
You're welcome
You've got that picture too, don't you?
Huh?!
I saw it in Mr. Usami's room too.
Oh...
Huh?!
Making him take the witness stand again?
Yep, he says he goofed it the last time,
so he'd like to be given a chance
to make up for it this time.
But, with the alibi invalid and all,
what difference is-Mr. Mourn
standing witness going to do?
It seems to rave somet Ing to oO wit tye
blank time, that he talked about last time.
And he also said yousd understand
fl show you this...
This is the match box of Mimasu, isn't it?
This is
his and another thing.
He said take a good look at the contents
that was in the victim's stomach...
The contents In his stomach...
Ms. Kisaki...?
Then, Mr Mouri, let me confirm what
happened that night once again.
Around what time did you go to Mimasu?
About 19:30 like I always do.
And, when did you doze off?
20:30...
In other words, you were sleeping from
20:30 to the actual time
you were awakened at 21:55?
Yeah, I guess so.
Just what is Ms. Kisaki trying to get at?
Wonder...
I guess she just being a bad sport.
Which means that no matter what
happened inside the shop at that time,
you wouldn't have noticed, right?
Just what are you trying to get at anyway?
Let's say,
even if Mr. Usami were to have
brought the victim
to the shop while you were asleep...
Objection, your honor!
That's just groundless guess work!!
I do have something to stand on.
Please take a good look at the
victim's autopsy report.
There should be iidako inside the contents
of his stomach.
Mimasu always has iidako being that
it is one of their specialties.
By the way, I checked with all the
restaurants in the vicinity and found that
there is no other shop that includes iidako
in their menu except for Mimasu!
Let's say it was as the defense claims,
and the defendant did
in fact visit Mimasu that night,
what difference does that make?
It:makes a great difference!
Because it means that the victim has met
someone other than the defendant
that has the motive to commit murder.
Hey, hey, the only customer that was there
bac {then at the shop was me!
The person didn't have to be a customer,
right?
What?!
N,No
D,Don't be ridiculous!!
PO PS
1, Kogoro Mouri will guarantee that the
owner of Mimasu would never do
Cy Fy Fuge Fur Fd Fear Fy Fd Fay ay Say
Is what I'd like to say, but I can't!
- Cc -
w.ouecatl., LL.
The point that leads to the key
to solving this case is
the actual kind of relationship
the defendant Usami
and his wife Masako had with each other.
It is true that the relationship between
the two became quite hostile
to the point of getting a divorce after they
Iost their beloved son by accident...
But, they also believed that
the man Hirasawa was to
blame for the entire incident...
And, that night,
defendant Usami ran into the very person
who had torn them apart
and got into an argument.
After the argument they were chased
out of the shop at 20:30.
The defendant took Mr. Hirasawa to
Mimasu where Masako was...
Well, I guess you could say,
he coincidentally ran into the guy he
had held a grudge against for years,
and didn't know what to do,
so he took the victim over to his
ex wife's shop...
And that was about a little past 20:45...
On the other hand, Masako ,
who sees Hirasawa right before her eyes,
finds that all the flames of hatred that she
had almost forgotten revives within her
So, she sends the defendant home and
Iures Hirasawa out to the construction site,
which after she kills him...
After that she rushes back to Mimasu,
sees me asleep and
goes ahead to establish her false alibi...
In other words,
the false alibi that the prosecutor
saw through was not for the defendant,
but rather actually of Masako!
Just as expected of a detective.
Your story is very well made up indeed...
However,
this happens to be a courtroom
and not a place to make people
Iisten to your fantastic deductions!
This is a place to battle truth
against truth!!
Do you happen to disagree
with my deduction?
First of all,
how do you know that the defendant
went home while leaving the victim behind?
How can you tell that
he didn't ask his wife
to make up his alibi and
then take the victim out himself?
If so, then the defendant should be
insisting on his alibi to begin with, right?
Another thing.
How are you going to explain the car key of
the defendant that was found at the site?
That's simple.
The defendant, himself put it
near the corpse.
Huh?
Although the defendant left the shop alone,
he probably got worried and
returned to the shop.
There, he runs into the site
where Masako had killed Hirasawa.
The defendant probably thought as follows.
That it would be better for him to
be accused of homicide on the grounds
that he was drunk,
rather than his wife being charged...
Maybe he thought that just like Hirasawa
whofhad Killed his son,
he would be able to
get away with a lighter sentence.
That's ridiculous!!
A sentence doesn't always get lighter just
because a person is drunk, you know?!
It could be the opposite and the person
could be charged with a heavier crime...
That's because the defendant
Ioves his wife even now.
And because Masako deep down
inside still loves him too...
s proof of this
This is, the, match of Mimasu.
On the back side
Mimasu is written in romaiji.
What kind of proof are saying it is?!
A. If you read this fr
the opposite end in roma,
It reads Usami M...
In other words,
it's the name of their son Masaki...
and her name before she got divorced
back in the days,
when they were a happy family...
And the defendant after seeing that match,
found out how she really felt
so he went out of his way
to take the blame for the murder
in order to save his wife
That's a lie!
I'm the one who killed that guy!!
It's a lie that my wife did it!!
I killed him with my very hands...
hkilled Hirasawa with these hands!!
Stop it already, dear.
It's all right,
I understand very well how you feel now.
I'm so sorry that I testified the way I did...
I didn't know anything at all about the key.
Just as Mr. ouri has pointed out,
I'm the one who killed Hirasawa!
Asako...
e... ..had forgotten who I was...
Haven't we met somewhere before?
Huh, with you?
Nope, I don't think so.
Because I'd never forget
n attractive woman like you...
He messed up and broke our family up,
yet he doesn't even remember how I look.
I just couldn't forgive him...
Masako...
Kugh...
A couple mutually trying to protect
each other at first glance looks beautiful...
However, a crime is a crime...
If you really love your wife,
you should help her get back on her feet
after she makes amends for what she did.
Don't you think
that's what real love is all about...
Original Comic Books By
GO HO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
KAT JO ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor
JUNICHI I11OKA
Scripts By
KANJIS(KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INDUE
Animation Directors
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUD OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBUHORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYAS 1
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KaDA '74
Produced By.
MS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DE dn: ( ONAN
O COSHO AGYAMA SHOGAKUKAN YTV TMS
All Rights Reserved
I was completely beaten:today.
I lost completely.
Besides, to have my case turned around
Iike that not by the defense attorney,
but the witness is a first time
experience for me.
I guess, same here.
I'll see'you in the courtroom again
with the next case.
Take it easy on me then, will you...
Same here.
I need you to keep up your successive
victory record: yet Ms. Kisaki...
Huh?
It's my mission to throw dirt on her...
Dear, thank you for everything today.
I guess I'll thank you for now.
Huh?
And, about after this,
if you have some time
why don't we go to a restaurant for a meal?
Then, we can take our time and talk . .?!
Ms...
If it's okay with you,
would you let me take you out
to eat or something
D,Dad...
He seems to be very busy right now,
so I guess we can go to dinner
some other time!!
Let's go, Ms. Kuriyama.
Y,Yes...
Ugh, mother, wait!
Mother!
Really!! Dad!!!
Well, well,
it's not going to work out the way
an wants it to for a while...
What?!
Mr. Nigaki is nowhere in sight?!
Anyway, let's go search for him
before the visibility becomes zero.
Conan, wait for us in the lodge.
» «VT
Let's go, Saburo!