The heart contains mysteries,
stars and snow sparkle for the two
Valentine's Day is coming up soon!
Would you like a case with chocolates?
He sees through the oner:and only truth,
a child in appearance with
the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan.
Bloody Valentine Part 1
Valentine's my foot.
Nonsense @
Everybody's just fallen for
the tactics of the candy industry!
But, I think people on the
receiving end are ven happy!
Chocolate is good, besides!
I'll bet you're all sulky
because you're not going to get any.
Yeah you're so right!
With a body like this, all I'll be getting are
those for kids type chocolate anywa
Well, he's right...
Japan's the only country where
people are lightheartedly getting
all carried away over chocolate candies...
not even aware that St. Valentine, the one
Valentine s Day is actually in memory of,
was killed after being tortured...
Is, is that true?
But, my mother told me .
That Valentine's Day is a day when
girls create precious memories
after getting the power of love
from the chocolates
She explained that is why
chocolates are bitter and sweet.
Did you, buy chocolate, then, Ayumi?
No...
Father sai Kit was still too early for me
todo something like that...
Well, I guess it's too early for you
o be talking about love...
Andy
What did the detective agency girl
say she'd do? ?
OhOyou mean Ran?
She said that we'd be going to
a mountain lodge called Suito,
but*she didn't mention about chocolate...
op goo
Well, I sure hope it doesn't turn out to be
arbitter memory like Bloody Valentine...
Hey, hey,
Bloody Valentine... That's Al€Capone.
He made the 7 members of
the Muran family that he antagonize
all stand in front of the garage
and shot them to death
on February 14th, 1929...
Capone...
Come to think of it, he said
he was raised in the town
where Capone was
Conan, hurry; or we'll leave you behind!
Oh, yeah!
Why the hell do we have to go to a lodge
way out in the remote mountains
to make candy?
We're training ourselves to become
good wives, get it!
You can do all you like of things
Iike that at home!
Oh well, easy does it, okay...
I heard nothing about
making candy, though...
I was told that I'd get to see
a lot of cute mountain animals...
Oh, you mean you don't know?
Suito Mountain Lodge is famous for
being able to make chocolate
that will make your love come true!
What!
Which means that you're going to
hand make the chocolate,
and give it to Mr. Kyogyoku,
then finally confess your feelings to him?
Y,Yes, that's what I plan on doing...
What's the matter, Sonoko?
Makoto, ™ hasn't called recent! ¥£%.
Even if I call him, his phone is
always set at voice message...
I guess I goofed... «
I told him that I'm making chocolate for
somebody I really like, over the phone.
I went all out with this
I love you a whole lot strategy
that I didn't get to do
when I gave him the sweater...
I'm sure that's itor:
I should've told him straight
that the chocolate was for him...
Everything will be just fine!
If you send him the chocolate
m sure that Mr. Kyogyoku...
You're so strong, Ran .
Huh?
Just one week of not talking to
him makes me this sad...
But, as for you and Shinichi,
this kind of thing has been
going on all this time, right...
Yeah, well, you see,
e gotten used to it...
And besides, who cares about
whether he's around or not...
Hello, we've come to make chocolate!
How do you do?!
Oh, so you're the old lady!
The owner of the lodge
who is deceiving young women
ripping them off making candy
In a remote mountain lodge like this!!
H.Hey dad, cut it out!
'EYE;
I'm so sorry...
Chiyoko Yuasa
ART CT (61)
Oo, -7
Deceive?
Chiyoko Yuasa
AATF (61)
It's just that the press may
such a big fuss over a couple
Chiyoko Yuasa
es & CO
£33313? (61)
OO, 2 -2
that coincidentally
happened to get married
Chiyoko Yuasa
ARTF (61)
QwJAx-7
that coincidentally
happened to get married
after making chocolate
over here about 10 years ago,
and that reputation stands to this day!
My husband who was the previous owner
also passed away 4 yearns ago,
and thanks to a succession of
spook scandals
the number of guests
ecreased drastically...
A spook scandal?
Well, I advise you all not to go outside
alone because a snowstorm is coming!
That is, if you don't want the spook
that lives here to give you a strange gift...
A strange gift ?
Chocolate
This mountain is pretty intricate,
and there are many people
who get into trouble here.
The weird thing is,
every year during thisseason,
chocolate is left
near the corpse that is found.
The local people say that,
Yoshitaka Nigaki
Dre Es. ED»
{£ J (28
Oy WMA
it could be the-curse of a girl
who was heading for this lodge
Yoshitaka Nigaki
{+ 4% (28)
in onder to make chocolate,
but died on the way, after getting lo
Or that it could be the show woman.
There are various rumors going around...
S. Snow woman?!
But, there's nothing to worry about.
The police say that
it's just that the chocolate
that is inside the belongings of the one's
who get into accidents in'these mountains
are scattered about, because of
the hungry animals looking for food...»
ay...I'lllbe going off to work, then.
Bye!
Mr Nigaki?
Huh?
I'm not against you pursuing it
enthusiastically but...
Don't let the show woman get:to yo.
Mika Konakawa
Ill RR (26)
o/Jmak
because of your enthusiasm
and get yourself lost in the woods.
Mika Konakawa
WN Te IR (20)
OvJ/ maw
I'll be just fine!
If the Snow woman offers me chocolate,
I'll tell her...
that I've got a girlfriend
alled Ako already...
Ako Amar
HF IEF (25)
Late
Come off it, Yoshitaka .
Ako-Amari
HH & FRY)
Lap ill
IIl/Jllifi!
See you, then...
Huh? What is it, sonny?
He said he was going to work,
but what does he do?
He's a journalist...
He went.out to get films and pictures
that would serve as evidence of
a case he has been pursuing
from about 5 years ago!
Since I'm a photographer,
I used to accompany him too,
In the beginning
because he insisted
he saw it in the forest
S Saw it"...Don't tell me that...
it was the s,. snow woman?!
He's pursuing an animal
that actually existed!
Well, I guess it's not much
different from the snow woman
In terms that it is pretty much
a phantom too...
A phantom...?
Ight...
Ever since it was caught
and killed in 1905...
Yuzo Sakami
BE 6 - (42)
The phantom:mammal that hasn't be
seen for over a period of a hundred ye
Yuzo Sakami
FEE 176E012)
O//mAa%
and was written extinct on the red list.
Rs SN
Yuzo Sakami
AR B= ER)
0,/maw
and was written extinct on the red list.
The Japanese wolf!
Oh...a wolf...
Is it okay. though?
To go after such a valued animal
with a hunter's rifle like that...
Oh, you mean this rifle?
This rifle is used to threaten the wolf
and corner into the trap...
granny, take care of my friend that
will be coming here soon, will you?
Talk about everybody getting
infatuated over wolves!
Okay then, I guess I'll be on my way too.
When that guy's friend comes,
show them to their rooms, will you...
You mean you're leaving too?
I'm going to visit my husband's grave
that is in the woods!
Are you going to be okay,
going-'there all alone?
These mountains are like my backyard...
Besides, Saburo will go with me too!
Saburo?
Oh, good boy, good boy!
Oh, it's a dog...
Don't tell me that the journalist
who just went out...
mistook that.unleashed dog for a wolf?
No way!
It was 10:00 at night
when he saw the wolf...
Then, the more so...
Saburo is put in his cage after it gets dark.
Oh, I see...
Okay, so shall we start making
chocolate whileygranny's out!
Oh, okay, yes!
Huh?
That granny's not the one
who's g ing to teach?
She didibefore, but...
We're the ones who teach the guests now!
It's our way of thanking her for putting us
up here every time at this timewof year.!...
Oh...
But, granny does do the finishing touches
on the chocbolatésfeven now, though!
Nam a
I guess that thing about
Iove what-nuts is something
you can't really look forward to then...
Oh, shut up!
Okay, only three more days
to Valentine's Day!!
Let's givelt our best shot!!
Let's give it our best shot!!
Granny's husband died in an avalanche...
Yes...
4 years ago, on February the 14th...
It seems that he was buried
under the snow for a week
until Saburo dug him out...
The other one was never dug out after all...
Huh? Another one...
Y brother...
Is whereabouts have been
nknown ever since...
The police say that he's probably
buried under the snow...
But I can't help feeling that he's still alive...
That's why I come here every year!
And besides I visit
the previous owner's grave too!
I'm sorry for talking about
something so glum...
Oh no, not at all
can we help with something?
No, no, guys stay out!
You'll get hurt like Mr. Nigaki did!
1.I'm sorry.
There...
Okay!
All right, I'm almost done!!
Oh, how: lovely!
Pretty good, pretty good!
Very true!
Okay, so why don't we all take a picture
together with the chocolate!
Okay!
The blizzand is getting stronger...
I wonder if Mr. Nigaki is okay...
Uh, sorry, but we'll go check on Mr Nigaki
So, wait here okay?!
Kay...
Huh? Where are you going...
We'll be right back!
Mr. Nigaki, where are you?!
Mr. Nigaki!!
Mr Nigaki!!
What?!
Mr. Nigakigissnowhere in sight?!
Yeah, we split up to search for him, but
The blizzard's getting worse!
Anyway, let's go search for him
before the visibility becomes zero.
Conan, wait here in the lodge.
All right!
Like I'd do that...
Let's go, Saburo!
Yoshitaka!!
Mr. Nigaki!!
Where are you?!
Mr. Nigaki!
Where are you, Mr. Nigaki?!!
Hey!! Answer me!!
Where are you?!
Mr. Nigaki!!
What?
The sound of a rifle?!
Ooks bad...
Maybe he got to it first?
Who are you?
I'm a guest staying at
Suito Moutain Lodge...
Hajime Itakura
OOQ Q2
Id J 718000
I'm a guest staying at
Suito Moutain Lodge...
Hajime Itakura
0. JmAa%
oO oma%
Darn, where the hell are you,
r Nigaki...
Hey, Saburo?!
MM. Mr. Nigaki?
Mr. Nigaki?!
No good, he's not breathing...
He was beaten to death...
What's this?
T,This is
chocolate?!
Yoshitaka, please answer me!!
O ooeol
The blizzard's getting worst!!
Hey, what are you going to do?
If we keep on searching
the mountain like this,
We Ill end up dead ourselves.
B,But, we can't just leave Mr. Nigaki*and...
Huh?
A dog?!
In a remote mountain like this?
Could it be Saburo?
It can't be,
because he should be back at the lodge!
D.,Don't tell me it's Conan?!
C Conan?!
Just what are you doing here?!
I told you to stay at the lodge, didn't I ?!
L,I'm sorry...
But, Ms. Konakawa said a while ago that...
when.the previous owner of the lodge
gotycaught in an avalanche,
Saburo dug him out!
» Pa ~
Ih, 1 CO...
That's why I thought that maybe Saburo
would be able to find Mr. Nigaki too!
Since Mr. Nigaki had come to
the lodge many times
I was sure that Saburo would
be familiar with his smell too!
And? Did you find Mr. Nigaki?
Yep...ll found him...
But, he's already cold...
What!!
This isn't happening is it, Yoshitaka...
Yoshitaka?!
Stay away!!
Look!
His face is smeared with blood...
And this fat blood stained branch
that is on the ground right beside him...
This is undoubtedly a homicide case...
Now that we know it's a murder,
we can't mess this site up anymore...
Murder...
h no...
Hey, what's with that
g shot attitude of your...
You're not a police detective
or something, are you...
ah...You're right about m
not being a police detective anymore...
But, I am an ex-officer and now detective,
Kogoro Mouri!
What?!!
M,Mouri, don't tell me that you re that...
Renown detective?!
Then, do you know who the killer is ?
Because his body is frozen from this cold
making¢it impossible
to figure out the estimated time of death.
Moreover, the wind has
blown away the footprints...
the only thing that may be left as a clue 1s
that Mr Nigaki's blood may have
stained the killer s clothes...
I'm pretty sure
he was killed in the day time...
The reason why the blood on Mr. Nigaki s
face is wiped off part way us,
that it had been wiped off
when something rubbed against it
And the fact that he is still wearing
his goggles goes to show that
he was killed when it was still bright,
and the blizzard hadn't come yet!
It would be too dangerous to move along
insthis'blizzard with these goggles on...
I see... . Just as would be
expected of a renown detective...
Fuh, it's no big deal"
This is a mere first step
n any investigation...
I wonder about that...
Ot you again...
Take a good look inside his goggles!
His left contact lens is out of place!
You idiot!
That's probably because
he killer punched him...
But, he's not wearing
contact lens in his right eye,
nor is it inside his goggles!
T, True.
Oh, I get it!
The right one probably fell to the ground
when he was punched,
and at the same time his sunglasses moved
out of place, so the killer fixed it for him!
I OTT...
(3) - -
I OTC...
hat a meticulous killer...
Hey, this is no time to be convinced...
Uh- could it"be that
the killer deliberately made him wear it?
Huh?
That's right
But, why do something like that?
Come to think of it,
I found something strange!
See, this chocolate!
I found it on his stomach!
Hmm...
Yoshi is written on it...
Huh?
H.Hey, isn't that the chocolate
you made today, Ako?
WwW, Why?
Why is my chocolate over here. ?
Aren't you the one who
put it near the corpse?
Ako couldn't have done it!
The chocolate was in the kitchen
until we all left the lodge...
She was with us right through after that...
Then, who put the chocolate over here...
robably the killer...
The corpse has been touched here there
and everywhere too it seems...
It's pretty likely that
the killer brought it here
to make it look like
Ako committed the crime!
At any rate, let s talk this over
after returning to the lodge
and contacting the police...
The police are not going to be
able to get here for a while.
Huh?
Hey, Mr. Sakami,
I'm surprised that you found this place...
I heard the dog barkin
Never mind that.
Just what do you mean by
the police can't come here?
The tunnel located partway along the road
that leads from the foot of
the mountain to the lodge
has been blocked off by an avalanche
that occurred about 30 minutes ago!
I'm pretty sure it's going to take
at least a day
before they can open up the road again
Oh no!
Seriously?!
T, Then, what is it?
Are you saying that we're going to have to
spend the night at the lodge tonight?
When the one who killed
Nigaki may be among us?!
I don't give a hoot?
That's more thrilling besides...
If you don't want to spend
the night over at the lodge,
why don't you spend the entire night
beside your big brother who was killed?
But, by day break you may have
turned into Snow Woman though...
The remains of the blood stain
hat was wiped off...
Sunglasses that were replaced on him
d...Ako s chocolate.
Why did the killer go out of the way to
bring Ako's chocolate out of the kitchen?!
Why on earth?!
Original Comic Books By
COS HO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIRO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By
KANJI'KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INO
Animation Directors.
AsATOMO Supo
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN]! KGDAMA
ProdncodsBy
TERTAINMEN
wr HE ASSULatiurrg 1,
' )  8
awe 3"
DEIECI] ECON AN
C COSHO AOYAMA SHOC ARUKAN YIN IMS
All Rights Reserved
It's a picture that was taken
when he was punched!!
Huh? How can you tell?
Come to think of it,
before I met all of you here,
I ran Into a queer guy in the woods...
Huh?!
A huge guy wearing a black knitted cap!
A man wearing a black knitted cap...
on:t tell me; it's him...
(ET ER)
Bloody Valentine Part 2