The heart contains mysteries,
stars and snow sparkle for the two.
Valentine's Day is coming up soon}
Both love and the case get to the core.
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance with
the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan!
We all came to a lodge called
Suito Mountain Lodge
Iocated in a remote
mountain area together
with Sonoko, who invited us...
However, one of the guests
staying at the lodge,
a journalist named Yoshitaka Nigaki
fails to return to the lodge 2
after going inte the woods
despite a violent blizzard...
After awhile of searching for
Nigak! in the woods.
We found him dead
Blood stains that have been wiped off...
Sunglasses that have been
put back on him .
AndOAko"s chocolate...
Why did the killer bring the chocolate
from the kitchen to where it was found?
Why on earth?!...»
(# Btw)
Bloody Valentine Part 2
(3 BR)
And, what did they say?
ChiyoKo Yuasa
(Owner of the lodge)
Did the police say they'll be right. ove
IyO 0 uasa
(Owner of the lodge)
BRTFLF (61)
QwJd-F
An avalanche is a lie, right?
There seems
have been an avalanche
about 8.00 this evening and
the tunnel seems to be blocked off...
They say they don't know when
they'll be able to come
here until tomorrow...
See! It's just as I saidOO
Oh, how was the chocolate?
It was gone after all
Just Ako's chocolate...
Darn!
I brought back Mr. Nigaki's
camera and video camera
thinking that we could get some clues,
but thé video tape is unused...
The only clue we have left now is
the used roll of film that
is left I Sidé his camera...
But, if the forensic officers can't come,
we can't develop-the. film...
Oh...l can develop and print the picture
if you want me to.
Huh?
Since Mr. Nigaki said that
he wanted to see the pictures
right away after he took pictures of them
I brought a set of
the necessary equipments
Let me use your bathroom. okay?
It's just right to usesfor a darkroom
Yeah, go ahead...
I"1 help you then!
Hey. was that all that was inside?
Weren't there any more films or tapes
in the knapsack
of the guy who was killed?
Yeah, there were...
but the films and tapes
were all unopened...
Which means that the guy was killed
before he filmed anything on video...?
Or'maybe Mr. Nigaki preferred
taking pictures to filming videos...
That's not true!
He preferred filming videos
to taking pictures.
He was filming a lot last night too...
Can you show us that video tape then?
OO. Okkayrsoo
there are a lot if) his bag.
SO I don't know if we can tell
which one is last flight's but...
F.Forget it. kid!
Let's not watch the video
a dead man took...
Huh?
Did he film something he shouldn't have?
That's not what I mean...
t's Kind of eerie...
Why don't we all watch it
together in the living room?
Okay...
If we. watch:it'together
we may'be.able:toifind a clue...
I'll go get it from his room then...
Oh, is this the love chocolate
you're going to give me?!
Wisong...dl This is for me!
Hey. hey. don't tell me you're giving
it to someone else...
uld be...
It sure is no fun watching
somebody elses home Video after all...
I'm going to make
your €hocolate with the girls
that are coming to spend
the night here tomorrow.
Why are you keeping me
in suspense for
Irve got @ super gift for yow too. you know.
I've got a super gift for you too. you know»
I've got a super gift for you too, you know.
Huh?
Darn!
What a lemon!
Come onl!
Come mun
Sorry. it's a lemon...
This is a treasure that
my hdisband bought
for the first time with Reiko!
Reiko?!
She was fy husand's ex-wife.
I was told that she died
12 years ago because of an illness...
_y ay Ry
Hey, Saburo!
It's time for you
to go back to your cage already!
She remarried him
I've heard about them
from the previous owner too.
This granny came to spend the night here
just when he was depressed
after having lost his wife.
And they hit it off right from the
start and got married just like that!
Granny's sweets were highly reputable
and this lodge was going
well for a while but...
I guess it's tough without
husband after all...
You heard about this before, you said?
That means you both come here a lot?
N.Nope. just once in the past.
Hey, by the way, is that
the last of the 4 video tapes we watched?
Yes...that's all of the videos
with yesterday's date on it...
Okay. so there's only so
much left of this video tape!
I'm going to challenge making chocolate
for the first time in my life starting now,
SO goodbye everyone.
Good grief...it's finally ended...
You two don't seem
to have been in the video?
O,of course, I just got here this morning!
I just got here a while ago...
SO. Were Mack to where we started.
We've figured out
what time Mr. Nigaki was killed. though!
Huh
Take a look at this picture!
It's a picture that was taken
when he was punched Mt
Huh
How can you tell?
Do you see this blurred shadow?
It's not in any of the other pictures,
just this last one...
This is theyshadow formed by
7 blood stains on the cameraYvens!!
What?!!
The shutter probably
went off accidentally
after he was punched and fell to
the ground from the shock...
But, you can't really tell
if those are blood stains yet...
There's no mistake about it!
We put film in his camera
and tried it out,
and got the exact same result.
Which means he was killed
uring the day time...
Something's not right...
Mika's explanation
doesn't make sense!
In other words, the killer
may be among the three of you...
Who were not at the ledge
with us during that time .
Hey. hey...
Then, what's with that chocolate?
It was here at the lodge
until 8:00 at night, wasn't it?
Just who brought it out then?!
In the first place,
what stupid person would go back out
into the blizzard just to put
the chocolate near the corpse!!!
T.That's true...
It could be that...
it really exists...
in this mountain. a being other than us...
WwW. What do you mean,
1 being other than us.
Come to think of it,
before I met all of you here,
I ran into a queer guy in the woods...
Huh?!
A huge guy wearing a black knitted cap!
I mistook him for a bear
and almost shot him.
A black knitted cap ?!
It.It can't be...
ont tell me...
A man wearing @ black knitted cap...
Don't tell me. it's him
Uh, excuse me...
T.The person you saw in the woods.
Do you remember what he looked like?
Huh
I may know him...
I wonder...
I could tell that he was
a man from his physique but...
he had goggles and a muffler on so
I didn't get to see his face at all...
see...
It could ve been Natsuya
I'm sure it was...
It's Natsuyal!
He was alive after all...
Let's gO@et him
Mika
No way!!
You can't go out in this blizzard!
H.He's. Natsuya's waiting in the woods!
Natsuya's waiting...
NatSuya died!!
Hé died in the avalanche -4 yeas ago!!!
M sorry...
I'm sorry, Mika...
h...who is Natsuya...
He's my older brother whose whereabouts
have been unknown since 4 years ago
Mika was going stead, with him
Sc. the checkered chocolate that Mike
was making this afternoon was...
Yes...l was going to take
he chocolate to his grave...
because he liked checkered patterns.
My brother grave is also in the woods
beside the graves of
the previous owner and his ex-wife...
Not only the graves of
e three are here...
In this forest there are the graves of
those who have died in this mountain,
whose identities are unknown...
But. all but the three graves were all destroyed
by the mountain animals.
Why are only the three
graves left undestroyed?
Probably because I pay visit
to them everyday with Saburo...
Just like my husband
used: to when he was alive...
Well, but if you insist that
someone other than us,
are in the mountains...
The guy wearing the black knitted cap
roaming around in the woods
is definitely the killer.
What do you mean?
I have no idea when that guy
called Nigaki was killed but...
the guy who left the chocolate
next to him is the killer. right?
All six of you left the
chocolate in the kitchen .and
went out about 8:00,
to look for Nigaki. right?
If everyone found the chocolate together,
it's impossible to put
the chocolate there...
I met all six of you near the lodge.
It was probably right after you all
Ieft the lodge to look for Nigaki.
It would take 20 minutes to get
from the lodge to the site of the crime,
which is the woods,
no matter how much I rush.
So. I would have no time
to put the chocolate there.
And of course,
I wouldn't have been able to do it either
At around 8:00 I was far away
from the lodge watching the tunnel
get buried under the avalanche...
you could've heard about
the avalanche on the radio news...
No. because the avalanche
was announced just about the same time,
we got back:to the lodge
and called the police...
Well, the only one who
could've brought the chocolate is
that lady there who
was making the chocolate...
Huh
I hear that before everybody
went out together,
you and the other lady left together
to look for the guy, right?
You two weren't together
all the while, were you?
N.No, we split up part way
and searched for him...
If you made similar type of
chocolate the night before,
you could've placed
the chocolate near Nigaki
when you went out the first time and...
if you secretly took the chocolate
that you madéOftoday together with you
when you went out to
search with everybody else,
you could make it look as if
the¥Killer took it...
S.Oh no...
That's impossible
Huh?
There w $ a blizzard.outside already
when we went to.look for
him the first time!
If he was killed then,
th re should be'snow.in: this picture
picture that was taken at
the time of the crime too. shouldn't there?
What about the chocolate...
Why §6n't you compare them, then?
Took a picture of all the chocolato
that everybody made today...
If you take a close-rook.
The chocolate that was found
at the scene of the crime is a bit melted
and dented slightly out of shape...
I would sure like to meet a person
who can shape the letters
exactly the same: like this,
as well as insert it onto
the chocolate so much alike as it is.
What she's saying is,
your deductions are off.
Y.,Yeah...
well, that's for the better. isn't it...
Now we know the killer isn't among us
I can sleep without worrying then.
Goodnight then, everybody.
Goodnight then. everybody
Which means...
the killer is the man
earing the black knitted cap...
hh... . you know the film that was
Mr. Nigaki s camera. are you sure
the pictures are tic one ) tht ere taken
by Mr Nigaki yesterday and today?
What?
Because it was already used
and wound, wasn't it?
It could've been inserted
some time later, right?
Then. would you like to look at and
sompaie he other pictures in this film?
The video that
he filmed yesterday is also here...
The clothing of the three are all the same
in the Pictures andtinsthe video...
And of course. «Mr. Nigaki who is
taking the pictures and
filming is virtually not included...
Moreover, mostwef the pictures
were taken at night
The fact that at the end of this film
there was that blood
tained picture means...
the pictures were-taken
this afternoon doesnat it?
Nobody's gone outside since
we arrived at the lodge yesterday
to the time he left with
his camera this afterfdon...
Which means that he's the
only one who could've take the picture!
Well, the only other possibility is that
some trick is used when de eloping film
How could I have done
something like that
Ran was with me right through
while I was developing the film!
Right
Right?
Oh, yes, she didn't do anything strange.
Nd besides.
she even used a glove
when taking the film out of the camera
SO that he wouldn't put
he fingerprints on the film.
Moreover: if you look at the negative
I'm sure you can see
that nothing was done to it...
Right. if there was anything strange.
There was a picture
that was completely black.
Completely black?
There W 8 two of them
the pi&turO with blood stains @n them...
Pictures that were completely black
and you couldn't see anything...
Really?
Uh-huh...
I think the shutter just
accidentally went off
when something was over
the Tens covering it...
Just as I thought...
The picture with the blood stain on
it is A trick after all!
But. I can't figure it out.
How can you take a picture like that?
And what baffles me more is
fro chocolate that was by the corpse...
Putting something like that there,
would nullify the trick...
Hey, Saburo
Don't tell me that the killer is actually
It's your favorite ball!
Ronit tell me that the killer is actually
Donrt tell me that the killer is actually
that man wearing the black knitted cap
who is hiding in the woods?
Huh? Strange...
when I came last year, you loved
playing with the ball. Saburo...
why is the name ofithat dog Saburo?
Because before him there was
a Tare and Jiro: but they both died...
Huh? They died?
Yeah, Taro was the name of my husband.
It seems that Jiro was
a Shikoku dog just like Saburo.
But after the death of his first wife
it seems to have died as
if going after her...
I want to see he picture of
that dog named Jiro!
I think I can find pictures
of Jiro in my husband's album...
If I remember correctly, Mr Nigaki
was 'using my husband:siroom...
Oh. would you like me to go andlgenit?
I'll go with you then?
Uh- does:Saburo have some
odd-habits or something?
Like going out on walks
a lot and stuff like-that?
Nope. he usually stays inside the lodge...
T.he:only:time:he goes out is when
e-comes:aong: 0 egravewl me...
He's smart...
so when we get near
the grave he runs ahead of me
and waits for me in front of the grave...
Come to think of it.
When there is a blivzard
and he can't go out,
he doesn't eat his dog food...
although he usually
eats it on regular days
Well: buton-the:day after the blizzard
he seems back to his normal self
and pigs.out on the food...
Oh...
Isn't that Ako's voice...
What's the matter?!
Talk about rude!!
T, y were in here
going through Nigaki's things!
What?!
Oh, no, it's not what it looks to be...
We just thought there may be clues
to solving the case, so!
We didn't take anything...
Okay. I guess I'll have to body check you.
Yeah...
Let's go to the room over there.
A blood stained parker
The blood stains are
not on the stomach area
Oh, that's the parker
that Mr. NigaKi was wearing
when he got hurt!
Ur? when he got hurt...
He hurt his left hand thumb when
he was dicing chocolate with a knife...
It wasn't much of a wound
but he was surprised
and flung his hand around
so the blood splattered
onto His parker too
Granny rushed to get
he first aid box and turned it over
Ako, who worried about him
breaks out in tears
It was a total mess, with me holding him
down from going wild and all.
Well, the worst part was looking after Ako
who got super depressed after that
Right?
Oh, sorry.
@h, here, here,
here it is!
See, the dog to the left is Jiro
and the dog to the right.is Saburo!
He's wearing a medal
he was awarded by the prefecture
when he rescued alperson who got into
an accident in the mountains...
Huh
I wonder if the one to the left is Saburo
and the one to the right is Jiro...
Just as I thought...
I've figured out the case...
Now I know why there
were black pictures taken
before the blood-stained picture...
Who took the chocolate out and
why it was put near the corpse.
Who killed Mr Niga
That is...
That person!!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO_AOYAMA
Original Comic Books By.
GOSH AWGYAMA
Producers
MIGHIHIRO SUWA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO Sum?)
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KANJI'KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARY KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
y 4d » >»
TOSHIKI INOUE
Ammdtion Dircalors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKI KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYOD
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director:
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KCDDAMA
Produced By
EN ERTAINMENT
in associdtion with
YOMIURI TELECASTING °°
CORPORATION
Ir 1 JIN EGON AN
CXEONHO AY AM Av SHOGARUKAN YTV TM
UI Ry his Reserved
PREVIEW
You found out who the killer is?!
A.Are you serious, sonny?
PREVIEW
And. who is it?
15 it that man With the black knitted cap?
PREVIEW
Well, Mr. Mouri says he'll explain
all that in the kitchen to you now!
PREVIEW
In other words,
REVIEW
PREVIEW
NO one else other than
you can be the killer!
PREVIEW
Don't move!
WE RR