The heart contains mysteries.
Stars and snow sparkle.for the two.
It has been 3 days since
the murder case happened.
What's the destiny of Ran and Sonoko?
He sees "Arough the one and only truth,
a child in appearance with
the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan.
To -7
WoO 1 Grins Oe) (0CAgo
ered) $3 Wolonmietin I oy)
Iocated in a remote mountain area
together with Sonoko, who invited us...
However, one of the guests
staying at the lodge,
a journalist named Yoshitaka Nigaki
fails to return to the lodge after going
Into the woods despite a violent blizzard...
After awhile of searching
for Nigaki in the woods,
We found him in dead.
Just as I thought...
I've figured out the case...
Now I know why there were black pictures
taken before the blood-stained picture...
Who took the chocolate out
and why it was put near the corpse...
who killed Mr. Nigak
That person!!
The Truth of Valentine
Case Solved
eo (Co
eo (Vo
uM rd
Now, all I need is the evidence
db #*
The evidence of the one
who took the chocolate out of here...
So long @8 I can get-seme_evidence of
the one who killed Mr. Nigaka...
So-longrasilikcan-get some evidence of
we. one who killed Mr Nigaku...
Huh
Sonokds chocolate is
the one in the foreground...
The checkered one next to it is Mika's...
Them Ram's is...
Hey. what are you doingr
Hu he
ow come he's here... :
Yikes ?!
WwW. What?!
You found out who the killer is?!
A.Are you serious, sonny?
And. who is it?
Chiyoko Yuasa
(Owner of the lodge)
BRFLF (61)
Ow Jd -2
Is it that man with the black knitted ¢
Chiyoko Yuasa
(Owner of the lodge)
BR FRF (61)
UwJ3-7
Well. Mg. ouri says he'll explain
all that in the kitchen to you from now!
Okay!
I've come, Mr. Detective.
Now that you know who the killer is...
Does that mean that you've figured out
the identity of the man
wearing the black knitted cap?
No, there is no need to
check on the identity of that man...
Because the one who
killed Mr. Nigaki is right here.
WwW. What?!
Are you kidding me?!
I thought we already told you
that it was impossible for us
to put the chocolate near the corpse
under the situation we were in!!
Ight/the chocolate...
The key to solving that
mystery was not us...
utWimnu.
S.Saburo?!
Then, you mean the one
who is holding the case is Saburo?!
Yes...thanks to him
I've figur dfSut the mystery of why
the chocolate was
near Mr. Nigaki's corpse.
Are you saying that the dog was the
one who brought the chocolate out here?
After you guys left the: Chocolate back
at the lodge and went to look for Nigaki
that dog was brought outside
by the boy wring the glasses, right?
If the boy who was together with
the dog was the first to find the corpse,
how is the dog going to
et the chocolate...
es... it's true that the do
was with Conan...
This Saburo...definitely was...
T,This Saburo?
Yes...
I realized this when
I saw Saburo liking round things
to the point of playing with the daruma,
showed no interest at all
in the video that we watched last night...
And when I heard that
the previous owner used to take
aburo and go visit the grave everyday...
Taking into consideration that
only specific:graves
were not attacked by wild animals
this assumption was easy to come by...
That the previous owner
probably made Saburo keep watch over
Ris ex wife's grave all day...
a. ha. ..just what are you talking about
How the hell are they going to let this dog
who is always being put back in his
cage every night watch the grave...?
It is impossible as you say...
If there is only one dog...
What?!
You know about it, granny, don't you?
About the dog that your
husband told you died 12 years ago
Saburo and the existence
of Jiro who hadktwo nails...
Well, I should've realized it
when I saw the dent on the chocolate
and the melted part of it
The fact that there were
two Saburos, and that the marks
on the chocolate was made
by a dog holding it in its mouth...
Whate!
To put it accurately, one was Jiro...
Each time they went to the grave,
they watched over it alternately .
He probably lied saying that Jiro ad died
out of his consideration
for granny. his later wife.
I see...
If that's how he was trained.
Than he would eat only every other day
That's why he didn't eat
when he couldn't go out
on stormy days and change places...
Then, the wolf that Mr Nigaki
said he saw in the woods was...
Probably either Jiro or Saburo...
They were also delivering
chocolate to the victims of accidents...
That's ridiculous!
Why.would:a: mere dog
arry off chocolate...
They were not mere dogs.
They were life saver rescue dogs,
efficient enough to win
awards for saving lives!
It can all be explained
if they were trained to give chocolate
that is highly nutritious to
accident victims, explanation is easy...
And that the actions of the dogs doing so,
was limited to this time of year
when a large amount
of chocolate was stocked...
The blood on Mr. Nigaki's face
was wiped off part way because
the dog thought he was
a victim of an accident
and tried to lick him to wake him up...
H.Hey. wait!
If the dog was the one
who took the chocolate
then anybody could've
committed the crime.
Just what are you talking about?
You saw it yourself, didn't you?
The blood stained picture
I showed you during the day!
In other words,
the killer is one of yo two who have
no alibi during the day tolBack you up...
Don't you think there-s
something odd~aboutsthat picture?...
Huh?
That picture was the last one in the film
and it was wound after that.
The killer would've most
naturally heard the sound of the
buzzing sound of the film being wound...
But the killer did not
ake that film away...
Despite the fact that
the Killer might be in the picture.
T.True...
But, why?
That's because that picture
was not taken at the time of the:crime...
It was a picture that Mr Nigaki had
casually taken during the day!
Unaware at that time
that his blood stains were
already on the lens from the nightibefore!
Last night, you mean
the night he cut his finger with the knife...
Yes...
the blood that stained only
the stomach part of the parker
parker he was wearing
back then as the evidence .
It's most likely that the blood stained
the lens of the camera that
he was hanging from his neck...
Yes.
The killer made Mr. Nigaki
take pictures with the camera
with blood stains on
its lens during the day,
promised:to meet:him that evening.
Hit and killed him
then put his sunglasses back on.-him.
This way, the killer made
it look like Mr. Nigaki
was killed during the day...
n thar words...
No one else other than
you can be the killer!!
In other words,
Ne one else other than you
can be the killer! Ms. Ako Amari
Huh?!
It can't be...
H.How can Ako be the Killer...
It can't be!...
Because we went to look: for
him after the blizzard started,
and the sun was still high!!
That's why you went to get him earlier!
Because if the blizzard got worse and
he decided to return to the lodge
before the time he promised
to meet her, everything would be in vain.
By the way
the reason why
there were two black pictures
before the pic ure
with the blood stain on it ws
to leave room for just one mere picture...
If space for three more pictures are left,
then the other two pictures would
also have blood stains on them,
and the pictures
would turn out strange...
She probably switched
all the other films and video tapes
to unused ones for the same reason.
B.But, I could've used
the same trick If I wanted to too...
No. only Ako could've done it!
In order to keep the
blood stained film inside
the camera after
the crime was committed,
the trick wouldn't
work unless all the films
that he had in his back pack are
completely r 'moved beforehand...
If there are other used
films in his knapsack
after the crime is committed,
it would be impossible to tell
which film is the one
with the blood stain
ight
singe You were with him right through
taking) are of his wound
you're the only one
who could've removed the films
without being suspected at all.
Would you like to take.a look at them?
; The tapes that you
collected. and disposed of,
after committing thecrime?
Huh?
The film that Mr. Nigaki took of you
when you went to
meet him in the blizzard...
He delivered it to us
He probably thought
that you had forgotten it
and brought the bag
with a lot-of Video tapes in it back here...
I haven't confirmed the
contents of the tapes yet
but tapes from 4 years ago
ere among them too...
That is most likely...
Right...
that's the scene of the previous owner
trying to help my older brother
whO was hunt and couldn't move
get buried under @A avalanche. ,...
It's a cruel tape that was being filmed
from the woods in the distance...
Don't tell me that
Mr. Nigaki kept rolling the film
without going to help at all?!
because my brother was
against me going steady with him...
I found that tape when
I was looking for clothes for him
to change in after Yoshitaka got hurt...
After seeing the date of 4 years ago,
I figured that this was the present
he was going to have ready for
me and watched it in secret...
That's why you were crying...
I didn't think that Saburo was
going to take my chocolate to him...
Maybe Saburo already knew
what I Was going to do...
He probably knew
hat I was the Killer too...
As well as the fact that
I really did love Yoshitaka...
What a stupid thing«to;do...
You don't even know
if Mr. Nigaki really filmedeither...
I Know he did...
There was a loud.sound twice,
nd then the avalanche.
His voice was In the tape too...
Sorry Natsuya,
I" aking your little sister.
Ioud! sound! twice...
Iey, wait a sec...
It's this sound that
you heard on the tape, isn't it?...
Right
we're the ones who
aused that avalanche...
We mistook her older brother
for a wolf and shot him
We were called out here,
and told by Nigaki to "Dish out cash.
He told us that if the:whereabouts of
the corpse was found through the video
and a bullet is found in his body,
we would be finished...
Thanks for getting rid of him for us.
Either way
we were going to cause an avalanche
stall him and kill him slow and easy...
All of you, line up beside the detective!
Hurry up'?
What do I do.now:?
I've already used the anesthesia gun and
I don't have my super kick shoes either.
So... .how shall we cooky Tguys...
H Help.
Elp somebody...
Otherwise I won't be...
able to give him this chocolate...
Okay. you brown-haired one!
Stab your friend that's next to you
with the knife that's behind you!
What?!!
Come on. quit stalling!
W. Who is it?!
Hey. go take a look!
Okay...
Huh~~~~7?
Hey. is anybody there?!
W.Who the hell are you?!
S.Stop!!
Don't move!
H, Hey I'm telling you, don't move!
Don't move...
Don't worry
If I concentrate on
the direction of the gun barrel
and his finger on the trigger
I can dodge the bullet
Darn you!
Don't take me lightiy!!
I'm not taking you lightly
I was just stating fact...
Darn!
If you think you ean dodge my bullet,
go ahead and try!!
Ma... Makoto...
You rat!
Over here!
Over here)
Th81 MUS???) hill 1t...
MMakoto. what brings you heme?
I came to check out the man you: care for
To see if he is really good for you!
Huh?
Please don't play dumb with me!!
The one that you made
the hand knitted sweater for; the one you
bought the tea cup for and this time
the guy's whose going to
receive the chocolate you made!
Where is that lucky guy?
It's you...
uh?!
See...
By the way, although Sonoko,
quit knitting the sweater half finished,
she did send you the tea cup...
Oh, I thought that was a flower vase...
Is everything clear now?
H, yes...
I...Il gue 2 kill be on my way. then.
Hey. wait a minute!
You've come all the way out here,
so please take this with you too!
Here
Oh, t.thank you so much...
Wow.
Her love attack is
really working out well
By the way. Sonoko,
I wonder about that
animal pattern outfit that you're wearing
I'm happy for you, Sonoko...
The-police arrived after day break
The horror of the
snowy mountain passed over
together with the blizzard...
Then, February 14th
nally comes along...
Uh, why didn't you write
anything on your chocolate?
I was going to write
something later secretly!
Deny an BS RS
I'm going-to the airport
to see Makoto off then, okay...
Good luck!
Sonoko...
I can't write anything on it...
Your feelings don't reach the one you
want to give the chocolate to
if you give it after Valentine's Day...
I can't make myself
write the name of someone
who don't even know
the whereabouts of...
Mm home...
Maybe I should give
this chocolate to dad...
Ran. you sure are strong...
I really... wish I were all that strong...
Don't cry, you fool...
it cry I'm telling you...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO_AOYAMA
Original Comic Books By.
GO HO AOYAMA
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
11 KC
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDQO
Story Editor.
IUNIVGHIJIOKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNART KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGU
TOSHIKd INOUE
Anim %1on Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
ro A . DN
FTT1TIKC HOOD TARVIN
HARUO OOGAWARA
AISUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KGDAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
Di 10a ENON INT
WCGONHO AAMT SHOGARURAN AY IV SIMS
VITRig hts Resend!
Hun?
I wonder who put the coat over me...
Ah. it's snowing...
Oh no!
It's this time of night already!!
I better hurry and get dinner ready...
got mail
There's an image attached to it?
Huh?!
Hey. what s this?!
This I's me?!
I got a shot of you sleeping?
Detective Kid?!
Oh, yes!
Good evening. this is Detective Kid.
SShinichl?!
Was Shinichi here?
Yeah, until just a while ago...
If you had time to do
a stupid thing like this,
you should've woke me up!
You were fast asleep.
Looking comfortable and &fooling so...
Drooling?
Oh, and while I was
waiting fer you to get up,
got hungry...
so I ate me chocolate
hat was on the desk...
What?!
Ut. talk about rare...
I mean a peach shaped chocolate...
P. Peach shaped...
Well, it didn't taste like peach,
but it sure was good...
R.Really?
Yeah, it was the best I've eaten so far.
Where'd you buy that chocolate?
No! I can't tell you'll
It's a great store that only I know of...
Oh...
But, Shiniehi,
callini?yourself Py
Detective Kid is kind of dorky.
Yeah, I thought so 100.
Just a minute!
See Irv got a customer
I wonder what kind of case today is?
Are you kidding?! If you've lost something
in the house go find it yourself!
I'm the renown detective Kogoro Mouri!
I can't be bothered with trivial stuff like that!
we'll find your lost wa Eh