The heart contains mysteries,
stars and snow sparkle for the two.
Youth Detective Squad is looking for
a lost wristwatch.
We encountered a big case.
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the l1.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Wow! It's 'so mute!
This is me!
All of them look just like us!
Are you sure
it's okay for us to take these chocolates?
Yes!
I made it with all my skills at the lodge
just for all of you!
When did you make this. though?
I didn't see it on the desk of the lodge.
I made it as I try-out at first
and kept it in the refrigerator!
I'll go make you some tea,
so» wait here. okay?
Okay!
Judging from the way she's acting
it seems you somehow succeeded In
getting the chocolate
from Ran who was in tears. huh...
Huh?
How'd you know she was in tears?
A creation reflects the heart of
Its creator.
Just take a look at this chocolate.
It's laughing but it has a sad face...
Now that you mentioned it...
Really, a face so ad that
it seems as if it's going to
break out in tears any minute.
She's trying sea hard.
You sometimes talk like a girl. don't you?
Oh, do I look like a boy?
& CL.
LA AA
Forgotten Keepsake of a Crime Part 1
WA. NA.
(RA)
This good!
You can say that again
It's like chocolate that re sold in stores!
Would you mind holding the noise
down a bit more?
I can't concentrate on my work!
Sorry, sorry!
We:ll leave as soon as we drink our tea.
Are you really working?
I heard that you're always sleeping.
You idiot!
Can't you see that I'm listening to
the tape of my client even now...
All the horses
have started off at once!!
What's that?
Horse racing?
Ell, you see this is...
OtYes. one moment please.
ST Withe client's come just as expected!
What makes you think that a man like me
who is bombarded with job requests
for investigations all dver Japan
has spare tim@ at ail
I wonder what kind of difficult case
v I'm going to have to take on today...
Welcome!
H, well, you see...
DID!
BE 5549
{HERA
All I want you to do is search for
a watch that I've lost...
Hideo Morita
BEE 998 (49)
BE 549)
I see...
so the watch you're looking for
is your late wife's...
Vi=@
It's an old hand-wind type wristwatch
that I sent my wife some time ago.
Why do you need the wristwatch now?
Your wife died. didn't she?
Oh, I get it!
You want to take it to the pawn shop?
No...
my wife comes to my, bed side
night after night...
and asks me,
What time is it now: dear...?"
I'm sure you're just tired
I think so too, but...
Did you lose it
when you went out somewhere?
Or, was it a thief or something?
Well, I think it's somewhere in the house.
Huh
She was quite scatterbrain.
There were times when she was looking
for her lipstick
that she left under some magazines
for a whole day...
Therefore, I think that if I find the watch,
she'll be able to rest in peace...
You gotta be kidding!
If it's in the house, go look for it yourself!!
On, but...
I'm just as bad as my wife
when it comes to being scatterbrained...
I'm the renown detective Kogoro Mouri!
I can't be bothered with trivial
stuff like'that!!
Huh? K.Kogoro Mourn?
You mean that famous Sleeping Kogoro"?!
He's planning to slack off!
He's like those snobbish shops
that refuse entry to customers
depending on how they feel about them!
There shouldn't be a case that's too big
or too small to take on. should there...
Oh, but if you insist you want to look for
the wristwatch at all costs. then...
No. I'll look for someone else
to do it for me.
I just happened to come across
your sign outside
and kind of just dropped in so...
Oh. .7?
Where'd everybody go?
They've all disappeared some Mere.
Hello!
Huh
Shall we help you look for
the wristwatch youllost?
Huh?
Of course we won't charge you fort.
Oh...
we are coming in!
What beautiful flowers!
But, some of them are bent...
Yes,
These are flowers that my wife arranged
before she died.
So even if I change the water everyday.
The more days pass. the more they bend
Which means that it hasn't been that long
since your wife passed away yet?
She passed away just 3 weeks ago
in a traffic accident.
What's with this room?
Oh, that's...
Wow!
Get a load of this!!
♪ s full of audio equipment!
What @ big TW!
T's like a small movie Theater, isn't!
Hey, this is the English version of
Gomera-- isntloitey
I went all the way to the States to buy it.
The desk if is full of videos, IDs, DVDs,
AV amp, as selector and TV monitor.
So many remote controls on the desk.
The floor is full of stacks of pamphlets.
It comes as no surprise
that things might get lost here
Oh, well
The only room that is messy is this room
Huh?
It seems you have a guest.
It seems so...
Come on!
De you have it»?
yes, 5.000.000.0000 yen for now.
Bike Idezuki
e AW CT
HA RF (46)
NY 4 #3 XIN
5.000.000.000 yen?
Eiko Idezuki
e AW CT
(tH 2 BR + (46)
Iva EA
Eiko Idezuki
tH 23 BR + (46)
RX AAAS XIN
You're missing 15,000,000.000 yen
Eiko Idezuki
of Noy =
tH 23 BR + (46)
V2 8A
I was thinking of selling
this room to get the remainder ready.
Oh, is that right...
I'm sorry that it sure looks like
I'm evicting you or something.
JUS as my apprecia ion or waving
waited for me to return the money to you,
I found the video Sakura Sanjuro
that you've been looking for.
Oh. really?
Oh. then'! hope you don't mind me
viewing it right now on your big screen.
0... ple Sed
My... who are these children.
Oh. well, ub.
Come now; al of you!
Never mind this room for now.
Please search another room.
Oh, after you finish watching it
can you please return it to the manager
of the video shop in front of the station?
It seems to be a valuable video tape
that they don't even have at the shop so.
Oh. okay,
I was just going to go out anyway
I'll watch this enjoy myself thinking it
to be the interest for the money I lent you,
Which room shall we search next?
Oh, how about the living room then
That lady is sure blasting
the volume while watching
It sure sounds like
an interesting movie, though!
Come on, no more talk and start looking.
Or the sun will start-setting.
Oh. okay
But Ai, we've already searched
all of "We moms. 'yet fiothing
I'm so hungry I can't move...
Shall I make you some sandwiches then?
Huh
I run a coffee shop in the next town.
I've got the ingredients I need,
so as a token of my appreciation for
Iooking for the wristwatch, let me make it!
All right!
Uh..».-shall n help you?
No thank you. I can handle it alone.
Okay then: I guess we'll give,it one last
search until the sandwiches are made
Okay.
Here you go. eat to your heart's content.
It l0ooKO Super delicious!
Clubhouse sandwiches!
Just as would*be expected
of a professional!
Wonder if anyone of you can
take some sandwiches
over to Ms. ldezuki
who 1s watching the video?
I'll take it to her!
Oh, I'll go too then!
Thank you.
We brought you your tea and sandwich.
This is the best-part!
Just leave it on the desk, will you!
OO. Okay.
Did Ms. Idezuki say it tastes good?
No...
She said she's watching the best part.
SO she'll eat it later
Oh well
she's a movie-lover
so I guess it can't be helpled
Huh?
What're those clothes in the plastic bag?
The laundry
I'm going to the coin laundry
to wash them.
But there was a washing machine
in the bathroom!
I don't know how to operate
that washing machine without my wife
because it's spit of difficult to use.
Uh, you know
the wristwatch you're looking for,
did your wife wear it all the time?
Yes. she liked it so much
that she had it on until the day
before she got into the accident.
She virtually never took it off...
But. she'd take it off
when taking a bath. right?
Conan!
Huh
Agh!
Here's the wristwatch!
It's, moving just find too.
What?
.88.
Thank you! This is my wife's watch!
I see.
She probably took it off
before taking a bath
and threw it inside the washing machine
together with her clothes...
that watch wasn't lost to begin with!
Then. what is it?
Why is ihe making up a lie like this?
It's the sound of something cracking.
That's the sound of somebody running.
D.Don't tell me that!
Hey, what was that sound?!
N Xt, it's the sound of the
front door closing.
The flower vase is gone!
WwW. What happened?
Hey, Conan?
M.Ms. Idezuki?!
The murder weapon is the vase
that had water and flowers in it.
The killer probably took the vase
and snuck up from behind,
then attacked the Victim with the vase.
Beaten to death.
It seems the victim Ms. Eiko lldezuki, 46,
IS a resident of this condo
And.
Mr. Hideo Morita, the owner of this room,
What is the relationship
between you. and Ms. Idezuki?
I borrowed some money from her.
She came here today
to get some of it back.
When I gave her the money together
with the video she had been looking for,
she said she wanted te watch it and
that's why she was in this audio room.
And you came to this room
after you heard the vase crack.
Then found Ms. Idezuki lying here
bleeding from her head?
Y, Yes...
The movie Ms. ldezuki was watching is
the video she was.holding,
judging from the manufacturer of
the remoté she was holding in her hand,
the video deck she was using
is this deck...
Oh, it's Sakura Sanjuro!
How nostalgic.
Inspector Megure, you know this story?
Yeah...
If I remember correctly
it started off something like,
the path you are to walk along
IS as beautiful as a flower
and you are to live as strong
as the trunk of a tree!
Right?
We heard the movie!
Because the lady was watching
the movie full blast!
WwW. Why are you all here?!
We came:to help to sea ch for
s rmething that was lost!
We came to help look for
Na hand-winding wristwatch
that Mrs. Morita had misplaced
the day before she passed away!
Although Conan already found that
wristwatch in the bathroom already.
Why did you ask the kids to help
you look for something like that, though?
I asked Detective Mouri
to help me search for it at first,
but was refused...
So. I had the children and Dr. Agasa
who at the office to help me search.
I see... so Mr. Mouri's not here.-then.
Huh? Bid you want anything with him?
Oh . no.
Oh. no.
I just had something I wanted to
confirm with Mr. Mouri, that's all
\\ 73
The tape's been rewound to the beginning.
It seems that
she finished watching the video
and took the tape out of the deck.
Which after
she was attacked from behind.
I don't mean to be rude,
but where were you at that time?
Oh. think lw 3 in the bathroom...
He's telling the truthrand the whole truth!
We heard the vase crack at the
same time that Conan found the watch
and Mr. Morita was
with us in the bathroom!
And we heard the sound of someone
running and the front door closing to
the Killer must've come from outsid 1
Which means-that Mr. Morita was
with you and the children right through?
No. he went into the kitchen
to make some sandwiches part way.
The kitchen? Where's that?
It's way inside beyond this living room.
Over here.
Where were you then, Dr. Agasa?
I was in the living room
here with the children
If you open the door
on the corridor side of this kitchen,
it is one straight line to the audio reom
where the corpse was found.
Np VA 3
Besides, it's a blind spot
from the door of the living room.
It's possible to sneak out
for a while in this situation.
WwW. What do you mean, Mr. Inspector...?
In other words
the sound of the of the flower vase
cracking. the sound of footsteps
and the sound of the front door closing.
If these were all sounds
recorded beforehand by you...
you could've pretended
to go kitchen to make sandwiches,
and after beating Ms. Idezuki to death,
could've played the pre-recorded sounds!
It's net strange that nobody heard
her being beaten to death
if she was listening to the movie
with the volume turned up high.
O.Oh come on...
But, that's not possible!
Huh
Well, you saw the tea and sandwich
in the audio room, didn't you?
Ayumi and I took the tea and
sandwich to Ms lldezuki,
but at that time she was watching
the video and nothing was wrong!
It was after that when we heard the flower
vase crack and found the corpse
Mr. Morita was with us
right through until then.
Oh. I see...
Inspector Megure!
I've finished asking around the people
of the condo just now!
Okay.
It seems that Ms. Idezuki
had been lending money
to some other residents of this condo,
and if they couldn't pay her back on time,
she would take the valuables
that thosegpeople owned as interest!
Which means she didn't have
that great of a reputation.
Besides, it seems that
the people of the condo knew
that she was going to come here today!
What?!
The sound of the video.
It seems that she used to watch videos
in this audio room
with the volume turned up full blast.
Hmm ae
If they knew that{
she was going to be here,
it could be that
the killer came from outside.
Okay
chec everybody"
who had borrowed from Ms. Idezuki!
Yes: sin
Yes, sir!
If its a killer fromfoutside, I guess there
won't be anything for you to do this time.
NO...
I think that the killer is Mr. Morita.
What?
But you just mentioned a while ago that
it was impossible
for him to commit the crime.
Don't you think something's fishy?
A hand-winding type wristwatch
that was lost 3 weeks ago
was still moving accurately
when we foun it.
The longest a hand wound watch
can keep on operating
continuously is at most 50 hours...
It could never go on ticking
for 3 weeks if left as is.
Then don't tell me
that the wristwatch is...?
Yeah,
An excuse to get us to-come here.
Probably to set up an alibi.
But. it's for sure that
Mr. Morita didn't enters
the audio room
during the time of the crime.
I looked in on the kitchen
in question every 2 to 3 minutes
but he was
where he was supposed to be
He hasn't made any funny moves
even after the corpse was found.
He could ever have
committed @ Crime like that...
By the way, Mr. Morita.
When you went to Mr. Mouri's office
did you run into anyone
suspicious in the vicinity?
No. not that I recall.
I see. thank you.
Officer Takagi. what was that about?
Oh. nothing...
I'm still considering whether
I should tell himbin person
about this or not with the Inspector,
But it seems that someone is secretly
checking up on Mr. Mour.
A whole bunch of investigation records
that Mr. Mouri handled up to now
disappeared from the police department.
Since Officer Matsumoto had copies of
the investigation records stored,
no problems arose during the trial, but...
The surprising thing is
that all the investigation records were
sent back to the station last night.
They were all in a sealed envelope
with no return address on it.
And. when did the papers disappear?
I think it was the day when you and
the others got messed up in a bus-jack.
We're investigating the case
because it may be a crime
that was committed
by the relative of a suspect
who is after Mr. Mouri's life
out of hate for him
But, we haven't been able to
come up with anyone for a while,
SQ we're trying to decide
whether we should protect
Mr. Mouri with bodyguards or not.
Oh, but then it could be
a simple prank too.
At any rate, if you see anybody
suspicious around Mr. Mourn,
make sure you call the police night away!
Okay. I got it!
No, the one they're after is not Pops...
but maybe...
And,
maybe the killers are...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO_AOYAMA
Producers
MIGHIHIRO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSH DKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor
JUNIGHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
T SHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
AISUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
S\ENTERTAINMENT, LI
in associdtion with
11 LC
CORPORATION
DETECLIVEXC ONAN
YaOSHO TOY ANY SHOGARUR ANY IV IMS
All 21 giots I yur sad
hey. doesn't something smell odd?
Now that you mention it. a burnt smell
Maybe that microwa ¢€
There is no question its coming
from this microwave oven
Yes! Some leftover sandwiches!
It's okay to have some right?
I get it now