The heart contains. mysteries,
Stars and snow sparkle for the two.
He mysterious case using a vase.
Reenacting the scene of the Case.
He sees through the one and only truth,
1 child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult.
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
We, the members of
the Youth Detective Squad end up
helping Mr. Morita look
for the lost wristwatch in place T Pops.
While we were looking for
the wristwatch at Mr. Mortars condo 48
Ms. Eiko ldezuki, a resident of
the same condo comes over
and starts watching a movie
in the audio room.
And starts watching a movie
In the meantime, we found the wristwatch
in the washing machine.
Just then.
We heard the flower vase
crack from the audio room!
We rushed over to see what happened
and found Ms. Idezuki hit on
the head with the flower vase and killed!
The killer is most likely Mr. Morita...
However, he has an alibi
and it would've been impossible
for him to commit the crime...
How the hell did he do it?!
And, there's one more thing
that bothers me.
It seems that someone is
secretly checking up on Mr Mourn.
but 7
A whole bunch of investigation records
that Mr. Mouri handled up to now
disappeared from the police department.
And. when did the papers disappear?
I think it was the day when you and
the others got messed up in a bus-jack.
The one they're after is not Pops,
but maybe...
And, maybe the killers are...
FORGOTTEN KEEPSAKE OF A CRIME
Part 2
Hey, Shinichi,
what did Officer Takagi say?
Huh
Oh, it's nothing important.
Just as I thought...
You refuse to tell us anything...
Come off it, the same to you.
I guess so.
What's this, are you hiding
something after all, Shinichi?
Oh, no that's not it
Although he doesn't think of
what will happen
when he is pushed fo ward by justice
and-pursues only the truth at times.
He yet at times. takes on all the pressure
alone, so asunot to hurt anybody...
That character of yours,
boyish and dangerous...
It's extremely interesting.
But I wonder if you're at all aware...
that the pure fragrance of yours
IS binding all the girls, including me
as well as yourself up in
an isolated and dangerous fragrance.
Shinichi Kudo.
don't you smell something funny?
Huh
Now that you mentioned it,
it does smell like something is burning.
Maybe it's the microwave oven
over there ?
There's no mistake about it,
the smell's coming from in here!
But, there's nothing inside.
Conan?
This is dried flower. isn't it.?
Or. it was thrown away)
because it withered.
If so, that should be
somewhere near here.
Darn, where the heck?!
It's impossible to hide anything
SO conspicuous away so easily.
Don't tell me it's in another room.
There are some more sandwiches left!
May I eat this or what?
God, Genta, you're eating too much.
Sandwich
Wait a sec...
Maybe...!
I found it!
Here it is
This was a trick after all!
Which means that inside the audio room...
Hmm? What is it, Conan?
I was playing flying a paper plane
in the afternoon and it went on top there...
Where?
Behind the curtain above "he TV!
Will you please get it for me, please!
Okay. okay. I'll get it for Wu now.
Really, sometimes he acts intelligent,
but sometimes he acts like any other kid.
There's nothing here, Conan?
There's no sign of 'an airplane anywhere...
Wow. it's. full of machines!
Huh?
It's super!
Hey! Just what do you think you're doing?
Put him down quick!
Oh, yes. sir!
You sure have a lot of decks. don't you?
Yes, I put all the decks that have gotten
old and out of use on the top shelves.
Conan!
A timer?
Come down, Conan!
I see... so that's what it was.
Idezuki was watching unaware.
What so ever that...
This would be the last movie
that she would be watching...
That she was going to be a part of the
ruthless story Mr Morita had schemed.
She didn't even have the slightest idea
of what was going to befall her.
$ range. nothing was mentioned
about going out or anything
Hey. I told them!
Oh, okay
and what did the Inspector say?
He says it's an interesting
deduction, so he'll cooperate!
Okay!
Next. it's you guys then.
DO exactly as told you. now!
Yay!
S71 44
You sure look worried.
You're worried about &
your precious girl, aren't you?
It's okay .
I don't know what Officer Takagi told you.
But just make sure
that you don't blow.your cool
and reveal your identity or
anything about the organization to her...
Well. I can sew that your feet is off the
ground after receiving chocolate from her,
because afte, all you are a guy, but...
Come off it! My feet's not off the ground.
I haven't told her a thing...
Huh?
B.But Shinichi, you accepted
the chocolate from Ran, didn't you?
Yeah.
Which means that you got something
in return for it, right?
I don't want to have to miss her.
If I say anything now...
she's going to miss me even more.
The hateful guy is just one sidedly
telling her to wait for him
and can't even appear before her.
Id Wt wan ito see her cry anymore.
Even if it means-blotting
my existence out of her.
I'm so childish, what a laugh.
It hurts, doesn't it?
TRO GOA 3S Ga tang)
What? Something was stolen?!
Really?
It's true, really true.
A strange thing disappeared.
The killer was actually a thief!
Please come to thelkitchen.
Let's go. Mr. Morita
And? What is it that was stolen?
It's this!
A bowl?
Nofl It isnit the bowl!"that was stolen.
But the bottom of the bowl.
See?
The bottom of the bowl with
the sane pattern of that bowl issthere,
but the bottom of this bowl is gone right?
Hmm, true...
Oh. the bottom of that bowl
was gone when I bought it.
It seems to have been a detective item.
Inspector!
Everything's ready!
R Read ?
If it's okay with you,
we'd like you to stand witness too.
It's just a simple on-site investigation.
O. Okay...
Shall we go then
to the audio room where Ms. Idesuki was
struck to death with the flower vase.
Please go ahead inside.
O.Okay.
The switch .
The switch of the video deck is on!
Isgsomething wrong
with the video deck on the shelf?
N.No. it's not the deck
it's the stack of video tapes in front of it.
0 Sexcuse me. \
I put it there.
I mean, there're so many of ther...
Ah =80 the victim Ms. ldezuki
finished watching the video,
rewound it and took it out of the deck...
that's when she was
attacked from behind by the killer?
Yes.
So, shall we use the video like she did
and replay the scene of the crime.
Huh
Officer Takagi,
you play the role of the killer,
Dr Agasa,
please-play the role of the victim.
Oh. uh. well
Anything
Well, you see,
I. I'll do it.
I, I'll do it.
Since Ms: lldezuki used to
watch the video a lot in this room,
I think that a. person who is familiar
with this room is more appropriate.
Oh! It's that right!
Then, please do. by all means.
First you insert the video tape
into the video deck on the very bottom.
The victim sits in the chair and-
watches the movie all alone.
Is that right?
Yes.
Then the victim who finishes .~
watching the video rewinds the tape.
What's the matter?
Please rewind the tape.
Oh, yes, sir.
While the tape is being rewound,
the killer comes along with flower vase
that is at the front entrance
and sneaks up behind her.
And, as"she is.about to take the tape
that is rewound out of the deck,
The killer flings up the flower vase.
Mr Morita, quick,
please take the tape out!
Oh. y.yes!
O. Okay.
Why don't you use the remote controller?
Huh?
Look, the remote controller
that you're holding has an eject button!
Oh. that's...
I'll eject it for you then!
Huh?
The video tape won't come falling.
We changed the code number for the
remote for the video deck on the shelf.
In other words. Mr. Morita.
This is how you committed the crime!
You rigged it so that the video deck that
you use all the time on the lower shelf
and the video deck on the upper shelf
would operate with the same remote.
Then you put the tape in the video deck
on the upper shelf
Then you put the vase
with the flower and water in it
in front of the eject slot of that tape deck.
Of course you made sure it
would fall by putting a tape under it!
After that, all you had to do was close
the curtain to complete the scheme!
Then you showed Ms ldezuki the video
that she had been wanting to see,
ind lured her into this room.
If you tell her to rewind the tape
and return it to the video shop,
you knew that after she finishes watching
the video she would use the remote
to eject the tape,
and at the same time,
the tape on the top shelf would be
ejected and push the flower vase forward
and just when she pulls
the tape out of the deck,
the flower vase would
come falling towards her.
In other words.
SO long as you were aware of her
actions when she frequented this room,
it wouldn't be difficult to set the timing
right so that the vase would fall on her!
Like this.
And-the-video deck
on*the top shelf had a function
CCUZR
that would push the tape back
into the deck if it bumps into something,
so if You pre-record
something into that tape
and break off the pin
to prevent further recording.
The tape will automatically start to play.
Therefore,
right after the flower vase falls on her,
sound of footsteps of someone running
and the door closing would be heard,
making it look like someone
from outside committed the crime!
We heard it very clearly because
she was watching the movie full blast.
You made her use the deck
on thO very bottom
to get the vase to fall
from as high a distance as possible.
You rigged it so the video deck on the
top shelf would switch off with a timer,
so that when the police opened it.
You wouldn't be suspected. right?
I guess you already knew
that we've seen through your scheme.
But. the-flower vase
that you had-at the front entrance...
Was this bowl!
You glued it together like sandwich
and put it on the entrance. right?
You carried it secretly over to the kitchen
when you went to make the sandwiches
disassembled it
and hid it between the bowls!
These are the flowers
that were inside the vase.
You dried it using the microwave oven
and threw them away.
Peer thing, after your wife decorated
the flowers there.
My wife didn't arrange those flowers.
Those flowers are out of place flowers
that the woman bought and brought
to my wife's funeral...
We didn't even have the money
to buy flowers in this house anymore.
Huh?
Stocks...
That woman urged my wife
tordo stocks behind my back.
She was eventually buried in debts
and was driven to death.
Which means your wife's car accident...
Yes.
The day after
she told me about the stocks.
She ran in front of a car
and got run over.
That wristwatch was wrapped in a letter
that she had written to me.
It said. I don't want this
to be destroyed, so I'm leaving this behind.
So who cares whether the flowers
that woman gave me
are withered or burned...
We'll hear the rest of your story
out at the station
But. I feel sorry for them nevertheless.
They were so beautiful,
and flowers have such short lives.
They were forced to wither
before their time came.
Yes.
I'm going to head on home then.
Flowers are fragile and short-lived.
No matter how much we try
to protect them from rain and wind,
and build fences arrow nd them
flowers will wither in want of the sun.
If a storm comes a fragile fence
cannot act as a shield at all.
Do you understand this, Shinichi?
Darn!
How come
nobody's answering the phone?
Darn!
Ran. Pops!
Right, it's dinner time.
They may be at home upstairs.
Ran?
Dinner made part way
The TV in the office isdeft on.
D.Don't tell me that...
Somebody seems to be
checking UP on him in secret
Don't tell me that he got them...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO_AOYAMA
Producers.
MI@HIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Charactef Designs By
MASATOMO sum»
Story Editor.
IUNICHI 110161
Scripts By.
KANJI'KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KDUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animdtion Dire «tors.
MAsAroMo 510130
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKI? KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
ENTERTAINMENT
in 1ssocid Fon with
YOMIURY TELECASTING O
CORPORATION
12018 C_d0N EF Ce (IN ANT
VGOSHOTYOYANT NY AHOGARUKR ANY IV TMS
"I Ri hi? Restrved
Who is it?
Ran...
Bingo!
Uh. um. where were you?
) went to the supermarket on 2nd Street
Pad had a big win with the horse race.
A.A big win?
Dad was elated and said,
We're having steak tonight!
Go buy the meat and sake!
That's why I left everythinggpart way
and rushed over to go shopping
Because unless I go right away,
they sell out of meat all the time.
Where's Pops?
I think he's going around the
neighborhood boasting about his win.
Hold on just a while longer, Conan.
I'll maKe you a steak that's even more
delicious than first rate restaurants!
Ran.
Huh?
Um...
The man wearing a black knitted cap.
Maybe an acquaintance of mine.
Wihat is" it?
B. Black...
Huh?
Black...
Don't burn the meat black.
How prude! 1 ell Jou!
You can count on me!
I don't believe she knows him.
What? Something is on the envelope
circle, Xx and a triangle
LP CF
FLY 7
rs go?
Iv. pro
58 possible suspects
The only hint is circle, x and triangle
How Interesting