Suspense and deduction
closes the gap between
two people's love and hate
Officer Takagi makes a mistake
Let's help him Youth Detective Squad!
He sees through the one and only truth
a child in appearance
with the IQ of an adult
nojcase is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Hey. everyone
Something has happened.
What? Detective Takagi
Where is he now?
He-he's over there in that park.
Yes, really. =
he's trying desperately to find something.
Is he finding evidence of a.case;?
No, he isn't,
because he isn't wearing gloves
Ah-ha. I got it!
What?
That should be here somewhere.
It cannot be anywhere but here
Oh, it's you
We're ready to help you Well.
You'd do the same for us
if we were in trouble.
I know. I know.
You lost something like this, right?
How do you know about it?
Don't you know
we're the Detective Boys.
I can see all what you are doing.
If you don't find it...
You're in big trouble. aren't you?
Of course I am.
It's very important to a police person.
It comes second only to his or hew life.
What you lost is
Maybe not your purse, but
Oops
Oh. you lost your police notebook.
Hush! Don't speak so-loud.
Uh-oh. This is no good at all.
Missing Case of Police Notebook
This morning I realized that
I hadslost my notebook.
And I looked through mygroom
but couldn't find it.
Are you sure you were carrying it
on your duty yesterday?
Yes, I'm sure.
And then, on the way home.
I happened to pass in front of this park.
Shut your mouth! YOU, liar.
Hey. cut it out!
What're you doing?
YOU Cheat!
I oughta beat you here and now!
Break it up. you two.
Step off! Don't mess with me.
I'm a police officer and
am telling you to stop fighting right now.
I must have lost it then.
So: youircdigoking for it around here.
Do you think that maybe one of the two
fighting guys picked up the 1 dBtebook?
Oh. that's right.
I think that's very likely.
So. do you remember
those two men's names?
Or what about their addresses?
Wa-— Wait
Why can't you believe me. Hanzaki?
Hanzaki.
The younger one's name was Manzaki.
Anything else you remember about them?
How can I believe you.
I'm gonna tell you, my manager, that
I'm still a struggling singer
because all those jobs that
you got were always crap for me.
The truth is that
you have to pay your dues in
Enka (Japanese Ballad) business
You know that!
Have a little more patience, please.
How many times are you
gonna say that huh?
I know you've
deceived me for a long time.
Give me back my time up to now
and the money you owe me,
you bastard.
Hey. hey! Hold on. you guys.
So. he's a struggling singer.
Don't you remember
what kinda shoes they were wearing?
That reminds me...
The man named Hanzaki was
wearing sandals.
Oh I see.
Er aps 1@ ives neary.
Yeah! OK, then.
Let's look for him together.
But what if that man lhasA>> picked it up?
why don't we divide into teams of two?
One is to go find
the man named Hanzaki
and the other is to loo &for
the notebook in this park.
Alrighty.
One-Two-Three
Sorry to leave , ou here.-Hang on.
See a.
Oarno.
No good,
there is no such name.
What about asking
the record companies?
I'm afraid that's impossible.
There're an awful lot of big
and small record companies.
asking one by one
Excuse me,
but do you know
the man named Hanzak\?
He IS a singer and supposed to
Iive around here somewhere
He is a singer and supposed to
Iive around here somewhere.
Pardon me. sir...
Uh-ha, the police handbook...
Yeah
I wonder...What if he can't find it?
Detective Ta "ag.
Perhaps..he's..in a pathetic state.
YOU CHEESEHEAD!!
You lost your police notebook,
which is supposed to be
an extension of a
police officer's soul and mind.
Get out. You're fired!
Detective 1akagl What 3 real pity.
H-hey. you.
This is NOT the time for a snack.
Help me you two.
Oh. sorry.
Oh. they came back.
Hey. how did it go?
Did you find the man?
No. we didn't.
We can't find him by na ie and looks
We can't find it either.
Hey. Detective?
Jirou Hanzaki
¥m\ XB (30)
RAN tr tr Le
mad +
What're you doing here?
Jirou Hanzaki
um BB (30)
RA or Le
mua yd
Jirou Hanzaki
39g BB (30)
RA tr & Lo
-- By ao 9
max ax -1
Oh, oh!
You here!
You, um... Yesterday
I'm sorry for the trouble last night.
So is this the man everyone
is talking about?
Mr- Hanzakil.
Why now? I just wish you had
walked by earlier.than you actually did.
Mr. Hanzaki, did you pick up
anything last night?
My stuff um. like this
No. I didn't.
Perhaps neither did the manager. I think.
OK. you didn't.
You lost your thing like this. right?
Am gonna Inc 1 wi 1 you
Thanks but you don't have to do that.
Just wanna repay for your'kindness.
Last night, thanks to you Detective
the manager and I
could get back together soon.
So. today. we were supposed to
have a lunch.meeting together, but
I was waiting for him at my apartment,
but he didn't come
I guess he is getting drunk
at his house, by now
He always boozes You know.
That's the trouble
I called him several times
but the manager didn't pick up the phone
That means he is now getting
falling down drunk at his house.
I assure you.
If you think he doesn't show up
no matter how long you wait,
then why don't you
go to his house yourself?
Cuz, it takes one and a half our
to get there
even if I drive at top speed. you know.
I think that's a bother
Oh, something is attached to you.
Oh. it's a shampoo.
A little while ago
when I cleaned my bathroom,
I accidentally stepped on
the shampoo bottle.
Hu Al
By the way
do you have the time, Detective?
One o'clock. It's just one o'clock.
Uh-oh, it's already one o'clock.
We'd better hurry-and find it!
All right already. You
don't have to help.me anymore
But. Oh!
So then, let me buy your lunch, please?
Just two thousand yen:and
all you can eat for two hours.
Come on, come on.
No thanks. I'll pass on that one.
I understand...
But you don't have to be so modest.
All right,
I'll eat as much as I can for two hours.
See ya, Detective
What a strange man.
He's too weird
If they hadn't picked it up
then it must be still here somewhere.
That man, Hanzaki...
I suspect he s up to something.
Yeah.
I wonder why
he bothered to ask what time it was.
Yeah,
it's hard to think that someone
in this neighborhood doesn't know
that clock.
Yet, he bothered to ask Detective Takagi,
what time it was?
What for?
I got it!
What?
Oh. have you found it?
Uh. no. not yet I mean.
It isnt about the notebook.
Oh, all right.
Then what did you get?
Don't scare me like that, man
'ev... Everyone. gather around.
What!
That man named Hanzaki
killed the manager?
Mitsuhiko, are you sure?
I'm 100% sure about it.
And also he killed him just now.
Hanzaki seemed to think that
he's still a struggling singer
because of the manager and
to Hold a grudge agaist him for it.
So far as I know now. he has a motive:!
The droplet of shampo clung to the
bottom of his trousers. right?
Yeah, he said, he accidentally
stepped ontthe shampoo bottle
while cleaning his bathroom.
First of all,
I wondered why he lied about it.
Did he lie?
It goes without saying that
you should roll up your pants
SO as not to get it wet
while cleaning your bathroom.
And if he rolled up his pants.
The shampoo shouldn't stick to
the bottom of it.
That is. he was not cleaning his bathroom.
But he was in the bathroom
for anther purpose.
What?
W wait a sec. Mituhiko!
And then?
This morning,
Mr. Hanzaki called the manager
to com) to his apartment,
saying that
he wanted to make up with him.
That's enough.
I can't drink that much Oops.
Phew
He skillfully encouraged the manager,
a heavy drinker to drink Sake.
He drank the manager
After waiting for the time to be right,
at just before 1 PM
He carried him to
his apartment's bathroom
and had him drown in the bathtub.
Then he accidentally,
stepped on the shampoo bottle.
And he dashed out of the apartment
then came to the park.
To set up his alibi!
To set up Kis alibi?
Yeah!
He's going to carry the body out of the
his apartment in secret, perhaps tonight.
And sink the body
in the bathtub of the manager's house.
In doing this,
the police will treat
It as an accidental death.
And even if
they treat the case as an homicide,
his estimated time of death was
around one this afternoon.
Yes!
By the way, do you have the time,
Detective?
One o'clock. It's just one o'clock.
At the time when the manager was
supposed to be killed at home,
Hanzaki was here.
It's one and a half hour drive
from here to there.
As the real police officer,
Detective Takagi proves his alibi,
nobody doubts Mr. Hanzaki!
That's the perfect crime.
Well done {Mitsuhiko! Perfect reasoning
sum)
I think W's far from perfect.
Detective Takag:.
What a pity .
He lost his police notebook
and he was even
used to set up the murderer's alibi.
Hey Mitsuhiko,
Did you say. "Everybody knows that
he or she should roll up
their pants when cleaning the bathroom.
That's just a matter of common sense
all over the world.
Mr. Kogoro doesn't pull up his pants
because he thinks it's a bother.
It's a
Incidentally Dr. Agasa also doesn't
That means there was a possibility that
he was really cleaning his bathroom.
And Detective Takagi came here
to search for his police notebook
because he happened to lost it.
It's very difficult to suppose that
Mr. Hanzaki relied on such a chance
to establish his important alibi.
What do yourtRirk, Mitstifiko?
Its.
Your guess was far § f'the Iinark.
I won't take it
A-Ayum!
Cut it out, Ayumi.
Cuz. I can never forgive that man.
Thatyman tried to use such a nice guy,
Detective Takagi.
B-but, my reasoning was wrong. so.
What does that mean anyway?
Wihat is what?
Kook at that!
How strange...
He isn't eating anything yet.
Yeah, it's true
That man... Is he still U4) to anything?
He's still not eating anything.
That's a waste.
But he cares only about what time it is.
Oh, yeah
He's only watching the clock
How strange!
If he didn't get hungry.
Why did he enter thejAll-you-can-eat
restaurant for two 'hours, at all?
Yeah, that's right
How come?
Oh. I remember he said.
I am gonna find that
square thing with you.
So then, let me buy
your lunch at that restaurant, please?
He relentlessly tried to be with him.
So thatlexplains it!
BB Mitsuhiko.,\, our
reasoning isn't entirely true but half true.
What do yourmean "half true"?
AS you suspected,
hat guy is trying to kill the manager.
So, he entered: this restaurant and is
now passing himself off
as a customer
in order to establish his alib...
To establish his alibi?
I Detective rakagi hadn't sent him away.
He would have wanted to
establish an alibi
by continuing to find the police notebook.
But you said Detective Takagi
happen 4 to come to te park today.
No. He knew Detective Takagi
would be sure to come to find it, perhaps
because he picked it up last night.
You mean that man still has the notebook.
Um. no. Unfortunately
I'm afraid he's already thrown it out
Y ah.
There's no reason to keep
such a dangerous thing around.
Flefiéxw
I said Mituhiko's reasoning
was half correct.
What was wrong is
TAO meme ei's Ce no (
The time isn't 1 o'clock,
but even more later,
around from two te two thirty or so.
Huh
But, it's just past one o'clock. \
Yeah.
The plot to kill the manager is
now going on steadily
Perhaps in the bathroom of his apartment
That's why he cares
about the time like that
Anyway,
it may not be
too late now to save the manager's life.
Yes!
But, wait, do you know
where that guy's apartment is?
Oh. no.
He'll never tell us if we ask.
Let's split up and find it!
Oh. eah.
Alas. even the
Detective boys gave up on me
Oh. man...
Oh. that struggling singer.
He's quite a character.
Last night, he was
picking-up concrete blocks there.
Whatever
but that's not what we wanna to know.
Well, I have no idea.
Hanzaki! His name is Hanzaki!
He's a Enka singer!
He must be living around here
Like I care. I don't like Enka at all.
Hey! Wa-wait.
Et's go over there.
Hello. Flo? Do you copy?
We've got his address.
Really?
Good .
The second floor of
the "PARK SIDE HIGHTS,"
3-Chom Jover.
Roger! We'll be there soon!
I'm gonna get Detective Takagi.
Good idea!
Hopefully. if he can prevent the murder
it'll help to offset the blunder of losing
his police notebook *
Yeah
The shop owner said that
Hanzaki bought
a big block of icetat the store today
Andiconcrete'blocks he picked up.
Ana! I gotit I saw through his trick!
And only if Hanzaki leaves
the body laying on the stairs,
he can make it look like the manager
himself loses his feoting and dies,
in his drunken state.
oo< eavens. We mus wurry.
What!? Murder case?
Not yet,
but ..um...if you ask me... I mean...
he's gonna be killed soon.
I don't get what you're saying.
Sorry but I have to find my notebook.
B-But
Leave it to me.
Hey. the man named Hanzaki actually
picked up your notebook yesterday.
Did he actually picked it up!
And he said, "keep it in my apartment,
so please come to pick it up."
Wh-where!? His apartment!
Conan!
I managed to get a master key
from the! landlord!
Hey!,,
Conan!
Is this Ris! room?
Ye-yeah.
Where?
Where! Where! Where!
Where is my notebook?
Huh
Way to,go!!
Ok. now I'm gonna Ugh... untie your,
Thank you for your help.
Oh. it's you, yesterday?
Seiichi Sugiyama
re os CLT IVS
210 mm - (52)
RRDT -Iv
Yes. My name is Sugiyama.
Seiichi Sugiyama
ve ee xXLY IVS
21 Mm - (52)
RDI - Jv
Seiichi Sugiyama
ge oy IVS
2 Mm - (Be)
HRD TR- J
You helped me both
yesterday and today.
Seiichi Sugiyama
re ew LY IVS
2 Wm- (52)
wRoTr-Uv
You helped me both
yesterday and today.
Thank you. Mr Takag:.
How do you know my name?
I don't think I told you yesterday.
I saw your name
on your notebook.
Yes. this is it! I've found it!
You did it) You found it at last!
It would seem that that Hanzaki guy
didn't pick up the notebook himself,
but just saw him pick twp.
Yes. So it seemed.
Oh, what a relief it is.
Why-are you here?
That's what ll wanna know Hanzak...
I've gone along with you a long time
because I believed you
had a special talent.
Why didn't you believed in
me until the end?
Hanzaki!!
I'm sorry...
I'm Takagi. an officer of
the Criminal Investigations Division 1
of the Metropolitan Police.
Mr Hanzaki.
Can you come with me
to the police station.
Yes.
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO_AOYAMA
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MIGHIHIRO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSFI OKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
[UNICHI 110161
Scripts By.
KANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNAR! KBUCHI
NUCH dl TL
YUICHI HIGUR 3
TOSHIKI INOU
Anmnmimdtion Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Prodnced By
ERTAINMF
in 43s0ciatiGApMth,
all'); 0
DEITCIINVE CONAN
COSHO VOY AMA SHOGARUK ANY IV TAS
PRI ht€ Reserv]
I heard you prevented a murder.
Yes. Sir.
Well done
You did a great job
and appreciate your hard work
Yes sir.
By the wayXhow are you feeling now?
I's your headache gone?
Did yougrun a high fever of 39 degrees?
What is your temperature now?
Oh...
Did you have a stomach ache then?
Did you stumble and sprain an ankle?
And you couldn't move
because of your nausea, could you?
Detective Takagi pretended to be sick \
in order to find his lost notebook.
Looks like it
He played hooky from work.
You fool
Shame on you as a police person
Or Dirouiding 80 Do
Go to your police station. JUST NOW!
Yes, Sir!!
Double Time!!!
Yes!!
Please wait "Inspector Megure!
After all. Ma
he ended up being scolded by him.
Huh
That woman..at that time...
What?