There is a gap between liking and hating
Sleuth work and suspense
Today, it's Chinatown in Yokohama
The surprise figure linked to Ran
He sees through the one and only truth a
child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
An-9!
Who presented Emperor Daigo the
Twelve Article Recommendations?
Miyoshi no Kiyoyuki...
What is the name of the Jodo painting
depicting the descension of Buddha on earth?
The "Shouju-raikou-zu", right!
Hey. hey, hey... get done with it! I can feel
my brain beginning to hemorrhage!
I can't help it! I have a
Japanese history test tomorrow
I didn't have time to study with all the
extracurricular activities I have!
Then, why not do it at home?
Did I hear you say something?
You're telling me to stay
home when I was the one who won
the meal coupon for dinner
in Chinatown in the lottery?
That's why, I'm telling you to
do it when you get back home!
That's not enough time!
There're a lot of TV programs
I want to watch tonight...
But, reading inside a
car can make you sick
Worry not! I have superb sense of
balance, thanks to my vestibular system.
It's started to rain!
It's starting to rain pretty hard...
Rain...
He was standing in the ran
But I can't tell where it was...
A backstreet in a strange city...
And, but why? That man...
Every time I try to recall.
His image comes back in my mind...
s... standing in the rain just like this.
That lonely and gentle face,
Shinichi's face...
Why are you wet?
Why that lonely look?
Tell me, Shinichi...
Hey, Ran... Ran. .!
What happened, Ran?
You looked scary with
wrinkles between your brows...
Oh! I couldn't remember the answer
to a question in this book...
Lets see...
) n o™ 72
'P. RNA
Insel rule, Fujiwara no Kiyohara...
Oh: no...
Darn think I'm getting carsick...
CRY ids)
Chinatown: D¢ja Vu in the Rain - Part 1
What are we to do...
The shoot is about to begin
and the female lead suffers bone
fracture in a motorbike accident...
Well, it probably means
this movie project must be scrappe
Kaizou Isogami
Well, it probably means
this movie project must be scrappe
Kaizou Isogami
» NEY
ARMED
sk TH] Ya
It seems to me that it's cursed...
Kaizou Isogami
SH LES
Br B/G?)
IVfifilMu-'rt
Buk TY) RE 0
Now, now are you going
to throw away this moneymaker?
We're attracting attention
for this sequel to a hit movie!
But, Mr Kawabata...
The girl we finally managed
to find to play the role got hurt.
Motohiro Itou
The girl we finally managed
to find to play the role got hurt.
Motohiro Itou
FR NE QR)
WV La Ov
Wk TE) Buh RA 9%
There's no one else! This is an ome
Motohiro Itou
2 EDD
FA HR G8)
RUD La AC
Ba TH 1) Wn
Motohiro Itou
- 2 YRJY
AE ELI (3D
4 uni b4 nwr<
1k [I] KH NE PF
ou might be right...
Keigo Kitaura
Em MEER)
If we continue,
e might end up same...
Keigo Kitaura
1.0 FHEQY)
YY Cl
0111755
with a major accident...
Keigo Kitaura
tM ER )
oR fr
Anyway, I must admit that,
as the author of the book
that girl wasn't exactly
my image of the character...
It turned out lucky for me!
Mr. Kitaura!
Hoot! I wonder...
hoot! I wonder...
Shirou Kawabata
um: mil? s)
hoot! I wonder...
Shirou Kawabata
JAW PU BR (AG)
where I can find a girl who's young ai
pretty and can handle stunts...
Shirou Kawabata
NOR PA BR (AG)
JI PY BA (46)
What! What do you mean?
Shirou Kawabata
JI10% PY BA 46)
What! What do you mean?
We can't use the coupon?
So, I'm telling you...
But. look here!
The name of your?restaurant!
Yes, that's us...
We issued the coupon.
But
Then, why can't we use ith.
I demand an explanation
and a clear one!
So, that's why...
Hey. kiddo.
What?
What's your sister's name?
Who in the world are you?
Who am I?
I'll tell you, kiddo... My name is...
What kind of joint is this!
Don't tell me you pick your customers
No! Of course not!
If you want to pick up a fight...
Excuse me, mister...
Let's talk outside...
You're not forcing us out of here!
We're not moving unless
you give us a good reason!
Wow! Your sister's got brawn, too!
We-we're trying to tell you
that it is written in the coupon
that it cannot be used
on Sundays and holidays!
Oh, yes! It's written in the fine print!
What!
Oh no... I sincerely apologize.
I'm so sorry...
Oh, no, we're happy
that you understand the provisions
Geez, why didn't you check
in the first place?
What about you!
You're the one who rushed out first,
saying that early bird catches the worm?
Who says!
Well, young lady, that was a good kick!
How about you and
me going to see a Bruce;lL.ee movie?
Who's talking?
My name is... Mike Hama
and I'm not kidding.
Mike Hama
My name is... Mike Hama
and I'm not kidding.
Mike Hama
- - v1 -
IV ATE
$1 IRA
Hama... Mike
Humm? I've heard that before...
0, that's Mike Hama...
I've got an office on the second floor of
Yokohama Nichigeki in Kogane-cho...
Yes. I remember!
That second-rate private eye who has an
office on the second floor of a movie theater!
Well... that's that!
Well, lady, call me when
you feel like going out with me!
See you later, kiddo!
What was that?
Don't know...
Your dinner, sir...
What would you like to do?
Well... actually...
Xxcuse me...
If you don't mind,
how about dinner with us?
Of course, it's on us
What! A leading role in a movie!?
You're exactly what we want!
Of course aif you're interested...
Well...
Don't even think about it!
You'll only embarrass yourself,
blowing your lines
Unless you have the skills of elocution
and persuasion I have...
The skillsrare not yours but mine...
I guess your right...
But, young lady
If you become popular with the movie,
you're going to join the stars!
You'll get to be friends with
a lot of show biz celebrities!
What?
Not only the celebrities!
There will be pro baseball players,
pro soccer players, race drivers...
There may be shoots In
America or Britain or France!
You can get to foreign
countries around the world!
Why don't you try it?
Go for it! Take on challenges!
Really?
But you should be resolved to take
anything if you intend to take the plunge...
Yeah, considering a movie producer
who likes add a kissing scene that is
irrelevant to the plot of the book...
Kissing!
M-Mr. Kitaura! You don't mean me!
Is\changed my mind! Don't!
Dontshdidn't know that!
Me neither...
Hah! Forget it
If you're intimidated by kissing...
You might even die
Iuring the shoot if you're unlucky...
Hey!-Stop scaring her!
She's a gold mine!
I am not!
Ouch!
I'm sorry!
Are you all right?
Never mind...
I'll wipe it off with this towel...
Waiter, can you get me a
new pair of chopsticks?
Yes, sir. Coming up.
What the...
You definitely have a-fever...
Are you okay?
M okay. Just a light cold...
u.! yous ou aint 1 e »e ore
Before?
Nothing
Come and sit here away from your
pigheaded father. Let's talk...
Tell me what you want. I'll serve
some up on a plate for you.
Oh, thanks...
Here you are.
Thanks...
Hey! I said no "pitans
and egg dishes!
What's wrong?
I'm allergic to eggs.
I'hate even the sight of them.
Is that so...
Anyway, young lady, eat all you want.
Thank you Well
A 1 on
I want curry with rice!
IF CD»
What?
Hey, kid, this is a Chinese restaurant.
They don't serve curry here.
What? I want curry!
I want to eat curry! Curry! Curry! Curry!
No curry?
This place stinks! Let's go home!
Ple-e-ease, we'd better
goshome, Ran...
You're being so pesky... Okay...
How about this meat dumplings!
You hiked it when you
had it the last time, jemember?
Oh, yeah...
Boy, are you good at
picking up my message...
Well... where's... the... soy sauce...
There! In front of the old man!
Hey!
Darn it, it's bac en front of Kogoro
Iell gethit this time. . Hup! Hup!
Huh
again...
What is it, Conan?
What do you want?
Ell... some soy sauce...
Here!
Thanks
Next. the chili oil is insfront
of that fox-eyed guy...
Here... it... comes...
What? Dang!
Here, chili oil, right?
Y-yeah...
Gwa-a-d, now she's takingycare of me...
Oh! Here it comes!
Peking duck here is the best!
Oh. wow
By the way, are there
actresses who you like?
Yes! There are two!
One is Yukiko Fujimine.
Actually, she is the mother
of a friend since kindergarten
I've idolized her since I was a child.
Who is the other one?
The other is an American actress...
Sharon Vinyard though
she died a year ago...
Oh! That great actress!
I had the opportunity to meet her once.
She was wonderful .
When did that happen?
Meeting an American celebrity...
When you weren't around!
Yukiko Fujimine and Sharon Vinyard...
more substance than ,
glitz seems to be your taste...
They both have gained ,
Iegendary status .
Iumph! If she had died, s
he could have been a legend, too...
Huh? Who's she?
The victim is Mr. Shiro
Kawabata age 46, film producer.
Death by asphyxiation triggered
)Y cyanide poisoning...
Geez cyanide, arsenic, caustic soda where
do criminals these days get these toxins?
And, did he eat
something before he died?
Yes, a peking duck.
According to the waiter who served him
he started to suffer right
after he put it in his mouth...
Ho. ho... Peking duck for his
Iast dinner! What a way to go!
But, poison was not
found in that piece of duck meat,
and the waiter did not
have it in his possession.
The victim probablJlhad cyanide on his
hand before he bit into the food...
ee... That means that the murderer
Was sitting among you
here at the table?
Anyway. I would like to ask all
of you your relationship with the victim...
Yes, member of the
movie production staff...
The female lead in the movie got
hurt before the shooting started...
That's why we were discussing it...
Whether we should find a replacement
or scrap the project altogether...
Then, Mr. Kawabata took
on a liking for that girl
and invited her and
her father to our table...
Hum? You, with the beard!
I've seen you somewhere before!
Yes, of course! I am the...
Probably a criminal on the run!
No. no, no I'm Kogoro Moun!!
M-Mourni!
Not that...
Famous detective
Yes, yes!
That two-b
detective called Smoking Kogoro...
Sleeping! Not Smoking!
Inspector! I found positive toxic reaction!
All right!
All night!
We didn't find it in the other dishes...
Cyanide has been found on the chopsticks,
plate, and towel the victim used
It was strongest on the towel...
Who sat beside him when he fell?
Me! I sat on his right!
Then, who was at his left?
I sat on his left eating my dumpling...
That makes things easy...
the person who poisoned the victim by I
acing his towel with cyanide is...
You, Mr Detective!
What! Me!
A kid like him won't be able to.commit
murder, and with you sitting on his right,
switching must have been easy!
If the victim was right-handed, he-most
probably had his towel on his right!
Hey. hey...
You expected him to wipe his hands
before he ate his Peking duck, right¢
How's that!
I think I've seen you
somewhere before...
Don't try to distract attention!
I have the same feeling...
You do, too, eh?
I've only seen your face on
TV and newspapers!
Inspector Yokomizo! Sir...
Huh? What is it?
Yokomizo...
Oh! Yes! You're Yokomizo! Yokomizo!
I suspect that you committed a
and had to shave your head.
That's why you're so embarrassed and
are pretending not to know us!
Hey! Hey! You, the great pretender!
Well, to tell you the truth, that hair you
had was quite unkempt.
You look much cleaner...
You are talking about my brother
Sango with the Shizuoka police.
I am Jugo Yokomizo
of the Kanagawa Police!
A brother?
For real?
It appears that the naive and trusting brother
of mine respected you, but I'm different!
I don't have an inkling of respect for
slaty peope I ece ec ives.
Sir... Inspector...
Oh. kept you waiting...
Look what I found on the
jeans the victim was wearing...
Some sort of the stain...
Oh, that's Mr. Kawabata's soup!
I spilled it when I sat next to him...
What? Next to him?
I thought that you and the
kid were sitting next to him!
Mr. Kawabata changed
seats just before he fainted...
He took a seat between Ran and me.
Later, Conan sat next to him.
Then, before he changed seats,
he was sitting next to the girl and...
It was me...
But, I just happened to sit
there because Mr. Kawabata
invited that detective
and others to our table...
Incidentally, before Mr. Mouri arrived,
we sat beside Mr. Kawabata...
But then, we were seated
quite apart from each other...
I-I was seated right at opposite of him, ¥
so I'm innocent.
We will know after we investigate...
Then, why not check his jeans?
Mr. Kawabata changed his seat
after he got the soup on his lap...
He wasn't trying to
wipe it off with the towel.
If you check the stain, you'll probably know
when the towel was tampered with, right?
Isn't that right, Uncle Kogoro?
Well... yeah...
What! There was no cyanide in the stain?
Did you check it thoroughly?
Yeah... the waiter said he replaced the
chopsticks that fell on the floor
with the soup on the victim's order there
was no cyanide on the chopsticks either...
That means, the culprit replaced
hat towel with a poisoned on
which means the suspect
IS you, who sat on his right!
Nonsense!
Why would I have to kill Mr. Kawabata,
when I have seen him for the first time at
a restaurant I came for the first-time!
Humph! There's no telling...
Well, the story about your daughter been
asked to appear in the movie
at a restaurant you came for the first
time sounds suspicious, too...
Hey, that's...
That's true! We came here...
By coincidence...
wants happening...
win... a rainy day again.
I saw him who is he
Or, is it somebody else
who looks like the Inspector?
I can't remember...
That faint image of three faces
A mouth smiling...
Angry eyes...
What...?
What are you saying?
I can't hear... Shinich
Ran! Ran!
What happened? You look pale!
Oh, I'm okay. I just felt faint...
Why don't you sit down here. I think
Uncle will solve the case soon...
Yeah... thanks...
And, don't get in the way, Conan.
We're in trouble...
Ran must be really sick...
We have to get her to the hospital soon...
Original Comic Books By
GOSH AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
Background Music
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDQ@
Story Editor.
\ 2 Cr
Scripts By.
KANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI *
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDG@
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO QOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYOD
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMIT UJ OKADA
Chicf Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in association with
RI TELECA
CORPORATION
DEIHCIIN Peon AN :
GOSTD AY IM Ay sh 1G ARLUKAN YTV IAS
Ul Rights Resprved
I get it! You brought the towel tosthe
restrooms and laced it with cyanide...
How many times do
I have. to tell you... I didn't do it!!
Don't want to see...?
Did you find something else?
Well..."none in particular...
Hmmm... really...
Nothing on it...