Suspense and deduction closes the gap
between the love and hatred
between two people
Mystery revolves around a chinesestable
Ran"s memory comes back
He sees through the one and only truth
a child in appearance
with the'l.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
With a dinner coupon that
Ran won in a shopping mall lottery.
We are heading toward
Chinatown in Yokohama.
There, we met people
In the movie industry.
Mr. Kaizo Isogami, film director
Kaizo Isogami
film director
Mr. Kaizo Isogami, film director
Kaizo Isogami
film director
Br 8mGdD
RAD NA
BR Tk BE
Mr Motohiro Ito, assistant film direct
Motohiro Ito
assistant film director
Mr. Motohiro Ito, assistant film direct
Motohiro Ito
assistant film director
>» GET
(FR EIQ)
WR UH BH BR
Mr. Keigo Kitaura, author of the boo
Keigo Kitaura
author of book
Mr. Keigo Kitaura, author of the boo
Keigo Kitaura
author .of book
AEM BITE (2<)
And the producer Mr. Shiro Kawabat
Shiro Kawabata
producer
And the producer Mr. Shiro Kawabat
Shiro Kawabata
producer
Circumstances led to us
having dinner with them.
But. suddenly...
Mr. Kawabata died.
Poison was not found in his clothing.
Because chemical reaction was found
on the plate and towel that he used
Pops who sat beside him was
suspected of planting cyanide.
This is ridiculous!
Why do I have to kill 2a man
I met for the first time
at a restaurant I came for the first time?
What you say sound suspicious already!
What's superb timing for your daughter
to be asked to appear in the movie
at a restaurant you came
for the first time!
True!
We came to this restaurant
Just by coincidence...
Ahhh
Are you all right? You look pale.
I'm okay. I was just a bit dizzy.
Why don't just sit over there.
Uncle will solve the case soon.
Yeah. thanks.
We're in trouble
wv op
Ran looks really sick.
We need to take her to a hospital soon.
Chinatown: Deja vu in the Rain-Part 2
Anyway, the killer replaced
that poisoned towel...
After the soup was spilled, and
the victim changed seats. that means...
You were sitting to his right
at that time and are the prime suspect!
Hey. hey...
Hey. Inspector...
what?
Umm Ra...
Inspector!
This bottle believed to have contained
the poison was found in the restroom.
What!
I see... the towel was brought into the
restroom and laced with the poison...
That's why. it's not me!
In that case, Uncle Kogoro
IS not the culprit!
What?
Cause Uncle hasn't been to the
washroom since he arrived here!
So that's why, Inspector!
Mr. Kawabata changedseats, holding
his towel he used to wipe the soup off.
That's why, nobody
could have switched towels...
No. there must be something to wait...
a way to switch without people noticing...
I see!
The killer used the rotation
of the turntable!
The cyanide-laced towel is placed at the
edge of the turntable and it is rotated cleverly
It can fall right in front of Mr. Kawabata!
How's that!
Even if you say "How's that"...
If something like that falls, everybody
will find it strange. right?
So. that's why it has to be done cleverly
SO Nobody notices...
If nobody sees it, the speed with which
the turntable has to turn
to drop off the towel would
make all the plates fall off, too!
In the first place, who'd use such
a towel when you have one yourself?
Ha. ha... you're right!
Wait...
I remember when I tried to
get the soy sauce and the chili oil...
The turntable rotated so many times,
that they were hard to get...
The order of the dishes that
were placed.on the turntable was...
in the clockwise direction...
Twice cooked pork
1:8 PS
We 2-0
Pepper Steak
¥/v0 RX
HEY $4
Crab Omelette
Century Egg
Sweet and Sour Pork/ /
BF BX
Lid of a Steamer
ZRAED TD >
The soy sauce was between the
sweet and sour pork and the century co S
and the chili oil was between the
twice cookeed pork and the steamer lid.
- - «de
At that time. the order of the seats was...
Starting with the victim Mr. Kawabata,
In the clockwise direction,
Me. Ran. Mr. Kitaura,
Mr. Ito, Mr. Isogami, and Pops...
And the soy sauce went back in front
of Pops again and again...
And the chili oil went
back in front of Mr. Kitaura...
Oh, yes, Mr. Kawabata said...
Actually, I'm allergic to eggs
and hate even the sight of it...
even the sight of it
Okay, work on this area with caution.
Yes. sir!
Excuse me. officer!
Yes?
There's something I'd like to ask you...
What's that, kid?
If you checked the food...
you must have checked the plates and
the top of the table as well, right?
Yeah...
Then...
So you checked places like there right?
No. not yet...
Then, Uncle Kogoro is
asking you to check it right away!
What? You mean Sleeping Kogoro?
Yes, also, did you find anything
funny on the towel with cyanide?
Huh? You mean other than the cyanide?
Oh, yes! Yes, there was
a light brown stain!
I sniffed it. and that's soup for sure!
You must have seen it, right?
Mr. Kawabata spilled the soup on his
jeans and wiped it with the towel. right?
It's a stain from the spill...
Anything else?
You found nothing else?
Oh. no . nothing special...
Really... nothing else... right?
Then, I'll tell that to Uncle Kogoro!
Oh... okay...
I was right.
Mr. Kawabata was not killed by switching
his towel with the poisoned one...
The towel was switched
after he was killed...
By that person...
If that is right, the evidence
must still be there...
On that table...
Anyway...
The killer is the one who laced his own
towel with cyanide in the restroom
and switched it with the
victim's towel at the table!
Yeah... without attracting the attention of
Rang Conan and me sitting on both sides
But how... how can you do that...
Oh. that's how!
All three suspects are In
the movie industry!
Maybe he used an invisible line used In
special effects to move the towel...
For goodness's sake...
They've got to turn
down the air conditioning!
What is it, Inspector Yokomizo?
Well... there's something...
I heard from my brother...
Kogoro Mouri makes bizarre comments?
At first. but it's only to fool people...
His attitude changes abruptly with a
weird voice and dance...
As if a spirit takes hold of him
A whole entirely different person...
But. of course. he can be exaggerating...
Is that what you mean ..7?
By a weird dance...?
What?
So. enough joking around...
Now, I would like you to take your seats...
At the same table the crime took place.
There was Mr. Ito,
Mr. Isogami and Mr. Kitamura...
Then, I'll be able to tell you everything...
hat happened during dinner...
It's happening!
The Sleeping Kogoro detective show!
First, I would like to have Inspector
Yokomizo take a seat where the victim sat.
From his right, in the exact same seating
arrangement, there's me and Mr. Isogami,
+2 Mr. Ito and Mr. Kitaura...
Next, at Ran's seat,
I'd like another police officer...
'  ~r@
Humm™ Why?
hh... my daughter is and feeling to we
I'm all right!
I can do it.
Ran...
And Conan sits
between Ran and the victim...
Now that all the seats are taken,
I would like to hear an exclamation...
of a mysterious incident that took place
immediately before the crime...
A mysterious incident?
Yes, the table! Somebody was moving the
turntable, trying to give me a hard time!
What?
Look!
Do you see the bottle of soy sauce on the
turntable right in front of Uncle Kogoro?
Yeah...
I moved the turntable
to get the soy sauce...
Each, time I tried to get it.
It will return/immediately in front of
Uncle. No matter how many times I do wt
The same thing happened with the
chili oil in front of Mr. Kitaura!
Each time the bottle came close to me...
We It would go back to where
It was right away...
This means that someone was having
fun, giving me a hard time. night?
Hey, Mr. Detective... Is what the kid is
saying related to the crime?
H-hey... don't...
It's all right...
What?
Uncle Kogoro said we don't have to do
anything for the culprit will expose himself.
Expose... himself. ?
Here you are, little boy. Your bun"
Wow! Thank you!
Hey why now?
Oh... yes. Detective Mouri ordered
Chinese bun for this little boy...
Thank you! First. a big bite!
Don't eat it!
What is it, Mr. Isogamir
Somebody got killed just
now at this table! VY
Poisonamight still be
found somewhere on the table!
And you allow a kid to
eat with his hands here?
But. the forensics have already checked
and did not find cyanide anywhere...
Mr. Isogami is right...
There might still be cyanide...
Somewhere... where we cannot see...
Hey!
Don't fool around with me!
Get to the point!
Who's the culprit=and™
where's the cyanide!™
How would you turn it?
What?
The turntable...
How? Of course,
you placeryour hand like this...
you place:your hand like this...
What would you do if plates are crowded
Iike this egg and crab dish and the pitan?
Well, in that case...
Ill pick up the edge
of the turntable withimy fingers...
It can't be...
The cyanide is under the turntable?
No. wait There are a lot of problems
here making the victim touch this...
What is Mr. Kawabata
didn't like these two dishes?
What?
What is Mr. Kawabata ¢
didn't like these two dishes?
Is that right?
Y-yes. . Mr Kawabata
was allergic to eggsO.
Now, Inspector Yokomizo. please check!
Right in front of you,
seated at the victim's chair...
are the two dishes.
Now. where is the chili oil?
In-in front of-Mr. Kitaura...
Yes: of course!
That's why. when the, kid
tried to get the chili oil.
The turntable was returned
to the original position!
The victim would try to
avoid the two dishes 'and
hold the table to moving
around, again and again!
It might be true for the chili oil But this
time. the soy sauce is in front of the kid.
Why then did the table turn when he
tried to get the soy sauce?
To get the victim to touch the cyanide, you
have to get the cyanide on that spot, right?
In addition, the cyanide must be applied
immediately before the Peking duck is served
a dish you have to eat with your fingers
If you do that eailier, somebody might
touch it accidentally
Then, when the kid tried to get the soy
sauce, he had not applied the cyanide yet?
Right...
Most probably, the culprit tried to apply
cyanide on the underside of the turntable
where the two plates were placed
when the waiter could be seen
bringing the Peking duck.
He couldn't apply the cyanide and
turned the turntable again and again,
because Conan would rotate it.
Y-you mean...
the person who had the two plates
in front of him when-the soy sauce
was in front of you is the...
Yes...
That person...
Killed Mr Kawabata...
Here... tonight!
Mr. Isogami!
Then, what was that
towel with so much cyanide?
That was Mr. lsogamrs towel...
He brought the towel to the restroom, poured
cyanide on it, and returned to his seat
He applied the cyanide on that spot...
In the chaos that ensued when
Mr. Kawabata lost consciousness...
He switched towels...
To make sure nobody notices the switch,
he drenched his own towel with soup...
He wanted to make the
towel look identical to
Mr. Kawabata's towel after
he wipe the soup of his pants, but...
You missed one small point...
that Mr. Kawabata was wearing jeans!
Es... on Mr. Kawabata's
towel that you switched...
Along with the soup stain...
There was a blu stain from his jeans!
I get wt... if that towel is night
In front of Mr Isogami.
That is proof that he is the killer!
No... that towel is not proof enough...
Why
There is the possibility that the towel was
placed there to frame Mr. Isogamu...
But, you will confess,
won't you? Mr. Isogami?
When Conan touch the place with
cyanide just a while ago...
And he tried to eat the bun with
those hands. you stop him...
There is enough conscience left in you...
Conscience...
If that guy who let Rika die had a bit of
conscience, I wouldn't be doing this...
Rika? You mean the girl
who died a year ago . ?
But. that was an accident during the shoot...
It was no accident!
That was full-fledged murder...
That Rika took over the stunt in the
Iast scene from the stunt pro...
Kawabata knew about it all along...
R-really!
He told me that he made her wish to
do it on her own come true
He said the movie became a hit, thanks
to her. grinning that evil grin...
We had so many opportunities to stop that...
F) ('U f
B-but why? The diretor snubbed her
for:being such a ham...
You're still green...
A director's job is a sad one...
When you keep on I coking at the
actress through the camera lens,
You fall in love with her...
No matter how amateurish... or uncouth
You'll never get to direct a film,
If you don't understand that.
Okay. let's go...
We'll talk to you at the station...
Mister Detective, I'm sure you had
already wiped off the cyanide...
But. what were you planning if I had
pretended not to know and let him die?
If I was a man like that scoundrel?
Then, I was planning 10 say something
different to corner you...
And stop you from
trying to make excuses...
I wanted to see that!
I have a gripe to whoever gave
melthis thing called conscience...
As a film director, I most certainly wanted
to see you interrogate ruthlessly...
I'm not the one to believe in a god...
God...
Is there a god in this world?
That voice... Who?
That calm voice of a woman... Who is it?
Ran?
Rain...
The noise of the rain is fading...
Is that okay?
I can hear
Should there be a reason?
Is there a god?
Your Japanese?
The angel did not smile at me.
Get out!
Not even once...
Sharon.
Yes . that time
I met her.
With Shinichi
IFRS
Ran!
Original Comic Books By.
COSHQAQYAMA
Producers.
MI@HIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMQ@ SUD@
Story Editor.
111N161 110161
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARY KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Anim$ion Dircctors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chicf Director.
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By.
ENTERTAINMENT
In assoctation with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DE THIN fx NAN
GCOSHO VOY WITT SHOGARUK ANY IV TMS
Ab tl guts ued
Ran. can you hear me!
What happened. kid?
Ranis... Ranis...
She's so hot!
We need an ambulance!"
Yes: sir!
Ran! Ran!
Ran. can you hear me!
what
Is that you? Shinichi? Shinichi?