Suspense and deduction closes the gap bet een
the love and hatred between two people
Going to New York with Ran.
The suspense starts with a actress.
He sees through the one and only truth
a child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Ran...
Rain...
Do I need a reason?
Does God really exist
Are you Japanese?
No angel ever smiled down on me...
Get lost!
Not even once...
Sharon .
Now I remember... that's when
I met her...
I went with Shinichi...
Rank.»
(FF)
SHINICHI IN NEW YORK-PART I
Ran! Ran!
Ran! Hey Ran!
What's the matter! Hey!
Ran! What's wrong!
Ran! Wake up!
What's wrong kid?
It's, Ran...she
¥, »¥4
This"is terrible! She's burning Up
Hey. call for an ambulance
Y. yes sir!
No, wait! Call the hospital and
tell them we're bringing a patient in!
Eh? But Inspector,
which hospital do I call...
The one on the other
side of the Bay Bridge!
They have an emergency ward!
Yes sir!
Oh my... what happened... ..-to me
I know a doctor...at that hospital...they'll
give us a bed right away and
it won't take us 10 minutes to
get there with in the police unit!
Got you!
Start the engine!
We'll be there right away
Yes, sir!
What happend...
Ran! Ran!
Hang or! Ra 1}
what?
Ran... Ran
Ran...Ran...
Who's there?
Shinichi...is that you Shinichi?
How embarrassing... he saved
me again .just like the last time
whenever I'm feeling depressed. he
seems to be able to see right through me
I hate to admit«it but,
It makes me happy...
Shinichi.
Shinihi...
what?
Wait a second...
isn't that...
the Statue of Liberty.
In Japan. we call it Jiyu no Megumi
I've heard that New Yorkers
ca er ISS 1rery ougn...
For goodness sakes!
Why didn't you wake me up!
I was really looking forward
to seeing this night view
of the city from the Brooklyn Bridge!
And look, we're almost at
the end of the bridge already!
Listen you...
If you'd have slept in the
plane like everybody else
you wouldn't have
fallen asleep like you did!
How could I sleep after that last case?
I'm not like, some people.
Can fall fast asleep after
being satisfied they solved a case!
I wouldn't say I was completely satisfied.
When it comes to the reasoning
and analysis of crime
I don't think we can learn enough,
it would take a lifetime and
I still wouldn't know
everything there is to it, Watson
What?
Just listen to you two
this romantic view of the city would
charm every couple in the world,
are you two having a lover's spat?
How I envy you!
Mom, this is all your fault you know...
we weren't supposed to
arrive in New York until tomorrow
but the minute we arrived in Los Angeles,
you made us get on the
Iane to New York...
I didn't have a choice.
I wanted to see this musical
but I didn't think I could
get the tickets, but I did!
What? Did you say musical?
Yes. see, that one.
Good grief...
Golden Apple, I hear
It's very popular now...
That's right! Broadway's Phantom
Theater, 8pm. I'm so excited!
There sure seem to be a lot of police cars
on the road tonight. don't you think?
I guess they're after that slasher.
S. slasher?
I heard the slasher's Japanese and
he only goes after young women
You don't have to worry!
He only appears after midnight
you won't run into him as long as
we get back to the hotel by the besides
it isn't even 6 yet!
Don't you mean 7?
We're on daylight savings time now.
What?
Oh no! It slipped my mind completely!
Starting the first Sunday in April,
we set our clocks 1 hour ahead, don't we!
Oh no!
Why re you so upset?
It only takes about 40 minutes
to get from here to Broadway!
And it's still before 7,
we'll get there in plenty of time
You don't understand, I promised to meet
the person who got the tickets for me!
I'm supposed to get to
see the dressing rooms is
I get there 1 hour before
the curtain goes up.
I guess you're just going
to have to forget about it.
This so called "English Lady you bought
because you fell in love with it
will never get you there on time, mom.
Now you've done it. Shinichi
Ran. grit your teeth and hang on tight.
Okay...sure...
The people at the Jaguar
company put everything
Into this E type when they built it!
You can't be serious...
Never underestimate me!
Are you sure about this?
This car was in the
shop for repairs last month...
you just:got it back the other day!
Don't worry mechanic was a pro,
the car works like a dream!
The 267 horsepower
engine won at LeMans!
What are you doing!
That's enough! There're
police cars all around you know!
I don't care!
They were in the opposite lane.
While they're admiring this beauty of
a car, we'll disappear from sight
By the way will you and
Ran do that thing you always do?
It's pretty tricky up ahead. okay?
Will you do it for me?
Oh good grief...
Thanks!
I hate to ask but Ran,
can you come up here
Eh? Okay...what is it?
Don't worry, just trust me
it's only scary in the beginning
I guess so...
Are you okay?
What are you doing. Shinichi?
Just hang on tight.
See. it wasn't so bad.
Are you crazy, how can you say that!
Hmm...it's exactly an
hour before the curtain goes up!
Tod ou.
We got here right on time. no problem!
I. guess I was wrong...
BBL (on J
Your license andiregistration! please!
Okay. okay...
You were going/40 miles
4 over thgspeedilimit
409 AILF - A 11
Sa -I\J)-ODEOLHMLY
404A - At)
who do you.think youya,eDirty-Harry
Sorry we-were, ina hurry
You-~look familiar...
Well 3yoursmight have.
Yousmightihave:met-her-onfanother:case.
Youzseeisshers;one of uss...
Captain!
FiadSheisan-undercoverragent! Ar
fF MN BESR > WARE SAT
It looks like the criminal
iB Lgotrawayifrom her this,timesthough
Who's the old guy?
Radesh...
Yusuke met him when he solved a case.
That's how they became friends, he's a
captain on the New York police force,
his name's Radesh Redwood!
His Japanese is pretty
good since his wife's from Japan...
Thank you Radesh!
That was embarrassing.
No problem,
it's not me you have to thank.
Eh? I don't understand...
If you want to thank someone
you can thank me!
Thank me. Sharon Vineyard.
Sh, Sharon. .what are you doing here?
The officer who was just
here. he's one of my fans
He and-!- started talking
while I was waiting for you,
then a police bulletin came in
about a silver Jaguar heading this way
travelling at a ridiculous speed
and I came up with this idea of disguising
myself as Captain Redwood!
You should be impressed!
This man's coat was pretty expensive.
I am impressed but are you sure it
was okay? Everyone's looking at us
Don't worry, it won't be a problem,
I told everybody we were filming a movie.
Oh Sharon. I just love you!
Hey, mom...explain
things to me... who is this lady?
You mean you don't know, Shinichi!
She's a famous American actress!
Like I was saying...
how can a famous actress.
Like her disguise herself
so well that nobody recoggnizes her!
Didn't I ever tell you the story?
When I was just starting out as
an actress, I got a role as a spy.
And to get into character
I signed up to study under a famous
magician to learn how to disguise myself
Sharon was also there since
she had gotten a similar role,
that's how we became friends!
Only thing is. I never got
to be as good as her
she can disguise herself perfectly!
Yeah, you were always fooling around
but you seemed to be playing dress up
instead of disguising yourself
Sorry I wasn't good enough for you!
But I was doing my best!
I'm so thrilled! I got to meet such a
famous person and in New York, no less!
I've got to thank God for this!
Does god really exist?
If God does actually exist...
then all the people who
are striving to survive
should be rewarded with
happiness, isn't that right?
Yes, at the very least...
no angel ever smiled down on me
not even once...
The sadness in her smile might have
been a premonition of things to come
of the tragedy that would soon follow
I didn't want to
remember it. that awful incident
Wh...what do you mean by that?
About no angel ever smiling on you?
She's trying to say she's had a hard time!
Isn't that right ..Sharon!
That's right, my life's been
one hardship after the other
I struggled to become an actress and on
the day my debut film was to be shown
my parents died in a fire...
thentthe day after I received the Oscar,
my husband died from an illness
then there's Chris who made her debut so
easily just because she was my daughter
everything was handed to her on a silver
plate, what a difference between us.
Don't exaggerate, I know you're proud of
her, you put everything into raising her.
That child, I don't
consider her my daughteranymore
What?
I don't know if you can believe this.
But she stood behind me while I was
putting flowers on my husband's grave
and she had disguised herself
to look exactly like him,
don't you think it was rather
sick to be considered a joke?
I just remembered what
you once told me
you said you taught her
how to disguise herself
because she begged you so much...
I haven't spoken to her since
it's been almost 10 years
and it seemed like she was hanging
around some shady characters
but enough about that, go park
your car in the parking lot
Iet's head for the dressing rooms.
I think those people have started to
realize there're no cameras around
But why did you want us
here an hour before the show starts?
We'd be less of a bother
for everybody if we came earlier
and we'd have had more
time to talk to the performers.
Don't be silly, if we came here earlier
the performers would still
be just regular people
but seeing them just
before the show starts
Why if it isn't Sharon!
You came to see us after all!
Lira Sanchez
Why if it isn't Sharon!
You came to see us after all!
Lira Sanchez
oA ST ST AN
Lest, ODD
MATE IR)
I guess our coach does
tell the truth sometimes!
Akane Nirusen
I guess our coach does
tell the truth sometimes!
Akane Nirusen
) NX-"-)veer/
L'a 9
£27 (8 (27)
Rose Huide
How exciting! I'm so happy!
This is like a dream!
Rose Huide
Acca-A In
ML» 5
Hr . (28)
How exciting! I'm so happy!
This is like a dream!
Rose Huide
O-X-Ea-_1 bk
woe BD
£3371 (28)
I'm suprisd you had time!
Are yousfree today?
Let's go eat later!
Now I get it...
when we see them just before the show,
they're already in make up
and they re actresses.
Wow... they all adore her. don't they!
Yes, they do she knows
heir troupe leader very well,
when she said she wanted to
come and give them her support
she was handed to the
tickets, just like that.
Is that?
I don't believe it. is that who I think it is?
It sure is.
( ") ¢
The people's favorite
female private detective
Night Baroness!
At your service!
Night Baroness?
Night Baroness
SA h/NOA=ZR
(MD RIB FAN)
Night Baroness
FA A=
(MOB RN)
That's what she's called back here!
Night Baroness
FASO A
(MOHAIR AN)
Because she's married to Yusuke Kudo
the author of the book Night Baron?"
And being married to a mystery
writer, mom once appeared
as a guest on a special investigative
program on television here
She analyzed a crime and
everything she said fit,
the criminal was arrested right away.
that's how she became so popular and
they nicknamed her Night Baroness.
Wow...
But no one knew she was
only repeating what dad mumbled
while he read the
newspaper every morning.
You mean those two are your children?
He is but she isn't
maybe shell become
family Tithe future. though.
How wonderful!
She's so lucky!
Well, Well...
I thought the Night Baroness
was here to solve the mystery
of the strange parcel...
But I see she's only come 10 gossip a
Nd she's even brought her Kids with her
Everess Hamilton
ANIJRXIN=)Lb/
£27 (30)
I'm so disappointed.
Everess Hamilton
ANJA I\N=)Lb_/
rams
Ilfiill (30)
Everess Hamilton
ANJA I=)
Lyla 5
=I (30)
Strange parcel?
That's right. a package
was sent to the troupe 3 days ago!
It was apples sprayed with
a golden coating. golden apples
there was a message inside, it was
written in animal blood and said
To the most beautiful woman
BOLL iE
TO the most beautiful woman
So that explains*the ominous feeling I
got when I walked into this dressing room
Alright people, just calm
down my lovelies
Heath Flockheart
NJ- fi a
> Led bs
Alright people, just calm
down my lovelies
Heath Flockheart
A-20,0)/\ bk
RLEL'OD
RARER)
I'm sure it was just
somebody's idea of a joke
But Heath...
Who's that?
That's Heath Flockhart,
the star of this theatrical group
But tonight's his last performance
because he got a role to star in a movie
I see...
Okay. everybody cheer up.
Let's all give Sharon and p
her friends the backstage tour
Are you sure it's alright?
The show starts in 40 minutes, maybe
we shouldn't be bothering them
Don't worry about it!
The first 20, minutes will be a narration,
a narrator will just go on
and on about Greek mythology
What's that up there?
Oh that. they're stage costumes!
They have it suspended up there
so it doesn't get in the way
I see...
Look out!
Armor!
Ran!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO_AOYAMA
Original Comic Books By.
GOSH AWYAMA
Producers.
MIGHIHIRO -SUWA
MA AHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUD@O
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I110OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KDUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
In assocration with
YOMIURI TEDECA TIN
CORPORATION
DETHCIINVE CONAN
GOSH TOY AN Tv SHO GARUA ANY IV TMS
All Rights Reserved
Wh.what!
Mom. take care of Ran!
Sh, Shin!
Rats...
I knew I wouldn't make it in time...
A bullet casing?
This is...