Suspense and deduction closes the gap between
the love and hatred between two people.
A mystery on the shining
broadwayiwith. my mother
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
After the case in €hinatown
at Yokohama was solved
Ran suddenly collapsed and
In her delirium,
she recalls a case from the past...
The ase was.
When Mom finagled us
into going with her to
see a musical in New ork.
Waiting for us in front of
the theater. was Sharon Vineyard.
A famous actress and
also mother's very close friend.
She was going to give us
the backstage tour
but as we walked through
the wings before the show...
What's that on the ceiling?
Oh that, they're stage costumes!
They have them suspended up there
so it doesn't get in the way.
I see...
Look out!
Armor!
Ran!
(38 BxR)
SHINICHI IN NEW YORK-PART II
Hang in there Ran...
We're almost there,
we're almost at the hospital Ran...
Ran!
Are you alright, Ran!
I knew it was me
somebody wants to kill me!
I don't think so the rope snapped
because it was worn out.
Alright, whe did this?
Who hung that thing up there!
Things could've been worse though...
We were lucky that huge
mirror over there didn't break.
You're right, that mirror's
CL UR
What are you girls talking about, you don;t
owe that mirror or an angel any thanks,
You should thank her!
Thank you'll} I owe you my life!
Oh. it was nothing.
Hey! We should be getting ready by now.
We'll see you in our dressing
room after the show then
Okay!
Ouch!
Oh. I must've scrapped it...
Let's see, a bandage
do I have a bandage!...
Here
I was right, there is no God after all
If there was things wouldn't
have turned out so unfairly.
Yukiko, I'm, going home.
Weren't you going to watch the show?
Yes, I had intended to but
something important's come up
Besides, I've heard it's going to
storm tonight so I'm canceling...
This is great!
% knew you'd liKe it. You don't see
musicals of Such grand scale in Japan!
But there seems to be one kid
who doesn't feel the way we do.
Listen you! We've come all this way,
the least you could do is
pay attention to what's going on!
What's so great about this anyway?
They've just taken a Greek myth and
fixed it up into a romantic comedy.
Alright then, what's the
Greek myth it's based on.
The Golden Apple.
A long time ago, tere were 3
goddesses. Hera, Athena and Aphrodite,
had been invited to a banquet but there was
another goddess named Eris who wasn't
and filled with jealousy,
she sent them a golden apple...
with 2 message reading
To the most beautiful goddess"!
What? Isn't that just like...
Yeah, and the 3
goddesses decided to let
the prince of Troy choose which
one was the most beautiful
and each vied for his vote by telling him
what they'd give him for choosing them
that actor we just met, playing the
poor prince.he's the Prince of Troy
The actress playing the
rich man's wife is Zeus's wife,
Hera, the goddess of
marriage who promised to
make him the most
powerful man on Earth.
That headstrong looking
Japanese actress
IS Athena. the goddess of wisdom
who promisedi't "make
him victorious in battle
That sexy actress is the
goddess of beauty, Aphrodite
who promised to give him the
most beautiful woman in the world,
and the gloomy looking
actress in the previous scene
is the one who was jealous of the 3
the one who sent them the golden apples,
Eris. the goddess of discord, even
their names sound similar!
But in this play, money is power,
and work is the. battle
and romance is the beautiful woman,
and the golden apple has been
transformed into a necklace of jewels
And then? So who did he choose?
Aphrodite, of course!
But that was what eventually
caused the battle of Troy
But that's a Greek myth,
this musical is.a. little different,
you're going to be surprised
when you see who that sorry
Iooking poor prince really is.
Look! You poor souls
My name is Michael.
MM. Michael does he
mean the angel Michael!
He's got to be kidding...
You must heed my:swords.»
aly vA
What the!
Heath
It ca be...
You're right. he's probably playing...
No; he's: not playing
he's dead.
A gun
Somebody shot him!
Yes, it looks that way, I think it'd
be best if we got away from here too
Mom! Take care of Ran!
Sh, Shin!
Dang it...
I knew I'd be too late
A bullet casing?
This is...
What in the world!
I never thought it'd be
Heath who'd been shot...
Do you know him, Captain?
My wife's a big fan of)
his so, what happened?
The performers are
waiting in their dressing rooms
but the audience all ran off...
He, took a bullet in the
chest. 1it'srembeddedl~
in the wings on his back...
The wings on his back?
Oh. y6u mean this?
From the angle of the entry wound,
I'd say he was shot from
above at a 40 degree angle.
40 degrees? That's pretty high up.
Of. course it-is!
The shooter was up there
in the balcony seat,
And he used a laser sight.
Night Baroness!
Well if it isn't Yukiko.
And why are you here?
I just happened to watching the show.
I never dreamed the musical
would turn into a mystery though.
He was shot during the
climax where the angel appears,
the fireworks went off
and smoke filled the stage.
The image of the angel in the mirror
slides up and at the same time,
Heath, dressed as the
angel rises up from behind.
It was meant to look surreal, like
he had actually flown out the mirror...
So:what you're saying .is. the shooter
shot him: from the balcony
as he flew up from behind the mirror.
That's right and then the shooter
threw the gun onto the stage
to cause a panic, that way, the
shooter could get away in the chaos
Are you sure about that?
About the shooter being
in the balcony, I mean.
Of course I am! Thanks to all
the smoke on the stage. I clearly saw
a red beam leading from
the balcony to the stage
Besides. I think my son saw it too.
Your son?
Yes. he's standing right beside you!
What? Ouch!
He's the real thing alright.
Is this your son Shinichi, the
one you're always bragging about?
Yes, isn't he the splitting
image of Yusaku?
And they're both so mischievous too!
C€aptain! May I have a word.
What is it?
X, Cr
Shinichi, can't you behave yourself!
Gr . b)
Yeah, yeah...
Yukiko, it seems you were right.
There was a suspicious person who
bought that seat a month ago in advance.
And it seems they couldn't distinguish
whether it was a male or male!
Since the person wore a scarf and hat.
That's {he shooter. no doubt about it
But why that seat?
Is that a good seat. is it expensive?
That seat's at an angle. it's not a very
good seat, that's why it's cheaper
If someone came with their face hidden
and specifically requested that seat
they'd leave a lasting impression...
that's exactly what
the shooter would w ft.
I don't understand...
what are these two strange
marks on the deceased's body... \
Strange marks'? -
Yes, on his neck,
don't they look like burn marks?
And there s blood on his right hand...
Maybe he got it when he
grabbed his chest after he got shot
No, what: puzzles me is the
blood on his palm is smeared
It probably got smeared
when he touched something after
getting the blood on
his hand but there's no blood
on his clothes and it
wasn't possible for him touch
anything while he was hanging in mid air.
I don't think even you,
Might Baroness can solve that riddle.
0, 1 cE, elt Yor
Then let's ask Yusaku!
I'm sure he'd know
No, Yusaku's holedup in a
hotel room In Los Angeles-now
Thatis too bad a famous actor.s'
been murdered, what a mess
the murderer got away and on top
of that, we donit have a single clue
there's no telling what thegpeople and
the Chief will say, not to mention my wife
Excusemme...
then why don't you let Shinichi solve this?
Let Shinichi do it?
No way. impossible!
He s still a child and this is a
real murder weyre talkingtabout.
Yes but Shinichi solved the crime that
happened in the airplane
Sure, I'll bet that after the criminal
was caught, he whispered
I knew it, it's just as I thought, didn't he?
Uh, no, he was involved in the
investigation from the very start
He was?
Yes, and in the end, he
got all the suspects together and
smugly began to solve the crime
he acted like he was Holmes
or Poirot or something
So he did?
My Shinichi did that?
What?
The murderer is one of those four
actresses? I, I don't believe it...
Right after the shooting.
I went up to the balcony
¢ "at and I found this bullet '¢asing
it wasn't hot, it proves someone
Ieft it there beforehand...
But you saw it too, didn't you?
There was a red beam
ff@m that balcony seat to the stage.
Yes. that's whit it looked like,
but there's no way we could tell
where that beam came
from and where it was directed.
That's right that beam probably came
from the stage. not from the balcony
It was to make us think it
was coming from up there
what I'm trying to say is...
the person who hid their
face to reserve that seat
and the strange package: that arrived
was all a ruse to make us think
someone was after the actresses!
Oh. uh huh
Yes. I see what» ou mean...
And of course, this is part of it too
Huh? This is where that suit of armor
fell just before the show started...
Look at the floor
there's thin fishing line tied to the nail
and there's markings
on the floor beside it.
It looks like something was cut...
And there's fishing line on
the suit of armor that fell too.
Are you saying somebody
did this deliberately?
That's right, the culprit
probably had a blade
or some kind attached to
their shoe and used it to cut the line
causing the armor to fall...
The culprit knew that Sharon's friends,
that's us, would pass through here
during our backstage tour!
Which means, the culprit Is someone
who was here to drop the armor,
and was also one of the
performers on stage with Heath
that way she could aim the beam
at the balcony then shoot him
anyone of those four
actresses could have done it!
But he's 6° 3" tall!
All of them are under 6°
How could anyone of them shoot him
from overhead when he's taller
than them and on top of that,
he was behind the mirror
Yes, he's right explain that, Shin!
I. uh, haven't figured that out yet...
Lila...where you telling
me the truth just now
me the truth just now?
Yes, Heath and I were seeing each other,
we had been for about 5 years...
Then you knew he was
also going out with me too!
Will you two calm down! Must you
talk about that today of all days!
Hey now...
I'd. think you'd be the
most upset 'aboutithis
your boyfriend has 2 other girlfriends...
You mean you too, Rose?
Lila Sanchez
IDI IOFxA
ELVES a OB
RE THR (32)
Were you dating him too?
I see those four do seem to
have a motive for killing Heath...
Why? I don't understand. I know he was
dating the three of them but...
Everess doesn't seem
to be involved with him?
Unlike the others, she doesn't have a
photo of him on her mirror
The truth is. Everess
and Heath are married
What!
Sharon told me secretly when we
wer& being given the backstage tour
she said it was a secret because
his popularity would
drop if it\became public.
So that's why she hated him. because
he was dating the other three.
But what we have to figure out is,
how he was shot from above!
Rose was the closest to the mirror,
but, she was on the ground,
acting the part of a startled woman
Everess was staggering...
Akane was on her knees praying
The only one able to
shoot him from above was Lila
who was standing and
clutching her head. but
unlike the others who
were hidden by the smoke,
Lila's hands were in plain view,
everyone would have
seen her take a gun out...
Do you think it's
possible Heath bent down?
I doubt it, those wings
were. foot operated
and rigged so he couldn't bendadown
I see...
Hey Shinichi have you
come up with something?
Hey Shinichi.
Wait a minute
You've figured it out, haven't you?
Don't keep me in
suspense, tell me about it!
Hey Ran... how tall you are?
160 centimeters!
That'd be 53...
this pamphlet is about
172 inches so that's a foot
1 feet...
I hate to ask but can
you put this on your head
and stand in front of the mirror?
What?
What's this supposed to prove. Shinichi?
What. are you going ts do'?
Amman...
A clue.
A clue?
See, up over there!
There's a small crack...
That's strange. this mirror's been with the
troupe for years, it's their guardian spirit,
Sharon told me they took
good care of it because
they thought it'd be bad
Iuck if it got cracked...
He" what's this...
it looks like: its been patched!
Are you sure they took good care of this?
Don't yousthink this
curtain's a little crooked?
Somebody might've bumped into it
when they were trying to get to safety.
Hey Shinichi, let's go back already.
We're going to get scolded...
Feathers? How'd they get stuck here?
This cover of the floor
isn't used for anything...
Blood!
That's it now I understand!
The Killer used that certain
stage prop to commit the crime...
This bloody crime...
Was committed by someone
Iike that sneaky goddess Eris.
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO_AOYAMA
GOSH AWYAMA
Producers
IHIRO S
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASAEIIGMO sum»
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARY KOUCHI
JUNIGHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOU
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWATGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By
S ENTERTAINMENT, 1
in assocrifion with
YOMIURY TELECASTING O
CORPORATION
DETFCIIVE CONANT
(GOSH AY TM Ay SMMIOCARUK ANY IV IMS
VE Rights Reserved
Hmm... judging by the
position of the body
it doesn't seem possible that any of you
four could have shot him from above.
What's Happening?
Who turned the lights off!
The killer used that thing...
Are you saying the killer...
That's right!
There was only person
who could have done it!
Ve PEE
SHINICHI IN NEW: YORK-PART lI