Suspense and deduction closes the gap between
the love and hatred between two people.
Spending time with Ran in New York,
turning rain and mystery into memory. B
He sees through the one and only truth.
13/)
a child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Mom takes Ran and I
to see a musical in New York.
While we were being
given the backstage tour,
we met an actor Heath Flockhart
who ends up getting shot to death!
Feathers?
How'd they get stuck here?
I get it now...
SHINICHI IN NEW YORK-PART Ill
Let's see, from this position...
It doesn't leek like any of you
four could. have shot him from.above.
Then would you mind if
we changed our clothes?
Go ahead, since you all tested
negative for gunpowder residue too.
Which means the killer was
probably someone rom the outside...
Yeah. that's the only explanation...
What. Happend?
Who did that?
Who turned the lights off!
Me, I did it!
Some people know me as the
most beautiful actress in Japan
others know me as the
globe trotting mystery writer's wife
But in reality. I am...
a highly intelligent female detective.
I am Night Baroness!
Xcusefme. light man!
I'm over here!
Ukiko...
That's right!
Captain, the fog has been lifted!
I'm talking about the fog that hid the
truth behind the murder of course!
What?
Hey mom, don't get carried
away and mess up the ending.
Don't worry
I'll tell it exactly like you told me to.
Gosh...
Hey. are you sure you're right?
If you're wrong, your mom's
going to look like a fool!
Don't you think it's strange?
Heath's 63" tall, that's
about 190 centimeters
That's just about the height of you
with the pamphlet on your head
when I measured it just now, the
pamphlet stuck out over the mirror.
And on top of that, Heath had
those wings on his back
so he couldn't bend over,
even if he were behind the mirror.
You'd be able to see the top of his head.
That's why the killer used that certain
thing so his head wouldn't stick out
performers use it to appear
and disappear suddenly on stage
it's called a trap door!
But there wasn't anything
Iike that behind the mirror!
There was only a strange metal
cover on the floor beside it
Think, if you see a cover, you
should know there's a hole under it!
Feathers from Heath's wings
were caught under the cover,
and the blood on the floor
under the lid was arc shaped
and the stage has
a doughnut shaped ditch,
now add the crooked curtain near the
ditch and you should get the picture
By moving'thg,doughnut
shapedyfioor like that
the unseen trap door.
Opens right up!
I think if you check it,
you're going to find...
more feathers, the gunshot
probably knocked more off
and you should find
Heath's blood too
And you'll probably find the
bullet casing from the gun too!
But...
If the bullet casing's there,
that means he was shot at close range?
That's right... Heath was standing
by under the trap door
the metal lid was
resting against the mirror,
the killer shot him from above
but sticking her right hand
which held the gun,
between the mirror and the lid!
Are you saying the Killer...
Yes...
The only one capable of doing it...
under those circumstances,
was the once lying beside the mirror...
Ose...it was you, wasn't it
Rose?
I don't believe it...it can't be...
I mean, no one, not even the staff
mentioned the trap door would be used!
I'm sure that's true, because...
It's not that the staff DIDN'T tell you...
they COULDN'T...
All of you believe the mirror's
your guardian spirit,
they couldn't tell you
at it's been damaged...
I'm pretty sure Rose did it
when no one was looking
when the stagehands saw the crack,
they removed the damaged portion
Then adjusted the frame to cover it up.
SO everyone wouldn't be upset
and worry about having bad luck.
But since the frame was made shorter,
Heath's head would show
they knew that if they put
the mirror on a stand,
everyone would be suspicious
and notice it'd been damaged
that's why they decided,
on the spur of the moment,
to use the trap door so that
Heath would be out of sight!
They only told Heath and Rose about. it!
But why did the? tell Rose?
Isn't it obvious?
By moving the doughnut shaped floor,
they 'd be able to hide the opening but,
Unless Rose reached under
the mirror to lower the lid,
the audience would see it!
Then what about the gun?
It fell from way up high!
She was lying on the floor,
she couldn't have thrown it up that high
Of course she can!
Heath the angel was going to be
suspended ih mid air,
all she had to do was use him!
Remember, Heath had
a burn mark on his neck
I'm sure he got it
when she put the gun there,
it'd just been fired so it was hot...
if she put the gun there
in the folds of his costume and
when he stopped being lifted,
the vibration would cause it to fall,
that was the idea!
But I don't think
she even imagined for a second
he'd grab her with his bloodied hand
The reason the blood in his palm was
smeared proves that he grabbed her hand
And the proof should still be there
on her right hand and
on the inside of her glove...
Heath's hate filled handprint!
I'm pretty sure she performed
with her gloves inside out
And after firing the gun
she quickly turned them back correctly.
So that she wouldn't test positive
for gun powder residue
after the investigation started!
But Shinichi... when'd you
realize there Was blood on her glove
I realized it when I saw her struggle to
open the can of juice in the dressing room!
All she had to do was
take her gloves off but she didn't,
sO <figured.she was hiding
something under them!
But then I also got an epiphany right there
and then as to her motive for killing Heath
Her motive?
Remember, both Lila and" Akane had
photos on their mirrors,
taken with Heath
but not Rose, her photo
The angel Her photo
was of him in his angel costume
You weren't in love with him,
you were in love with his role as the angel
That's right... that's why
I killed him as the angel Michael
Because I just found it unbearable...
But he was quitting because
he was going to star in a movie
It was his own decision though...
he was responsible for Michael's death!
He knew how much I leved him
as Michael and he still did it
But it seems that
God was watching over me
When the suit armor fell,
I couldn't run away
because my clothes were caught
on a nail and God saved me
Thankyyou. sweet angel...
TA UL
DLILWVKEEE A
You helped-me.do it...
Alright then Shin!
I have to go to the police station and
stand in{when they questiontherifi/
so you'll have to go back
tofthe hotel by taxi
Oh and by the way, be careful,
there's a slasher on the loose!
He's Japanese and has long hair
See yourlater "Shin!
Good grief, she still treats me like a kid
doesn't she realize
I'm in high school already!
And then! This is what Holmes said...
Even if the world does revolve
around the moon, it will never
affect my work in any way
how'd you like that!
What's the matter. Ran?
You're not letting what Rose said to you
back there bother you, are you
Did she say something?
Her English was so fast,
I didn't understand a word
Forget. it.then!
It wasn't important anyway
Would you mind closing the window,
you're going,to.catch a cold!
Didn't you say you were feeling like of hot
since this morning?
Oh I'm fine already!
Besides. if I close the window.l won't be
able to see the city lights very well!
But..if the rain comes in and the seat gets
wet, the driver's not going to be happy
Don't worry! I have a handkerchief.
I'll wipe the wet areas before I get out!
Good grief
Oh, excuse me! Stop the car!
Please, stop!
That's strange. it should be around here...
I wonder if it got blown
away by the wind...
Just forget it! It's just a handkerchief...
It's not just an ordinary handkerchief!
Sharon gave it to me. it's very precious...
I guess there is no God after all.
Huh? Isn't that it?
See, it's caught on the railing
O 10Sses airs a wie ng.
It looks like an old abandoned building...
I'll get it for you right now!
You wait for me by the taxi.
If there is a God, it wouldn't
work out this unfairly.
3 ihhank-youn sweet angel...
DHED HHLILVKEEXA
35 You help,e'd1m'e_3do'~it...
MFTRULD'RIFSN-D
I wonder if Sharon, knew about it...
that Rose will commit the crime
and I saved the murderes life...
What'll I do...it's all my fault...
If I hadn't saved her then...
Heath wouldn't have been killed.
It's all my fault...
It's*my...
A Japanese man with long hair...
What! A gun?
Oh. no...
Il can't... I can't move.
He, (hurry-up jumpgin!y
He must be the serial killer!
FL\DZ EM 10 An BPE
Come on!
Dang!
Hey. Wait!
Are you Japanese?
What?
I asked you if you're Japanese?
Uhh...yes!
Did you see a suspicious man around?
What?
A Japanese with long hair dyed silver
and a sporting a beard
N. no, I haven't seen anyone like that...
Did -yourfind*him sir?
Non I only found:a tourists
aamscaamnucuamt max-Br
I:guessheghasn't toithisstreet.
Coma.
The gunfire againstjus excitedithe beast.
RE -RRIZATNBUr-BDOHKH
He. couldn't have
'gone;withoutjcatclginggheg:
This is no place for you young lady...
Turn right at that corner and
you'll be on the main street
and get a cab right away.
But wait. 1 have a friend...
I'm waiting for my friend here...
his a boy and same age as me...
Then I'll tell you and that
friend of yours one more time
Get lost!
Get out of this area right now!
THX KTIT OD PIRTEBRMDOELNT
-% Can we-leave her;alene? Ly
Nojproblem.
Every crossing to
this streetiispalready secured.
oD; this) streetlis already securedynw rs
So it's true...
that serial killer's
somewhere around here...
I've got to let Shinichi know right away
and we've got get out of here...
Sh, Shinichi...hey!
What the...l just saw something red...
Blood!
It couldn't be Shinichi's. could it...
Somthing must of happend to Shinihi...
Sh, Shinichi!
Oh no. is my cold coming back?
Come on Ran!
You've got to get a hold of yourself!
Shinichi came in here because
you let your handkerchief go!
That's right...everything is...
it's all my fault...
Everything...t's all my fault...
Oh, somebody's coming down...
Sh, Shinichi!
S. silver hair!
Blood!
Ran, get away from there!
That's the serial killer!
he's right girlie... was hiding out in here
But that kid found me...
If you're going to blame somebody,
you should blame God
for putting you in this situation...
Wh, what're you doing!
Hurry! Grab my arm! Hurry, my
hand's slippery because of the rain!
Sh, Shinichi...
Good grief...you're so much trouble
Why'd you do it? Why'd you save me?
I don't understand!
Do we need a reason?
I don't know what makes
a person kill another personbut
I do know why people save each other...
Logical thinking doésn:texist, does it?
Oh I get it...
yes, he's right...
I should have realized
it earlier... .how foolish of me...
Ran, you okay?
Don't do it...
I notice you're wounded, that mean
the police must be close by
You don't have a silencer, if you shoot,
the police"ll be all over the place
Not only that, you'll be giving
me the opportunity to capture you too...
I'll let you go today, but if we ever
meet again, I won't be so lenient!
I'll be like the Devil and list all your sins
and look at all the evidence
then I'll send you straight
to hell, so don't you forget it!
That's right...
didn't you see it on the news?
They found that serial killer...
Shin, turned him in!
But when the police got there,
he'd already been shot
they say it was a suicide...
Yes. .Ran's fine!
She had a fever last night but
after a good night's Fest
she's back to normal .
But so many things happened yesterday
You knew something was
going to happen, didn't you?
You knew [Rose was
UP to something didn't you?
Yes... I've always had a sixth
sense about things like that
But I never imagined that
she'd commit murder...
By the way. will you give
Ran this message"?
Tell her she was right, there does
seem to be an angel looking out for me
Oh really, has something
good happened?
I guess you could say that...
Hey...maybe you're not
over your cold yet...
I'm fine. really!
I'm going to check if you
have a fever, don't move
I'm fine!
What?
He was right! The doctor said her
fever would go down and it did!
Yo! So you're awake!
They said your fever was
caused. by exhaustion
I guess you'll have texgo easy on the
studying and club activities now!
The fever madeX ou delirious
and you were mumbling something
I did?
Something about saving somebody and
about logical thinking and stuff...
Uh oh!
No, stop! Those are my private thoughts...
What?
That's night! They're private
thoughts and very personal!
I don't want you say them
in your raspy voice!
What do you mean by that?
Alright then, I'll come pick
you up tomorrow.
Stay here tonight and rest up!
Good night Ran!
So that's what it was
I'd forgotten all about it
That's when it started, that's the
moment I fell in love with Shinichi...
Something's the matter with me...
how could I have forgotten
such an important event...
I guess the bad memories
suppressed the good ones...
I met so many people and so
many things happened, that's why...
That man in the black knit cap...
I wonder who he was?
F.B8.0.7?
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
IF TOUULULT by,
(SIFTFFIT SM IWA
VIAN scar Xd If9K
Background Mus:
KAT TO - ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KANJI*KASHIWABARA
KAZ UNARI_KOU CHI
JIINICHI MIYAS , TA
YUI(»HIT HIGURE
IC SHIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MASATOMO SUDO
» - cao Bb . - >» - TN
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
» 5 » & > wr eo Mn > -
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
whief Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
TMSSENTERTAINMENT,; LTD
+ 1N7AsSOGIa tion with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE (( NAN
Outlet 0 AOYAMA HOCAKUKAN:-YIV - IAIN
So you were in bed
because of a fever...no wonder
So that's why you didn't answer
the mail I sent you on the cellular,
Why Shinichi,
were you worried about me.
Uh... I just thought they might've
stopped service to your phone!
What's that supposed to mean!
So you feeling okay now?
Yes! I'm perfectly fine!
And thanks 10 the fever, I remembered
what happened in New York!
Oh. that was a horrible case...
Are "Ou okay though? »
That case left you feeling?really depressed
\ Don't worry)!
I remembered some good things teo
by the way, what ever happened to
Sharon's handkerchief?
Remember, you went into the abandoned
building to get it for me?
Oh that. I have it!
Oops...l wonder where I put it...
2 murders took place that day and...
I didn't:-want it to bring back
those memories so I put it away
2 murders? The serial
Killer committed suicide, didn't he?
Yes...that's what the police report said
The blood stains and finger prints
that should've been
there had been wiped clean...
If you were going to commit suicide,
would you go through all the trouble
of covering up your tracks?
I'm pretty sure...
somebody shot him just before he
was going to make his get away
Somebody got to him
before the police arrived...
: PE A
He took non-perishable food and
his wallet with him. that means...
Don't worry. everything"ll
be all right
we'll find him with these
Iocator eyeglasses
Officer Yamamura from the
Gunma Prefecture Police...
We met him in Osaka,
what's he doing here...