Suspense and deduction
closes the gap between
the love and hatred
between two people.
It's summer, ocean. and the islands!
Start of the case written on the sand
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
Alright then, that girl with
the short brown hair is next!
Her suit's dotted and kind of dull so
how about the one in the dark one piece
No... she's Kind of chubby
shess wearing thatfblack bikini
to make herself look thinner
See, I told you!
I win again.
You're not very good when it
comes to solving this kind of mystery
Aw shut up
What are you two talking about?
Ka. KazuhaO
Playing "Guess whatsKind. of swimsuit
she's wearing withearlittle boy...
Playing "Guess what? «kind of swimsuit
she's wearing withea little boy...
Playing "Guess what kind of swimsuit
she's wearing withra little boy...
Iffyour parents could see you now. I'm
grsure they'd be crying their eyes out
You don-tunderstand!
This kid kept bugging me about it,
I had no choice!
Heiji's really good!
He guessed right off that you'd be
wearing a tiger striped swimsuit, Kazu ha!
Shut up!
T, tiger stpiped...
You call this tiger stripes
This is a zebra print! Zebra...
What's the difference! The only stripes
that matter in Osaka are tiger stripes
Yes. .you're right .
Kazuha...
yousre-not still mad at me forymaking you
wait inxfront of BiggManiinr Umeda, right?
Ha... don't bensillyfl
why would I be mad at ajstupid}
boy~forrmaking me wailsfour hours...
Am not the least bit mad!
Not one bit!
She's ..furious
I don't blame her...
Just calm down, he invited you to;
Okinawa to make uPafor it. didn't he?
I'm not here because he invited me!
I only came here because
your father brought me.
Your father. the Sle&ping Kogoro...
Tomorrowss the big day, isn't it.
The battle of the/ best detectives
fromiathe -East and West!
How dosyou feel?
Are. ou confidentsyou.llrwin??
Confident?
No one can be completely
confident of anything...
Al I'm certain of is, I, Kogoro Mourn
will not lose to a kid from Osaka
who's still wet behind the ears,
that much, I'm sure of.
The old fool.
(BF %R)
PRINCESS OF THE ISLAND AND
THE DRAGON KING'S PALACE-PART I
Will all the staff gather round!
We're going to go check things out soon!
Check things out?
Yeah, we're going to check
out the area on the island
you and Mr. Mouri are
going to tomorrow.
It's an uninhabited island, a body an
some strange words were found the
MaséoTeiketornn
TV station.Director
TR TR (43)
SLE >a OF
You want to come along?
Young detective from the East?
Might be interesting...
I might be cheating by taking a
Iook around before them but
if that Conan helps
the old man and just by chance,
he solves the mystery before me,
It's going to burn me up...
Okay then! I'm going to go
check things out with them!
Okay thenOI'm going to go
H. hey.
That's fine...
What are you talking about?
We're going to put our heads together
and solve the mm ster In No time.
To show all the people in Osaka that we're
smarter than the detectives in Tokyo!
But I'm from Tokyo...
Hey! Look. that's it!
That's Funaura Island where the
unidentifiedObody was found!
It's nicknamed Onikame Island.
Onikame?
Take a look!
The tip of the island looks like
a turtle's head, doesn't it?
And then? So why're you and old
Kogoro going there to solve a mystery?
(0 guess it's some sort of local
event they came up with.
Mr. Kaneshiro's the mayor of
that island we were just on,
he told me that members of his family
have been kidnapped and robbed,
that's why the island has a bad reputation
and tourism has gone down the drain,
ay,»  * ? *
avi? 7
so he called the television station and
they can improve the image of the island!
It seems the mayor owns
that island too...
I don't think solving the
mystery behind a killing
going to improve the
Island's image though
he re from the television station but,
Mr. Taketomi's the only one
with television experience,
the others are locals who
know this area well...
Where're you girls from?
Tokyo?
I'm from Osaka!
Yoshizuki Kume
Then how about coming diving
with us after tomorrow's shoot?
Yoshizuki Kume
ZH or BB (25)
We live here so
we know some great spots!
Noburou lkema
Staff
th RA {8 BA (24)
AY yD
Oh no, no way!
Noburou Ikema
man imam)
AP yD
Oh no, no way!
Their schedule's full for today,
oOMmorrow an 1e@ ay a er.
You can't expect them to stick a tube
in their mouth and put fins on their feet
to make them look like
penguins so that they
can waste time staring at fish
In the ocean with you guys!
Huh? Who the hell're you?
That kid your boyfriend or something?
I'm glad you asked that.
Shes my .
She's my...
She's nothing
just an old friend but she's a real pest
SO you better not try anything with her!
He's not making a, lot of sense...
So what's your business then?
Why re you on this boat anyway?
You're not part of the crew
He's Heiji Hatton,
the detective from the East!
He's one of the main guests,
he's Kogoro Mouri's opponent
Yoshie Taira
Staff
EM 3R7I(6)
He's one of the main guests,
he's Kogoro Mouri's opponent
Yoshie Taira
Staff
ZR RT (26)
He's one of the main guests,
he's Kogoro Mouri's opponent
Yoshie Taira
Staff
He's one of the main guests,
he's Kogoro Mouri's opponent
Eh? This kid?
But... he's still just a kid...
That's what makes it so interesting!
The popular high school detective!
Challenges Kogoro Mouri. how's that!
I'm challenging that old fool?
Who cares about that...
Just do what you came here to do and
then let's get back as soon as possible...
They say that when it
gets dark around here...
Mikihiro Daitou
Staff
2+ bE
They say that when it
jets dark around here...
Mikihiro Daitou
Staff
WED EQ DC
AW RE (47)
gusds messenger"
comes for the "mabu
Mikihiro Daitou
Staff
£Do HT OO
AW 89 (47)
guso's messenger"
comes for the "'mabui
Right, Captain!
Takashi Shimoj
Toe. (30)
Guso's messenger
Comes for the mabui?
Guso means the nether world,
and 'mabui means soul.
It's an old Okinawan legend
When a woman is up all night
whiling time away
The messenger from the other
world dressed in death's robes
rises silently from the ocean
and sucks her soul out. so they say...
You're giving me the creeps!
I was planning on going for a swim
when we go to the island...
It's probably white...
What?
That girl's swimsuit,
I bet it's a white high leg cut!
Who cares...
Hey Captain!
Don't make so much waves!
She's wearing a black wetsuit.
Huh? That's strange...
From what I've heard, this island...
Hew!
The Director's calling you!
You've got to get to work now!
Yeah. I know...
Wow...
The Princess sleeps. not in B but in A
Are you sure the body was found in front
of this pillar with the words carved?
That's right...
He was leaning against it,
the words behind him .
They found him a year ago
he died of starvation, he hadn't eaten or
drunk anything for who knows how long
It was exactly a year ago that several
big typhoons passed through here,
so everyone figured he
was a crew member
from some shipwrecked
ship and got washed up here,
that's what the locals told me...
These strange words puzzle me...
Uh. by the way. who built this place?
This island's uninhabited.
Who's place is this...
It's Mayor Kaneshiro's
It seems he used to use
it as a vacation house...
It looks like he hasnnt fixed it,
the 'typhoon wrecked 'it though
I knew it was white!
You're right, it doesn't look
Iike it did the last time I saw it
I feel like I'm in another dimension...
You mean. you come to this island a lot?
Yeah. until two years ago.
I used to look out at this from my ship.
the ocean around here's full of
brown striped mackerel scad.
Brown striped mackerel scad?
You guys did too. didn't you?
Yeah. There's a great diving spot
right at the tip of this island...
But ever since they found that body.
Nobody comes near here,
it gives them the creeps
Hey guys well
Heiji and I will be discussing
things around here
SO you go look for other
spooky areas on this island!
Look for something that you
think will solve this mystery!
Okay!
What the...
he doesn't make this show sound so
serious. I bet he doesn't believe in me.
The Princess sleeps. not in B but A...
A & B probably refers to 1. 2 and 3
The Princess is sleeping in number
LWW OIT aa Nec THE Olga Hv
Hey Kudo. you got any ideas?
No. nothing...
You sure you haven't
figured it out already
but you don't want to tell me
cause you want beat me?
I wouldn't do that!
Listen, maybe it means the princess
sleeping face is the prettiest?
Hey wait!
Maybe it means .
The princess who's usually pretty I0OK™
gross when she's sleeping?
Hmm, that's not grossly impossible...
Hey! Pretty good!
Stop gabbing! Ninnies!
Aw, rats!
Ms. Taira's late. I wonder where she-is...
You're right .
It's been about an hour
since the rest of us got back to the ship.
Do you think she's still diving?
It's possible...
Wait up!
Hew!
I'll search from this side up to the shore!
Okay. I'll take this side!
Hey Miss Taira!
Where are you!
Miss Taira! Miss Taira!
Hey!
MM. Miss: Taira»
Miss Taira!
What!
Miss Tara's been murdered?
Ihcan't believe it...
You've got to be kidding!
She was killed about 2 hours ago...
She was strangled
something like a thin rope
she probably got those scratches
on her arms and legs
when she struggled as
she was being strangled
Which means the murderer
killed her in the woods
then carried her out her to the beach
then ran away not too long ago...
after leaving this weird
message in the sand
I am the "guso's' messenger?
Hey young detective...
How do you know that the murderer
ran away not too long ago
it's easy!
Look over there!
The sand's wet up till there.
That means the water was up
to there during the high tide.
But the waves are just
below the words now,
you'd have had to write them recently
when the tide was low or the
waves would wash them away.
Let me also add that this place is exactly
on the other side of the boat landing!
We were all on the boat a hour
ago waiting for her to get back
This kid and I were the first
to go look for her,
we split up and went around the island
then we found her body. which means...
there's somebody else on
this island besides us
And that person strangled her to death!
No way...
Somebody besides us?
Kazuha, you've got a digital
camera, don't you
Uh, yes...
I have it with me
Alright then Kudo.
Let me have that glowing watch or yours
and one side of your sandal!
Eh? I understand about the
watch but why my sandal
Oh I get it. _.
You needed something to
show how big the words were
I have to take a picture now or they'll
get washed away at the next high tide
Hey what is this! You
didn't need my watch
I guess not.
Okay then let's carry her body back to the
boat before she gets washed out to sea!
Yeah, okay...
Who'd want to kill her though...
Maybe...there's something in the ocean?
Something inside the ocean?
You remember, she went snorkeling
as soon as she got to this island.
I'm sure there's something there for
her to be so dead set on diving here
What do you think they mean?
I don't know. bum! think it'd better if we
went back to.the boat now
and wait for daylight before
we investigate
I knew he'd say that...
Hey. what'd you do that for!
I don't believe him, he threw my sandal
knowing I'd see him and try to stop him
Somebody. stop Heiji!
He's going to go into the ocean!
So what. he's just going for a swim...
But the key to the murder's in the ocean?
That kid's got guts!
The current around! herefs fast and
to dive at night is reckless,
even a professional diver
could end up losing his life
What!
17] prettyssure it was around here...
Heiji'! Don't do it!
It's dangerous!
He. Hei!
What's that?
There's something black down there...
Is. that an...anchor?
Heiji!
Hew!
There he isl
Hew...
Hey, you swim pretty fast!
The current swept me away. you fool
What? You mean you knew the
current around here was fast?
Yeah.
Remember what those guys said?
About there being a lot of brown striped
mackerel scads around here
well, they're migratory fish that swim in
waters where there's a fast current
and there were a lot of seagulls flying
around trying to get the fish
Is that why you rushed
out to look for Miss Taira?
That's right!
I figured that if she was
still diving at that time.
She might've been carried out to sea...
But you know Heir,
you try too hard to look good!
You dummy! I just wanted to solve this
case as soon 1s possible
Yeah. sure!
I'm sure Heijji wouldn't be so
sneaky and cheat by getting
as much information possible beforehand
so that he can beat Kogoro tomorrow
You know me. I wouldn't do that...
Anyway, let's take Miss Taira's body back
to the cruiser first then talk things over
Where did you say you
were taking the body?
You heard me. I said the cruiser...
Hey. what the.
The cruiser's gone!
Hey you think that captain panicked when
he heard somebody got
killed and left us here
Fool! The only ones who <<
know it was murder is us.
we're the ones who found the body!
Then maybe he's the<murderer!
After we all left to 10Ok for Miss Taira,
he took the cruiser and got ahead of us,
carried her body out to the
beach and wrote those words.
Impossible! Conan and I were
scouring the shoreline at that time
We'd have noticed if the
cruiser went past us
It doesn't matter anyway...
It seems that captain holds
the key to this crime
Well anyway
We just have to wait for
someone to come rescue us
Yes, you're right...
When the TV station realizes their staff
hasn't returned by nightfall
I'm sure they'll come looking...
Uh. .don't hold your breath...
We weren't supposed to
come here until tomorrow .
We were having such a hard time getting
the boat and setting things up so we
decided to come here today instead,
and we didn't tell the producer...
You've got to be kidding!
Are you telling me no one:knows
we're on this deserted island)
Uh: 'Yeah. I told them we'd
et everything done tomorrow
I just hope you and that captain didn't
plan this to bring the ratings up!
Of course not!
Don't worry. everything'll be fine!
I'm sure Ran's father will notice we're
not back, he'll come looking for us
Let's wait inside that house!
Boy this awamori is the best!
Yes. it is this is a well cured sake,
I ordered it special so you'd relax
and your wits would be
sharpened for tomorrow's match
I'll be counting onyyou to solve
the mystery tomorrow Detective Mot
Hyougo Kaneshiro
Mayor
I'll be counting onyyou to solve
the mystery tomorrow Detective Mot
Hyougo Kaneshiro
Mayor
LE O25 DO
w= & (63)
MDIGD
Hm) 5%
whatever the outcome...
I'll be prepared for it
I wonder what's keeping that Hattor
fellow, your daughter and the others
Oh. you don't have to worry about them
He probably doesn't want to
face me the night before the match
That seems pretty immature.
Let's forget about those kids,
I intend to drink until morning
and sharpen my wits!
Here's to my victory!
I think we're in a lot of trouble here...
I think so too .
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKQ SUUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
YIOUIry 1 uirtur ,
JUNICHI I110OKA
Scrip ls=By.
KANJI*KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARUKOUCHI.
JUNICHI MIYASFITIA
YUI(HI HI(GURE
TQSHIKI INDUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
ChicfDirector.
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By.
IMSIENTERTAINMENT, LTD.
IT ass Jciation with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
GOMOD AOYAM AY SHOGARURAN YTV TAS
All Ri. Reserved
Wow, this is interesting...
Iook at this tea cup
It looks somebody
used it as an ashtray...
The cigarette's not an expensive brand
and the water at the bottom of
the cup isn't completely dry yet
Yeah...there might have
been several of them
Several of those "guso messengers...
PRINCESS OF THE ISLAND AND THE
PALACE-OF THE-DRAGON:KING-PART Ii