Suspense and deduction
closes the gap between
the love and hatred
between two people.
Lost island and the deep sea. Conan
and Hells case going out of control!
He sees through the one and only truth
a child in appearance
with "M% I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
A television programypitting the best
detectives. from 'the-East and West bring
us, along with HeijirHattor,
here-to: Okinawan
We accompany the filming crew
to an uninhabited island
where an unidentified body
and a mysterious Message is found.
Then a female member of the
film crew. Taira Yoshie,
IS murdered and a mysterious
message is found near her body
then the boat we came
on and the captain, disappeared!
PRINCESS OF THE ISLAND AND THE
PALACE OF THE DRAGON KING PART II
What? An anchor?
On the bottom of the sea
where Miss Taira was diving?
Are you sure about that?
Yeah.
The chain was cut and it was rusty
but it was a ship's anchor all right...
Maybe it was from that man's ship
you know, the man who was
found dead here a year ago
Yes, I bet you're right!
He probably got to this island on it
and he decided to wait out the storm
in here but the chain broke
and the boat drifted away!
No. no. no!
What?
There was a lot of mollusks
and sea weed on the anchor
it must've been down there for
at least four or five years...
Four or five years...
It's been about that long. huh?
Several incidents happened at the
mayor s: house around that time
Yeah...
What do you mean? Incidents
Noburou lkema
Staff
ox 55
thd {8 RA (24)
AS v2
The first time was five years ago...
Noburou Ikema
Staff
ox 35
{QM {$58 (24)
AY yD
Noburou Ikema
Staff
HM {4 BR (24)
AY 2»
the mayor's only daughter...
Noburou lkema
Staff
OR DD
'EM WEB (24)
AY 20
the mayor's only daughter...
Miss Miyako was kidnapped...
then a year later, a gang of robbers
broke into the mayor's home,
they took a gold screen which
was a family heirloom
According to the mayor and his
butler who took the call from the robbers.
Ar ~~ ~~
the kidnappers and
the robbers were the same group
So ..what happened to them?
The mayor refused to pay the ranso
and the money for the screen
so they were never caught,
and both Miss Miyako
and the screen were never
seen again, orsso I've heard
It was a terrible blow to the mayor
Masao 1
TV Station
By &H» Te
FT LC FT
Masao 1
TV Station
reo oi: xo
SLE or
his daughter was kidnapped short!
After his wife passed away
Masao 1
TV Station
Br Eb
FUZZ ><
his daughter was kidnapped short!
After his wife passed away
and one of his maids
was killed by the robbers...
the butler was so scared. he quit,
people started to bad mouth the mayor
saying he was a heartless money monger
and on top of that, the corpse
of a man who starved to death
was found on this island the mayor owns,
along with that mysterious message
And now this...
I'm beginning to think the
Guso's'™ messenger really exists
Hey listen...
The words carved on the pillar
didn't they say
The Princess sleeps in A not B
am I right?
You're right .
Don't you think that the princess
might mean the mayor's daughter?
Are you saying she's been killed and
is buried somewhere on this island?
That's right...
she came back as a messenger from
the other world and killed Miss Taira .
If you're afraid of ghosts,
you can use that knife
Mikihiko Daitou
Staff
If you're afraid of ghosts,
you can use that knife
Mikihiko Daitou
Staff
E&Y we VT
CE 71.
AX I= \4/)
there's an Qld legend that women kept a
dagger in their mouth so that
that their souls wouldn't be sucked
ut of them through their mouth.
and. it could be used for, self protection
Hey. this is very interesting...
take a look at this tea cup!
It looks like somebody
used it as an ashtray
there are more than one
kind of cigarettes
and the water on the bottom
Isn't completely dry yet
which means that
just before we got to this island,
there was another group of people here...
That's right, and there
wasn't just one or two of them
they killed a woman and now they're
hiding somewhere on this island
I'm talking about the
messengers of death
Oh come on you're kidding. right?
Are you saying there's a
group of killers on this island?
I'm just saying that it's possible.
They could be watching us from
somewhere waiting to steal our souls...
I don't believe it...
Th, then they might
already be inside this hous™
That's not possible! We all checked
to make sure nobody was inside, right?
But there're a lot of broken
windows In this place.
It'd have been easy to sneak
in while we were busy talking
Then I think we should
split up into groups
and search the place one more time.
I agree, it won't help
to stay here and panic...
Then Mr. Kume, you and Mr. Ikema
andr. Daito check the second floor
Okay. sure...
Mr. Taketomi and we will
check the first floor
Yes, alright...
I mean, you'd be at a
disadvantage if you got attacked
since you'd be the only
male with two girls to protect...
Huh? You've got to be kidding!
You're the one that they'll be protecting
No kidding. really?
karate, eh...
Il took first place in the city competition
I hold a second rank in aikido™!
Impressive, I feel very safe...
Yes. uh, thank you...
If we come across any bad guys,
you can ave them to us!
We made the right decision
making him join us
Yeah...he looked the weakest
Okay Heiji...
h, this is the last room
Don't keep us in suspense, open it up!
Aybe it wasn't a good idea after all...
Is anybody in here?
Hey...
No. nobody...
seems to be inside...
I think you're right...
This room's not like the
others, it's really big
think the mayor's wife
used this room, see,
there's a picture of them together.
I see
it's really corroded...
Now look what you did Heiji
There's two pictures in here...
What?
What is this? There's a
picture taken with a young girl.
Do you think the mayor was
having an affair with her
No. you're wrong.
That's Miss Miyako, the
mayor's only daughter
She looked just like her
mother. they were both
fair skinned and good
natured, everyone liked her
when she was kidnapped five years
ago while still attending junior college
and then never found.
Everyone was shocked...
Didn't you say you work for a
television station in Kyushu
how do you know so much then...
Yoshiko Matsumoto the maid that
worked for the mayor is my cousin.
She used to talk about them all the time.
That maid. is she the one who
Who was killed during the robbery...
Yes, one of the robbers killed her
during the robbery four years ago...
Speaking of family, Ikema told me his
mother and the mayor's wife were sisters
so that makes him and Miyako cousins
This castle in the back
ground of the picture,
I've never seen it before,
which castle is it?
Oh that's not a castle,
that's the mayor's house...
It's a huge mansion
according to my cousin,
when the house was first built,
Miss Miyako was still little
and she was so happy!
She said she felt like 1
princess in a castle.
A princess...
In a castle!
That settles it, the princess
carved on that pillar really is...
Miss Miyako?
Speaking of strange messages,
there's some here too
What?
I think they-were written by Miyako...
What!
See, there's three...
You're right, it looks it
was written with crayons
The top one says "Chiyoni 20
centimeters below that it says "Kaachan
and on the very bottom, it says me
judging by all the lines.
Near the word me
I'd say she was comparing heights
with someone when she was little
That's a relief, you had
me scared there for awhile
I know kaachan means mother
but for a well bred young lady,
she certainly uses common language...
No. I don't think she meant mother...
What?
Take a look!
They're very faint but you
can still make out
some words on this door
written with the same crayon.
It says 'Mama's Room"
You're right!
Then who'd she mean?
Who are these people,
Kaachan and "Chiyonl
Beats me...
Maybe they were her
friends from school
I don't think so! She was
still very young when she wrote this,
her friends wouldn't be that tall!
Yes, I see your point...
Those words are written on this door too!
The room over there's
Chiyoni's room and this is Kaachan's
and that's not all. there're strange
drawing by the words too
Kaachan's drawing is a bird...
Chiyoni's drawing looks like an eel...
You know, looking at a little girl's
drawings in this dark is kind of .
Creepy. hub...
Well anyway,
seeing as how these two have
rooms here on this uninhabited island
they must've come here with her often!
When the rescue boat comes to
take us back to the main island,
I guess we'll just have to go ask the
mayor personally about these two.
They may be involved in this murder...
Wh. what was that sound...
I think It was Kume...
It came from upstairs, what happened?
It couldn't be the killers...
Rats!
Hey. what's the matter!
Did you find the killer?
No. it's not that!
That guy let out a scream and
he fell back inla panic
he saw what was behind the curtain...
this painting
Look, isn't the model in
that painting. Miyako?
You're right, it looks just
Iike the girl in the photo
It was probably done by her mother,
Yoshiko told me she was quite an artist.
Yoshiko?
Yes, she's my cousin and she worked
as a maid in the mayor's household
I see, that means that there's four people
here who are connected to the mayor
Did you say four?
Yes, my mother was
the mayor's wife's sister,
the director's cousin was the maid
Kume was Miyako's classmate in
elementary, junior high and high school
and Mr. Daito over there was a
childhood friend of the mayor's wife
Childhood friends?
Yes, when I went to visit Mrs. Kaneshiro's
grave last year with my mother,
he was there too.
My mother asked and he told her
they were childhood friends
But my mother said she didn't
remember him, so he could've been lying
I don't blame her, their ages were far
apart. that's why she didn't remember
If your mother and
Mrs. Kaneshiro were sisters,
then you must've come
to this island before too
No. I never came to this island, in fact,
I rarely went to the
mayor's house to visit.
The reason was, he was a very
wealthy man and we felt uncomfortable
I only saw Miyako a few
times when she was very young.
I wonder why Mr. Kume panicked like
that when he saw her painting though?
Beats me. maybe he thought
he was seeing her ghost?
There's been gossip
that she was killed...
W. well anyway
it doesn't look like anybody
suspicious is hiding out in this house
so let's all just stay together in,one
room and wait for the rescue boat
Don't you think it's
taking a little too long?
Yeah...
but you know old Kogoro...
you can bet he's found himself a
girl and they ve gone out drinking
the old good for nothing...
Ah... what was that?
M. maybe it's...
Yes, I knew wt!
It's the rescue boat!
We're saved!
Hey there!
Here, we're over here!
Hey!
Something's wrong with that boat!
Yeah, there're no lights on
and it's not docked right
What a horrible way to die...
the killer used something like a
hard pipe and hit him so many times
even after he died...
H. how awful
Then the Killer tied-his body to the side
of the boat and wrote those words
I Death's messenger
whoever did this really hated him...
Who would do such a thing...
So there is somebody else here...
somebody besides us is here
on the island or in the ocean
Somebody who enjoys killing
IS hiding out somewhere!
You're right, when the boat
rammed into the landing,
we were all inside the house.
Whoever piloted this boat is still
around here. I'm sure of that
Yes, that would be the so
called "Death's messenger
No. that's not necessarily true...
Co. Conan.
I just looked around inside,
there's a teeny tiny thing that looks like
a television by the steering wheel
I checked the screen and it looks
Iike this boat just went from
this landing to the ocean
and then came back again!
Oh I see, it was on auto pilot!
That way. no one has to be steering...
But kid. there're currents in the ocean,
you wouldn't be able to control how the
boat crashed into the landing by auto pilot
That's where you're wrong, it
doesn't have to be exactly right
The flow of the current would affect the
boat by about 50 to 100 meters
To have the boat come
to this side of the island.
All you'd have to do is set the
auto pilot to move along the shoreline
then the boat would move along the
reef and crash into the landing
Look at that! You can see the
side of the bottom's scraped
That proves the boat moved
along the reef scraping it!
By using the auto pilot, anyone
would've been able to commit the crime.
No matter what time the boat
was set to leave this landing!
So you see, any one of us
could have done it.
Are you trying to tell us that...
Th, that the killer is one of us?
That's right, when the four of us
Ieft the boat to look for Miss Taira
you said you all left the boat
right after us, didn't you?
Well, it would've been possible for the
man who left last to commit the crime!
So who was it?
N. not me!
It wasn't me either...
I was the last one to get off the boat.
Th. then that means you did it...
But any one of you could've come
back after I'd gone, right?
And another thing you shouldn't
forget. young detective
When that woman
Miss Taira was killed
Th, that's right,
I remember what you said!
About the words in the sand
where her body was found
you said it'd be impossible for us
to do it since we were on the
opposite side of the island...
Yeah, you definitely said that since the
words were written where the last wave
of the high tide receded, they must've
been written shortly before we found her
when the tide was low, otherwise,
they would've been washed away!
B. besides, the words on both
scenes were the exact same,
so they were written
by the same person, right?
Then the killer couldn't
possibly be one of us...
If there was more than one Killer
they might have talked it over and
decided to do it the same way
it may have been part of their plan...
to make us suspect
each other of the crime .
Well the boat's back now anyway...
That's right
you think it'd be better if we discussed
this after we get back to the main island?
Thing is, while we were
taking the captain down,
I looked around the boat and saw
that the fuel tank's pretty much empty
And that's not all.
The radio's been broken and all
our things are gone which means
the killer wants to keep us on this
island and is planning to do something
What do you mean...
You mean another murder?
Yes, if you don't want to get killed,
we better all go back to the house
and wait for the rescue boat to arrive,
that's the only thing we can do
Good grief, how long do we have to
wait for that rescue boat?
Who knows...
Alright Heiji...
We'll see you back there later...
Alright
Be careful!
Don't worry.
Listen Kudo, something
about this isn't right...
I Know...
With the first victim Miss Taira,
the killer took the time to fold her arms
neatly over her chest and close her eyes
but the second victim, the
captain, was beaten to death
Their killers might've
been different but still,
the methods are drastically different...
Another thing bothers me
the way Miss Taira and the captain
behaved before they were killed
Yeah, she deliberately chose to dive
where the current was fast,
knowing how dangerous it was
and the captain circled around
the island until the very last minute
And there was seabed exploratory
equipment on board too...
he must've been searching for something
and it was probably attached
to that anchor I found
but what was it...
But besides that Kudo.
Remember the words written on the back
of the chairs in the room we were all in
Uh huh...the ones
written by a child in crayon?
The one I was sitting on, had "Me"
written on it. and Ram's had "Mama"
But. on the back of the
one I was sitting on was
Mr. Kaneshiro...
The little girl wrote it didn't she?
Then Mr. Kaneshiro would be
her father then, wouldn't he
I wonder why she didn't write Papa?
And those were the only
chairs with names on them
Another thing bothers me, there
weren't any chairs for
Kaachan and Chiyoni
who she compared heights with...
I know, { seems strange that they'd
have their own rooms but no chairs
Kaachan and Chiyoni
I wonder who they are!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MIGHIHIKQ SUWA
Ny» -
Background Music
KAT 'UO -ONO
Character Desions By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
.B RA
KAZUNARI.KOUGHI
JUNICHI MIYASH IA
YUIGHI HIGURE
HIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
AZUNARI KOUCH
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
CHI HIG
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief:Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
TMSENTERTAINMENT. LTD
1 association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
LOH AOYAMA SHOGAKUKAN- YTV: EMS
All Ri +h Feserved
Here it is, found it
Crackers and cookies!
What was that sound?
I don't know, It
sounded like water dripping
Oh no!
It's coming this way!
You don't think it's
Death's messenger?