Suspense and deduction closes the gap
between the love and hatred
between two people
A surprising island secret
The battle of deduction ends in a twist
He sees through the one and only truth
a child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
A television program pitting ithe best
detectives from the
East and Westibring:us
along with Heiji Hattor:,
here to Okinawan
We accompany the filming crew to
an uninhabited island
where an unidentified body and
a mysterious message found,
the) a famaliO member of the film crew.
Le Taira. is murdered and
a mysterious message Is
found near her body
I'm the Gusds messenger
a mysterious message Is
found near her body
then the boat we came on
and the captain disappears!
Having no other choice,
we wait for someone to come rescue us
at the village head's villa
that is on the island...
What was that sound of the?
M.Maybe it's
M.Maybe it's...
Wow, it's the rescue ship after all!
Saved!
Something's wrong with that ship!
Yeah, there are no lights on either...
And the way the ship is a
nchored is messed up...
I'm the Guso's messenger
PRINCESS OF THE ISLAND AND THE
OF OF THE DRAGON KING PART IN
Hey. hey. it's already 5 in the morning
No wonder I'm starved
I haven't eaten a thing for half a day
Yeah. I'm thirsty too
Shall we go get something
for you from the kitchen?
There may be non-perishable food
or canned juice
I guess so.
Are they going to be okay,
just those two girls?
They'll be fine
I hear they re pretty strong. those two
there we go!
Rice crackers and fried dough cookies!
But won't eating things like that
make you even more thirsty?
But, it's better than
not having anything to eat, isn't it?
What was that sound.
I wonder .
It sounded like water dripping though
Oh no!
It's coming this way!
D.Don't tell me that .
It. It's the Guso's messenger
What're you two doing?
What're you two holding knives
with your mouth like that?
H.Hew.
We thought you were the Guso's messenger
You know, the one that
Mr. Daito was telling US about?
If you don't want it to suck your soul out
hold a knife in your mouth
But. what's with you Heiji?
How come you're all wet?
Oh, you mean this?
Heiji dove into the ocean after that,
Because he thought that if the killer
threw our things away at the wharf,
his bag with his cell phone
inside it would be stuck
on some coral around the area!
And. did you find your bag?
It seems to have drifted
into the lake...
Kachan" it says...
Kachan
What?
On the chair over here
the word "choinii is written!
Hey, maybe kachan refers to
the maid, Kako Matsumoto?
I see.
KA" is taken from her first name
If she's a maid, it's only natural that she'd
spend most of her time in the kitchen
Then, what about this choinii?
Huh, there's a faded writing over here.
It seems "Choinii was written
over what was originally written here.
It's faded and hard to read.
But I think it's weatherfish
Which mean that
the picture that was drawn
on the door below
chiyonii was weatherfish.
But, Chiyonii and weatherfish
have no connection whatsoever!
If the drawingOunder the word "kachan
IS a Crow means karasu in Japanese,
then they are more or less connected
Because when they crow it sounds like
they're saying "ka-ka."
Karasu...
But, Maybe that picture is
ust something that the girldrew By
Iooking at the picture on
the folding screen
Then, that's a white heron?
White heron?
The directo was saying a while ago
that a white heron was drawnscreen
that was stolen from the mayor
4 years ago.
It seems to be of'Nationa) Treasure
class and is said to be worth 2 billion
Bird... white hero..weatherfish...
With all these clues
out in the open, no King.
¢ Tiger symboli-res Osaka...
Eagle. FM "fika.
And Carp Hir shi 7a .
Sea bream and flatfish would be
the Dragon King's Castle
The Dragon King's Castle?
That's it!
I think something's strange
about Conan after all.
Are you sure he's not
Iying about his age?
I don't think he Is...
Kazuha. what did you just say?
Huh?
I asked you what did you just say?
M.Maybe...he's...lying?
H.Heiji?
Conan?
The time now is 10 to 6 I the morning.
More than 12 hours have past
since Ms Taira's bee found!
If our deduction is correct,
it should still be here"
Yeah...it should still be there!
It. it's nowhere.
I wonder of the killer got rid of it after all!
No. we overlooked it...
'hese little footprints of mine
Then, that's a trick after all.
Yeah... we were completely deceived.
But, what re we going to do?
We figured out the killer
but have no evidence.
Iff we got nothing.
We just gotta: come up with something
By luring him out to this forest
that the princess lies asleep In.
Yeah...although that princess
may already be crying.
"Heap!
Conan!
Really, where are they anyway?
The nerve making us worry like this!
Oh well. all's well since we found out
F.Found out what...
Don't tell me...
Right...the trick that the killer used
As well as the fact that the
killer stayed near us all this time
but was playing against us!
What?
You mean the killer is among Us?
Who is it?
Tell us who, quick!
Not just yet
We'll decide who it is after listening to
what everybody has to say...
First of all, Mr. Kume...
Let's start from you.
It's going to be really short,
so bear with me a while, okay
Will the rest of you who are
waiting decide the order in which
you want to be asked...
Hey. what's taking them so long?
They've already been in there
for about 30 minutes
I'm sure they)" becoming out soon
After all, he did say
It was going to be really simple.
Hey. hold it
Hew?
Hey. what's up?
Nothing's up! He ran away!
R,Ran away...
which means he's the killer, after all
It's because you made that
sarcastic remark, Heiji
You didn't have to say,
If I have to wait for you to talk
I'll turn into Taro Urashima.
I didn't have a choice,
I since he refused to talk
no matter what I asked him did .
Let's split up and fine Mr. Kume
If he commited suicide going into
the ocean, it wouldn't be right.
Hey, Kume!
Where are you!
Mr. Kume!
Hey!
What the?
What're you surprised for...
You're the one who told us
that if we don't want our souls
to be taken by the guso
we should hold
knives in our mouths, right
Mr. Daito?
Mr. Kume,
the man you're after is still in the house.
He's fast asleep. though.
I borrowed his clothes to catch you
To get you who killed Ms. Taira and
the Captain.as well as wait for Mr. Kume,
who you thought was coming!
The three were the thieves
who not only kidnapped Miyako,
but also stole the folding screen,
and on top of that killed the maid. right?
Hey. hey,
just what do you think you're saying
I was looking for Kume when I
saw a suspicious silhouetted figure
so I tried to catch him, that's all
Besides, I couldn't have killed
Ms. Taira, right?
The writing on the sand that
was near that lady was written right
after the waves pulled away.
And you said it would've been
IMpPOsSsSI O or me,
who was in the ship
on the other side of the island to write.
That's true.
Even if something is written
on the sand before the tide pulls back,
it'll be washed away by the waves.
Ere ore. 1 ( >e mpossi re o
Ieave the writing on the sand.
If it was really the waves that
was pulling back then.
Don't Joke around.
You saw it too, didn't you?
The sand was wet up to about
a meter above the lady's head.
If the water was
up there during high tide,
no matter how you think of it,
the tide was receding, wasn't it?
That's we calculated wrong
and were deceived.
The waves actually don't come up that far,
but because the sand was wet,
we mistakenly thought that during high
tide the waves came all the way up there
Right
the time we found Ms. Taira
was actually high tide.
If so. then it all fits just right. doesn't it?
If the tide is high all you have to do is
write where the waves won't wash it away
then lie Ms. Taira
right next to the writing
Okay. then why don't we go look for
the writing right now!
Half a day has already past since then.
If it was written where the waves
wouldn't wash it away,
the writing would still
be there, wouldn't it?
No. it was no longer there.
You probably erased it the minute
we left the site, anyway
Hey. hey.
But. my footprints were still there!
Huh?
When Heiji took the picture of
my sandals and the writing.
I was standing right next to him.
But. my footprints were still there.
Yeah, but kiddo,
the sand was wet all over...
I couldn't have wet the sand that way
even if I used a bucket.
You didn't use a bucket.
You used the cruiser we came here on!
The waves that the cruiser created
we he shore more an curing ug. ice
All you did was use it to your advantage
You knew that the captain was going to
go around the entire island
Iooking for the stuff
In question until it's time to leave
A. And just what is that stuff I
n question supposed to be...
What else?
The anchor that I found...
He was looking for the princess
that was supposed to
be tied onto the anchor.
Princess"?
It was on the writing on the pillar,
wasn't it?
The princess lies in A and not in B
It's hard to understand what
this means.just as it is.
But if you put together the folk tale
of Taro Urashima and the fact that
that this island is called Onikame Island,
then the puzzle fits...
The shell of the turtle.
Princess Oto who lives in
the Dragon King's Palace.
In other words, the Princess I's not
in the sea, but on the shell of the turtle."
That is, "it is in the forest on this island
Princess is a code name that
the thieves called
the thing that was sunk in the ocean,
but was washed up on this island
during the typhoon that struck a year ago.
This golden folding screen!
After they stole it, the thieves were at
a loss where to hide the folding screen,
so they put it in this air-tight case,
tied it onto the boat,
sunk it deep into this part of the ocean
that nobody dives into
with an anchor and
decided to wait till things cooled off.
But, then a big typhoon hit a year ago.
And the boat was washed up to shore.
Although it was okay that
one of the members
came to see how things were,
but when the next typhoon hit,
he boat that the thief
came on was washed away,
Ieaving him behind on this island.
That's why he left the writings to indicate
the whereabouts of the folding screen
for his fellow thieves
And, since you figured out
the meaning of the writing.
You decided to take revenge on the thieves
after hearing about the TV program
Renown Detectives of the East
VS. Renown Detectives of the West"
Since the thieves didn't know
where the folding screen was yet,
you figured that there would be
a high possibility that
the members of the thieves
would come mixed up as the filming crew.
B.But, how would I be able to
tell the thieves from the filming crew?
Taro Urashima
See. like you were saying!
You feel like you turned
into Taro Urashima
You knew that the members
of the band of thieves
ho sunk the folding screen into the ocean,
would immediately figure out
the meaning of the writings
That's why you killed Ms. Taira who
came to look for it in the forest, right?
In the way that
you tried to kill me a while ago
It sure is an interesting deduction,
but, if that's the case, anybody
could've committed the murder, right?
No, you're the one who
committed the crime.
Unlike the captain
who was killed violently,
Ms. Taira was treated
as a corpse should be treated
That's evidence that the killer knew that.
The true identity of Ms. Taira was
actually the daughter of the Mayor,
Miyako who was
kidnapped 5 years ago!
In other words, that
kidnapping incident was made up
and Miyako herself was also a
member of the band of thieves!
I realized that I figured out
the meaning of folding screen
why the thieves called the,
Hime "means Princess, and the meaning
of "choinii andkachan that were written
by Miyako when she was
Iittle and living in that house
Folding screen was
called Hime because
- the name was taken
from the Shirasagi Castle
Kachan", is the Karasu Castle,
formally known as Miyamoto Castle!
In other words, it stands for
Ms. Kako Miyamoto the maid!
Chonii came from the Chiyoda Castle,
which is also known as the Edo Castle
The Edo Castle is a large
castle that is located in the East
Isn't that right? You who served as
butler at the Mayor's house,
Mr. Daito?
Although it seems that Miyako
used to call you Dojo-san
with the "e omitted in the
beginning though
I found out that you were the butler, when
you didn't sit but stood by the doorway.
You have a room but your
chair is only in the kitchen...
The time when you suddenly opened the
dish cabinet when looking for the ashtray
It was as If you knew there was no
ashtray in this house to begin with!
You're the one who prepared that
tea cup with the cigarette butts inside it
beforehand too, to make it look like
the doings of multiple criminals, right?
You probably thought you'd
get away for now somehow,
and was thinking of killing Mr. Kume
who you goofed trying to kill
Iater, too bad you can't
Because the rope you're
holding now and the rope marks
around Miyako's neck are
going to match completely
But, there's still one thing I
can't figure out
I can understand that you found out
about Mr. Kume after he got flustered
when he saw the picture of
Miyako who he thought had died, but
How'd you figure that the
captain was also one of them?
If you didn't predict that the captain
would make his rounds around this island
this trick wouldn't have worked out...
How could I ever forget...
He was the only one that I witnessed
four years back at the time of the incident
The very one who killed the one who was
to be my wife my cherished loved one
He is the hateful killer who killed her...
Which means that the maid,
Ms. Matsumoto was...
Yes, I was engaged to her, I asked the
master for a leave to avenge her death.
I changed my outer appearance
as well as my way of speech
speech in order to pursue the thieves.
But, I was shocked when I found out
that Miyako was one of them...
Which means you didn't know?
No. because she looked so different...
Until she mumbled those few words...
I'm sorry, Chiyonii...
I felt like I understood for the first time
just before her death, how she really felt
That kidnapping incident was
made up because after her mother died,
she wanted to test her
step-father's love for her.
But, when Kaneshiro rejected
to pay the ransom,
She decided to steal what Kaneshiro
cherished, and it was the folding screen
Miyako was actually Kaneshiro's wife's
child from another marriage after all
Yes. now that I think back.
It could be that Mr. Kaneshiro
knew that Miyako
was somehow involved in the incident...
Because when he gave me time off,
this is what he said
All this happened
probably because of me...
So. hate me and forget about
pursuing the incident, will you...
I think that this incident was
just as the master said...
a box that shouldn't
have been opened
As if to speak on his behalf,
the golden folding screen was
watching sadly over him...
Because the folding screen
was suddenly exposed to air
after being sealed for so long
and oxidized, the paint began
to run and fade.
Resembling tears falling
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO_S LU/WA
MA AHITQO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUQO ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 110OKA
Scripts By.
KANJFKASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI.KOUCHI
JUWNICHI MIYASH INA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
[Jill
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHIS5A OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chict Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
roduced ?
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
In associa ton wath
YO! 1RI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
CLONED AY MAP SHOGARUKAN-YIV TALS
All RE hi Reverved
What!
The case ha Ween solved?
Are you fiious. hey?
Yeah, while you were drinking
nd fell asleep feeling good
T,Then what about my TV
appearance? My pay?
How should I know. darn dude?
Then you make something happen!
Eat and run or anything
you like. Go on, do it!
Hey, hey...
Oh, that's for me!
Oops. Detective Mourn is
stretching over for his 12th bowl!
Renown Detectives
Big Eater Contest
Is this what you guys
came to @kihawa to do?
W. Well, sort of...
Give me a break...
My God, I've got to hurry
and inform somebody .
Cell phone, cell phone,
where's my cell phone
Ran disappeared?
Hey. answer me, Ran! Ran!
The line's cut .
(RY)
Smash of Lover:and'Resolve
Pa rt 'i