Suspense and deduction
closes the gap between
the love and hatred
between two people
The truth in this difficult case
becomes clear.
Kisaki and Kujo clash in court!
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child I appearance with the IQ.
Of an adult,
noycase is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Hmm. the hot springs eh...
haven't been to one for so long...
and the autumn. colors must be
Iovely this time of year.
Yes, that's right!
"Think this open air bath would be great!
They say the water here's
good for the complexion!
AMom, you need to take off
from work once in a while and relax...
You<remright...
Midori
How's my schedule for next month?
The conclusion of the trial you're
working on now is slated for next week,
SOIT
so all you have to do is decide
whether you want to take this "duty case
Oh, that's right,
I'd forgotten about that
Can you get me the files on that
Okay
What's a duty case?
When a person is financially or
otherwise unable to hire a lawyer,
the court appoints one,
but if no one will take the case.
Then the bar association decides on
a 'duty public defender
and that lawyer takes the case
I see.
Here it is.
Thank, you
I've just taken a fast look but,
I don't understand why
no one would take this case.
I think this case is defendable...
I guess it's because of the prosecutor
Who would that be?
Ms. Kujo's the prosecutor on this case
I see, so it's the prosecution
office's Madonna...
(B1%R)
COURT BATTLE ll-KISAKI V/S KUJO
What are, ou doing to do?
Shall I tell them you're busy
and Win them down?
11143.
Excuse me ma:am
What is the case about?
Cages:
It happened about a month ago in Haido
Office in a building was broken into and
1e company presicen was ound ceac.
From the fingerprints and evidence:.
Found in the room,
the defendant. a confirmed criminaltwith
a record became the suspect?
It sounds like an open and shut case...
Yes it does...
the defendant has confessed that
he broke in thinking the office was empty
(-71)
but when the victim found him and
they struggled.he hit him...
The problem is the charge
on the indictment
What's the charge?
He's being indicted for burglary/murder
Murder!?
But-this case soundssmore like
accidental death, doesn't it?
Yes...
I don't think Prosecutor Kujo would make
a mistake as big as this...
Midon,
I have the prosecutor's
report and. the deposition
but the. crime scene
investigation report isn't here,
could you have them send it up?
And I'll needfthe coroner's report too
Okay
Mom...
Sorry Ran, as you can see,
I won't be able to go to the hot springs
with you, maybe another time
Good grief...
The new Tokyo Prison
ERIN I
SRI IE Ir
Let me ask you one more time,
on the night of the crime,
you entered the Otsu Realty Office o
the second floor of the Nomoto Build
the second floor of the Nomoto Build:
(66)
by breaking the window
(55)
you searched the office and
then tried to open the safe
in the president's office,
the president, Mr. Otsu
unexpectedly returned to the office
he saw you
and you two fought.
You then hit the victim on the head
Causing his death...
(DIS that correct?
Yeah
What happened to the money
that was in the safe?
But according to
the employees' statements,
they had just closed a deal and
there was 12 million yen in the safe
but it disappeared.
The prosecutor is saying that
you took the money after killing Mr.Otsu
It wasn't me! I'm telling you the truth!
It's true. no money was found
in your apartment but,
your fingerprints were on the safe so
I don't blame the prosecution
for suspecting you, don't you agree?
I didn't take~the money. CD
honest and about that creep...
That creep?
¢ Did you know the victim?
How many times did you hit
the victim on the head?
I don't remember...
Once, twice?
I don't remember.
He surprised me when he walked in,
my mind went blank...
The coroner's report says the victim
received three blows to the head...
The third blow was the one that killed him
Striking him-once, is understandable
at sine ttr'ére was a second
- - ll
and then a third,
could show intent to commit murder.
I honest don't rememberO
I-see. O Well, I'm on your side
so I want you to tell me the truth, even
if it's-detrimental to your case, alright?
I just want to make absolutely sure,
are you positive you-had
no intention of killing the victim
I'm positive
Alright.
We'll argue our case on that point
alone in court.
Thank you.
Tokyo Courthouse
E545 8 BS ou EA La
R53 PAR
The defendant Takashi Inoue,
Tokyo Courthouse
5 Cad 8B BOD TWLwWEA La
Est SERRE HR
at approximately 20.30
on the evening of the incident
Tokyo Courthouse
&BEad 8 BOOLEAN La
ERIS ERHIPH
at approximately 20:30
on the evening of the incident
Trial of Takashi Inoue
at approximately 20:30
on the evening of the incident
Trial_-of Takashi_lnoue
DER HHEK IRATE
8B [EH
broke the window to
the Otsu Realty Office
Trial of Takashi Inoue
THER RAZINARGE
Beet » I
SI TN
on the second floor of the Nomoto Bull g
Iocated at 3-2-9, Haido Street.
While he was ransacking the president,
Mr. Toshiyuki Otsu's office,
the victim, Mr. Otsu returned and saw him.
The:defendantithen-used+the weapon
he had te threaten the Victim
and forced the victim
to open the safe in the office.
The defendant then struck the victim
three times on the back of the head
causing the victim's death...
Defendant then escaped with the 12
million yen in cash which was in the safe
According/to penal code 240,
the prosecution asks
the defendant be sentenced-to
Iife imprisonment for burglary/murder.
Does the defendant have anything to say
regarding the charges
the prosecution has just stated?
Do you wish to deny the charges?
1. 1 just broke in to rob the place,
I didn't mean to kill anybody.
Your honor!
The defense may speak
The indictment states my client
is guilty of burglary/murder
but my client would like to plead not
guilty to the charge of murder.
So you're pleading not guilty to
burglary/murder, is that correct?
@€orrect.
The defense asks the defendant be charged
under penal code 205, accidental death
The defense is challenging
the prosecution's indictment,
do you have anything to say?
Yes. I do.
Could the defendant tell me why
he chose to break into the victim's office?
Well,
I was looking for some place to break into
and it just caught my eye, that's all...
Then you are claiming
it was mere coincidence
that you broke:into- the: victim:s office
and tha™ ou heldino:grudge:toward
Mr. Toshiyuki'Otsu; iisithaticorrect?
Right.
I wonder what she's trying to get at...
Your honor.
The prosecution's line of
questioning is unclear!
Alright.then...
does the defendantaknowe-woman
named. Noriko Endo?
Well?
Don't tell me you've forgotten
your only daughter's name?
<< <<
Only:daughter?
Here it is!
When he divorcedshis-wife 20 years ago.
His daughter was 8 years old
I wonder what that has to do
with case though...
Aren't you going to answer me?
Objection!
The prosecution is merely trying to
confuse the defendant
by mentioning a family member's name!
Does this daughter have anything
to do with the case? ,
Yes.
NorikolEndo runs a pub:in another building
the victim's company, manages
There are rumors that she and the victim,
were involved ina personal relationship
.00'-
So you are claiming the defendant
had a premeditated motive
for breaking into the victim's office,
is that correct?
we have proof that the defendant held a
grudge against the
victim over his daughter
You're wrong!
I don't even know the creep!
Would you like to ask her'yourself thenr'?
She's in the gallery, we can have her
take the witness stand if you'd like
Noriko Endo
aNoriko Endo
MR BR #27 (28)
FF. FEE OM
Dad...
aNoriko Endo
3 O CT
BB #c 1 (28)
+L BED
Noriko
80 that's the ace
the Madonna had up her sleeve
We are prepared to call Ms. Endo
to the witness stand if necessary,
7 So what the prosecutor said was true?
Yes, that man tricked me.
He told me he'd let me have
my own business, then he used,me...
When did you start communicating
with your father?
We met"2 years age
when mother died after an illness.
He'd drop in to my pub
every now and then to see me.
Seagoan!
And you told him; about Mr. Otsu?
And you told him about Mr. Otsu?
He said he'd get him to pay me
consolation money.
This case isn't looking too good...
What do you mean?
Well. if you hada motive
and Struck the victim 3 times
no one would believe
you didn't mean to kill him.
I see...
One last question and I'd like you to
give me an honest answer...
Po you think your father killed
Toshiyuki Otsu?
No! He maybe a good for nothing thief
but"he's not capable of murder)!
I see
She's going to have it hard this time...
Oh good grief, dad
sleeping again!
I always close my
eyes when I'm thinking!
Who.says "was sleeping!
I see. so you must've thought of
something that would help mom then!
Well. uh, you see
It-s;her-fault for taking .a
case like this in the firstiplace!
The defendant had a
motive for committing murder,
and what's more, he went and left
his fingerprints all over the safe's dial
How in the world can she
think she can get him off!
I wonder why his fingerprints were
only on the safes dial though
Eas . he srobabl
wore gloves when he broke In.
But he couldn't turn the dial with
them on so he took them off!
That's when the victim
came in and wham,
he hit him over the
head with the ashtray
If that's how it went
then there. should've been
fingerprints on the ashtray
I guess, since he took his gloves off
But they didn't find any.
Well, he probably wiped
them off, that's why!
Give those to me!
Read this part carefully!
It says that there were traces that
it dabeen-wiped with
a cloth containing oil. see!
Then why didn't he wipe the
safe at the same time too?
Welleethatlfibecause
he'd just killed someone.
He panickedsand forgot,
he just ran out of there
Oh, okayeso when'd he take
the money from the safe?
Well, after he=killed-the victim, he
opened the safe-one more time
But you just said he
panicked and ran out of there!
Well, uh...
It ixudoesn't make any sense...
You're a:fool!
Criminals aren't logical, that's why!
What's that supposed to mean?
You're just making excuses!
Shut up!
I oli) doe ewan [osingoe
Wait a minute dad,
where're you.going?
Play pachinko- lg
Good grief:
R1513?
HS ASK
AHFXARL
SILT KK
RIA 5
715283021111
AHFXRARL
SILT FF
RIB RE
Oh SANK
AhFxRARL
It NW
Ri% RE
OHS RBA
AX WAL
HF) WM
RIF RAH
OP SS XBAI
AhxrARL
TILT
R158 EH
ho AEA
*hxAnL
:1»71< 1»
fiigalfi
oh SAND
A HZ Al
2111,71 1»
Ri% RE
OHS ANAM
AX HW <All
TILT FT
OHS ARAKI
Well, well, well.
Oh, it's you.
What-are you deing here?
He wanted to see if there was
anything he could help you with
so he came to check the
scene of the crime
Shut up you little brat!
For a famous private detective you
sure have a lot of free time. don't you
What'd you say!
Did you come to check
the scene too?
That's right, I just went
to see the superintendent
Takuya Akiyam
Superintenden
Supeirintenden
ALL $63 (56)
Sorry:tokeep:you-waiting.
Follow -me:"it's thiSiway
Takuya Akiyam
Supeirintenden
BALL $518 (56)
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Follow me: it's this. way
Takuya Akiyam
Superintenden
Were you the first
one to discover the body?
That's right, Kid
Could you tell me aboutiit in detail?
At about 9 that night, I was watching
the baseball game on TV
Why Mr Arima
Did you see the boss?
No, nobody was in the office
when I made my rounds at 8.00
That's strange, when he left
my place a little while ago.
He said he was coming back here...
Then he must've come in
through the emergency it
But his office door's locked
and I called but there was no answer
Maybe he's in back, in his office
He forgot his glasses,
I came to give them to him
I hate 10 ask but can you come
with me and open the door?
Okay.
That Mr. Arima is Mr: Otsu's
son-in-law, isn't he?
Yes: he runs an Italian
restaurant in the neighborhood
And this door was locked. you say?
Yes...
I used this spare key to get in
It doesn't look like he's here after all
Father, are you in there?
It's me. Masahiko.
That's strange .
What's this?
There's somebody inside
What!
This is bad!
What is it?
S. somebody's
getting beaten up in there!
What!
The key! Open this door!
Only Mr Otsu has
the key to this office!
Dang!
Get out of the way!
Father!
Father, can you hear me!
Mr. Akiyama, call an ambulance!
Oh. right!
Is? that the. office where it happened.
Yes.
Hey. this door's locked
Mr. Arima has the key to that room
oh, there he is!
Mr. Arima, this is Ms Kisaki, the
Iawyer I told you about on the telephone
And I'm Kogoro Mourn.
Private investigator
You're that famous detective!
Pry.
BE 2 J
Italian-Re
Yes, I suppose so
pony
alian-Re
Yes, I suppose so
Mr-Arima, I'm sorry we had to
botheriyou at work.
We:d like to take a look around
your father-in law's office
Isn't anybody using this office?
No. the police said we could but since
father was killed in here so tragically,
I haven't decided what to do with it yet.
Go ahead. I've left it
exactly as the police left it
Thank you
By the way, Mr. Arima, where
was the victim's body lying?
Let's see; right about
here in front of the safe,
he was lying clutching his head
I see...
I've got it!
What do you mean?
I'll bet Mr. Otsu caught Inoue
trying to open the safe.
The defendant confessed to
that in the very beginning
I'm not finished
Inoue was hiding a
knife or something. he threatened the
victim and forced him to open the safe.
When the safe was opened, he hit
the victim with the ashtray from behind
You're net implying the
defendant was lying".'»"are».you?
Well, I guess you-could:say I am
How can you expect to defend
a chient if you don't believe him!
You'd better open your eyes of that
Madonna's going to fry you in court!
What's that?
Wait a minute, it couldn't be...
Hey, is that the window you
saw the Killer through, sir?
That's right
Okay...
Hey Conan=whatsre you-up to?
Uncle Kogoro::could you stand in
front of the safe one more time for me?
Oh good grief,
now what.
Here)?
Hold it right there!
I knew it!
don't get it...
The partition Is blocking the way,
I can't see you from here!
Whatdmn ou*say!
Mr. Akiyama,
what is the meaning of this?
Well, uh,
I wasn't looking over there
I was only:looking at the person's
shadow reflected on this wall over here
Didgyou say the
reflection on the wall...
Yes...
there weren't any lights
on in the room that-night
and the neon lights from
outside the window came In
that's how I saw the killer's shadow...
He hit Mr. Otsu over
and over again
Besides, I heard Mr Otsu fall after
that, I'm positive about that!
Let me clarify one point,
you didn't actually see the defendant
Sr e evicim, cic you.
But Ms. Kisaki...
I don't see how much
difference it makes
The defendant himself has confessed
hitting my father-in-law, isn't that right?
That's where you're wrong Mr Arima
There's a big difference in
actually seeing the beating
and seeing the shadow of
someone being beaten!
Besides...
until the defendant is found guilty
in court, he is presumed innocent!
Unfortunately, most
people forget that fact
Well excuse me.
Excuse me, sir
What is it?
This clock isn't working.
I know, the late president won
that in a golf tournament
he just left it there for
decoration, he never used it
Oh...
Mr. Arima, I need to ask you
Yes,
what is it?
Was there anyone besides the victim
who knew the combination to the safe?
No. he was the only one.
He was a man one operation,
he didn't even tell the accountant
Ouch!
Watch out,
stop wandering around!
Ouch!
And what's this?
That's it, I'vergot it now! I've solved
the mystery behind this case
The silhouette of something
being hit that Mr Akiyama said he saw
and the sound of something falling,
everything can be this
trick will explain everything
and the only one who
could've have set it up-is
that person!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO_SUWA
Background Music.
KAT UO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor
JUNICHI I110OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
CHI HIG
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MA ATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief rector.
KEN]! KOUAMA
Produced By
TMSSENTERTAINMEN( . LTD
nr association with
YOMIURI:TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
CGONMTO AOYAMA SHOGARURAN YTV EMN
All RiT1Hhi™R¢scrved
This restaurant l6oks fancy but
the pasta's not very good
You're right, the olive oil's
a little heavy
What is this!
I set things up just like
Mr. Mourn told me to
Set things up? Areasyou saying
you know who the murderer is
Yes, Mr. Mouritsaid he'd
explain everything in court
COURT BATTLE IFKISAKI VS KUJO
PART II