Suspense and deduction
closes the gap between
the love and hatred
between two people.
What will happen to pops testimony!
Prosecuter, Lawyer,
and Conans solution!
He sees through the
one and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the 1. Q of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Ms. Kisaki and Ms Kujo
the "Madonna" of the prosecutor's
office are to battle it out in court again.
The defendant is accused to breaking
into an office and when he is discovered,
he and the victim fight,
and during the struggle,
he accidentally kills the victim...
But'Prosecutor Kujo claims
that he did intend toukill.the victim
and: heliis charged with
burglary andimurder!
And he is charged with
burglary and murder!
Old man Kogoro and
I start to investigate
investigate and we discover
something at the crime scene
It's can't be!
I knew it!
I don't understand.
I can't see you from here, the
partition's blocking my View!
Whatydide oursay?
Mr Akiyama, what
is the meaning of this?
Ouch!
Watch it,
stop wandering around!
Ouch...
What's this?
I've got it!
I can explain.everything now
COURT BATTLE ll KISAKI VS KUJO
PART II
(TR)
COURT BATTLE ll KISAKI VS KUJO
PART II
Thank-you for your help ¢
No problem, was I
of any help to your case?
Makihiko Arima
Italian Restaurant Owner
No problem, was I
of any help to your case?
Makihiko Arima
Italian Restaurant Owner
HM HE (35)
49 JP IVANDY RM
Well, the police and. the
prosecutor's office already.
Went through the place thoroughly
I didn't expect to find anything I
to-overturn the case
I see...
I Know.
Why don't you come to my restaurant
from now and have something to eat?
I'll bring out a speial wine.
No. that'd be too much
He was nice enough to offer!
It wouldn't hurt to drop by!
K. Kogoro...
Have.you forgotten-Ran"s
waiting:for you at home!
Your daughter?)
Yes...
Why don't you ask her to come too?
Gee, that's nice of you
The more the merrier when it
comes to dining, I always:;say
Thank you, we acceptythen
This is a very good wine...
nag! 8 you like it
I likes\the atmOsphere
of yourn.,restaurant
Thank you very much.
I'll be testifying at the next trial,
please go easy on me
You found your father-inzlaw's. body,!
When you went te return something ow
he'd forgotten, didn't you?
Yes. He had dinner
here and left without his glasses»
His glasses ua.
Yes, his reading glasses
Take your time and
enjoy your meal
this restaurantdooks fancy but
the pasta isnst very good, is it
I agree, I think the
olive oil is a bit;heavy
By the way, how
are things for the next trial going?
Not too good...
You'll lose unless
you change your approach
And. what do you mean by that?
You won't get him off
on thesburglary and murder charge.
So you've got to stress the
fact that he did it out of love
for his daughter and that
the victim was also at fault.
Are you saying I should accept
the prosecution's charges
and ask for leniency due to
extenuating circumstances?
What choice do you have...
Don't be ridiculous!
@ defendant insists
he had no intention of Killing him!
You believe everything
your client tells you,
that's why Madonna
always gets you in court
Don:tsyoutell me how to do my job!
I'm not helping you because
I want to you know!
Oh come on you two. that's enough!
Why do you always fightlliKe. this
I'm sure that on~the list of
things found on the crime scene
Fm sure it wasin here.somewhere...
Here it is!
I've found it. the undeniable proof!
Conan?
What is it?
Why are you looking through the files?
Well, something
in here was bothering me
What do you mean?
Il QUE, 83m Wis it a3'? iiiiifimgva
found on the crime scene
LOR, S00 Wdke I TET ARCS
A Cc:
oA ul
Hey you!
You keep messing around
with important documents!
Good grief!
Well if you're going to be like that
why don't you think of
something that'll help mom!
She's so stubborn. I hope
Madonna creams her in court
Just listen to you!
I'll bet you just don't have the
confidence to beat Ms Kujo
You've got some nerve!
She's no match for me
Then why don't you defend him?
He can;t. Dad doesn't
have a license to practicellaw.
Why can'the be a
special counsel then?
What's that?
If someone with a
Iicense to practice law or
if the defendant makes a request, the
person they indicate can act as lawyer
Show the court how brilliant
your deductive powers are
My: brilliant: deductive powers?
Any crime can be solved by me.
Well, if you insist!
But let me think about it
Him, special counsel?
Yes!
He wants to help you so much, mom
Thanks but no thanks.
Dad really wants to help!
So you say but I just don't
think he has the ability
But .
I have a message"from Uncle
Kogoro, he Wants you
and the building superintendent to
come to the crime scene tonight
To the crime scene?
He said you'll see something that will
change the way things are going in court
Change the way things are going?
B2B»
I'm sorry to have to
put you through this again
I don't mind but what I
do you want me to do?
I'm not too clear on that myself
Mr. Akiyama, will you do exactly
what you did that night?
Hey Conan, where is Kogoro?
Oh, uh, he stepped
outside to get things ready
Outside?
Alright, I 'understand.
Alright, I understand.
Ua AK. ama
uperintendent
Alright, I understand.
uya Akiyama
uperintendent
Ii 35 th (56)
Just do exactly
Iike the other night, right
ya Akiyama
uperintendent
136 ta (56)
Just do exactly
Iike the other night, right
ya Akiyama
uperintendent
Just do exactly
Iike the other night, right
Iet's see, there was no one
here that night when I got here
Mr. Arima looked through that little
window to see inside the office
And he said somebody
was inside, didn't he?
Yes, that's right
So I took a look too and...
What the?
I. I don't believe it!
Impossible!
Is there somebody inside?
I don't understand
Take a look for yourself: Ms- Kisaki
What the!
I just set things up exactly
Iike Uncle Kogoro told me
Set things up, are you saying,
he knows who the killer is?
Yes. He saidghe'd explain
everything /in court
Homicide and burglary-crime
Second trial
APNEA RAZINARE
ggzfizfigfl
With mom and dad on
the same side, we can't lose
Takashi Inoue
RX. n= C-
Fr BEND
Who would have thought,
Takashi Inoue
RR >»
F¥ = BE XE (55)
Takashi Inoue
AR EL
+ It b& EE (65)
she'd ask Kogoro Mouri be
appointed special counsel
Kisaki mst really be desperate
All rise!
Mr. Akiyama: you stated that you
Iooked into the victim's office
through the:small window,
and saw him being beaten,
is that correct?
How many times did
the killer strike the victim?
I saw three blows being delivered
Shortly, after that
you heard the sound of the victim
falling to the floor, correct?
Yes...
End. of;questioning!
Does the defense have any
questions:for the witness?
1 do...
Mr. Akiyama
you claim that you saw the victim being
hit but did you see the assailants face?
No. I, I didn't actually
see the assailant"s face
Whatsdo you mean by that,
whattexactly did you see then?
The light outside cast the
killer's shadow on the wall
Order in the court!
So you're saying you merely saw the
assailant's shadow, is that correct?
Yes, that's correct
Its the same thing.
As: long:as-hersaw the assailant,
seeing his shadow is good enough
Let me ask you one more time
Mr. Akiyama, is the defendant here,
the assailant you saw that evening?
No. like I said, I only
saw a shadow on the wall
So you can't say for sure the defendant
iS the assailant then, is that correct?
Yes, that's correct...
Thank you
NO more questions
Oh for goodness sakes!
What is«dad doing!
He hasn't done anything except sleep
Don't worry, his tim Oillrcome
Are you sure?
I call Mr. Arima to the witness stand
\ Mr. Arima, you and Mr. Akiyama
heard the sound of
the.victim falling. didn't you?
Yes, I'm certain of it
The. door was locked so you
brokevit:down by/ramming
ntostandithen ran inside.
Yes. But the killer had already
escaped:through the window
and my father-in-law, I mean,
Mr. O@tsu was on"the floor
And what about the safe?
It was open
No more questions
Defense, your turn.
Here goes
guess it's time for me to
Iiven up this boring trial
Good luck. dad
I'll see how he does first!
Yo. ef
vo <4
NW os Yr -
Special counsel, you may
proceed to question the witness
Yes sir!
Mr. Arima,
you claim you arrived at the
victim's office a little
past 9 PM to deliver an item
he'd forgotten, is that correct?
Yes, my father-in-law forgot his
reading glasses at my restaurant
But the office was locked
and you couldn't enter
That's right.
The dogr Was actually
unlocked, wasn't it?
And the victim was in his office
counting«#h& money in the safe
What are you getting at,
A, are you implying I...
No. I'm merely pointing out the fact that
you could have committed the crime too
Ridiculous!
Why would I kill my father-in-law!
When it comes to money, you
can'titrust your own family.
Unlike usual, ole Kogoro is
actually making some sense
Objection! Special counsel 1s
merely voicing his own-opinion!
Ee! 3
Objection granted. Special counsel
shall stick to the facts at hand
But based on my
many years of experience,
the first person to report the
crime is usually the guilty one
Alright 'then. based onYou r
many years of experience,
how do you explain the
things left on the crime scene
and the defendant's \
fingerprints on the safe?
When the witness and the victim
were fighting over money
the defendant was looking in through
the window: watching them
Well that's. anew. theory...
Then after the witness hit the
victim over the head and left,
Defendant took the opportunity to enter
the office to steal the money in the safe
The who was the assailant
Mr. Akiyama saw?
The truth is,
the victim wasn't dead yet
he regained consciousness
and struggledWith the defendant
now you're going way off base
You-re saying then is, the defendant
did indeedzcommiit the murder
I. I guess I am...what?
What are you saying! You're supposed
to be here to defend the client!
I'm a famous private detective,
I'm here to solve this.case!
I was a fool to depend on you.
Forget:it! You just keep out of my way ll
How dare you, I'm not finished,
I'm getting to the best part
Family fuels should be
carried .out elsewhere
I hate you dad!
I guess it's time I took ole Kogoro out
You just sit down
and keep your mouth shut!
A decoration piece!
Your honor, I'd like to
retract my previous statements
Just forget it!
The defendant entered
that office befor Mr. Arima,
not after.
The victim walked{in on him while he
was trying to get the safe open.
He hit the victim inadvertently
and ran out of the office
The question is what
happened after that
The defendant thought
he had killed the victim
but the truth-is, he had just
knocked him unconscious
someone else arrived on the scene
shortly thereafter and killed him!
Are you saying that it was me?
You claimed that the victim
forgot his reading glasses
in your restaurant, isn't that correct?
Did he need his reading
glasses during meals}too?
Well, he needs them to read the menu
That's strange.
The indictment:states.that'the victim
opened the safe because the
defendant threatened him
The victim didn't have his glasses
I wonder how he managed
to get the safe open
and his office was dark, the only light
was from the neon sign outside
How should I know?
The victim was still alive when you
delivered his glasses, wasn't he?
Father, are you in?
What happened?
Your head's bleeding!
Leave me alone!
It's nothing!
That was right after he
wandered in on the burglar.
The first thing he got worried
was the money in the safe
I have your glasses here
When you saw the money,
you thought of killing him
and you hit over the
head with the ashtray
Prosecutor! I came here as a witness,
why am I being treated like a suspectlr
Mr. Mouri, you've forgotten
one very important-detail.
The witness has an alibi
You bet I do! I was on the other side of
the door when father was beaten
and fell to the floor,
Mr. Akiyama was with me
Didn't you hear
Mr. Akiyama's testimony?
He said that he
never saw the assailant
B, but he saw a shadow
Yes, a shadow on the wall
You committed
murder blinded by the money,
now you had to make it look like
a burglary, you were desperate
Then you came up with ah-idea,
you used the clock in
the victim's office
Your honon!- This clock is
exactly like the one:in the victim's office
The killer evidently used the
movements of this figure
along with the light from the outside
and cast it's shadow on the wall
then led Mr. Akiyama
into mistaking the time
Wh, what about the sound!
Explain that!
Mr. Akiyama and I hear my father fall!
That's easy
What?
You probably put a golf ball
tied with a string under the leg
of the desk in the victim s office
The other end of the string led under
the door to the outside of the office
and when Mr. Akiyama looked inside
and got a scare, you pulled the string
See? Didn't I say it was easy?
Do you have any proof I did it?
Anyone could have
done what you said!
If you have proof
that I did it, I'd like to see it!
The witness is right. If you're insisting
he's guilty, I'd like to see some proof too!
The proof, Prosecutor,
IS on that list of items found at the
crime scene, which you are holding
On this list?
See, it says screw for
eyeglasses, doesn't it?
If it belongs to the victim's
reading glasses,
when did it get where it was found?
He was supposed to have left
» his glasses: at the restaurant
It came loose and fell off
when the assailant hit the victim,
that's the only
explanation I can think of
Another thing Mr. Arima, you
used your cook.s apron to wipe
your fingerprints off the
ashtray&didn't you?
The lab report stated that the ashtray
was wiped with a cloth containing oil
Request permission to have a sample
of the olive oil used in Mr. Arima's
restaurant be tested against the oil on
the cloth used to wipe the ashtray
/ Mr. Afima. after the crime. you repaid a
Ioan of 50 million yen, didn't you?
We can always have that
money tested for fingerprints
it was my father-in-laws fault...
he was so greedy
you must be relieved,
your money's safe
Do you want some of this?
But if you don't pay me back
what you owe me by next week
I don't care if you are my
daughter's husband,
I'm going to have you kicked
out of that restaurant
Mr. Mouri, you were
right about everything.
I killed my father-in-law!
I move that the charges of burglary
and murder against the defendant
be dropped and I will draw up a new
indictment for attempted burglary
Does the defense have any objections?
None
Then court is dismissed!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producer?
MICHIHIKO_SUWA
MA AHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUQ ONO
Character Designs By.
MASA OMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
CHI MIYAS
CHI HIG
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chict Director.
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By
TMSSENTERTAINMENT LTD
In. association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE (( NAN
Owlt AOYAMA HOCAKUKAN YIV IAN
All Ri: hi Reserved
Uh. Ms<Kisaki!
A terrible, injustice was about to
be made. thank you for preventing it
TR TY
JAN O
\ I. I was just doing my job
I'll be looking forward to
seeing you in court again then
Why don't we all go get
something to eat to celebrate!
That reminds me, I'm hungry.
How about some delicious
wine and Italian cuisine.
Ah, I think I'd like somc.
Japanese sakeand sashimi instead...
no wait, cold beer and some piping
hot stew sounds good too
Oh who cares...
The murdered occurred after that,
probably sometime past 11
I'm so happy. all four of them have alibis
Yeah!
The alibi can be broken tien!