The distance between love and hate is
filled as the two solve mysteries together
Officer of police headquarters
and the detective squad,
Love and mystery is on
the verge of explosion
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
NoJcase is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Hey! Isn't that Hide?
Where. where, I can't see!
They said on radio just a while ago that
Hide is going to be riding the car
at the end of the line!
Oh, that's right!
It'sure.is unusual to have a soccer
victory parade though...
It can't"be helped...
Everygyear a-big-fuss-is made over
the Spirits being:the-winning candidate,
and. finally this year they won
the J1¥¢hampionshipsfor the-first time!
Moreover, they won by a dramatic
come-from-behind victory...
Right! In the second half lost time
they were losing 1 to 0,
but Hide tied the game!
And then right after playoff
Naoki scored V goal!
He was awesome!
But with all this crowd,
we can't really see the parade.
Ght... It's so disappointing becau
I even brought my video camera along...
That's why I told you, right?
We should've kept watching TV
ike we wens!
Come. come!
We set the video before coming here,
SO we can all watch it together later!
Uh. .Hey! Maybe if we go there,
we can have a better view!
Huh'?
There! Over there!
I see!
If you go on.topathe empty cans container, 4
we may-get a better view!
Let's go!
Okay!
How is it? can-you-See?
Wait a second...
I can see glimpses of their heads,
but not their faces.
Ouch sF=.
Hey. hey!
Dang. if it was only a bit"higher!
But, I don't see anything that is higher
than this empty cans container
Neither do I...
That's it!
Hey. hey hey...
PARADE ANDE MALICE AND SAINTS
PART I
(B1%R)
PARADE ANDE MALICE AND SAINTS
PART I
On. I see him in the distance! Ms Hide!
Naoki is also betfhdi=>
It Seems like he's looking this
way and waving his hand!
R.Really?
Hey. let me see too!
Oh, wait a minute.
This is the best part!
Hcy!
You shouldn't climb up there!
Oh. I.I'm sorry
Ill put him down right away
Staying up here a little while
won't hurt will it, old lady!
Hey! What's with the oldflady bit?
How dare you call me old lady!
If you don't listen to me I'm going to
arrest you.
Officer Sato!
What are you doing dressed like that?q
Oh, I get it! You sneaked of f from work
and came to watch the parade in secret!
I see!
That's why you're in disguise
No way!
I have my reasons
You're dating, right?
With Officer Takagi
Y. Yumi!
I happened to see...
Saw what?
Officer Takagi choosing
a wig in the restroom!
Dating while on the move,
you guys are pretty cool!
N.No! This is
You can't talk about us then...
You mean it's okay for
officers to do stuff like that? 7
It's against service regulations
What will become of
the future of Japan...
1.I'm telling you
you got it all wrong!
We're on duty, on duty!
It's no date!
Inspector Shiratori,
How come you're in disguise too?
We just received an odd fax at
the headquarters a while ago
am an anti Spirit.
Something interesting will happen at
Al) (xr WO [Re eid
fo - pallor Silo (ereks KR ee
Something interesting will happen at
WO - moRiern Salo IF Ta, RR 0
And that FAX. was very similar to the ow
one in a case that I previously handled @P
That's why we, of the 1st
Investigation Unit is here too.
But, the culprit knows our faces,
sO we all disguised ourselves
and are investigating right now!
Well, it's more likely a bad prank
of some fan jealous of the championship
so it's not a date..."
And besides, the date in question,
IS supposed to be next week...
I thought that you couldn't wait till
then so you both got eager and...
I guess not then...
H.Hey. how come you know about it?
Everybody,knows about it
You're going to Tropical Marine
that just opened. right?
E.Everybody?
Don't take the Japanese police lightly...
If he takes a day off on, the day that
you're off everybody can tell
Il heard thatiwhenpOfficer Takagn
was shoved into the interrogation room
and crossyexamined by everybody,
he confesse limmediately
C.Confessed...
Well-just be careful, okay.
It seems that a lot of other people
asked for the same day off too.
Right, and it also seems
that rental reservation
of the binoculars and communication
equipmentfor that day is full too.
D.Don't tell me that they're
planning to keep an eye on us?!
It sure sounds interesting.
Then, shall we go to Tropical
Marine Land too!
Yeah, let's, let's!
Y.You know what...
I'm just going out with Officer Takag:
because I want to show him my
appreciation for having helped
me before! So, it's not a date!
Really?
That's hard to believe...
I'm telling you it's true
and I'm not lying...
Halk SF
Believe me...
You're just going to sit back and watch
this all take place, Inspector Shiratori?
That's not it.
I'm not going to wave a white flag just
because she refused to marry me
They still call each other very formally
There's still room
for me to try for her...
Besides, as far as this stakeout is
concerned. I'm the one in charge
Oh, Is that right...
Date, 'date, date
Hey. Yum,
help me out here: will you
Give it your best shot!
Oh my, talk of the devil,
You idiot, showing
up at a time like this
Mr. Matsuda
Oh, it's Officer Takagi!
You're not hiding
under your disguise at all!
You've figured me out after all.
I had no idea that you guys 9
would be here, though
But, all three police
officers were surprised!
Really?
Y.Yes. sort of...
How about you, Ms Sato? Don't you
think I disguised myself quite well?
Ms Sato?
Inspector Megure gave
you instructions saying
that you didn't have to
disguise yourself, didn't he?
Oh, yes, but, I
thought I should anyway
Then, why do
you come dressed like that?
I...I'm sorry...
Now that you know,
get rid of that disguise right
away and go back to your post!
Understand!
O.Okay...
1.1 wonder if, I
did something I shouldn't have
Nope syou just-kind of resembled him...
The you just a while ago...
Him?
The officer who was employed. for only
7 days at Investigation 1st Division
before you came to headquarters...
Hide!
Naoki!
Oh, the car that
Hide is on seems to have come! 4
Let's force. ourselves to the
front and take a video of him!
Oh. but: since I've
been taping from a while ago
'don't think there's
much tape left already...
You mean you didn't
bring any spare tape?
Oh, I brought it!
Then, insert'it and let's get on with it!
Okay!
Come on. hurry, hurry!
Please wait
I wonder if everything's
going to be okay...
You received an odd FAX saying
that something was going to happen
at this parade, didn't you?
Yes, but it seems to
have been a prank after all
B*By the way,
what are=yoill doing here, Yumi?
I've come to back up giving
tickets for illegal parking!
A lot of people parking their cars all over
the street in order to see the parade,
You better move your car
quickly too, Officer Takag:!
Or, Fl have to give
you a parking ticket!
Oh, I'll move it right away!
WwW. Where are you
everybody!
E.Excuse me, somebody...
H. Hey!
Congratulations!
But, aren't you a fan of Big Osaka?
It's a wonder you
came to watch this parade
I came to place a curse
that they won't win next year...
I see...
Hey, where the hell were you?
You've got to film it
quick or the car's going to leave!
W.Well. the thing is...
The key. the key...
Oh brother, it's not my day today
What?
Somebody took your video camera?
Yes. just a while ago. in the crowd...
What's this...
Oh, my god...
Cancelsthe parade immediately
and evacuate the people
Yes, sit!
W.What the heck was that!
A bomb, it seems like a car blew up.
Isn't, Isn't that
car Officer Takagi's car?
Don't tell me that Officer Takag...
It's possible, because just a while ago
I saw somebody go over to that car
from the space between the crowds
Dang it!
H.Hey. Conan!
Inspector Shirator!
WwW. Where's Officer Takagi?
It exploded just as he
went over to the car.te-move it.
If he got caught in the explosion,
I doubt that he would make it
Then<you mean that Officer Takag:...
OS Oy
That's only if the worse happens... 'l
W, What's that supposed to mean?
I made it*te.safety by a hairsbreadth,
so please don't talk like I didn't maketit!
Officer Takagi!
You're okay!
Yeah, somehow...
I coincidentally
found a paper bag that wasn't
under the car when I parked...
Just when I was about to return,
and consult with Inspector Shiratori
that this may be a bomb
the car exploded...
It's amazing that
you though the content
inside the paper
bag may have been a bomb
Oh. that's because...
It's only natural...
I mentioned already that the FAX that
was received at headquarters resembled
the one of a case that we were
involved with previously, right
If the officer was informed that this
was the case of the serial bombings
and yet failed to realize that itimayg,
have been a bomb, something is wrong
Talk about failing to notice,
Iook at her
She still doesn't seem
to realize that you're okay
Let's stop her!
O.Officer Sato!
Officer Takag:!
Officer Takagi!
No, Sato!
You won't make it!
It's dangerous, stay back!
But, he's still inside...
He's still inside...
He's inside!
Hey. Miwako!
What do you think you're doing?
I I'm trying to lift
the car up and get him out...
Officer Takagi is fine.
See?
O.Officer Sato!
You burned the palm of your hands!
H. Hey, we've got
to treat it right away!
I guess so...
I'll let you take care
of things from here then
It seems that the one Officer
Sato was trying to rescue was...
probably Mr. Matsuda...
O Officer Matsuda?
The type of bomb is a plastic bomb!
The detonating device
IS not the timer type, but wireless!
A cell phone or something" was
probably 'used to activate it...
Then, don't tell me that...
The bomber was
probably watching you
you approach the car
from somewhere nearby,
and pushed the switch
of the detonation device
What!
Which means that although the type
of bomb being used is not the same,
it is highly probable that the bomber
is after the lives of we the police
just as the case three years ago!
So, all of you keep that in mind and
work with great care, arrest the bomber
yet speedily to arrest the bomber...
Xcuse me...
What is it?
The bomber could've been
recorded in video camera
Mitsuhiko was taking video all
through right near the site
Really?
Yeah...
And besides, somebody among the crowd
of people watching the
parade stole the camera.
Yes .
1. The camera was stolen?
Oh. but the tape is fine! >
He inserted a new tape
just before the camera
was stolen because
he was running out of. tape...
The video camera's fine too!
It was thrown away in a.trash can
of a nearby station
with only the tape removed!
Which-means y
the person whoistole:the camera,
wanted the tape and not the camera?
The only ones ho wuld do a thing
Iike steal the camera back then,
has to be a fervent fan of the Spirits or
someone who didn't want to be
taped, like the bomber, right?
We connected it to a large monitor
and looked through it but
It was mostly only
of Mitsuhiko's feet
R.Right, I forgot that I kept the camera
going with the camera facing down
I can tell what you
guys are talking about,
But, scene cannot be seen on the tape...
Inspector Megure, gave you
instructions saying that
you didn't have to disguise
yourself, didn't he?
Who is this man?
Oh: IF sorry, that's me.
How come you taped this part okay?
I'm sorry,
I just happened to film it...
Hey. Officer Sato looks to be crying.
Oh. no, well you see thisfis...
Somebody is behind
you near the car
It looks to be a passerby...
Besides. at this distance it's hard-to
tell one person from the next
On no! vg
The camera's face down again!
And that's-the. end ofsthe tape
It seems that the scene that we were
I expecting of the bomber placing
the paper bag under Officer
Takagi's car was not filmed
Maybe something was
filmed in the-first part of the tape,
that among the crowd!
Why don't we rewind
the tape-and look at it then!
Yes. this is Megure
What?
Another bomb went off!
Yes. this time'it was at the
phone booth in front of Haido Park
Fortunately.
Nobody's been.hurt, though.
From the type of bomb that was used,
it's most likely the same bomber
Okay, got it, go on and
continue investigations.
Hey, what road is there to get from the
first site of explosion to the Haido Park
T.The road order
of the parade of the Spirits!
Which means that the bomber
IS not after we, the police
but carried out an extremely
heinous prank against the Tokyo Spirits
O Officer Sato
Are you all right?
How's your hands? I hear got burns
No problem.
I can go!
Okay. we've figured
out what the bomber as after!
Mereover, he may have set
bombs up elsewhere too!
Get all the officers nearby;and go to
the front of the course of the parade,
and evacuate the
people in the vicinity!
Do what you can to
take the suspect into custody,
then search for the
bombs with all your might
On the double!
Yes, sir!
Just in case-Officer Shirator,
will you contact™the bomb disposal
crew and have-them stand by!
Yes, sir!
Officdr Takagi. I want you to stay
back here and keep checking: the video
If you find anything
contact me immediately!
Oh, I'll go to the site too...
You wait back here.
@ Officer Sato...
And. I d like to
have a word with you later
Strange, what is the
culprit after anyway
Pretending to be
the bomber of 3 years ago,
sending FAX to headquarters.
And blowing up the car of the
officer that is dispatched
But, soon afterwards
the culprit blows up a phone booth
that has nothing to do with the police
I wonder if it's really only a prank
of bad taste towards the Spirits...
And, besides, this...
tape that Mitsuhiko took...
Is something that will point out
the bomber really recorded on it?
If so, what the heck. is recorded?
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YCSHIOKA
Background Music
KAT -UQ ONO
Character Designs By.
Story Editor
rrs 1
Scripts By.
KANJ1*KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI.KOUGH
JUNICHI MIYATA
YUIGHT HIGURE
I SHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MA ATOMO SUDO
» . CY  ) '. \
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWACGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chict Director.
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By.
TMSIENTERTAINMENT, [TD
117 association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CC NAN
GOW AOYAM Af SHOGAKUKAN YTV - TA1S
All RE hi Reserved
Did you really watch it?
I watched it three time already...
If you think that the crowd is suspicious,
everybody in the crowd looks suspicious
and if you think nothing is suspicious,
nothing looks suspicious
Maybe the culprit thought
he was being filmed?
Although nothing was filmed...
Not filmed? I see!
PARADE OF MALICE AND 'SAINTS
PART