Ne distance between
Iove and hate is filled
as the two solve
mysteries together.
We'll get to the truth
of the bomb threat case.
The story of an officer at police
headquarters who is In love.
He sees through the
one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
We. The members
of the Youth Detective Squad
who came to see the victory
parade of the Tokyo Spirits,
ran into Officer Sato and the others of
the police department in disguise
Since a FAX warning
of something bad happening
happening at the parade
was sent to police headquarters
the officers were out investigating
and checking the site out.
FF ny
the officers were out investigating
and checking the site out.
cues] eden) Wine KE og
Just then Officer Takagi's car...
They key... My key... There...
Officer Shiratori!
What about officer Takagi
It exploded just as he
went over to the car to move it.
If he got caught in the explosion,
I doubt that he would make it
Then<you mean that Officer Takagi...
It can't be...
That's only if the worse! happens...
W.What's that supposed to mean?
I made it*to-safety by a hairsbreadth,
so please don't talk like I didn't make it!
When we were checking to
see If Mitsuhiko who was
taking video pictures near theliscene
had taken any pictures of the bomber
What! Another bomb went off?
Yes?Othis time'it was at the phone
booth in front of Haido*Park
From the type of bomb that was
used, it's most likely the same bomber
Which means that the bomber
IS not after we, the police
but carried out an extremely
heinous prank against the Tokyo Spirits
I wonder if it's really only a prank
of bad taste towards the Spirits
And, besides, this...
tape that Mitsuhiko took
Is something that will point out
the bomber really recorded on it?
If so. wh-at the heck is recorded!
(1 ¥)
Parade of Malice and Saints
Part 2
This is«it.-this-is it!
Don't you think this
Iady is suspicious?
She's been glaring
towards the camera right through
True, she kind of looks bothered...
She just doesn't like
the idea that Mitsuhiko
is filming her mini-skirt
from a low angle!
Oh, but, no.l.l didn't
mean to do anything like that
Twin. what about this man Withuthé beard?
Yeah, he seems to be looking around
the ground. deesn't he?
Look carefully at his hand!
He's holding a child's shoe, right?
He probably came to the parade with
his wife who was carrying their child
both shoes ust ha) ened to come off,
and I'm pretty sure he's looking or them
I see...
\ Hey! Officer Tékagi. you've gotta tell
us some things that;you've noticed too
And, I'd like to have a word with you later
Officer Takagi!
Did you say something?
Are you watching carefully or what?
I've already watched: it three times...
But, no matter how many times I
Iook at it, it's the same thing
In a crowd, if you think someone looks
suspicious, they look suspicious.
If you think they don't then, they don't
It's virtually impossible to pick
the bomber out of this crowd
That's true...
Which means that the bomber
would've thought the same thing
But, the bomber stole the
video camera
and attempted to remove
the tape that was inside
Whatever for...
The bomber just thought something
was recorded, when nothing was...
Nothing was?
Wait,
Welk 61 ol
NOthing was taken means
Don't telllmerthat
I see...
boyy
Conan." Was something recorded?
No, nothing really...
Then, it's no good?
No, not really.
because something was recorded o Sit,
bu rather because he was trying to hide
evidence that nothing was recorded!
What?
Just what do you mean?
There's something
mfve got to confirm first. though
Hey. Conan: what thclhecks going on!
What do you mean hide evidence
of nothing recorded!
Nothing was recorded on the tape I took,
the bomber didn't have to steal it, right?
Wait up @onan!
Hey, Conan!
Just as I thought
It's just as I thought!
W. What's with the mail box?
You know what time Mitsuhiko climbed
on top the mail box, don't you?
I don't remember details like that!
We can figure that out by
watching the video tape
because the time is also recorded
T.That's right!
'a Ww
Uh. it was the lime I was recording
something far away by zoom so .
Here it is!
It was 2:28 in the afternoon!
After that we ran into Officer Sato
until 14:38 when Mitsuhiko quit taking
video, we were by this mail box, right?
S.So what?
Then, take.-a look at this!
Look at the time the mail is
supposed to be picked up!
On holidays it says about 14:30
that meansythey come to pick the mail
uprabout 2:30 in the afternoon, right?
Y.Yeah...
Which means, we didn't see what we
were supposed to see, doesn't it?
Right!
The mailman"s car!
CI}!
He never came to pick the mails!
The road was blocked by the parade
so maybe it couldn't come through
No. they usually choose
a parade course
that does not interfere
with duties of that sort!
Besides only one lane is being used for
the parade that there is no way
that the mail truck cannot
make it's way here.
But, if the roads are crowded, it's
easy to be late about 8 minutes
No way, It didn't looK
Iike there was a traffic jam
and the collection time indicted on
the mail box is iniintervals of 5 minutes
If there is a discrepancy of
5 minutes earlier or later,
the only thing thinkable
is that something came up.
The one who triedbto steal Mitsuhike's
video camera is the bomber, right?
Right, what does the mail truck
have anything to do with this?
And besides. would anyone want to
steal the video tape in the first place?
If it was left as is, nobody
would've noticed anything
but now, it's like telling everybody
that something may be there!
Yeah, I guess they
didn't intend to steal it either
If we were just a bunch of ordinary kids
who came to watch the parade
II get it! Yumi's mini-police car!
You were witnessed talking intimately
with Yumi in front of the mailbox.
The culprit tried to
get rid of the evidence!
Yeah, If a bombing
incident takes part nearby,
it means that there is a possibility the
bomber would be recorded on the video,
and the police would without
doubt check the film out
Moreover, if we are
acquainted with the police.
The time it would tak) to check the
tape out would be pretty speedy...
That's what the bomber was afraid of!
They probably noticed Mitsuhiko's
video camera only after
they set the bomb up
under Officer Takagi's car
that was parked right
opposite the mailbox
They couldn't go retrieve the bomb
So they decided to get rid of the tape
I don't understand. though...
The bomber FAXED the police
to sort of let them know that
something was going to happen, right?
Y.Yes!
If they go ahead and call all the police
officers over here and blow the car up,
it's obvious that the police will
come frantically after them
Maybe they want
to distract the police?
By pretending to be the
same %Brhber 3 years ago?
Although»! have no idea
what kind of a case it was
Similar to the case 3 years ago,
it is extremely likely that the
bombers are after the lives of we,
the police just as they were then!
You looked so much like him,
the you in disguise...
It seems that the one Officer Sato was
trying to save just a while ago was...
I want to have a word with you later...
The question is,
what the bomber is after...
Yeah, it's very likely that the bomber
is not after the police ,
nor playing pranks
against the Spirits.
If my deduction is
correct, they are after...
But, since I'm still not sure,
I want you and Officer Takag
to check something out for me
You can count on us!
Officer Takagi. are you listening?
Y.Yeah, I'm listening
This is Ayumi!
€onan, I've found: the mailbox!
Okay, what's the location of the
mailbox and the collection time?
The mailbox is under the
pedestrian overpass,
two traffic signals away
from the first mailbox...
The collection time is...
AbJtit 14:35!
Okay's
MitsuhikO here! I've found in front of the
convenience store on 2nd Street!
Mhe'timeti about 14:45"!
T. This Genta! I found one
near the park on 3rd Street
The tithe i1sp14:55
Hey, Genta, how
come you're whispering?
I can't help, because I went through
someones yard. which was a short cut.
I was mistaken for ajthief
after women's underwear,
and I'm hiding from the
Iady who came after me
Hang in there
Now all we.have to
do is wait for Al
Yeah...
vy <4
Oh it's her!
This is the woman in black...
Hey!
The location of the mailbox is
on the side of a bus stop
that I's about 150 meters west
from the mailbox on 3rd Street.
The collection time is 16:25
I just saw all of you now,
can you see me?
Yeah!
« Lastly the pick up time
for the mailbox is...
150...
So. if I match all
information with the map...
The course of the mail
truck is like this...
Just like you said. Shinichi
it seems to be getting-farther and
farther from the course of the parade
In addition, today is the
/Sunday/before payday
Now, all we have to do is wait for I
@fficer Takagi to contact us
If there were no traffic-accidents
or road construction is this area today
the reason the mailstruck-didn-t
come to pick up the mail is...
Excuse me...
What's the matter, Mr. Tsutsumi
If you're dropping off the mail that
you collected, 'go around the back and
Oh, well, a large number of very
odd mail is mixed in the bag
1.1 want everyone to look at it now.
But could you open
the front entrance please?
O.Okay. I'll go open it right away...
T.Thank you.,so.much,
for the trouble
No problem
Se. what's this odd
mail you're talking about
W Well that's
H.Hey, just what do
you think you're doing?
Sorry, sorry, the
stuff I wanna.show is
This, Mr. Mailman.
AA gun!
Hey! The guys back there come up
front here with your hands in the air!
If you hesitate I'm going to kill you!
Hurry it up!
Over there. too!
Quit taking your time!
Okay, take!it all out, the cash
It's right before pay day
so I'll bet you're loaded!
So that's why you chose today, that would
overlap with the Toyo Spirits parade
Today, when the employees
at the post office
office would be reduced
because it's a Sunday...
You sent faxes and used
bombs to deceive us
into thinking it had something to do with
the bomb case 3 years ago,
and lured us out...
You went on te make-it 10ok like a bad
prank towards the Spirits to throw us off
And while we were being confused
you attacked the post office using
the mail truck you hi-jacked
Well, it's;not such
an intelligentuideatthough
Hey. you over there! Gut out your
babblingOHurry it up andget up here!
So. he says. Hurry all of you!
Come on, hurry!
HHey: what's going on?
W. Why...
Why are there so many of you,
when it's a Sunday!
Oh, didn't you know?
Although we all belong to civil service
we're not like the post office employees
who have regular days off
We're on duty
24 hours 365 days a year
That's how it is for us police officers!
C.Cops!
Inspector Megure!
We've taken:custody of all the mailmen
we found tied upyin the mail trucks!
Good.
Y.You cops!
Cut it out!
Because your way of
thinking sure isn't wise
D.Dang it!
So. the post office
thieves were arrested.
The other robbers; who
set bombs at different. places
different places and were waiting\for the
others to return were all safely arrested
And. that night...
And. that night.
But. it's a wonder you figured out
that the bomber's real target
was robbing the post office
Oh, well, not really,
the kids dropped the hint
Oh, you mean Conan, right?
He's no ordinary kid after all!
V.Very true...
I'm sorry, about this afternoon, for
slapping you all of a sudden like that
I'll bet it hurt?
Oh, no, I'm to blame
for not following orders...
A.Are you all right, @fficer Sato?
The burn on the palm of your hands...
I'm fine, though it still hurts a bit
Although it still kind of stings.
I'll be fine.
All"ll"have to do is put a
Iittle-spit on it and wallah!
O.Oh%I guess so! I'm glad...
Officer Sato?
What?
You mentioned earlier that
you wanted to talk to me...
Oh. that...
@ @Officer Sato...
Let's call off the
date we were planning on!
I'm cursed!
C.Cursed?
Because, all the people that I ¢
herish vanish from before me
My father, my
PE. teacher in elementary
school, my senior
in baseball club and...
And, him too...
I don't want to go through
anything like that ever again...
@.@fficer Sato...
So. I'd rather we stay like we are now
colleagues at the police station
O.Officer Sato...
Officer Takagi...
That's the way to go!
Go for it Takagi!
Push! Push!
Push it, man Push!
You guys are sort of heavy...
Officer Sato I...
Officer Takagi?
I will never...
Right, You and me, we don't
really work out to begin with...
Right, right!
I cuter girl is way better for you!
Y.You think so...
Yes, yest
You chicken... w
Bye for now then!
Officer Sato...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MIGHIHIKQ SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUQ ONO
Charactr Designs By.
MA1SA=IOMO Sum)
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
ScriptsBy.
KANIPKASHIWABARA
KAZUNAFPI.KOUGHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUWI, ~H 1 HIGURE
16 SHIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
>, \N . 2 » TTT ae
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
CHI HIG
OSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI ADNO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU GO ADA
Chief 1 rector.
KEN]I KODAMA
Produced By.
TMSZENTERTAINMENT, LTD
nt association with
OMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CC NAN
(57) AOYAMA HOCAKUKAN -YIV ATS
All Ri) Reverved
What's the matter,
Officer Takagi
You look kind of pale...
Are you eating right?
Let's hurry up and start questioning the
people about the post office robbery
It seems he's still hasn't recovered
from the last time he was brushed off
C.Come now Au"
Why do you know about it?
Hey, Takagi! Howazit!
If you're notffeeling up to it, I can
take over questioning for you!
Oh, no, well .
Hey!
Takagi, your shoulder sure is stiff!
Takag:!
Wat some coffee?
If you 'ref hungry, there are rice
crackers, you know, Takagi!
Wow! Officer Takagi's
really popular: isn't he!
Oh, well, this is 'not quite right...
But, when we.got there, that person
was:really surprised and looked pale!
The person couldn't have be acting!
I wonder if that story is true...
It's pretty unbelievable. isn't it...
A mistake?
I've figured out who
the culprit is!
What!