Unsettled Policee Department
12 Million Hostages
W-What's that!
Bombing. again!
Bombing. again
Shuratori!
Shiratori!
It's dangerous,
get out of here, quickly.
Are you all right ¥Shiratori?
Yeah. I couldn't run as you did.
Takagi! Block off this
road and get an ambulance.
I will.
But: he can speak
that means he's okay...
Not quite...
Bleeding at the side of his head. with
paralysis in the left limbs-this could be.
Accute subdural hemorrhage...
We'd better take him ASAP to
the hospital. He's in critical condition.
Oh, no...
Anyway, if the gas catches fire,
it might cause secondary explosion!
Let's m ve Inspector Shiratori
away from the car
until the~ambulance gets here.
Yé Wet's do that.
This is terrible, really terrible.
Yeah, who on earth
would do such a thing...
don'teknowlthe bomber: but I'm
sure that he's after a police officer.
What!
He gave false lead saying that
he set up a bomb in the restaurant,.
and lured the police into the restaurant.
While the detectives were lookingifor the bomb
heiplanted the real bomb into the car
hiding himselframong the customers.
Who wereglead'out of the restaurant.
Brom what I saw.
the trigger mechanismeseems to work
in a way that the safety pin goesvoff
when the-door is first opened,
and when'the door is-opened again
In order to exit, thensiteexplodes.
The question is why did Inspector
Shiratori try to get out immediately
What's that?
I wanted to show this
to you as soon as possible...
The memory that you harbor
within you and cannot erase...
This. is.a chance to get rid of it...
- (38a
I am a major league player
who hits and throws well.
X doh
fam a major league player
who hits and throws well.
I am a major league player
radon
Te LOL
who hits and throws well.
x doh
I am a major league player
who hits and throws well.
who hits afd throws well.
Now, this is the beginning
of an extended game
iv KT
x l3.BR
Now. this is the beginning
of an extended game
ee O
Now, this is the beginning
of an extended game
.» B
- (8a
Now, this is the beginning
of an extended game
009 Vv
Now: this is the beginning
of ER extended game
» O re
«(1888
Now: this I's the beginning
of an extended game
«15888
Now, this is the beginning
of an extended game
of an extended-game
ee" 9
The game starts at neon tomorrow
It ends at three in the afternoon.
Ey DY
The game starts at noon tomorrow.
It ends at three in the afternoon.
The game starts at noon tomorrow
The game stats at noon tomorrow
It ends at three in-the afternoon.
>2 {J8EE
The game starts at noon tomorrow