Unsettled Police Department
12 Million Hostages
What! False bomb again!
Did you check all of them?
Is there no real bomb?
No, sir.
We have checked all the
¢ red trains that go through the city.
But all the suspicious
ones have been
false'or pranks...
I see, the bomber's probably trying
to throw off our investigation.
Anyway, be patient
and continue your investigations!
Yes, Sir.
Director Matsumoto.
What is it?
\ Report from the Ozaki team, sir.
They are at the ballparks.
And, what did you get?
Yeas, Sir.
Tihey have finished
checking all the major ballparks
in the city but
nothing came up so far.
They say they will continue
investigation covering smaller ballparks.
We don't have to check the
ballpark anymore. I guess.
All right.
Stop: all the red trains in the city.
Get all the investigators
out of the ballparks
and dispatch them to all the
stations to conduct investigations.
We still have five more hours till the first
explosion expected to go off at noon
He can outfox us .and
try setting up a bomb from now
Right sir.
Five more hours
I wanted to.say we
have only five hours left for us.
Yes...
I'm sleepy...
ta) Rig
RX ~~
Isnrt it strange?
From this-note, you would think that
he .expected somebodyitorcome:
-_- « Fr
come looking for it to the ballpark
but nothing happened.
He thought nobody would come: It's off
season and no big game is scheduled
Oh yeah?§
If he wanted toe play pranks on the police.
He could have set a false trap or two
At any rate,
we can't keep those
kids with us anymore.
Yousre right.
Oh, by the way: how is Shiratori,
did you ask thow he is?
Yes. I didh
Yumi is taking care of Shiratori.
And she told me that the
operatiOn was successful.
They are waiting for him to
regain consciousness.
That's good I'm relieved.
That's. good. I'm relieved.
Takagi, make sure Miwako
stays out of dangerous situations.
If the bomber is the same bomber
that killed Matsuda with a bomb,
who knows what she might do
and there will be no one but you
who will be able to save her!
Wha? Wh...why me?
You're so much like Mr Matsuda.
But that's only because I
happened to be disguised like him.
Of course, he's five to ten times
better in looks or attitude
Te... Ten times. is" it.
But something about you reminds
me of him, it may be your heart,
feelings or whatever,
something resembles Matsuda
I guess Miwako },
came to realizejthat lately.
Takagt!
What were you thinking over so seriously?
Oh, did you find out
where the bomb is?
No. I didn't.
Then what?
It's something unimportant.
Okay, for now
I'll continue investigation.
You send the kids home.
Then you return to the MPD
to get some sleep
and stay there to help
Inspector Megure.
Oh. but I can keep investigating...
Don't be silly.
A detective who is
unsteady from lack of sleep
will only :get'in the way
of the investigation, got it?
Y-yes.
Oh. no. You won't.
You will not take anyone with you.
Not anymore.
Never!
Taking a test right after new year holidays makes
me feelzlike=I'm livingsa gray life of a prep.
Takingra:test-right-after-new year holidays
Yeah...
New year days are
meant-for everyone: to enjoy!
So, yousenjoyed-yourself; didn't you?
Sure. I didn't-want to regret not
doingiwhat-! wanted to do.
Well, only thing I can depend on is...
Isn't it a... is that a...
Your wrong!
Here!
Why!
It's the photo of Kyogoku
Yaeah;
This photo gives me energy.
Even if my test results aren't
good. I won't gen depressed.
As long as I have Makoto's love a
don't need to score 100 on my test.
Oh4noO% I'm so ashamed of
myself for being so bold!
Sure, sure, sure...
OK, kids. Ill take you home.
Tell me where you live, will you?
OP» Are you taking us back home?
We may be able to
solve this code in a moment...
You haven't slept for a long time.
I can't keep you,
school kids, witfYme any longer.
Say! Where's Detective Sato?
She's investigating on the case.
I see, Detective Sato
told you to send us home.
You do everything she tells
you to do, don't you!
I have to. She's two years
older and my senior as well.
And you think you'll do
fine after marrying her too?
Marry her?
I won't be,
Cuz she just dumped me the other day.
Sato-san...
Yes?
You said you have
something to say to me.
Oh. That...
Sa..Sato-san...
Let's forget the date,
the date we were gonna have.
I'm cursed
Cursed?
All the people that I care dearly for,
seem to disappear from me.
My father, the PE. teacher in school,
myasenior in the baseball club, and...
him too...
I don't want to have to go
through that kind of pain anymore.
Sato...
We have been good friends and police
officer I want us to stay that way
SS. Satoh-san...
Yes. Takagi?
You're right. We are not
well-matched in the first place.
Yeah, you deserve a prettier cuter girl.
Yeah? Do I?
See?
I'm not getting married.
So you gave her up
What a chicken!
No guts at all.
I don't want to give her up. but...
But what?
But.
Detective Matsuda risked his life
to save the people in the hospital,
buts can"tibe his equal
Right?
W.Where did you learn that?
Detective Takagi
A head! Look ahead!
We heard about it from the
Iady on the mini-patrol car.
You mean Yumi?
She told us in detail.
Then, Detective Matsuda
decided at that time to riskhis life to tell
us where the other bomb was planted.
\ YEA 5 WEY 3
I have to hang upinow. Click.
Oh, wait;"Matsuda,
Matsuda!
You can't listen to it
7 tell it without tears.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah?
He has good rea Gn to give up. I guess.
The memory of one
who's gone is sealed
and will be kept in the
heart for a life time.
LiKé someone I know.
Hey!
I" ; Mot dead yet
How did you @& on the math test?
Bummers...
Unlike you, I have nobody to
help me in my difficulties.
Help-me?
Ou-can=t-fool me: Ran!
You were often looking at Shinichi's
desk for the right answers
Help, Shinichi! I have trouble solving
this derivative, integral problem...
Be honest about it.
No, you're wrong.
I looked at Shinichi's desk because...
Because Keep on!
Oh. because...
Yousres=blushing crimson
Red is a'sinister color during test time.
Speaking of red, there has been so
many police sirens since this morning.
True. You're right.
What's happened?
RR dd... red... red...
What's the matter with red?
250"
Something dees not fit. This
Climb up the bloody mound. means
Xx AX
You mean that it's not a red train?
Wes-kind«of notiraghtt
Now: wait.
If it's like the case 3 years before,
the first bomb is set in a place
that's rather easy for the police to find
Think simple. the simpler the better
Something that reminds you of red
the post and! fire truck...
Red-demon. little fed riding hood...
Tomato, strawberries,
watermelon, apple,
cherries, hot chili pepper,
red salmon and red lobsters. I
Red... climb... steel...box
Genta, all your ideas are food
I've use up my brain. now I'mihungrys
I'm, kinda thirsty...
Well, then we can go
andstop at Some parking area <
Red, . ou sa .
There's another red over there.
There, you see.
Yeah.
I, I see, red. climb up-box of steel...
is something already happening?
W.What is it?
There's smoke coming out
won eri. a om > was
set up here after all?
I'll go ask what happened, so
youikids wait in the ca J okay!
We scheduled to bring you a special
on Toto Towers mascot Toto today but,
ddue to an accident, we have
inevitably changed the schedule.
Excuse me,
what on earth has happened?
Oh, you see the thing is.
What?
The bomb is inside Toto Tower?
Yes. I'm pretty sure.
Just what do you meany
Tell me about it in detail. will you!
Yes. just before"! got
here there was a small explosion,
and the elevator
seems to have stopped.
What!
It's most likely that the suspect thinking
that the police located the bomb,
used a remote control
to set off the explosion...
The control board of the
Ferris Wheel suddenly exploded
and the Ferris Wheel couldn't be stopped!
It's the-same as back then...
I'll go over to the elevator that had
stopped and check things out
No! That bomb has been set to
Iure officers there, it's a'trap!
What, a trap?
I'll be there in 5 minutes so wait
there until I get there! Understand?
O. Okay...
Hey. we have trouble!
It seems that a girl's
been trapped in the
elevator that stopped because
of the explosion a while ago!
What-did you say!
Officer Sato. a child is in the elevator...
Calm down! We've still got two hours to
go before the predicted time of bombing!
But, I'd better go and check things
out as soon as possible
Don't worry! I'll work something
out, so you just stay there!
B.But...
Understand? Don't make MiwaKo get
into dangerous situations. okay.
I'll rescue that girl. I promise!
But...
She's bound to do reckless things...
Understand, this is an order!
You stay there until I get there!
Understand. Officer Takagi!
Hey. Officer Takagi?
Can you hear me?
\ Officer Takagi. answer me!
Hey, Officer Takagi!
Please Officer Takagi. don-t.go!
I refuse
I'm going to check .
How things*are inside.
O.Officer Takag!?
I'm going to go inside the tower/now,
so you all stay still and wait here, okay!
Understand?
Yvesssir... »
11 be right back)!
I wonder if Officer
Takagi is going to be okay...
Ail, take careO "everybody, okay.
What?
Hey, Conan!
What, are you going too, Conan?
I'm just going to go
check how things are.
You guys keep watch and make sure
nobody suspicious comes near this car!
But...
We"ll.be in big troubl )iffanbomb
IS set up on this cayagain, right?
But. I know you,
the detective squad will be able to
take care of things even
if I'm not around. right?
WwW. Well, I guess...
Leave it to us...
See you!
Be careful, okay, Conan.
According to he.
report from Officer Takag.,
about 15 Minutes ago.
There was a small explosion near
the special observatory area
It seems that one elevator of
this observatory is stalled
Only it hasn't been confirmed whether
this explosion was due
to a bomb or an accident.
It much too resembles the case of
3 years ago to be an accident.
True...
There's probably no doubt-about it
Emergency, emergency,
He dquarters to all stations.
There is 2 high possibility that a bomb
x has been.set at
Toto Towers in Minato Ward.
Head to the site on the double and
block off the entrance 10 Tote Tower.
- Secureanievacuation site for the
citizens in the vicinity. I repeat!
Officer Takagi...
Emergency announcement
to all visitors
We are very sorry to announce that
we will be closing for the day.
Please follow the instructions of the {
guide and leave the tower immediately
Please remain calm,
and move along without rushing!
E.Excuse me, police.
Please let me through!
Please remain calm.
Police!
Where's the elevator that stopped?
Oh, the one at the very end!
Thank you
Akemi, you'll be fine.
Don't be afraid. Come on out.
This is the elevator
that the girl is trap in?
Yes, sir
It came down from the tep floor
and stopped just before
reaching the observatory.
Akemi!
What are you doing. Akemi!
Hurry and come out!
Come over here!
Only one child W81 mm 3
elevator but she's so scared that
she won't listen to her mother
telling her to come out
this space is too small for
an adult to get through
Will you carry me up then!
I can make it inside, can't I?
Cc, Conan...
We continue to bring you live
broadcast news from Toto Tower.
T6day. at 'approximately 9e45 aim. there
was an explosion inside Toto Tower.
The cause of the
explosion is still unknown.
Fortunately,
no casualties have been reported
but due to the impact of the explosion
one of the elevators have stopped.
A four year old girl whorhappened to
be on the elevator is trapped inside.
While trying to
find the cause of the explosion...
Conan, are you all right?
Yep. I'm just fine!
Hello: Akemi.
I'm going to go over
to you Row: :56.-hold on; okay.
Akemi, what a cute teddy bear
What'd its name
Jam]!
Wow. what atcute name!
Is he a-boy
Yes!
I want to go over and
say hello to Jam. Is it okay?
Yep. okay.
I'm going over there, okay
[Uh;, we just got a report
that a police officer
, went into theelevator
to rescue the girl
that is trapped inside
A child went into the elevator!
It.It can't be!
And. Mommy'boughty
me Jam for my birthday.
I see: since mommy's,
waiting outside, shall we go?
Yep.
Okay. that's a good girl!
Mommy!
Akemi!
Okay. Conan. now you.
Okay.
Conan!
Dang it!
And?
You went off wanting to look and-now
you're trapped in the elevator with Conan
1.I'm sorry...
By the way, are you sure there's
no bomb in that elevator?
No, there's nothing that looks like
a bomb here in the elevator...
I'm going check the top
of the elm Na Or now.
Do you knew about
where you are now?
Uh, probably
All the wires seem
to have been sev Ted,
$0 I think with the
emergency stop
we are in the middle of the obse vatory
and roof of the tower building.
Okay then
I guess I'll have to climb to the ceiling
and wait for the rescue I; wad
No, don't climb up to the ceiling!
The mercury lever will operate!
The mercury lever?
Mercuny lever! #
Even a slight shake can
make the mercury inside roll,
and once the mercury
touches the circuit that-s-it...
Conan. what's a mercury lever?
It's a part of the trigger
device of the bomb.
It's a bomb big enough that
IS capable of not
only blowing up this elevator
but the entire Toto Tower as well.
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO_SUWA
MA AHIT( YOSHIOKA
B« ckground Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Saripls By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
CHI HIG
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA GM GA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief'! Wen for.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
TMSIENTERTAINMENT, LTD.
Mn 1ssGcral on with
vomit/RI rut CASTING
CORPORATION