Happy New Year, everybody!
Detective Conan
enters the eighth year, and
We have broadcast
more than 300 times.
We will do our best iin
TV's
movies
magazines and books.
So, be sure to stay with us€folks!
This is Location One, the explosive has
beenforocessed and disposed of.
The helmet is equipped with
a duct for cooling for respiration
that alternates as the
mist remover for the lens
And, we, are heading to Location
Two with officer Matsuda with us
To protect against
the hot air of explosion,
the structure of the protective gear
does not allow any openings.
The structure of the protective gear
The gear is so complex that
you cannot put it on by yourself
It weighs 40 kilogram
In the protective gear,
it's' a sauna even in cold winter
You can't keep wearing it
for more than five minutes
I'd say it's impossible.
Head quarters to everyone!
First area the...
All roads are blocked
The second area...
Capture all suspicious
Iooking suspects
from head quarters
Keep cool and collected.
No baggage. please.
Vacua e quic yan quie Yy.
It's dangerous, please move swiftly
Do not get scared
Evacuation of the residents
of this building is completed.
Confirmed.
Well, let's start...
You've done a good job, Matsuda.
How's Hagiwara ?
Lets see,
bomb with automated timer...
Silver lever with a white wires...
Moniter to the...
Matsuda? What's up?
Hagiwara!
What's taking you so long!
Go. tear it apart fast.
You're too loud. man
You're making\mylfingers shake.
Have you finished already?
Yeah. I opened it and found
out it's rather simple clockwork
it's sO simple...
Three minutes was long enough?
Right?
How about yours?
Takes more than 3 minutes for sure.
It looks simple but
there're so many traps around it.
I suppose this is the real one.
Right
By the way. you're in
protective gear. aren't you?
In that hot torturing thing?...
No way.
Darn! You want
to get killed "man? I
Well. you can get the guy for me...
Are you trying to get on my nerves?
Can't take a joke?
I'm not @ klutz.
Anyway, finish ASAP
and get on back here.
I'll buy you a drink tonight.
Lucky me!
You lured me into full throttle...
What's that!
What's up. Hagiwara?
Run, everybody.
Runaway!
The timer started counting again!
Hagiwara! Hey!
Hagiwara!
Hagiwara...
Why? How did you find out?
I asked that boy wearing glasses.
So. that's why.
By the way, Shin'ichi,
\ what-'re you going to do
about the all-country sim-test?
All-country sim-test?
You can't make it, can you?
I'll bet you're going to say you'r tied
up with-a new case or something
What s-this?
What's this?
I've leaded it in again.
You...
Pad. €@onan!
Don't be late
Breakfast is ready!
J Dad!
What stall the commotion¥about
from so early in the morning!
It's noon already.
I-m-:going to prepare for tomorrow-test.
Sonoko and I are going to work-on .it-today.
Will you finish up quickly?
That's your problem. not-mine.
You're-taking your report
to a client; aren't.you? .
And, @onan, you promised
Ayumi and the-others that
you'll go to
Hairdo Shopping Mall with them.
Yeah.
Haido Shopping Mall?
Oh, the mall with
that huge Ferris Wheel.
Yeah...
January: 6th "Monday.
The Winter holidays were-almost over.
That first day started very peacefully
but theffollowing twordaysiwere
Burned out to be a nightmare.
Unsettled Metropolitan Police Department,
12 million hostages
Sato-san, what do you think of
this disguise of mine?
It's cool, isnt it?
Sato-san?
What's the matter with you?
Anything wrong?
Sato-san?
Miwako!
Hey. Miwako?
Oh. Yuma.
What's the matter with you?
IN a coma or somethings'
I'm alright.
Just a little tired. I guess.
I'm going out for a while.
I thought you said you were going
to do paperwork all day today.
I just remembered something
I have to go out, and take a look.
Don't forget the karaoke tonight.
Oh. yeah. What time was it?
Nine o'clock.
I sent mail to your cell.
You can look at it.
Oh. ah...
Sorry. I've deleted it already.
Stop deleting mails right after
you finish reading them.
That's one of your bad habits.
If I don't delete them
I'll soon get a mailbox full of junk mails'
and lose track of important mails.
So, you mean mine is not important.
That's not what I meant
You better not.
Okay. nine o'clock.
Donitibe.late!
Roger and out.
Mail that you can't delete...
Wow; it-'s-so high!
Wow Really.
Great!
This Ferris Wheel is 125 meter high.
It's the highest in Japan.
It takes 18 minutes
to make one round.
You can make:6.instant noodles!
Diameter of the circle is 105 meters and
it takes 18 minutes to go once around
That means the speed of this car is
about 30 centimeters per second.
Can't you think of anything else?
Oh? Such as the power
necessary to make one round?
Cut it out.
It's been three years now
Everybody.
Let me introduce...
Mr. Jimpei Matsuda.
He will start workin with us as of toda
In the Criminal Investigation Section.
He has been in the Securit Department,
Special Task Force »
and I'd say that he is a bit of
a stranger here but...
We can do without that kind of
introduction, Insp&ctor.
I'm not exactly a new kid
from the country.
I don't think this show and tell about
me would be of any use to anybody.
I was stationed where I donst want
te be and lyn upset about it.
Well then, Detective Sato!
Ou ep IMOou an
Me: sir?
Don't shy away!
He is here for certain reasons, and they
asked me in person to play-along.
Will you take care of him?
Yes. Sir.
Hey, what kind of questioning
was that supposed 'tobe?
Questioning people like a mobster I
ike that, nobody will answer you!
You have been with us for 6 days new.
Why doMt you listen to me and
do as I say?
Oh'; you got mail?
F Fast
Yeah- I just-happen
to be clever with my fingers.
Are you mailinggyour girlfriend?
No. to my pal,
I'm sending my best friend mail.
Though I know he's
not going to write back to me
because he blew up 4 years ago.
Pass? Pass what?
Are you crazy?
I have to wait here-today
I'm sure -you guys
can bring the old suspect
from the local police 4
up here withoutime.
Now, you listen to me.
I am. Yiou said you receive it on
January 6th every year. Today is the day.
Yes, every year for three years,
yousmean the fax with
just one large number on it, right?
Number 3 was written
Oh it three years ago
number 2, two years ago.
And number 1, a year ago...
I'm sure it's the time bomb count down.
If the guy's making
any moves, today is the day.
Inspector!
We got one this year, too!
That fax with a number
on it. you mean
And?
What is the number this time?
It. it's not a number this time.
Let the foolish, cunning police know
that today at noon, at the 14th hour,
Let the foolish, cunning pelicesknow
that today at n on. at the 14th hour,
Let the foolish, cunning police know
that today at nOon, at the 14th hour,
I ¢t the foolish, cunning polic:Yknow
that today at noon, at the 14th hour
Let the foolish ..cunning police know
that today at noon, at the 14th hour,
I ¢t the foolish=cunning police know
t at today at noon, at the 14th hour,
Let the foolish. «cunning police know
that today at noon, at the 14th hour,
Let the foolish, cunning police know
we will bury the head
» our fellow knight,
and in his memory,
we will set off fireworks
If you want to stop it. come to us.
We prepared the 72nd
seat for you and we are ready.
What does it mean?
Hey!
Just where do you think you're going?
Where else? The knight of the round
table says there are 72 seats.
If it's round and has 72 seats,
its the big Ferns] wheel
in the Hairdo Shopping-Mall N\
Thanks for coming!
Gosh! We are too Mie
But it's thirty minutes to noon
pm the police.
What happened?
The control room suddenly blew up.
Wescanit stop the wheel
We-:d like to get the
people out of cars but...
Wed likelto get the
Where is the 72nd car right now?
What!
Oh, it's coming down soon.
J Id yg
The knight was not waiting for us
but there's something beneath the seat.
You don't say. a bomb?
Hey, Matsuda!
Let a pro handle work like this. \
Wait a second. Matsuda!
What does he mean by pro?
He was at the explosives disposal team
until last year. in the Security Task Force.
Then the pal he was talking about
that he said had passed away...
That's probably his
pal Hagiwara of the same team.
Killed on duty while he was disposing
a bomb, four years ago. on January 6th.
In that case.
There were two
bombs in separate places.
Matsuda disposed of one bomb.
But, Hagiwara didn't
have enough time.
The bomber has not yet been identified.
Matsuda requested
transfer to the special team
that is investigating on the bomber.
He kept requesting the transfer,
but was turned down.
Since they thought
he wanted to do things for his pal
they chose to transfer him, so he
could cool off. and sent him
to-our section...
Inspector. what shall we do?
It's six minutes to noon
- L€_
WW Lake the car/40 more minutes
to make a round and return.
It stopped. we have no choice,
but to leave it to Matsuda
It stopped.
Put-out-the-fire-quick.
We've got trouble.
Hello!
Matsuda? Are you alright?
Yeah...
but with the shock just
now. and odd switch was turned on
What?
The mercury lever.
Mercury lever?
A-slight shake can
make the mercury-drop roll.
And if the drop touches
the wire, that it.
If you don't want to see me blow up
keep the ferris wheel
still until I dispose of this bomb.
B-but. we have less than five
minutes:-untilthe blow up.
Three minutes would be more than
enough for this kind of device.
To the Brave Police officer, in praise
of your courage we will give you a prize
B-but, we have less
than five minutes until the blow-up.
A clue to another bigger
firework will be displayed
firework will be displayed...
A clue to another bigger
at 3 seconds before the explosion
With best wishes'
These are the words displayed
on the LCD panel right now.
I suppose if we stop the
bomb and turn off the power,
we will n ver be able
to read the clue again...
That is, the guy intended to put someone
into this car and show these words to him.
This ferris wheel and show
these words to him...
Then, that blow-up was turned on
because the guy saw you enter the car
In other words, the
bomber is somewhere close by...
It's very difficult tolidentify him»
out of this crowd &fpeople. but...
I can guess where
he set the other bomb.
The fax says,
the head of our fellow knight,
Those medieval knights wore helmets
designed with a cross in front.
Itislabvious now. isn't it?
A diagram sign of a hospital!
You guessed right.
I'll tell you which hospital
it is after I read the clue.
You-liOtell me after you read it. but the
clue comes up just 3 seconds before
Well. the battery is almost out. bye«now.
Matsuda! Matsuda!
Matsuda...
Allow me, for today, will you?
This is bad.
Tthere's only one minute left.
Everyt™ddy!
Get out of here!
Matsuda!
Don't, Sato!
It's too late.
But, but he's still there.
TOO dangerous.
Back off, please.
But he's still...
He's inside!
Cate
Sorry, Hagiwara,
I guess I couldn't keep my word...
What!
What are we going to do?
The fax says there's another bomb...
I already know that!
Beika Central Hospital...
What?
The other bomb is there!
Dispatch the bomb
disposal squad on the double.
RI Br
Dispatch the bomb
disposal squadzonithe double.
27 fr
Dispatch the bomb
disposal squad on the double.
He was like a puff of wind...
)&%%#v%
yesgat 27
He vanished in an instant
All he left behind is the sad sound...
Detective Satoh!
J FoF AX
Hello!
I didn't know such a thing
took.place three years ago.
If she still has lingering memories about
the incident, we don't have a chance
I suppose so...
If you want to be like him,
you can die on duty.
Hey! Don't say things like that.
Say! It's Satoh.
Oh! Takagi and Shirator:.
What's the matter?
Conan and the kids.
I just happened to run into them
Because I am grateful to them
for helping out in the case,
I'm going to get them
sweets or something.
All the cake we can eat.
And, what brings. ou here?
We sort of got a squeal...
We looked through inside this
restaurant. but nothing showed up
It'-s very likely to-be-a false-lead.
OK, then, I am gong to
karaoke with Yumi this evening,
would you guys care to join us?
S, Sure we do
Well, then, you go ahead. Takag:.
I'm not in the mood for singing today.
And I guess I'd rather not.
Hey, letss hurry up and go.
Yeah!
What kind of squeal was it?
Yeah. It was a phone call, a warning,
that a bomb is set up in this restaurant
MERIT
al! em [J
ER ITD
SOL MABCRBRIOMR Ur
AM AWVNMDR UV»
Today is January 6th 4
The same day as the bombingdYof
7 years ago and 3 years ago
So we came and checked.
A bomb threat warming. a false lead .
_F<B¥koD% AL FE Jr
Wik: DO
1-77
LEfiwfifii if
1-73
_REDISE JS
CREDIBE J
CREDA E JS
NO. he €
Shiratori!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKOSUWA
MA AHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Mus:
KATSUO ONO
Charact .r Designs By
MASATIOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KANJI*KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI_-KOUGHIT
JILINICHI MIYA_SITHTA
YUM'!!! HIUURI:
I SHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MA ATOMO SUDO
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJIBKODAMA
Produced By. >
TMSENTERTAINMENT, LTD
Inri1ssotciation with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
(9 I§HO AGYAMA / SHOGARU KAN YTV TAN
All Rights Re erved