Unsettled Police Department
12 Million Hostages
A.A bomb!
On the ceiling of this elevator?
A.Are you sure about that, Conan?
Yep! I saw-! bomb
that looks just like this one on TV!
I heard that.if it's just one
type of liquid it's okay,
but when it mixes with the other liquid
it turns into avery strong bomb!
Hen, wouldn't it-be.more the reason
to have the rescue squad come here?
I just said that the
mercury lever is set, didn't I?
It's most likely that the switch went on.
With the impact of the elevator
stopping just a while ago
The switch of the trigger device that
will go off with the slightest shake
So if you climb up to this roof
or if the rescue squad comes
down here with a
the minute they set
foot on the ground
and even if it shakes just a little bit...
it's BOOM!
Is ity that strong?
The mercury lever...
Mercury lever...
Just as I thought!
I'm sur hatgthe one who set this up is
the same bomber as three years ago!
Then, don't tell me that...
It can't be!
Then, why don't we have them lower
a rope from the elevator door above
and we both climb and escape...
I don't think
that will work either
What!
There's wire tap near the bomb...
I'm sure that the bomber is
near by us and listening
to our conversation from somewhere.
And the minute we leave here and he
stops hearing our conversation
he's planning to turn on the
switch and set the bomb off
Which means
we're trapped either way...
No. we still have cane way out
I disassemble this bomb!
I need them to lower the bomb
disposal tool from above though!
I repeat, all citizens
within the vicinity of Toto Tower,
please follow theflnstructionsé
of the police and evacuate to safely!
What!
Are we running away?
But Conan and
Officer Takagi Te still in there<
NO need to worry; because those two
are probably heading this way already
Officer Chiba, please take
the children to a safe place!
Okay!
The two are going to
dispose the bomb right?
What?
The bomb disposal squad is
not evensggoing into the tower
and are waitingifor communication,
so that's what it means. right?
They'll be okay!
The composition of the bomb is
virtually the same as the one
that was set up in Beika €huo
Hospital 3 years ago so
those two will somehow
work something out!
Yes. I guess so.
As long as they don't lend an ear to the
voice of the devil, like 3 years ago
Let it down slowly!
Easy now, easy
Okay! Okay!
Are you all right?
Okay. I got it!
Roger!
We've completed
giving the equipment!
Okay!
Okay, Officer Takagi,
Iet's start!
Y.Yes, sir
You fool!
Shape up and stop panicking
The one who's going to do the actual
work is the boy that is with you!
If you get flustered
you may make the boy
anxious and that may
call for careless/mistakes!
Yes, sir
Don't worry.
If you take it easy and follow our
instructions, it'll finish in no time at all
Calm down!
I understand!
Okay, first of all...
Let's start by removing the
photosensitive trigger device!
Yes, sir
We will turn off the elevator
Iights in a minute from now, so
put on the infrared night scope.
When it gets dark remove the
mercury lever's right side cover!
Be carefulnnotito touch
the mercury lever!
First we remove the cover, right
Right!
We'll turn off the lights now!
Did:you get that, Conan?
C,Conan?
Here it is!
The light sensitive tube!
If I cut the cord...
What a relief...
Conan, can you hear me?
Yep!
I can hear you, so keep on going!
Yeah...uh...let's see...
If you take off the cover you
can see a lot of machines. right?
Just above those machines
should see a device that moves when it
detects. light called a light sensitive tube.
First of all cut the cord that is
sticking out of the light sensitive tube
Then, I turnrtnis...
Electricity's flowing!
Watch. out, watch out
Okay, then, I'll place the plastic plate
in this space and use it as a stopper
Stopper?
Come to think of it...
That code "Getting a good stopper
IS not going to help.
That's what..it said...
Good stopper
probably means earned run average 3
But.-why a major leaguer?
This is Japan...
He could've just
written pro baseball player
Wait a sec!
Extended game. earned run average...
Turn over, Major Leaguer...
Don't: tell me that, the
other bomb is located at...
There's still a lot of time but...
unless I figure out where it is...
Now listen, Conan, when you're
finished 'what you're doing. next
Uh, Officer Takag:...
What is it. Conan...
I have something
I want to discuss with you
Hey. what. what's going on ?
Now it's the helicopters
of the TV stations!
I wonder if something's
happened after all...
Hey!
Oh, bummer!
We're having a test now!
Be quiet!
The time now is 11:40!
There is less than 20 minutes to go,
before the bomb is to go off!
The boy and the police
officer who are trapped
together with.thesbomb
havggnot'been rescued yet!
Time is definitely ticking away!
What will become
of the boy.and police officer
Will they perish
together with the symbol of Tokyo?
What! He can't cut the cord!
There are only three more left!
First the yellow cord to
switeh off the liquid crystal panel!
Next the white cord that is connected
to the mercury lever!
And the black telephone cord that is
set there for remote control manipulation
If you cut it in that order the
bomb will stop completely!
How come you can't.do that when
you've already gone that far!
Give me that!
Officer Takag!!
Just what are you doing?
Hurry!
Hurry and cut it!
N No, we can't cut it...
Just what are you talking about?
You've only got 10 minutes left
Gallant police officer...
I shall reward you for your courage...
I will tell you the place where the
great fireworks will
color the sky after the game
It will be displayed 3 seconds
before the bomb goes off
Good luck...
Conan says these are the words that
are displayed on the LCD panel
I would at least like to get
Conan to evacuate somehow, but
in order to specify the other
place where the bomb is set,
and to avoid a large
number of casualties
there seems to be no other
choice than for Conan to
Iook at t;e hint and for me.to
relay the location by phone
I'm sorry...
Officer Takagi
But, you understand,
don't you Officer Sato?
You fool...
4 minutes to go! There's 'only 4 more
minutes till the bombygeeés off!
The timer has not been stopped yet.
Mr. Bomber!
If you are watching this broadcast.
Please stop the timer, please!
If you have a tinge of
conscience left in you...
Heck with conscience
I#ll"still can't believe that it's
all working out so well...
Then. why don't you pick the
broadcast of the TV on radio
andalisten to our heroic story
The timer of the bomb is still moving
What?
Mr. Bomber, are you watching!
D.Don't tell me the
remote control didn't work right!
Let them be
We got the money already besides
1.I'm going to g
o tell the police how to
Hey!
I'm going to go tell them!
Hey. stop!
The police, those cops...
Took advantage
of his conscience and.
I feel sorry for the brat, but...
If the bomb goes off,
the police will be blamed for
not being able to save the kid.
If they go chicken and stop the bomb
before it explodesthey lose the hint
and a greater number of
casualties is inevitable
I'm going to, make
this publicito.the media
and colossal blunder of the police
will be exposed in broad daylight
Either way. you're finished
you dang police...
Oh, that code had such a meaning...
If you talk too loud,
the bomber will hear us
Yeah, but there are more than 400
places in Tokyo that fit into that category
Yep, it would be impossible to
check all the places from now
without the bomber noticing...
If we try to evacuate all the people
that are at the more than 400 locations
judging from the bomber's
character, he will probably
turn the switch on
using remote control...
In other words,
to definitely save everybody
we've no other choice
but to look at the hint
we've no other
choice but to look at the hint...
Just like Officer Matsuda did, right?
Yep and besides
the person that I don't
want to let die no matter what,
want to let die no matter what.
I'm sorry Officer Takagi
It's fine...
Hey, Conan
While you're at it,
tell me one more thing, will you
WwW. Who on earth are you?
Oh, if you want to know...
I'll tell you...
In the world beyond
The two have notrbeensrescued yet
There is only a minute left,
The seconds are ticking away!
Wait a second!
What's going on!
Conan and Officer Takagi are still inside!
Oh. well...
Seems that the members of the riot task
force has also been ordered to evacuate!
What!
Take the car back to Toto Tower!
Hey. it's dangerous. dangerous!
Take the car back!
Hey. Chiba!
Take it back!
They listened to it...
The same words of the devil,
as 3 years ago.
You guys, the Youth Detective Squad can
handle it. evenYif I'm not around. right?
C.Conan!
15 seconds to go...
Are you ready, Officer Takagi?
Yeah...
I wrote all your
deductions in the mail
All I have, left to do now is to punch in
the hintiyou're going to read and
send it out...
It's going to be coming out soon!
The first letter is...
The letter "E"
N No!
Get out of there...
get out of there!
Get out of there, Ran!
SShinichu?
Ran!
Takag!
Conan? Hurry. what's next!
WwW. What the. the slightest
shake will set the bomb off!
What the...
I was too scared to die af er all,
sO I cut the rest of the cord.
What!
I'm sorry...
Then, you stopped
partway through the hint...
Yep!
With only the letters EVIT,
we can't
tell where the other bomb is.
Well, it can't be helped...
Let's call the rescue squad
and have them come rescue us!
So. they went chicken after all...
The kid's the one who stopped
the bomb, but the people will think
the police made him stop it...
They'll think that the police sacrificed
the lives of a lot of people
just to save their own skin!
Please listen to the people cheer!
The bomb:has safely been stopped!
Moreover, the one who disassembled
the:bomb was boy who was
trapped in the elevator!
Let's ask the boy some questions then!
I'll bet you were scared. sonny?
Sfihiriichi?
But the police taught
me how to do it really well, so
I-had an-easy time taring it apart!
Officer Takagi
Officer Sato...
You fool!
Don't blame yourself
Two hours and a half left to go!
Let's go look for the other bomb!
Oh, but the thing is...
I'm glad you're okay!
I knew you'd do it. Conan!
Just as would-be
expected-of my following!
Well, you did right to stop the bomb
It's a silly thing to sacrifice your
Iife for people you don't even know
Yeah. I guess so
I'm sure that's
what th) bomber thought too {
finally only one more subject to go...
What's the matter. Ran?
You look depressed
The next subject is
your best sub™@ct, Japanese
I was just thinking that there sure are
a-lot.of cars going in and out today.
It's probably because they
kor yelling) Wh [ling ) foe) loko
into-the warehouse
of the gym in the basement!
It seems that the next ping-pong
tournament is going
to be held at our school
While they're atdit, they should
take the space-consuming
drum cans that are .inside the
warehouse with them too.
What are you talking about?
Don't you know?
[Because of those Sbig cans
it's so hard to take-out» the tennis net
so they couldn't find it after all...
Oh well, eveniif they were to find.itenow,
they wouldn't be able to evacuate
There's only 5 seconds left to go!
Four /
Three,
Zero
BOOM!
What!
WwW. Why?
Why isn't it exploding?
Dant, it ant be helped!
Dant. it an't be helped!
I'll have toset the
bomb off with remote control
I'm sorry to say
the guy you called
can't pick up th phone
The bomb disposal squad secretly went
into school quietly taking
care not to leave any voices on
the wiretap that you set up
and took apart all 5 of the bombs
that you set up in the drum cans
Oh, you look as if you're wondering
how we located the bombs?
We deciphered the code you sent of Toto
Tower and the time of bombing as follow
RE gp
I am a Major Leaguer, a
strong pitcher as well as batter
Here goes the beginning
of an extended game
No use getting ready a good stopper,
I'm winning in the end
The phrase Major Leaguer means to
change everything into English
A good stopper means, a pitcher
with good earned run average
Extended game in English is
called Extra inning game
the abbreviation of
earned run average is ERA
If you remove-the 'no-use words "ERA"
from the word EXTRA. you get XT!
XT is written vertically
and when it is turned over
it becomes the
Japanese Kanji character!
That's the map symbol
that stands for school!
And the hint that was displayed on the
LCD panel of the first bomb,
EVIT. is the English spelling of
DETECTIVE, that is,
a part of it, spelled reverse
If you reverse detective ~you get Teitan
The school with the name Teitan
has a grade school,
intermediate school,
high school and university,
the only school where a lot of students
gather during winter vacation is only
Teitan High School that is
holding national trial exams...
You didn't plant a fake bomb at
the baseball park is because
you wanted to
keep everyone's attention
away from the schools
with baseball grounds
Well, but I guess you took us
Iightly looking through your
binoculars from a A
conspicuous place like this,
keeping watch over
Teitan High School. You lose this time
Look out!
Oh no!
Officer Sato!
Dang it!
No:she can't!
Officer Sato.
WwW. Wait!
I.I'm not!
It's,one of those things that
occur frequently, I heard it in my head
a child's voice...
It, It told me to Kill the police
No. it told me to kill anybody
T:That why it's not my fault!
To think that he
was killed-by a guy like this
A guy like this!
To a guy like this!
Officcer Sato!
4 What do you think you're doing!
Don't stop me!
ING. Officer Sato!
Let-me go!
Let me go, I said!
To,think that he had to die for a
guy like that! So, let me go!
Just what do you
think you're doing. Officer Sato
Wasn't it you who always said
contribute to the nation and the citizens
with pride and'a sense off mission,
never to-¢ringe in fear and hate
and 'at all times to
respect the rights of people,
and perform our duties
as police officers wit justice
That's what you always said. right!
But: bit...
wag?
Acting the way you are now, I'm sure
that Office Wiatsuda will scold you
Stupid... Stupid. stupid...
I wantitosforget it!
Let me forget him!
You fool!
Ou shouldn't, forget him...
If it's a precious memory, /
you shouldn't forget it
Once a person dies, that person can
only live within one's memory
Officer Takagi...
Hey!
What was that gun shot just now?
Well um...
Hired one warning shot...
Don't-tell"me you
wounded/him or something
We did not kiss!
What?
Original Comic Books By.
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA,
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MasaTomd'Supo
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MASATO O SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
AISUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
IT AKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
wv Chief Director. ¢
KEN]? KbDA MA
Produced By
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DET CONAN
COSHO AN CIA, SHOT AKUKANTT IA IAS
All Riv his Reserved
But, it's really amazing
that you stopped it
You had less than 3
seconds to cut the cord, didn't you?
Well, I kind of figured it out
partway through the hint so
Besides. I couldn't
afford to let Officer Takagi die
But, you're really something, to
figure out that just by seeing
EVIT" it's the reverse of DETECTIVE
You can say that again!
Fool. of coursed figure it out
I've beenthoping
that it wouldn't be there
I've beenyhoping from the very
start that it wouldn't be there
Hey, Sato, we're going to visit
Shiratori at the hospital!
Oh, yes. I'm coming!
Bye-bye Officer Matsuda...
But...
But. I won't forget you!
Is Ms. Ooja that?
Ms. Ooja the number 1 nicest actress!
Does that mean we
can meet her in person?
It the real thing!
Move it!
Invisible Suspect
Marci