Suspense and deduction
closes the gap between
the love and hatred
between two people
Today. we're on the set of a drama
the members of the
cast are human too!
He sees through the
one and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Good evening everyone,
I am Detective Kogoro Mour.
The stage for today is
this remote western style building
A mystery entangled
with love and hate
The focal point of
this case is color
When people go shopping,
they tend to
unconsciously select
the color they like
even at the scene of a crime...
Let's meet again at
the end of the show
This was Kogoro Mourn.
Okay, cut!
Fantastic! Mr. Mourn,
you were just great!
Is that so?
Dad, you were really awesome!
Oh, yeah?
You could've cut out that wink
at the end of the scene, though...
YA AA
(RR)
Invisible Suspect
Part 1
Well, thank you so very much,
you were really a great help!
The big name actor who always
does the introductory remark
at the start of our show
caught a nasty cold
You don't have to use me just as a
pinch hitter, do feel
free to call on me anytime!
If itrs okay with you,
I. don't mind acting
in this -detective.-drams
as a special guest
or something either.
Oh, well, not really...
That's impossible, Mr. detective
Because, in this story
there are only 5 characters,
They are the widowed mistress,
her daughter the shrew, their
ecrepit butler and me...
Hey. what's with that shrew bit?
Come on, that's not nice.
I'm supposed to be a
character that slightly favors
- flashy things, that's
about all, isn't it?
The character turns out a shrewd
because you're the one playing the role!
What did you just say?
By the way, Kazami
I didn't like you remark, decrepit either.
I just turned 60. you know
I wasn't referring to your age.
I meant that your acting is decrepit.
What did you say?
I hear that you were a great actor
some time in the past. though
Now: now,
please calm down dad.
Let's not quarrel
just before shooting the film!
Mr. Kazami, please calm down
Ms. Ujo sure is late, though...
are you referring to that
Ms. Ujo who
used to be the number one
comforting actress, Ruri Ujo!
Uh, yes...
Y.You mean I get to see
Ms. Ujo in person?
What?
Get to see her in person?
She's the one who
named you to substitute to do
do the introductory
comment in the first place.
What!
I don't know if she's
some former healer type actress
I sure wouldn't want to be
healed by an old maid like her
My. the same to you
You're no more than a failure of
an idol kid, who smells like piss
Wow! You're really her!
Wow. you're even
prettier than on TV
Well, hello. hello.
How do you do?
I'm Kogoro Mouri.
I hear that you're the one who
named me to take: this job?
Oh, I don't think it's the
fist time we're meeting: is it?
Really?
Have we met somewhere before?
Oh comevyon! Doesn't this mole under
my lips remind you either?
Kogoro-chant!
M.Mole?
D...Doigaki...Ruri?
Bull's eye!
Rurippe?
Long time no see!
You can say that again!
We haven't seen each other
since junior high school!
It can't be...
They know each other?
Are you serious?
I had no idea whatsoever!
Your last name is different too.
Besides, back than you were wearing
glasses with super thick lens
Well? I turned out
to be pretty foxy, don't you think?
You did, you sure did.
But, why haven't
you gotten married yet?
Being as beautiful as you are, I'm sure
you got a lot of guys to pick from
Don't be silly!
It's because one-sidedly in love with
you all these years, why else?
Please stop joking with him, because
he's bound to take you seriously.
My. who is she?
Oh, she just some
girl who lives in the neighborhood
I am his daughter, Ran!
Oh. then she's Eris?
Do you know my mother?
Yes, I was with her all the way from
kindergarten to junior high school
But, it still is sure a mystery...
as to whyygEri, the smartest
girl in school and Kogoro-chan
the most mischievous boy fell so
IOvey dovey in love as they did...
and finally ended
up marrying each other
Very true...
Oh, you mean they were in love
with each other for that long?
H. Hey...
Yes! Eri who always kept her cool,
would really get upset and go all out
when her counterpart was Kogoro!
So, we all took it to be a lover's quarrel,
and they were constantly being teased
they're still quarreling to this day...
What a surprise though,
that the lewd Kogoro that I used
to know is now a renown detective
Okay, let's start camera
rehearsal for scene 134!
Ready. start!
The corpse in.front of the fireplace
IS covered with a gray tablecloth
And the victim's black coat is hanging
on over the chair of that table
Near the corpse. on the floor
Is the murder weapon, a golf
club with a white head cover on it
I guess we can say that
the case has already been solved...
Don't keep us in suspense,
spit it out!
Come on, tell us who it is!
Who on earth is the murderer?
I was actually supposed to
explain what went on but...
H.Hey
there's no such dialogue in the script 8
Tonight, Detective Mourn!
Let's have you solve the case!
First, tell us why the killer
covered the corpse with a tablecloth
T.That's probably because...
the Killer loved the vigtim...
that's why the killer didn't want
to leave the corpse just lying
there without doing
anything about it...
But, the coat was
, on the chair, you knows
Why would the killer go out of the way
to cover the corpse with the tablecloth
Oh. the reason is».
The gray tablecloth seemed to
be warmer than the black coat!
Hey: hey, don't tell me that you're
serious about what you Wst said.
Give me a break...
you were dropping hints in the
opening commentary yourself
Why does gray seem
warmer than black?
Really?
Don't you think so?
Your friend's not
all that great either, is he?
Dad. talk seriously!
Come on.
Get serious, Kogoro!
No way!
This is as far as this old man goes...
geez...
He's come out!
The Sleeping Kogoro!
Oh, excuse me.
Since the deduction was so simple.
I sort of felt like playing a bit of a prank
What?
It wasn't that the killer wanted to cover
the corpse with the gray tablecloth,
the killer didn't want: to cover the
corpse with the black coat
because the person, that is
the killer, likes the color black
It's most likely that the killer
sub-consciously thought that
using a favorite color at the scene
of the murder may bring on suspicion.
See, please take a
good look at the golf bag
that is left standing
against the fireplace!
Only the club with the black
head cover is sticking out, right?
This is because the killer was going
to use the-club with the black cover
as the murder weapon
but decided against it
while pulling it out.
This is evidence that the killer decided
to use the-white head cover instead.
Furthermore, taking into consideration
that the furniture in this room,
as well as the curtains are all
coordinated with the color black,
goes to show that
the owner of this house
that is. the killer is
wearing a black dress
Rurippe. ites the role you're playing
the mistress of this house!
don't you agree?
Wow, just as expected of
the Sleeping Kogoro!
He hit the bull's eye.
Just as rumor has it, you
didn't let us down, Kogoro!
I tell you, why didn't you start
off seriously to begin with
The real thing is
distinguished after all!
Corpses aren't supposed to move!
Dont move
Hey! Just what do
you think you're doing?
Are you okay. Nobuharu?
Kazumi?
So. after that playwright you're
switching over to that guy?
This was still supposed to
be off the records, right?
Hey you!
Enough is enough!
Are you we want
to talk to me like that old fart?
I Know about you secretly seeing a
young lover night after night, you know
What the?
I'm not really sure who
or where that lady is yet, but...
I sort of have an idea...
Yeah. I do have an idea...
Let me go!
What's with that look
on your faces, you guys!
I could make this program go down the
drain if you want it that way, you know?
What a bummer
I'm going to go take a snooze in the
room beyond until I feel more up to it,.
so go ahead and film the
scenes that I don't appear in.
What's with that guy...
He's the oldest son of the
owner of the newspaper agency.
That,is the main
sponsor for this program!
I see, that's why he knows so much of
what's going on behind the scenes
Yes, and to make things worse,
his obnoxious character
seems to be getting high
ratings among the viewers
To be honest, I really don't
want to act on a program where
he's the star of the show, but I
have no choice because my
office says I should,
since the ratifig is high
It doesn't bother me much. now that
I got to see you after so long, Kogoro
Okay, why don't we
take a 30 minute break
Okay. why dogs
we take a 30 minute break
Yes, sir.
What?
Fighting over sauce and shoyu?
You mean Mom and Dad?
Right, they got into a great battle
during home economics class
in elementary school over
whether sauce or shoyu
should be used on sunny side up!
Eri insisted«that sauce should be
used becausersunny side
up is a western.style dish,
but Kogoro insisted that the
Japanesesshould'use shoyu!
It puzzles me even more...
So. why'd they get married?
But, the order in which they ate whatgzr™
was made, was exactly the same,
«-) cw
so the entire class
burst out.laughing!
Next, they get into a fight saying,
Stop copying me!"
It's really hard to tell .~
whether they get along or not
Never mind about the past. already...
Ale please tell me more,
as much as you can!
Hey...
W.What is it?
Oeo00dO.
Xxx fF
Snow...
See, it's snowing...
Oh, they did say that it. may snow
today on the weather-forecast
Hey. why don't we all go
outside and watch the snow?
But, we've only got
5 minutes of break time left!
Who cares. if it's only 5 minutes!
It's the first snowfall
this year. you know!
1. guess so!
Come on, let'shurry!
I love It when
it. snows after all...
right, Conan!
What seems to be the matter?
I don't see Ruri around...
Where's Ruri?
I thought I came out
together with her...
RRurippe!
Rurippe!
K.Kogoro!
No good, his pupils
are completely dilated...
He's already dead...
Ran! Call the police! .
O. Okay!
B.But, who did it? Who could've done
something so-ruthless like this
Beats-me...
He was the type to
make enemies so
B.But, in cases like this...
isn't it the routine to suspect the
one who first found the body?
N No. I didn't do it.
When I came to this room,
he was already smeared with blood!
T's true!
Please believe me, Kogoro!
Yeah, I believe you...
We won't be
fooled by your crying and all!
Actress crying is one of her weapons!
Hey. hey, Kasumi
But, if things go as is. we may also
be suspected of homicide, you know?
Everything"ll be fine
We'll be okay
The victim is
Mr. YoshikiiKazami-age 28!
The cause of death is loss of blood
due toxdamage to the carotid artery!
He was probably attacked
while asleep on this sofa here
and slashed in the
throat or something
Estimated time of death is between 19:50
when the victim came here to take a
snooze to the time he was found dead
at 20:20, a period of 30 minutes!
I think it was shorter.
Because when we were
Iooking around this house and
and came into this room on the way,
he was snoring away and sleeping!
Hey. Conan!
That was just
around 20:00, right, Ran?
Y.Yes, because
Dad looked at his watch saying
that he was fast
asleep in 10 minutes...
It's Ran and Conan!
Which means that
Oh, Mr. Mouri!
So. you're here after all!
Thank you for looking after my
younger brother the other day!
Oh. no. that was really no big deal!
Kogoro, do you know him?
Yeah...
How do you do! I am Officer Yokomizo
from the Shizuoka Prefectural Police!
How [do you do! I am Officer Yokomizo
from the Shizuoka Rrefectural Police!
So. I've finally got
to meet you Mrs. Mourn!
Arm I wrong?
Well. I guess you're wrong,.
but then again maybe not
Wrong!
I'm only joking. it's a just a joke!
Wait a minute...
could you possibly be?
Don't tell, you're
Ruri Ujo, the actress?!
Y.Yes...
Wait a second, so are you, you and you!
What's going on here? Why are there so
many actors and actresses here
It's just as if you're shooting
a drama or something here.
That's 'what we're doing here...
so this is how it goes?
You were shooting a
detective story here at this
European style building out in the
boondocks of Mt. Fuji when,
a real homicide happened to occur!
So, this is indeed a
case of the biter being bitten...
Well. I guess so...
And? During the 20 minutes from 20:00
when the murder is thought
to havé been committed.
The shooting was stopped so
everyone could take a break,
and all you staff members stayed
in groups of more than two people,
so all of you have an alibi.
The ones without an alibi are
Ms. Ruri Ujo, who found the corpse
and each of the acters and
actresses who went back
back to their respective rooms to
check the dialogue in the script
That is. Ms Kasumi Namihara
Mr. Akira Nagumo
Mr. Nobuharu Nagumo
the four of you!
Then, Ms. Ujo, please
explain in detail h "W
things were when you-first
discovered the corpse
Yes, sir!
Since we decided to take
a break, Kogoro here
and everybody else including myself
went looking around inside the building
Then, we noticed that
it began to snow
SO. we invited the staff to come along
and went outside to look at the snow
Since the snow was so beautiful
I wanted Mr. Kazami to take a 10Ok
at it too, so I came over to this room
He was sulky after going, through
what he did during film shooting too
But. when I opened the. door...
He was lying on the floor
smeared with blood
I thought he was joking and
shook him, but he didn't answer.
That's when I finally realized that
he was dead and screamed
I see, you three heard her
scream and ran over here
Yeah...
That's right!
Okay. will you four go into the other
room and ge through a body check.
Fl- NW
We can't find it,
It isn't anywhere in this building...
the murder weapon,
the knife with a blade of
about 10 centimeters long
that slashed Mr Kazami's throat...
Inspector Yokomizo!
How about it?
Did you find the weapon?
Well, all four of them
had nothing like that on them
We also checked the staff just in case,
and the other rooms
from one end to the other but,
things that could've been used as
the murder weapon were
only the knife in the kitchen, a
small knife for cutting fruit,
and a cutter knife that was found
in the tool box of the staff
We found no luminol
reaction on anything either!
The victim had on him was this pack of
cigarettes. this lighter, and his wallet
We're searching inside
the drains and
around the building with
a metal detector
but wethaven't got any report that
anything was found yet
dang. and we've already found
the golf club and coat
Why can't we find the-murder weapon?
Moreover, the glove and the coat are
props that are used
when filming dramas,
but, it seems that nobody was in
the room ring break time
where these things
were during break time
Which means that anybody
could=ve taken it:with considerable ease
And? Where are
the four"suspects now?
Have them waiting in the room
together with Mr. Mouri.
If the killer is among them
it would be impossible to
get rid of the murder weapon
murder weapon by-taking it somewhere
far away in such a short time!
And yet, why?
VD &)
4d Sr
Why can't the murder
eapon be found!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
AN 1BrA
Background Music.
KATSUQO ONO
Character Designs By.
Story Editor.
Scripts By.
KANJI*KASHIWABARA
KAYUNRARI_KOUG.HI
JWNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
1OSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONQBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU 0 mm
Chief rector.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
S-ENTERTAINMENT: LTI
ny association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING.
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CC NAN
voLOW AOYAMA HOCAKUKAN YTV: IAS
All Rit 1'Reserved
Something's not right...
I can't figure out why Rui after seeing
the snow through the window
suddenly invites
everyone to go outside...
1. That brat!
Roaming around the
scene of the crime again!
Hey!
I see!
I ot it!
Invisible suspect
Part 2