Reduction flows withthe rhythm of the wind
Dark stains are rinsed clean and exposed
A real case at a Drama shoot
The murder weapon and suspect is nearby
A child in appearance
with the l.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Us? r1
oy €aO
Pops was asked to act as substitute for
doing the opening commentary
of a detective story.
He runs into a childhood
friend of his, Ruri Ujo
who turned into a big name actress.
However...
Kyaaaah!
Ru, Rurippe?!
K.Kogoro .
(#527)
Invisible Suspect Part 2
D.Damn...
Oh, so you smoke, Kogoro.
Eah. You don't smoke. Ruripj
Oh did you forget? About my father...
Oh. right he was famous in the
neighborhood as ene
that hated smokers...
Right! Thanks to him, yr
I hate cigarettes too...
Oh. the same here!
But in my case,
my mother hated cigarettes...
So. my father who was a heavy smoker
says that
he was forced to quit
as soon as I was born...
But. what if you have to
smoke in dramas?
I just hold the cigarette
n my mouth at times like that...
Right, right, we push the
director and producerito do it our way!
That's why you can never be
any greater than you father!
K.Kasumi...
Well, I guess for Ms. Somebody
who was selling herself
as an actress with soothingeffects. phoo
Cough!
It was geod thatnot smoking
gave off a healthy image.though...
Phooey...
K.Kasumi...
What's with her anyway...
She's jealous...
of me because
I'm talking intimately with him...
Chuckle, I think she's cute, don't you?
I see.
Just like the victim
Mr. Kazami was saying,
It seems that they're going with
each other
Which means that the lover
he is secretly going out with is...
Um. have you already figured out
who the killer is... Mr. Renown Detective?
N.No not yet...
Muuumlljlu 47
May I have a word with you...
Oh, sure...
Agh!
Conan, where are you going?
To the men's room!
Don't bother the police officers, okay!
Okay!
What is it...?
Just what are you up to?
Huh?
I'm asking you
why you're making passes at her!!
Oh...you mean?Rurippe?
I'm not making passes,
we're just childhood friends...
Are you sure that's all there 'is to it?
Huh
Is' that honestly true?
YY, Yes...
Okay then .4. If you do anything
funny, though,
I don't care if you're a-renown
detective or what, I won't forgive you...
Hey, hold it...l feel as if...
I've gone through
sometime in the past too...
If I'm not mistaken... it was...
Hey kid. what re you doing?!
But this toolbox was left here in
this room
together with the golf glove
and coat too, right?
That's why I figured maybe
there's something in here
besides a cutter knife that is
capable of slashing things!
Playing detective is okay,
but the police checked every
nook and cranny of this tool box.
Even this tape measure?
Yeah...
Hey. who is it? Who bamitted
in a crummy place like this?
Huh? What the "bamit mean?
It means to mark the floor with masking!
It's done to indicate
where the set is to be placed or
to determine the place
where the actor is to stand!
Well, I guess the shooting is
going to be called off...
But, I'll
remove this for now...
Wait!!
Something is
fishy about the masking tape...
It's a little bloated...
and something is stuck te the tip.
What is this?
A wire?
INNATE 2
I got it!I've figured
hat the murder*weapon is...
As well as why
we can't find it!!
The room where the coat
and the glove were is hear...
and the scene of the crime
Is diagonally beyond...
If from this room. the crime can
be carried out easily...
Al I need to figure out next, is who did this...
But, something bugs me...
about Ruri, who looks out the window
and invites everybody
to suddenly go outside and
Iook at the snow...
Huh? Agh, on no! Pops!!
T.That brat! Skittering around the scene
of the crime again!!
Hey!
Damnl!!
Where the hell is he?!
Heave, heave, heave...
I get it now!!
Huh? Where is Inspector Yokomizo?
He just stepped out a while ago...
I see . By the way, do you guys smoke?
Oh. okay...
I'd like to see the evidence once more.
So will youplease lend me a glove?
Y.Yes sir...by all means...
Uh- this is the wallet
and this is the cigarette...
The coat and the glove...
and this is...
the victim's lighter...
Shoots-it's out of oil"H
I've figured out the mystery!
All I have to do now is
put Pops to sleep with
this anesthetic-gun
Huh? -Huhp Huh?
Can't use the gun...
O Oh! I used it
at the filming site a while ago...
Bummers! What now?
I can't use Sleeping Kogoro!
I've got no choice, but
to drop a lot of hints at Pops...
U,Uh, Pops!
There are many things that I've noticed,
will you lend me an ear?
Maybe I can help solve the case...
Phooey; ll don't need
anything like that anymore...
Huh? B.But.
D.Don't tell me Pops...
already figured the case out...
M. Mr. Mouri!! I looked all over for you!!!
Just where were you'd!
Well,
I was going around this building
Iooking for a key to this case...
And? Did you find the anything?
Did you solve the mystery
of the vanished murder weapon?!
Well, what a found was not the key,
but just this kid alone...
Just as I thought...
OO. Oh.
We'll continue to look
for the murder weapon then
so if you come up with anything...
Okay. I'll let you know right away!
Yes. please do by all means!
Agh~~=Only if I could
use the anesthetic gun...
Huh?
Huh
HHS facial expression changed...
Maybe Rope's figured out
the Killer after all.
Rurippe... I'd like to talk
to you for a minute
N No. she's not the killer!!
Damn,
I guess I've no choice but
to hit Pops on the head
with something and pass him out...
Uh, something to kick...
I wonder if there's something I kick...
Agh!
Huh? They locked the door...
H.Hey,
I can't go inside if you lock the door!!
Y what's up, Kogoro?
Hy lock the door...
Don't tell me, Koggoro.
That you're going to seduce me?
Damn. I can't hear
what they're saying inside.
If I can at least get this wiretap inside
1° - 4-7
from the space beneath the door...
are you suspecting that I killed Mr. Kazama,
and going to try to persuade me
till I admit! committed the crime?
Yeah exactly...
I want you to confess on your own initiative.
Just as I thought!!
Pope's got it all wrong!!
I've go ate stop him. quick
I want you to confess
on your own initiative.
Just as I thought!
Pope's got it all wrong!!
I've got to step him. quick...
But, you're not the one
who's making the confession...
The one you're protecting
Mr. Nagumo is the one
who's confessing!!
Huh?
J.Just what are you
talking about, Kogoro?
Why would I have to
otect Mr Nagumo...
You saw, didn't you?
Just before seeing the snow
fall outside the window...
SS, See. what?
Back then,
the staff opened the door to the room
near the window and came out, right?
I'm sure you saw Mr. Nagumo
from the reflection on the glass door...
coming out from the room next door
where Mr. Kazami was taking a nap.
You saw the staff about to
come out of the room,
as well as the figure of the Killer
who rushed back into the room!!
¢ ¢ ob
You saw how acted and sensed
that he did something, so
you invited everybody to go
Iook at the snow outside
and tried to get everybody
away from the room
I realized just a while ago that's
what happened.
When I found Conan by the doorway
of the room of the sceneof the crime
just before I turned the corner...
Just as would be expected
of a renown detective,
I'd like to say but...
you haven't found the murder
weapon yet, have you?
The knife that slashed Mr. Kazami
who was taking a nap...
Isn't it more important to figure out
the mystery of the missing knife
that has a blade about 10 centimeters
before you go around
making assumptions
about me having witnessed the killer?
Yeah...
We were all too concerned about
the blade being 10 centimeters long
because it's hard to believe that
the blade is a small clump of steel,
NO more than two 2 centimeters...
Huh?
A cutter knife...
After the killer killed Mr. Kazama,
the blade was folded compactly away
and hidden...
inside this lighter
that Mr Kazami had!
WwW. Wow! Pops got it right!
B.But, Kogoro,
even if a blood smeared blade
were to be inside that lighter,
it makes no difference that the murder
weapon hasn't been found yet, does it?
A blade of 10 centimeters means that
the knife sunk that deeply into him, doesn't it?
Unless the blade is firmly attached to the handle,
it's impossible to poke
that deeply into something, and
I'm sure that blood would've splattered
on the handle too, right?
If so, a cutter with a handle
indicating luminol reaction
should've been found already!
Okay. Pops. slash back at her .
I guess so...
See?
Hey, hey
First of all, yourre going to have to
Iook for the handle of that cutter.
Oh boy...
Hey, Conan,
just what are you doing here?!
Oh, well...
right! Ran...
Do you have something sticky like gum?
Huh?
Sticky like gum...masking tape?
I have some gum that
Dad wanted me to bring along
to keep him from getting sleepy...
Il seell
Masking tape!!
If you wrap the handle of the
cutter from the end of the blade
connected to the handle with
masking tape*then blood won't
splatter onto the handle!!
After committing the murder the
masking tape was removed
after the blood was wiped off,
and the tape was probably pasted
onto the floor of
he filming site or something .
There were masking tape
pasted all over the floor as
indicators there, so it would be
very inconspicuous too...
B.But...
But, why would Mr. Nagumo do
something like that?
Even I, the first one to find the body
could've rigged the trick too!!
I could've used snow to
move everyone away,
and committed the murder myself!!
BD». Don't be ridiculous.
You could never kill somebody...
Damn. she sure is a tough one...
Sorry, Conan, it seems
that I left the gum in the car
Uh-um, Ran...
Huh
How do yon wear brassieres?
Wi at?
Iineverwsed them) so I donit
Know ho 7to us ) them!!!
Hey!! Boys don't have to
know Row to use them!!
1. guess so...
Rurippe...
you could never
have committed this crime...
WwW. Why not?
Okay then tell me!
How would you hide the blade
of a cutter. inside this lighter?
Il just put it inside the lid and...
There's nothing inside the lid.
T.Then your deduction
must've been wrong, Kogoro!
Maybe you're wrong about
Mr. Nagumo being the killer...
Rurippe...
In a lighter such asfthis,
you add oil to the cotton that is in here...
So. first you remove the bottom
and take out the cotton that is
inside and make space...
otherwise you cannot hide
the blade of the cutter...
Since I smoke. I realized
when the lighter didn't light.
That the cotton must've beenYFemoved...
But, since you don't like cigarettes and
have never used a lighter,
you would never even think of
hiding somethingin a place like this...
So. the only person that can
think of something like this.
As well as someone that you
would want to protect is...
Mr. Akira Nagumo. who used to
be a heavy smoker in the past...
T.That's:why I just said
a while ago, didn't I?!
Why would I have to
protect Mr. Nagumo?
WwW. Well, it's true that I've met
him sometimes at work,
but...I'm not all that intimate with him...
I wonder about that
He's your...
Lover, lover...
Because he's your real father?
Huh? Is that true?
Exhale-Nothing that was used
to commit the murder
murder seems to have been
prepared ahead of time.
It was probably something that
occurred on impulse...
As for the cotton with oil'on it,
he probably pasted masking
tape over it and hid it somewhere
on the floor of the filming site
but it would probably be easily
found if searched for...
Besides, after committing the murder,
it; would be impossible to
remove the cotton from the lighter
and putting the blades of the
cutter into it with gloved hands,
with the risk of somebody
walking in anytime...
So I'm sure that we'll be able to
find fingerprints somewhere...
So. before any evidence comes up...
persuade your father to turn himself in...
That's right, Kogoro...Akira
Nagumo is my real father
I was bern when my mother and he
used to be no-name
actors at an acting school...
My mother found out she was pregnant
only after she split with my
father and started going out
with my present father that you
know too. Kogoro
Fuh, fun...
It never even crossed my mind...
until we acted in a film together
and he mentioned that
I looked exactly like
his lover in the past...
After he heard of the truth from my mother,
I went to complain to him
because he called ask to see me...
I wasn't going to have him
saying that he was my father!
Then he broke down in tears before me...
So, I used to meet him now
and then from that time...
Fuh. fun...
A father is a father after all...
He killed Mr. Kazami for me...
if people found out that he's my
real father,
my whole family would turn out a mess...
That's why, you see that's why Kogoro...
I'd like you to keep this all inside you...
because after all.
We are childhood friends...
aren't we, Kogoro...Please...
No way...
Huh?
Being that you're the one asking me to do so
the more I can't accept the deal...
I don't want you,
my childhood friend to be bound
by suchza painful and sad lie
for the rest of your life...
uh...Just as expected of you, Kogoro.
You haven't changed at all,
your Kind heart...
Shut up...
Well, I guess it can't be helped...
because he was the one who
called you and told you
that he was my real father
from his side...
No...
Mr. Nagumo said nothing of
that sort back then.
Huh? Then, how did you know
that we were father and daughter...?
I figured 'it.-out from
how Re acted back then.
The hostility I felt from him back
then was not of a man who was upset
over another guy making
passes at his lover,
but rather similar to what I felt
when I went to introduce myself
to Eris father
In other words,
the feelings of a worried father...
Oh boy, so it's Eri after all...
I can never out beat her...
Uh, no...not her. I remembered
er stubborn father and...
Hey. do you know why I was studying so hard
wearing those thick lens
glasses during jr. high school?
Elt's because I wanted to
attract someone's attention...
I was under the mistaken impression that
you liked smart girls.
Huh
Huh?
Thirty minutes later...
through Ruri's persuasion
turned himself in...
The actual detective drama
that occurred came to an end
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers *
MICHIHIKOSUWA
Background Musi
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
JUNICHI MIYASHIT
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUQO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
. ro I Te ET >
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chic! Director.
KEN]! Kodnmq
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT: LTD
ny association with
YOMIURISTELECASTING.
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE Ct NAN
OH AOYAMA IIQFAKUKANYIV-IAM
All Ri} (Reserved
Oh. so you met Run...
She was more beautiful than
she looks on TV wasnstsshe??
Yes, did you know mother, that
shes Run Uo. the actress 7?
Yes, of course, because unlike him,
I attend the class reunions...
Right, I heard-a-lot about.you
two from Ms. 01ml"
About Dad and you getting into
a big fight over shoyu or sauce...
He got me angry because he
used to always pour sauce over
his sunny side up too, but just
because he was embarrassed to
Oh. I see. .Come to think of it,
Dad always pours sauce
over his sunny side up...
He's that kind of a pee-wee...
Then, why'd you marry him?
It's been, so long ago,
that I've already forgotten.
Which 'gloves do you think are better?
Let's see...l like the black...
I prefer this gray one...
Because it's the gray color of a mouse.
Doesn't it make you feel warm?
Huh?
It's because the gay tablecloth
I0ooked warmer than
the black coat...
odovoo t
O., did I say something funny?
No. you didn't...
Hey: 'whatisegoing on? Funny girl...
snore
Snore~~Snore~~~Snore
Eccentric man...
Is...
(BI%R)