Deduction flows with
the rhythm of the wind
Dark stains are rinsed
clean and ex rosed
LIC AVITQAVINATT AY STU
Something smells fishy
Let's figure it out during this case.
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with DeEctive Conan.
W Ta O
NC 4 - TT ua
7 «2 v
Us» Y;
2 » or 7
vr pr
Excuse me, Detective Mouri!
I'd like to ask you about-the
recent homicide case.
It is said that
Mr. Nagumo who was arrested
confessed that he committed the murder
because Nebuharu was being
bullied[by Mr. Kazami
If that's what he's saying. so it is...
All I did was expose the trick that
he used and advised him that
it would be wiser to turn himself in
before any evidence came up...
If you will excuse me then...
Ooh, Mr. Mourn!
Please wait! Just another word please.
Hmm==~~A man -says-few
but the message is: still there...
Ir sO cool!
Gyaha. ha. ha.
Ghads.
When he rarely solves the case without
goofing, he gets all carried away
Well, I guess I can't help
making Pops play detective
because I got to get information
on the men in black.
They sure don't show up...
Rewind, rewind...
They collect large sums of
cash by repeating assassinations
They force people like Ai to make drugs
and go) around gathering
competent computer programmers.
At...what the hell are they
Yes. this is the Mourn Detective Agency
Don't tell me that they're planning to
create an incredible game
using all that cash
Huh, a game?!
Huh'...
The whereabouts of a system engineer
who makes games is unknown...
ands ou'd like us to find him for you
Hey...tell him I'm not in!
I have to record the re-run
of Yoko-chews drama
cutting: all the.commercials you see!
Yes. now"ll be just final!
Dad's got a I t of free time today.
H. Hey
H. Hey.
Come on,
hurry-shave and fix your necktie!
Y,Yes...
The whereabouts of a game
system engineer Is unknown...
Pon't tell me that. ..It can't be...
<< Au
(BR)
The Remains of Voiceless Testimony
Eh AA
(BR)
Oh... so he's the system engineer
that disappeared about a week ago...
And? You say this is not the first time
he disappeared like this...
What do you mean?
Well, each time the deadline for
the game system that
he is ordered to.do-closes in...
he frequently disappears...
Wells we think it's the usual
this time too, but...
We can't afford to just wait with
our fingers in our mouths either...
0:4 \n
We asked the police to ask him
previously and he really bawled us out,
so this time we decided to
ask you instead!
Add \
Oh...
They don't seem to have anything
to do with the guys I'm looking for...
So, if you doe find him,
please contact me...
Hey, you gotta be kidding!
My place is dishing out the most cash!
Hey!
Our company's the one that first ordered
the system to him this time!
Ce You're not of the same compa
I'm Sugai. the one who ordered him
to make the system
for the igo software this time!
I'm Naito. and asked him
to make a chess software...
I asked him to make a shogi software...
My name's Soma.
But, is it possible for
one person to handle
making three different kinds of
game software at once?
That-s"why we want to find him
and complain!
That'things are not how we
thought they were!!
We all went to place our order
to him separately,
and this is what he told each of us...
I haven't signed a contract with
anyone this time so leave it to me.
When did you find out that he
was taking work
from all of you at the same time?
A week ago,
\ we all received this e-mail from him!
Ugh! Takipg'on three jobs at
the same'time sure is tiring...
Well, since my heart seems to
be-doingsprettyagooderecently...
I think I'll leave my office for a while and
- «takemmy time-working.ongmy-onders=vw-—
So. pleasexrberpatient untilslimafinishe
So, please be patient until I'm finishe
Huh. this man
I didn't notice because he was
wearing glasses in the picture but
Isn't he Mr. Taku Itakura, who is famous
for computer graphics?
Yes the wears contacts when
he appears in public...
Do you know him?
Yes. he is comes out a lot in the
credit of the movies!
Ever since his eyesight got bad
about 3 years ago. he left the
field of computer graphics and now
concentrates on developing systems...
If he's that famous, he could've
been kidnapped.
No way...
Rather...with that guy anything
IS possible...
About 2 years ago, I saw a guy with
a mustache at Mr-ltakura's office.
He was a big man with a Kansai accent...
Huhr¢
I'm sure you-ve seen him too.
He-was thererat:the Manten
announcement.event
T. Tequila!
Uh. what did the big man say?
Wore
What were they talking about
at the office?
I. don't know.
When I got there he was saying,
We-don't need you no more,"
and he was ready to leave.
Is't at all?! Isn't there more!!
Hey,. Conan, just what's the
matter with you?
Damn! I've no choice but to find
Mr. Itakura and ask him myself!
If I'mynet mistaken thatfbig man
supposedly died
in the.explosion back then! so I
donitithink he's involved.
The problem-is this picture. -
How shall we start:searching for him...
I think he's in a hotel or
something somewhere...
Hotel's refuse to give out
private information of their guests too...
Besides. he's probably using a
pseudonym anyway.
Ran. I want to eat sashimi, Tientsin food
and beef stew tonight!!
Hey. wait sec., that's Japanese, Chinese
and Western style food!
You can't even get that
combination of food
at a family restaurant that's got
most all kinds of food!
Which means if one customer
orders all three kinds by himself,
people"ll think he's a weird
customer, right?
A weird customer?
Come to think of«it.O
he has a Shogi board, anslgo
board and a Chess boardtin his room...
Have you heard what he took
with him from his work place?
I heard that he packed the
notebook type computer
that he always uses. and a few
discs in his bag and left...
He didn't take anything else
with him then?
What-is with this hotel?!
Huh?... Who may I ask are you? )
I'm the one-who borrowed the
Shogi. Chess and Igo game from you!
The phone of my room is
suddenly not working!
Im calling from my cell phone now, hurry
and. do something about it!!
We do not rent out things like
that in our hotel...
Oh, I'm sorry, I made a mistake...
Okay. next it's Hotel New Beika.
If a guest borrows asshogi,
chess, and igo board all by himself
and stays at the hotel for a eek
I'm sure the employees of the
hotel are talking about him...
I'm calling on my cell right now,
but hurry and do something, will you?!
Oh! You're Mmltakura of room
2004, aren't you?
R.Right! Room 2004!
9+ send somebody over to your
oom right away, sir...
<WO-Oh~~? The telephone cord
seems to have unhooked!
I'm so sorry!!
Hotel New Baker room 2004!!
Ghads, why are you guys
coming with me?!
You're nothing but trouble!
No big deal. Mr. Detective.
You just want to go back after
finishing your work
and eat dinner all by yourself, right?
Hey, its okay, isn't it detective?
If Mr. Itakura is found: we'll
treat you to a mean...
O.Oh well...
So this is his_.hide-out...
You're all. competitors in the
business, aren't you?
Why'd you all end up coming
here all together?
Because we found out that he took jobs
from all three of us at once...
All of us who are in charge of
the job we ordered to him decided that
we three should talk to him together...
And so, it dawned on me to ask
you to help us, Mr. Mour...
I was the-one, who suggested that
we ask a detective to help us!
No. I'm the one who
mentioned your name!
Idiot!; I'm the one who
contacted him by phone!!!
So, I'm the one who first
mentioned the idea. right?
So I'm the one who first
Ghads...
Ah, man, Yoko-chan's program is over.
My. wearing a cheap
wristwatch like that I'm sure you'll get
some snide remarks about it!
Huh?...
Mr. Itakura is really pic «
when it comes to watches...
Remember!
That's why we also...
Is your wristwatch genuine or what?
Hell with you! I just bought its
days ago. it's brand new!
I'll bet yours is fake?
Sigh
Oh, I'm sorry Mr. Naito, can you
push the 20th floor for me please?
Sure...
Ag Sings Saas
I'm sure that Mr. Itakura will be
surpr ed seeing us all here!
Y.Yep...
I wonder: if it is okay to head for
the hotel room just like that?...
Mr. Itakura is a man who is
somehow involved with Tequila,
a member of the organization...
I wonder if it's safe for Ran,
Pops and those people to go to his room?
Those last words that Tequila
said to Mr. Itakura,
You're of no use to us anymore.
In other words it could mean,
We refinished
finished with you, so we're
going to kill you
What if those guys are hiding near
here in order to get rind of Mr Itakura
Rather, they may already be in
NS 00, .+
Come on, idiot...what're you
getting all panicky for. cool head...
Tequila said so 2ears ag...
If they really meant to kill him, Mr. Itakura
would ve been killed long ago.
Besides, if Mr. Itakura is a
member of the organization,
he would never let
an outsider such as Mr. Soma,
enter the room while he is
talking to Tequila.
At any rate, we've got to meet
Mr. Itakura*and
get him to somehow tell us
what's going on...
I've got to find out
why Tequila came to his office...
Strange? He's got this "Don't Disturb
sign anging'on ee o0oran. ye...
He probably went out
to eat or something.
Let's wait in right in front of here, then...
Thank you so much for the trouble.
It's an automatic locking door,
SO please make sure
take your key along with you
Yes. I will...
Excuse me, bell boy!
Uh, could you open my uncle's room too?
Huh?...
It seems he forgot that we were
coming and went out.
But...
Hurry! Or. I'm going to leak-1!
I gotta go. I gotta go
I'm really sorry. thank you...
You're pretty sharp. sonny!
Because, if Mr. Itakura comes back
and sees us all in
front of the door of his room,
he might run away, right?
But, sonny...it.seems
we didn't have to do so...
It seems that Mr. Itakura
has just dozed off...
Of all things I tell you
Hey, get up! Hey!
You can't get away, Mr. Itakura... Huh?
What the?!
Mr. Ntakuga! Mr. Itakura?!
No good 4.He's been dead
for more than a day...
What?! It can't be?
I'll go call the police!
Why...
Probably a heart attack...
Pills are scattered all over the desk.
He probably had a sudden
heart attack and tried to drink medicine,
but couldn't, and died
I tell you...it's because
he goes into hiding.
No! Mr. Itakura didn't dig;of @n illness!
He was killed by someone!
But, why?!
Why did all clues of
those guys vanish just like that
7 pr 4
Darn!
What's this? A diary?
Mr Itakura's diary
If so. maybe theress something in it
About what Tequila
came to visit Mr. Itakura for
and what the men in black are trying to do
Maybe looking through this will
give us an idea
Hey!
Whaaa!
Don't you dare touch the
belongings of a dead person!
I tell you... The minute I
take my eyes off of you...
Darn!
I can't do a thing about it after all.
I guess I'll have to let him know what's
going on in order to look inside the diary...
About the fact that Mr. Itakura didn't
die a natural death by heart attack.
But was made to look
that way by someone...
'a- xe poss! 11 yo 1a someone
being one of the three here is very likely!
The victim is M raku Iitakura. age 45...
A system engineer of games...
a system engineer of games...
And. the cause of his death isy
A can't say anythin \decisive but
there are no visible external injunies.
Judging from the fact that he was taking
doses of a coronary enlargement drug,
it is likely that he had a heart attack...
He's probably been
death for about 2 days...
Inspector!
We got- a hold of Mr. ltakura's doctor!
And?
Mr. Itakura's.heart-seems to have been In
very bad shape, and he was scheduled to
undergo surgery as soon as he completed
the work he had taken on this;time!
Her «Which means, 4
this case 1S Not one thates to
be handled by you...
Yes, it sure looks to be that way...
Ha. ha, ha...
But, if he's been dead for two days, why
didn't any of the hot?! personnel realize it?
He used to hate people
coming into his working place...
Right, right! Just the other day
he was fuming about the fact
that the papers on his desk
had been moved 10 centimeters...
And, he rarely changes the
sheets he uses at home either,
so I'm sure he refused
ta have his bed made...
Who are those three people?
They are employees of the companies
that ordered jobs to Mr Itakura!
They came to ask me to search
for Mr. Itakura who
disappeared a week ago...
And- you found him all right,
but-he was dead...?
Yes...but it's no wonder that
he ended up this way. being
that he confined himself in a hotel,
neglecting his health...»-
I see...
I think this man favors tidiness.
Because when we came into this room.
This man was sitting on the chair with his
face pushed down on the desk,
and yet there are
no marks left on the desk!
Marks?
The marks of his saliva!
If somebody drools as much as he does,
it would usually
dirty the desk too. wouldn't it?
I'm sure the -man wiped it!
Fool! Why would a man who is
suffering from a-heart attack
SURO Nom - oak fg vd
wipe the desk before drinking his medicine!
Then. who wiped the desk?
I wonder who can it be?
Besides! This is the first time that I heard
that the victim was found,
with his face down on the desk!
Oh well, he slid to the floor
when he was shook...
If so, then it's strange.
The back of the victim's hand
If the hand of the victim
Ww i0se ace was. ¢c own on edc es
was found stiff in this position,
his hand would've had to be stuck between
the desk and his body all this time
But. there are ne such traces left.
Don't tell me that Mr. Itakura
died somewhere else
But, Inspector!
The hands and feet of the corpse
Is completely stiff in this manner!
If so. it would be
impossible unless someone
tied Mr. Itakura onto
the chair deliberately
Oh...
I see... so Mr Itakura was
probably made to sit in the chair
tied up with his hands on his chest,
and was unable to take his medicine
unless somebody helped him drink it...
Then, don't tell me that this is...
Yeah... this is in a case within the
range of our profession...
homicide...
But, if so there should be marks
of him Yaving been tied up.
How about it. coroner!
There are no such clear traces but.it
seems that exterior pressure had been
applied to a wide area over his body,
from the many visible traces of
blood congestion.
Just what does that mean?
Wow~~~this blanket is soft and warn!
C.Conan!Stop that!
But. what's this? It's got sticky
stuff on here and there!
00 of
II get it! It's the blanket!!
The blanket?!
The killer probably wrapped Mr.
Itakura's body with the blanket,
made him sit in the chair and then
wrapped his body up with masking tape!
A-pillow or something was
probably placed in
between his lap and chest, to
make. him lean against the desk.
I see. if so. there would be no traces!
Which means that the legs of this table
that are fixed in place is what
held his chair in place.
Although it:looks as if
they removed it once...
A little of the adhesive of the
masking tape can still be detected.
In other words. the killer left Mr. Itakura
in that position until
he died of a heart attack.
Then after postmortem rigidity
spread throughout his body.
They came back again to remove
the masking tape and blanket.
That is, they made it look like he
died of an illness!!
Okay!
Ask the hotel employees
if they saw any suspicious looking people
during the last three days!
Yes. sirll
A hotel...
Well, the thing is, I called this hotel
making believe that
that I was Mr Itakura in order to
hunt down this room...
I told them that I was the one
who borrowed
the Shogi. Chess and Igo games...
And complained to them
saying that my telephone broke down,
so to hurry and do something about it!...
dingy gs Eg
Anatinats Now I gotitne
room number to this room.
I heard"them laughing on the
other side of the line after that...
Saying. .."Not again.
Which rjeans that semebody else
could've done the same thing
to find out where he was too then?!
Well, but I wonder if there would
be anyone
who have the same sort of brains
that I, Kogoro Mouri has...
Inspector! We found anether
suspicious person
who pretended to be Mr. Itakura saying
that the phone of his room broke down!
Oh. so there was someone else...
When the employee went te check
the room later, Mr. Itakura yelled at him
and chased him away saying.
Didn't call you!
I guess it would be safe to say
that the killer is the one
who made the phone call.
But, how did you know that
Mr Itakura borrowed the Shogi,
Chess and Igo game from the hotel?
From 'his mail
I saw the mail with the image attachment
that Mr. ltakura sent ta the three of 015m.
That is, Mr. Itakura sitting in front
of aShogié Chess and lgo board.
I see in other words.
All three of you could've used
the same method
that Mr. Mouri used to come here...
No way!
It can't be!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MIGHIHIKO SUWA
MASAFITO YOSHIOKA
Background Musi
KATSUQ ONO
Character Designs By
MAKATOMO sum)
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Sariplts By.
KAN]! KASHIPWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHIITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
AZUNARI KOUC!
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
CHI HIG
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU GKADA
Chiel Director.
KEN] KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
In association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CC NAN
u LUHYM AOYAM \] II()(.AK(JKAN'YIV-I-AM
All Ri Reserved
It seems that Mrltakura had
been writing a diary
On a daily basis from 5 years ago...
Which means...it's there, the info
IS there!
Information on the day two years ago
equila visited him is... ir
4!...This can't be...
Yes...Mr. Itakura had written information
indicating who the killer is.
That is. his dying message...
The Remains-of Voiceless Testimony
Part