Deduction flows withthe rhythm of the wind
Dark stains are rinsed clean and exposed
An unnatural victim's final
moments reveal a message
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
- - We. -
. 2 - W
) BRB
<< «2 »
no» I
OW To
0 oY!
est gn
Fs FF £5
€'u<
on op ~~ Ts
Pops takes on the job of searching for the
whereabouts of a game system engineer
whose whereabouts became unknown...
But, while listening to their story
I found out that
Mr. Itakura once had contact with
the Black Organization!
We somehow located the hotel where
r. a ura was I(- mg. an<- wen \ere.
But it turned out that
he was already dead!
I see...Mr Itakura was most likely
made to sit in a chair and tied
with both arms at his chest.
Therefore, it was deliberately set up
so that he couldn't drink the
medicine he was supposed to drink...
Then, don't tell me that this is...
Yeah...the specialty of our profession...
O.Oh no...
The Remains-of Voiceless Testimony
Part 2
(137)
The Remains of Voiceless Testimony
Part 2
(1378)
H.Hey. why do we have to be suspected?
We the ones who asked Kogoro Mouri to
Iook for Mr. Itakura, you know!
What stupid killer would come
back to the scene of a crime
and bring a detective along!
I guess so...
If you insist on suspecting us
why don't you show evidence!
Evidence that we came here!!
Okay, the time's now!
If so, why don't you look at the
diary in the bag?
That's his, isn't it?
Maybe we can find out who came
to visit him before we got here!
It's truefthat diary is written on it but...
Officer Takagi, how do you look at this?
It can easily be viewed with the
Iap top computer on the desk.
But, if I were the killer, I would've gotten
rid of something like that long time ago...
This is it...
a Ura seems oO nave YRC a clary
everyday since 5-years ago...
Which means...It's in there, I'm sure!
The day two years ago when Tequila
came to see him should be there!
Here it is! This is his most recent diary!
DY £7
Three days ago, eh!
ND £9
tows
The hotel employee said
something strange today.
Maybe one of the three found
out what room he's in?
Oh well, all we've got to do is
change hotels then.
You three are suspicious after all...
Isn't there a continuation to that diary?
No, there's none.
Then, then, I'll go put it back
where it was.
OO. Oh. okay...
All right!
Huh
We'll pass it on to the forensic officers
just to be on the safe side.
I agree.
Shoots!
If the police take it with them, I
won't ever get to see it again!!
I've got to find the killer among
the three as soon a possible and
prove that the diary has nothing
to do with the murder...
Cool head...I'm sure that
something-is been overlooked...
That is, the clue to who the killer is...
Excuse me, Inspector.
What is it?
About the right ankle of the corpse...
Traces of his socks are left as
seen by congested blood on his
Ieft leg, but, see...no traces are
Ieft on his right leg...
On the other hand, on his right ankle,
there are traces of what look to
be scratch marks that seem to have been
made by the toe nail of his left feet...
Which means that Mr. Itakura tried to
take the socks off from his right leg...
But why
was he tied up in a place like this,
and why did he take off his socks .
I see, he did so to leave this behind...
No doubt about it!
That person's the killer!
Moreover, if I use this 10 my advantage,
I can even get a hold ofuthe diary too...
Okay, coroner...
Take care of the autopsy, okay.
Yes,
Officer Takagi, go and give the diary of
the victim to the forensic officer.
3, Sc
The point in question is the one who ordered
Mr Itakura to make the game software
and found Mr. Itakura's corpse .
The three of you who're all
employees of the same game company...
We're not from the same company!
We're all from different companies!
I am Sugai who asked him to
make an Igo software!
I'm Naito who asked him to
make a Chess software...
I'm Souma! I ordered a Shogi Software!
Please let us go already. We
just happened to be brought here
to this room by Mr. Mouri who
Iocated where Mr. Itakura was...
Inspector, what about me?
I.--:-We know now that Mr. Ita
had been killed by someone,
but we don't have all the
evidence to specify the killer
I would like the Mouri group
and all of you
to come over to the station
at a later date...
Oh great! I was concerned
about whether the drama
that I've been recording was
being recorded right...
So. I guess I'll do as you say for
now and...
No, I can't afford to leave just like that.
Oh, no, I mean, well... who was that?
I'm saying that we can't let the
suspects leave this place!
Aheen!
Because the killer is rejoicing
with both arms open
in front of our very eyes,
TN TN
thinking, how lucky that
Inspector Megure is a klutz!!
W What!!
H.,Hey, Dad!
How rude!
Shape up, mister!
Saying all you did Mr. Mouri, I
hope you know...
who killed Mr. Itakura!!
Yes...Mr. Itakura himself told me...
Huh?
Hey, hey, don't tell me that you
heard the voice of the corpse .
His ankle
Huh
You saw it too, didn't you, Inspector?
Only the Mr. Itakura's right ankle had
no traces of socks being worn...
That's because the killer who came back
to this room after Mr. Itakura died,
thought that just one foot
wearing a sock would look unnatural
and put it back on him...
Why did Mr. Itakura have to be
barefooted...?
Why 2!
T's because unless he is
barefooted he couldn't grab
a certain thing or order of something...
Grab. .grab what. ?
Don't tell me...
Yes...Mr Itakura used the time he had
till his heart medicine wore out
and wrote the following on his right leg...
A dying message that
indicates who the killer is!!
1, This is his dying message!
What on earth is written? It looks nothing
more than an incomplete game of igo...
Okay, then, please help me Inspector,
so that I can explain it
simply and clearly...
Officer Takagi! Please give the
disc with the diary inside and
the unopened disc that was in
Mr Itakura's bag to the Inspector!
Oh, yes sir!
When you receivejthem, please sit at
the desk where the lap top computer is.
Hmm.
B.But what does this have to do
with the dying message?
I'll explain later... Will you please
boot up the computer first of all...
B Boot up ™?...
BB... Boot... up...
Boot...up...
Boot..up...
Bufiootmup...
In, Inspector to boot means to
start the computer.
Ha, ha, ha, only joking, just a joke...
Next, move the data of the diary
onto the desk top, and
put that into the empty disc
Open it... "Move it...and put it in...
Oh, so all you.have to do is copy the/data
of the di into the empty disc!
Like so...
Hey, Mr. Mouri, don't tell me that
you're doing this to make fun of
me not being digital minded...
And then finally, please turn the
computer off.
Phooey, that, even I can do...
Hmm?
What's the matter?
Oh, that's...
Don't help him Officer Takagi.
Agh .
Ugh! These electronic goods, I tell you...
You do this, and they all switch off!
You shouldn't pull the plug out
abruptly like that!!
Doing so may.destroy the data
within the computer or cause damage!
But, it didn't switch off even if I
pushed the switch...
For safety reasons it's made so
that you have to push the button
for a while before the computer
switches off.
Right...
That is a prohibited strategy that
computer users should not do...
And words like "boot" and open
are terms that are incomprehensible
unless the person uses the
computer on a daily basis...
You've already figured out what's
written on that Igo board, haven't.you...?
Do you understand?
Huh
Isn't there something strange
about this Igo stone?
Huh?
What's strange about it?
Because when playing Igo
if you surround you opponent's
stone, you've got to take it,
and to leave a stone surrounded
IS prohibited strategy!
P.Prohibited strategy?!
There is some meaning to this
Igo stone after all...
But, what could it be...
Okay, while everyone iJaistracted
with their attention on the Igo stone,
I'll take out the disc
with the copy of the diary...
What are you doing, Conan?
RR. Ran...
Hey, didn't you hide something just now?
II didn't hide anything...
What are you doing then?
1.1 though they sort of looked like
Igo stones
The strange patterns on the seals
that are pasted onto the keyboard
Huh
Patterns? Isn't this Braille?
Come to think of it, Mr. Itakura's vision,
just like me was getting pretty bad,
so he told me he was learning Braille.
Braille...
I get it! So this is what Mr. Mouri
was referring to when he said,
words that only people who know can
understand." This Braille here...
What do you think?
N.No...There is no form of Braille
that looks like this .
Oh, but if you ignore the white
stones it's readable...
The killer is...
Souma...
The evidence is the watch...
MM. Mr. Souma...
No!...Are you the killer?
Y how come it turns out like
Maybe somebody's trying to
frame me or something
No, you're the killer!
The reason is because you don't
know about Igo nor Braille!
Therefore, the killer is the one
who still has conclusive evidence
on him, that's you, Mr. Souma...
W,Wait a minute. Mr. Mourn...
Please don't talk so fast and explain
things in order as you usually do.
The reason why he's the killer and
the evidence that shows he is...
Don't rush things...Cool head...
The copy of the diary is already
In my hands .
Cool head...Cool head...
Whew
Right! When Mr. Itakura left this dying
message
this is probably what he thought...
That the killer would return
to this room for sure
after he died in order to undo the
masking tape that is wrapped up in!...
That's why he used this code that
Mr. Souma wouldn't be able to
read or even suspect...
And besides, if his corpse is found,
you three would be questioned
by the police and
it is certain that you will be shown
the picture of&this Igo Board!!
He figured that Mr. Naito whose
vision is bad enough to have to
trace the Braille in the elevator,
would read the Braille code
and that Mr. Sugai who asked
him to make the Igo software
would! think the prohibited
strategy strange,
and that he would realize that
this is some kind of code.
1.0 see.
And the watch which is the evidence is.
The watch"that Mr. Souma still
has on him
Mr. Itakura disappeared and confined
himself to this room a week ago
Mr. Itakura is really finic « when
it comes to watches
and has bad vision...
When you first came into this room,
I'm sure Mr. Itakura naturally
took it and looked at it!
The wristwatch that is your pride
and joy!!
I see! If his fingerprints are on the
wristwatch that would be evidence!
Yeah... Mr Itakura who has
turned corpse
and meets his killer again after a week,
could not have touched Mr. Souma's
watch that was bought 5 days ago...
Okay; Mr. Soma, could we have
the forensic officers
check your wristwatch then?
Yeah, go on and check it.
I'm sure that his prints will be
found all over the place.
I put a sleeping drug into his wine while
he was absorbed in this wristwatch,
put him to sleep and wrapped
him tightly with masking tape .
20 years ago, when he was a
no-name game creator and
I was a green-horn that just
entered the game company,
we were shogi pals who used to
o to play shogi together.
We used to talk a lot while
rinking together...
And we talked of making
a shogi software
that would outdo the masters of shogi
when we became big shots
But three days ago. when I finally
found where he was,
he said to me as
I walked into his room.
How many times do you think we should
allow a person to call wait?
Oh boy,
what a laugh, don't you think?
I collected cash from the master
play games
and kept sending it to him for 20 years.
And all I had to go on were his
words, "The time is ripe.
I went into a great amount of
debt investing in him too.
And yet, he has the nerve to say,
wait to a real master of shogi software
that was supposed to have been
completed...
I told him I was going to get some wine
to energize him and left the room.
I bought some sleeping drug and
masking tape along with the wine.
I didn't refuse your offer to make
Kogoro Mouri search for him
because I wanted to avoid being
suspected even slightly later.
After all, I used to talk stink about
Itakura at the company a lot
because he wouldn't get to
making the shogi software
but became famous as a
computer graphics designer
But, 20 years was much too
Iong a wait for both of us...
Being apart changes people...
Their hearts, their dreams...everything...
If I can call wait to life,
I'd like to go back to 20 years ago...
To the time... when we both held
the same dream...
Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO_SU WA
MA AHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music=
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWACGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chic f Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD.
In 1$sSocration with
YOMIURI TELECASTIN(
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN"
COMO VOY AM AP ASAHOGARURAN YTV TMS
All Ric hi Reserved
See you, Ran...
I still have some things to talk over
with this:groggy father of yours here
so if. you're going home hail a
cab or something and...
No. because:it only takes about
30 minutes to walk home from here...
Bye-bye, Inspector!
I have it...it's right here...
In my pocket, the clue to the
Men in Black!!
Now all I have to do is go over to Doc's
house and check this disk thoroughly...
Conan?
I wonder if people change...
If they're apart... will their
elings change...
It's kind of tough
to just keep on waiting...
You don't have to worry about Shinichi!
I think he's just the way you
picture him to be, Ran!
So. I don't think you have to
worry about him at all...
It would really be nice if you
were Shinichi, Conan...
How stupid of me, what on
earth am I talking about...
Ran... that's not it...
I...Actually, I really...
No!! Don't tell her!...
Not until I disclose their identity...
until I crush them...
I can't tell anybody about me!!
Y.You're...
(2 HR)