(3 BFR)
Although it can be a bit risky
Huh
No, we've still got another way out of this
and make it out the back door
camouflage. ourselves in the blizzard
I guess we've got no other choice but to
Hurry up and answer me!
I know you're there at that villa!
Hey! Answer me!
All RIM Reserved
CO AOYAMA HOCAKUKANYIV- IMS
DETECTIVE CC NAN
CORPORATION
YOMIURI TELECASTING
nr association with
TMSSENTERTAINMENT, [TD
Pfodurcd By. >
KEN}! KODAMA',
Chicf Director.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Editor.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Recording Director.
TAKAHISA OWAGA
HIRONQGBU HORIKOSHI
TAKASHI NOMURA
Directors Of Photography
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Art Director
TAKASHI HYODO
AKIO KAWAMURA
ATSUSHI AONO
HARUO OOGAWARA
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
MASATOMO SUDO
Animation Directors.
TOSHIKI INOUE
CHI HIG
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
\{ > » Co a
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
Scripts By
TOSHIKI INOUE
YUIAHT HIGURE
JWUNICHI MIYATA
NARI KOU
KANJI*KASHIWABARA
Scripts By.
Story Editor.
MASATOMO SUDO
Character Designs By.
KAISUO ONO,
Background Music.
Vista. Yaw aK A
V (SE THYT 3 &9TIWA
Producers
GOSHO AOYAMA
Original Comic Books By
Can't you hear me! Hey!
What's going on?!
Hurry up and answer me=Mr. Itakura
Shinichiu...
I know you're at that villa!!
Hey! Answer me!!
Escape? We're trapped!!
Hey, hey, if so, how are we going to
What?
Aware that they were
without Mr. Itakura being
were watching this villa
Yeah, or maybe they
failed to open the e-mail!
They found out. They found out that we
You're there, aren't you?
Vodka
Hey, what's up?
Please record your message after the tone.
To the phone right now
I can't come
Shinichi
happened to Mr. Itakura-and come here!!
What now? They may think that something
using this computer.
Found out that the mail failed to be opened
Yeah:--Not only that, maybe they even
the mail wasn't opened...
So, don't tell me that they found out
opened immediately, it would disappear!
Darn, It was set so that if it wasn't
The mail disappeared...
Darn
Hey it's counting down really fast!
Password?!
Okay. if I open this...
Here it is! The mail!
Show:your-dirty rat selves!
Come on, you guys in black!
'Yeah...
SShinichi... it's almost time.
Without having to see them
sO he gets-to sever all ties with them
and the check,
and find the software
Iook for Mr. Itakura
they'll eventually come here to
they are about to send here,
And as for the e-mail that
in a place like this
would be left so carelessly
the software that they wanted
Because they wouldn't think that
that very reason!
He left it here just for
But, how dangerous...
I, II see...
whenever they wanted to
so that his friends could come in
was hidden somewhere
Which means that the key
5 years called: me from my villa.
A friend that! haven't seen in
Remember it was written in the diary?
It was hidden behind those stairs
Where did you get that key?!
Huh
make it inside...
So, now how do we
hew... we've finally arriv
Whew... we've finally arrived
what the hell is the punishment?!
What is the punishment,
by force. they will be punished
If people try to bend things out of line
the stream of time...
People cannot go against
Don't rush things...
Making-zombies, that's ridiculous
Ha, ha... no way
Al was trying to make was...
don't tell me that the drug
hey. VoL...
What does it mean anyway:...?
Against the stream of-time."
since we are trying to raise the dead
God and the Devil,
We can be both of
Yeah
are the last words in the diary
The thing that bothers 'me though.
The jewelry robber who is on the run
but all they're broadcasting is about
the radio all this time,
I've been listening to
That's still okay too
on TV or radio
has already been aired
about Mr. Itakura being killed
The problem is. whether the news
down the drain
they'll be throwing everything
the software is completed
If they upset him before
That's true...
had been moved 5 centimeters
he is bothered that the pen on his desk
with a character who'is so jittery that
They would never break a promise
not to snoop around him anymore!
Mr. Itakura made them promise
We'll be fine!
In 'ambush or something...
What if they're waiting
Will it be okay though?
His acquaintances and so forth
his house, villa, the addresses of
that Mr. Itakura could be hiding like,
He was asking the man for places
Iook for Mr. Itakura
that came to ask him to
the game company
Pops asked the man from
that Mr. ltakurars villa is in Gunma
It's amazing how you found out
at midnight!!
They're going to be sending
the e-mail that
Then, weire going to receive
system software in question
and get a hold of that
Mr Itakuraes villa right now
We're going to
What else?
And, so what now?
Um going to go to bed
Sounds silly...
@h. that-s some value!!!
An ad balloon
it can become as large as
gas that's puts in,
Depending on the amount of
However:lit is very elastic!!
On...
for 10 seconds
it can only maintain its form
it leaves. the belt
air leak-once
Because, of the nature of rubber
Because of the nature of rubber
No. maybe just one or two...
of-culprits with this!!
I'd be able to catch a load
WwW. Wow!!
There! One soccer ball to go!!!
Andypush the button
But whén you adjust<the dial
No it doesn't...
on first glance...
It looks like any ordinary belt
Fire a ball anywhere belt!!
This is called...
Yeah!!! Ha. ha, ha...
My newiinvientions!! Right?
He tame to try out
Oh, me? I was. uh
doing here. Shinichi?
And? What are you
of weste :n novels: you see
I Mm hooked eon this internet series
Y.Yeah, exactly!!
Where a witch-or something appears?
Some kind of fantasy story
Are you reading
What is that?
AAI?!
Against the stream of time
we're trying to raise the dead
Since
We can be both of God and the Devil
W., What?!
Against the stream of time
Singe we're trying to raise the dead
the dead
Since we
God and
We can b
TATE
ZO OJ
HE JI
We can be both of God and the Devil
We can b
She laughed and replied in English
Just who the hell do you think you are?
so I taunted her saying,
tone of voice of the woman
I couldn't stand the overbearing
Yes...
won't leave my ears
who first answered-the-phone
The queer words of that woman
do with that software?
A2 "ha IE ™ oo nis.
gm NICHES HOLD
LDHLiRSIEHD JT k
TD ILE ZINE
February 10th
JF ssh BE ruin a
Hg JNIZCE=sadl 7 HOE
LHL IEIHD JZ
TTIVEZ AND
%%;%%mHmbfin¢
finczic L£w§@
LOL lEHD JT bk
TTIVEBEZANL
BE NICHE ITREHD
LH ULiRulEHD JZ
TTIVEZ AND
TTIVEBZANG
Huh
even after the last day!
There"seems to beinvisible writing
Hmm?
Escape abroad before seeing that e-mail
I guess Mr. Itakura was planning to
arriving 3 hours from new at 09:00
which means the e-mail should be
is four days age,
The date on this diary
abroad by then...
I'll try to somehow make it
Iater at midnight
should be arriving 5 days
handed over.to them
where the software will be
to the time and place of
The e-mail with instructions as
and escape abroad
to me near the computer of my villa
the check of the payment they made
the unfinished software and
I have decided to hide
the deadlife is drawing ne
February 9th,
FE .For the sake of mankKi a!
but for the sake of mankind...
because my vision started weakening,
that software not only
I abandoned making
cant do it after all .
December 22nd. nO good...
around me anymore .
And that they stop snooping
into my account in advance
they deposit the payment
under the condition that
I decided to accept the offer
contacting me changed to e-mail
February 13th, their way of
EDRF EX
IVICEDD
EDRRBH ER
that previously came to see me
A=JVICE DOT
EDORRH ED
that previously came to see me
the same group as the big man
I guess she's a member of
if I could finish making it in a year
that I was developing at a high price
that she wanted to the buy the software
Her request was,
as if she were a queen.
A stuck up woman who talked
a woman answered the phone
To my surprise,
and call them instead
I decided not to notify the police
on what to do for a while,
January 23rd, although I was deliberating
Tell no one or you're dead.
It probably means .
Written with blood
The red words were probably
phone number was written
Along with a mysterious
OK was written in red...
there was a memo from the intruder
wan \
In place of the message I inserted,
earlier {tan expected
January 8th, I-got an-answer
go along with their demand.
I wrote that I would y
to the intruder in the desk...
I inserted a*message addressed
free myself from this terror,
January#6th, in order to
I'll probably be killed one day
Ifirthis keeps up
December 19th, I'm pooped...
July 6th, Who is it?! Show yourself!!
Surveillance cameras. but to ne avail...
I changed the locks and set up hidden
June 11th.
Or anything being taken...
there were no traces of a break in
I guess it couldn't be helped because
The police won't take it seri TSly...
\ into my house this time...
April 15th, somebody has snuck
into myghouse this time...
April 15thsomabody, hasssnuek
sneaking) into myaoffice after all
It seems that domeorte's been
has been moved another 5.centimeters...
March 17th, the pen of my.desk
has been moved another 5 centimeters...
March 17th, the pen of my desk
(XX JEN NHDSE Zp
has been moved another 5 centimeters...
March 17th, the pen of my desk
(XX JDSENHSE EPRI
BBL TWD
has been moved another 5 centimeters...
March 17th, the pen of my desk
(XZ JED E EPA
has been moved another 5 centimeters...
March 17th, the pen of my desk
(x JED EF PRI
has been moved another 5 centimeters...
March 17th, the pen of my desk
3 )HEMIMRT Pil
has been moved another 5 centimeters...
March 17th, the pen of my desk
(at J finvfié? PEI
has been moved another 5 centimeters...
March 17th, the pen of my desk
(1 J flnvbiii PEI
has been moved another 5 centimeters...
March 17th, the pen of my desk
(3 SEND RIEPR
VJ" \
has been moved another 5 centimeters...
March 17th, the pen of my desk
\3 HOHE PR
It goes on to say,
3 JED BEEPRI
BL TLS
It goes on to say,
3 JED BIEPRI
writing 10 days after the big man came
It seems that he's started using invisible
Doctor?
I finished taking a bath
Doctor
them O see itl!
Yeah, I'm sure he didn't want
the somebody is...
SS. Shinichi. don't tell me that
somebody snuck a look at his diary
Probably as camouflage just in case
Probably as e¢amouflage just in case
Song OR ASE OAR eh titre Clty
Probably as camouflage just in case
Om Koh LK 1 ook ext ks ely)
NTLEIDHDD
74 -~ g >
somebody snuck a look at his diary
Probably as camouflage just in case
NTLEIDS
H KkJIAFDFHZD
SO DOC Sid) a look eft he's Ay
Probably as camouflage just in case
2 TL FE Do HOhhB
OEZTTRIWWDMILI
HEN: Ja HOOF
somebody snuck a look at his diary
Probably asycamouflage just in case
LL TL FEO
DEX TIIWDDILIZ
Win J HDF [EDT
SSIMEPSHYES HUE KES SS KE HUE NE I 315),
Probably asycamoufliage just in case
NTLEODDD
DEX TIED NIL
Bk Jil_HADFHREDTS
SNTLERIDD
something like this to his own diary?
But, why would Mr. Itak ra do
the internet website...
what is written on things like
when people want to hide
It's a method that's frequently used
Invisible writing"!
[ <21 Co.
«if thisskeeps up.
NTLEOIMD
DFE FE TI(IUND NILE
+HAT
5 , PL - Y 8 and, o J
OF T= a
éinflfi Fwwkfiéwr
NTLESIHLD
DE EX TIED DILIR
T.This is?!
Then. highlight it...
and drag the mouse along
RTS LLY
SREEDITTRM
Watch. okay?
A¥ssLW
SMES EDITS
Watch, okay?
Huh
are not disorganized...
The space between the pages
Wrong: doc.
10 centimeters out of place...
Even if his papers were moved
Mr. Itakura would get upset
he said back then, that
Come to think of it...
not placing everything in'order...
If it were me, I wouldn't be able to stand
of the book is disorganized
the written and unwritten pages
Because look, the space between
Huh?
Some unreliable character
This Itakura guy sure must've been
and that they wanted it
some kind of software,
Mr. Itakura was do veloping
The only thing I found out was that
to get a hold of this diary...
And*I-went through all thé trouble
in the diary in the days following either
written about the big man
There seems to be nothing mere
Hmm#
Roy Woy, te dks We
I never want to see him again...
from head to toe
This man was dressed in black
I gave up the development. he left.
Dv -RoeEneartibnd
WAN Ww WINE RE WN ob of Ve Ca A
SHRPDLAT LT MN
PART & 7.
SAICTOEE ro»
I gave up the development: he left
IOIV-=RTHOBRBLTOND
LWREBCLTHMREWSLAEENDE
SHMRPD SN ATLIT MIN
SS AISHDIZTED DI,
I gave up the development: he left
IT -MELNWMBEATHND
LATBCLTHRNREGSLAERDE
SMRBOV ATL II +
RAN ROE ENO
I gave up the development, he left.
IV-METOBMALTHND
LAER LTRREBRS LEAD LE
SHRPOIAFL IT MM
ROALDOIZEMOR
Car. RIMIRBDL.
my vision had gone bad and
as soon as he found out that
IV-MLTHOBREXTHNAD
Rf-Ii
:v ON EAN I I EY Your 72 « 0
kfi 1
SANRPDLATL JT BIS
IN PANIIT & IT
Bo AIKHRDE EMS.
re, BARM<7
my vision had gone bad and
as soon as he found out that
IF -MTHBWMAntFTHNnd
AR 7X 53
LEBEB< LTRRSEHELAZAd LE
SRNRPDL AFL IT bE
SAKROIEE MoM
x. BIIRWM<7
my vision had gone bad and
dd S001 do lie 10Ulta oul ial
IO --MINBMAsToNd
LTRREHSLN
MRPORAFLIT NI
SAICROIEEMO NM
ao JBL]
my vision had gone bad and
Ss Soon as he found out tha
THREES I
SHARP ARTF I IT BIO
SAICROIEE D>
rs. MIMS
my vision had gone bad and
as soon as he found out that
tomes ison
CLTHRERILALE
SMRPDATL IT BIS
MUShT87
SAICROIEEDO™
BRIM <
which was under development:but
I¥-MToEmenrizbnd
MM. LB.
REE LTRARETELALND LE
SMARPODRATALIT BIS
Hon Ter
ES AICTE
RE (Xi < /
which was under development. but
IT -MtoBVMEFITOND
Er QC WANE € RIN IR Lr 7
5 RBOIRATFLIT BI
RR TE
SAICHODIEE MO.
MITE 7
which was under development but
ST-MZoWVMERAITONS
MRPOD AFL IT ID
MITE ™
SACRED
we lath SU
which was under develo hymen! but
IX MIowdBanttond
<< 53.
LTHRReETSELM
WRBPOLATFL ITN
RR TE&7™~
SAICHMDIZE Mo ™
Bim< 7
VERA LIRR ORE YT
seems that he was after
\ & [IV -
BRPD ATL IT BIS
MATE
SAICHRDIIE Ho
BIZW< 7
a system software
Itrseems that he'was after
BERALTMREGE LELAND LE
MRPD ATL IZ MI
RTE.
ALCBDIT EMH
wit. IIXM< 3%
a system software
It seems that-he was after
RRRPDODLAFL II
ms TeEr
SAICHMDIEE Po
AH. MIM BDL.
SI--MTOBREsrlFTHND
MAREBLTRREGETLLEAND LE
MRPD ATL) MD
Rote
SAICHRDIIE MOM
<Bo7., BIIMS ZBL
suddenly came to see me .
March 7th, a man with a Kansai dialect
There! This is wt!
Two years ago.
Uh. 2 years ago
while-'she's:not around!
So I've gotito check things out
it may cause heraneedless worry,
NG. Al findssout,
are-youShinithi?
You<sre«not pulling my leg.
Clues to those guys?!
What? You got hold of
Oh, come on...
to take a peek?
Don't tell me that you're going
That's just.great.
Hey, Shinichi, what do you mean,
That's just great.
Al's taking a bath right now...
By the way. where's Al?
about running out of batteries...
SO-you won't have to worry
ar'Other pair of pursuit glasses,
While I was at it, I also made you
I've invented something new again!!
It's been a while, but
Oh. Shinichi! Great timing!
As well as of who they are!!!
What they're after .
And get a hold of...
from corner to corner
I'm going to check it out
of the men in black!!
One of the members
who, 2 years ago. met Tequila,
The diary of Mr. Itakura
now is the diary that's inside this disc
More important than Hidekazu Aka
I tell you, he's so childish...
Playing games again?
At his plae tonight...
so I'm .goin to sleep over
I would play a game with him,
I promised Doc that
Hmm?
Conan?...
Huh?
But.choose only one of the dishes.okay...
Or.beef stew?
Sashimi? Tenshin rice?
What would you like to eat for dinner?
Hey.Conan
Don't tell me that his true identity is...
Shuichi Akai...
If he were deeply involved with Au...
who killed the street slasher...
If he were the one
Ai reacted the street slasheer...
during the James kidnap case,
And besides...
they would never goof like that...
If the F.B.l. had that area covered.
Making it looks as if he killed himself
Somebody killed that street slasher
really belongs to the F B.17...
But, I wonder if he .
Oh.okay...
Come on.let's go home. Conan!
He's gone...He's disappeared!!
Be doing here in Japan...?
What would the FB...
It can't be!?
wearing a jacket with the charaters F.B.l on it
Because he was together with a person
Huh. why'?
But. don't think he's anyone suspicious...
the street slasher was hiding!!
Inside that building where
Iong silver dyed hair and an unshaven face
and asked me if I saw a Japanese with
When he came walking along...
in front of dilapidated building
I was waiting for Shinichi
Huh
New York with Shinichi
Yes...ll met him when I went to
Do you know that man?
Huh?
Hey. Ran
Stupid girl?
But used to ry in preivate...
A stupid girl who pretended to be composed
of a girl who resembled you...
you sort of reminded me
It's just that...
Huh
Huh?
Does it bother you?
Always?
You're always crying .
Again?
Huh?
So, you're crying again...
(Negotiation Edition)
Contact with the Black Organization
You're...
I can't tell you about me, no matter what!
Until I crush them to pieces...
Until I find out who those guys are...
Noll Donsit tell her!
I...the truth is I...
Ran...It's not that.
Just what am I saying
How stupid of me...
I wish you were Shinichi, Conan...
That's why you don't have to worry at all...
He's just as you think he is!
Shinichi's okay!
It's kind of tough...to just wait around
Ther hearts of people, if they stay apart
I wonder ifipeople change
Hey. Conan?
And check the dis from corner to corner...
Now all I have to do is go to doc's house
The clue the men in black!!
Right here in my pocket.
I have it... I have it for sure
to Ow
7 -> ~Y
- - 7 es wm .
» (79
> % O)
with Detective Conan.
No case is left unsolved
with the I.Q. of an adult
A child in appearance
He sees through the one and only truth,
diary with the professor
We've deciphered the
We've uncovered their secret
Dark stains are rinsed clean and expobed
the rhythm of the~wind
Deduction:flows: with