Deduction flows with
the rhythm of the wind
Deduétionsflows with
the rhythm of the Wind
Dark stains are rinsed
clean and exposed
The Black Organization
and -Yjewel robbery
The case moves on and
the truth gets closer
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the 1.Q- of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
> be O
am Lore av - Dd AN O
NN Ye
3 =< 10
5» <3
Dr. Agasaandsl got a hint of coming
in contact with the.Black*Organization
from the diary of Mr. ltakura
who had been killed
DEEXTIEILD NILE
NTLEINDD
from thetdiary of Mr. Itakura
who had been killed
a I] -—
DEE TIED MILZ
NTLEOMND
Bx HAH OFHFEOT
on - -
DEX TIIWWD MILK
NTLEODND
Therefore... € came over to
a MI FRET Fm = or
Therefore. we came over to
Mr. Itakura's villa.
Then...
Hey. what's up?
Vodka!!
You're there, aren't you?
They've found out!
They've found out that
we failed to open the e-mail at this villa!
Yeah...
Hey. answer me!!
I know you're there at the villa!!
Shinichi?
Hurry up and answer me,
will you, Mr. Itakura!!
Hey!!
( 33$)
Contact with the Black Organization
(Pursuit Edition)
Hey. answer me!
I Know you're there at the villa!
Hurry up and answer me, Mr. Itakura!!
I guess we've got no choice
but to hide ourselves in the blizzard
and make it out the back door...
Oh, sorry...
It's so dark in here that I was having
trouble picking up the phone...
Hey. hey, hey?!
It seems that the electrical circuit
went out because of this blizzard...
I couldn't open the mail
because of this too...
Phooey...
That's what you get for trying to receive
mail in a mountain villa like that...
Hey. wait a minute!
How come your answer phone's working
despite the black out?!
Yeah, well black outs are frequent in
this area because it snows a lot...
That's why I'm using a phone
equipped with a built-in battery.
Oh, I see...
It's amazing how...
you found out I was here...
Ha, ha. ha...
We know all about you...
Huh
Don't tell me you were keeping watch
over this villa, were you?
Don't worry, we weren't
Just as promised
we're nowhere near you
More importantly,
did you finish the system software?
Yeah, somehow...
Is there anyone with you?!
Hey, answer me!
What as that sound just now?
Sound?
The wind...
The sound of the wind
tapping on the window.
Oh...
That's right,
I SS SNOWING Yeaviy over ere 00...
So. I can't use the computer...
I hate to say this,
but won't you give me the info directly...
The time and place of where
I should hand this software over to you...
Phooey...
No choice...
I'll say it just. once, so listen well
You know that station that's under
construction called Kenbashi, don't you?
The fashionable station that's going
to be added to the Toto Subway Line...
Tomorrow morning at midnight...
Come and wait in front of coin
Iocker number 0032
Iocated on the basement floor
of the station...
Don't forget to bring the
system software, got that...
No...tomorrow s a bad day...
What?!
I'm going~to have to be:hospitalized
from this evening for a health check...
You know about it, don't you?
About my bad heart condition
Don't tell me that you're
trying to buy-time
because you still haven't
completed that software?
No... it's completed all right...
Then, when is it convenient for you?
After I'm discharged from the hospital,
so about three to four days later...
No. give me five days...
You idiot!
We can't wait that long!
Extend your hospitalization!!
I finally got an appointment
with a famous heart surgeon,
so I can't move the date...
If I were to hand it over to you
before I enter the hospital,.
It has to be today
but the construction people
will be there at daybreak
It's not convenient for
you guys then, is it?
At 4:00 then...
Four hours from now at 4.00 a.m...
Bring the software to the place *
I just gave you info on
Four hours from now?
From Gunma to Tokyo?!
What's the problem?
If it's completed you should be able to
bring it with you, shouldn't you?
Okay. ..four hours from now,
I'll take it there
Huh?
But, don't ambush me...
If I spot any of your people
this entire deal if off
Even if you were to force
this software away from me
keep in mind that doing so may throw
the method of using this software
into the pits of darkness forever...
Phooey...
You're sure a cautious fellow,
just like rumor has it.
Okay. four hours from now!
In front of locker number 0032
at the basement of Kenbashi Station.
Don't be late...
Yeah...
All right. I got them!!
Hey. just what do you intend to do?
Don't tell me that you're going to listen
to them and take that software over?
I'm not listening-to them...
I lead the conversation so that
the hand over time of the software
would be rushed to 4:00 this morning,
by sounding flustered!
What?!
The news of Mr. Itakura's death may
be aired when morning comes. right?
If they find out.
Then this deal as well as clues about
them will go down the drain...
Now. the jewelry robber who is at large...
Fortunately. it seems that none of the
stations are covering news
about his case yet
Which means, this is what you
intended to do to begin with?
Yeah...
I was planning to tell them to rush
the hand over time to an earlier time,
when I receive the e-mail from them...
Let's erase all traces of
us having been here
and get out of here with
your beetle. Doc!
Out of here...
They maybe watching us from
somewhere around this villa, right?
If we carelessly go out just like that
to the car that's parked outside,
they may spot us...
Don't worry!
If Vodka or any of his
people were around
they would've easily seen through my lie
about the electrical circuits going out,
sO that I cant use the computer...
I see. that's why you turned
on the lights to this villa?
Yah...
We know at the least that
none of his people are at a distance
where they can see the lights of the villa!
If"!
They probably tracked this place.
Using some alarm system
that would warn them
and specify the computer of the one
they re sending the mail to.
Just in case the mail that they sent isn't
opened by the receiver of the mail
Either way
part of the members of
the their group will be arrested...
I'll confirm the contents of this software
with the lap top computer in the beetle,
and if it's some outrageous
software that could
be used for a hideous
crime or something...
You're going to report it to the police
and specify the place of the deal.
So they can ambush the culprits
and arrest whoever shows up!
Yeah...
Damn! No good!
You need to enter a password
for this software too!!
Just like the e-mail a password's been
set between Mr. Itakura and those guys
Then, just make a copy of it for now...
I can't do that either
It's protected with a copy guard.
Under this condition,
the police won't move!!
Aren't they always secretly
armed with guns?
If you report that there will be
a deal involving guns,
maybe at least two or three
officers will come...
We don't even know how many
those guys have on their side.
So. with 2 only a small
number on our side,
we're more likely to be
biting off our own heads...
Unless we find out what their purpose is
and present evidence to the police
as to how dangerous they are,
as well as how large
their organization is,
and have the police come
equipped with sufficient men,
it'll be difficult to lay our hands on them
Hmm...how frustrating...
We know that they're coming
and yet we can't do a thing about it...
Not really. there's still a way...
Huh
It's a bit dangerous. though...
Hey. hey, don't tell me that
you're planning to meet them directly...
Hey. Doc. don't tell me that...
Yeah, you're most probably right...
It's a flat: after all...
We've got to call a nearby service station
and have them bring us over a spare tire
Is it going to work?
I don't think there's any service station
that'll come at this time of night!
Well. we may as well relax
and wait in the car then!
We won't make it in time for
meeting those guys if we do that!
I'm sure that this is God's
way of telling you
to keep from taking dangerous
action, Shinichi!
Dang!
Hmm
A...car?!
Hey! Hey!
What's up?
Oh. well. uh, we got a flat...
We want to go back to Tokyo.
But won't you give us a lift?
Tokyo?
Yoh. what do you say?
Why not?
We're going in that direction anyway...
Gramps,
are you familiar with the
roads around here?
Well, yes, sort of...
Okay. gramps. you get in the front seat
and the kid in the back seat...
Thanks...
I'm sorry to intrude on you
when you were sleeping. miss...
It's okay. I was just kind of dozing...
Wow, cool!
This is a foreign car, isn't it?!
Um. is this car yours. sir?
Yeah...
I've gotten tired of it and was just thinking
of getting myself another car though!
You must be rich,
because this car is really expensive!
Sort of...
Although he may not look it,
he's the heir to a big company, you know.
Oops...
That sure was close...
Snowy roads are dangerous after all...
Well, let's not rush and drive safely!
Hey...
Didn't you hear something
funny just now?
Yeah?
I didn't hear anything...
The stuff that we have in
the trunk probably moved...
It's nothing to sweat about...
Hey, don't smoke!!
Did you forget that 1 hate cigarettes?!
Oh, sorry... that's right...
Oh, to go to Tokyo turn left there...
Oops...
It's stopped snowing so I guess
we can get there before 03:00
But why were you guys in Gunma?
Were you skiing with your grandson?
I guess you could say so...
Sounds great...
Hey! Watch where you're going!!
Sorry, sorry...
I shouldn't have driven in
the snow after all...
Strange...
There's something fishy about them...
Don't tell me that...
Don't tell me that, they're...
Oops.
Whew...
What's with you anyway?!
How many times do you think
you got honked at already?!
Didn't I tell you that
I'm not good at driving on snowy roads?
You're right!
This car needs a tune up
and hasn't got its safety check yet,
SO you've got to drive more carefully!
Huh
You're going to get a safety check
for this car soon, aren't you?
Yeah...
I guess so...
You don't remember?
The number 2 is written on
the sticker on the windshield!
That's the inspection'cértificate
and depending on the number
and the color of the.sticker'it tells you
when yousre_supposed to be getting
your next=safety check. rigt?
The color is this year's color.
So it's obvious that you have to get
your safety check by February this year...
Oh, that's right I remember now!!
Come to think of it.
I got a postcard saying for me to go
get my safety check within this month...
But. sonny. when did you see it?
The sticker was covered with snow...
See.
I saw it when the on-coming
car passed us.
When the headlights shined on it
the number outside could be
seen transparent from the back...
Huh
Oh, I see!
I thought it was "2" because
I saw it transparent from behind
but it was actually "5"!
But. t hat's strange...
You got a postcard saying that
you had to go get a safety check
within the month of February. right?
I wonder why...
Oh, well,
you see, that's...
Didn't] just tell you a while ago sonny.
That he's a Richie Rich!
That's why he leaves all the details
up to others to do it for him...
He answered you casually
but the thing is,
he's not even bothered about
the date of the safety check
Oh...
you've got to turn right over there,
or we won't make it to Tokyo...
Huh
I tell you
I mean the kid keeps blabbing on so...
I'm sorry...
He's such a curious child...
Well. I guess it can't be helped...
Okay...there...
By the way sonny...
what are you listening to?
Oh. this?
I'm listening to the news!
News?
Yep!
There are all kinds of news!
About economy picking up and
the new coach of Big Osaka...
Or about the jewelry robber
who is on the run!
you're still so little,
yet you like news...
Yep!
And? Was the robber caught?
Nope...
They're still escaping
somewhere in the Gunma area!
But. I'm sure they'll be arrested soon!
Because see.
They seem to have checkpoints here
there and everywhere like over there.
License please...
Yeah...
Excuse me, but where did
you come from?
Uh, well...
Agh, Officer Yamamura!!
Huh
You're, if I remember correctly, Conan
Uh, Officer Yamamura
this Is a checkpoint to arrest
the jewelry shop robbers, right?
Yeah...
There are group of three
wearing baseball caps!
After robbing a jewelry shop in Gunma
they abandoned the car they made their
getaway with in the
mountains and vanished...
But one of the three is hurt,
so I don't think they got too far away yet.
Hurt?
Ri ht!
When we got the report,
I just happened to be nearby
doing some questioning
When I got to the scene of the crime
I happened to run into the robbers
who fled out of the shop!
So I pulled out my gun and said.
Freeze. freeze. or I'll shoot!!
Wow, cool!
But the robbers refused to stop.
So I fired a warning shot towards them...
Hey!
Bang!
And. I hit one of the robbers in the tigh!
E-hem!
We, anyway!
Either they had another car stashed
away in the mountains before hand
or they stole a car that coincidentally
passed through and are on the run!
Didnst you see some
suspicious looking people?
Yeah, I did!
You mean people who are riding
in a car that is not theirs, right?
Huh
That's us!
Huh?
My car tire went flat in the mountains,
so we had them give us a lift.
Right
Dr. Agasa. then where is your car?
I called the car dealer and they said
they'd come get it in the morning.
So I left it in the mountains
with the key inside...
Then. isn't your car in trouble?
Huh
Maybe the robbers got a hold of it
and are riding it around
That's possible...
Then,
maybe you shouldn't-be bothering with
us and keeping watch over that car.
It's a yellow beetle, so it's easy to spot!
How strange...
Your voices...sound familiar...
I donst think so...
So. may we go now, officer?
Uh will you take that jacket
you have over your lap. just in case?
Hey!
Don't tell me you suspect us?
See. I haven't been shot or anything!
I guess not...
Be careful, then!!
Yawn...
Yes. this is the Agasa residence...
Huh
The Gunma Prefectural police?
According to Dr. Agasa.
He said that the dealers would be
picking his car up in the morning...
But, leaving the car as is in the mountains
may give the robbers a chance to use it
so we have decided
to tow it away for now...
So. please tell him to come and
pick his car up at the station...
Oh. yes. I will...
Goodbye then
Thank you...
I wonder what they're doing in
Gunma at this time of day?
I'll bet he was talked
into by Shinichi again
and went sticking their noses
into a criminal case or something...
Really...
I don't see what thrill they
find in looking for
faults in others at
the cost of losing sleep .
I see no fun.at all in playing detective...
Yawn...
Spare pair of pursuit glasses...
Yeah, we're going to pick up
the stuff earlier than scheduled
An hour from now. at 4:00
The place remains unchanged.
It's inn front of the locker in the basement
of Kenbashi Subway Station...
Tell Gin about this too. will you...
Yeah, of course...
Get the men ready armed with guns...
He could've gone chicken
and called the cops...
Either way, after the deal,
it's good riddance with him anyway...
We were planning to get rid of him
inside Kenbashi Station to begin with...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
v ab » . ea
Background Music
KATSUOQ ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I10OKA
Scripts By.
KANJ1*KASHIWABARA
AZUNNRLKOUCJ
JWUNICHI MIYASHIIA
YUICHI HIGURE
I'OSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
AZUNARI KOUCH
CC rr1 /vii1r/ 21
CHI HIG
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA WA GA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJIZKODAMA
roduced :
IMS ENTERTAYNMENI, LID.
In associa on with
YO! "URI TELECASTING
CORT ORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
OMGOMI AOYAMA SHOGARUR AN YTV TAN
All Re: 1 ITIRCSscrveed
It's about time.
Is every one in position?
Okay. don't let anyone escape.
Ooesrthat mean...
Yeah, that means his still
hiding some where around here.