Deduction flows with
the riiJthm of the wind
Dark stains are rinsed
clean and exposed
On a hike to the tenboudai
the truth behind ax)
sorrowful accident.
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
& pr, «
Ve oy,
vr
Tp gr
\/3 Js
an TC Ng.
& . .
Huuh
Whossaid there are lots of gals up here?
Not a soul, as far as I can see, man
Well, the guidebook says this place
IS quite popular among school girls
Those reporters are so
irresponsible and disgusting
Sure..man. Sure thing
You want-me-to 'go. okay I will
Wait-a minute: Hirai!
What's-up?
The place is tricky
You need to be very careful when you work
14')
You're quite right
We may have another fatal accident. right?
Well. I'll bet you'd rather like to
see me get into an accident
Hold it there
See you guys
Good morning. everybody
There is a broken fence
at the scenic view point
Please be careful
Eh, Hem
The Scenic View Point with a Broken Fence
Hold it
Wait for me guys
Why ¥So soon again?
We took asrest just a while ago
Be nice guys.
We're not in a hurry
Like we said, it's too much for you,
old. man. wasn't it?
Thanks for nothing
I just worked too much lately
and worked myself out
Sure!
Well, Ran, let's leave the old man alone
and go. shall we?
A good idea
No you don't! Hey
Wow. What a beautiful sight
Yeah
He's the man we-saw down there
Right. What is he doing, there?
They said there's a broken fence
He-s probably working on it
You're right
Finally
Oh. Hi. Pops
You finally made it. dad
He...fell off. \
Darn it!
Conan!
Hey. Watch out!
What're you trying to-do, «q
You want to fall off the, cliff?>
But...
Go down to the office
and tell them about this, Ran
Yes, dad
Is anyone there?
What's the. matter?
A man fell down the cliff
What!? Could it be Hirai?
Could be
Anyway, how do we get
below the view point...
This... this way
Ran, call an ambulance:and the police
Sure.-dads
No good. He's already dead
Hirai! Hii-ra-ii!
It's all my fault. My fault...
What do you mean, may I ask?
I asked him...
I asked him to fix the broken fence
at the view point
I should have gone
I should have gone and done it myself...
then this wouldn't have happened...
Huh
Why is it?
The two ropes that
were. left here are twisted
as if they had been tied to O
something for a long time
Da-a-ad
The police and ambulance will
be here soon, they say
Good
Anyway. this seems to be an accident
Let's leave everything here as is,
go back to the office
and wait for the police to come
Conan. We are going back to the office
Yeah
What's this?
This...
is a spider's web and threads
Why on earth is it here?
And when did he get it?
Lo TIN,
Just as I thought.
There was no spider's
web around here and
At the place where Mr. Hirai fell,
there are no traces of slip
marks made by his boots.
It's as if he had jumped] off the cliff:
Another thing puzzles me.
The ropes that were left beside the body
were twisted at both ends as
if they had been tied to something.
If the rope was tied, then why
Mr. Hirai fall to the ground?
And the way the ropes are twisted.
Are as if they have been tied
in a knot for many hours...
Why did Mr Hirai use that
kind of rope?
It's just a hare.
A animal trail?
Conan is still out somewhere. Dad.
Don't bother.
He is playing around somewhere nearby.
But...
Well. I'll go look for him.
There could've been an
accident or something...
But um...
Please stay here and
wait for the police.
Don't worry.
I'll be back with him soon.
Thank you.
He's a nice person.
Oh. dad!
This tree was...
the one that is sticking out
from beneath the view point.
What's that?
A piton and a ring.
It's a mountain
climber's spike and a snap ring.
Something strange is going.on.
Why. they're white-eyes.
What's that?
Darn!
I can't see clearly.
What're these?
Traces of spikes.
They're still new.
A rope can leave traces of
scratch marks lik) this .
I see what it is.
Hey. Conan!
What are you doing up there?
It's not safe up there.
I was looking at the
nest of white eyes
Oh. you were.
The white-eyes are protected birds
do you better leave them alone.
Yes, Sir.
You'd better come down right away.
I will, ric ht now.
They are worried about
you at the office.
Say. Mr. Kondou.
Your boots look very old, how come?
Oh. you mean these?
I got these when I was in college.
These are so comfortable so I don't
ant to change them for new ones.
The only thing is that they re heavy.
Now I see it. Just as I thought.
This is a murder case.
Mr. Kondou pushed Mr. Hirai to and
made it look as if he fell off by accident.
He used these tricks
Since there are
eyewitnesses to this incident,
we can assume, as Mr. Mouri says,
that this is an accident.
Yes. officer.
But if people keep
falling off by accident,
you could be held responsible for the
safety of the park, "Mr. Kondou.
I apologize
What are you. talking
about, may I ask?
Well- About a month ago.
Another worker of this office had an
accident: She: fell off the cliff and died.
Oh, she did.
Excuse us.
We want to move and carry
the body out, if you don't find.
Sure, guys.
Well, everybody,
We need to draw up a report
at the police station.
SO please come with us to the station.
Yes, officer
Wait a while. everybody.
Dad?
What's the matter, Mr. Mourn?
There is some doubt about
Mr. Hirai's death being an accident.
What's that, Mr. Mourn?
Ran, when the man fell off the cliff,
did you see his face?
Uh. No. I didn't. dad.
You didn't. Conan says
he didn't either And I didn't either.
That is. the manithatsfelljoffiimay
not have been Mr. Hirai.
But if he was not Mr. Hira,
where did he disappear to?
Mr. Kondou,
you probably know that there
IS a tree sticking out just
below the view point.
Is that right?
Yes, there is a tree but
it's not a large one and
I don't think it can hold
a falling man by any chance.
True. It's unlikely that the man got
stuck to the tree by chance.
That is, if that someone actually fell off.
What do you mean)by that?
The man at the view point did not fall off,
he jumped off deliberately,
so he could make the
people who witnessed the fall,
think that they saw
Mr. Hirai fall to his death
So, this is a homicide
Right. This is not an accident,
but a case of murder.
Then. whe on earth is the culprit?
The culprit is the person who knew that
Mr Hirai was expected to
go repair the fence.
He.is also someone who could prepare
the: same clothing that Mr. Hirai wore
In other words
It's
none other than you, Mr. Kondou.
Then it's like this, you say. Mr. Kondou
pushed Mr. Hirai off the cliff.
Then waited for Mr. Mouri
and the others to arrive,
which after he jumped
down on to the tree.
No. that way the time that
Mr. Kondou jumped off
would be different from
the time Mr. Hirai fell off.
Since we came up here as tourists.
We were approached
the view point completely
irrelevant of what
Mr. Kondou had in mind
That is. we could've arrived five
minutes after Mr. Kondou pushed
Mr. Hirai over the cliff,
or it could've been an hour later.
Then, how on earth
was he able to do that?
The tree.
The tree?
Yes: Mr. Kondou jumped onto the tree,
where Mr. Hirai was already was.
Mr: Kondou jumped down onto the tree
1, and pushed Mr. Hiraa off the tree.
That explains it.
That way, there would be practically
no time difference what so ever,
But how could he dare
do something like
risk his life jumping off
the view point like that
Well.
I wouldn't say it was such a great risk.
Conan found a mountain climber's spike
with a snap ring driven into the rock
above the tree, just below the
edge of the cliff at the view point.
Probably, early this morning
or last night,
Mr. Kondou prepared two ropes
and tied them to the snap ring
He put one of the ropes through the tree
below and fastened the rope in place,
then he wound the other rope to the
pole of the fence and tied it in place.
When he saw us coming to the park,
he chose us to be witnesses.
And told Mr Hirai to go
repair the fence.
Mr. Kondou saw us go. and then,
he ran into the path in
the back of the, office to short cut us.
The climbers' path to the view
point is the long way around
so it wouldn't have been
difficult for him to get there
there before us if he ran
straight through the mountain
Then he ambushed
Mr. Hirai. knocked him out.
And put him on the tree
beneath the view point.
He waited for us to arrive. then took
the rope that he had tied onto the fence,
tied it around his body as
his lifeline. and jumped off.
Mr. Kondou who was
suspended in air with the lifeline,
next took the rope that
was tied onto the tree,
untied the lifeline,
Iet go of it,
then climbed up the rope he was
holding and landed on the tree.
He then untied the rope as he previously
did with the other rope and let go of it.
In the end. he pushed
Mr Hirai off the tree
You're talking nonsense!
Everything is your imagination.
There's no proof
I knocked him out and
kept him on the tree, you say?
You're talking nonsense.
If you have any proof. show me!
The nest of the white-eyes...
You know that there's a nest of
white-eyes, don't you, Mr. Kondou?
Wha. what about it?
When the white-eyes make their nest,
they collect twigs and weeds
and bind them using spiders' webs
There was a web on the right
side of Mr. Hirai's body.
What!
I see a spider's web.
So. it's there, but what does
it have to do with me!
I said. show me proof that I did it!
There were traces of metal
spikes on the trunk of the tree,
Mr. Kondou.
The spikes of mountain climbing boots.
I've heard that because
of improved quality.
Mountain climbers' boots
nowadays have no metal spikes
since they are slip-proof
even without them
Mr. Kondou, you've been using your
boots since your college days,
Is that. right?
Are your boots spiked. Mr. Kondou?
Darn it!
That Hirai, he kept on picking
alpine plants and capturing
the protected animals to sell
them at premier prices
She. I mean the worker who died,
and I were after him
wanting evidence of what
he was doing.
And that evening. we
caught him in the act...
But, while I was struggling
with him, my arm, hit her and
She fell off the cliff.
Since then. Hirai has
been blackmailing-me
I couldn't put up with him any longer.
But. maybe this was all for the better...
I can finally amends for
what I did to her.
Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKOSU WA
MASAHITO=YOSHIWKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
1aracfer Dgsigns By,
ASAIGM 0 Suva.
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I10OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
CHI HIG
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN] KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS-ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
im=associration with
YOMIURI TELECASTINC
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
CLONIO AOYAMAY SHOGARUKAN YTV - TASS
All Rivh Reserved
I thought he had enough sleep already.
Apparently not.
What's theymatter. dad?
Let me have 'em.
Hey. don't. You can't!
No it's not what you think...
Just what're you peeking at. dad?
Well, it just so happens that
You're looking through the binoculars of
your own initiative and
you dare say it just so happens that
I.Like I said, it just so
happens that I...
happens that I
What're you going to do if Conan gets
interested and tries to take a look?
Yo '1 dirty bid mam
You dirty old man.
You obstinate dumbbell of a girl!
I'm telling mom about this!
What! Hey!
This is none of her business. is it!
Don't blame me for what
happens to you after she finds out!
Hey. you wait!
No way!
Please. Ran. dear!
Pops: just what
did you happen to see?
Oh. It's a nightingale.
It's on this way.
This is Mr. Seizan's studio! I guess...
I've got it. This could explain it
A Rlace in the Sun