Deduction flows with
the rhythm of the wind
the -rhythmeof thie wind
Dark stains are rinsed
clean and exposed
The sun shines brightly and
warmly like it knows no limits
It can also nurture«a suprising case!
He sees through the one and only truth
A. Child in.appearance
with the: 1:Q: of an 'adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
am ha
Veo 2
«7 wD >
tw GO
Ce NY 4
more or less have an
idea of the situation
thanks to the telephone
call last night but,
Is Seizan Sensei's slump that bad?
YesOmhe hasn't drawn
one picture these three months.
By'?
Of course maybe it has to do with
his.age since he's already 70,
it seems that he can't
come 'up with anything creative
and because of pressure from this
his: fingers have begun to shake.
That sounds troublesome.
He hasn't been eating very much
Iately and 1s emotionally unstable
He has sudden spurts of anger, while at
other times he goes completely-silent.
He finally: went on to attempt suicide...
A Place in the Sun
I asked you to come today in hopes that
Sensei would feel at least a bit refreshed
I'm sorry to have-called you
knowing how: busy you-are.
Oh no. don't be If: can be of help to
Sensei:who 1s my drinking friend,
Ir'couldn't;be-happier:
He would never turn down an
offer that comes prepared
with. Japanese sake and ha
hot spring. would he?
You're right!
Just what was that?
But. Sensei sure is a lucky man,
because he has a kind
hearted disciple like you.
I'm-what I am: thanks to Sensei.
Oh. it's a bush warbler!
They reside in this bamboo forest.
Hear them from this side.
Oh. he's,
Seizan Sense!
Good friends who travelfgreat distances
just to see you arefas precious as gold °
Thanks for stopping by on the way
When I saw the name of the station,
your face flashed through my mind. so
I'm glad to see that
you seem to be very well.
The older I get the more
filled with energy I am.
I was just sketching the
bamboos around here now too
He doesn't look the:least bit pressured.
Can-t.you tell?
He's putting On an act because he
doesn't want you to see his wretched self!
An act?
Did you just see that?
That's called the flight of a
bush warbler from valley to valley.
That's they're cry of alarm.
I'm sorry. Please forgive them
because they'll fly away in time
This bamboo forest is a
sacred place for the
bush warbler and is not to be infiltrated
Let's leave them so as
not to intrude on them
Oh. welcome back. Seizan Sensei.
We've got guests: Please
make them something good to eat.
Yes.
Who is she?
She is:Noriko Yamamoto. who comes
herefdaily to take care of/Sensei...
Is that so.
Mother!
Look. look. I'm good. aren't I!
K. Kenichi
Noriko!
I.I'm very sorry!
My mother came down with a sudden
fever and couldn't take
care.of him so. that's why...
No excuses!
I told you never to bring your child here!
Yes, But; just today...
No! Make him go home!
Don't ever bring him before me again!
Mother...
Go home,
right this minute! Understand!
By the way, is that a new piece of work?
Fantastic mountain
This is Mt*Fujiethat I drew recently
because a
certain company asked me for it.
Mr. Kuroki, don't you draw?
It's been a while since you've
become Sensei's disciple. isn't it?
Sort of.
I saw it some time ago.
But he's pretty good.
Unlike the Sensei's it's colorful.
Yes, mine are pictures in-color.
Come to think of it, youlknow the contest
that Sensei 'serves:asta judge for?
Isn't it about time it: starts?
You knowtivery well,
don't you?
+ The day after tomorrow is the deadline.
Why don't you make
an entry Mr. Kuroki?
I think you'll do pretty good,
don't you think so too, Sensei
I don't think so.
1. his teacher Seizan
Hayakawa will be laughed at.
Kuroki's skill is way
from being able to enter the contest.
But. Sense:...
Mr. Mouri, it's just as Sensei says!
I haven't gone through
enough training yet
Right; Ran,
would you please be my model?
As part of training for me?
Oh, Mr. Kuroki, one minute,
Sensei, could you draw us a picture?
Mr. Mourn!
When you were in Tokyo you used to
draw a lot for us to enhance gaiety.
No, I don't think so, not tonight...
Please don't let him.-Mr Moun!
Sensei has already drunk liquor...
He used to drink and
draw for us in the past too.
Please: Sense
Please!
No good!
I.I'm sorry, I got carried away
and I got kind of pushy
No. don't be. It's just that I've lately
gotten very weak
when it comes to drinking
Sensei! Why don't we go
fishing out at sea tomorrow!
Of course with Mr. Mouri and the others.
That sounds great!
Do let us accompany you, Sensei!
I haven't gone fishing in a long time...
I wonder if we can fish
when it's raining like this?
According to the weather forecast,
the rain is supposed to stop by sunrise
and it's said that
tomorrow will be a hot day.
Well, as for tonight,
I guess I'll go hit the sack already.
Good night. Sense.
Good night.
Dad. T at:s'rude.
You shouldn't do it!
Mr Mourn
Please take get me wrong,
Mr. Kuroki.
I want to confirm with my own
eyes whether he, as you say,
cannot draw because
his fingers are shaking
That's why I put on that act...
Il see
«a\O) Shy
So this is your work-place.
Oh, how cute. Is this your work?
It's still incomplete, though.
What beautiful colors.
It's drawnubysmixingkthis
powdered paint with hide glue.
This white one is called
Paris white, right?
You're knowledgeable, aren't you.
It's made by crushing the shell of oysters
and making them into powder.
Oysters?
Huh? That picture...
It's a bush warbler.
G.Good morning!
Oh, Mrs. Yamamoto...
What's wrong? You look pale.
I haven't had much sleep having
to look after my mother...
I'm going to go call the doctor
and ask him to come here.
Mr. Mourn!
I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
Sensei hasn't come out of his room yet,
SO please go ahead to the harbor.
I see. all right.
You mean Sensei isn't going to comer
He says he wants to stay home and relax.
Sensei, I'll switch over to
Mr Mouriinow.
Yes.
I'm sorry. but ll don't think I'll go today.
Are you all righty Sensei?
Maybe you should see how things go...
Okay: we'll see you by sundown.
Yes; you can expect good catch!
Please let's not stimulate
him too much for now.
Octapus!
That's amazing!
Fish!
You did it!
Rubb boosts...
That's bad...
Yes, this is Kuroki,
You mean, Sensei? He left a note?
Yes. I can't draw anymore,
Thanks for everything.
Hello. please come back right away.
It seems she found it when she went
to clean up at the'usual time
Please call the police immediately
and have them search for-him.
You heard him; didn't you?
Well head back right away!
S.Seizan Sense!
Is it suicide?
Who are you?
I'm a private detective
called Kogoro Mourn.
You mean you're theifamous!
I'm Ohmatsu from the local: police station.
We found a death note too.
So it's probably undoubtedly suicide...
He tied a rope to the bamboo. jumped
off from the rock and committed suicide.
The estimated time of his death is
thought to be between 11:00 to 13:00.
He tied.the.rope to the bamboo
justtwhen we were fishing.
I wonder why the bamboos
were all cut down...
Water wasn't accumulated so...
therbamboo was cut this 3.
Morning after the rain stopped.
So what! Go away!
Bush warbler?
It's too early to decide
this Is a suicide.
So this is Seizan Sensei's atelier
Seizan Sensei confined himself in here
and was drawing all the while after that.
Bamboo Diary?
I wonder what this is...
The record off the growth.of bamboos.
I see. maybe
Tihere are expensive drawings
here. stop scampering around!
Look at this!
This is a sketch of Ran...
What about this?
What?
I see...
Oh. I was just thinkingrtheisame thing.
Mr. Mourisl've finished most
of the questioning,
so I'm heading back to the station now...
Please wait Isnt it too soon to
decide that this is a suicide?
What do you mean?
Sensei was:.saying.yesterday.
This bamboo forest is a sacred place
for the bush warbler
and is not to be infiltrated.
I wonder if Sensei who loved the
bamboo forest would do such a thing
as pollute the bamboo forest
with his corpse?
One more-thing! Last night Sense
confinedrhimself to the
atelier after/dinner and was
drawing this right through
He was probably/planning to give it to
us as*a=gift at the time,we leave here.
If so. I wonder if he
would commit. suicide...
WwW. Which means!
Ashomicide under the
pretense of suicide!
Sensei-saidsthat .,"The bush warbler's
flightifrom valley to valley
means that«the bush warbler's are
crying] atrsound of the of alarm
Mrs Yamamoto, just before
we met you this morning
we heard the cry of the bush warbler!
And. you ran off with a pale face.
I'll bet you were at the
bamboo forest then?
N.No!
What's that?
Conan!
But. his estimated time of death is
between 11:00 a.m. to 13:00
She has an alibi during that time.
W. What!
I was at the city hospital.
I was told that I should take my mother
to a large hospital, so I took her there.
What's the matter. Conan?
Oh, Mr. Kuroki's
painting is completed!
Mr. Kuroki must've stayed up
Iast night and completed..it.
Ran. Pops says to bring-that
painting and the sketch.
what time?
Right now!
I see, you were by your
mother's side, I understand.
You seem to have a definite alibi...
Which means it's most likelyathat
Sensei committed suicide then.
I guess I'll be going then.
Officer Ohmatsu, please wait.
Seizan Sensei
did not commit suicide!
What?
The motive of the killer
WwW 10 committed this homicide and
made it look like a suicide
can be found in the
pictures that Ran has brought here!
Mr. Kuroki, you were planning to enter
the contest with this painting.
Which deadline is tomorrow, right?
But Seizan Sensei wouldn't let you.
Therefore: you decided to kill him.
Mi:Mr. Mouri, what a thing
to say out of the blue...
You invited me to come here saying
that Sensei was in a grave slump.
And wanted me to come to cheer
him up. but that was a lie!
Sensei was not in a slump nor did he
have any reason to commit suicide.
Sensei was not in a slump nor did
he have any reason to commit suicide
B.-But his:fingers were shaking...
-I "guess that's true.
But that painting of Mt. Fuji that
was in the guest room.
How do you explain that?
Sensei said: I just finished
drawing-in-a-few-days ago.
That's probably what you completed
using Sensei's rough draft
No. not only that.
Weren't you the one who was drawing
all of Sensei"s paintings
these past few years?
OO. Oh no!
So. having you enter the contest a
Nd going. independent was
totally absurd as far as
Sensei was concerned.
Last night you suddenly asked Ran to
be your model and diverted my attention.
I see! He knew that you would try to
test Sensei and ask him to draw!
Right. and after seeing
Sensei's condition. Mr. Kuroki,
I believed what you said that
It's not surprising that Sense
would commit suicide.
By the way: M mKuroki
early this morning
you carried Sensei's body to the bamboo
forest where he was found. didn't you?
No! You talked to Sensei
onthe phone, didn't you.
That's an entry level trick!
You. recorded Sensei' s voice beforehand
and set the voice that
you,edited on the answer phone
B.But like I've kept telling you
time and again. I have an alibi
You mean. you-were at-sea with us?
Ran, please show Mr. Ohmatsu
the sketchbook Conan gave you.
41TH!
Here you go
Bamboos grow way faster
than we imagine them too.
Very true.
Please show us how much they
have grown in a period of 3 days.
About 2 meters.
Bamboos grow greatly at once. when
Iike this morning$there is rain,
then it clears and the temperature rises.
Mr. Kuroki, you took advantage
of this and killed Sensei!
This morning you carried Sense!
Who you put to sleep with sleeping
pills to the bamboo forest
You made Sensei sit in front of a bamboo
ou chose and put a
rope around his neck.
Then cut the bamboo
that was around Sensei
You made sure that a lot
of sun would shine
on the bamboo that you
tied the rope onto
The cry of the bush warblers flying from
valley to valley we heard this morning.
Was the cry of warning aimed
at you. Mr. Kuroki.
The bamboo that was showered
with a lot of sunshine grew rapidly
and eventually suspended Sensei in air.
This is how Sensei died while we were
our fishing with you Mr. Kuroki
The white sawdust on your
tabi is the evidence!
T.This is Paris white,
Just-what kind of evidence isithis?
No. that's not Paris White
Please take a<good look.
That's sawdust that fell on
when you cut the bamboo with the saw!
I'm sorry. it's just as 'yoursay
I've been drawing on behalf of
Senseifsince a few: years ago
But I wanted to at least once
and sign my name on
givéhap pail ind HathkaSensehe.sun
and sgn Mm ; name on
them instead of the Sensei"s.
I wanted somebody to look at them
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKOSU WA
MASAHITOYOSHIDKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Desiens B
MASATOMO SUDO
JUNICHI I11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
CHI HIG
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
oh Ab
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJIJKODAMA
Produced By.
TMS-ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
ir=assocration with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
COSTHO AOYAMA HOGARURAN YTV TM
All Riv) Reserved
Okay I finished!
Really? Let me see. let me see!
What's that supposed to be?
You fool!
Don't you know of realism?
It's nothing more than
a child's doodling!
What did you say!
Even Conan can draw
way better than this, right Conan?
Don't compare me with a brat like him!
I'm just telling you the truth.
You have no sense
for this piece of artwork!
Good think I don't!
So where's the restroom...
Wolf Face!
So cool...
Don't you hear a strange song?
A hidden camera?
From the TV station?
T. This is!
(51%)
Soiled'Hero/Mask
Part 1