Se Rr. LL
Deductionsflows with
the rhythm of the wind
Deduction flows with
1 yo. 3 t
eriynmao 1e wine
The alibi trick will be revealed
Pro Wrestling and the mask
Let's unmask the case at hand
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
NO case Is lefts<unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Ar 3)
Pv ("av Go
<25'?
Wr Ne
SF OY
8 we tw
gr" + 6
3 IVs
Now, let's have detective
Mouri Kogoro answer the question!
The undeafeted Mask man from
Teito wrestling!
Who is it from these 5 people!
Here!
Mere! Here! Hera!
Is it, number three?
Correct! Correct!
You :are correct!
Expected from the sleeping detective!
A perfect answer!
Everyone would know the answer
if they have it in front of them...
I1:8
TA AA
(ma)
Soiled Mask Hero" Part 1
FA AA
(mm)
Dang. I took the job
because the pay was good but...
That was a joke!
My is that?
Why is that?
Wrestling is getting popular among
young people right now.
The boys in our karate club
use wrestling move on each
other all the time!
Hey now...
Especially that ene hit KO move!
Wait. what was the name?
No matter how cool they act,
it's just a ehilds play.
There you go!
You're totally into it...
Hey Ran, when is that
Masked Wolf coming out?
His pretty strong right?
Wolf face match is a Jr heavy
weigh title match so...
It's the last fight. the main event.
D.Does that mean his a champion?
Yes he is!
After making a contract of takingioff his
mask after losing even 1 game,
his been 65 singles game, undefeated!
But I kind of want to see him lose...
Why is that?
If he loses we get to see his face.
His hiding his face with
a mask for a reason.
His either extremely ugly or his bald!
Sorry for being a ugly man.
But I'm not bald.
Wait then, that means you are!
This is the true identity of Wolf Face...
A.Are you sure it's okay, though?
Coming out without your mask
to a place like this
No worry,
Wolf Face is said to be Mexican...
Besides, I sometimes fight
in the opening performance with this face
But, everybody thinks that
I'm just a young wrestler
Well, of course I don't use the techniques
of Wolf Face at that time,
so I'm just another young wrestler...
So. no one knows your true identity then...
No...
Nobody except for the personnel
of Teito Pro Wrestling know about me...
Neither do my parents nor my girlfriend...
I debuted as a mysterious
masked wrestler in Mexico
to begin with so...
You don't have the kind of face that
you'd have to hide, though...
I hike to wear masks!
It's been my dream since I was a child...
Doesn't it bother you at all?
To hide your identity
and deceive everybody...
I'm sure that your girlfriend
wants you to tell her the truth...
I really wish that
you were Shinichi, Conan...
Ran...
I just said a while ago. remember?
That my true identity is
a secret that only the personnel
of Teito Pro Wrestling know of...
If in case my true identity is
revealed to those outside,
I won't have to suspect her
for having given away my identity
if she doesn't know, right?
But...
Besides.
I don't want to worry her
Wolf Face's match is
red on TV during Golden Time...
The match may turn out
to be violent and bloody too so...
Well,
I'm more or less prepared
for what is to come...
The time when I take my mask off is
when I lose and sink into the mat...
It's when Wolf Face dies
and leaves the ring...
But then,
why reveal your identity to us. then...
Oh, well, that's...
The thing is.
My girlfriend is a great friend
of the Sleeping Kogoro...
I figured you wouldn't
give me your autograph
if I was just another young wrestler...
Why didn't you ask me
when you were wearing your mask,
ust a while ago, then...
Wolf FACE can't communicate in Japanese
unless he uses an interpreter!
Therefore, I wouldn't be able to ask you
to give me an autograph addressed
to a girl with a Japanese name!
Besides, I figured that
you're not the kind of people
who would give away my secret
and shatter the dreams of children...
WwW. Well, of course not...
Mr. Ogami. it's about time...
Okay!
Her name's inside,
so please give me your autograph!
0... Oh...
His identity will be revealed...
when he dies...eh...
Mr. Nagase
Mr.Nagase!! Turn this way please
\ aaah
Mr. Nagase!
You're finallydgeing to be fighting against
the invincible champion
Wolf Face for his belt,
can you tell us how you're feeling new?
Hui,
Hew I'm feeling...
All I want is for the.people here
to watch me...
To watch me fight with all my might...
against that idiot Japanese leopard
whose mask will be.
Torn off when I defeat him
Japanese leopard?
You mean Wolf Face is Japanese?
Oo...
It's a joke, just a joke!
We're in a rush, so interview us later
Hey. Nagase!
Just what do you think you're doing?!
Didn't I tell you that
Wolf'Face's identity is top secret?!
And that you're not supposed to
say a word about it to anyone!
Are you aware of the fact that
Ogami shoulders half the popularity that
Teito Pro Wrestling 'enjoys!!!
Hen; what is it you're saying.
Mr Ushigome?
Are you telling me,
the star of the main event,
who has worked and polished
strength as well as gain popularity...
to go out of my way to lose deliberately...
on this gala occasion?
It's true that you're just a good looking
but with the strength that you possess now.
You couldn't possibly beat him...
Just what are you talking about?
What's important for a wrestler is looks
If not.
A wrestler with your ability would've
become popular long time ago. right?
What?!
Hey Nagase!!
That's no way to talk to your superior...
You don't want to hurt 2 precious body
just before a matéh, do you?
Ugh.
Okay then,
I'll be flexing my body
Iike always, in the room
so when it's ti; e to fight the match
please call me
Well
fl win, I'll give you all a mask as a gift...
So that you go can
all. hide your ugly faces
and gain more popularity...
Yeah...No problem...
Chances are 2006 my win...
Although, it's a hidden fact.
His left knees is not completely healed yet.
If I target: his weak point,
I can stop him in"his moves...
Phooey...
and if by any chance it were to look
as if I'm about to lose, that's fine too...
All I have to do is peel his mask off
on the mat, that'll be it...
Everything will work out just fine...
I made the young ones
at your place wear masks
and I practiced time and again with them...
on how to tear off the mask
during the match .
The match will be cancelled
once hisvdentity is revealed,
and I'll be fired,
but Teito Pro Wrestling's popularity will
go down too...
I'll end up the unfortunate wrestler who
is fired from Teito Pro Wrestling
for revealing the true identity of Wolf Face,
and go up on the ring at your place...
I'm counting on you
when that time comes...
Okay, Bankoku Pro Wrestling?
Dan!
He sure is the leader
of Teito Pro Wrestling
I gotta go to the restroom!
Aah...
You better come back quick
or the match will start!
Yep!
Uh~Where's the restroom. restroom.
M. Mr. Ogami?
He's so different from who we just saw...
Hey Wolf!
Good luck...
Shoots...
I better to the (restroom quick...
Hey kid! ,
nus pace iso Im s oO everyone
except authorized personnel!
Come on, I'MmMsyjust going to the restroom!
No. no,
The restroom for the general public
is on the 2nd floor.
Hey. Nagase!!
Huh?
Just what do you think you're doing!
The match is going to start!!
Hey. Nagase! Hey!
What's up. Sakuma...
M Mr Kiba
Is something wrong with Nagase?
Oh. well
Nagase won't come out
of the waiting roomr
Well, we had a slight argument a while ago
and nobody wanted to be his corner man,
so I decided to be his corner man
and came to call him but...
Then, why don't you
just drag him out of there
and make him get up on the ring!
B.But. he gets outraged saying that
his concentration is interrupted
if we go in without his permission...
Phooey...
who does that green-horn think he is...
Hey-Nagase!!
Come on get out.here!!
NNagase?!
Hey. get a hold of yourself!!
Nagase?!
No good...
there's no pulse...
sgWhat?!
Hurry and get an
ambulance and the police!!
Y Yes, sir!
Damn. who...
who the hell could've
done a thing like this...
Shhh!
Don't you hear a strange sound of the?
What?!
A strange sound of the
It's coming from that bag...
A hidden camera?
Nichiuri TV?!
I D";on't tell me that
\the killer isn the video...
T:This is...
Wolf Face?!
We're sorry to have
kept you waiting for so long...
The challenger for
the junior heavy weight title match,
Hyota Nagase is unable to fight
because of a sudden accident
Therefore, the title match with Wolf Face
that had been scheduled
has been cancelled...
What 7?!
Oh no
The murdered is
Mr. H ota Nacase a e 25...
A pro wrestler who belongs to the...
Teito Pro Wrestling Team...
- BS
he'd been getting stronger
dabda
and was steadily gaining popularity...
He seems to have been stabbed to death...
Yes...
he's been stabbed inia total of three places,
his back. his chest and his stomach,
and the blow-that took his life
was the final stab in his chest...
Huh
How do you know that
the final stab was in his chest?
Oh, well
that's what we saw on the video
before you got here, Inspector...
The video?
You mean a surveillance camerar
It is a hidden camera that Nichiuri TV,
who holds broadcasting rights
to our Teito Pro Wresting Team set
up In this room!
They wanted to film in secret Nagase
just befo e the title match
Whenever he fought at the Tohto Kokugikan
he used to do warm-up exercises
alone in this room.
Oh...»
Will you show me that video too?
Oh...here it is!
Hmm.
If so. the case is just as well solved!
The killer is shown on this tape. right?
WW .Well. the thing is...
yo 'W
W. Well, the thing is...
Iiq 'Q
W Wolf man?!
Rather. a wolf's mask?
Wolf Face
the masked wrestler that is popular now
He's a junior heavy weight champion
and was scheduled to
fight Nagase tonight for the title...
Since Wolf Face publicly announced that
he would reveal his true identity if he lost,
it was a match in which
his mask was at stake...
Which means that the masked wrestler .
In order to protect his title and~identity *
without realizing that'thére
was a hidden camera here killed/Nagaee
before the match...
Oh.not really...
Not really!
Almost all the people
of the Teito Wrestling Team
- besides Nagase knew that
there was a hidden camera here.
And once this wolf's mask is worn,
Wolf Face could be anybody. right?
C.Conan?
Which means that
the killerflis Wolf Face himself
or a pro wrestler with the same kind of
physique as Wolf Face
who wants to set him up as the killer, right?
A pro wrestler with the same physique?
Because the killer that is in the video is
about the same height as Mr. Nagase
Wolf Face is about the same height
as Mr. Nagase, right?
Y.Yeah...
Besides, this room is closed to everyone
except authorized personnel!
Only another pro wrestler could
stab a pro wrestler in a place like this!
Oh, and I already gave the forensic officers
the murder weapon. which was a knife.
The gloves and outfit of the killer.
That was found in the restroom nearby,
so don't worry!
Ii] see...
Ehem!
So. Mr. Kiba, please bring that
masked wrestler and the pro wrestler
that has the same physique
as he does here!
Y.Yes sir...
But. Conan-why did you. come here?
I wanted to goto the restroom
and I heard the other wrestler making a fuss
over Mr. Nagase
not coming out of his room,.
so I came to check
out what was happening!
No. rather.
Who brought you
to this pro wresting grounds...
Renown Detective Kogoro Mourn,
Mr. Inspector!!
Not you again. you god of death...
Please let me see it too.
The video tape which shows
the murder being committed
Huh? Oh, it's you...
This is when...
the killer comes into the room. eh...
Hey. hey. I haveynothing to talk
to you about before the match...
Or do you want tojask me
to lose on purpose?
Huh? The scene just shook...
I think the killer's/fool touched the bag
in which the video was hidden...
I already told you that
I'm going to go for it seriously tonight...
Oops! He's already holding the knife
Wha!
He stabs Mr. Nagase in the back first...
Then as he turns around, Mr. Nagase
IS stabbed again in the stomach...
Hey.::Isn't the victim trying to
say something.
But, the killer covers his mouth
so nothing can be heard...
Oh! He's going for the mask!!
Come to think of it, the blood smeared
mask that I found in the restroom
was ripped about 10 centimeters
under the part of the right eye!
Then, maybe the killer's face can be seen...
Then, the final.blow in the chest...
Darn! Only if the killer would look this way...
But. why is he looking around like that?
Maybe he's looking for something?
Oh. his clothes goti:Caught:on-the chair...
Okay. get up. just the way you are!!
Then, we get to see a close up of his face
rom the ripped part of the mask...
Darn... It's the left profile of
his face of the part
that's not ripped that we first saw...
And. he leaves the room...
But, if ablood smeared man
hike him walks around.
I'm sure that
somebody wouldjve noticed him...
Oh, . es.
The youngswrestler who
was in front of the restroom
seem to have, seen a man
with blood on his outfit...
It seems that the man went into the restroom
hiding his head with a bath towel,
that the young wrestler
took no special note of him
thinking that it was
just another veteran wrestler,
who was smeared in blood
after fighting in the opening performance...
"SEQ...
if he hid another outfit in the restroom
beforehand, he can change clothes
then come out looking
as if nothing had happened...
Whatstime isthe estimated time of deaths?
A definite time-has not been
concluded on yet but...
It was probably some time
during the match Mr. Kiba was fighting...
Because three minutes
after the killer left the réom.
Mr. Kiba's roar of victory...
- Se.
You'll hear it«soon!
Dah!
T.True...
Which means that the time
the murder was committed is...
Around 7-20 pm...
L& OD
Huh
Inspector. I brought the four
who haye similar physique to Nagase...
So. please let me know
when you find the murderer...
It's a promise...Inspector...
O.Okay...
Oh. there he is!!
Mr. Kiba!! Is it true that
Mr. Nagase was killed?!
Are the four that just went in suspects?!
Please answer us. Mr. Kiba!
Mr. Kiba?!
Shoots. his lips are sealed, eh...
But, this means the end
of the Teito Pro Wrestling Team...
Yeah...
All right then. from the person on the right
please give me your; name
and where you were around 7:20 pm...
Y.Yeah...
Judging from the circumstances,
the killer should be among the four...
Who of the...four is it?
Which of them killed Mr<Nagase!!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MITCHTHTKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
sharacf r Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUGHI
JUNICHI-MIYASHN AS
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chicf-Director.
KEN JIFJKO DANA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, ITD
1r=associration with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
NCO VOY AM ALAHOGARURAN YTV IAS
All Re: ht™¢~crveed
It's the blood match wrestler.
Officer Takagu...
Huh?
I'd like to ask you two things...
Next Conan:sThint
Soiled:Mask Hero=Part2