Deduction flows with the
rhythm of the wind
Dark stains are rinsed
clean and exposed
Crime scene shown
on the camera
Conan's solution will
take off the mask.
He sees through the
one and only truth,
Ig OD
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
Ne case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
(Bqe;
V4 YY!
Ran and I accompanied Pops on the
job to go see a pro wrestling match
The main event of the day was
the title match between Jr. Heavy
weight champion Wolf Face and
young ace, Hyota Nagase.
However. just before the match...
Hey. Nagase!
Hurry up-and come out!
Mr. Nagase was killed in
the waiting room
Coincidentally, the scene
of the crime was video taped
T. This is!
Wolf Face!
€37)
Soiled Mask Hero"
Part 2
Is it true that wrestler
Nagase was killed?
Tell us!
What happened
to the police announcement!
All right then, from the
person on the right,
please give me your name
and where you were around 7:20 pm
Y.Yeah...
At around 720 I was watching
the match Mr. Kiba was fighting
Because he gets angry if I don't
watch his match closely
Is there anyone else who
was watching with you?
No. I was alone.
Well, someone in the audience
may have remembered seeing me
but they, were all absorbed in
watchinglthe match...
S. Same here, I was watching
Mr. Kiba's match alone too
Oh. my name is Hiroyuki Sakuma!
But, right after Mr. Kiba's match I came
to this room to get Mr. Nagase!
Because his match
was right afterwards.
Are you sure?
T's true! I heard this man-say+
Nagase. hurry up and come out!
But, it's after the time
the murder was committed...
Then, next you, the one
wearing the wolf mask!
I'd like you to remove
your mask and talk to us
Inspector, he doesn't speak Japanese.
Because Wolf Face is Mexican
And besides. he cant take off his mask
in front of Woiien and children
It's okay. Sakumafl
They already know who I am.
You're the one with the handsome face,
but super weak wrestler Noriharu Ogami
N.No way!
Dd gy
I saw you in the. Tohto:Sports
Newspaper-thisimorning:too
Seeli-Here's a picture
of you'and 'Wolf side by side!
Oh. that's Sakuma!
He plays Wolf Face in my place to
deceive all the reporters who come to the
the gym and the match grounds trying to
reveal the identity of Wolf Face!
Oh I see...
But the mask that you just removed
and.thegmask'in the picture
Iook somewhat slightly different...
That's the mask I use
when I eat! It's made of thinner
material with less decorations on it.
And the opening of the mouth part is
made larger to make eating easier!
Fl see..,.
B, But what#a shock to find out that the
identity of Wolf Face is wrestler Ogami
Aren't you the: one who lost to Wolf
Face at Mascara Contra Mascara.
And vanished soon after the match!
Leonardo Ross!
Oh. yes!
MM. Mascara?
Mascara Contra Mascara!
It's a match in which you fight to
remove your opponent's mask!
Well. what a surprise
I thought that you resigned. .
I'm more surprised that you know
so much about Pro Wrestling...
Leo had his mind set on
resigning when he lost to me,
but Mr. Kiba convinced him otherwise
And he debuted once again in Japan
wearing a Wolf Face mask
with a different color
Then, he gathered popularity as
Wolf Face's shadow
He was supposed to be the
Jr. Heavyweight
challenger after Nagase.
But, who would've foreseen that
anything like this would'happen...
And?
Where were you all around 7.207
Since it was just before
I go out to fight the match,
I was doing warm-up exercises in the
waiting room of the foreign wrestlers,
All the other foreign wrestlers had
gone to see Mr. Kiba's match
And, were you watching
Mr. Kiba's match too?
Yes .
Which means all four
of you don't have an alibi...
No. Mr. Inspector!
This murder couldn't have been
committed without Wolf Face's mask!
Which means that the killer is
one of the two who had
free access in and out of the
foreigners' waiting room
Oh, no, Wolf Face's masks are
kept inside a bag and
hidden in the toilet of the restroom only
authorized personnel have access to,
SO that we can wear the mask in secret...
If not, people will suspect
me for being Wolf Face.
Because theysll see me going in
and out of the foreigners' waiting room
"SEQ...
Of course we handed the bag
over to the forensic officers already.
Darn. only if the victim left a
dying message or something.
What's up. Ram?
Remember I said a while ago that the
skills used in pro wrestling is
popular in our Karate.club?
The name of the technique
resembles "Dying Message.
Maybe you're talking about
Diving Body Attack?
The one that Mill Mascaras used to do!
Huh? Oh, well.
Then, what about
Bruiser Brody's Flying Knee Drop
or Funk's Pinning Toe Hold
If I remember correctly, I think it was
the technique of a Japanese wrestler...
Oh. then it must be Mr. Taketds!
Well. putting that aside.
Well, weire staying here a while
Ionger and continuing investigations,
so I want the rest of you to go to another
room with Officer Takagi and wait there.
Please say something!
Hey=Ran, take that
brat with" you and go outside too!
Okay!
I'm sorry. Officer Takag:...
No problem...
Wow, check out the
number of press people here
dd A).
It's the wrestler-that did
the bloody match.
Arelyou all right. Mr! Kayama??
You look like a mummy.
O. Oh. it's you. nothing to it.
Qfwéw
By the way. is it true
that Nagase was stabbed?
Y.Yeah...
Um. Officer Takagi...
I have two things I want to ask you...
What is it?
Uh, you know the mask man.
Yeah, that's right!
I heard that they're all that
way in the beginning
and all masks are more or less that way.
The same goes for Wolf Face's mask!
Hey. Conan, where are you going?
I forgot something!
What do you want?
I forgot something.
Now, where did I put it...
Inspector! We got a report
from the forensic officer!
Oh, okay!
The blood on the mask that was found
in the restroom was determined
to be that of the victim's
and the remnants of hair and eyebrows
that were found on the inside
inside of the mask
were the same as those
found on the other Wolf Face masks.
Which means that the mask was worn
only by its original owner Mr. Ogam.
And what about the victim's nails?
Although a thorough investigation
was made, nothing was found...
Strange. if he tried to tear the mask off
the killer's skin or something should've
been found left on his nails
Just as I thought...
There's no mistake about it!
It's the one who couldn't become a wolf!
At any rate, Mr. Inspector!
It is an undeniable fact that only the hair
an eye DOTrows OO wires er gam
were found on the inside of the mask of
Wolf Face that the killer was wearing!
We have no choice but to
judge him to be the killer!
But, even Mr Ogami knew that the
TV station had set awdeo camera
up in this room where the
murder was committed. right?
Why would he go out of his way to wear
his mask and commit the crime,
knowing that it would draw
suspicion to himself?
That's probably exactly
what he was after.
He probably figured everyone would
think so, and used it to his advantage
Well, I think that if we call Ogami back
here again he'll confess what he did!
Because he doesn't seem to be
such a bad person to begin with.
Theres something
strange about-this mask!
See, look in the back of the mask
that the killer was wearing!
In theaback?
The design of the mask is different
from the one that
Mr. Ogami was wearing a while ago.
Design?
You're right.
The other maskihad more fur in the back.
The mask in this video doesn't have it.
Ikl}
You mean this mask is imitation?
Probably a replica or something
that was sold at stores for fans.
Oh. no. don't think so.
Wrong!
This mask, is the one that was around
when Wolf.Face made his debut!
Mr. Ogami said that the old
masks were also in the bag.
So the killer probably just
happened to pick this old mask.
Hey. I thought I tolafyou to keep
an eye on the four suspects?
Oh, well, Ran asked me to come check
because Conan didn't come back so
Which means that the design of the mask
has nothing to do with the murder?
No. probably not...
So. he says.
So. that's...
What was that "Huh?" for. eh sonny
You fool!
All you ever come up with are
ideas that confuse the investigation!
Understands?
I guess you're right! +
No. wait, "see...
So that's what.it was!
I wonder if you could cooperate with me.
After you change this room
according to my directions
can you bring the four suspects who are
waiting in the other room here.
Don't tell me that.
So. shall we peel off
the mask of the killer
wolf that stabbed Mr. Nagase
to death in this room. inspector.
Look!
The four are going in again.
Just a while ago.
Kogoro Mouri also went inside too
Maybe the Sleeping Kogoro's deduction *
performance is about to begin.
We can't miss this!
Please let us interview you!
You're putting on a deduction
performance. aren't you?
Let us in!
O:Officer Chiba. don't let anybody in!
Conan is)still inside!
Just what is it with you officers?
Summoning us like this again...
Don't tell us you've
figured out who the killer is?
Y.Yeah, well sort of...
No. not just yet.
Hey. hey!
You just said a while ago that.
But, we'll soon find out.
All I need you to do
is to disguise yourself
1s Wolf like the killer did and
me walking toward mm
First, let's start with you,
Mr..Ogami, who is Wolf Face himself.
Please wear that mask you are holding.
Please do as you are told.
Y.Yes sir.
Please come towards me.
Come a little more...
Closer...
Uh. what next?
Okay. that's fine.
Next, Mr Sakuma! Please take the mask
from Mr. Ogami and do the samesthing
Oh. yes sir...
I. Inspector, do you notice any
difference between the two
No. not at all.
Okay?
Then. finally you. Mr. Ushigome.
Yeah.
I wear this and walk towards you. right?
M.Mr. Mourn,
I'm sure you have your reasons
But unless you tell me where
and how to look carefully
I don't have the slightest idea...
Are you okay. mister!
It's me.
ts. we.
O.Oh. it's you, sonny. I'm fine .
Will this do. Mr: Detective?
Yes, I more or less thought it would come
out this way. but now I'm positive.
That Mr. Ushigome, you're the
one who killed Mr Nagase!
WwW. What?
It. It's the same, as the killer who
was in the video he kept looking around!
Looking around?
Yes, you'll find out when you wear itmbut
a wrestler's mask makes for narrower
vision than is actually thought to be!
Unless you're used to wearing it,
you tend to look around, trying to make
out the situation of the surroundings
or trip over.things that are at your
feet. because.it is a blind spot
In other words.
Mr. Ogami who is used to
wearing the mask of Wolf Face
Mr. Rossi who is used to
wearing the mask of Nega Wolf
and, Mr. Sakuma who usually
pitches in for Mr. Ogami
have all been ruled out as suspects...
You're the only one who's not
used to wearing the mask!
You mean I'm branded killer just
because I looked around and tripped!
The evidence is right there on tape!
Remember what Conan
said about behind the mask a while ago
Do you see that extra something?
T:. There are four strings sticking
out from behind the mask!
I get it!
The killer was wearing the thin mask worn
when having meals under, another mask!
That way. the hair and eyebrows of the
killer won't stick to the inside
of the mask on the top that
the blood splatters onto!
I see, that's why although the
victim tore half the mask off.
No remnants of skin of the «killer were
found in the nails of the victim
Isn't this the mask for meals
that you're talking about?
It was sticking out of
our pocket when you fell.
Oh-no that's the mask I keep in
order to scare the young wrestlers
and not the one that the
killer was wearing
It's strange.
Wolf Face's mask is black and white,
but there's a red spot by the right eye
Oh. I get it!
Oh. I cet it!
The right eye part of
the mask that you were
wearing on top got ripped so the
blood splattered on here"
Y.You brat.
Okay. that's it!
We'll hear you out at the station.
Be quite!
Hey. Mr Ushigome!
I'm telling you to be quite!
I killed the betrayer
who wanted to transfer
) the Bankoku Pro Wrestling Tean
Cool it, Mr. Ushigome
That's not all}!
I was going to take the mask
away from you by framing you up.
A young wrestler
with no name. as the Killer!
So that I become Wolf Face!
Didn't you hear a
strange sound just now?
R.Right, .as long as
I get to wear this mask I can become...
You can never become Wolf!
You may be able to
hide your face with the mask,
but you can't hide your
heart that's full of soot
and rotten to the gut,
having no respect for pro wrestling
C.Conan!
Brat. what do you know about me!
Stop it!
Shi. Shining Wizard...
Right, that's it!
That's the name of the technique!
I'm glad,
I finally came up with the name
And then after that
the killer Ushigome
was slapped once in the cheek
by a speechless Mr. Kiba
He was then escorted from the
white mat to a dimly lit hell
Original Comic Books By.
Producers.
MITHTHTKO*SUWA
MA AHITOXOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Tigh \
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I1OKA
Scripts By.
KANIPKASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI.KOUGCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHIIA
YUICHI HICURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chiét-Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
im=association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
CONHO AOYAMA PSHOGARURANY TV TMS
All Ri 1 Reserved
But, things are going to get
rough for you from now on...
The mass media is going to bash
you from now on saying things like
you're a murderous pro
wrestling team and stuff...
we'll be fine
We, wrestlers are tough.
We're used to being bashed and hit.
So. I'll see you all then.
I wish you luck.
Yes, they're the toughest
guys around
It's no problem for them to
overcome difficulties like this
And. so long as Wolf
Face keeps on winning
his identity will stay undercover...
Then you see,
Mr. Ogami from the top rope
Mr. Ogami? I thought you
were talking about Wolf Face?
Oh, so you know wolf! Mr. Wolf!
Oh, because he's called wolf?
WwW. Wolf Faces identity will
probably never. beRevealed. I.] think
What's going on!
Please stay away!
Mr. Umetani are you okay?
The knife fell out...
What is the meaning of this...
This is...
The knife poked into the cigar case!
The Cigar Case:of Good Luck"
Part 1