Deduction:flows with
the rhythmeof the 'wind
Deduction flows with
the rhythm of the wind
Dark stains are rinsed
cleanfand exposed
The mysterious answering
machine.is*the mystery!
The strange inconsistencies will be
cleared-mane shot.
He sees through the
one and only truth,
A child in a) earance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
No case is left unsolved
30-26
Pops! Pops!
Be quiet. let me.sleep in peace. will you!
EZ en
Pops!!
12.00
Sunday. isn't it.
You've 'got a guest!
G.Good morning...
Huh? Officer ,Chiba...?
Ghads, what's this...
What do you want this early
on a Sunday morning...
Aha, ha... I'm sorry . Well...
So like I was saying. Inspector Megure...
Ugh!! C,Conan?!
Ninja Technique of Alibi Scheme
There are no signs of any struggle here.
SO the victim must've.
Been killed somewhere else
then brought here
to North Beika Park and abandoned...
Is.something bothering you?
Well I'm not sure
why I was summoned here...
What're you talking about?!
Isn't he an acquaintance of yours?
We found this
IN the victim's pocket... See!
M. My name card...Why is it here?!
Likewise, from the driver's license
the victim had on him,
the victim is YuichijKusaka 26, a resident
of Kofu City. Yamanashi Prefecture
Well'? Mr Mourn'?!
B.But...
remember him!
C.Conan?!
Sticking your nose into the case again...
Well, well, now,
Mr. Mouri. And. Conan... 7?
He's the one that came together with
novelist Mr. Ryutaro Tsukigata before
Tsukigata...
Tsukigata
Hmm Oh
Hmm--~- Oh 1!
Right, he's one of the two disciples that
was there back then!!
He's the famous samurai novelist that
IS good at writing about Ninja stuff?
Yes, six months ago
he came to visit me saying
he wanted to challenge
writing detective stories too.
And suddenly came to interview me.
So, at that time you alse gave
Mr. Kusaka your name card?
He was indeed a salaried worker who was
training to become a professional novelist,
and because he was
just about to come to Tokyo,
hesaid he brought him
along to experience interviewing...
What about the other one?
What?! What do you mean?
Mr. Saruhashi!
Oh... Saruhashi...
His name is Masaru Saruhashi,
and he was saying that he lived
in Beika-cho just like Mr Tsukigata,
SO he went through training by always
helping to clear up the manuscripts
Okay-First, we'll go see
Mr. Tsukigata!!
Yes, sir!
Heh, heh, heh...
Let's go, Mr. Mourn!
Oh, yes. sir!
What!! You mean Mr. Kusaka?!
So. I think he was on his way here...
I see...
He was supposed to
come here yesterday
with the new story
he had finished writing...
Um. did Mr. Kusaka
have that manuscript?,
No. he didn't have anything on him
I got a call from Teito. Station
Iast night a little after 8:00,
saying that he would come by at 9:00,
but since he didn't come
I was a bit concerned
Oh, you got a call
from Teito Station at about 8:007
Yes...
Inspector! The estimated time of death is
between 7:00 pm and 9:00 pm
If he was at Teito Stationtuntil'past 8:00
we can narrow down his tracks
until the time-he:was killed. «
I got two calls from Mr Kusaka yesterday
One was at about noon
It was from his residence in Kofu
He asked me if he could come
and have me look over his new novel
But I had to go out so...
I told him I'd be back about 9:00 at night
9.007 All right I'll be there around that time
And then I got the second call
from Teito Station around 8:00 pm
Since I was out,
his message was in my answer phone
There is-one message
This 1s Kusaka.
I've arrived-atTeito Station
I'm going to head over
to your place from now,
so I think I can get there
by 9:00 as I promised...
Oh, the train's leaving, so I've got to go!!
Saturday, 8:10 pm
May I listen to it one more time?
Sure...
There is one message
This is Kusaka.
I've arrived at Teito Station
I'm going to head over
to your place from now,
sol think I can get there
by 9:00as I promised...
Oh, the train's leaving,
so I've got to go!
Saturday, 8:10 pm
At 8:10, Mr. Kusaka left
from Teito Station to go to Beika Station
There's no doubt about it...
But, there's something
about this phone call, that bothers me...
we RE
ERAS
He left the TeitorStation at 8:10...
On this train
Which means it takes approximately
30 minutes to Beika Station so...
He arrives at Beika Station at 8:40!
The crime was committed
between 8-40 to 9-00,
in the vicinity of Beika Station...
I guess this is more or less the picture!
Huh! Oh!
I've figured out who the killer is!
The killer is the other disciple,
Mr. Tsukikage!
Y.You mean Saruhashi?
I hope you have your reasons
for saying that?!
Of course
He said that he lives right
on the other side of Beika Station,
so he knows his way around here
And more than anything else
he has a motive!
I just remembered, 6 months.ago they
had a brawl, didn't they?
Are you telling me
to quit being Sensei's disciple!
Mr. Saruhashi, you studied
under Sensei for many years now
Haven't you studied
all you have to already!
What!!
Come, come now...
Mr. Kusaka, stop it already
I want to study under you too, Sensei
But since you can't watch two disciples...
That's not true, Mr Kusaka!
You have a stable life
of an employee of a company
No matter where
you live there's no difference
in the fact that you're my disciple...
Whether we live near you or not,
makes a difference
in the amount of things we get to learn
Mr Saruhashi,
please change places with me!
That's for Sensei to decide!
Worried of his position as a disciple
Is indeed a motive for killing. but...
It's too childish of a motive. it's absurd...
This is Takagi. yes, I see, goodbye...
It's from the forensic officer
Mr. Kusaka's fingerprints were not
found on the lighter in question
What's this about a lighter?
It was found on'the ground...
by the corpse. the lighter...
Excuse me...
This is the lighter I gave
Mr. Saruhashi some time ago!
What?
Now we not only have a motive,
but also have material evidence...
N.No. Saruhashi. couldn't have!
Mr. 8aruhashi: does
this lighter look familiar tegyou?
It's my lighter...
Though I lost it some time ago...
Lost it? When? Where?
1.l1. don't Know
Please try to remember!
1.1 really don't know
Hmm?!
The key to a cein locker?
Right
It's a precious lighter that
Sensei gave me as a gift
I'm sure that Kusaka stole it
from me because he was jealous...
Mr. Saruhashi!
Officer Takagi...
Mr. Saruhash:...
Where were» ou last night?
Oh, yes...
I was at a coffee shop
in front of the station about 8:00
I came back here once
and from about 8:30
I went 102 pub in front of the station...
Are you sure it was from 8:30?
Wasn't it a little later, like 9:00?
Huh
Mr. Kusaka's. estimated time of death is
thought to bebetween 8:40 to. 9:00 pm...
What?!
Mr. Kusaka called Tsukigata Sense
at 8:10 pm from Teito Station
So he arrived here
at Beika Station after 8:40 pm
Ha. ha, ha #
I went into the pub at.8:30 pm!
I'm sure!
Please check on it.
I'm not lying...Ha, ha, ha...
Thank you so much...
Inspector!!
As to the coffee shop .
It seems he was there
from sundown and left about 8:00!
I got his alibi on this side too
He came at 8.30
and was drinking until midnight
Which means that
Saruhashi has an alibi!
What's going eon...
The story about the lighter is
just a cop out
If Mr. Kusaka stole it,
his fingerprints should be on it!
I'm aware of that... #
He's got a motive
and there is material evidence
But he has an alibi...
Please wait...
It's possible for him to commit the crime!
He left the coffee shop at 8:00
He came to this pub at-8:30
There're 30 minutes of unaccounted time!
And ?!
And he lied about returning
to his apartment
He killed Mr Kusaka
during the 30 minutes!
The scene of the crime is not Beikacho
but between TeitO Station
and Beika Station
If he uses the 30 minutes that
is unaccounted for to the fullest,
he can make it to a station in between
After committing the murder there,
he can still make it
back to Beika Station at 8:30
The actual time the
murder was committed
was not 8:40, but rather, around 8:15
That's not possible, Officer Takagi
What?!
Mr Kusaka left Teito Station at"8-10...
5 minutes later, at 815
Mr Kusaka is still way before reaching
\ the middle point of both stations.
During the 30 minutes time
it'd be impossible to commit murder,
much less even make contact with him
Impossible...
That is, unless. you use
some kind of Ninja technique that
Is described in Ryutaro Tsukigata's
novel or something...
Ninja technique of creating an alibi...
What kind of Ninja trick did he use...
What kind of trick'...
did Mr Saruhashi use anyway...
Hmm?
It's Tsukigata Sensei's new book...
Mysterious Centipede Ninja...
- - -w \v--49
The enemy is your friend
and your friendlis your enemy...
Counter turn after counter turn...
Counter turn?!
Counter...
I m not lying ..Ha, ha. ha...
I got two phone calls
from Mr. Kusaka yesterday...
Tihis is Kusaka
I arrived in Teito Station just now
Saturday, 810 pm
I see, I get it!
If so...
The coin locker
can be used for a period of
3 consecutive days in a row!
0101...Please berinside!
It's there!
So...he's the killer, after all!
Hmmthere're no
hints, no 'matter how muéh I re 4 this...
Huh ?!
What brings you all here...
What're you talking about?
You're the one that told us to
come here. Mr. Mourn
M. Me?
Vv ha!
I made.
No such.::phone ca...
Iaid call you indeed...
Of course, I did so to talk to you about
the homicide case of Mr. Yuichi Kusaka
D.Did you figure
out the Ninja technique?
Yes, one alibi trick was used
in this murder case
It's a very simple trick,
but it was very difficult to figure it out...
Why? Because the one who
used the trick was not the killer!
Not the killer?
Then. who was it?!
When I heard the message
on the answer phone,
something bothered me
That was because despite knowing that
Tsukigata Sensei was
still not home a little after 8:00,
Mr. Kusaka called twice
Why did he go out of his way
to make such a phone call
when it really was no big deal...
Saturday, 8:10 pm
Yes, he did it only
to make everybody believe
1e was a el oO a 1on a pm
To make everyone believe?
Which mean, he was
actually not there?
Mr. Mouri, I found it!
Officer Takag
I found it!
The ticket you asked for...
T.Ticket?!
The ticket that was
retrieved at Beika Station
that day ith
Mr. Kusaka's fingerprints on it
Officer Takagi. what time was it issued?
Oh, yes! Uh
It was sold at Teito Sitien...
at (30 pm /
What, 7:30 pm?
It's not after 8.107?
Just as I thought
He bought the.ticket at 7:30 pm
If he boarded the train right away,
he would've reached Beika Station
a little after 8:00.
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting...
Officer Chiba?
I asked Officer Chiba
% do me a favor 100
I had him go and get
the contents in the coin locker,
which pick up date was overdue...
T.That's Mr Kusaka's bag?!
Huh? This is the victim's belongings?
Is it?
Y.,Yes .
Please put the contents
of the bag on the table
Oh, yes!
Thank you?
And Inspector!
Please rewind that tape recorder a little
Huh?! O.Oh...
TeitoTeito
Mommy, hurry!
It's dangerous to run, Kenichi!
T.This is?!
It's the same as the message
that was in the answer phone!!
Hmm...
Yes, Mr. Kusaka who
reached Beika Station.
Usedsthat to make it seem as if he had
reached Beika Station at 8:10
in order to create his alibi!
The Ninja technique of creating an alibi.
Once the secret is
revealed it is a very simple trick.
The only thing is the one
who used this Ninja trick
was not the killer, but the victim himself.
What did Mr. Kusaka
do something like that for?
In order to kill Mr. Saruhashi!
After the answer phone trick,
Mr. Kusaka rushed over
to Mr. Saruhashi's apartment.
I guess he told
Mr. Saruhashi beforehand.
That he had something important
to talk about or something
If Mr. Kusaka were to work
out the way he planned.
He was probably going to make an
anonymous call to the
police right after killing Mr. Saruhashi
And the time of the crime would
be precisely determined
by the police. who get
there right after the call.
According to his alibi scheme,
from between 810 to 8:40
Mr. Kusaka would be riding the train
to Beika Station, so he would be
erased from the list of suspects.
All he had to do next, was visit
Tsukigatazss house at 9:00 as scheduled
However. it didn't work
out as he planned!
He was counterattacked
by Mr. Saruhashi
who he meant to kill
Dang it!
Mr. Saruhashi who counterattacked,
carried Mr. Kusaka's
corpse to the park and
disposed of it there.
Then. just as you already found out from
Investigations, he went to
the pub at about 8:30
s 7/0
I'm not lying.
Exactly. You weren't lying.
You realized that the police
made a mistake and all y™u
did was decide to use
this to your advantage.
So, you're the one who
killed Mr. Kusaka after all...
I know nothing of that:sort!!
He didn't come to my apartment!
No, I'm sure he did
) If he had intention to Kill.
He wouldn't take the tape recorder that
he used to create his alibi,
nor his manuscript along with him.
So, I figured that he would leave it
at the coin locker of Beika Station.
If something is left in that
Iocker for more than 3 days
the maintenance company
opens it with a spare key.1
Since today was the.3rd day,
I asked Officer Chiba to go get the
thing that was in-the locker.
Mr. Kusaka's bag. that's over the se
But. how did you figure out
the number of the locker?
That's the point.
When we went over to Mr. Saruhashi's
home, Conan found the
key to the locker in
Mr. Saruhashi's room.
0101, It's a number easy
enough for a child to remember
You say that Mr. Kusaka didn't come, but
how.can a person. who didn't come,
drop the key in your room?
My room,
he did come to my room. But...
It's, okay already.
Mr. Saruhashi...
S.Sensei...
1. was afraid of him all this time.
Afraid that he would!take
you away from me...
I'm'happy how you feel about me...
But whether you succeed as a
professional is how much effort you exert!
I guess both Mr. Kusaka and \ 0)
forgot what was most important
DIISINATR SITE SPKS IBY
Producers.
MICHIHIKOSUWA
MASAHITQ YOSHIOKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Gharactcr Designs By
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KANIPKASHIWABARA
KAZUNARIZKOUGHI
JUNICHI MIYASHIIIA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
CHI HIG!
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
. ? 4,00), » 4
EI/NIN UN UJUJUI/AVY/NIN/A
+ ep wd : \
AKIO KAWAMURA
LVL ow CI
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
TMSSENTERTAINMENT, TTD.
Ni association with I
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
AOYAM. 14 JCAKUKAN YTV A
All Ri*1 ever ved
Well, I thought this time for
sure that our hands were tied
But, you never let us down,
do you, Mr. Mouri!
You mean Inspector Shiratorfs
new unmarked police car?!
Oh, come on. Ninja technique
of playing dumb, eh?
You got me there
I can never beat you. Inspector!
He Ninja technique you're
really good at is. all talk. Pops
Then, somebody's just gotta stay at the
hospital in his place. right Conan?!
w0O.Okay
Oh, no...
TheiKidnap Car that Disappeared
Part.1