Deduction flows with
the rhythm of the wind
Dark stains are rinsed
clean and exposed
The summer camp smells of crime
The Youth Detective
Squad helps. out a lot
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the l.Q. of an adult
NO case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
. $2 F
7/2 .
7 O Tp {
& (> -% oO
Oh, hello. Megumi? It's me. Ayumi.
Megumi, about next Saturday...
I have something to do,
but I'm supposed to be
rabbit monitor that day, so I was/wondering
If you could change places with me...
Oh. okay!
You're going out with Conan. right?
Yeah, could you....?
Okay. I'll change with you!
What?!
But promise that yousll tell me
about your trip like always!
Because every time you and
Conan go out together
you get mixed up in
a case of one kind or another...
Okay! I'll tell you everything that goes on.
See you! Thank you, Megumi!
All right!
I get to go camping! I get to go
camping Saturday and Sunday!!
Oh. no...
I wonder-why -everybodysseems to
treat Ai astif she were an adult...?
Everybody tends to call
her by her last name...
I guess it can't be helped because
people who transfer over from
other schools seem mature...
But. friends shouldn't discriminate!
Friendship Torn Apart Part 1
(31%)
Haibara and Doc are late
I wonder what's keeping them...
Doc's probably taking
his time getting ready again!
Okay, when she comes out,
I'm going to smile naturally and
say good morning to her
and call her by her first name.
I wonder if shell be offended...
Oh. but:she might:just,
greet meiintimately too...
But, insher case most times not...
Well, it doesn't matter if she
greets-me the same way or not!
After all, we're friends...!
Oh: Doc! You're late!
It's way past departure time!
Sorry. sorry.
It took a while for us to get prepared...
It's because you didn't get.~yp
everything ready before going to sleep!
You got me there...
What you took time doing,
was:not getting ready
but cleaning up. right?
The minute I take my eyes off you,
there are heaps of trash...
Oh, good morning...
Al. Ar.
IN. 7 \I
I. think you look so sleepy. Ms. Haibara...
Sort of...
Because I'm nocturnal...
Oh bo
Oh well...
I still have a lot of time left...
Hey. Doc
Did you find out the
meaning of that diary?
What diary...?
The-diary of Mr. Itakura
the computer programmer,
who was asked by the Men in Black
to make some kind of system software!
The diary that had the secret dealings
of the Black Organization written
in it in invisible ink on the blank page...
The meaning of the mysterious
Iast word that was written inside!
Oh. you mean the words...
We are trying to revive the dead?
sf BB
We can b
God and
Since we
the dead
We are trying to revive the dead?
ecanb
God and
Since we
the dead
I have no idea what
those words mean but
I've found out that
the woman hates cats!
She hates cats?
I stopped reading then,
because Al came along.
but there was a
continuation to that diary...
After she finished saying so, the meowing
of the cat started getting louder behind her.
The woman started to panic a bit and hung
up the phone. That's what was written...
That's like knowing nothing at all.
She could've hung up because
her cat frolicked with her...
Or she may have been allergic to cats.
There are many people who are. right?
Only if you knew more
about Haibara's father,
Dr. Atsushi Miyano...
Atsushi Miyano
I know Dr. Miyano
I think I met him once or twice at;
the invention announcement site
You mean you know the mad scientist
who was ousted from the scientific society?
Mad scientist?
He was a-'nice and
friendly man. Dr. Miyano
took a liking to my inventions too
His wife-was-reticent and you could
never tell what she was thinking
If I remember correctly,
her name was Elena
Elena?
You mean his wife wasn't Japanese?
Nope. They seem to have met
when she was here in Japan
as an exchange student from England...
But, I had no idea that
she was Al's mother...
I see, no wonder she
Iooks a bit non-Japanese
Come to think of it, Dr. Miyano never
mentioned what he was researching
H.Hey. look ahead!
Whatss wrong!
Thank god...
Be careful. will you. Doc...
It's because you talked
to me while I'm driving
What a big car!
That is big!
It looks to be a camping car.
It shouldn't be left in a
place like this, it's dangerous
Nobody seems to be inside ¢8
KM»,
How lucky I'm sure
camping would be a lot of fun
if we get to come in a car like this!
RE an
Hey. brats!
Quit touching my car
with those dirty hands of yours!
It's our best friend's
precious car, you know!
Right. Haruka?
But, I don't think my uncle who lent me
the car would mind them just touching it
You're kind to kids. aren't you?
You hate me when
I smoked in the car and then
You smoke too much, Reiji!
That's why you fell for her, right
Reiji, because she's kind?
Shut up...
Oh, so it was your car.
I'm so sorry...
It was such a rare car
that I couldn't help myself
I'm sorry...
But our hands aren't all that dirty!
Okay. okay. sonny
I'm sorry.
Hey. Yasumi, will you come take a look?
I think the meat's just
about ready. already
Wow. it looks delicious!!
The meat looks really expensive!
Would you like to join us?
Since there's some more meat left anyway
Are you serious?!
But. NETS for tonight
Come on, don't get stingy!
If we run low, we can always
borrow Haruka's wallet and
go get some more at the supermarket
at the foot of the mountain! Right Haruka!
Sure.
Please eat to your heart's content!
All right!
This is delicious!
You're members of a university circle
?7 vf
Yes. the name's The Outdoor Club!
We go to the mountains
and the beach.
We all went to Hawaii
together before too!
Well, everything is thanks
to our sponsor, Haruka. though!
Not really...
You're good at cooking
Yasumi and Relji's a good driver.
I don't have any
special talents like picking
edible mountain plants or
fishing like our cook here so
the most I can do is dish out cash...
I'm a helpless Ms. Richie-Rich, so
the most I can do is dish out cash
If only for once in my life, I'd like to
say something like that!
Honestly, you're way too
good for a womanizer like Reiji!
Didn't I just tell you to
A rich friend. huh...
They're just like Ran and Sonoko
Are you feeling sick or: something?
You don't seem to be eating much
No. VF was just thinking,
that's how things usually are
Okay I'm going to take it.
How is it?
Too bad. 10 seconds 31!
You couldn't make it under 10 seconds!
No joke!
And I was quite confident
Too bad!
Oh? That. belt,
t's the:same kind that
Yoko Okino:was wearing the other day!
That's. right!
She was wearing her
outfit for her new song. right?
But. I'm the one who found this first!
You've been wearing that a lot
recen y, xaven you, asumi.
Because it's the same as
something an idol IS wearing!
That's right!
Why don't you eat at our place for dinner
as a token of our appreciation for lunch!
Oh: really?
Wow, that sounds great! I guess we can
take it easy till dinner time, then!
Yeah!
How is it, Conan?
Yep. I think it's good.
Let me taste it too!
If you taste it, half of the.curry will
be gone. so you may: not!
Oh well, so sorry
I'll go get:the other people then!
Oh. let's go together!
A A AI
Ai, Ice: I wonder if it'll make them happy
if I told them we also have ice cream
I guess so...
Wow! This curry is delicious!
Like to make our chef taste this too!
Where's Yasumi?
Haven't seen her for quite some time...
Her bicycle's not here so
It seems she's gone somewhere...
Going shopping to the foot
of the mountain is too far
Maybe she went there,
the time is just about right too
There?
There's a great place about
5 minutes uphill by car from here.
I guess I'll go look for her.
Yeah, you guys
want to come too? It's a nice place
Yes: I'll go!
Then, I guess we'll accompany
you all on our Beetle too!
Then. why don't you come with us?
You'd like to ride the
camping car, wouldn't you?
Yes! I'd like to ride it!
Wow, fantastic!"Super!
This sofa is so fluffy!
Wow, fantastic! Super!
There's a TV here too!
There's a toilet and shower too!
It's like a hotel.
This is really something!
What is that sound...
Sounds like it's started already!
Rep!
Can you do what we
did last year this time too!
Okay.
What is it?
Oh. the sunroof
I'll hold you up, so would
you like to take a look?
Can we see something?
You'll see!
See. look
Wow...
Fireworks! Ites fireworks!
Hey. I wanna see too...
It's covered by the mountains
and I can't see it anymore
Okay. let's go back inside...
Okay...
Don't worry. When we get to the top of the
mountain you'll get to see it nice and clear!
Look out, Reij!
What's wrong?
I. I ran over something
that was on the road...
H.Hey. what do you mean something...
D.Don't tell me that...
D.don't tell me that...
WwW. What the
A wooden fence,
wooden fence!
What the, it-scared me.out of my wits,
I thoughtlittwas Yasumi
It seems to have decayed
and fell from above...
So. let's hurry to the spot!
The fireworks might end soon.
Okay.
Wow! How pretty!
Tamaya!
This is indeed a great place
to watchithe fireworks!
Yes, we coincidentally found this place
when we camped here four years ago.
It's a place that not too
many people know of yet!
But, since we'll graduate
start working.
I guess this will be the last
time we'll be coming here together
By the way. I wonder where Yasumi is?
There are bicycle tire marks here!
By this broken fence...
D.Don't tell me she fell
from there or something
D.Don't be silly. If so. we would've
found her on the road on our way here...
B.but...
I'm sure that someone who recently came
here bumped into the fence
with his bicycle and broke it!
I wonder...
Even Yasumi is not that
much of a klutz...
But. I wonder where
Yasumi disappeared to I was positive
that she beat us to that spot
Yes...
Is Yasumi a person who
usually does things like that?
Yes, even last.year she went
there-by bicycle before us
Yes, even last year she went
there by bicycle before us
and boasted being the first one there...
I'm sure she went to
get something to eat!
She's not you. Genta...
Hey. Reiji!
What now?!
S.She, She's there
Yasumibya 4
Yasumi?!
W. Where?!
T.The road...
In the middle. of the road...
The victim is Ms. Yasumi Shirato,
age 22, a university student...
Judging from the wound on her head
it seems she probably hit her head hard
on something and passed away...
You mean she fell to her death?
I believe so...
Is something wrong?
She's bleeding so much and yet
there is virtually no blood
stains on the road
You're right...
/When is the estimated time of death?
Around 5:00 or 6:00 in the evening...
That's strange!
You guys again. what's strange?
We came up this hill by car at night but...
Nobody was lying on the
road at that time!
We found Yasumi when we came
back down by car after a while!
Just what do you mean?
Will you give me more of the details?
Well. brought the kids
to a camping ground nearby,
and we happened to hit it
off well with these people...
Then we decided to ride in their
camping car and come to this
scenic spot to get a view
of the fireworks!
You're friends of the victim. Yasumi?
Yeah, when we went to see the
fireworks and first passed by here,
the fireworks had already
started so it was past 7.00 p.m.
Then, on our way back at about 9:00 p.m.
after the fireworks. we found her...
our friend Yasumi,
who belonged to the same
university circle as
us lying here on the road
Which means that when you passed here
at after 7:00 pm.
You really saw no one lying here?
Yeah, the only thing we saw was the
wooden broken part of the fence
A wooden fence?
See, there's a wooden
ence on OP 0 O Moun awn.
That's where we were
watching the fireworks...
A part of the fence had broken off
and fell to the road below
so I avoided it by slamming on the
brakes. I kind of hit it a bit though
Was it eally a wooden fence?
Of course.
Only when we got to the top it
Iooked more like somebody had
deliberately broken it than
as if it had naturally broken off...
I thought that maybe Yasumi had gone
through it with her bicycle and fell off
Bicycle?
A bicycle that we had in the camping car...
Since the bicycle was missing we decided
to go up the mountain to that spot to
watch the fireworks
and look for her at the same time.
She always liked to
beat us to places too so
I figured that if she did fall from the above
we would find her bicycle or something
on the road along the way,
so I didn't think much of it...
This is...
Let's go to the place where you all?
Say you watched the fireworks!
There are tire marks of a bicycle
near the broken fence
I wonder if she fell from here after all...
Didn't you notice any tire
marks when you came here?
1.1 did notice, but I didn't think
that it there was any connection
Inspector Megure!
What's up. Officer Takagi!
I found the bicycle!
It seems to have been stuck in
the bushes on the
outer side of the guard rail!
Oh, is that right!
Let's verify it. Will you bring it here!
Y.Yeah, no mistake about it!
That's the bicycle we
had in the camping care
Okay, try matching
the wheel mark then!
Yes. sir!
They seem to match!
Isee. which means...
Yasumi came here by bicycle
before you all got here,
and because it was dark, she
stopped her bicycle a bit too late,
broke through the fence and fell over hit her
head somewhere on the road then bounced
and fell together with the bicycle into the
bushes on the outer side of the guard rail
And, while you were
all watching fireworks here
Yasumi's body that was stuck somewhere
in the bushes slipped off to the road below.
Then, on your way back from the fireworks
you happened to find her here...
This looks to be an accident...
Yes, then the thing
about no blood on the
road where she was
found is understandable too
I wonder about that...
Yasumi came here last year too. rights
She should've known about this
open square as well as the fact
that there is a cliff on the other
side of the fence too, right?
If so, I wonder why
she crashed into the fence?
So, it was dark
and she couldn't see the fence...
If it was dark. wouldn't
she try to be even more careful?
She should've known it
as dangerous, right...?
WwW . Well...
Maybe she was happy that she was the
first one here and got carried away?
Right! That's why she couldn't stop
herself fast enough and fell over!
Then...
Oh, watch out. Conan!
If Yasumi fell from here, there
should be a place on the road below
where the blood
stains of when she hit her are.
How about it, Officer Takagi?
Well, the shattered pieces of the
broken light cover were found, but
no blood stains were found yet...
What did you say!
Inspector, could it be that Yasumi
did not fall to her death but rather
Somebody deliberately left wheel tracks
and tried to make it look like an accident
In other words, a homicide.
Which means that the killer is someone
who could freely take
the bicycle from the camping car
Yeah, her friends who
belong to the same circle.
The probability of the killer
being among the three is high!
Orieanal Comic Books By.
SHO AOYA A
Producers.
MICHIHIK@ SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONG
Character Designs By.
MA~SATOMO SUI)()
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
WKANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHI A
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Direlors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI-TAKATANI!
HARUO COCA WA A
ATSUSHI AON@O
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUITANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSH
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chiet Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT; LTD
in: assocration with
YOMIURI TELECASTINC(
CORPORATION
DETHCVE ONAN
¢ GOSHO V\OYAMA SHOCAKUKAN: YTV TMS
Yl Riz his Reserve
ogg =a -
Who drives this camping car?
The one who's good at driving is Reij
who used to be in
a motorcycle gang before
Hey. hey, if it's moving
the car. all three of us can!
What's this?
D.Don't tell me that!
So: that's the story
I figured this case out!
And the only one who
could've worked out this trick is