Deduction flows with the
) yo. \ - t
rmymm-oi the wind
Dark stains are rinsed
clean and exposed
The sad reality over friendship
You can't buy happiness with money.
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the l1.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
)e...
U~=u 1;;
72 Ve ,
Orv Ty
We, the Youth Detective Squad
come along to camp with Dr. Agasa
We happen to run into 4 university
students of an Qutdoor:Club
riding a luxurious camping car,
whose names are
Reiji Fukuura,
Yasumi Shirato.
Haruka Tendo
and Takuhito Meshiau...
But, while we were all having barbecue,
and chatting away
Yasumi disappears.
So we left to look for her and headed for
the scenic point
to watch the fireworks while we were at it,
but she wasn't there either...
On the way back to the camping grounds,
we find Yasumi lying dead
in the middle of a winding road!
Which means that the killer is someone
who could freely take the bicycle
rom the camping car...
Yeah...
Her friends who belong
to the same circle
The probability of the killer
being among the three is high!!
(13214)
Friendship Torn Apart Part 2
W. Wait a minute. officer!
Why do we have to be
questioned for alibi?
Yasumi died of an accident, didn't she?!
Well, it's just to be.sure!
So. please tell us where you all were
around 5:00 to 6:00 when Yasumi died.
Well, we were:all doing/different things.
Moving around here and there...
I was fishing alone...
I was keeping watch over time
and camping!
Then, who drives the camping car?
Reiji used to be in a car gang before
SO he's good at driving...
Hey. hay. if it's just moving the car:
all three of can do it!
Takuhito, sometimes takes
over driving for me,
and Haruka's the one who brings this car
to our meeting place!
Uh, why are you asking us
something like this?
Hah)
Oh, well, I figured if
you can't drive the car
it would be impossible
to move the corpse to wheresit was...
So, you're suspecting us after all?!
Yeah, right!
Huh?!
What the?!
If you leave Yasumi's body
in the middle of the street beforehand,
and pretend not to see her on the way
uphill, then act as if you saw her
for the first time
on your way back, it's not impossible
Moreover, there aren't many cars
going through here,
and if the driver is the killer with nobody
riding in the passenger's seat
when going uphill...
it's true that nobody was sting
in the passenger's seat
when I was driving but...
If I drove in the oncoming lane,
the view outside the window would
change and somebody sitting in
the back seat would've noticed.
And besides I could never do such a feat
as to avoid somebody lying
in the middle of the road
without changing lanes
Besides, when we passed here
the sunroof was open,
and we were sticking our heads out of it,
but there was nothing on the road...
You stuck your heads out of the sunroof?
Yés, When we did so last year
we saw fireworks
from between the mountains...
So. we wanted to show those children
the same thing too:
Well, but you can only catch a view of it
for about 10 seconds
until turning the curve...
ut...if you open the sunroof afte
you successfully avoid the corpse then...
So, like I've been saying,
its Impossible to go by
without running over the corpse!
Right. the car didn't w Be
before or after the sunroof was epened...
What the?
There are-strange looking lines...
on the edge of the sunroof...
It It can't be?!
Conan?!
Hey, Conan!
What're these lines!
This is blood...
Blood dried in streaks...
I $&O...
So, that's the story...
I've figured this case out!
And the only one
who could've worked out this trick is
the one who seems to be
highly skilled in...
Huh?
Oh, my flashlight!
There!
On thank you...Genta!
Are you all right?
Thank you A, A, A, Al...
Please be careful!
It's sort of windy today, and
the car .is-slanted
because it's a slope here...
It's not too bad up here on the car, is it...
Because the night view is so nice...
Agh. this is the place where
we watched the fireworks from the car!
Over here?
Wait a sec... Then, the trick
that I was thinking of a while ago...
Hey, everyone!
It's dangerous Climbing up
a place like that...
Huh /!
C.Conan?!
Hey, Conan!
Where do you think you're going?!
Close call...
I was about to fall for the killer's trap...
The real trick is...
I found it! This is it!
D.Did you find somethin?
Yep, a vinyl sheet.
It seems to have blood on it!
WwW. What?!
True, We'd better report this right away
to Inspector Megure...
I sure am in a fix...
Anybody can use this trick
and there is no evidence
to specify the killer...
I'll just have to...
show the sheet and
watch how he responds...
What?! A blood smeared vinyl sheet?!
Yes! It was stuck on a guard rail
about 50 meters downhill!
I see...It sure is blood...
H.Hey, isn't that the sheet that
we always use when we go camping?
What? Will you come
here and confirm it?
Yeah...
Just as I thought!
h,...But, we haven't been us
recen y ecauseil as a oe in.
But, why would it be in a place like this...
No good...
None of them. are reacting at all...
I've got to search the mountains
and look for some other evidence...
Huh...?
I see...l get it...
Blood splattered on the Killer...
I can understand that
it was done on the spur of the moment...
But, now the killer has no way out...
The killer's made a grave mistake...!!
So, like I've been telling you?!
At around 7.00 p mm. when we passed
here with the camping car
to look for Yasumi
there was nothing on the road.
And 2 hours later, when we came back
we found Yasumi
Iying in the middle of the road!
The only thing that was on the road
was the wooden fence
that fell from right above this road!
And didn't you say
so yourse .0 lcer...
that the place where the fence was
broken and the place where the broken
piece was and the place where
Yasumi's body was,
were all in one straight line.
The traces of the wheels were found
near the broken fence,
and the bicycle was stuck in the bushes
outside the guard rail of the road
where the piece of broken fence was,
SO...
Yasumi probably accidentally crashed
through the fence
and fell to her death...
You also explained that
we didn't see Yasumi
when we first passed here
because she was probably stuck
in the bushes with her bicycle and
slid then down to the road
just before we passed here
on our way back, didn't you?
Y.Yes, that's right.
Then, it was an accident after all!
Why do we have to be suspected?!
There are no blood stains...
on the road that
Yasumi was thought to have fallen to...
If she crashed through the fence and fell,
isn't it strange
that there's not even a drop of blood
on the road where she fell?
N,No...Are you saying that vy
Yasumi was...
And this vinyl sheet!
If these blood stains are Yasumi's ,
it has something to do with the killing...
It sure is connected to the killing!
Huh?!
D Dr. Agasa?!
What the?!
Huh 7!
What?!
Doc...7?7!
With the window closed,
it's hard to hear my deduction, isn't it?!.
Will you please open
the sunroof for,me?!
Oh, yes...!
Why are you up on the car like that?
I just wanted to get a taste of
what it feels like!
To be loaded on the roof of a camping
car after being killed. Yasumi was!!
What it feels like to be loaded
on a camping car after being killed...?
W.Which means that the killer loaded
Yasumi's body on the roof of
this car after all...?!
Yes! The killer. under the pretense of
going to.look for Yasumi got into the car
together with us and dropped Yasumi's
body romdhe top of the roof on the way!
The way Yasumi was killed,
probably went like this...
The killer probably asked Yasumi
to climb up
and wipe the dirty
sunroof or something...
And Yasumi probably agreed,
which after the killer snuck up behind her
and hit her on the
head with a stone or something!
As proof of that, there is a streak
of reddish black line
on the glass of the sunroof!
A streak of blood that remained in
the corner when the killer wiped off
blood that splattered on when he hit her!
But, gramps,
How was Yasumi's body dropped in
a just right place like that!
We were all in the car, you know.
Reijr...
When you. .:.tried to avoid the fence
that came falling on the road right above,
you slammed on the brakes
and drifted slightly, didn't you?
YyYeah....so what?
Ee. . You took advantage
the impact of drifting
and made the body go over the guard rail
throwing it onto the road below...
You left the debris of
the fence on"the road
as a marker as to where to drift the car...
That way, you would be able to
find the body on the way back...
H.Hold it, but there are many
sharp curves before going by there!
If the dead body's not fastened
to something
it would fall way before that point!
Were there masking tape or ropes
on Yasumi's body?!
Oh...come to think.of it, her belt...
IS the same one that
Yoko Okino was wearing the other day...!
Something was on her belt!
But. how could that have been used...
Oh, didn't you notice...
Huh?
The decoration on the tip of her belt,
only one edge was tied...
Yeah, I saw that (00.
I thought it was a fashion of some kind...
Oh, right!"Officer Takagi!
Williyou please close
the sunroof for now?
Oh. all right...
See! 1 here's. the blood streak
I mentioned a while ago!
T's a little away from the edge. isn't?
Why do you think it's that way?
Es it's probably because
the sunroof was a little open
when the person killed Kazumi!
Why was the sunroof a little open?
What do you mean why...
I.l see!
If one edge of the belt was tied. then...
Exactly!
The killer pinched the tied part
to the sunroof
and fixed Yasumi's body in
place on top of the car!
After bending her body in half!!
The killer left the sunroof a little open
so that he could carry out
the murder smoothly.
He left it open because
unless he did so,
after he hit Yasumi to death
on top of the car,
he would've had to go down,
open the sunroof,
then climb up again to stick the string
between the sunroof
and finally come down again
to close the sunroof
Since there is only one button
to open the sunroof by the driver's seat.
You did say a while ago that
when you first passed by here,
you opened the sunroof and watched
the fireworks. but who opened it...?
O. Of course, I did
since I was driving the car...
HaruKa asked me to open it so...
W Well...
I just wanted to do what was good
Iast year, this year too
I see, If so, it's net difficult
to assume that
someone will ask
to open the sunroof this year too.
Even if it is not so,
since you're at the driver's seat ,
you could secretly open it
without anybody noticing it
H.Hey...
You opened the sunroof
and removed the tied part
that was stuck to the window
and let the corpse go free
then you drifted the car on the road
where the piece of broken fence was,
and swing her body down
on the road below
In other words,
the one who can work out this trick is
one with skilled driving techniques
Iike you
who used to belong to a car gang!
You'd think so, right?
Huh?
Huh 2!
The fact is not so!
Actually, I thought so at first too...
But. I had forgotten that...
this car had been going uphill
and that this was just the place
where the sunroof was opened!
But, after seeing the blood smeared
vinyl sheet it dawned on me!
If the vinyl sheet is laid
under the body of the corpse
and friction is decreased, it's easy.
The minute the the sunroof is opened
because of the impact
of the wind and the slope
the dead body would slide off
the top of the car!
Which means that any of you ¢
three could've committed the murder.
I'm very sorry to say this.
But I would like\ ou all
to come to the station with me.
You don't have to do that!
What?
Because the killer has made a mistake
wearing-clothes!
Wearingsclothes?
Will you three stand up
and go out to the corridor?
Shoots...l tell you...
So what the hell can you find out
doing something like this...?
Aght!
What's the matter, Ayumi...?
See, her belt...
Her belt is net through the belt
Ioop of her jeans!
Huh?
Then, don't tell me that...
You're the killer?
(No! I was in a rush
when coming from home...
Ayumi, you took a picture of
everyone, didn't you?
Oh. uh huh...
I think you took a rear view shot
of her 100. if I remember correctly...
Wait...
Here it is!
This is the one!!!
But her belt is through the belt loop
Iike it should be!
It was through the belt looprat first and
why isn't it now?
On, well I took a shower
In this camping car at sundown
0 I may have done: then...
Uh, isuikhecessary to remove your belt
when you take off your jeans?
Oh, it's because I changed into
a different pair of jeans...
Oh...you changed jeans...
Y,Y@Ss...
Could I have a look at it?
Yes...
mm...it sure looks like the on
you reswearing
although you say you changed jeans...
The one in this picture...
W. Well, I guess so...
Then, I don't mean to be rude, \
but please show me the jeans
before you changed...
WwW. Well...
You can't show it to him
even if you wanted to, right? \
It's probably the jeans that
you were wearing when you hit Yasumi,
and you threw it away in the mountains,
somewhere with the clothes
you were wearing back then, right...?
Because they were splattered
with Yasumi's blood!!
But, she let us ride this car
when we went to go watch the fireworks!
R.Right!
Why would she want us to ride the car
that she had the dead body on?
Rather..she had to make us ride the-car!
If I followed this camping car
with my car from behind
I would see the dead body
sliding off the camping car...
But, but .
ou're so rich...
I'm not rich...
ob 00
I'm an ordinary university student
with no special talent...
That's: why:unless I acted rich
nobody would even look at me...
I really had a tough time...
I worked part-time with all my might,
and even borrowed money
to rent this expensive camping car
in order to take everybody
to the beach and the mountains...
U., SOMe Ow Pu eC rough) recause
they were the first friends I had...
Yes...l thought they were my friends...
Until I heard what Yasumi said...!!
Huh, didn't you know?!
It's all just a bunch of baloney that
she's from a rich family!
I could tell right off the bat
that she wasn't
So I followed her, and sure enough,
she was living in a rundown apartment!
Which means I was being deceived
for four years?!
Then why don't you tell her to stop lying?
You're her best friend, aren't you?
Yasumi...
Best friend?
All she means to me is money
Do you think I could continue faking
that I didn't know
about this for four years otherwise!
It was really tough for me
to keep from laughing though...
Besides. if I told her and
she gets angry at me
demanding to get back all she dished out
up to now, what would I do?
I don't think she's that kind of girl...
Too bad, Reiji...
I guess you were sort of
Iooking forward to getting rich, right?
Yeah, too bad...l guess I'll
bid her farewell as soon as we graduate
Well, I guess I'll have her devote
herself and money to me till then
Dear Ms. Richie-Rich, Haruka!
I believed, I believed that
you they were my best friends
T.That's why you killed:Yasumi and
tried to frame Reiji up as. the killer
Yes! I got angry at her
just as she thought I would!
At that woman who had the nerve
to step alllover my feelings of friendship!
That's\not 'being friends at all!
That's not being friends
at all to begin withl!!
Yes, she's right it's no better than the
vending machine of juice cans +/
In other words, if you put money into the
machine it-will quench your thirst.
But if you don't insert money, it
won't give you anything
You can't buy
people's hear-ts with money
Ori191n1l Comic Books 'By.
SHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
WKANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Direlors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHFTAKATANI
HARUO COCA WA A
ATSUSHI AON@O
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
\rt Jirzcius
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
11004 J)
IHHIRONOBU HORIKOSHIIT
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, [dD
In assowition with
YOMIURI TELECASTINC(
CORPORATION
[2872 CIP VIREO LAY O
e+ SHO AOYAMA SHOGAKUKANYTY TMS
\fl Rights Reserved
Al's final remark was splendid!
Yes. it made me feel good!
You sure can make good remarks
when you want to. can;t you, Ail
Not really it's some phrase I heard
somebody elsé say... »
thought:that's how it would nermally be...
Sometime in the past, Ran refused
Sonoko's invitation to go skiing with her
When I asked her why,
she told me a bit depressed,
that she didn't have enough
allowance that month...
I told her to have rich
Sonoko pay her way too.
Then she angrily looked
at me and said
she would never do such a thing because
she wants to stay
friends with Sonoko forever.
That's why I felt that their relationship
with Haruka seemed kind of fake
They seemed to be flattering
her only because she was rich.
But, you were really cool!
You. can call me by
my first:name, it's okay.
You want to call me
by my first name. don't you?
Really, Ail
T.Then can...
Wercalll you:by your first. name too!
NO yourtwo:can t
want to see Senoko s
villain Karuizawa too!
And besides, if I know
Sonoke: for what'she is,
she'll probably think.up.Some no
good idea like always anyway
He's not in bed...