Friendship. Romance. Mystery
Because we 'cherish them wazcan- c "Mime
We will finally get to seethe Yaiba movie
that we had ibeen lookin forward to
Asurprising incident occurs
just before watching it
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
HA AA
(33%)
Secret of the
Toto Processin Station Part 1
295800.
220 horse power,
V=6 cylinder, 24sbulb,
equipped with DOHC engine...
Hey, hey,
couldn't you find any other
rental car, or what?
What's wrong with:this!
US car Is Jus 1e car or me
I think you're speeding too much...
Don't worry!
They don't have any speed traps here
and I'm'being very careful toe...
Hey. fool!
What you gotta be careful of is
not the police/but the speedometer!
Could I ask you something?
Huh...What is it?
Where are we headed?
It's about time you tell us!
Please!
To-a.place that you'd all leve to go!
Gee, how mean...
MrsfEdogawa!
I told you that she's not my mother,
but a middle aged relative™of mine...
She's my older sister...
Se oe
Hello?
What's wrong with calling her middle aged,
when that's what she is...
Huh
Oh. Mr. Karata!
You're having trouble with the timing
and the time for Zero may be delayed?!
Okay. okay...
We're on our way there, so I'll see you!
What is this Zero about?
The number of a robot or something?
Come on, please tell us!! (
It's a secret.
What!! Stingy-! What's the big deal!
We're probably just
going to see the prerelease of "Kamen
Yaiba the Movie II" or something, right?
Huh?
Is that true?
Wow-~~!!
4 I want to see it! I really want to see it!
Here goes. Joker!!!
Kame, Yaiba
How did you...
figure out.that we were going to the see
the prerelease of Kamen Yaiba...?
Because timing means adjusting
the color of the images and
zero means a film that
has just been made.
Both words are a jargon of
the movie and drama industry.
Then,
That's how I figured out it must
be "Kamen Yaiba the Movie".
Oh...
Since we get to see zero'...
It probably means the release
date is coming soon,
ge'!
SO they're going to use "zero
for the prerelease, right?
Right!
Just as expected of you!
Hey, the signal's changed
to green some time ago!
Huh»?
No: joke...
«Oh no, it's changed to yellow!
I'm sorry...
How absentminded of me...
Hey! Cut it out, will you!
You got children in the car, you know!!
Okay! Okay!
Hey, wow!
It's like we're riding a jet coaster!
Ouch!
Hey!!
Conan. your mother is sure a lot of fun!
Keep telling you she's...
So; this is the Toto Processing Station...
It has a very long history...)
It has walked the path along
with the movies of Japan.
Come on, lets: go.
Behave yourselves, okay.
Okay"!
Hey th Ye. Yukiko. Long time no see!!
You're as beautiful... as ever!
Yes. of course.
You haven't changed
a bit yourself Mr. Karata...
Oh, that's right.
He's Mr. Katsuta the one who's going to
show us.the-newly made
Kamen Yaiba movie!
Nice to meet you!
He's the timing man and
he finishes all my movies with nice colors!
Right!!
Huh
Whichemeans...
Did you used to be an actress?
Yes.
Maybe I was
adored by your mother and father.
What?
No joke!
Really?
I see...
Huh?
Your power of deduction was
handed down. from your father I see...
Liking to stand out,
your confidence the acting talent that you
display when using the voice changer...
Moreover, your dangerous character of
acting on impulse when angered...
you inherited from your mother...
Well, sorry...
And?
When will you be able to)
show the zero preview?
Well, I think it's going to take a while yet...
I think we can manage to get it
done around 7.00 p.m. though...
I'm sorry, but could you
wait around till then?
You can takefa tour around
this place'if you like...
Okay!
Mr. Hojima and Mr. Megami!
Do me a favor and show:Yukiko
and the kids inside the processing station?
Sure...
Okay!
This is the preview room where you'll
all be watching the movie later!
Wow -----1! It's like a theater!
I want to see it quick
This is the dark room! This is the room
where you check for scratches
and spots before putting
the film through the developing machine!
And this is the developing machine
for the 35 mm films!
Well? Isn't it interesting
with all the machines around?
Yes!
It's' like a laboratory!
What's this sound?
It's a warning telling us
not to open'the double door
because someone's
going Into the: dark room
While the film is being checked
even a slight amount of light with
over expose the film and damage it!
After the film is checked, Mr. Megam/
here is the man who makes
the negatives by putting the films
through the developing machine
Then,
I make his negatives into positive prints!
Oh...
Then, the films are edited and
dubbed with sounds, the timing man,
Mr. Karata who you met earlier adjusts
the color and the finishing touches!
Oh...
How come only you don't have
man" at the end of the job you do?
Huh?
Come to think of it,
we don't say, print man...
Right...
Could it be that-you-re weak?
W.Weak...I'm not a transforming hero
or anything lik" tba you; know...
Oops.it's almest™6:40 p.m...
Shall we go into the preview room then?
I guess so...
It's going to take a while
to see that preview!
But Mr. Karata told us a while ago
that it would be, ready about 7:00...
According to Karate.
He says it'll take till about 11:00
It's going to run that late...
Well, I guess it doesn't concern me
cuz I goofed and I'm out of work...
You sure look sleepy!
Did you play mahjong again?
Sort of...
But...what a fix...
What seems to be the matter?
I won't be able to make my flight back
if it's going to be 11:00,
I can't make the children stay here
till that late, besides .
Then
shall I watch the children in my room?
Huh?
My condo is right clo. 8 by...
They can sleepgthere
until it's time for the pré-iew.
Then I'll take them home by car
after they finish watching!
Okay...Could I ask you to do so?
Are you going to imakethe children sleep
in that sloppy room?
How rude...
It may be sloppy. but it's not filthy
Well, it's only
if the children want to though...
Let's stay over and watch-it,
okay Conan?!
Bedsides, tomoerroldis: Sunday 32
We can boast about it to the other kids
in school too!Okay, Conan?!
Okay, then call. your folks and
tell them that you're going to be late!
Okay!!We did it!! All right!
Okay then, let's get work over with
and take: a snooze too then!
Right! We'd better get ourselves ready
for the usual film completion celebration
all- night mahjong game, man!
What's an all-night mahjong game man?
Does it have something to do with
the developing man?
It means we're going to
play mahjong all night!
What?
What's with you!You sure are
popular with girls, aren't you!
Oh Ayumi...
And the other girl too...
Ms. Haibara...
What?!
She...stared at you at least
10 times today!!
Ha.ha...l guess she was watching
the growth process of the guinea pig
who drank the drug she made.
How Ty! Girls look at boys...
either because there's something
on his face or because...
she's in love with the boy!
No way...
I hope you got rid of that car
that was tailing us on our way here!
Oh, so you noticed them too, Shinichi?
@f course...
You were stoppedwall-the while the traffic
signal changed from green to yellow,
butitheicar behind us
didn't"even toot.a horn.
In other words.
They didn't want us to notice them...
That is, they were tailing us!
They were tailing us for quite some time...
Right... thought so too.
So I was planning to take off
as soon as the light turned red...
I wonder who they are?
Well...if that car was after me...
it's highly likely that it 'those guys...
Those guys that shrunk my body
The probability is high
that they are the men in black...
if that car was after me...
it's highly likely that it's those guys
Those guys that shrunk m body
The probability is high
that they are the men in black...
Hmm.
Nos .there is another possibility...
The person who is riding that car...
is a great fine of mine!!
That person probably wanted to kn
where I live and get my autograph!
Oh my-poor thing
I sure hope so...
You'd better protect them nice and good,
because you're all they've got...
Yeah...
I Know...
See you then, everybody!
Enjoy watching the preview
and go home safely!
Okay! Thank you!
Oh, that's right!!
Uh, come here...
Huh? What is it?!
And the girl that was staring at you...
Make sure you escort her all the way,
and see that she gets home safely
I know.get off my back...
You're going to be late for your flight...
Oh. right. see you then, Shin-chan!
I'll see you all some time again!
T,This is...
It's way messier than I imagined it to be...
Don't you know how to clean up...
Hmm~~~Okay then,
Iet's clean up before we take a nap!ya
Agh!
No. no, don't touch!
Huh? Why not. ?
L.I'mrgoingsto loose track of
where everything 1s
OoOh~~~~I see #
Oh, really...
There...
Okay. wé'll'sleep on the sofa,
so you kids sleep in this room...
If you sleep sideways on this bed,
I guess you can all sleepihere!
Ugh!
This room is messy too...
You can say that again!!
I've been busy recently so...
Aha, ha. ha .
E hem! Uh...
I Oood work...all day today! ,
I'm going to give my best shot...
playing all-night mahjong tonight
What is he doing?
(\O)
I will tell you later...
Recently,
he's been hooked
on making video diaries...
I'm going back to the station
because I've still.got work left to do
Wow, what shall I do?!
What shall I do?
I'm so excited, I can't sleep!!
Hey, Mitsuhiko, are you asleep?!
Uh...no. not yet...
The subtitle was "Counterattack of the
Lord of Potatoes right?
No. the subtitle that was shown
in the preview was...
The subtitle... was
It was...subtitle...
Oh darn~~~I
The Requiem of the Potato Queen!
Don't forget!
They're fast asleep...
It can't be helped...
They're children...
unlike us...
Can...
Can I ask...you something...
Is there anything on my face?
Huh
Guaaah!!
Hat was that...
Hey, Mr. Furumura? What's the matter?
Mr. Furumura?!
Fu...Furu... M\Mr. Furu ura
Conan... What was it...?
Is it time?
Mr. Furumuraw 4
How was it done in the dark...
Ori1einal Comic Books By.
SHO AOYA
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
» @haricter Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI IO A
ScPipts By.
WKANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHI
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUD
HIROTOSHITAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
IAKASHI NOMURA
IRONOBU HO
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By.
IMS ENTFRIAINMENT, 1 TD.
In assowation with
YOMIURI TELECASTINC(
CORPORATION
DEC HVESEDNAN
CDHO AOYAMA SHOGAKUKAN-YIV IMS
AllRip his Reserved
rope) = pefyper
I think it's almost impossible to
run away in such a short time
from this dark, messy room
without makingra sound...
There was no sound of the...
what so ever...
A soundless murder...
I see...that's why he was flustered and
CH «9
No doubt about it, he's the killer...
Secret. of the
Toto Processing Station Part 2