Friendship. Romance and Mystery!
Because we cherish them we can contin'e
A soundless murder in darkness
Conan's clear deductive in the messy room
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
We all head over together
with mom to the Toto Processing Station
to watch the preview of the new movie
Kamen Yaiba the Movie II
However, it ends up that the preview
that was scheduled could only be
shown late at night. so wethad to wait
Mom goes back to the U.S.
while we all go over to Mr. Akira
Hojima's condo to take a nap
Guaaah!!
(152%)
Secret of the Toto
Processing Station Part 2
(152%)
The victim is
Mr. Tokuhiro Furumura, age 39...
He seems to have been employed
at the Toto Processing Station
Iocated opposite this condo
One stab through the chest with a knife...
He seems to have been stabbed
from over the blanket
in order to avoid blood
splattering onto the killer...
Oh...uh
Hmm'!
They all just happened to come
to take a short nap at my place
We were planning to
play all might mahjong
after the movie was completed tonight...
MM Movie 7?
Yes...
The preview showing of that movie
was extended to around 23:00
o we all decided to
take a short nap together,
including those children... ,
I see...
And?
Where were you all sleeping?
That room!
and>slept on that bed.
All five of us lined up sideways
Then.
We heard a man shout...
When we opened: the door
and turned on-the light,
this is what:we saw...
Oh...
I see...
But. it's strange
What's strange?
We didn't hear the murderer...
That's because...
you were sleeping...
But, it's after Mr. Furumura was killed!
It's only natural
hat we'd at least hear the sound of
somebody leaving the room...
The killer probably
tiptoed out
Well, isn't it true...
ell, isn't it true...
That it would be pretty impossible
to escape from*his room in a short time...
being as messy as it is?
Which means that the killer...
IS the person sleeping next to the sofa
the victim was sleeping on...
Mr. Hojima...
Oh no...!
There were no signs of the door
being forced open either...
WwW. Wait!
People other than me
have the spare key to this room!
People who work at the same
processing station as I...
Iike Mr. Karata...
and Mr. Megami...
What?!
F.Furumura was...?!
By who?!
We'll soon find out after
you all tell us about yourselves
Will you please tell us
what you were doing and where you were
at the time of the
murder around 10.55 p m!
At that time,
since "was almost done with timing...
Ieft the rest of the work
with another worker
went to take a rest at the nap room...
T. Timing?!
It involves adjusting the color
for movies and dramas...
Can anyone verify that for you?
There were two to
three other people there,
but they were all asleep...
And...
1.1 was alone
in the dark room checking the film...
SO you both...
don't have an alibi?
N.No...
And?
Will you explain why you had a spare key?
So that I could play mahjong right away...
The ones who finished work first
woul '1 come here
and get the game. set up and all go
But,
maybe we weren't the only ones
who had the spare 'key/
He seemed to'have other people
he played mahjong with too...
the only people I gave my spare key 10
are those two
and Mr. Furumura
But...
If you,used to come here
and knew where everything was...
maybe...
It could be possibleito move around
easily even in the dark...
But...
Huh?
C.Conan?!
See! This room is really...
pitch dark...
Hey! Don't interfere with the officers!
Yes. sir
But Conan's right
Right...
If it's that dark. no matter how
used to you are/to this place.
You're bound to bump into something
inspector, may I have a moment with you
Huh 2!
The 3rd button of the corpse's shirt
has been yanked off...
Hmm...It seems as if...the victim has
struggled with the killer, before he
was stabbedthe victim has struggled
with the killer, before he was stabbed
His shirt sure is dirty though...
His collar«is soiled black...
Mr. Furumura used to hate bathing and
used to take baths only once a week or so
Come to think of it,
when werplayed 3 days ago.
He was weainingithis shirt too...
Which means he
hasn't changed since then...
I could never do something like this!
I could never struggle with him.
Yank off his button or stab him WM
in a pitch dark place like this!
But. if you were the only one
ISP
awake at that time,
you could've confirmed
the position of the victim
with a flashlight or something
and approached him. couldn't you?
And besides. the children haven't heard
the killer running away...
Or...did you hear the killer
making any sound?!
Oh.no...
I was surprised at hearing Mr. Furumura's
voice that I noticed nothing else...
What's tha a.
Inspector!!
There's a video camera on the floor...
Huh
W.What's with this video camera...?
Oh, this is the video diary that
Funumura used-to take everyday...
Don't tell me the video was
kept running all this time...
Okay! Connect it to the TV. right away
and play it!!
There may be something it in
that would give us a clue to the murder!!
Y.Yes, sir!
Good work...all day today!
I'm ..going to give my best shot...
playing all-night mahjong tonight
Ill report the result later!
Hmm? It's been switched off once here...
Oh!?
It switched back on again
But, it's pitch black and
you can't see a thing...
Guwhaaa "
In Inspector!
Agh. aaaagh...
Hey. Mr, Furumura, what's the matter?
Mr. Furumura?!
1. This is my voice...!
That's the sound I made *
when I opened the bedroom door
MM. Mr. Furumura?!
Kyaaaah!
This is where this boy
turned onsthe light.
But. why did the video camera
switchback on again?
The impact of the video camera
falling to the floor when he struggled with
the killer probably set it back on again.
The problem here though. is the sound
Until the.victim shouts. Conan opens
the door and Ayumi screams,
there is no sound
other than your voice, Mr. Hojima...
Which means that...
N.No way! If I was planning
to do something like this,
I wouldn't have brought
hese children here to take a nap!
Besides, I have no reason
to want to kill Mr. Furumura...
Y. You do...
You had a grudge on him
for spoiling your precious movie...
h... The last episode of the series
Doting Parents' Diary
T.The same goes for you,
right. Mr. Megami?!
You weresreally"angry too,
werenlt you. Mr. Karate?!
WwW. Well. it's true. 1 but...
What do you mean?
W.:Well...
when he was checking the film,
Furumura overlooked a scratch.
Developed it the way it was
and cut the film...
Because of it we suffered a great loss...
We had to pay for all the retake
of the scenes
that were no good after being cut...
But film checking is done
in the dark room and is tough work
thatlis done virtually by the sense of
touch of the fingertips so...
It was work that was. too hard
on him to begin
because he used to play mahjong
till early morning almost everyday...
Checking the film I ithe dark room...
Mr Megami?!
Don't you do that too?
Yes: :-He usedjpto be
a developer before too...
After that incident,
Furumura was switched over to sales...
I don't see why three.of you need
to hold a grudge against him, though?
Were your bonuses decreased too?
That Doting Parents' Diary series was
the pride and joys
of all of us working here...
It's only natural to hold a grudge against
him for damaging the final episode...
Mr. Furumura alone, didn't. seem
to proud about it. though...
It's not that we held that much
a grudge against him...
In a SA,
KRY =~ F
a grudge against him...
rE 2»
poe As /
- y - or
He was one of the members
we played mahjong with after all...
Ja 7 O
- (O2--
Most of us have forgotten
about it already...
A soundless murder...
From that front door to this door
Even if you were to be able to pass
easily with no obstructions...
The toughest part
would-be this living room...
It's virtually impossible
to go through here in a short time
without making a sound .
Then, the killer would have to be...
Mr. Hojima, who was here
begin with...
Mr. Hojima. who was here
to begin with. .?
C.Come to think of it!!
That video camera was also...
I see...That's why he was...
flustered and did what he did...
If so. the unexplained thing about
no noise on the video tape...
And the button
that was yanked off all fit in!!
QC» 4
The killer 1s probably hum...
\ The only one who could've committed
the murder in this pitch darkness is him!
But. I don't have proof...
What now?What do I do?
What's the matter. As?
You look dreadful
it's nothing...really
She says it's nothing .
Really?
D.Don't'tell me that?!
So. what we clearly know now is...
Mr. Furumura who was sleeping
on the sofa around 23-00
was stabbed to death
by someone in the dark...
If the Killer stabbed Mr.-Furumura and fled
he would've most naturally, bumped
Into something and made noise...
But the children who were
sleeping in the next room
heard no noise at all...
Moreover. the video camera
which seemed to have fallen
to the floor and switched on
when the killer and Mr. Furumura was
thought to have struggled with each other
had no such sound recorded in it...
In other words,
the killer is the one
who was sleeping next to the sofa
where Mr Furumura was sleeping
Mr Hojima!
You're the only one~lscan-come up>with!
Agh. wait!
Absolutely!
D.Dr. Agasa?!
DD. Doc 21
Conan called me to ask me
to come pick him up
I heard about the case on the phone...
No matter how much I think it over,
I come up with just one answer!
That there is probably no-doubt
that Mr. Hojima committed the crime!
An ordinary person
wouldn't be able to move
around in the dark
without making a sound....!
Maybe it'd be a different story if you were
a ninja or a ghost, though!
Gha. ha. ha. ha...
Dr. Agasa! You think so too...
But, there is just one thing
that bothers me...
Huh'?
Remember. the third button of
Mr. Furumura's shirt that was yanked off
when he struggled with the killer?
It hasn't been found yet, has it?
N.Now that you mentioned it. no...
Without it. it just doesn't feel good" .
It couldn't be that the button
had wings and flew off
It's probably;somewhere
in this messy room...
or. the killer still has it on him...
I'd recommend you to do a thorough
body check of Mr. Hojima
when you take him for questioning
to the station...
Y.Yes. I will...
Mr. Hojima!
Please come to the station with me...
A-All right. . -
But...l.I'm not the killer!!
Then, Mr. Konjo and Mr. Karata,
Iet's go too.
Yes. sir...
Did I do okay?
Yeah... just great...
So, we'll go to the police station
for questioning too!
You all slept once,
SO you can all stay up. right?
Ay III
Hey [Ai..let's go!
Y.Yes...
But...l really wanted to see
Yaiba's movie...
Oh, wait...
Let's all go see it together
when it's released...
W Why /!
Just as I-thought...
It was you after all...Mr. Megami...
W Why
Sound...It was the sound...
ound...?
B:. But the children said
they heard no sound...
the same with the video tape...
Right. it's true that
there were no suspicious sounds,
But. it was too soundless...
If the video camera dropped to the floor
NY and switched on the sound back
then of the video dropping or the sound
of the struggle should've been recorded...
But. since it had no sound.
Chances are,
the killer deliberately pressed
the record button and put it on the floor...
It could be that the killer was
confident of fleeing from
a dark room without making a sound...
And, your job as a developer also
made me suspect you...
Huh
You seemed to have mentioned that
working as a developer requires one
to check the scratches on the films only
with the sense of touch of the fingertips...
No matter how used to you are to
the dark room,
it is impossible to work in
a room with no light at all...
That's why I thought you would've had to
place some kind of mark
in the room to help you locate
things even in the dark...
And walla! I found it
as Soon as I entered this room...
Among all the things cluttered in 7
this room. on every corner
I found these black tapes!
This probably...
IS black vinyl tape pasted on over
fluorescent tape...
See. "there are tapes
tape under them are slightly showing...
Unless...light is kept
at a low level in this way.
The film in the darkroom would
probably over expose...
So. although
an ordinary person can't see right away
when the lights are turned out...
when their eyes get used to the dark,
they gradually start being able to see
Using this light as a guide
and walkin carefull
aware of where everything is located...
U's possible to go through
without bumping into anything...
I happened to change
the position of some things.
SO you seemed;to have
panicked a'bit this time...
That's why when Conan turned off the
Iight you turned it right back on right?
You did so because you didn't want others
and realize what you had done...
Now that you mentioned it, there is
black tape on this video camera too...
Even if he could tell
here the camera was...
would he be able to tell where the chest
of a person who is asleep is?
If the body were to move even a bit.
It would be impossible
to commit the crime...
The button
He probably put a bit of fluorescent
paint on Mr. Furumura's 3rd button
to make out where the chest
was even in the dark
In other words, if you can get into the
room with the spare key,
you can stab him in the
chest even in the dark...
You must've painted the button
3 days ago
when you played mahjong all night and
he was fast asleep...
Knowing that he only takes b
aths once a week,
itss very likely he wouldn't change shirts...
Then, you decided to bring back the button
after peeling off the fluorescent paint from
it because if someone finds
it the trick would be revealed...
On top of that since you heard me say
it's strange that the button
hasn't been found.you returned the button
after peeling off the fluorescent paint...
After Dr Agasa explained
everything to me,
I finished questioning you first of all,
and was waiting herein this room...
but I didn't expect this outcome...
It's amazing how Mr. Furumura
who worked tapes...
as a developer like you,
didn't notice the fluorescent tapes...
Notice what?
These tapes were pasted on b
y Furumura himself...
He told me that he pasted the tape
onto the video camera
so that he could get a hold of
it any time in the dark...
He said that he also pasted tape around
the room so that he could find
the restroom if-he needed
to go late at night.
He did it as a-prank and
didn't let Hojima in on it
I always knew that
he was unreliable, though...
But; I just couldn't forgive him
for what he did back then...!
When he damaged
the film of the final episode
of the series "Doting Parents' Diary
I just couldn't overlook his mistake!!
But. you did a:retake and the movie
was successfully completed, wasn't it?
No good .r~it wasn't perfect...
Because in the original film,
the younger brother of the star
of the show was also acting in it...
But. just before the retake
he died in a traffic accident...
So we had no
choice but to do without him...
That's why that movie is not perfect
or ever will be complete...!
Just because of him...!
E's to blame ..Uuugh...
Orion] Comic Books 'By.
EOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I1OKA
Scripts By.
WKANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHI
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Dircewlors.
MASATOMOSIXJIDO
HIROTOSHITAKATANI
HARUO COCA WA A
ATSUSHI AON@OO
AKIO KAWAMU A
TAKASHI HYOD (9
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
IAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIK@ HI
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
IMS ENTERIAINMENT, 1 TD
in assowaltion with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DEE CLVE LON AN
OGOHO AOYAMA SHOGAKUKANYTV TMS
Al Rivhis Reserved
rope /7 . ~7 a
Doc.
Thanks for everything!!
H.Hey...hold it...
Come back here then. will you!
Although it's a bit far, run over here
because it's good for your health!
C.Conan...
Shh...
Don't worry...
that cigarette is like...a car tooting its horn
waiting for the traffic light to change...
If you don't want them to
be aware of our existence,
Iet's not toot our horns from our side
The same with the condo
they were watching...
From what we saw from that window,
he was not smoking a cigarette
If we saw the lit cigarette he was smoking.
It would be: like.we were telling/him
from our siderthat we:are: here...
It's the basics of a stake out!
But, he just happened to be smoking
a cigarette in our view
it's only proof that he lost track of us...
Since he's still waiting around here,
it means that he most probably doesn't
have an idea of where we live, right?
I had Officer Takagi deliberately go
through a drunk driving checkpoint,
and bring us all the way here...
It's no wonder they lost track of us...
Dflbnttlfitell me... that they...
Beats me...
The only thing I'm sure of is
that he's not one of my mom's fans...
It seems that
his target is either you or me...
So, we've lost track of them...
It's all right...
The string hasn't been severed yet...
keep it up...
But...
She sure resembles...
W.What are those scratches...
I got it.
I've figured out the real meaning
behind this accident
The Tiruth Behind 'the Death Fall