Rriendship. Romance. Mystery
Because we cherish them we can continue
A strange case at an ordinary train station
«+ There's only a marginal differences
between goodwill and evil
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Ghads...
You keep drinking so much juice.
That's why you have to keep
going to the restroom!
But. it was good. wasn't it, Pops?
It would've been nice if Ran
could've come with us too...
It can't-be:helped. can it!
She had club practice and suddenly
ended up not being able to come...
By the way.-what do you say...?
We go have some Ramen
before going home?
What?! You're going to eat again?!
There:s, something about French food
that gives me stiff shoulders.
I don't feel like I've satisfied my appetite.
Come on, let's 0 dro » at a ramen sho!
Next stop is Nishi-sumida.
You can transfer for the Saika line.
The Truth Behind the Death Fall
The train will be come:-in.
Please stand behind-the:white line.
So. for ramen!!
Here we go. Conan!
I think I want salt flavored ramen.
What flavor do you want?!
Hey. hey. Pop's really set on going...
You jerk!!
Talk about trouble. those guys.
Cut it out, cut it out!! Stop fighting!
I'm telling you, cut it out!
Are you guys deaf or what?!
Whaaaa
Oh, Inspector Goto!!
We've been waiting for you.
Is anything wrong?
Mouri...?
Agh»! You: re Mr Mount.
That renown detective!!!
Huh? Really?
Y-Yes...
I am Goto of West Sumita Police Station.
Well, I've heard a lot about you
But. I didn't think I'd get to see yoyhere!
I'm really honored...
He coincidentally witnessed what
may be the cause of this incident...
Huh!
You did. Mr. Mourn?
es, u..we...
I didn't think that something
Iike this was going to happen...
Well, its reallyia great help
that you're here Mr. Mouri.
We're:counting=on you.
Oh, uh, I hope I can be of help...
I guess you can leave things to me,
since I'm here anyway.
6y...
And. have you identified the victim?
Yes,
he is Keisuke Furuta age 42.
He is an office worker who lives nearby
He seems to always
come home on this train,
and it seems that he was on
his way back home today too.
The cause of his death is due to a fractured
skull from a violent blow to his head
He got into a fight... with this person here
Mr. Hideki Sugimoto age 27.
He works at a company
in the city of Tokyo.
I am Goto from
the West Sumita police station.
Will you please explain
what just happened...
Hmm~~~ it's kind of noisy here...
You may use the break room
for station employees if you like...
Mr. Noriwaki!
Yes sir,
this way. please
Oh, that would be a great help.
What is»... thisswound he has here...?
I went to an after-hours
business contact meeting tonight,
and I was on my way back home...
I suddenly had to-go to the restroom .and
put my knapsack-on the. net shelf,
then headed for the restroom.
Myistomach was feeling queasy
soil stayed inside. for some time.
And came out.
My knapsack was gone!
Oh!... And?
Then? I happened to look out
it the platform and...
saw him with my knapsack!!
H-Hold it!!
What do you think you're doing...
That's my knapsack!
Just what do you think you're doing?!
W-What's with you?!...
He wouldn't give my knapsack back to me.
So you got into a fight...
Yes...
and when I tried to bet
ck... apsack ba my kn
the strap cut off and...
Whaaaa
Unluckily the under construction
fence wasn't there...
Which means you
haven't met Mr. Furuta before?
N-No...
I haven't!
What do you think, Mr Mourn...
el sorry for him...
Mr. Furuta wouldn't have
gone through what he did
if he didn't take Mr. Sugimoto's
knapsack in the first place...
U... Uh...
I wonder if Mr. Furuta was really
trying to steal Mr. Sugimoto's bag?
What do you mean?
Maybe he thought that
somebody had forgotten it?
F-Forgotten?!...
YES.
He has delivered forgotten goods
to us several times in the past too...
I Among all of us we thought that
he was a nice person, a rare breed,
a rare breed, not too easily found in
Iately. He doesn't seem like the type
who would steal something that
someone else had forgotten.
Are you serious?
Definitely!
Mr Mouri
Hmm...
If it's really as you say,
he may have confirmed the owner
of the bag before he got off the train...
Go and question the passengers
on the double!
Yes sir!
Inspector...
Please calm down, Mr. Sugimoto.
Anyways, we'll just wait till
an eyewitness testimony comes out.
Y-yes, sir...
It's just as the Station employee had said...
Mr. Furuta seems to have confirmed
whether the owner was around
before cettin off the train.
R-Really?
Yes.
There was a passenger
who remembered you, Mr. Sugimoto,
when you stood to go
to the restroom, and
also saw that Mr. Furuta
came on the train after you.
In other words...
Mr. Sugimoto went to the restroom
Ieaving his knapsack on the net shelf.
Then Mr. Furuta who boarded the train later,
took the knapsack to be a forgotten item,
took it and got off the train...
mm Mr. Sugimoto who had gone
to the restroom; thought
that his knapsack was:being stolen.
Found Mr. Furuta among the passengers
who had gotten off the train
and tried to get it back.
Mr. Furuta thought that
e confirmed the owner,
so when he was told to
Give the knapsack back
he couldn't believe it off the bat...
Mr. Furuta was also probably
a ven righteous man.
He probably got into a fight trying to keep
the knapsack from being taken away...
I guess this Is a tragedy...
That was born from misunderstanding
O-Oh no...
You're to blame too.
You know, Mr. Sugimoto!
You didn't have to jump on him
so aggressively as you did too...
I lost my temper...
He goes out of his way to deliver
a forgotten item and dies,
poor guy...
You can have this back.
It.It's gone!
What seems to be the matter?
The receipt is gone!
Receipt?
The receipt of the store
I went to with my client.
I had it-in here with the change!
Both are gone
Maybe you put it in
your pocket or something?
No. I'm positive I put it in the wallet.
Give me a break...
Maybe it fell on the platform when
ou were stru in with each others...
Officer Saito!
I'll go check!
How was it?
Well,
there, was nothing of
that sort on the platform...
ut... Inspector!
I brought Mr. Furuta's belongings...
Japanese Restaurant Sasayama? )
Inspector.
Could you show me that?
Excuse me.
Just as I thought!
This is the receipt I was looking for!
See.
Mr. Hideki Sugimoto.
The price was for the food was
25000 yen.
ut, why was it in Mr. Furuta's pocket?
I can't figure it out.
U-Uh... the thing is...
It was just once in the past...
But. there was a time that money
was taken from the forgotten item
that Mr. Furuta had turned in.
AN -»
What?!
Back then...
Mr. Furuta was suspected too...
But. he was deemed innocent
after we decided that the thief wouldn't
go turn in a stolen item...
see, so that's the story.
Mr. Furuta probably had
a habit of stealing money
from the forgotten items he turned in.
A habitual thief?
That's why he
couldn't return the knapsack.
Because if he did.
The fact that he stole the money
would be revealed on the spot...
Iv 1) [Al
1a SS es ory...
Mr. Furuta would never
do something like that...
It's very difficult to believe...
Mr. Sugimoto!
Oh... yes!
Just to be safe.
Will you check to see
if anything else had been stolen?
Y-Yes, sir.
Everything else is here
I see...
Please fill in this form then.
Yes...
Oh. could you please lend me a pen?
Oh, excuse me...
for not noticing it...
Here you are.
Oh. thank you...
You jerk!!
It's just as I thought...
I see, that's the story...
I figured out
the real truth hidden behind this accident...
Ghads...
what kind of important talk could there-be...
And, where'd Conan go off to...
after calling me out like this...
Pops
you can leave the rest to me...
Okay... this will be fine
Inspector Goto!
What's the matter?
Mr. Mouri wants all of us
to come to the platform
To the platform...
What on earth is itr. Mourn?
Look at the pose?!
The rumored
Sleeping Kogoro?!
But Inspector...
Agh... Mr. Mouri,
this case was solved already as
being an accident that happened from
a man trying to get back his knapsack...
That's not the story; though,
Inspector Goto!
What?!
Just what do you mean?!
I'll explain that in a minute.
First of all, will all of you try to
recall Mr. Sugimotds testimony.
It's true that Mr. Sugimoto returned
after going to the restroom and
realized that his knapsack was gone.
He sees Mr. Furuta on the platform
and rushes off the train...
That's right, isn't it...
Yes. right!
But the Mr. Sugimoto that we saw
came dashing out from
near the vending machine.
And. is there anything strange about it?...
Don't you think it's strange?
If Mr. Sugimoto jumped off
the train from the front.
Why would he be in a place like that?
He would've ran there from
an absolutely different. direction...
Agh?! I see.
Ome to think of it, yes...
It's unnatural that he was by
the vending machine over there...
ut. why did Mr. Sugimoto do that...?
He was waiting.
For Mr. Furuta to take the money out!
What?!
You're only running wild on imagination!!
Mr. Sugimoto probably knew that
Mr. Furuta would take
money out of the wallet
pretending to turn the knapsack in.
That's why he left the receipt
inside his wallet deliberately
with the money
Because if the receipt is found.
And the fact that Mr. Furuta stole
the money is revealed. Mr. Sugimoto
aggressively trying to'get his
knapsack back would be justified.
T-That's not true!
Then?!
Yes,
Mr. Sugimoto deliberately put the net shelf
and went to the restroom
to make)Mr. Furuta steal the money.
But there were other
passengers on the train...
Why did Mr. Furuta think that
the knapsack was a forgotten item?...
The cell phone.
The cell phone?!...
Didnit 'you realize that
there, was a cell phone
inside the knapsack?!...
Probably
a cell phone with
a history of incoming calls...
Mr. Sugimoto. who went to the restroom
just before arriving at West Sumita Station,
with his other cell phone and
called theicell phone in the knapsack!
The phone rang. but on one answered it!
That's why he thought that
the knapsack was a forgotten item!
I see...
just as would be expected
of the Sleeping Kogoro.
Mr. Sugimoto quietly watched
while Mr. Furuta hid behind
materials of the construction site
and took out the money.
He grabbed Mr. Furuta and dragged him
and pushed him into the KEEP OUT area.
Then; he pushed him
over with all his might!
Of course the rope that held
the fence of the KEEP OUT area
in place was cut beforehand.
Then all hé had to do next.
Was pull the knapsack from Mr. Furuta
who was down on the ground.
If Mr. Furuta fought back to keep
the knapsack from being taken away
the strap which had been slit
in advance would be cut
and Mr. Furuta who loses balance
would fall off the overpass platform
to the ground below.
The shoulder strap
was slit beforehand?!...
Excuse me, please.
In-Inspector?!
Yes,
it was not accident!
It was a planned murder under
the pretext of an accident!
T-That's absurd!
That's nothing more than a far-fetched story.
Listen!
He tried with all his might and
resisted giving me back the knapsack!
How could I have knocked him down,
then pushed him over...
Things don't work out that well!
As a matter of fact it does.
Huh 2!
If you use the ballpoint pen that you have
stuck to the inner pocket of your suit!
Ballpoint pen...?
You cornered him to behind
the materials and
poked Mr. Furuta with
all your might with that ballpointpen.
While Mr. Furuta flinched
from pain,
you pushed him.
The mark left by the ballpoint pen was left
plain and clear on the back
of his hand that you poked!!
How about it,
Mr. Sugimoto!
Mr. Sugimoto...
I couldn't forgive him!!
He took the life of my girlfriend!!
Huh
6 months ago...
He rammed full speed into my-girlfriend
who was crossing. the crosswalk.
We were going
to get married soon...
There were no witnesses and
Furuta's version insisting that
the pedestrian ran into
the street went through,
and he wasn't even prosecuted!
That's much too cruel... ruthless.
So. you decided
to kill Mr. Furuta
under the pretext of an accident...
I just couldn't...
I just couldn't make myself
forgive him...
Ori1ernal Comic Books By
SHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MIEHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Sump!» By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHIIA
YUICHI HI@URE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUMO
HIROTOSHITAKATANl
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONQO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photovraphy .
IAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, ITD
In assowtation with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DITFCJIVEL ONAN
CHSHO AOYAMA SHOCAKUKANYTV TMS
ARI his Reserved
rope Jr
Mouri Detective Agency
Okay! It's ready
I tell you, Dad...
Just because the
ramen shops were closed
you don't have to go out
of way to cup ramen, do you?
Don't you agree, Conan!
Agh
Who cares! What's the.big deal...
This is just the thing for me after all...
Ooh~~ It's s000 good!!
Maybe I'll have another serving
You're going to get fat.
Ell... it's sure that this matches Pops
more than French cuisine for sure...
Strangled...?!
I feel bad for Au.
But I guess she'll just have
to stick it out till then...
I'd at least like to know
if it's me that's being Marked or her...
Otherwise. I can't move...
Don't worry...
I'll solve it right away!
(ay Sh)
Four 'Porsches~'Part 1