I Friendship. Romance, Mystery
Because we cherish
them we can continue
Four Porschesyist like
the ones those guys have.
The case far surpasses all expectations!
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
<< DD
HA AA
(RR)
Four Porsches Part 1
Since she came back home,
she's runninc a fever.
Hey! Are you all right...?
It's just a cold...
It's not something you have to go out
of your way to come see me for...
So much has been going on recently
that she probably just
psychologically tired...
By the way. Are you okay?
Huh
Remember...
The guys the other day,
that were tailing us.
If they tail you back here
and find this house,
we'll get Dr. Agasa into trouble too...
Don't worry!
I wasn't tailed by anyone.
And nobody's watching
over this house either...
She should go see a doctor. but...
today is Sunday and
he hospitals around here are all closed
Right! We could ask
Dr. Araide what do you say?
Yeah... I called him a while ago,
but he wasn't in...
He's probablydbusy because
the trial for that case is coming up...
Come to think of it, there's a hospital inside
the Tohto Department Store in Haidocho,
SO maybe we should take her there.
If I remember correctly,
their day off is Thursday...
You don't have to
go out of your way to take
me to the hospital...
Well,
there's nothing better than getting rid
of your cold as soon as possible!
Like they say colds may lead
to all kinds of diseases...
You mean you can't see her right away?
No... We have a lot of patients today...
You'll have to wait about
2 hours if you come now...
Well: it cant be helped. S
Let's put in an appointment anyway...Doc.
Oh... excuse-me.
We'd like to make an-appointment...
Yes.
I guess'we can kill time
in the department store then...
Yes... thank you.
Guess so...
I'm getting kind of hungry too...
A. OB PO- ey
eres Ye sa20op 1a 1s amous or servings
great egg porridge
in the restaurant arcade!her.e.,.
I'm sure that eating it will-make-Ai
feel a little better...
Okay! Doc...
Okay... Okay...
URdy... URdYy!!
Okay... Stop!
Okay. we're here, Al!
O-Okay...
Here... hang on to me!
You're still feeling unsteady aren't you?
I'm not that hopeless. ok
Never mind,
will you just move out of my way...
Oh... yes...
I can manage to get off the car
There you go again...
by myself...
P...Porsche...
356A...
Gin's car...
Hey" AW!
Hey. Ail!
That is undoubtedly the same model
as that of Gin's but...
His is black and this is green!
The color is different...
and besides
since all three Porsches are parked
so close together
I'm sure that a bunch of
Porsche lovers got-together to
eat at the department store...
Another Porsche...
It's a 911...
Okay!! We're here...
We're here, Mr. Banba!
Mr. Banba?
Darn...
Another OB...
Ghads. hopeless...
Well, it's not something
unexpected though...
Okay then
why don't we do some
shopping or something like always
until Banba's booze wears off...
Hold it!!
Let me go back to
the car and get my wallet.
Yeah...
I guess I'll go too...
Excuse me, mister!
Are the 4 Porsches parked here...
all yours?
Y-Yeah...
That green, old one is... Mr. Hotei's
Porsche 356A...
The new. car to the right edge-is
Ms. Taeyama's Porsche Boxter...
(-1... this is my dear ca
Porsche 911!
And this red one is...
Porsche 928 that belongs to Mr. Banba
who is asleep in my car!
But why were all four men
riding in your car?
Well, that's because...
We're all Porsche lovers as well as
friends who play golf together...
When all four of us go
golfing we gather here,
then take Kureko's car and
head off together in one car!
The more the merrier...
and the highwayfee is
cheaper that way too...
Even the parking fee here is free if
we shop in this department store too...
ides... after we make half a rot
there's someone here who gulps down
more beer than he can handle
and passes out wasted...
We have no other choice but go shopping
or something until he sleeps it off!
Well,
and this parking lot is crowded on Sundays
and it's difficult to find an open stall,
so it's like we're saving
a stall for ourselves...
Hey. it's time we get going...
Yeah...
See you!!
Saving a stall?
I guess he means that
nobody has guts enough
to park their car between two Porsches.
Oh. I see...
Okay. so Al... shall we start off too...
Count me out...
Huh
I don't feel too well...so
I guess I'll wait here in the car until the
» time for my appointment with the doctor.
Hey! Al...?
It can't be helped...
She was tailed by people
she doesn't know the identity of...
It's no wonder she's all worked up...
W-Which means that!!
The ones who were tailing us
were the Men in Black...
Could be.
Although I'm not all that sure myself yet...
I've got to at least find out whether
it's me or Ai that they're after
otherwise, I can't make any moves...
rday before dawn...
It's the follow-up news of the robbery case
which occured in the city of Tokyo.
The killer is still on the run...
The police are collecting
the information from an eyewitness
Me... OF Al?
Uh~~= I think it was the 10th floor...
wonder if it's okay. though.
To have left Ai back there alone...
We had no oterh choice. did we...
CA oto pe ramen
They serve western style food here.
Italian food...
And . Chinese food...
There sure is a lot of variety, isn't there?
H...? What is it
Boy... what a long line...
Tarugatei Oh!! Here it is...
Hey. hey...
You,gotta be kidding*
Iook at this line: Doc!
Just as would be expected of
a shop famous for egg porridge.
We can kill time just standing in line...
Huh
AAAb AA
No... I left my cell phone in the car...
11 go get it...
You guys go on inside...
I'll 'be: right back...
They're the people we just saw
a while ago in the parking lot...
Hey!!
Cool Kid!! Long time no see!!
J-JO...
Jodi...
Oh... Ran-and Sonoko too...
Oh... Ran and Sonoko too...
Hello!!
W-What's up?
What brings you here?
We came to eat
the egg porridge of Tarugatei!
Bug ou?.
No not at all...
I wasn't referring to you Sonoko...
We told Jody that it's really delicious.
then she said she wanted
to come and eat it...
Yes!!
Japanese food is healthy
and very. very good!!
Oh... ll see...
And... why are you both here, Conan?
You were saying that you were going to
visit Al who is in bed with a cold...
Oh... well...
Y Yes...
SO ai IS here-with. us and
IS here with us and
we-were going to eat
the egg porridge-with her...
but her cold is so bad...
and she didn't look like she could make it.
So we. left her behind!
Right, Doc!!
Agh. that's the story...
Look-at this .everybody!
What a long line of people!
This is the restaurant arcade inside
the Tohto Department Store.
See! It's even popular on TV
SO we had an urge to come eat here...
Oh!! She's Tomomi Kato
of the Gourmet Corner...
You're right!
Hey. hey...
Listen to me, will you
Okay. Fl start my interview right away.
The serial arsonist
hasn't been arrested yet...
The Metropolitan Police Department
IS calling on the people
in the vicinity to be very careful...
So...
Come-on..no! It.can't be!
Thank you very much!
So... here is Yuka Saegusa with
The Place I Promised to Meet You."
So...
Iet me go and interview someone else now.
Hello, boy!!
Can I talk to you for a moment?
Did you come to here to Tohto Department
Store to eat'Egg porridge too?
Yep. But, since ther are so many people
in hne... 'guess I'm not...
Is that right...
Did you come to eat the egg porridge
here at Tarugatei too?
Yes.
So...we're
Ieaving!!
UT}!
Come on!! Doc!
Let's go!
Quick!!!
H-Hey...
Hey?!
Hey 7!
C-Conan!!
People go in and out of
this shop quite quickly so
you'll be able to eat soon!!
I el them be. Ran!
Yep. but...
Kid's wouldn't really know
the difference in taste anyway...
Hey?!
What's up...
All of a sudden...
Hey! Shinichi!! :Shinichi?!
The person I saw a while ago...
He came back...
Doc... and Shinichi...
What's up?
Y doesn't he look s
dreadfully serious?
Shinichi!
M-Mr. Banba...!!
This is...?!
What's the matter,
Shinichi?
No good...
He's been strangled...
- -Hello... police?
I'm calling from the basement parking lot
of the Tonto Department Store
from my cell phone
I'll stay back here, so take Ai
and get away from here, Doc!
Huh? Why ?
My face was taken by
the TV cameras a while ago...
If the guys who were
tailing us the other day
were the Men in Black...
we can't be too sure that they Won't
come here after seeing me. right?
Don't worry!
The TV program just a while ago
IS the afternoon wide show...
The viewer rating is only about 1046...
It's not a live broadcast that's
aired during Golden Time...
It's most probable that
they're not watching...
Heck!!
The number of TV viewers in the Kanto
District is approximately 4 million people.
Even if the viewer rating were to be 1%
the number of people watching
would be about 400,000!!
10% makes it 4 million people.
There's no guarantee that
they wouldn't be watching!!
So... now that you understand
hurry and get Al out of here!
If you look around Tokyo,
I'm sure you'll be able to find
a hospital that opens even on Sundays...
I feel sorry for Au.
But she'll just have to hold up till then...
Tarugatel
It sure rains a lot. doesn't it
Huh 2!
Wow! Hey, look!!
There are police cars parked
in front of this~department store!!
in front of this department store!!
I wonder if something happened...
Don't tell me that...
the glasses kid is
messed up In some case again...
N-No...
Seeing is believing.
Which means...seeing is believing.
Shall we go check?
Y how come you're not letting us ou
Oh... well,
we were contracted
by the police a while ago...
\ There's been a grave incident
inside this parking lot that
I can't let anyone out of here.
So... now you know,
we. can get.out:of here until
the killer is caught... Shinichi.
It can't be helped...
Find an empty'lotand wait there...
it... what if they come.
Don't worry...
I'll solve the case right away!
Don't move till then!!
H-Hey... Shinichi!! Shinichi!?
Don't worry...
I'll solve the case right away...
Ori1einal Comic Books By.
SHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONQ@
Character Designs By.
MAMTOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I10OKA
SOipts By.
WKANJI KASHIWABA A
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASAI
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Dircewlors.
MASATOMO SUD @O
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO COCA WA A
ATSUSHI AON@OO
AKIO KAWAMU A
TAKASHI HYODO
Art director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photoeraphy.
INKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU O ADA
Chief Director
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, ITD
In assowtation with
CORPORATION
OF TECTVEL ONAN
«EDO AOYAMA SHOCAKUKAN:YIV IMS
1 Rohs Reserved
Brown hair...
with a reddish tint...
I don't understand...
How did the killer strangle Mr. Banba
and how did the killer
collect the murder weapon?
This is it!!
I've got to contact Doc right away and
get Al out of here on the double...
There are not around?
Doc and Ai are both gone...!!