Friendship. Romance. Mystery
Because we cherish them we can continue
Ail gets messed up in the Porsche case
JodienShinichi and Bellmot appear
He sees through the one and only truth.
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the l1.Q of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Four Porsches Part 2
The victim is Mr. Yukiya Banba age 41...
The cause is death by suffocation...
From the traces left on his neck.
It seems he was choked
)y a string-like object...
Moreover, it seems he was choked
with quite some strength...
And?
Who is the one that found the corpse?
He's the one.
He seems to have gone
golfing with the victim...
and stopped byashere on their way back .
Huh?
Who are the two people
standing behind you?
Oh, yes...
They are also golf friends...
As well as Porsche friends...
C-Conan?!
You're also Porsche friends, right?
What's the matter?
I came to this department store
with Dr. Agasa and got off the car.
Then I saw them park their cars too.
And I talked to them a bit.
Where's Dr. Agasa then?
I think he's still shopping upstairs...
And. Conan...
Will you give me more of
the details back then?
It was about 1:00 in the afternoon...
4 people came...
on this white Porsche and
only 3 got off.
They were saying that they
were going to shop here
until that man's booze wears off.
It seems as if they were going to leave
after a while on their own cars.
Which means that
these 4 Porsches are yours?
Y-Yes...
Inspector Megure!!
Hey...
Ded you find anything?
Yes Sir.
I see
COON NY
I OTC...
Thank you...
It seems that the suspects have been
narrowed down to you three.
Huh 2!
As a result of the autopsy...
the estimated time of
death is around 1:00p.m
Just about the time you all got here...
In other words...
It is extremely likely that one of you
strangled Mr. Banba
when getting off the car...
Well, it may be a different story
If you left the car unlocked
when you got off...
U-Uh, I locked the door for sure...!
He was still alive when we got off...
Mr. Hote,
Ms. Taeyama,
is it true?
Y-Yeah...
He was wasted and talking in his sleep...
Saying something like "Another OB."...
Besides we all got off
at about the same time,
SO Nobody had time to strangle anybody.
Il... please tell us more in deta
Please give me your names and
your relationship with Mr. Banba
who had been killed,
the order in which you got off the car
and which car you own...
I'm the first one who got off.
My name is Yoshihito Kureki...
I got to know Mr. Banba at
the Porsche new car exhibition...
My car is this Porsche 911 here...
When we go golfing.
I park my-carahere and
all four of us get on this car and
head off together in one car,
just like that boyamentioned
We got off in order to wait for
Mr. Banba's booze to wear off
and decided to kill time
at the department store.
But I realized that I had left
my cell phone in the car
so I came back to get it.
Only to see how I found him...
Which mean
you're the only one
who could've killed him without
being seen by anyone...
Oh. well...
WI came back to the car
about an hour later though...
Huh
What is this?!
This box in the dashboard compartment?
A-A music box...
The pin broke, so I was thinking
of sending out for repair.
But. I had completely forgotten it was here.
It seems to be working okay...
I guess you can't strangle somebody
using something like this though...
I'm the one who got off after him.
My name is Eiji Hotei...
I used to car race with him
on mountain roads...
When we were young. that is...
I'm into antique-like cars recently...
and bought a Porsche 356A that
was made 50 years ago...
Excuse me.
Oh? There's something in the back seat...
There...
O-Oh, those're my fishing goods...
I'm kind of into fishing lately.
Huh
You've even got an electric reel!
If this is used,
you could choke his neck automatically...
Cut out that talk!
The reel was in the bag. wasn't it!
I came back here after
I received call from Mr. Kureko
and haven't even touched the car yet!
I'm Kaoru Taeyama.
It's true that I was the last one
who got off but...
Do you think that a woman like me
would be strong enough
to strangle a mant to death?
Besides.
After golf my gripping strength
IS weakened as is...
And?
What is your relationship with Mr. Banba?
Nothing special...
I just got into talking with him
about Porsches on the golf course
and started making rounds with him...
This Boxter that I got right
after it came out on the market
caught Mr. Banba's eyes...
Huh
You have something in
the passenger's seat too...
Oh that...
It's a gift for the son of my cousin...
It's a radio controlled Porsche...
I could never
strangle someone's neck with it, could I?
And besides after getting
off the car to go shopping.
I came back here after I got a call
from Mr§Kureko saying that something
awful had happened to Mr. Banba...
But. I haven't touched a thing!
Hey!
Why don't you look at that?
Huh
A surveillance camera?!
I see!
I'm pretty sure we can
find out if someone is lying!
Okay.
To the security room!!
Yes, sir!
Will all of you please come with me too...
What?
I guess we don't have a choice...
I told you to stay still!
But...
Al doesn't look too good...
I figured we should take her to the doctor.
We can't leave her like this...
I guess we have no choice.
Just to be safe,
maybe we should ask Officer Takagi
to secretly let us out with his police car...
Because they may be
ambushing us outside...
Who are they?
Conan!!
You were mixed up in this case after all!
Uh. well...
how did you get in h
Only those from the police and those who
are involved in the case are let in, right?
We told them that wcame
to pick you:up then they let us in.
Right. Ran?
Right...
Ai is here too?
C-Come to think of it,
you're some detective, aren't you?
We're going to the security room
to look over the surveillance camera,
so won't you come along?
Come on, let's go...
Okay. Sonoko!
Hey!! Jody. you too...
Let's go!
Hey. Conan!
Reddish...
brown hair...!
Huh
What're you both doing?
Ms. Yasuyama and
Mr. Hotel?
After you got off the car.
Both of you have gone back to your cars...
I just went back to get my wallet.
Mr. Kureko always paid the golfing
charges ahead of time so...
so after this all three of you went-into
the department store together to shop
and until Mr. Kureko went back to get
his cell phone an hour later
nobody went near the car...?
So. didn't I tell you that
it was impossible for us
to commit the murder...?
It's unreasonable to think that
they would call the police knowing
that they'd be .T8pected...
Besides, all three of them
got off the car at about the same time...
There wasn't anything strange
about their moves...
I can't make it out...
How did the murderer strangle Mr. Banba
and what Bf the murder weapon.
How did the killer come to get it?
Darn!!
I've got to solve the case
and get Ai out of here
as fast as I can, and yet...
Inspector Megure!!
The pictures of the interior of the cars
of all three suspects are ready!
Thank you, please leave them there...
Yes, sir!
T-This is it!!
Sonoko, did you figure it out?
Maybe all three of them strangled him
before getting off the car...
Hey...
Why don't we go back to where the car is?
We could figure something out!!
In-Inspector!
I-I guess so...
Like they say, check the scene of
the crime out 100 times...
Let's go back...
74 JA
(W!)
She's the girl who was wearing the red
hood in the bus that was hi-jacked...
The girl who was lying down in the car...
Don't tell me that...
It can't be...
Shinichi said don't move,
ut if I leave Ai as she is...
I've got no choice...
I'll call Dr. Niide once more
although he may not be in...
Yes, this is Dr. Araid...
Oh, Dr. Araider!
I take it that you're Dr. Agasa.
From your voice?
I'm in luck!!
It seems that you weren't in
when Conan called so...
Conan did? That's strange...
I was home all day today...
What seems to be the matter?
ROTC .
So. you can't move from there
because there's been a murder?
Well, yes... sort of...
Why don't we do this them?
I'm here at the scene of the crime but...
Have noticed anything?
No, not really...
Why don't you have
Sonoko check everyone's car?
Who. me?!
You're a great detective,
SO you may come up with something!
First from Ms. Yasuyama's car
that's at the very edge...
Will you lend me your key?
S-Sure...
Here. Sonoko!
Okay...
I can tell that it's an expensive car, but...
there seems to be nothing strange about it.
Don't tell me...
Don't tell me Sonoko...
You mean it's come?!
I've figured it all o
The way Mr. Banba was strangled to death
while sitting in the passenger's seat
and who did it too!!
R-Really?!
If at all possible,
I wish she'd explain why she's explaining
while pretending to be asleep
Iike Mr. Mouri does...
But. have you really figured out:the case.
When all you did was
get into the car and sit:down...?
I touched it when I sat down...
couched it...7?
You see that little groove on the top
side of the window glass?
When my finger touched it,
it dawned on me...
That Ms. Taeyama
the owner of this Porsche Boxter...
You. are the killer!!
Hey. hey, are you serious...
s. Tae ama...
Officer Takagi...
Please sit in the passenger's seat of the
Porsche 911 where Mr. Banba's corpse is,
and play the role of the victim...
O-Okay...
Conan will you take care of
you know what, like I told you to...
h... you mean this fishing lir
that you told me to go buy...?
But, can you... really do
something like that with this?
Never mind. just do as I told you to, okay...
n... everything wil become clea
OKay!!
First. hook the fish line
around Officer Takagi's neck,
who is sitting down...
Then pull the string through
behind the head rest...
Get off still holding the string
and close the door.
Hold both ends of the string...
and pull it through the Porsche 928
that is in between.
Go back to Ms. Taeyama's car...
and hook it on to the groove on
the window of the driver's seat side,
that was made beforehand,
and then go back into the car, right?
But... he marks left on Mr. Banba's neck
showed signs of him being
strangled with great strength...
You probably want to say...
that the string was pulled secretly
from inside the car but...
I don't think it's possible with
the strength of a woman...
Right...
That's why Ms. Yasuyama used the...
the strength of the power window...
Ms. Yasuyama probably
wrapped the stringaround
the neck of Mr. Banba who was asleep,
Iike Conan just did.
Then she got off the car.
Pretended to go get her wallet
and got into this car...
She then opened the door
And tied the string pulling it tight,
then tied it onto
the transmission lever or something...
All she had left to do, was push the switch
of the power window and close the window.
The string would be pulled by
the strength of the power window and...
This way, she can choke his neck
even if she's at a distance from him!
Hey. Sonoko?!
And, besides.
Since this parking lot is dark to begin with
it's hard to see the string.
If the key is stopped at the first level,
she can move the power window
without having to turn on the engine,
so there would be no loud sound.
Okay. I have a question.
How did she retrieve the string?
That's easy...
if she uses this radio controlled car...
She leaves the string that is tied
beforehand to the axle of the rear tire of
the radio controlled car outside the box
cuts the string that had
finished strangling his neck,
then ties one end of the string to
the string that is outside the box,
and left the radio controlled car
running inside the box,
and left the car.
It's true that if left that way the string
would automatically rewind, but...
If she left the car running,
I would have heard the sound
of the motor running
when I checked this car.
Oh, don't you know?
The battery of a radio controlled car
keeps only for about 10 minutes...
By the time you got here
it would've been stopped...
Why don't you try checking out
the radio controlled car?
I'm sure you'll find the string
wrapped around the axle.
If it's just to roll up the string it would be
possible to do so using
r. Hotel's electric reel 100...
but, I knocked him off
the suspect's list because...
of the power window...
Out of the three of us...
my Boxter's the only one with
the power window, right?
I thought I did a pretty good job...
But, I didn't think that such a cute detective
ould see through my trick...
So. you're the one who
killed him after all...
but, why?
Why ?
I'm sure that he's thinking
so in the world beyond too.
He's probably wondering,
Why the hell was I killed...
I'm sure you've heard from him
before that he competed
with a yellow Ferrari at
a mountain path before...?
Come to think of it, yeah,
some time in the past...
But. he said the driver of
the Ferrari picked on him...
That's a lie...
He's the one who picked a fight...
I guess all he wanted to
do was tease a couple...
But the one driving was
my younger brother...
After a heated battle,
our car went over the cliff...
I was saved.3 hours-later
by a person who, happened to pass by...
But, my younger brother didn't make it...
I couldn't remember
the number plate of the man...
But. I remembered his face and
that his car was a red Porsche 928.
I remembered that
he had a golf bag in his car...
$0. I bought a Porsche and
searched around the golf courses,
finally found him and
was waiting for a chance to take revenge.
Why didn't you report
the incident to the police?
I had no mind of telling the police about it...
Because my younger brother was also at
fault to for being provoked into competing.
And my purpose for meeting him
was not revenge to start with...
Huh
If that man had called the ambulance
right away for us back then,
my brother would've been saved...
I wanted to know
why he didn't call the ambulance...
If he said that he was
afraid of getting caught or
if he said that he still regrets that day,
I was going to forgive him...
But. he continued to play golf after that too,
just as if nothing had happened.
That's when I decided to take revenge...
Make sure that all you guys
make speed rounds only
with your golfing and
never with your cars...
Okay, the case has been solved.
I've got to get a hold of Doc right away
and get Ai out of here fast...
Quick, quick, hurry!!
Huh? Ran... where's Jodie?
She went home
saying she had something
urgent to attend to...
What the...!
Agh, Conan!
T-They're not around?!
Doc and Ai are both gone....!!
Don't tell me...
hno...?
H no...
Orioinal Comic Books By
GCOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABA A
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUI(
HIROTOSHITAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUIANI
Directors Of Photoeraphy.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HOPIKOSHI
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, IND.
Mm assocratron with
YOMIURI TELECASTINC(
CORPORATION
OLECHVELON AN
CGO EHO AOYAMA SHOGAKUKANYTV - TMS
All Riohis Reserved
Ar rr /)y of sr ~
1, ve )een wan mg or your ca .
What do you mean you've been waiting!!!
I told you not to move and yet
why'd you go back home?!
You don't have to shout...
This is Dr. Araide's suggestion.
Dr. Araide?
Is he there?
Yeah, Ail is being examined now...
You said that he wasn't in.
But:-when I called him he was at home...
I told him that we can't seem to move from
where we are since there was a crime,
he said. The police know
who you are, and moreover,
with a sick child, if you
ask them to let you out
I'm sure they'll let you out.
They gave us a lift in the police car
and helped us get out.
But just when we got out
of the department store,
she happened to pass by...
ey... Don't tell me that she's...
Hi! I cut a lot of fruit.
Vitaimin C is best for colds!!
Shh! She just fell asleep.
Ah . Sorry .
Jody...
She's the one who brought us here.
Thank God. she had parked her car
in a different parking lot
It seems that Ail has just
come down with a cold,
so there's nothing to worry about...
Seven...
Eight...Nine...Ten...
Ready or not...
Are you ready?
Here I come...
I'm going to go look for you.
I see you...
I've found you...
Doc!!
The Secret\Hidden-in.the: Toilet Part 1