Friendship. Rofance. Mystery
Because we cherish them we can continue
Al's older sister. Akemi Miyano
Leaves the secret of
the-organization somewhere
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
no.case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
HA AA
(8%)
Secret Hidden in the Toilet Part 1
Do you know?
Huh
If you put those on,
nobody will ever-guess your identity
You fool!
Don't run. At!
Don't run from destiny!!
Besides.
I gave her my word...
That if she.gets into trouble
I would look after her!!
Because she's not
as tough as she looks...
Medicine...
A doctor examined me...
But. don't remember...
The only thing I remember is...
that Doc carried me...
and we left the department store...
If I remember correctly... after that I...
How stupid of me...
If they found me
I would be in no circumstance
to be dreaming something like that.
Dr. Agasa wouldn't be dozing off like that
Doc .
Doc '2!
Hey. Al...
Hey. Ar...
So. you're up?
Tomato juice...
Tell Doc
not to drink canned tomato juice
while looking through the Internet...
because he always falls
asleep part way and spills it...
B-By the way. why are you here...
I had this bad feeling
so I came to check on you...
I told Ran I was going to
help Doc take care of you...
Well, it seems it wasn't worth the worry,
SO you can go back to sleep...
Sorry to keep you waiting
Your egg porridge is ready!!
It's not as good as
the one at Tarugatei, but...
Huh? She went to sleep?
Strange...
I thought she was up just a minute ago...
Okay then I'll leave this here...
After Al eats this.
tell her to let me know how it was
O-Okay!
See you, since I've got to go see Sonoko.
Ah. go out the same way you came in...
Go through the basement and then
through the back door, right?
You'd better hurry and
get the front door fixed. Doc!
Y-Yeah...
Bye. Conan.
Thank you Ran!!
What's with you...
You're really good at fake crying...
But you're the pits when
it comes to faking being asleep...
What is it with you?
She comes all the way here
to make egg porridge for you
and you ignore her completely!
I didn't...
ask her to do it for me...
It's not that I understand you
don't care much for people like Ran
who like to take care of other people but...
he did make it for you.
So eat it before it gets cold!
You don't understand anything...
do ou...
Well
it's not that I want you.
To know either. but.
But. we:re lucky that the weekend's come...
Yeah...
we can't let Ai go walking around
when weird guys are sniffing around...
LA TX
It seems that Ali's recovering
from her cold too...
At this rate. we may be able to go visit
Al's father, Dr. Miyano's friend next week.
Huh
Hey. what does it mean?
Oh, didn't I tell you?
I asked my doctor acquaintances
about Dr. Miyano, and
found out that he had a childhood
designer friend who
was with him together in elementary,
intermediate and high school!
Something about this designer
having helped him bind a book that
he had privately published...
Although the book didn't sell,
the design was innovative and
was reputed highly
among the other doctors too...
If we see that person,
we may be able to find out
about the Men in Black
that you're looking for
and about Ali's parents too...
My... father and
mother...
Hey. hey!
You're not well at all.
We don't need to go today. do we
We don't know
where they're looking out for.us. you know.
Aren-t you the very one
who wants to go?
Well,
it's true that I'd like to see him if I get
to find out about those guys. but...
Then, stop blabbering.
Well. it's true that I mm worried.
But we're fine just like this.
So I'm sure they haven't
grasped anything on us yet...
Yeah...
fl guess so...
If my deduction's correct.
We should all be
in the world beyond by now...
na~Design Office
Yes...
it's true that I that Atsushi Kanno and
I were childhood friends...
But. unfortunately,
I haven't seen him for the past 30 years...
The last time I saw him was when
he rented this house that he inherited
from his parents, to me...
Which means that
this house is Dr. Miyano's?
Yes...
I wanted a design office,
so he said that
since he'd be leaving his house empty
for a while, he'll rent it to me...
I've been renting this house
ever since for 30 years.
Thisyis where...
my father was 'born andOfraised...
Then... where was Dr. Miyano living
I after lending this house to you?
Beats me...
He said that he was going to
a large research laboratory of
a sponsor that approved of his theory...
u ave no icea wiere 1a Is...
It's those guys...
1 Co Deee
most probably.
And? You got no word
from Dr. Miyano after that?
N-No
I just got a postcard saying that
he got married, that was it...
h...That person came once whe
» ou were out President Dejima.
Huh
Remember...
you used to go out for walks when
you couldn't come across designs
and stayed out for quite some time.
He happened to come by just at that time.
He: cameralong with
a.pretty-foreign wife and
a cute girlkabout'4 or 5-years-old...
He seemed to want to talk to you
about something important and
he ended up spending
the night here. then left...
I mentioned that you may be back, but...
Didn't I tell you about it?
No!! I haven't heard anything.
And...
his wife's name was Elena
His daughter's name I think was Akemi...
My older-sister...
There seemed to be
something odd about them...
Yeah...
His daughter's mischief
was really hard to handle...
She hid our tools all over the place...
She saw how troubled we were
nd seemed to enjoy it...
His wife remained quiet all the while so
we thought she couldn't
understand Japanese,
but she spoke in Japanese
with her daughter...
He kept looking out the window and
seemed to be worried about something.
Come to think of it.
a car was parked for some time
outside this house.
Oh!! it was a black
car with smoked glass...
Yeah...
They were being watched...
Hey. hey. just when was that?
It was just after
we reformed the old
house into an office so.
I think it was about 20 years:ago...
Did Dr. Miyajosay anything
to you all before he left. ?
Nothing that I remember.)
By the way, what's your
relationship with Dr. Miyano?
Oh. well...
we're both doctors...
He's going to finally get married at his age!
And. he is going to ask him to come
to the wedding but...
he didn't have the doctor's address
so he came to ask you for it!
Right?!
Y-Yeah...
I'm going to go buy lunch pretty soon...
Okay. get me a hamburger then. will you!
You want the usual Teriyaki
and fish with M size French fries
and corn soup. right?
What else?
I'll take the same thing as the president.
I'll take the same with apple pie
and two learge size cokes!
Ghads...
you always drink too much, that's why you
have to go to the restroom so many times
orry, I'm so much like a kid
Oh. Imai
will you please get
coffee for the guests too!
Yes. sir...
So. ll don't know
Dr. Miyano's address either...
I don't want to be rude,
but since we have work to do.
After you drink your coffee. please...
Oh. yes, sure...
Akemi dropped by some time ago...
PT ~~ =
She did?
WwW Why
Remember the girl?
The cute one who came to use the toilet!
She greeted us saying "Long time no see.
So. we were surprised...
Was she Dr. Miyano's daughter?
Huh? Didn't I tell you?
I said, you didn't tell me!
Sorry!
And. that woman
really only came to use the restroom?
Y-Yeah...
But. she did say something strange...
She said she was embarrassed
that-she came to use the toilet
so.to not tell anybody about it...
I wonder... who she wanted
to keep it a secret from...?
Hey. wait...
There...
Huh
Y-You're both going in together??
No doubt about it...
Akemi definitely hid-something...
Yeah...
Somewhere in this toilet...
But... even if she hid something
in a small toilet like this
I'm sure-that. someone
would've foundOitalready...
Yeah-iltswvern likely...
But. still...
something may just come out.
Some clue... to who those guys are...
H-Hurry... Hurry up. will you!!
I guess we'll search later...
Yes.
Thanks for waiting!!
You guysiwannachave some too, sonny?
Oh. no thanks!
You know, after that woman came,
didn't anything strange happen?
Yeah...
a burglar broke in...
And. twice too!
A burglary
Nothing was stolen, though...
Is your stomach okay...?
Yeah, somehow...
The problem's the other stuff, though...
Huh?
After that woman came...
for some strange reason...
For some strange reason...?
Pr-President?!
President?!
Poisoned to death...
Yes...
'The victim is Mr. Shohei Dejima,
54 years old,
the President of this design office...
He seems to have been
eating his burger for lunch
together with the other
three employees there
when he suddenly started
suffering and collapsed]
And. who bought the hamburger?
Oh... 1 did...
Which means you had the most probable
chance of poisoning the hamburger?
W-Wait!!
The President picked up
the hamburger on his own.
Besides, he picked up the Teriyaki burger
that everyone else also ordered!
I couldn't have poisoned the hamburger
because I would've had no idea who
would pick up the hamburger he did!!
Is this right....?
R-Right...
It could be that
the poison was on something that
President Dejima always used.
Where is his desk?
H-Here...
Whose seat his that next to his?
Oh , Mr.Imai's .
Then. he would've been able to use
the poison without being noticed too...
That may be my seat but...
Before eating the hamburger,
we president was picking on cookies.
that empty cookie bag next to
the coffee cup on his desk?
I brought that from the kitchen...
Since he asked me to
bring coffee for everyone,
I brought his coffee for him too.
'1. \\
I STC...
If poison was on something
that the president used.
You're saying that he would've
died when he ate the cookies?
What's with this medicine?
Medicine for constipation...
The president had a bad case of
hemorrhoids and used to drink it all the time
But, he would over drink it at times
and get a bad case of the runs...
Yes,
especially recently...
Yeah, he went to the restroom
just before eating the hamburger too.
He had a stomachache
and ran to the restroom.
Restroom?
Didn't anyone go into the restroom
before the president did?
I-I went I A
before I went to buy lunch...
I went in after him... and after me,
Mr. Zaitsu...
Then, after that the president went in.
Came out and ate the hamburger?
Yes...
In other words.
If you had put poison
somewhere around the restroom...
You gotta be kidding!!
It's true that I went into the restroom
before the president did.
but it wasn't right before
the president went In
Because between me and the president,
these children went in...
C-Conan?!
And, Al and Dr. Agasa too?!
Oh. well
we just happened to come by because
we had some business
with Mr. Dejima but...
You people sure get mixed up in
all kinds of cases, don't you?
You re starting to look like Mr. Mourt...
And? Which one of'you went in first?
We went in together...
Huh
You used the toilet together?
Yeah... well
I dropped my loose change some place...
I though maybe it slipped through the
space of the door and rolled into the toilet,
so. we lookedtfor it together, right?
Yes...
We looked for the thing
thatiAkemi hid from
the eyes of the guys of the organization.
If so where:'was the poison...
Then, why not check all the way
from the work place to the restroom?
from the work place to the restroom? _g
From the work place...
to the restroom...?
After eating the cookies,
the president went to the restroom,
went back to the work place,
and ate the hamburger.
Then, he collapsed. didn't he?
Which means that the poison
may still be around some place!
Because from the time the president
collapsed to the time you came here,
nobody left the work place
took anything out,
threw away or wiped anything...
I guess so... Let's start checking anyway...
1 CO...
Iet's do that together with
a body check of everyone
W-What?!
There's no poison reaction anywhere?
Nothing from the toilc
corridor, work place and
everywhere else that
the victim could've touched...
the strange thing
there was a reaction by the right side of
the victim's slacks and the:place
where the belt holes are,
as well as the victim's
Ieft fingertips and handkerchief...
and the wrapper of
the hamburger he was eating...
it was a very small amount,
and it seemed that the victim
touched them with his poisoned hand...
But why was there poisons
L.get.it!! The handle of the-coffee cup!!
If the poison is put there,
he would eat the cookie
with his right hand and
poison would go on his left hand
when he drinks the coffee!
If so. even if he went to the toilet after that.
If he opened and closed
the door with his right hand,
there would be no poison
reaction in the toilet!
In other words. the killer...
IS the one who brought the, coffee...
You!! Mr. Imam
You!! Mr. Imai!
Oh... No... Inspector!
We of course checked the handle
of the coffee cup andithe cookie bag,
but there was no poison reaction.
Besides--the lever to flush
the toiletiis on 'the left side...
If the poison:was on his righthand
before he went into the toilet."
when he pulled his slacks up and down,
the poison would most likely
be on the left side of his slacks...
$0. why was there poison on
the right side of his slacks...?
Uh, did the president have
some kind of habit?
Was he left handed...
the only character
I can think of was that I
he was very neat and loved coffee...
He was neat and loved coffee?
He used to first always wipe his hands with
wet tissue before he sat at his desk.
It took me 10 years before I succeeded in
making coffee the way the president liked.
Didn't you seé'any suspicious
people watching this house?
We were burglarized twice...
But. nothing after that...
B-Burglarized ?!
Yes. the burglar broke in through the window
Uh. AI,
don't tell mesthat the burglary is...
Yes.
It sure is similar to the way
those guys get rid of their target...
without any evidence...
And vanish like the fog...
Oricinal Comic Books By
SHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I10OKA
Scripts By.
WKANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHI A
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Direwlors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWA A
ATSUSHI AON@O
AKIO KAWAMU A
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUIANI
Directors Of Photoeraphy.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, ITD
In assowation with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DIE ITCIAVEL ONAN
COO AOY MA / SHOGAKUKANYTY - TMS
Wei hits Reserved
rd 34
After my older sister Akemi:came here
the burglars who broke in
were probably them!...
Yeah...
They probably guessed that
she 'may have hidden something here
and came to look for it.
No! Don't!
You don't have to know!
If you get involved any deeper,
you'll really...!
Secret-Hidden in-the Toilet-Part 2