Friendship. Romance. Mystery
Because we cherish them we can continue
The true killer is found together
with a secret cassette tape
A message that sways Al's heart
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Secret Hidden in the Toilet Part 2
After my older sister Akemi came here,
the burglars who-broke in
were probably them...
the burglars who broke in
Yeah
they took it that
she hid something in this house
and came to look for it...
There were traces of them having
set up wiretaps in the toilet too.
It's most. likely.that they couldn't find it
when they'broke'in here the first time.
And so they set up a wiretap. Ir
But after hearing that the people here
knew nothing of something being hidden,
they probably broke in here a second time
to remove the wiretap.
But. I think it-has nothing to
dorwith this case:n don't you?
President Dejima could've
been your father's friend
and.your father may have been
a member of the Black Organization.
but they haven't met for 30 years
What if it's me that they're after...?
They killed my father's friend
to mentally corner me... Then what?
Don't be silly!!
How could they ever
find out-something like that...
I felt it...
That day when we went to:that
Department Store in Haido-cho...
I could feel that:callous glare...
1$ liwas going faint...
W-What Y
Tiheniwhy did you come here?!
If 'youlknew you'd be in danger why?!
I wantedito know...
Willithat do?
Whether my parents were
really the kind of people
the organization rumored them to be...
After meeting your cheerful mother,
I had_this; urge of wanting to do so...
But. letting aside my mad scientist father,
It seems that my mother was reticent,
somber and hard to
understand as rumor has it.
Don't be silly .
It's just rumor, isnt it?
Don't go deciding things
without seeing for yourself!
Do you know what
my: mother was referred to
as in the organization...?
Hell Angel...
n Angel who fell to hell...
Well now I'm totally'uninterested in her
and feel sort of.refreshed...
So, now that I've finished:all
I have to do here,
Iet's leave the homicide case to the police
and hurry out of here.
I'm not even sure
If we have any place*to,run
to at this point already: though...
But. unless we find what
your. older sister had hidden...
he deduced a whilea
regarding«the wiretap.
Iticould be that after hearing
the conversation of the employees here.
They specified the place
the object was hidden,
broke in here a:second timem
found what they were looking for
and retrieved the wiretap
while they were at it too, right?
That's why there's no reason why
we should stay here any longer...
Oh... so you were burglarized
but nothing was stolen?
N-No...
It seems that the president thought
that his design was stolen, though...
He insisted someone had secretly
taken a picture of his design...
The president was always
nervous about things like that...
He used to lose his temper every time
he saw a design that was similar to his...
He went to shout his mouth
off this morning too...
This morning...?
To another design office.
He went to tell them off
for stealing his design,
and he accused them of
the burglary some time ago.
H-Hey...
Don't tell me that...
Yes.
There is a possibility that when
he went to that design office
somebody somehow
got the poison on him...
Well, I don't blame the president
for being angry though...
Because if his design is copied
and goes around,
people will get bored and it'd
be disposed of in no time...
Disposed of...
Yeah...
After that burglary
a strange thing happened...
Strange thing... 2
A pen that was lost a long time ago
suddenly came out...
Right. right!!
I Together with my ruler!
It was not stolen. but rather.
Came out?
N No 3 t
I IUD...
11COo...
from the shoe cabinet of
the front door. just like that...
But. wasn't that before the burglary?
Huh
Was it?
But even stranger,
was the president after that!
Huh
ah... now that you mentioned
it was from just about then, wasn't it...
He kept going around
saying to save water!
He started nagging us to save water...
So. we had to stop
taking showers during work...
He wasn't the type to be worried about
something like that before and yet...
See.
So that's what it was...
Could you take us to
that design office then?
It's not right after all.
This case hasinothingito-do
with the Men] Black
The Killer:is probably...
that man...
He used the toilet to his advantage
to kill President Dejima...
And, why should we leave'when
the treasure is right beforejour.eyes.
And, why should we leave:when
the treasure is right before our ::eyes.
Then...
Yeah...
It's still there
in the toilet...
The something that your sister hid in there!
Inspector!
Let's go...
to that design office!
Yeah...
Maybe we can find out how the poison
was put on President Dejima
without anybody being aware...
No. you'll find nothing...
Uh... well, you see...
Huh
Even if... there were to be
something poisonous,
wouldn't he have touched something
as soon as he.came back'here?
On the doorknob or the back of the chair...
But, the poison was detected only
on the president's left hand.
The right side of his slacks
the belt holes of his belt
the handkerchief that he had
and the wrapper of the hamburger that
he took a bite of just before he collapsedO
Besides.
The poison was of a very small amount...
And if it was poison that rubbed"off:, when
he touched it with his poisoned hand
you can already make it out, can't you?
That is. where the poison got
on the president's hand...
Huh
Well . the place where
you loosen your belt...
pull your slacks up and down...
and the place where
you use a handkerchief...
D Don't tell me...
In the t oilet?!
Yes...
President Dejima came in contact with the
poison in the toilet and was killed...
by one of the three employees. over there!
But... Dr. AgasaO!
There was no poison reaction
found in the toilet...
It's most natural that
there was no reaction!!
Because the thing with
the poison smeared on it
was taken out of the toilet by
President Dejima himself!
W-What?!
Taken out?
The thing that
you have to throw away
once you use it up...
There wasn't any aromatic inside...
And if he changed the towel
it would've been a cleaner towel...
Then, all that'd be left is changing
the roll of the toilet paper...
Right!
The cylinder!!
The cylinder of the-toilet-paper!!
If poison is smeared-on-it
and it's left in place.
When paper runs out and
the roll has to be changed
the person would take the cylinder
empty roll out of the 'toilet to dispose of it!
B-But if so...
poison should/be found on the toilet paper
that had been newly changed...
After you change the toilet paper roll,
you usually use it, don't you?
The part with the poison on it was torn off,
used and flushed down the toilet!
I see...
Huh 2
You see. now are you convinced?
Nd... this is probably what?
President Dejima did in the toilet!
First, he realized that
the roll was out of paper.
He touched the roll with poison
on it withrhis right hand and
put it on the floor...
Then, he reached over for the new roll
of toilet paper on the.shelf and replaced it
After he finished using the:toilet paper...
he pulled his slacks up with
his poisoned right hand
fastened his belt.
Flushed the toilet with the lever on
the left side of the tank with his right hand.
And washed his hands...
If he wipes his hands with the handkerchief
the poison would be wiped off,
and if he takes the used up toilet
paper roll and comes out of the toilet...
no poison would be left inside the toilet!!
But. the poison was: detected
on the victim's: left hand:
He wasn't left-handed and yet
why would the poison that was
on the roll go on his left hand...
Come on. Inspector!
If you open the door with your right hand,
you would naturally:hold the roll with
your left hand, wouldn't you.
0 eCSese
So. he brings the roll out of the toilet and
throws it into the waste basket,
then he grabs the burger with
his poisoned left hand. eats it.
And died!
Shall we test it out?
Huh?
Lets go-into the toilet...
h... Hey?! Dr. Agasa
The most important thing isn't solved yet!!
Who of the three employees is the one
that set up this trick?
The most suspicious would be the one who
went into the toilet right before
the president, but...
H-Hold it
but isn't it strange?
It's true thatlthe president can be poisoned
to death in the way he just explained, but
unless the president has the runs,
goes to the toilet and
uses toilet paper.
While in the meantime.somebody
goes out to buy the hamburgers,
this crime wouldn't have occurred!!
Besides, the president's the one who
said he wanted to eat hamburger...
It does fit in a bit too well...
So...
The killer carried out
epeated simulations...
President Dejima probably
didn't even dream that...
in the coffee that Mr. Ima
served him everyday.
There was laxative!
) L-Laxative?!
Mr. Imai's the one...
What?!
He put more laxative in
the coffee everyday
to get the president used to the taste.
And he calculated the timing of
the president going to the toilet
with the amount of laxative
he put in the coffee...
Then...
the president had frequent
runs lately because...
Yes,
and since the president
orde ed hamburger.
Ee ed ee oO I epresi en ocay.
Mr. Imai brought the cookie
toget er wit) te co ee so that
it would urge the president
to go to the toilet...
When people eat.
A strong peristaltic movement
takes place from the transverse colon
to the sigmod colon...
In other words when something
goes into the stomach.
The need to move one's bowels occurs!
Well, if President Dejima was talking
Iaxatives on a regular basis
because of his hemorrhoids...
there would nothing
strange about laxatives
being detected in his body
during the autopsy .
And even if laxatives were
to be found in his coffee...
I would just be thought that he had
always been drinking his coffee that way.
So. there would be nothing suspicious!
Which means that
Mr. Imai set the poison up
when he went to the toilet...
Hey. hey!
I went in before him?
If I didn't urinate but went to
move my bowels instead,
you mean I would've been dead?
(No!
(You always hold your drink
in your left hand and
and if you had to frequently urinate, it isn't
hard to imagine that you'd do the same
If you moved your bowels,
he was probably planning to give you
a wet tissue or something...
Telling you to wipe
your hands before eating...
How can you tell if somebody's going
to urinate or move his bowels?
He couldn't have looked into the toilet...
The sound of the toilet being flushed.
F-Flushed?
If President Dejima was nagging
everyone about saving water,
you wouldn't use the lever that flushes a lot
of water when you urinate. would you?
He knew that Conan and Au
who went into the toilet after
you and were rushed out of there
by:the president and didn't touch
theijpoison:smeared toilet paper roll.
Okay
All:lwe need to find now is the roll that
President Dejima threw away somewhere!
Yes! Sir!
Wait!
He always throws it in here...
See! I foundit!
I-inspector!
Okay, forensic officer!!
If there's poison,on this.
There should be a bag that
was used to carry it here,
or a container for poison somewhere...
It's inside the triangular garbage
disposenrdin the kitchen...
If it were me...
After I go to the toilet
and set the poison up,
after going to the kitchen to make.coffee.
I would hide it there...
It's dirty and stink.
And a place nobody would want to:itouch...
He wouldn't have to go and
dispose of it himself later...
Because somebody else would
probably do it for him anyway...
And unlikeithe;waste basket: just in case
he wants to:change the; place he hid it
it.would be easy to retrieve
Inspector!!
I found a strange plastic bag inside
the triangular garbage
container in the kitchen!!
Oh. you did!
If poison is detected from this bag
and your fingerprints are-on it...
I'm sure you'll find both...
I had it on me day and night so that
I wouldn't miss the chance
to kill the president...
I first intended to kill him
about 20 years ago.
T-Twenty years ago...
Yeah...
Not too long after you came to this office...
Remember,
I went independent and quit here,
and came back again...
It was back then...
Yeah, I heard about it from
the president some time ago...
That you went independent,
Il but couldn't make it
SO he picked you up again...
That I couldn't make it...
There was no way I could make it...
because the president was
moving behind the scenes
CON ac INg Ye pu» Is INg companies...
telling them not to give a traitor any work.
Are you serious?
Yeah,
a publisher friend told me...
I was enraged then too,
to the point of no return...
Iiwas=thinking of how to kill him
when he cames back...
I was thinking all sorts
of things in the kitchen...
Then it just so happened that
Akemiwho:was there with her parents
was standing behind me...
Sherasked me,
What's wrong? You look scary
are youjlooking-for;something?
r. are:you 1cing:some 1ng.
Don't hide it in the triangular
garbage container
because somebody might throw it away)
She remarkedjatime: with
a sad*look on:her'face...
When I answered, I think I'm just tired.
She-smiled and...
It was after that.
Akemi started hiding
our things all over the place...
But. after seeing her innocent smile
my will to kill vanished off somewhere...
Then... why did you decide to go
rough it at this time...
The other day when I told the president
I wanted to go independent again,
this is what he said...
You would never make it at your age.
It would've been a different;story
if this were 20 years ago, though...
It was a long time since I've seen her last,
and twas feeling like anything was possible.
So, the president's words
really made me blow my top...
S-She...
you mean Akemi who
came to use the restroom?
Yeah...
The thing is. I was kind expecting
her to come around again,
after she smiled and said...
I'll come back again
with my younger sister in about a week...
But... she never came...
I thought that she would
blow off my intent to kill with
that smile of hers again,
but... I guess I was just.being; selfish.
And.
You found it, didn't you?
When you went into
the restroom with Dr. Agasa...
The thing that Akemithid. .!
Huh? Yeah...
It dawned on me when they said, as soon
as your sister came to use the restroom,
President Dejima started nagging them
about saving water :all of a sudden...!
That something must've been
6 attached to the float in the toilet tank...
So that water was flowing out little by little.
I opened the tank and checked behind
the float. then! Sure enough...
A plastic bag with something inside
it was firmly attached to
the float with masking tape...
There were traces of
old maskingitape on/it too.
SO it's most likelythat 20iyears ago...
your' sister took
Mr. ilmai's I guess?
I'm just tired- seriously and
hid the pens and rulers so
he could take a rest from work...
Then, 20)years-later,
she came back again, took off
the thing she,had hidden and
replacedlit with this.
She put this cassette tape
numbered from 1 to 200
in this plastic bag!!
Cassette tape?
Yeah...
I think that there's at least some clue
about those guys in here...
Some really important information that
she doesn't want the Meniiin.Black
who are watching her to know about!!
Hey!
Don:-tell me that. you're
Iistening to it now?!
I was listening to the
numbered 11 to 15. but...
there;siso much space at the top that
I haven't heard anything yet.
No. don't!!
It's something you don't
need to know about!!
If you: delve any deeper,
you'll really...
Sorry Ar
This-is:definitely a tape
I shouldnst be listening to...
It's yours...
and your voice only...
Listen to it.
To Shiho who has turned 11 years old...
Happy Birthday...
MM Mother?
Have you found .
Somebody you like?
My first love was when...
She probably...
gave the tape to Akemi after feeling
that her life would soon be.ending.
Sheisent words to her maturing daughter
up to her daughter's 20th birthday
of the love she felt for her...
Akemi who received the tape
couldn't give it to TA:
because of severe monitoring...
But, she probably
remembered hiding things
at the design office in the past
and hid it in the toilet there...
so. she could secretly give it to you...
I'm happy for you Au...
Mother...
Your mother was genuinely an angel...
Sorry to keep you waiting...
I don't think I'll need any help¥from you but,
Anyway... get her the minute you see her,
Kalbados...
Orternal Comic Books By.
Or SHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Saripls By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOU (all 1
JUNICHI MIYASHIIA
YUICHI HI(@URI
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Direalors.
MASATOMO SUI(
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWA A
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMU A
TAKASHI HYODO
Art director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photoeraphy.
IAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
! <2 - a
Chief Director
KEN]! KODAMA
Pro (luucll b y.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, ID
In assowiation with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DLIECGVEL ON AN
OGIO AOYAMA SHOGAKUKANYTY - TMS
ATR his Reserved
Mpsr- 7 - : -v
Some wedding we were invited to...
We found the ring and now
it turns out to be kidnapping!
Where is granny?
Where is granny Tae now?
The-Bride-of Huis Ten Bosch