Friendship. Romance, Mystery
Because we cherish them we can continue
Today is 60 minutes special!
The ringlof'a bell in amusement perk.
He seessthrough the one-and only truth.
A chiding appearance
with the I'Q. of An adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
v 347
Wedding at Huis Ten Bosch...
It's so romantic...
I've always wanted to go to
Huis Ten Bosch
But. Sonoko
are you sure
it was okay for us to come along too?
Are you sure
it's not going to inconvenience anyone?
It's okay
because Id be bored if I went alone:and,
besides. just in case something happens,
you're nice to have around.
Hum
In case something happens?
Well
this wedding seems to have had a lot of
hassles before it came to. be.
Or»!
But,
«IO/,
Shinya and I have been friends
since we just started walking...
And there was even a time
When people were thinking of getting us
to marry each other.
It's not only because of that,
but, I really want him to attain
the happiness he deserves...
Oh... \
you're cool, Sonoko.
I Mirren «
Drinks?
Conan.
Would you like anything to drink?
Yes.
Oh. excuse me!!
Hink I'llchave...
Excuse me, Oolong tea please.
Ooolong tea.-please.
Excuse me. Oblong tea please.
Huh?...
Oh, my?
But this"is the Vast can of Oolongrtea -"m
A then. go ahead and"take it. sonny;!
Nope.
You order faster than'me so,
you can:have wt!
Oh. yeah.
Sorry. ..thanks.
Thank you*very much...
Please give me one of those paper cups.
Oh. yes sir
Here you go. sonny...
Huh?!
Thank you!
Oh...thank you so much
Thank you=very much...
Coffee and tea. any orders fordrinks?
Sister and brother traveling together
Coffee and tea. any orders for drinks?
How nice
Oh no.
He's not .my brother...
I wonder why...
each time ll invite Ranato come with me
the kid with the glassesatags along too ?
SOoNnoko
would you likesa sip?
It can't be helped
because if I'm not around
Conan won't be able to eat"his meals...
Right
Hey. hey. Sonoko
what's bugging you'...?
I guess I'll try to stay off her nerves
at least just for today...
Bride of Huis Ten Bosch.
Huh 7!
You're the one we met in the Bullet train...
what a coincidence.
So. you're all going to Huis Ten Bosch to
Yes!!
Are you sightseeing alone?
Yes,
pleaseldon't look at me with
such sympathetic eyes.
Then,
why don'ts ou come with us?
Okay?
Sure!
How delightful
to be able to go around together
with Cute girls like you...
Are you sure you don't mind?
But. the escort fee is expensive...
Huh 2!
Fuh. fuh. only joking! Just kidding...
Ha. ha, ha...
You really surprised me!
Come off it, Sonoko!
Ha, ha, ha...
Ha. ha. ha...
Hey. hey.how much longer
are you guys going to take?
Wow,
we're really at Huis Ten Bosche,
aren't we.
It's so spacious
It sure
doesn:t look like we're in Japan...
Sonoko!
Ow WY
Oh. there they are!
Shinya
Iong time no see...!
Thank you for coming all the way out here!
It's okay
because I came to go sightseeing
while I'm here too...
am She's my best friend Ran and he's Conan.
I'm Ran Mbufi. how do,you do?
I'm Ran Mouri. how dogyou do.»
Il. Conan ..
I'm Shinya Ohga.
She's my fiancé Akane.
I'm Akane Katori. Nice to meet you...
What a beautiful girl...
I'll be on my way then...
Oh, thank you so very much.
Who is he?
His name is Mr. Takahashi, and
he's someone we got to know on the train.
Let's go.
Look. theres -a windmill!
This is Delft Bridge...
Oh. '10Ok. look. there's a swan.
Wow. how graceful...
It's like we've really come to Holland.
I'd really love to go...
Now you know why we chose to have
our wedding here, don't you?
You should have your wedding here
at Huis Ten Bosch too. Sonoko!
What?!!
I'm still in high school!
But. I'll think about it when the time comes!
Hey. ey
how far in the future is that...
Dad,
I brought Sonoko and her friends along.
Hello, Miss.
Thank you so much for coming all this way
just for us.
My. how you've grown.
Sonoko! I'll bet you're tired'!
No. not at all Mrs. Ohga.
I'm not at all-tired.
Because I'm young!!!
Oh my!
This is my best friend.-Ran and Conan.
I accepted Sonoko's kind offer and
came along
Nice to meet you.
I was just thinking that
it was kind of sad
with so little attendance,
because it seems that nobody will be
attending from the bride's side...
Come, come, Mika. don't talk like that
in front of our guests. Ho, hon, ho...
Miss.
Is Chairman Suzuki doing well?
Yes he's just fine
and playing golf everyday.
u seem to'be doing really well yourself
Grandma Tae.
Thank you! ho. ho. ho...
Since I have no successor that I can rely
and entrust the Ohga Financial Group to.
I've got to stay healthy and
keep on working Foh, foh, foh...
Hey. hey...
Hey. Ran!
Do you think this would look nice on
4-Mr Makoto?
Hmm-1 don't really care for it...
Huh
I wonder if Shinichi had one like this?
Oh brother...
Here goes. Conan!
Okay!
Huh.
Hi. there.
Did you already go take a look
at the Glass Museum...?
No I just got here too...
Sonoko, it's Grandma Tae and Mika.
Oh, grandma likes antique glass.
Conan, take a look at this. Isn't it pretty!
17th Century, it says.
So glass has been around from
that long ago...
In Egypt. they seem to have been making
glass decorations since 3000 AD.
It's been around from that long ago...
urmg e umeo 1e Xoman mpnre.
The blown glass method was invented.
And it's also said that
they even had window glasses.
Is that right...
You're quite knowledgeable, aren't you...
Well, I'm a glass craftsman from Hotaru,
Hokkaido. I took time off from work,
and came here wanting to see the glass
works of Nagasaki.
I OTC.
My liking for glass, developed into
my having a glass workshop in the city.
What do you think,
we have dinner together tonight...?
I'd like to hear about glass in Hotaru too...
I would like to by all means
if you don't mind.
My name is Takahashi.
Wow! How tall.
The town is like a toy!
What a nice view...
I always used to like high places!
See, the people walking below
Iook like swarming ants.
Doesn't it just make you feel so good?
Foh. foh, foh...
This is Mr. Takahashi a glass
craftsman from Hotaru.
I invited him over because
I wanted-to hear his story on. glass+
I'm Junichi Takahashi.
Hm Mr Ohga.
y SON - yinya Ss wed cing Is omorrow,
and that's why we're all
spending the night here.
You're most welcome.
I didn't think that
Shinya would beat Mika and get married.
Ll V:
He beat you to it. didn't he?
I don't buy cheap stuff...
That's right, Mr. Takahashi,
I'd"like you to, attend tomorrow's wedding.
But. I really shouldn't...
You're more than welcome to
Shinya will have to shoulder the
Ohga Finance Group in the future.
I'm sure that attending the wedding
will not be a loss to you too.
W.What...I'm a glass craftsman and...
Okay. I'll attend.
Thank you
Akane.
Wear this at your wedding tomorrow...
This is a ring that has been handed down
for generations to the wives
of the Ohga family.
The founding president
who started a shipping
industry at the beginning of the Meiji Era
gave this to his wife
when he first went to Europe.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, mother!
Maybe it's too soon to give it to her yet.
But.
L'also=received-it from you
and wore it to the wedding.
Itrs: because in your case
everyone had viewed you
as"being the rightperson
as the wife of the family
head to begin with
The only time the ring
Is to be handed down
IS when the bride is approved of as
becoming a member of the Ohga family...
Which means you all don't approve of
Akane as being my wife?!
Well,
she can wear it
during the wedding ceremony. though
It seems like...
We've been invited to some wedding...
What the heck was that!
Is that how the family of somebody
who Is going to have a sacrediwedding
tomorrow supposed to act?!
What the hell's going on, Sonoko™!
I told you that
they went through a bit of a hassle
before the wedding was decided. didn't I?
Sonoko. why is that grandmother
so mean to Akane'?
Shinya declared that if they
didn't app ove of him marrying Akane,
he would leave home
So, it seems the Ohga family
all reluctantly approved...
But... Akane's such a nice person!
The family of a financial group has
all kinds of hassles. .l
What?! You mean
they don't like her family lineage?!
And it seems grandma doesn't like
the fact that
S1€esS "years ocer wan um el er.
that's no reason to be mean to her
Hey» the show's started!!
Ran! I'm going to go over that side
and watch.
Be careful. okay!
Ah gee
it sure is inconvenient- to have a
small body at times like these
Huh
That's Akane and Mr. Takahashi?!
kane, you look fantastic
You can say that again!
You look just marvelous
Make sure you throw me the bouquet after
the wedding ceremony. okay Please!
Promise now!
Hey. hey...
LIA wie)
I'm not sure if I'll be able to aim right.
But I'll try my best.
Only an hour more to go
before the wedding.
Akane is so beautiful!
Hey. Shinya
how about a word to the bride?
Oh. yeah.
You look really dazzling...
da __-
Wow~~~talk about hot. hot!
Oh. come on. Sonoko...
Shinya.
How unsightly of you
to be entranced by your bride.
Stay in your waiting room
until it's time for the wedding.
Akane...
I will take on the role of the brides father.
Thank you so...
Oh...?
It's your foot...
I think you stepped on this.
Huh, oh...is that it?
Oh, I'm so sorry. really sorry.
This picture,
are they your parents, Akane?
Yes...
at me
Aagh!
G. Grandma!
Grandma!
My heart's just started throbbing a bit.
I'll get better After a little rest.
Here
grab my shoulder...
Rest a while till. it's time:for the ceremony.
I wonder if Grandma Tae's okay?
I hope it's nothing serious...
I'm fine!
Huh? But...
Huh ?!
Huh 7!
Huh 2!
What's the matter. @onan...?
Akane! The ring! Do you have it...?
Huh?! No...
The ring is...gone
R.Really!!
It.It's gone!!
What's this?
You're in it!
SS eo 9
If I remember correctly. this is...
a picture that Shinya took for me
when we came to reserve
this wedding hall in June...
What does this mean?
Beats me...
If I lose that: ring
how am I going to take
responsibility for it .
I know I can't simply apologize...
Akane!! What-re you talking about!
It's just a ring after all...
Let's all look for it!
What,
we ru )y rung us 0s...
Is that... .true?!
Yes...
Call the wedding off!
Huh
We-re calling off this wedding.
What?!
There will be no wedding
until the ring is found!!
OO. Oh no. we can't do that now!
Come now. mother dear...
Think about it. Masayo!
Huh
Ever since talk of this wedding
came around.
Bad things have-been happening one
after the other.
And that girl's to blame for everything.
To top things off.
She loses the ring,
which is a family treasure...
It's not Akane's fault!
And? What is Akane doing right now?
Vs JT
She says she wants to be alone
and is in the waiting room...
I see. ..She must be in shock...
Everyone,
it's almost time for the ceremony to begin!
Is something wrong?
The ruby ring is lost...
What?!
You mean that ring that
the founder brought back from Europe?!
It was definitely there until all of you came.
Hey. Shinya,
just what are you trying to say'?
Don't tell me that you're suspecting us!
When Sonoko and her friends came
she says she was sure the ring was there.
Which means
it has to be the work of somebody
who came into the room later. right?
Uh, it couldibe that glass craftsman
from Hotaru called Takahashi...
This picture was left
behind in place of the ring.
Since Shinya is the-one
who took this-picture,
anybody from
the Ohga family could've got hold of it.
You can't really tell...
Akane had the picture too. didn't she?
She could've stolen the ring
and left the picture behind to make it
Iook as if someone from the Ohga family
took it. right?
OO. Oh no!
Well. no big deal
It doesn:t-feel.good
being suspected-anyway
so let's-have them check every nook
and cranny of our rooms right away.
However
so long as the whereabouts of the ring is
unknown, this marriage will be cancelled,
understand?!
Ori1einal Comic Books By.
SHO AOYA A
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
Character Designs By
MA ATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I10OKA
Scripts By.
OKANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Dircealors.
MASATOMO SUI(
HIROTOSHITAKATANI
HARUO COCA WA A
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMU A
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photocraphy.
IAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN]! KODAMA