Friendship. Romance, Mystery
Because we cherish them we can continue
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child inappearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
<< 2D
Wedding at Huis Ten Bosch...
The rings nowhere in sight...
It so small that it can be hidden
anywhere too
Hey, Ran... 7?!
What's the matter. Ran?
I'm worried,
so lym going\to go see how Akane is...
Ran!
What are the bad things that happened
that grandma was talking about?
Oh... that...
Recently, there were two incidents
here we experienced close calls...
Ma'am!! The brakes aren't working!!
Whaaa!!
M. Ma am?!
The second time was
on a clear. fine morning...
When was takingra walk with grandma
along Holland Slope near 'our house...
Huh
Look out!!
Well,
wé were saved by ashairsbreadth, but...
\ losing the ring is
the third bad thing that happened
so Grandma Taeiis probably fed up...
Akane...
Strange.
I'm sure that someone who
came into the waiting room took it, but...
Sonoko!
Ran!
A. Akane is not in the waiting room!
What?!
Meave. heave
the wedding dress was on the chair
and Akane was nowhere in sight...
Don't tell me that
Akane put on an act just as Mika had said.
Ind actually stole the ring herself...?!
Akaness not kind of person!!
O eo 0
Let's go look,for her.
But what about the ring?
Without it there'll be no wedding...
I'm... really bothered about
the Hydrangea in the picture.
Hydrangeas signify "A change of heart"...
I think we'll find the ring in a place
where the Hydrangeas are...
Shinya!! What's with the wedding?
Well,
Akane, disappeared.
W.What? The bride's gone?!
Y.Yes...
We were just thinking of splitting up
and looking for her.
I'll help look for her too!
Thank you!
I'll go look for the ring!
Hydrangeas,
where do I look for them
Kane
Hydrangea...change of heart...
Music box?
Change of heart...
Seabolt
Wait a sec...
I learned of it before.
Dr. Seabolt is the one who took
Japanese plants back to Europe...
And, one of the main ones was
the Hydrangea.
The old scientific name for
this flower is Hydrangea Otakusa.
The name was taken from Seabolt's
Japanese wife's name, Otaku...
Just as I thought...
Akane's picture was not
about 'what the flower signified
but rather about the scientific name...
jiKR
Otakusa ..Otaki san... Taki...
Taki(waterfall)...
Right!
I found it!!
Otaki-san... Taki(waterfall)...
My God...
I don't know who hid it but...
1. 1 get it.
This fountain-is Aphrodite and Pushke!!
Conan!
I found the ring!
R.Really?
Is something the matter?
W. Well...
Huh 7!
Akane's high heel shoe!!!
It's not normal for her to go around
with just one shoe...
I'm sure that she was kidnapped here!
We find the ring
and now Akane's Kidnapped!
Only...one shoe
was found by theiwindmill shed...
This is...
WwW. What's going on?
I'm just assuming from the circumstances.
But I think she was dragged away
against her will
N.No. do you mean she was abducted?!
Don't be ridiculous!
I'm sure she couldn't take staying/here
and fled!
I checked at the departure gate
of Huis Ten Bosch
and found that
she hasn't gone outside yet!
It seems that Akane,
in the past had a man that hertparent's
had decided' she get mariied to. I
I thinkithat-she is still seeing that man...
And maybe she had planned to
\. .1!
Embarrass Shinya to begin with...
N.No way!
I know her best!
Grandma's right!
Shinya: you've been completely deceived!
Like they say from long ago.
Love'is blind!
agNo!!
You're talking about the man that was
Akane's fatherzs'apprentice, right?
That's anold story that 'goes back
10\ ears ago
He left 10 years ago and
hasn't contactedlher
even once, since!
Well,
without the bride,
we can't possibly have the wedding.
After the engagement and all.
If it turns out that the wedding
IS canceled,
it will be a blow to the trust that
people have in the Ohga Financial Group.
If the wedding is really going to
be called off,
then Shinya's promotion to
Vice-President of the bank
will probably have to be reconsidered.
D.Dear...
She's slim and
her hair is about this long...
I think she was wearing
pink one-piece dress...
I wonder if you mean her?
Have you seen her?
Yes...
she went into the windmill shed alone...
About what time was it?
It was just about the time...
I came back from lunch break...so,
maybe around 13:00...7
About 13:00...
¥ she was abducted as you say.
Are you saying that
the one who took her away is here...
among us?
I can't say for sure, but
I think the probability is high )
How rude!
Do you know what you're talking about?!
Calm down. Mochida...
And just what are you planning to
do gathering us together like this?
Akane was seen going
into the windmill shed about 13-00 today.
by a sales clerk at the cheese store
So. I'd like to know
where you were at around 13:00.
Checking for alibi...eh.
I was here adjusting the books.
«I was here with my wife all the while
Around 13:00
I was horseback riding
in Friesian Horse Land.
Since the wedding was cancelled
I was drinking at the lounge here.
What about you. Mr. Takahashi
13:00...7
I think that's just about the time
I went once again to the Glass Museum
to look-at antique glass...
beep. beep...
Just as I thought!
Can I borrow it?!
Yeah. .sure
If you want the pictures that are in it,
they'll print it out for you at the front desk.
Don. okay!
Thank you .
, May I ask you something,.
Mr Mochida?
What is it?
,,ls there something special
about Akane's family?
Her father used to be a renown glass
craftsman in Nagasaki,
but passed away 10 years ago.
Anything else?
A WP.
There are rumors that
he committed suicide
because Ohga Bank pressured him
to return the money
that w financed 'him:...
Sfiuicide?!
The glass workshopsthat grandma owns
in the city used to be his
Grandma bought the workshop
that the bank forfeited as collateral.
She wanted the workshop.
SO she pressured him toreturn the money
nd got a hold of the workshop...
1IS'what some people say,
but that's wrong!
All we did was carry out
a legal transaction
Hmm -well...
Yes! This person came
He was drinking beer alone...
right through...yes. for about an hour...
Yes. I remember her.
She seemed to have really liked it
and rode twice...
Oh. I see!
Thank you so much...
This isn't the place...
It's more to the back...
Here?! The long hand fits.
So its 15:05 now...
Huh
Wait a sec...
Which means that this picture was
taken not at 13:00 sharp.
But rather at 13-05!
Since it's a faceless clock when the long
hand and the short hand overlaps.
It looks to be 13:00 sharp!
If the abductor abducted: her
at-the:windmill shed at 13:00,
and is here at 14:05...
Akane is probably confined
somewhere that's not too far away
between the windmill shed
and the flower clock!!
I've got to find her quick!
You mentioned that you like high places,
didn't you?
Right...
Oh...you mean I get to ride that?
Darn...where is she...
Hmm?!... The melody sounds strange.
I get it! Some bells aren't ringing
Maybe...
here...
Huh? Aren't you riding?
No way. I hate high places and
Aadiad 2
just thinking about it
sends chills up my spine
Aalad 2
So go ahead and enjoy yourself.
Wong,
'um'?
Foh, foh, and you're still so young.
Akane!!
Uguuuuh...
Mr. Takahashi's going to kill
Grandma Tae...
What?!
Hello...!!
Oh, Conan!
Grandma is...
Where's grandma Tide now?
Uh. she went to ride the balloon
ith Mr. Takahashi...
Yes. the hot air balloon... Luftballoon.
Foh, foh, foh...
I feel like a bird.
A a IP
- - 7 f
a or.
Huh?...
That's...
Huh? WW. What's that?!
AA bomb?!
There he is'!
W.we're not going to make it!!
There he is!!
W. we're not going to make it!!
Huh? What's that?
No! Don't touch it!!
It's a tgiggering device that will set off
the bomb set up on the balloon!
That's why don't touch it!
W What?!
I guess you two saved
I'm so glad grandma...
Akane!
I'm so glad you re okay!
Shinya. I'm so sorry.
Mr. Takahashi...
What?!
Mr. Takahashi?
A.Akane. did you know him?
Yes...
What is the meaning of this?
What do you mean Grandma was
in danger?!
S-Sonoko...
poke
Ugh?! Aaah
QYSOHOTKQR
H Huh
What?!
S.Sonoko...
This entire case to begin with,
started with two people
with different ideas
acting at the same time
Therefore, it looked as if one person was
scheming everything.
"SA 9
One of them was you,
wasn't it: Grandma Tae?
What?!
Since you were against the marriage
between Shinya and Akane
G.Grandmother!
My heart's just started throbbing a bit.
I'll get better after a little rest...
That's right. isn't it, Mika?
My God!
Conan. please bring the, you know what...
O «7 Bg Mag Sing
All!
Akane! Here you go...
Wow!! You found it...
the ring!
T.Thank you!
Oh. Conan!
I wonder where it was found?
You know the fountain by Mauritz
Square, don't you...?
He seems to have found it there.
Leaving it too close to yourself
would increase
the chances of us finding it
when we go looking for it.
Since Grandma Tae said so.
You hid in at the fountain!
Isn't that right, Mika?!
Y...Yes, that's right.
Then
« 2-0
what was the picture of
the Hydrangea about?
What was the picture of
what wasisthe picture of
the Hydrangea about?
I was deceived by that too.
At first because the Hydrangea signifies
a change of heart,
I thought it was criticizing
Akane for her change of heart.
But there was
another meaning to that picture...
Another meaning?!
The water of that fountain flows
Iike that of a waterfall. doesn't it?!
Yes.
The scientific name that was given to.
The Hydrangea in the beginning
was Hydrangea Otakusa.
A name that Seabolt had given it?
He called it:Otakusa
after his wife's name Otaki.
Otakusa...Otakisan...
Taki(waterfall)... right?!
That's what it was!
Yes... >
Yes...
Did you know about it?
Huh?...Yeah...
Although that picture looked to
be criticizing Akane.
Ifiwaswacitually indicating
where the ring was hidden...
Now you'know.
The people who stole
the ring are
Grandma and Mika!
But.
Akane being abducted
» we WW
2 we LY
was a mere coincidence.
is 74
J or y
She feltresponsible for \
Iosing the ring and
She feltresponsible for
gave up-on:marrying Shinya.
Then, on her own initiative
she decided to disappear...
What happened after that?
Akane? (
id aa
re LN
I went out from the waiting room
Or {Ts Dexa ginal,
II coincidentally found! Mr. Takahashi...
anc secre y oOo owed aim.
Mr. Takahashi, just what are you...?!
I'm going to give it to that old lady!
Huh 7!
Have you forgotten?
Your father passed away
all because of that old lady!
The one who stole the.ring is
that girl called Mika, you know.
N., No!?
Of-course the Old lady, told her todo so,
though...
Please let me go through with
what I've planned
And- till Conan came toisave.me
I was locked up
in Carillon Symphonica...
Th. Then he...
Yes.
He's the one who had been chosen;
as Akane's groom in the past
that Grandma was talking about.
What?!
I'm sorry I didn't tell you about it.
When I saw Mr. Takahashi yesterday
with Sonoko and theé-others
I was really surprised
because its been 10 years
since I last saw him...
Akane...
you saw Mr. Takahashi last night,
didn't you?
Yes,
I asked him why he came.
He answered
that he came to watch my wedding
from a far.
I was worried whether
he'was really telling me the truth
nd if hat,was all there was to it...
Mr. Takahashi,
isn't it about time you got up?
Just how long do you
intend to stay sleeping there!
Oh, my .
Since-when did youlrealize
I thought something was
strange to begin with,
because although you said
you were from Hotaru,
when you saw Akane
in her wedding dress,
you spoke in Nigasaki dialect
and said she was beautiful...
You're the one who tampered with
the brakes of Grandma's car
as well as dropped the rock from
above thegstone wall. right?!
Yeah, that's right.
Ops. . .Akane's father
was killed by this old lady!
Pops...
was suddenly pressured to return the
money that Ohga Bank had loaned him,
and committed suicide out of desperation.
I've never forgot the miserable
sight of her father,
not even once.
Pops.
Pops. why'd you do this...
Ieaving Akane all alone...
This all happened because the old lady
wanted a glass workshop for her pastime
ust before this, we were gradually
Iosing orders from our big dealers.
I went to ask a wholesaler in Hotaru
where Pops had transactions with.
He finally admitted
He was reducing-ordering to us because
he was concerned about Ohga Bank.
Wirong!
Mother liked Mr. Katori's glass works
So. wanting him to somehow continue
she even gave him advice on
how to manage the workshop
What?!
However
Mr. Katori who was a craftsman through @
and through refused to lend an ear.
He insisted saying, "My glass work is
only for those who see the value in them!
He kept making fantastic glass works
spending time, putting his all into them...
Of course his works were expensive
but they were indeed masterpieces.
However, they didn't make out
and he went more and more into the reds;.
As a result...
As a result, he started delaying payments
for the loan he had with us.
First he delayed 3 days. a week,
then two weeks and so on forth
We're not all that big a bank either, so
we couldn't afford this to goon forever...
@&L >
That's a lie!
It's not a lie!
Ts ale...
It's notea lie. Mr. Takahashi...
U.Uuugh...
ts ale
It's a lie.
Pops-isn't such a weak person...
He used to sweat from early morning
to late at night...
teaching me,
who knew nothing!!. from A to 2...
Grandma, you were against Akane
gettingsmarried:because
you blamed yourself for not being
thoughtful enough therefore,
driving Akane's father to suicide. right?
That's why it really hurt for you
to look at Akane, right?
Grandma...
So. since Akane found out
that Mr. Takahashi was attempting
to kill Grandma, she was locked up
I know U's not something
that can be forgiven
but. Please.
Please forgive Mr. Takahashi
Akane...
Grandma.
Chairman!...
About playing the role of the father
of the bride, Mochida,
although hess quite young,yet,
why don't we have Mr. Takahashi do it?
Lo.of course, I totally agree!!
» EN" «
GS ad a.
Then...you're approving of them
getting married?
The ring was found, so most naturally
Oh. I'm glad!
Grandmaghad intended things
to turn out this way to begin with
What?!
She was intending to approve of
their marriage when the ringpwas found...
How do you know?
The sculpture of that fountain is
Aphrodite and Psyche.
Aphrodite, jealous of Psyche
who had fallen in love with her son. Eros.
Gives Psyche many trials to.accomplish.
However, she finally approves both
to see throughstheir love
afters Psyche accomplishes everything
that'was dished out to her...
That fountain describesithis final scene.
Grandma knew of this Greek mythology
and had the ring 'hidden there.
She even deliberately left the picture
of the Hydrangeas
behind as a hint,
pointing to Taki, Seabolt's wife,
isn't that right, Grandma?
It" so full of western letters,
that I have no idea what it's about.
Ho. ho. ho...
Oh, my...
Just as expected off you. Grandma.
When things get inconvenient for. you,
you tryito brush it off...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
When things get inconvenient for you,
you tryato brush it off...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKO'SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUD
Story Editor
Story Editor:
JUNICHI 11GKA
Do you promise]
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
JUNICHI 110OKA
Story Editor
JUNICHI 11OKA
to love him?
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I110OKA
JUNICHI I11OKA
I do!
Scripts By
KANJT KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KQUTHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURK
TOSHIKI INOUE
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIW w Wm
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
» 9 I . »
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUD @QGGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHLNOMURA
HIRONOBUX* RIKOSH
WAGA
Recordin Director.
KATSUYOSHI KO 3AYASHI
Editor...
TERUMITSU OKADA
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
In association with
YOMIURI TELEW STING
CORPORATION
1137 af INV EC (ON ANT
Agh'!
I'm supposed to get married to
Mr. Kyogoku and yet!!
Huh...Oh...
Aaaghn~~~Ran took it!
N.Not my fault!
For some reason it looks as if...
the number of people acting weird
has been increasing recently...
" have a feeling that something bad
might happen soon...
What? That brat ran away from home?
How sassy. the next time I see him, I'll...
No. he went to take care of
WAI who's sick in bed
What ?!
Shinichi...
hat...
Ran...?!
(B1%k)
(RI*R)
Convenience Store Trap=Part 1