Friendship. Romance. Mystery
Because we cherish them
we can continue
A cheerful andspopular
convenience, store
A case arises from the back of the store
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the l.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
<< DD
Yes, this is the Mouri
Oh.Conan?!
Where are you? It's already late.
What?
You're going to stay over
at Dr. Agasa's house tonight?
Yep. Ars cold got worse because of me
so I want to take care of her.
Yup.
But what about your change of clothes
and school things?
Yep! Don't worry.
I brought them all here
Besides. itss almost winter vacation.
May I. Ran?
Well.
Okay!
Take good care of her now
Thank you, Ran.
See ou.
You don't have to spend!'the night here
to take care of Al. Shinichi.
I can take care of her myself.
It's because there have been a lot of
weird people around us lately
I feel like something
disturbing may happen soon
$A AA
GREET),
(ma)
Convenience Store Trap Part 1
$A AA
(mm)
Who are you?
Teacher.
Jodie?!
You look very tired.
I understand that
you may be having a tough time
with the bad behavior
of the brats of Japan.
But don't let them get to you!
No! No!!
They're all good students!
I'll have to say goodbye to all of you soon
It's so very sad.
What?!
Jodie. you re going to quit 7!
No'!
She has some family affairs to attend to.
So she'll be leaving us at the end
of this month to return to the US...
I wonder what
\er real affair as all about...
I wonder. 4.
Ehem.
Although it was only for a short time.
I really enjoyed studying
together with all of you!
I'm sure that you'll be going through
a lot:of things from now on too.
but I know that you'll all pull through!
So. good luck and stick it out!
J. Jodie.
Uh. Jodie.
Isn't it about time you tell usy
Tell you what?
The reason why you're quitting school
What is this family affair that
you're referring to?
Oh! That's a lie!
Huh?
The truth is
I've been looking for
something for a long time
It's a map of a very precious treasure
and I finally found it.
Well. I think I found it!
A treasure map?!
Maybe she's talking about her first love?
But if so, I don't think
she'd say map because it would be
the treasure itself that's precious.
Oh, wait Jodie!
You're not making sense!
No. No! It's a secret!
can ee you wo.
A secret makes a woman a woman!
Okay?
O. Okay.
But, how disappointing.
I really wish he could've taken
your classes too.
Oh!-You mean Shinichi?
Oh. es.
Let him be!
What?!
He leaves his wife all alone saying that
he has cases to solve. the pits.
W. Wife.
I mean how long is he going to take,
to solve one case
Hoe should just give up and come home
No way. he would never.
He'll never run from something part way
Because he loves to put on airs.
that's the thing you
Iove. love. love about him.
Just totally irresistible
Excuse me!
I'm just saying that
he likes to put on airs and is stubborn...
W.Who cares if he comes home or not.
Oh! Talking about coming home,
did the cool kid come home?
What?! You mean, Conan? ,
That brat with glasses?
Yes! Hews always at Dr. Agasa's house
when I call recently!
What?
You mean he ran away from home?
How sassy of twine -
Next time I see him I'll.
No! He's taking care of Al
wince she has a cold!
What?!
He says that he's to blame
for Al catching a cold
so he's going to take care of her
until she recovers completely and
brought his change of clothes
and everything over
Oh.you mean that brat has a soft side too
Well, sorry.
Right!
Why don't we go to
your condo and have a party?!
What is it, all of a sudden?!
Party?
A small farewell party for you. Jodie!!
We can buy snacks
and drinks at the convenience store!
Sounds great!!
What do you say: Jodie?
Okay!
Let's go to the convenience store
in front of the station then!
Oh, the one that Aya is working at!
Ava?!
Was there a student by that name?
She's our classmate
when we were inf intermediate school!
She's a cheerful girl.
So I'm sure you'll like her too!
SundayMar
Thank you very much!!
BundayMarta;
Huh?
Excuse" me.
Yes?
Is there a girliby the name of
Aya Nanakawa working here?
Q.Oh
she's inside with the shopkeeper...
Huh?
How many times do I have to tell you?!
Ghads .
During peak hours we're desperate
and needfall the help we can get
It seems we're just going to have to hire
someone new to take your place
Oh no.
WwW: What's wrong. Aya??
Aah...
Ran?
Uuugh...Ran!!
AAya?!
What's the matter. Aya?
Who are you people?
Friends, f-r-i-e-n-d-s!!
I'm a high school teacher!!
What seems to be the matter?
A lot's the matter.
The total sales of the store
and the number of items
In the store don't match!!
And this happens only
when Aya's in charge of closing the store! >
How rude!!!
And. why should Aya be blamed for it?!
Maybe one of
your customers is shoplifting?!
Aya tells me that this shop is
crowded in the mornings and at nights.
SO maybe then.
Yeah.
I thought so too,
that's why I set up surveillance cameras.
when this shop was renovated!!
I kept very close watch,
but there was no such customer.
Then, maybe it was a burglar?
I thought of that too! That's why
Iast night,
I parked my car opposite the store
and kept watch right through!
But, all I saw was Aya
who came out after cleaning the store
and closing:the shutter.
Nobody Came to-the store from then
to the following morning
when the store was opened
When I opened the shop
and checkedrthe storeroom
the figures didn't match.
The only thing thinkable is that Aya stole.
1.1 didn't steal anything!!
By the way,
what was stolen?
A lot of things.
Game software: DVDs~CDs
Iunch boxes and riceballs,
mineral water--Oolong tea
Cokes and snacks including chocolate...
I can just see young kids gather around,
playing music
and games, watching DVDs
and catching their thrills!
But. if Aya were the one,
wouldn't Aya be displayed
on the surveillance camera?
The surveil ance cameras are
set to go, off at closing.
Because the electric bills aren't
all-that cheap either.
Then, the light here is turned off
because of that?
Well, I'm trying to.economize to
regain what fl can. of my losses.
Besides the customers who come to use
the restroom are all regular customers.
So they can find the
restroom: even if it's dark.
Uh, Aya,
have you noticed anyone
who looks suspicious .«m
N.No.
I wouldn't say suspicioussbut
There are three customers that
I'm concerned about.
Huh?
Is something bothering you?
What type of people are they?
They all come to use the toilet a lot.
Tell us more about it!
Oh: Uh-huh.
One looks to be a university student
and occasionally stands and reads
game magazines until almost closing time
A game freak.
But. he never bought any_games_here
All he buys are cup noodles
and pouched food ¥
Besides. he's pretty selfish,
and cuts in line at the register.
The second one is a man
who looks to be a salaried worker
He seems to be very timid and is
overly hesitant over even thing
Overly hesitant?
Yes. he's always looking.down
Even when the university student
I mentioned earlier cuts in line.
He lets him do so without getting angry.
Even when using the restroom,
he lets everybody go on before him
saying that he's not in a rush.
He always buys things
Iike a toothbrush set. batteries.
Shaving razor sets and towels.
All things you would
take along when traveling.
The third one is a stubborn
and thrifty old woman.
Yeah. I know that old lady too!
She asks for discounts-on-lunches
that are almost past the expiration date.
She lectures telling us'to compare prices
with other stores and to stay-on our balls.
But that old woman's not a bad person!
She turns off unneeded lights,
and-also told me what temperature
I should set the air conditioning at,
to save money.
Well,
she talks all she wants with us
and leaves without buying a thing. though.
which makes all three of them suspicious.
Why?
Why do you say that?
Because
it could be that the game freak wanted
the game software that he couldn't buy.
The salaried worker may
Iike to go on trips
and maybe wants snacks
to take along with him.
And. the granny could've been ¥
checking'out which / lunch.
Shc: wanted to eat
without buying anything.
All three of them have
a possibility of being the culprit -
Phooey.
I think that it's more appropriate
to suspect Aya
before suspecting the customers.
I've been trying to tell you
that Aya's not that type of girl!
Give me an explanation then,
of why after scolding Aya last month
about the same thing
the items stopped missing!!
Huh?
Really?
Yeah.
Since the items stopped missing
for a month now
I was determined to stop watching
the store.after closing last. night.
I figured that Aya finally repented
what she did.
But. when I opened.the store this morning
a lot of things were missing again.
She probably. couldn't
stop herself any longer!
If you apologize for what you did,
up to toda
I'll let you-go this time! If not you-re fired!
He . Ran
things look really bad!
Right!
Why don't you talk about this to Shinichi?!
He can probably solve something
Iike this in no time at all.
But. I don't have his phone number
His number is never displayed.
How about you. Sonoko.
No inspiration at all?
If I was inspired I wouldn't be saying
things like this, would 1? Aha.
Maybe we can ask Conan?
He always comes up with interesting
ideas and.notices odd things!
0,0 guws s@oooooAhap ha;
although it irks me
to ask that glasses kid. a bit.
Uh. he's at Dr. Agésas house so.
Jodie?
Shhh
Huh?
It's not good relying on somebody
without trying all we can ourselves first!
Let's try to work things out
for her ourselves.
B.But.
I really haven't stole anything!
You still insist.
You never know when you will loose
the one you can rely on so.
SundayMart
Be.honest with me, will you!
You're the one who did it. right?
Y.You've got me wrong, shopkeeper!
I haven't stolen anything from the store!
I'm sure Conan would be able to
come up with something but
Are you sure that
I shouldn't call him. Jodie?
Yes, yes, I'm sure
The-cool Kid is busy looking after Ai!
We shouldn't bother him!
I.I guess so. but.
But ..if we leave Aya as is
Huh?
She'll be fine!
We don't have to rely on that kid!
1. the Queen of deduction Sonoko will
solve this case without his help!
Oh?!
RR. Right...
First, let's organize what went on.
The total sales of this convenience store.
And the number of items.in the. storeroom
for some reason don't match.
And the items start
missing for some reason
Aya is in charge.of cleaning the store
and closing the shop.
Therefore, it's only natural
that the shopkeeper suspects
Aya of having stolen the items.
But. we've known Aya
since intermediate school
and know that she's a good girl.
So, we think there's another culprit
and begin investigation.
Everything's okay up to here, right?
tight.
What concerns me are the three
customers that Aya referred to.
One is the university student
type game freak.
The other is the timid
and hesitant salaried worker type man.
And the last one is
a stubborn granny.
Each of them buys
different things such as
The game freak buys only cup noodles
and;pouched food.
The salaried worker buys
toothbrush sets, batteries,
shaving razor sets and-towels.
They were all things
that one would take on trips.
The granny buys nothing!
All she used to do was talk to
the personnel of the store
and buy nothing!
All three of them seem suspicious
and yet it could be otherwise.
Maybe it's just that somebody shoplifted
or the store was robbed. after all?
I think that's impossible!
The shopkeeper,
had surveillance cameras set up
you know?!
No chance for burglars.
No can do!
The problem is,
when she was scolded by the shopkeeper
after he suspected her,
the items stopped missing.
And yesterday, a month after that,
again on the day that she is in charge,
a large amount
of things were stolen again!
C.Come to think of it, Aya
You like snacks and juice, don't you.
You used to be hooked on games too.
Hey!
We're trying to prove. Aya's innocence.
Aren't we?
I. Know.
Think what he would think
at times like this.
What would Shinichi think.
What would he think.
The point is the discrepanciessyou find
when compared with the usual situation.
Whenever a case occurs,
something is different from the usual.
First observe very closely
ance pimMpoinNn "waa 11s.
No matter if it's something
that anyone would do
or something that's so trivial
and apt te occur.
If it's different frem the usual,
It's a great problem!
Those more than usual
and plain things are
the most worth noticing as different.
Something different from: the usual.
I see
so If the items only start missing
when Aya's in charge.
Huh?
B.But, all I do is clean the store.
Is there anything you noticed,
shopkeeper?
N.No, not really.
Anything, no matter
how trivial it may seem!
Huh?
It's nothing much, but.
It's nothing much, but
What is it?
When Ava i1ssln charge
The inside of the store is-especially clean!
See.
The boxes with the items inside
that arrived just
before closing are all in order!
The other employees and I leave
organizing the boxes to the employees
who come in the morning and go home.
It's the same with you too,
isnrt it, shopkeeper?
Phooey.
She probably did it to rid herself
of her guilty conscience,
but I won't be deceived.
O.Oh no.
Even for the lunches.
She probably thought it was okay
because all of them were
near the expiration date.
But a thief's a thief!
I could go ahead and call the: police
and have them investigate: you"know!
The police .
Huh?!
Aaagh
Then what is it?
Are you people going to figure out
what's going on?
And capture the real culpri...Huh?
A.Agh.
Shinichi...
Shinichi
Shinichi!!
Huh?
Ran?!
Just my imagination, I guess.
Hey. Shinichi!
Where were you?
Nowhere special
Huh?
Ail doesn't seem to be around?
Oh, Ail is In her room.
Hey. hey.
She's still not all that well, is she?
She's fine!
The heater is on,
and besides; I thought it best
to leave her alone.
She's probably listening to
thatstape again.
Shiho...
don't you regret
what yourre:stryingito: do now-.-7?
I'm with you all the way!
I'm with-you all the way!
I7llkalways be with you. so give it your all.
Mother
ow. ¥
Ill talk to you -againion.your 19th birthday.
Bye. bye for now.
Catch you later.
Oh. and
Huh?
May I help your
Hmm.
Excuse me!!
Whaaa?!
T,.The restroom! Restroom!!
Wow.
Look at the people at the cash register!
Oh my.
Its: really starting to get crowd&d.
Yes...really
Yes really
Even the restroom's starting
to get crowded.
Come to think of it, Aya was saying
that the suspicious three customers
used to use the restroom a lot.
Yep.
We'll get back to this after
we take care of all these customers.
Go back to the cash register. will you.
YO, Sli
If you two have no intention of buying
anything. go on outside. will you?
B.But.
You're interfering with business!
Go on...
There, there, there you go!
Agh., w, wait.
If.If we leave things as is
Aya will be
blamed as the burglar!!
Whaaaal!
Aya!
AL - 4
Ran, w,what shall we do?
Shinichu.
What on earth...should I do?
Shinichil!
Orioinal Comic Books By.
SHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
» 'Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
\ KAN]! KASHIWABA A
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHI
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation DirceGlors.
MASATOMO SUD
HIROTOSHITAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWA A
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photovraphy.
IAKASHI NOMURA
IRONOBU HO
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSéf 0101014
Chit Director.
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, ITD.
In 1ssoaration with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
GO RPORATION
DITFCINVEL ONAN
CDHO AOYAMA SHOGAKUKANYTY - TMS
All Rio his Reserved
We exclude the impossibilities I!
and no matter how impossible
the remaining things may seem....!
It is the truth!
Hurry. everybody!
Run for it!
What shall I do...
I could tell them my deduction but...
What if it's a mistake...
What if I'm off the point...
If you think your deduction is correct,
Huh? Try it?
Convenience Store Trap Part 2