Friendship. Romance. Mystery
Because we cherish them we can continue
Ran gets involvedyin a case at a
convenience store
A-pure deduction to save her friend
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child inrappearance.
With the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Convenience Store Trap Part 2
Who are you?
J.Jodie?! Jodie!
E you all right, Jodie...
Didg¢you come across
an idea or something?
You seemed to be in deep thought...
No idea... Not the slightest!
Huh? What's the matter?
Huh?! Oh...l saw you take off
your glasses for the first time so...
You know what I mean, don't you?
Yeah...
For the first time...?
But...those glasses
sure look old...
Oh, yes!
This is something I cherish...
The only vestige that a person very,
very important to me. left in this world
That's why it's so very important!
A very important person...?
Is.Is it a keepsake of your ex-lover
r something? Heh, heh...
By the way, did you two
figure out this case?
Not at allll...Hmm...
Huh?!
It stopped...
A delivery truck?
Right! The sales clerk
Huh...?
Huh... 27
Remember...
On the days that Aya is in charge,
even the boxes that arrive just before
closing are nicely organized, right...
Now that you mentioned it,
the sales clerk said so...So?
How does that connect
to what happened?
Uh?...
Grr 1 wonaocr now it connec.
Sigh...Ah .
I thought you had something in mind...
There!
Here are the items
you ordered!
Oh. you're early...
We'll stack the boxes up as usual in
the corridor.in front of the restroom...
Oh, a customer is still using
the restroom.. What should I do...
Oh...
We'll bring the boxes over again later.
We got otherplaces
to make deliveries to too
Thank you
Since a customer as
using the restroom...
The boxes cannot be placed
in front of the restroom...
If the boxes are placed there,
the customer cannot
come out of the restroom...
We'll be back! later then!
Thank you, see: ou later!
On the days that Aya is in charge,
the boxes in front of the restroom
re nicely organized...
Uh, what was it?
That famous dialog by Holmes...
Huh...?
Shinichi usedlto remark haughtily:...
When you have eliminated
the impossible. .then, this and that...
the impossible...
When-you have eliminated
the impossible.
Whatever remains,
however improbable, must be the truth
remains,
whatever remains,
however improbable, must be the truth
remains
improbable,
whatever remains,
however improbable, must be the truth
remains
improbable,
e truth
whatever remains,
however improbable, must be the truth
When you have eliminated
the impossible,
whatever remains,
however improbable...
ust be the truth...
When you have eliminated
the impossible,
whatever remains,
however improbable...
mustibe the truth...!
This dialog?
What, what?! Don't tell me Ran,
that you came across something?
H, not really...
Ah...stop bringing
my hopes up again...
I think I got it. I feel like I got it...
but I wonder if my deduction...
is correct...?
It's already 21:00,
I'll have tc¥Oall mother
The customers are decreasing.
Yes...
Aya!
$.Shop keeper...
SO. are you ready to confess?
B.But. really haven't done anything...
It seems have no choice
but to call the police!
OO. Oh mo...
WwW. What... shall I deo.
I could telllthem about my deduction...
But what if I'm wrong...
What. if I'm off the point...?
Then, I may be getting Aya
Into more trouble than helping her...
What shall') dos .What shall I do...
What would he do at a time like this.
What? ¥ ould he do...What would he do.
C. Caller unidentified?!
H.Hello?
Yon. Ran...
How re you doing. 5?
Shi...
Sorry, Ran...
I don't have anything to really say but,
there was a little something
I wanted to ask you...
S,Shinichu...
Huh...?
Huh? What? Is it from Shinichi?
Y.Yeah...
Hey, what's up?
U.Uh...my friend's
in a tight situation right now...
You know her too Shinichi,
Aya, who was our classmate
in intermediate school...
Yeah...you mean Nanakawa
For some reason
things disappear at the convenience
store where she:works:
and it happens only on the days
thatvAya is in charge of cleaning
and closing the store...
So, the shop keeper suspects
that Aya is stealing the things
and says that he will call the police
unless she confesses...
There aren't any customers
on the surveillance camera
that are shown stealing either.
The shop keeper insists
that there is no one but Aya
he was watching the store after it
closed, but things disappeared after all
And? What kinds of things
have disappeared?
Game softwares, CDs, DVDs,
drinks, lunch boxes and candies...
According to Aya, she thinks that
there are three suspicious people
among the customers...
h...what kind of people are they?
Those three?
One of them is a man.that looks
to be a university student
who reads gameimagazine
till near closing time...
He bought some cup.noodles
and pouched«food...
The second one is
a timid office worker type of man
who always lets others go through
the register or use the restroom
He bought a toothbrush set. a shaver.
Batteries and a towel...
The third one rs a stubborn old lady
who asks for discounts
on lunches are near
shelf life expiration...»
She seems toghave bought nothing
tithe store...
I see...yeah...And... 42
I see... yeah...And...?
I see...yeah...And...?
What all the three of them
have in common is
that they frequently come
to use the restroom at this store...
A month ago,
when Aya was scolded in front of
the restroom by the shop keeper,
things stopped disappearing
just likesthat.
Then, last night,
a month after the incident,
again on the night when Aya was
in charge, things disappeared...
ee...which means it's only natur
that Nanakawa is suspected...
WwW. Wait! Don't talk like
it's somebody else's problem!
And?
There's something else, isn't there?
Huh...?
Something that only-Nanakawa
does on the days
that she is in-charge
that nobody else does...
Oh, yes...
The other employees leave the boxes
that arrive just before closing time
stacked up in the corridor in front of
I the restroom. and go home but,
Aya organizes: the boxes
neatly before closing the store...
Since the surveillance cameras
are working all this time,
it should be easy to preve
Aya's innocence
but the shop keeper seems to turn off
the switch of the surveillance camera
after operating hours...
Uh... weren't the lunches-that were
stolen all near shelf life expiration?
Huh? How do you know?
Just as I thought...
The culprit...is-probably
a pretty nice person...
Huh?!" W.What? You
know who the culprit is?
Huh /!
Yeah...the culprit isfprobably...
WwW. Wait, Shinichi!!
Huh
1.1 sort of came up with
my own deduction...
So. will you hear me out
without laughing...?
Go ahead...
Let me hear your deduction. .:!!
So, that's my deduction...
I took everything into consideration,
and although it's hard to believe,
I came to the conclusion that
it's not shoplifting. a thief, or Aya...
Well? Am I right...
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha!
H.Hey! I told you not to laugh?!
Oh, sorry...
it's not your deduction I'm laughing at...
I mean I couldn't help imagining
you looking all troubled
after having deduced the situation
S much as you have...
Huh?
Then are you saying-I'm right?
Is my deduction correct?!
I wonder...
Just what do you mean by that?
Pon't be mean and tell.me!
I'm not an over confident detective
Iike somebody somewhere, you know!
Dont be silly
A detective is only human,
and not some almighty god...
Huh 2!
When a detective reveals
his deductions,
chances are that he carries
doubts somewhere in his heart...
Like...maybe, I left some detail out
or overlooked something...
That's why when your deduction
hits the bull's eye,
you feel more joy than anyone ever will!
I'm just thinking that I don't want to
take the best part away from you, Ran
Shinichi.
He's putting on airs like he always
does...that hubby of yours...
If you think your deduction is correct,
try it out...
T,Try it out?
You know? Come on, Ran...
there's a simple way to drag
the culprit out before everybody...
Drag the culprit out...?
If you were the culprit Ran,
what situation would
ou hate to be in...
If I were the culprit...
R.Ran?!
R.Ran...
R. Ran.
May I help you. 7?
Excuse me...
Py La,
( ad <<
ket me...borrow your restroom!
Y.Yeah...
R.Ran...7
Shinichi...
WwW. Wheres Ran?
1. The restroom...
Huh? T,The restroom?
Quick everybody!!
You'd better hurry,
or you'll burn to death!!
H.Hey!!
Hey!
You'd better cut it out
or I'll file charges against
you for interfering with business...
Huh?!
U-Uh.:. listen, here...
What on earth's on your mind...
1,Huh...
Huh
7?" What!
Yes!
N.No
AM ooooO WA oR
What's with him...
What's up...?
So. it was you after all...
What...?
Timid, office worker type customer?
Don't tell me it was him...?
Yes, it's him!
He's the one who's been stealing
stuff night after night
from this store and giving
Aya bad time!!
Night after night but I was in front of
the store watching last night too
But, I didn't see him sneak into the shop...
Of course. you didn't...
Because he was living in the Attic of
your store all this-tirely
I can't believe it...
It may be hard to believe
but this is the truth...
He, after Aya closed the store...
came out of the attic through the
restroom and sneaked inte the store
taking drinks and tons of food,
and was making a living!
B.But Aya is in charge only
2 or..3 days a week and not everyday.
If he steals a lot at one time,
he can probably last 2 to 3 days...
Then, why were games
and CDs also being stolen?
I think he was probably
taking them out of the store occasionally
and selling.them off fer cash...
He'd have to go get a hair cut as well
as go to take a bath at the times,
otherwise his hair would grow long
and he'd be smelly,
which would force him to stay
in the attic keeping him
from coming out forever...
But, can he come in
and out of that restroom
without the customers or
the employees noticing him?
If he suddenly comes out
of the restroom
or goes inside and doesn't come out,
he'll be suspected rightiaway...
No problem!
If he's hesitant and careful...
Because, if he keeps
Ietting people go before him
and keeps standing at the end of the line
Nobody would notice
him going into the restroom.
SO he wouldn't have to come back out,
right?
Oh, I see...
If he comes down
from the attic to the restroom
just before it starts getting crowded
and comes out of the restroom
after it gets crowded and goes
into the store among the other customers;
he wouldn't risk being suspected.
If he'd been living in the attic for a while,
he would probably have had an idea of
when it would start getting crowded...
Besides, if the restroom
starts-getting crowded.
SO woulds=thesstore, so the employees
wouldn't possibly be able to
rememberwho came into the store
and who went out. right?
Then the toothbrush set. batteries
and shaver that he bought...
The batteries
he usedifor the flashlight he used when
Iooking for stuff after the store closed!
All the other stuff he took
to make himself look decent!
Besides, there's a
mirror in the restroom too!
Shop keeper! It's just as she says!
The board of the ceiling
of the restroom is removed!
What~~~71
Which mean he was hiding
in the attic all this time, after all...
Wha?!
This place is a trash dump,
shop keeper!
Incredible!
Oh mygod...
ut, why did he do it only on the days
that Aya was in charge...
That's because Aya is a diligent worker!
Huh
The cardboard boxes with items
in them that are left out on the corridor
The other employees would leave
the boxes stacked,
in other words, the restroom door was
blocked. so he couldn't come out.
But, Aya would organize.them and
move them: to both sides of the corridor
making it possible for him to come out
of the restroom and go into the store!
But, Ran...
the boxes can be moved over
with just a slight shove, can't they?
Exactly .
That's one thing I can't make out...
H. Hey...
Maybe he could've gone through
the corridor if he moved the boxes...
But if the employees:find out that the
boxes have been moved even slightly,
they:might find out
that the culprit walked through
the corridor and get suspicious
Iid:
83d:
the corridor and get suspicious
fink \
They would suspect the restroom
that he's hiding in the
attic may be discovered...
Since he was afraid of this happening.
He couldn't make any moves...
That's the story!
Right!
I see...
But. I still don't understand...
Huh?
Why did he stop stealing for a month?
Well, it may be that he was working
things out with the cash he got
from.selling off the games and all,
but if he didn't stop at that timing
I wouldn't have suspected-Aya
as much as I did...
The culprit...is probably
pretty nice person...
T.That's probably because
he's a pretty good person...
That is, he heard Aya being scolded
because of what he did from the attic
and that's whyyhe probably decided
not to steal for a while...
I~~~seel
That s'the story
He stole only the lunches
that were near the expiration date
because he wanted losses
to the store to be as little as possible...
But...stealing is stealing!!
How dare you make
Aya go through something like this...
R.Ran?! Hey...
I could never forgive anyone
who did something like this to Aya!!
Uuudgh.
I'm s& sorry!
I'm so sorry!!
Huh...?
Three.months ago...
I was fired from my company
and evictedifrom my apartment.
I walked into this store
feeling faint from hunger...
But...I'didn't have money
to buy anything...
The lights were turned off while I was
in the restroom at a loss what to do...
Even if I wanted to go out,
the doors were locked
nd I couldn't go out...
Once my eyes got used to the dark
the thing that came bursting into
my eyes was the stack of food...!
And, that's why you stole
things from our store...
VOoOO...
I figured since there was so much.
Taking just a little wouldn't hurt...
You've gotta be kidding!
How much do you think we have to sell
In order to regain the amount
you stole from us!!
I'm really sorry
Either way, you're going to pay us
back for all the loss you cost us!
E Even if I wanted to pay you back,
I don't have a cent...
You're going to work here...
Although you'll have to work
for free for a while to start with...
Y.You're willing to hire me?!
After all the trouble I caused you?!
I quit being an office worker
and started working here,
so I sort of understand how you feel!
- Hop keeper...
T.Thank you so much...!!
Do your best and work hard.
Y. Yes, sir...!
Uh. I hate 10 he a wet blanket
when you guys are getting it on but...
Huh...?
Will you please apologize to Aya?
Both of you!
I,I'm so sorry...
I'm very sorry, really....!!
Gh Lo obol
I'm happy for you, Ava...
All is well! All is well!
Ran...Senoko...
Thank you!! Ran and Sonoko!
Nothing to it...
just leave it to me...
Aha, ha. hat!
Hey, woman detective
Sorry, Shinichi, what was it
you Wanted to talk about...?
Well, it's nothing much...
Bid you come to my house recently?
Huh? No...
Why?
Nothing...If not, it's okay...
See you, then...!
Oh, hey. Shin
It's not Ran...
Orieinal Comic Books By.
(rtOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
+ Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
WKANJI KASHIWABA A
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHI
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation DireGlors.
MASATOM@O SUI(
HIROTOSHTTAKATANI
HARUQ COCA WA A
ATSUSHI AONG
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photoveraphy.
IAKASHI NOMURA
IRONOBU HO" . (Cr
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]I KODAMA
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, ID.
In assoaation with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DIFTCLIVEIL ONAN
¢ (52940 AOY MA SHOGAKUKAN:YIV - TMS
Il Rights Reserved
Yes...s0. I'm going to-sleep over
at Jodie's place tonight.
Eat dinner at Poalo: Okay. dad.
See you!
Ghads...
It's her little farewell party and
and she gets wasted to
the: pointof no return
tmsure she s relieved, 1.
Because she gets to go back
to her country after a long time...
Huh? Where are you going?
To the restroom...
Again
He helped me again...
It's sO vexing...
Really vexing...
Huh
What...What on earth is...this...?
Pictures...?
Huh 2!
W What's... this ?
Ocle...
Why?... Jodie?
On the night the full moon cometh,
I shall invite thee to
this hideous night banquet.
To the blood smeared
party on the ship...
party on the ship .
To the blood smeared
party on the ship...
Be it known that
whether thou attend or not,
the pitiful lamb that
goes passing shall.curse its own fate,
and the sinner shallibe ecstatic
over theiagonies:of :death\, *
Ver Vermouth?
Night of"the:Full Moon.
and the Black Banquet Trap