An awkward; situation, two people
unravel a mystery
a situation that closes in on
Conan.and Haibara
A life threatening-situation is close
A breathtaking :2
and a:half hours begins!
He sees through the one
and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
CONFRONTATION WITH THE BLACK CONAECL
(1 HE AEWA 1
THE CONFRONTATION WITH HE SLACK CONNECTION
TONED C50 HG NU SSD 04 NER A
Y.You're...
T.The detective...
Sh.Shinichi...Kudo?!
What UN No way!
What brings you here?!
ShinichizKudo?!
K.Kudomyou mean
that famous high school detective
What?
So, he wasn't dead
It.It can't be...
N.No way
I got rid of that kid some time ago
See...You have nothing
to complain of now, do you!
H,Hurry and give me the film
Ugh!!
Fuh, fun fun
B Boss
Gin killed him with a
poison drug
W. What the hell...
IS going on?!
Cough, cough
Huh?
Will you grant me...just one favor?
Cough-Icough
Wha, ha, ha, ha
Detective kid, long time no see!
I don't want to bum you out,
after you've made
your grand appearance but,
11S Case as areacy een so ve
The one who shot Captain Fukuura
from the top of the mast
that you're standing by right now
when he was just about
to give out the hint to the quiz,
that is, the one who sneaked out
of the cabin, the party hall
and came out to this dark deck
as well as the one who was able
to place the card of the devil
on the arrow of the:bow gun
that was fired
can be none other than
the one who has no alibi at that time
on top of not having the card
of the d Vii on him.
Mummy. who's right here with me!
U.Uuuuugh!
Where in my deduction am I off track?
Hey! Come on say something!
Oh, excuse me
I've a bit of a cold, and my throat's
cough, cough...
Huh~A A cold?!
you mentioned
his alibi and his card, is that right?
The killer probably
plC -pOC €é€e ummys car
in order to frame him-as the killer
The killer pick-pocketed?!
Heck!
If you insist that
Mummy's net the killer
the only probable deduction is
either he dropped it,
or somebody stole it from him!
After all
the card is specially made so that
there's only ene card to a person!
whether the killer knew
was aware of this or not
he stole it from Mummy,
inside the restroom!!
In the restroom?
Hey. is that right, Mummy?!
B.Beats me...
He, himself says
he doesn't know
so that's out!
Well...
It's not surprising that
he doesn't remember
The killer probably
went into the toilet compartment
next to the one Mummy went inside
and injected an anesthetic or something
with a syringe or something
from the space of the partition of the toilet
After-Mummy
sucked the vapor in and passed out
the killer probably snuck in
from the top part of the partition
and pulled the card out,
taking it from Mummy.
Hey. hey!
Where do you have such evidence!!
I have no such evidence
I just mentioned
the easiest way possible
to carry out the murder
Besides,
I believe that the anesthetic and syringe
are already inside the sea
Just what do you think
you're talking about!
Don't tell me you're going to say
you don't know who the killer is!
Wha, ha. ha!
Fuh. fuh. fun
There is indeed only one person
who could be the killer though
Detective Mourn
WwW. What?!
The one who killed Mr. Fukuura
as well as
tried to put the blame on Mummy is
none other than
you!
Wolf Man!!
W. What?!
WwW, Wolf Man?!
Gaha. ha. ha!!
Your head must've dulled
from your cold
We all saw Wolf Man
come out of the restroom
as well as just before Mr Fukuura
gave out the quiz!
While on the contrary
Mummy wasn't seen by anybody!!
Just what are you talking about?!
When I came out of the toilet...
you were watching me!
Huh
A.Are you doubting my memory?!
I was here too
when the:quiz was just about
to be announced,
right near you!
Hey, hey,
don't tell me that you're going to say
that you weren't the Mummy
but the Invisible Man, eh?
Franken has the key
that will unravel the mystery.
W. Why?
Won't you tell us.why,
you were acting your role
as a monster even inside the toilet
as well as what you were surprised at,
right afterwards
It.It's a well-known thing
among we horror fans that
If there is anyone within
the party grounds that is sending e-mails,
that person is a movie staff
that is judging to see
whether they should give us a chance
to appear in the movie or not
That's why I knew right off the bat
that he was a staff member
So. I followed-him toiselmyselt and
kept acting my role until he came out
But the one who came out of the toilet
that he went in was
WwW. Wolf Man?!
What?
You mean Mummy was Wolf Man?!
Hey. hey,
then~Don't tell me that
That's right
The killer not only wanted to put the blame
on Mummy who was asleep in the toilet,
he also put something else on Mummy
And that}something else was
his Wolf Man's mask!!
You probably cracked the mirror
in the restroom
to keep Mummy
from finding out what happened
He doesn't have to look inte the mirror
to realize that he's not wearing
hisforiginal mask. does he?
I mean he's wearing something
Iike this, you know!
Since Mummy was originally
wrapped up in bandage,
and moreover, if he was put to sleep
it's no wonder that
he didn't realize what had happened
Onitopr f that, the mask covers and
hides everything from neck down,
so even if the color
of the necktie changes, it's hard to tell
Besides. both of them
were wearing white gloves
and their outfits
are more or less similar.
Sol don't think
anyone would've suspected anything
Their physiques are similar and
they hold the same card of the devil,
both of them are reticent
and they end up in the compartment
next to each other
Doesn't everything
fall too much in place?
The only coincidence here is
probably the pattern of the card
The killer was waiting for
the right person to come to the toilet
There were a lot of passengers
who didn't speak a word
because they wanted
to sell themselves as monsters
as for piercing the card with the arrow,
the killer probably
thought it up right on the spot
The person that would be suspected as
the killer would be someone
that didn't have his card
He probably made light of it.
Thinking that no one would figure out
who the real killer was
B.But...
when Sonoko called
Wolf Man came out of the restroom!!
If he was drugged to sleep.
How come he came out
at such great timing!!
You heard something before he
came out of the toilet, didn't you?
Huh
Oh. I see!!
The howling of the wolf!
Aoooon
It seemed that he was playing
the howling using a tape recorder
If he turned the switch on
from the toilet compartment next door
Aooon
Mummy would be surprised
and wake up!!
Yeah
The speaker was probably attached
behind the mask
The killer attached a wiretap
with the speaker
and put the mask on Mummy
so that he wouldjreact swiftly 3
to the voices of the people around him-"
Even if someone were to talk to him,
Mummy would think that
Wolf Man was being talked to
because the howling is heard at
close range.
I see... very true!
I thought it was strange
because each time he heard howling.
He was looking here and there.
That's how
Wolf Man gave everyone the impression
that he was at the party hall
and 'created his alib:.
Then he went up on deck
and fired the arrow from the bow gun
coos
at Mr. Fukuura who was
on top of the mast!
Then he.used the howling to guide him
to where Mummy was. among the crowd
and: tore off the mask within the crowd
and put it back on himself
then went back inside
the crowd of pebple
So. I guess this is how the story goes
Right, Wolf Man?!
Am I wrong in any. way?
Phooey...
I donstekNnow
if you're a high school detective
or what but...
you can sure blabber on, can't you!
I put this mask-on Mummy, you say?!
Do you have proof that I did it, or what"?!
If it's something that points in
the direction that you're the killer, yes.
I have two!
One is this!
The hint of the quiz was that a human
was among the monsters here
cock-a-doodle-doo
¢ RR. Rooster?!
H.Hey. where d you get that?!
It was tied to a rope here
I think that Mr. Fukuura with the spotlight
on himself was going to do this!
What?!
Suspend. itupside:down...?
Upside down?
The opposite of rooster...
retsoor...
retsoor?
Phooey!
Just what kind of hint
is that supposed to be
Retsoor...Retsoor...
I get it
Huh 2!
Male roosters are called cock,
and he's holding it by the tail
It is said that long ago
all-kinds of liquor were made by
stirring them with the tail of the cock.
C Therefore. -the drinks were called
cocktail since then
That's the origin of the word cocktail
What?
You mean cocktail is the hint?
Detective Mouri
you also drank it too,
that cocktail
I'm a beer drinker!!
I would never drink something
sissy like that... 7?!
Aagh!!
Come to think of it,
I was looking for Wolf Man and
Hey, boss! What's up?
Oh, bartender,
can you give me the same thing
he's drinking.
I did drink it
now that you mentioned it
If I remember correctly it was...
a cocktail called Silver Bullet!!
We were given instructions
by Mr. Fukuura
to drink it at the bar of the party hall!
Which means
you rushed out of the toilet like that
back then because
you fell asleep in the toilet
and still didn't drink the cocktail?
Y. Yes!
That's a coincidence,
because I drank it too.
What?!
Wrong!
It was Mummy
who you had put your mask over!!
It's just as Shinichi had deduced!!
Phooey!
Stop putting on airs brat!
I'm the only Wolf Man here!!
And... Wolf Man!
Did you really drink that cocktail?
You, who wanted to sell your act
as Wolf Man
and appear in the movie?
Yeah...to pep me up
Or. are you 'saying/that Wolf Man
is not supposed to'/drink liquor?!
You really drank Silver Bullet?
Shut up, persistent brat!
I drank it!!
Silver Bullet...?!
Hey, no way
Silver Bullet?
Ilver Bullet, that's...
Yeah...
Wolf Man would never drink it
Yes...
the name of the cocktail was
Silver Bullet
Just as the name goes. a silveribullet
Is the one weapon in the movie
that is capable of
killing the Wolf Man
It's a thing that
any horror fan would know
And...
a cocktail with that name is also
used to ward off evil
Mr. Fukuura probably intended
to use this cocktail as a hint
and lure people to the bar
then later ask{the bartender
who drank what kind of liquor
and have everyone answer that
Mummy who ordered Silver Bullet was
the human among the monsters
Because no monster would go out of
their way to order liquor t ward off evil
Isn't that right. Wolf Man?
Since the bartender heard nothing
beforehand from Mr. Fukuura
he seems to have served
Detective Mouri the same liquor,
though
If Mr. Fukuura was the one
who did the make-up for Mummy
it's most likely that
the thing-that is
the answer is under the bandage
the bull's eye mark that indicates that
you're the answer to the quiz!!
Ares
Excuse me
Here it is!
It says human
Qooo0
He's the one
And?
What about the other evidence?
Even a marksman
at the bow gun could never pierce
a person with an arrow poked
with a card through it
Of course. he wouldn't be able to do it
from on top this unstable rope too
In order to make sure he kills his target,
he would have to climb up here
and fire at his target at point blank
The traces of Wolf Man
having come up here back then is here.
WwW. What?!
The traces of pieces of glass that are
embedded into the soles of your shoes
that you stepped on when you cracked
the mirror in the restroom
If we have the forensic officers
match the pieces
I'm sure they will match completely
Now. Wolf Man
please show us the soles of your shoes
and tell us
why you came all the way up here
So. please show us then, Wolf Man!
Come on, and lift your foot
1. didn't do it
It.It's not me!
I had no intention of killing him!
That devil is to blame
Huh
It.It's all that devil's fault!
It's that devil's fault!
The one called BBellmott!
Seelam to er .
62ND Lam... O. Cm FT
s » vw 8 Co '3
Dr. Niide. what seems to be the matter?
That's for me to say.
What do you intend to do with her?!
No! No!
We were just taking a drive!
Unlike you,
I've got a lot of time on my hands,
you see!
Lot of time?
Dr. Niide. it's almost time
for the trial for the homicide case, isnt it!
You've got to testify
as would be expected of a good citizen!
And tell everyone that
the home helper Hikaru Tamoto is
the one who pulled the trigger
and killed your father
which is a hidden fact
Hikaru pulled the trigger?
No-use playing dumb with me!
Detective Mouri. told me the facts
to everything!
Just what are you talking about?!
The killer of the case back then is
my step mother
And, besides, he died of electrocution,
not bullet wounds!!!
B.Bellmott? You say
Are you saying that-you Killed Mr. Fukuura
because that character called Bellmott
asked you to do so?
Hey!!
N.No It's true that
I had a grudge against Mr. Fukuura
becausenhe concluded
the Unlucky Days series that
I loved more than anything else...
just like that
2h TUN
andustarted'this kindergarten-style
Phantom Ship @aptain series
Sow wrote about this,on the'BBSw
«Of a certainsinternet site
saying that
I wanted-to work off my grudge
T.Then, this personscalled Bellmott
contacted me
saying that she'd tell me how to kill him
as well as prepare the murder weapon,
so if I'd like to carry it out
What do you make of the life of a person,
carrying out murder on a motive like that!!
OQ. Of course I refused at first!
But, after that
pictures of mysfamily
and I that were taken secretly,
along with tapes
of wire:tapped telephone conversations,
as well as documents with my daily
actions written to minute detail,
a whole cardboard Bx full was
delivered to me!!!
I was told that if I refused
or reported it to the police
either my family or I would die
Everything I received implicated this!!
Zen]!
IS cause 0 ea : 'was e eC rocu ion
and not by a gun?
Fuh... fuh. fun. fun
Aha, ha, ha, ha...
WwW. What are you getting at?
Oh, sorry the trigger I was referring to
just now wasthe electricity breaker
The killer is the one who rigged
everything to commit the murder but
the one who actually lifted the breaker,
and triggered the murder is
Hikaru Tamoto who knew nothing at all.
Therefore.in order not to hurt her feelings
the killer and the police got together and
made up a fake record of investigation!
It said that the method of killing was
something else
Well, it's only natural that
you don't know about this!
Because nothing of this sort was written
on the investigation report that
you stole from the police
The document that
you~-stole to get over the trial and
keep existing as Dr. Araide
WwW. Who are you anyway?!
A secret makes a woman a woman
Do you remember?
Theselare the final words
you left behind with me
And the words I kept repeating
so as not to forget them
the words of the one who killed my father
right
Chris Vineyard?
Rather...
the other name that you go by
Vermouth!
Ori1oinal Comic Books By.
SHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
ScPipts By.
WKANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHI
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUD
HIRO TOSHPTAAKA TAN!
HARUO OOGAWA A
ATSUSHI A *N
AKIO KAWA
TAKASHI HYODO
\rt Jirzciusy
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HOI 1KOSHI
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSUY OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJI KWDAMA
Pro (Iuuwl B y.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, dD
in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DLIFCIIVET ONAN
« (OHO AOYAMA SHOCAKUKAN-YIV -IMS
AllRights Reserved