An awkward situation, .two people
unravel a mystery
a situation that closes in on
{{Conan and Haibara
A life threatening situation is-close
A breathtaking. 2:and.a half-hours:begins!
He sees through the one and only truth
a child in appearance
with the I. Q. of an adult
NO case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
CAFENEAIY NER 14 BK CNET
(1 TE 80 YES 444
THE CONFRONTATION WITH THE SLACK CONNECTION
(CENCE 760 YEAS OF 1947 ALL dy
AA: 2!
Darn!
Don't come!!!
Stay away!
Go back!!
You fooll!
No, Shinichi.
This is my problem!!
This had nothing to do with you...
Heave...
eave...
That's, that's why...don't die!
I don't want you to die!!
Sggyou had the spare pursuit glasses
hidden-after all...
Shinichi...
R.Run for it. Ail!
Hurry!!
Just what are you doing?!
G.Get out of here, Ail!
Hurry and get out!!Quick!!
Agh!!
Aaagh!!
Ugh...
oodnight baby...
and...
Welcome
Sherry!
The only reason I can think of that
Bellmott would o after Ai's life
and want me to stay away from her is if,
heridentity is the actress
Chris Vineyard as well as Sharon.
That is,
she is one and the same with both!
She was probably acting out
two roles under disguise...
If she knows mom, she would've probably
seen pictures of me as a kid,
so she would've easily
ade out who ll am...
and I also understand why
she-wouldrvt want to become
messed up with a scandal...
I'll be fine!
Don't worry, because
I promise to make it back alive!
Is t hat really true,
haron...
tupid woman...
screwing up this little boy's plan...
coming out here on your own initiative
o die...
I didn't come here just to die...
I came here to end everything...
Even if you were to be arrested,
s long as I'm alive...
you people will never
stop pursuing me...
But. I'd like you ta give me your word...
that you will not lay a hand
on anyone else except me...
Will you promise to give me your word?
Okay...
I'll save all the others except
for this woman FBI agent here...
But first, I'll get rid of you, Sherry...
If you want to hold a grudge on anyone,
hate your parents for starting
such a stupid research!
Uh, fuh. fun...
Fuh, fun, fun...
Uuugh.
Fuh, fun, fuh...
Cool kid...
uugh...
Fuh, fun, fun...
N,No...
WW... Why?!
Why!
WwW... Why 2!
Wait!! Calvados!!
She saw?!...
WwW. Wait!! Calvados!
Hold it!!
Ugh...?!
Ugh... ..7?!
@€an"t you hear I'm telling you to stop?!
Get away from that brown-haired girl!!
If you don't want to die,
you'd better hurry!
N.No~~!! Don't move!!
Come on...Hurry!! Get out of the way!!
N.No!!
I called the police...
so just put up with this a while longer...
Please!!!
Whaaa!!
Big sis...
S.Silver hair?!
The story was meant to end this way.
Hate God for what«is happening to you...
Whaaa!
W:What are you doing?!
Hurry! Hang.on to my arm!!
Urry, or my arm...
ill get slippery from the rain...
Whyaxd you save: me?
Why the hell?!
Phooey...
Who needs a reason
What?
Who cares what the motives are for
a person to want to kill another person...
Why would a person
Nt to.-save another then...
There is*no logical
reason for that either.-is there?
Get out. of the way!!
WwW. What are you doing?!
Hurry"and hang on to my arm!!!
Move it. Angel!!
W. What?!
Heave...heave...
This is a blind spot for the rifle...
When did you...
hrow your gun down...
Throw your gun down!!
If not. I'll aim for your head next...
! The sound of a pump?...
A shot gun?!
Okay!! Calvados...
We'll attack them from both sides!!
Oh no...
He's coming from behind...
Fuh, fun, fun...
Come on, Calvados...
use that dear shot gun of yours and...
blow up the little kitty FBI agent, will you...
ame is Calvados...
A rifle, a shot gun and three guns...
I thought he was a weapon vendor
r something...
SS. Shuichi Aka?!
Shu!
But. with two broken legs...
I don't think he'll be doing business
or quite some time...
Well, Calvados is like
rong apple spirit...
So, I guess he's just right for the partner
of a rotten apple like you...
RR. Rotten apple?
That's the name we call you by...
Golden Apple was the stage
in which the great actress
haron.stole the limelight...
You're just as beautiful now
Inside you're a wrinkled up rotten apple...
A really rotten apple!!
Don't! Shu...
Don't worry.
I can tell from the way he moves that
he's wearing a bullet proof jacket
Iayers of bullet proof pads
Iover his body...
- -O spas . WES. « +» Tew
I think he's got
2 or 3 broken ribs though...
of Vine E308 »ARK 4
Hey look!
Look at her face that tore
apart with the shot that was fired...
That's the face of that
woman with no make-up after all...
Shoots!
The brats are a nuisance!!
Fuh. fun, fun...
Cool kid...
To think she can blow up the gasoline tank
Iooking over the mirror in that situation...
Fuh, fun...
uh, fuh, fun...
he's pretty good...
Shut!
This is no time to be amazed by her!
She took a child hostage
and got away you know!!
Why didn't you take
he key out of car, man...
Ow. ow. ow... W. Well, I'm so sorry...
We did get our share though,
because that chick's comrade is...?!
Hey. hey!
You mean he still had a gun on him?
Don't tell me he killed himself?
Oops. the Japanese police are here...
Heave...heave...
This girl must've called them.
Inside the trunk
it's hard to make out conversation,
ut bullets can be heard...
I'm sure
she saw the pictures in my room
and got suspicious,
and snuck inside,
Oo search my car...
She heard the bullets and came outside...
Then protected the brown haired girl,
who had-a-gun: pointed at her...
But, because of the gun fire a while back,
they probably thought they were shot...
Nd both passed out...
Gee...l don't know
if you can say they got guts or not...
Then, I'll leave the rest up to you...
Just go ahead and explain to them that
an FBI agent on a long leave of absence
came to Japan and got mixed up
in a case of a kid being kidnapped...
Since that chick got away
nobody would believe anything
e say anyway...
The big guy behind all
this hasn't come up front yet...
and besides I
can't have that girl
with the brown hair see me yet...
IHL.
U2'. »
Okay. boss...heave, heave...
Hah...
ow...this child...
What shall do with this boy who thinks
he is capable of doing everything...
Huh /!
The electrodes of an ECG monitor?!
There is a tracing device
s well as a recorder...
D.Don't tell me that
the sound of the telephone
made just a while ago was...
Don't...
If you pull that out.
It means that my heart has stopped...
and the mail address of the boss
you sent an e-mail
o will be disclosed...
The telephone company
must protect the privacy of their clients...
But the police
can get that information
if they fill out a special form
and have one of the big shots
stamp a seal on it,
then have the information
disclosed before several witnesses...
If the call that was received was
not from a cell phone,
but a regular home phone,
even the address would be disclosed!!
In other words,
if the sound just now is recorded
and analyzed to decipher
the alphabets and number,
the name of your boss, as well as
his whereabouts can be tracked down!!
That is, even if I were 10 be killed!
I did figure that if you found Sherry
I did figure that if youfound Sherry
who you. guys are going
nuts looking for you
would unmistakably
ontact your big boss...
Since things began to
Iook dangerous for Jodie
changed my plans, but...
so. what now?!
My friends are waiting for contact
from me at a distant place from here...
If you don't want this to go out,
take me to your boss!!
Let's get things over
with once and for all, Bellmott!!
I want to stop playing
hide-and-seek already!!!
Kay...
Iose...
I'll give up going after Sherry...
uh, fuh. fun. .
Huh
What the...?!
Ss mere sleeping gas...
Y.You fool,
If you do something like this,
you'll suck in the gas too...
s...this is a gamble...
F you get up first...
you go ahead and call the police
and have me arrested,
then go raid the boss along with them...
What happens if I get up first...
You already know, don't you?
B, Bad news!!
I've got to go wake him up right away...
or else Shinichi is in danger...
Huh?
S.Shinichi!!
Shinichi!!
Original Cotif™Books By
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASAIGMO sumo
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
den. \\ 2?
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABHRA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICH1 MIYASHITA
YUICHIpHIGURE 4
eB Cx ab
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHIsTAKATANI
HARUO OGGAWARA
sw * 4 \ -
AKJUKAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KGB/WASH!
Editor.
Chief -Diréctor.
KENIIWKGDAMA
Produced By
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in associition with
a eo er
FT UIVIIU MN QRNGLUEUAD THING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE
< (-()SII()A()YAM\ 8H0.
All Rights Reserve
You guys were blasted by Shu Akai?
Y.Yes...he'just happened to find us by,
and-Calvados ended up
with 3 broken-nbs...
and Calvados ended up
with 3 broken ribs...
Oh...you mean that FBI agent that you
failed to get rid of back
in New York a year'ago: when you
disguised yourself as the street ripper...
I thought he'd be off
his guard if he figured
I was just a mere street ripper. but...
Heave...heave
I should've gotten rid of him
back .then even
if I had to risk being killed myself...
Whaaal!!
Heave, heave...
Heave., heave...
that guys. .
that our biabbss...
heave, heave
fears could be our silver bullet...
Phooey!
A sliver bullet capable of finishing us
off in one blow;doesn't exist.
A:At any rate, I'm in a phone booth on
route 20, so can you come pick me up?
1.1 got into a bit of trouble.
And can't move...
Before that I have something
I want to ask you...
Do you know a kid by the name off
Shinichi Kudo?
No..l dent...
WwW. Why did you save me?
Phooey...
Who needs a reason.
Does logical reasoning exist as to
why people save other people?
Yes. it's him...
He, the one who pierced
through m heart
could probably become...
the one that I have long awaited,
the silver bullet...
Sigh...
Atgany rate, we'll have to figure out
what this.mark that Ayumi drew is...
That's first priority...
H.Hey!!
The mark on Santa's
butt sure looks familiar...
(BIH)
Look:ifor the Mark-on the Buttocks
Part 1