An awkward situation; two people
unravel a mystery
a situation that closes in on
Conan and Haibara
A life threatening danger is close
A breathtaking.2 and: ahalf hours.begins!
He sees through-the one and only truth
a child in appearance
with the 1. Q. ofran-adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
CPENEATI OF 1480 OCT
1000 ST 4 A
THE CONS ONTATION WITH THE BLACK CONNECTION
(CE CE OF TF 0 SPEED OF £1) 47 A UL 00
All right!
All seven of us have-finally gathered!!
Phooe...
What dense guys...
Uh, Pops?
Huh
Wolf Man. Franken and Mummy
are nowhere in sight
What?!
I wonder if they went to the restroom...
I guess so?
If that is a case. Do you look for?
The party is about to begin too...
Y.Yeah...
Oh. it's over here...
Oh, there he is!
We looked all over for you!!
What a toilet this is, though.
It's dimly lit and full of spider webs,
even the mirror is cracked.
Not only that, men and women
have to use the restroom together!
After all, we're all monsters.
So I guess there's no need to
differentiate between men and women.
It won't come off...
The blood on my hands...
on't come off...
It won't come off
even if I wash my hands...
Hey. hey, acting your part
even in the restroom, eh...
Are Wolf Man and Mummy here?
They don't seem to be here...
Yeah...
What?!
What was that...
Hey. boss! What's up?
Oh, bartender. can you give me
the same thing he's drinking.
Silver Bullet?
White Lady for me. then please...
Yes. ma'am.
Hey. you don't look too hot...
Are you bummed out or\something?
Uh? H.Hey...
Aooooohn
What is it?
Are you looking for somebody?
Aoooohn
I wonder where Mummy disappeared to?
How should I know!
Talk about not being
able to work in groups...
An hour has already gone by...
Huh
What?
Since the party started...
Listen, you monsters...
I've got good news for you...
The bait's been set...
It seems that there is a human
among us at this party
that is neither ugly
nor possesses evil power...
Go now,
and join hands with the 7 comrades
that you will share your fate with.
Find the good-for-nothing,
tear its meat apart.
Pull out its guts and drink up to the last
drop the blood that comes flowing out!!
VvwWhao
Okay
If it's looking for the culprit,
there's none other than I Kogoro Mouri,
more suited for the job!!
But. not all seven of us are here yet...
Who cares!
If I figure out who the culprit is.
I'm sure they'll come
walking out from their side!
I have the keyword which is
the hint to who it is...
If you want to get hold of the treasure
that is to be your reward,
come out to deck
and receive my revelation...
Gugh. Galigha
W. What was that...?
What's the matter?
I'm sorry, the load that was
on the construction truck fell off...
We-ll clear it up right away.
So pleas Ygive us a moment.
I'm in a bit of asrush,
so I'm going» to go around.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry...
Thank you for waiting,
you may go through now.
Thank you. Goodbye...
Take care!
He just went through
W. What's that...
T.That's?!
Captain of the ghost ship?!
H~~~What a grand performance...
This is real blood...
What
Hurn
Hurry!
Hurry. somebody get him down!!
Agh!
111]
Oh. I'm sorry to have surprised you...
I'm an English teacher of Teitan High
School, where Dr. Niide is .in charge of...
His car broke down on his way here
That's why I've come
to pick you up instead!
If it's okay with you,
will you please unchain the door?
I'm really late...
Jodie...
His chest is pierced through
with an arrow of a bow gun...
Moreover,
the card of the devil is here too...
So. the:devil's the guide
to the world'beyond?
Hmm...
I don't think he needed any guide
to take him to the world beyond though,
because he seemed,/
to have died on the spot...
True...
And as for the bow gun
that fired the arrow,
it's probably been disposed of
somewhere in this vast Pacific Ocean...
so virtually will not be found...
So. I wonder if there's @ camera on this ship?
I'd like to take a picture of the scene...
We have a digitalOcaméra that we are
using to take pictures of this party.
Well
it's something that will serve as evidence
so I'd prefer something on film, but...
Pops
I've got a disposable camera on me.
See...
Well I guess it's better than nothing...
I'listake'a look at his face then
Huh?
I think I've seen him somewhere before...
Oh! Isn't he a movie producer
that appears a lot on TV?
I think his name was Senzo Fukuura...
Huh?
I think he became famous after
producing the series "Unlucky Days",
before the Phantom Ship Captain series...
Are you saying that the producer
appeared in the movie
in person and acted the role
of the captain of Phantom Ship?
Oh, no. the movie was filmed
using a real actor...
Mr. Fukuura loved
the captain of the Phantom Ship.
SO he used to play the role of his own
Initiative every year at the party on board...
Mr. Flkuura-is the one who planned
the performance of appearing on the mast
with the light shining on him
and giving out hints to the quiz.
Yeah...
You mean that quiz about humans being
mixed up here among the monsters...
There's a microphone attached to
the inside of the mask...
It seems he was talking I
directly into this microptOne.
And? What's the answer to this qui .
WwW. Well, The quizzes and hints
were decide on by Mr. Fukuura alone,
SO we, the staff know
nothing about them...
We heard that the first group \
to solve the quiz
wouldqreceive an invitation 3
to the preview of the movie, though...
Well.
It seems quite definite that one of you
among the staff is the killer...
What?!
First of all,
Mr. Fukuura who was disguised
as the captain of the ghost ship
started suffering
while he was announcing the quiz...
He was probably struck by
the bow gun then...
However. back then,
we, the passengers,
were still inside the ship at the party hall...
It would've been impossible for us
to fire the bow gun at Mr. Fukuura
who was on the top of the mast...
The only people who had the chance
to kill him! would be the ones who were out
on deck to begin with,
and the ones who prepared the lighting
and the sound devices when he was
announcing the quiz. that is. the staff...
Secondly, this card of the devil...
Thexkilleriprobably wanted
to. mislead people into thinking
that one of the passengers who boarded
this ship that received this card is the killer
Since you're the ones
who prepared the cards,
you probably could make as many of
these cards as you wanted to...
these cards were made by
Mr. Fukuura to avoid foul play.
So. it would have been impossible for
any of the staff to prepare thesecards...-
Las ear he used playing cards...
Besides there was a passenger
who was on deck
before the quiz was announced too...
saying that he wanted to
Iook at the ocean...
Huh?
I don't remember who exactly that
person was since it was dark though...
Oh, is that right?
I see...
Which means the possibility of
the killer being among us
who have received
the card of the devil is high!
Cough...cough, cough...
Are you okay?
The doctor that
we're going to see is very efficient!
So. your cold will be cured right away
and you'll feel better in no time at all.
Cough...cough...cough...
By the way.
When is this ship returning to the harbor?
I think it'll be another hour or so...
I see...
Then, shall we go inside the ship
and investigate the case?
Mr. Sleeping Vampire?
Oh. okay...
Huh?
What's up. Pops?
Yeah,
it seems we're coin to be late
so I thought I'd let Ran know...
Huh? She's not answering...
Maybe she's taking a bath?
Okay. then...
Please show me the card
of the devil that you all have...
H.Huh? Huh?...
Huh? What's the matter. Mummy?
1.1 wonder if I dropped it somewhere...?
I see.
You deliberately poked
your card with the arrow
and tried to free yourself
from being a suspect, right?
You played on the psychology that
the killer himself would leave
his devil card behind with the victim,
unaware that this card was
a one of a kind in this world,
that Mr \Fukuura had exclusively made!!
I. I was fully aware of that too!
Huh?! How'd you know?
B.Because...
I was asked¥y, Mr. Fukuura to
sit among the passengers
and choose someone
with great make-up on...
after all rmyalso a staff
member of the movie!!
What?!
You're a movie staff member?
would never dream of...
hurting Mr. Fukuura...
Are you the only movie staff that
isimixed up among the passengers here?
almost all the other mummies
besides me are staff members...
When we find passengers
with great make-up.
We contacted Mr. Fukuura by e-mail
Y.Yeah...
we received all kinds of instructions
from Mr. Fukuura during make-time...
structions...?
What kind of instructions?
Like. drink a certain kind of wine, etc...
I was told to eat only chicken dishes #
I was told to wear this red wig.
All his instructions were varied
depending on the person
and the only instruction
he gave us in common was not to talk.
What kind of instruction is that
supposed to be?
How should I know,
it's Mr. Fukuura's instructions!
But...
When we were waiting for the quiz,
you disappeared from before us,
didn't you 7?
I.ll went to the restroom!
These two were with me too!!
Right?
It-s. true...
that you were: with us
when we went to the restroom but...
S.See.
B.But...l didn't see
you come:out of the restroom...
Huh?! What are you-talking about?!
I passed right behind you when I left!!
WwW. Why're you saying
something like that...
I; ll guess...you didn't notice me
because somebody cracked the mirror...
Huh
You mean that
mirror wasn't cracked begin with
in order to give a creepy atmosphere?
Huh?! No...
It wasn't cracked until we departed!
A.Are you sure?
Y.Yes!!
We. the staff decorated
this ship together...
But, we weren't given instructions
to crack the mirror in the restroom...
Then, just before Mr. Fukuura was
about to give out the quiz,
where were you?
I... was herel!
Near Wolf Man!! Right?!
Y.You saw me. didnatsyou?
I wonder...ll don-tdfremember
OO. Oh no...
I was desperate trying to sell myself
because I wanted a part in the movie!
Like so!
Aooohn
Come to think of it,
you were roaring several times.
It seems that nobody's seen you around...
Which means...
you don't have an established alibu...
0Oh no...
( It.It's a trap!
Somebody's conspired to frame me!!
Phooey...A killer who's cornered
barks a lot...
At any rate, you have no alibi
and no card Mummy...
You're the only:one I can think of that
could've committed the murder!!
Detective Mouri. you're a little off there...
What? What~?!
The truth is still in the dark...
The>»voice is coming from the speaker
wine ghost ship captain was using!
Darn! The deck!!
Kugh...Out of my way!!
W.Who is it?!
Where are you?!
You've already acquired everything
you need to solve the case and yet...
How disappointing...
Agh!! Why you!
Who are you!
You better shut up
or you're going to pay for this!
Fuh. fuh. fun, fu...
Have you forgotten me already...?
It's me...Detective Mour:.
Fuh, fuh. fun...
In.Invisible man!!!
Captain of this ghost ship, Captain Gold,
that is, the host of this party,
and movie producer Mr. Senzo Fukuura.
Who killed him...?
And...
how was he killed!
Shall we...
Begin solving the case then...?
T.That voice...
Fuh, fun, fun, fun...
T.That tone of voice...
It.It can'tsbe...?
Fun. funsfuhn...
nder the moonlight...
that shines light:upon the dark.night...
Ori1einal Comic Books By
SHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 110OKA
Scripts By.
WKANJI KASHIWABA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
IUNICHI MIYASHPA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animi1tion Directors.
MASATOMO SUD
HIROTOSHITAKA IAN!
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AON(
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
INKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHIT
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, 1 TD
In assowlation with
YOMIURI TELECASTINC(
CORPORATION
DEL ITECIIVE LON AN
¢ dDEHO AOYAMA SHOCAKUKAN YTV TMS
1 Riv his Reserved