An awkward situation. two people
inal in in)
a situation:ithat closes in on
@€onan and Haibara
A life threatening situation is close
A breathtaking. 2-and :a:half hours begins!
He sees through the one and only truth,
a child in appearance
with the 1!1Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
OREN VER SEC,
THE CONFRONTATION WITH THE BLACK CONNECTION
TONED ACH HE OD SASED HAGEL wy
Who are you?
It's a secret...a secret...
I can't tell you...
A secret makes a woman a woman...
Daddy's glasses...
I'm sorry
Daddy... What's the matter?
Is he already asleep?
He promised to read me a story
efere going to bed and yet...
hen...Will you stay by your fathe
until he gets up?
Okay!
Then, you set fire to my house...
and burned everything down to ashes...
All of what my father... as an FBI agent
gathered behind closed doors,
the investigation data on all of you...
But, I was saved...
Because after that...
I remembered that there was
NO More orange juice
that father always drinks upon getting up...
and since he was lying down from
exhaustion from afternoon
taking care of mother
who wasn't feeling well...
I wanted to be of help
and went out shopping...
Pun 8
Oh $0 you're the little girl I saw back then)!
I really went all out looking for you
because all that was left from the remains
Mn Were the bones of your parents...
My father's colleagues protected me...
They applied the witness
protection program for me...
That stupid system of changing
the name and addressof a witness
whose life is in danger in order to protect
thatperson under a different identity
Phew
It must've been really restricting. no?
To live away from your hometown,
as a different person.
You went through hard times, didn't you...
And?
You took after your father,
and came after me?
FBI agent Jodie Sterling?
Just as expected of
a witch with a thousand faces, Bellmott.
With your ability of disguise
you can sneak in anywhere
and check on things to your heart's content
can't you...
I'm amazed that you sawgthrough
the disguise of Dr.'Niide...
It's obvious...
Despite of not having that bad of an illness
if you keep frequenting Niide Hospital
ith no make-up...
That you were planning to Kill him
and become him!
Then...
you mean that the time his car passed right
before me with his family and
crashed through the guard. rail,
eventually sinking into the sea...
was all set up by you?
Yes!
I made it look as if he died of
an accident before you got to kill him...
Because if the car was left {
at the bottorn of the sea...
and if nobody knew that he was dead,
it would make it easier for you (*
to go around acting as Dr. Niide...
Of course,
the people in the car were
my colleagues equipped with aigdpumps...
The real Dr. Niide is living in peace
in a place far away...
You,
just as we expected established
ot 0s :
yourse in 11 @ O0spla
and began checking on-something...
It was obvious what you were
Iooking for the moment
we snuck into your room in that hospital...
A picture was poked all over with darts...
The picture of a:girl in her 20's
with reddish brown hair...
You were planning to find her
and get rid of her!!
Ow...l have a question
The picture of the woman you were
trying to get hold of and kill
and this girl that looks just like her...
Of course the witness protection program
will be applied to her but...
Cough, cough...
Is she really the woman in the picture?
There's still more!
The two pictures
that were below her picture,
the meaning of the words Cool Guy and
Angel that.were written on the pictures...
That boy iscunmistakably sharp,
but he's more a "kid" than a guy. isn't he?
S...That boy called Cona
until that boy left the girl's side
you didn't do anything...
Inside the bus that was jacked too
Please don't!!.
It: just'the mischief of a child, ish:tit?!
Will tell me why you went all out
to protect that boy
to the point of almost risking your own life?
Fuh. fun, fun...
If she didn't come around...
T,Things wouldn't have
turned out like this...
S,So...
N.Nab that person called Bellmott too!!
And?
So that name Bellmott,
that sounds like the name of some liquor
IS probably a fake name. right?
Do you know the person's identity?
Uuuuugh...Brrr
You haven't seen that person yourself,
either?
N.Nope.
Then...
what about the receipts of the things
that you received
that she used to blackmail you?
Well
What?! N.No way!!
_~Y.You threw them away?
Phooey...
The address is probably a phony one too...
I guess for now...
until we arrive at the harbor,
we'll have to keep him tied up somewhere.
So now, the case is closed.
What?, ha, ha.
Come on...
tell me. will you...
Okay!
I'll tell you...
That's...
Don't move!!
Y. my
what a dangerous thing you have there...
Did you get permission
from the police in Japan?
We'll request joint investigation
from the police here after we nab you!
Of course I'm willing
to take full responsibility for this...
But before that
I have something I want to ask you!
Oh...and what may/that be?
Why...don't you...
Why don't you age at all?
You caught-my attention because of what
you said in front of my mother's coffin...
A secret makes a woman a woman...
I was really excited
and started investigating,
then sure enough,
there was a perfect match...
Remember back when you killed my father
making it look like he committed suicide.
Because of the way it lay
unnaturally on the floor.
The fingerprints that were
on the lens of the glasses
and yours matched perfectly!
But, I had my doubts...
You were too young to be a suspect of an
incident that had happened 20 years ago...
I didn't think it possible at first,
but when I matched your prints
with a certain person's
I got results that made
a shiver go up my spine...
You're the one and the same as
your mother Sharon Vineyard!!
And, I finally found the witness...
that could explain the mystery
of what was keeping you
from being arrested!
You guys! Come out and nab this woman!!
When I get custody of you from the
Japanese police I'll make you spit it out.
You'll tell me everything...
Well, even if you insist on saying nothing,
she will eventually...
Fun, fuh. fun...
Ugh. ugh...
Thank you Calvados...
Don't kill her yet...
I've still got something I want to ask her...
Heave.-~. heave
You all staked out here...
and figured. you lured me out.here but...
% I came here once already 2 hours ago,
disguised as you...
And this is what I said in your voice...
This is it tonight! Come back tomorrow!
Didn't you realize?
There was another reason as to why
the papers of the cases
that Detective Mouri was involved
in were stolen...
All ofithe documents Were stolen
sorthat the papers 'we actually
needed would:irnot be specified, however...
all of the documents were sent back to the
Metropolitan Police in one batch because...
I wanted you people to think
that my stay in Japan
had something to do with Detective Mouri
so that you would stake out
the detective agency,
which as a result... .would help me
figure out who the FBI agents are...
Just as expected,
I figured out how many of you there were,
the place you were all staying
and the way you were all communicating...
I also knew that you werestrying to trap me here...
Then, you knew that we snuck
into your room too...?
Yes...l was just playing dumb...
I thought that if you saw that picture
you would find her for me...
But...you surprised me twice already...
The first is that you are the girl
that I met 20 years ago...
The other is that you knew what went on
behind the scenes regarding Dr. Araide...
How did you get information onFit,
when nothing about it
was spoken to anyone. +?
Heave...heave...
I didn't hear about it from anyone...
I was asked to do so by someone...
To corner you and disclose your identity,
and in turn for doing so,
gs. she said that she would trust me...
T.This girl over here...
She said so...
Cough, cough.
Gha, ha, ha...
At any rate! Let's hear the whole story
hen we get to the police station!
He solved the case in such a short time!
Just as expected of Shinichi Kudo!
Fantastic!
Oh, the reason I got to solve it right away is
because I used the same trick
1S the killer...
Just what does...that mean?
What?!
The same trick that Wolf Man
over there used!
So, this is it, for our re-encounter
after 20 years...
It's time to say goodbye...
Fuh, fun, fun...
Come on and smile.
Because you're going to get
to see your father in heaven...
Heave, heave...
Fuh, fun, fun...
What?! Thé same trick
as Wolf Man used?
The killer...
put a mask over a monster victim,
who was already disguised,
and double disguised the victim, you know.
You've only got bandage
wrapped around you!
Just what the hell do. you mean!
Y.You're...don't tell me...
Yeah...
$0...this...
IS what I mean!!
Huh?!
What?!
Y. You're...
H.Heiji Hattori?!
C.Cool kid?!
Conan tdogawa...A detective!!
H.He wasn't Shinichi...
H.Heiji Hatter»?!
Disguise?! Disguise?
But. .his voice
and tone were just like Shinichi...
Yeah...
Fuh. fun, fun. .
Of course...
It took me six 'hours to disguise him...
It's my masterpiece...
As for his voice.
The. microphone on his collar picks up
the deduction that Heiji whispers into it,
then: Shinichi says it through
the microphone on the mask...
and that voice was output
from the speaker on Heiji's necktie so...
How do you like it,
a perfect collaboration by.Dr. Agasa and I!!
Ahawha, ha, ha!
Fuh, fun, fun...
Okay! We're okay on this side, Kudo!
Do: our thing on your side-too, now!!
Oops!! Don't move!
Your bodys the blind spot for the rifle...
Go on and-get in the car after Jodie...
Let's take a drive to the police!!
Jodie...
Quick and get in the car!
Ugh! Kugh...
Jodie!!I Are you all right?
Y,Yes...Ugh...
Yes...Ugh...
D.Don't tell me that...?!
Shinichi Kudo...?
Remember, boss...
the kid that you poisoned to death
with the drug made by the organization!
Sorry Vodka...
I make it a policy to forget the name
and face of the ones I get rid of...
And?
Are you saying that the kid rose from
the dead and appeared as a ghost?
Yeah: I mean no...
something strange is happening...
Why are you disguised as Shinichi Kudo
in the first pladO anyway?
Oh,sorry, sorry! Pops!
I haven't seen Kudo for sometime,
so I got kind of lonely...
I figured that if I came out looking like him
and made a deduction,
maybe Re joist might pop out too...
t... maybe he's dea
just as rumor has it, you think?
Aha, ha, ha...
Darn! Kid from Osaka
this is the second time
you're pulling this trick!!
Aha...
If Ran were here
you'd be way gone by now!!
If Ran were here...
You'd be way gone by now!!
S.Scary-give. me a break.
I had no choice...
After all Kudo e-mailed me
asking me to do this...
He told me that/those guys are trying
to pull him away from Ail and do something,
so he wanted me to disguise myself as him
and get to the bottom of things.
That's why I'm on board this ship...!
But, it sure freaked me out...
when I got to his house
and found his mother there...
She seems to have been
worried about him,
and hiding for a while
in the house watching him...
Fuh, fun
Mo. ..ther
Hey, hey...
I... didn't think she had a special
talent to disguise people...
but she would even freak
Arsene Lupin out too!...
Thanks 10 her I didn't have 10
complete my deduction all bandaged up...
The only one I'm worried about
is the little girl
that is left sleeping and confined in the
basement of "Doc Agasa"s house...
Kudo says shell be fine
if she doesn't have the pursuit glasses
hidden somewhere:with:her but...
if I were her...
knowing that he would be going to see
some dangerous guys disguised as me
I wouldn't be able to wait for him
ust like that...
I would break the door epen
no matter what and go after him.
No matter what, Kudo!!
Lid go after you...
AAI... you...
Oriromal Comic Books By.
SHO AQOYA
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 1HOKA
Scripts By
WKANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUC 1
JUNICHI MIYASHI
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Direlors.
MASATONMO SUI»
HIROTOSHI-TAKATANI
HARUO COCA WA A
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Dire tor.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUIANI
Directors Of Photooeraphy.
IAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKWSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Dire tor
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENjiKODAMA
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, 14D
In 1ssoaiittion with
YOMIURI TELECASTINC
CORPORATION,
DITFCHVE § DN AN
¢ (88H AOYAMA SHOGAKUKAN:YIV IMS
All Riphis Reserved
norte od of