An awkward situation, two people
unravel a mystery
a situation that closes in on
Conan and Haibara
A life threatening danger.is close
A breathtaking 2:and arhalfihours begins!
He sees through.the one and only truth
a child in appearance
with (Ke) of an adult
no case;ls left unsolved
with DetectiverConan.
HE CONFRONTATION WITH THE SLACK CORNECTI
0 CF OF 60 EHS 4444941
An off-season Halloween party?
Just what month do they think it is?!
Halloween is October 31st?!
That's why: itss written
Off-season. isn't it...
Huh, what's written on the invitation card?
On the letter it says...
In...Incapable Detective Kogoro Mouri.
On the night the fullimoonrcometh,
I shall invite thee to
this hideous night banquet,
To the blood smeared party on the Ship...
Be it known that
whether tho Yattend or not.
the pitiful lamb that goes passing
shall curse»its own fate.
Rf D!
and the sinner shall be ecstatic
over the agonies of death.
Rid?
and the sinner shall be ecstatic
over the agonies of death.
* To. em
15958. 4
and the sinner shall be ecstatic
OX RO Emilee OF exer,
IR re
and the sinneryshall be ecstatic
oY Qe o otis OF eke
Rf Pi
830s J
and the sinner shall be ecstatic
RAP FR eek os OF Cloeidn.
Rf 2)
fr...
and«the sinner shall be ecstatic
over the agonies of death.
and+«the sinner shall be ecstatic
Hah, ha. ha. ha...
This is a letter challenging the renown
Detective Kogoro Mouri, I see!
Who on earth:could"ve sent
thissinvitation card to me?
Maybe a foreigner.
Because the name of the sender is
VERMOUTH...
Ver... Vermouth?
Ver...Vermouth?
Ver::--Vermouth?
Vermouth?
I wonder ..I'm sorry Ran,
but I've never heard that name before...
I see...
I wonder who sent us
this invitation card...?
And...
Is Kogoro going to the evening party...
It's tomorrow. isn't it?.
Yup.
He's says Edoites always take
on fights they are challenged to.
Father's making preparations for it
and having Sonoko
put on all kinds of make up on him,
although he's still undecided
which make-up he wants to go with.
Make-up?
It says on the invitation card...
that since it's a Halloween party
all participants must disguise
themselves as monsters
and come dressed in formal
black suits and dresses...
Of course, anyone who comes as
company must do likewise.
Huh? Company?
You mean. you're going with him too?
Of course I'm not going to
such a monster-filled party!!
Ma. ha ..Oh, I guess so...
Oh, and...
Huh?
I have a favor to ask you. Doctor...
What is it?
If this invitation came: to. dad...
it could be that...
he got one to. so
h, yeah...
Shinichi too, you mean...
Yes...so could you check the mail box?
Unless you tell him about mail like these,
I'm sure he'll complain up later...
Oh, okay...
if it's here, I'll call you back...
Well, I don't think he got one, though...
Oh; and please keep
this a secret from Conan.
Huh?
Because every time
he goes to places like these,
he tends to stick his nose
into dangerous things...
Besides...
Besides. what?
Oh, yup...
and tell him that school will start soon
SO OO Ma € sure 0 comes ome...
Oh, and that he shouldn't go here
and there till then...
Yeah, okay...
I'll give him your message...
Yeah...
How's about it?!
This is a masterpiece
bearing marks of labor
and effort produced by Sonoko Suzuki!
I have this feeling that I don't look
much different from how I usually look...
What're you talking about
you don't want it to look too drastic,
do ou?.
Cover you wi eavy ma e-up
and goof. there'd be no way out!
Hmm -well.
That's true, but...
Fantastic!
You look really good. dad!
That amount of make-up is just enough
to bring out the good in you, Dad!
you think so?!
Oh, and Sonoko.
Did you decide what to go disguised as?
Of course
I'm going to go in a super cute mini skirt,
and knock the monsters out
Knock out monsters. my gosh
Well, who knows.
Maybe there'll be
super good-looking monsters?!
No way. no-chance...
So what!
I'll bet you're after some super
whopper body vampire
Whew
And?
Are you planning to board
the ghost ship too...
Yeah...
The sender's name
kind of bothers me so...
D.Do you have an idea of
who the sender us or something'?
No...
Aren't you the one who has an idea,
Because Vermouth, like Gin
and Vodka-arernames of liquor...
Beats me...
Never heard of it...
Besides: don't know much about liquor...
It's liquor from Italy...
Vermouth
is the English spelling...
In Japan it's called...
Belimot
Just as I thought...
It's written on your face
that the name sounds familiar...
Vanwauh.
prod
I guess it's the code name of
one of the men in Black...
T Then ou mean
that invitation card is from?!
Yeah...
an invitation from Bellmot
who is one of them.
I don't know if they're ready to take us on ,.-»-
or if they just got tired of waiting. but...
I can't pass up this opportunity...
Don't go...
Don't go!! Stop. I tell you!!
It's a trap and if you go you'll'be killed...
Cough, cough...
Yeah... it could be...
Then...
Then, why go?
- X SS
H. Hey.
Shinichi?!
You didn't have to do that...
Sorry. Al...
With things as they are...
I'm stuck
and can't move on...
B But
I wonder if it's okay for you
to leave Ail here
Iike this and leave just like that
Look. Doc...at the address
written on the envelope of the invitation
card that was delivered to my house...
The name Shinichi Kudo is written on
the envelope and invitation card but...
But the name on the letter
that was inside together
D.Dear Mr. Conan Edogawa?!
- 1. Sy
Hey. Shinichi! TT. Thus...
Hey. Shinichi! T. This...
Yeah...everything's out in the open...
My true identity.
The fact that my body shrunk
because of Apotoxin4869
as well as the fact that I'm Shinichi Kudo.
And they most probably...
also know that Al is the Sherry
who used to be one of them...
B.But. isn't it strange!
If they have that much information already
why aren't they here raiding us!
I don't know why...
but I have a hunch
about one of the causes...
but I have a hunch...
About one of the causes...
- Wn,
Cough. cough, cough, cough!
H.Hey. .don't tell me that you caught
ARSECOIS
I.I'm fine Cough...
Hmm? What the .7?
The telephone?
Shh...
Huh?
Mail?...
Problem left is...
A Halloween... Party?
Yeah...
It's going to start
tomorrow night at 19:00...
B.But boss
why do I have to go to
a crazy place like that...?
Bellmott is in this.
Huh?
We've got orders to go check out
the internal affairs...
I was just about getting fed up with
that lady's secretiveness too...
I didn't get the go-sign. but who cares...
If she acts up. show no mercy...
Even if that broad's that man's favorite...
Strange...
It's strange after all...
Compared to when I came here
to check the mailbox,
although it's really slight, the water meter
s well as the gas meter has moved...
Somebody's...
inside...
I guess this is the best place
to watch Al and me from...
I know I can handle two men.
But what if there are more than three?
Cool head...
Judging from the meter...
the most that would be in here is
ne or two of them...
Besides...
Wow~~~what a full moon
Really, it's so appropriate for
A blood smeared party on board!
Il right
mm getting excited
Hmm--I'm feeling
aipositive turbulent rush of blood...
He . Pop's
isn't the Wolf Man the one
who feels a positive
turbulent rush of blood
when the full moon is out?
You're Dracula, you know, Pops
Quiet.
I'm saying that I'm getting a positive
turbulent rush of blood as a detective!
Uh, excuse me?
Are you two also going
to be attending the
Off season Halloween party too?
Right
I thought it was ridiculous
because it's a masquerade party. but...
Well, the thing is...
I'm going there too!
Ugyaaah "
I wonder if it's going to be okay...
Ieaving Ai like that by herself...
wonder if it's going to be okay...
Ieaving Ail like that by herself.
Yeah...
I left the room warm
I left food and water behind with her too,
so I don't think there'll be any problems...
I can't wait to play that new game
you were saying you invented. Doc!
Oh. do you want to try it?
Cough..cough...
The position-of-the-things-in the drawer
IS also slightly out of place...
Cough: cough, cough...
You looked for it...
all by yourself...
In order to confront them...
Wow , look at them!!!
Wolf Man
Franken and
the Mummy...
Wow!
Even Kyonshi
IS here!
It's full of monsters!
Really, how exciting
Are you sure it's okay for the daughter
of the Suzuki Financial Group
to be mixed up among guys like this...?
No big deal. no big thing!
Unlike Ran,
I kind of like stuff like this!
By the way. Sonoko?
Just what are you disguised as?
How rude! I'm a witch, a witch!!
Don't you see that I've got a broom?
Ay May Sue
Ugah, ugah, ugah...
What?
Ugah, ugah...
Ugah. ugah. ugah...
W. What's with him...
Huh?
Hey. Pops?
Maybe he's saying move over
because the front seats are open?
Ugahugah.
Darn.
Then why don't you say
so in a way I understand.
He's just really trying to be
the character that he's disguised as...
Huh?
My. my. what a beautiful witch you are...
Thank you...
Huh?
Not a witch...
MM Medusa?!
I'll turn you into stone. you know.
Aha, ha...
Will the next person show us
your invi a ion car
sure, sure...
You're the famous Detective
Kogoro Mouri, aren't you?
Oh? So. you saw through my disguise?
Your name's written
on the invitation card, see?
Then, please fill in your name...
uh? Yeah...
Mo ~~~uri.
By the way...
I hope you're not planning to
really commit a murder here, are you?
Huh 72
Well, together with this invitation card
there was a letter hinting
that a crime may be committed here!
See.
It's true that this invitation card is
what we made,
but I know nothing of this letter
or the envelope...
Huh? Really?
There will be a "guess who the criminal is
game played during the party though...
Maybe the producer decided
to play a prank thinking
that a mere invitation card would not be
enough to get you to come here...
Producer?
Oh, no. it's nothing...
But, we're sure that you'll enjoy
the cursed banquet.
Come on, Pops!
Let's hurry and go!
Oh. Hey. you!
Next guest please!
Your invitation card. please...
Huh?
\ Oh...
A. Aren't you, by chance
the high school detective...
Thank you.
But, they sure got a lot of them
gathered here...
You can say that again...
Huh
It's finally going to start.
Yeah...
Ooooh
You devilish diabolic monsters
who wander through the nether world
thank you all for coming...
I am Captain Goldy/
and I will be navigatig this ght ship...
It's only an hour more to go
before the party...
First of all, please pick your comrades
who will be sharing fate with you.
7 comrades who have received
the same seal as yourself...
The same seal?
The tarot card!
You got one too, didn't you when you,
came on board?
I think we're going to team up
with people who got the same card
and play a game or something.
NS S 1 >
ou mean us 1a SS Wii en ere,
You mean this XV that's written here.
You mean this XVathat's written here.
Jeph!
Which means we're on the goat team...
That's not a goat!
In Roman Numerals XV is the figure 15...
The name of the card is DEVIL...
The card of the devil...
Oh. is that right...
Besides, we weren't divided
In groups just to play a game...
Huh?
This party is also an audition
for a role in a movie too...
An audition?
You know, don't you?
The movie that's played
every summer called
of «VV e\re
The Diary of the Voyage
of a Phantom Ship Captain.
Yeah...
the one about a load of monsters
riding a ghost ship
and coming to get people
who performed evil deeds...
Which means if things work out,
I may appear in the movie too?
Yes...
This seems to be the fourth time
this party's been held,
and each year the movie staff seem
to be mixed among everyone here.
To judge carefully for the cast...
May May May
I see...
Everyone wants to play,
the part of popular monster roles,
so they divide people into teams
to make choosing easier ¥
That's why everyone's trying
to put out their best. right #
The Wolf Man who roars
towards the moon...
The Franken monster that moves
Iike a robot and does pantomime...
The Mummy who keeps to saying
nothing no matter who talks to him...
Well, although they're 'going
to appear in the:movie,
they're no more than supporting.actors
who will appear behind
the starring monsters...
Since it'll cost an enormous
amount of money
if the film company has to
cover make-up fees
and everything for
all the supporting actors,
they let horror fans appear in their
best outfits and put on their best act...
Besides holding an event on the this:ship
that is also used in the movie
will-serve as advertisement of
the movie too...
All right all-ofiyou!
The time to set sail has come!
We shall cross the 7 cursed seas
and show the conceited humans our
power as well as teach them aidlesson!!
Qooooh
WINS)
Oooooh "
Huh?
Don't tell me this ship's really
going to move?
Is there anyone who has
the card of Death?
Hermit! Anybody around
who has the card of the Hermit?
What? Shinichi Kudo?!
You mean that high school
detective is on this ship?
Right. right!
But, I heard that he got mixed up
in some kind of incident and was killed...
No way! That's nothing but baloney!
And? And?
What kind of disguise was he in?
He was bandaged up,
so maybe a mummy?
A mummy detective...
Okay!
All seven of us are here!
Wow! They're the people
we saw just'a while ago...
So. this is Medusa...
Wolf Man. Franken. and Mummy.
And. uh...and can we call you Mummy 27
What?. #
Do you want to shake hands?
Whaa!
See~~~You're Invisible Man...
So...l wonder what seven
of us are going to do?
They:did say that this was
a~catch the culprit sort of game...
How do you like the
game I made this time?
It's. pretty cool. don't you think?
Yeah...It's a masterpiece
Right! Right!
Yes, Agasa residence...
I'm sure this'll satisfy them.don*ttyou?
I'm sorry for calling so late.
Oh... I call them first thingtomorrow
This 1s Nude...
Uh...is Dr. Agasarthere?
And have them monitor it!
He's not in.
I think he went out somewhere with Conan.
They were looking forward to it after all!
uh?2?But I hear their voice
Dont!
Oh, this? It's their taped voices.
Ail still has a cold!
I don't know what prank they're up to but...
You don't want them to catch it, do you?
It's been playing for some time now...
So. what's up?
Oh eah...
Well, your coldes taking
a while to get better, right?
Sol figured you should be checked
at a hospital with good facilities.
And asked a friend doctor of mine
but was told that he has to
go on a business trip.
Soghe's
only available tonight...
I know this is really sudden,
but can I go pick you up-now?
I'll notify Dr. Agasa later for you...
Well. I don't want to force you though.
It doesn't bother me...
I was kind of angry anyway
because they re doing their own thing.
It's boring staying home alone, besides...
Great...
Then. okay...
I'll be there in about an hour
so will you get ready to leave
as soon as I get there?
Okay...
I'll see you in an hour then...
Ortomal Comic Books By.
SHO AQOYA
Producers»
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Chariater Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I1OKA
Scripts By.
WKANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHI
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Dircealors.
MASATOMO SUI
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AON@
AKIO KAWAMU A
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photooraphy
IAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSH
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, 1 TD
in assowation with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DLIVCIIVE LON AN
CrEDSHO AOYAMA SHOCAKUKAN: YTV IMS
ATl=Riohits Reserved
raw) O ~F- -