Friendship, Romance, Mystery
Because we cherish them we can continue
Beginning of the yeargstarts with the
Detective squad!
Instead of a monkey's butt its
Genta's
He sees through the:one and only truth,
A child in appéarance
with. the I.Q. of'an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Hey!! Is it for real
that 'Ai and you:were almost.-kidnapped
Yeah
but we somehow made it through safely
The kidnapper got away though
I'm really glad for you both!
Since you both recovered from your cold
and .got to comerto school!
We were really worried about you!
Thank you
I'm perfectly:fine now
We actually wanted to go see you but
Conan insisted "that we shouldn't go-see you
dmbecause'we'd catch yourkcold
Right...?
Yes!
Oh. is that so
We even decided.on what time
to go see you and yet
He had th nerve to tell.us
not to come see,you
Now that I'm relieved. I'm starved
Not again!!
Um...
Are sure it's really safe?
For me-to go outside
Yeah petty much... for now
WwW. What do you mean, pretty much
Al removed all the wiretap
that was set up in Doc's house
and in fact; I went browsing around here
alone last night
disguised as you
I asked mom {0 helpgme
disguise myself.as.you once more!
HmmsShinichi
you 10OK just great!~What do you think?
You think so
D.Doing something dangerous
Iike that on your own again
There was nobody watching me
or anybody suspicious following me
I wouldn't say that it's 1006 safe,
but mot the type who can stayed
Iocked up just because I'm scared.
I decided to believe her words for now
I lose.
I'll give up on Sherry
Her words?
Besides. you prettyymuch recovered too,
haven-tiyou?
Isn't it because pressure
from those guys disappeared?
(BI%R)
(ma)
Look for the Mark on
the Buttocks Part 1
(ma)
An FBI agent?!
S,Sonokol!
RR Really
Sfionoko
But!
Y.You mean Jodie is?!
No kidding?!
S Sonoko!!
This is a hospital! /
Be quiet
Oh...
I'm sorry
Don't worry about it
Why'd. you think of working
as an Englishiteacher'in Japan...?
D.Don't tell me that you're an undercover
agent investigating something?
Sonoko...
No-NO!
Oh...that's not it
I There.was a culprit I was
after for a long time.
But I carelessly lost track of that person.
So. I was given time off
from work for a while,
that's why I came to Japan!
A really honestly: love Japanese games!
G:Games...
I became an English teacher,
because I always wanted to
be one for a long time!
But. my time off has come to an end!
As soon as the wound
on my stomach heals.
I have to head back to the States!
Then, the treasure map you said
you'd been looking for all this time is...
I got a call from my boss telling me
to come home
because they got a clue
to the culprit that I've been looking for!
He said he's going-to give me
a chance to make:things right again!
See...
I wanted-to say good bye to
cool'kid, before leaving too
so. I-went.to.Doc"s house. ¥*
That's when I saw cool kid and Al
¢ being pushed into the car and taken away
by some suspicious looking people,
so I went after them with my car!
I cornered them by a pier...
nd...
They suddenly fired a gun at me
They suddenly fired a gun at me.
Se. I did likewise!
Oh...
Of:course, the gun was what I had
taken-from the suspicious people!
But. I was sure lucky!!
That Ran was hiding
in the trunk of the car.
And that she protected Al...
Because back then,
I was shot in the stomach
and couldn't move.
Moreover, the kidnappers were planning
to give up kidnapping and
kill the children!
R:Really?
I found the pictures of Conan
and Shinichi hidden and pasted
behind-the mirror in 'the«restroom of
Jodie's condo.»
So I went to Jodie's place
to ask her about them
But, she wasn't home,
so I was ready to leave when I
saw her car in front of her condo.
The trunk of the car was open
so I took the liberty of...
So, you took the liberty of .
I mean you know
Huh
Im sure.glad yourweren't
2 bad person after all. Jodie!
I mean, I thought: that
you were-involved in some way
with the case that 'Shinichi is involved in...
Andlz~that you were being threatened \
by the culprit to take pictures of Shinichi
to find out what his weaknesses were...
I had every mind to confront
the culprit directly and beatthim up...
Hey, Ran!! Are you serious?!
I mean the things you think of
are so unreal...!!
Oh! Those pictures that-are pasted
there are of people thatufve
befriended in Japan!
What?!...
I actually had them: pasted
on the living room board
when one of my Japanese friends came over,
she had a queer look on her face so
I decided to move the pictures
over.to where:they:are:now!
I see!
Americans often have pictures
of their families
all over the desk at their work place too...
It's not too customary to do
something like that in Japan
so. I guess it's only natural that
it would be thought of as odd...
Come to think of it, even when
I went to watch an opera in New York...
the actresses had a lot of pictures pasted
all over the mirror
of their dressing oom.
you mean the time when you and Shinichi
were attacked by the street ripper!
Take care, because I've heard
that they appear in this area recently too!
Oh4dwe will...
Somebody's here...
I guess we'd better be going then...
I hope you get well son. Jodie,
Thank you so much, both of you!!
Please excuse us...
Howyre you doing?
All right. somehow...
The shot fortunately missed
my vital point so...
By the way, were the Japanese police
convinced with the explanation
we gave them?
Yeah...
After hearing the siren of the police car,
one of the kidnappers took the boy
hostage and fled.
Then he disappeared leaving the car
and the boy behind in the forest...
The other one who's leg was fractured
committed suicide with the gun
he had on him...
Unfortunately,
since it was the dark, neither
yoURner the children could see theiface
of the kidnapper who fled...
Of course I made both children say
the same thing...
I didn't want to create a sensation
by publicizing that
the kidnapperwas actress Chris Vineyard
after having failed to take her in,
on top. of not knowing what the actual
motive of the kidnapping was...
We also felt bad about
making you work undercover here
without acquiring permission
from the Japanese police, so...
The problem is that girl...who was called
by the name Sherry by that woman...
boos
I wonder if she'll accept
Well, it seems like the F.B.l. is in on this
too so I'm sure
they can't make any moves
that easily either!
Come to think. of it,
Doc was saying that you got a phone call
from Jodie this morning
What did she want?
Huh
Was it to verify whether
we didn't contradict. each.other?
Well "guess so...
I'll be frank with you...
We would like you to accept
the witness; protection program...
Back then, Chris Vineyard...
Yes...the lady called Belimott,
tried to Kill-you to keep you from talking...
In other words, it's obvious that
you have information
that she finds very inconvenient...
I think you-already know-what
the witness protection program is
about from movies and novels,
in which your name, personal history,
addressand everything else
IS changed to that
of a totally different identity
in order to protect you
from the people who are after your life...
You will be guaranteed sufficient
income and other miscellaneous things
from the country for life, and I will see to
it that you get™o live a happy life...
Of course whether you.want to accept
TS or not 1s:up to you...
However. once you accept it
you will not be able to.see or call
our family and!friends...
If you're afraid of that woman coming
after you in revenge
If you don't want to get
your friends involved...
I'll be waiting for you to
give me a:good:answer...
What's up Ail?
Maybe her cold's...
Huh?...
No. that's not.it...
It's been a whilé since I came outside.
Oo I'm just a bit tired...
Bye then. because I'm. going this:way...
See you tomorrow!
I'll see you at school!
Okay!
I feel great
splashing in the rain...
splash, splash
La, la...
Ouch!
Heave., heave...
Street ..Street ripper!!
Somebody, get him 1
Huh?
Whooooaaaaah
Kyaaaaaaa=
It's Ayumi's voice...
\ aaah!
Whaaa!
What's up?!
Ayumil!
Ay/unfii?!
I sea...
So, you don't'remember that
person's. face.
N.No...
It was raining and
It was raining and,
I was wearing my raincoat-and-hat...
It was raining-and
I was wearing my!ca'incoatl~j;and"hat>.»...
Besides. "was sO scared.
I couldn't look atitheiperson;s face!
Even the lady victim
who got her armed slashed
didn't see the culprit's face...
Judging from the way things 15Ok
the culprit is probably the same as the one
who committed
the other three previous cases...
But. the outfit is different...
I heard. the person shout, Wt $o006ah
I'm sure it was a man!!
But, youi{can't really tell
just.from a shouting véice...
Either way.
Let's go to the scene of the crime
and do an inspection!
Maybe you'll remember something...
Yup!
Bumped into the street
ripper-over here...
We heard Akemi scream so
we came running over
Which means that the culprit.ran.away
because you and the others.came?
He fled before that!
Oh...
Before he ran away,
he:came towards me once,
Oo I was: surprised:but...
He'came towards:you?!
Yep!
I heard a clinkingisound afterwards
SO I'm sure he picked something: up!
Maybe he dropped loose
change or something?
Maybe:it was his glasses or house key...
ItFcould ve been a necklace of bracelet...
Do you know what the-culprit picked up?
Nope...
I think it has something {6 do
with the: number 5!
The number 57...
Because there's a mark that looks like
the number 5 on the palm of my hand!
I looked around-the-area-after
that but I saw nothing on:the ground...
Can you drawer-picture
of thelmark- for me?!
Yes: I can.
It looked like this...
It doesn't look like a
50 yen coin or a 500 yen coin either...
I Kind of, looks like the letter-"S
of the alphabet too.
Well, I'll try go looking for traces
of this mark...
Boon
It could be a mark left behind
by some coin
from a slot machine
game center or something...
Oh~~~1]
T.There he is!!
Huh
Ex Excuse: us!!
.Don't let himrget away!!!
Wow!
Oops!
Damn!! Its so-hard to get through
with [so manysonlookers..}
Ge There is he, the man in the raincoat!!
There's the street ripper.
Hey-!!
Oh- wait...
Why you
Whaaaa!!
It. It's officer:Takag:...
Huh?!
WwW, OW. OW. ce.
Ow, ow, ow...
+Ghads! S,She's right, it's«officer Takagi.
WisssVVAEW hat a thing to do...
Hey, @fficer Takagi,
didn't a man wearing a raincoat
come running this way?
Here are so many of them:here...
Because it just stopped raining...
But, Wow bod.
To come back wearing araincoat to the
site of the crime.
Knowing that/the police IS
conducting investigations...
Yeah...
the culprit:probably figured that
) the police wouldn't think that
he would-come"back in the same fashion
as. when:he:committed the crime...
Don't tell me that he: came back to take
revenge-thinking
that Ayumiihad seen his face...?
No way
He probably came back because he was \
positive that she didn't see his face!
F:For what?
Beats me...He may have forgotten
something at the site
that he shouldn't have left'-behind-"
On: maybe he came back
to.confirm something
Darn..I"m:all wet...
Anywy S top priority to figure out
what:this mark that Ayumi. drew-is...
H.Hey!!
Agh!!
Gfienta'?!
Huh ?!
Y.Your buttocks. Genta
What?! Is it ripped or something?
The: mark that the street ripper left
behind is there!
The mark that the street ripper left
behind is there!!
What?!!
No kidding?!
That means he must've come in contact
withfthe culprit somewhere...
Genta. please try and remember!!
Huh
Where on earth did you?!...
Please answer. GentaHV
Where on earth
did you get that mark on?!
The mark of the street ripper
that is on your buttocks!!
I.wonder if this is really a mark
Ieft.-behind by the street ripper?
Yup!
It looks just like the mark that wasy
on the thing that the culprit dropped!
I coincidentally pressed
my hand against-it,
when the culprit got flustered,
came back toiget it and then fled.
After that, the same mark was left
on the palm of my hand...
Which-meansithat
Genta touched the culprit or the culprit's
belongings somewhere along the line...
It could've been when
you went after the culprit
who was among the crowd and
wearing a raincoat, went fleeing!
BB. But...
The-bag of somebody in the crowd,
staggered and.bumped into a bicycle,
it wasn't the culprit!
B.Besides.
Huh?
It.It's nothing...
Could it be that the mark
that was on the bag.and the bicycle were
the same as the mark
on the culprits belongings?
If so, it could've been
a name brand item...
Let's go back to the site and
ask the people in the areal
Besides the owners of the bag and
the bicycle may still be there...
Officer Sato...
O,Officer Sato?!
Oh, yes...
Yeah...
It's strange...
The mark that was left
on Genta's buttocks...
It: looks familiar...
Oh! There!!!
rippe over is mans ag...
But, there's nothing that looks like that
mark on the bag...
Besides, the bag isn't dirty at all
so I don't thin his is the one
Because the mark on Genta's buttocks
Iooked to be soiled with mud...
If he was soiled with mud,
maybe the bicycle is a better bet?
And. where is that bicycle?
There she is! She's the lady!
Poooo
It's true that itsis"soiled with:mud but...
The mark doesn't seem to-be there.
Where on earth did you get
I that number 5 or S of the alphabet
Iooking mark on you...?
It's neither a 5 nor an SS...
Huh?
The mark that is on the palm. of
Ayumrs hand and Game's buttocks
IS a reverse and mirrored image of
the actual shape.
In other words the actual shape is
a shape that is opposite that of an 5 or:S.
Oh, I see!
And what about the size of the mark? Ii
If that something left this big asmark
on Ayumils palm think
that she would have an idea of
what it is...
No... Mine was much smaller!
It was here about the size of
a one yen coin!
Which means that the two were
the same mark on separate things...
If it was that small...It could've been an
accessory of the same brand...
Mirrored image...accessory...
Huh=:the:'mark on the sleeve...
D.Don:t tell me that?!...
O:Officer Sato?
This!! It's this mark!!
What!! Officer Sato...
Yes..:After I drove through a muddy road,
I didn't wash the car,
I sO those traces were left behind...
. Come to think of it. you were sitting
on the/hood of Officer Sato's car,
weren't you, Genta?
Y.Yeah...
Why didn't you tell us right away?
Well. it crossed my mind to begin with
but I didn't say anything...
But, I didn't think...it can't be!
I didn't think that Officer Sato
was a street ripper sol!
1.I'm Not one!!!
LE not one
The culprit probably has
the same model caras I do!
Then
the mark that.was on'my palm...
Is the key to! the: car of thisr-model!
A cover with this mark:carved.on
it comes with the master key!
S>CC.
No kidding!
As proof of it. look at
the tip of Ayumi's sleeve!
See the zigzag vertical lines on it?
UP"...
True.
That's probably because
there was dirt on the tip of the key...
and when it.was pressed
against her hand,
traces of it stuck on to the tip
of her sleeve...?!
No. it's not dirt...
It's discolored and:-black...
butithis is...
blood?!
M:Maybe the reason
why the culprit came back here is...
Yes.probably to check whether Ayumi
and Genta saw this mark...
And after seeing our undercover
police car, the culprit probably figured
that it would be a matter of
time before everything is disclosed...
Then, we'd better hurry or
the culprit will get away!!
Officer Takagi, get a hold of
Inspector Megure
and have him set up a cordon!!
Check all the drivers that are
driving cars with the same mark
that are trying to leave this areal!
Y.Yes!!
Also check all the inhabitants in the is
area. who own the same model car!
If the culprit is a person who will risk
coming back to confirm
whether the model of
his car had been specified,
it's likely that. he has
a parking space or storeroom nearby!
Okay!
But, what if there are many cars like it?
D be one hell of a.job looking for it...
No, I don't think there are that.many...
The modal of this; car with this mark
Onfltheikéyriénd Body is
pretty old: and.-manufacturing of
it stoppéd-about:7 or'8 yars ago.
Besides, it was raining
when 'the crime=-was-commiitted.
If we were to search for a culprit whose
car is wet in the rain,
with no alibi and
who has lost his master key,
the criteria for the search would be
drastically narrowed down...
Why doesn't the culprit have
the master key?
He probably had it but dropped it.
A blood stain in the shape of a key
was left on the sleeve of Ayumiis outfit...
This serves as proof that the culprit
grabbed the key with hands
soiled with the blood
of the victim and fled!
This means that the culprit will not show
the police the key,
which he knows will display %
haematological response!!
Oriel Comic Books By
@OSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
»-Charicter Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
ScPipts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABA A
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHI
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Direlors.
MASATOMO SUI(
HIROTOSHI-TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWA A
ATSUSHI AONCG
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUIANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
IAKASHI NOMURA
IRONOBU HO
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief?Director
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, TD.
In 1ssoaiittion with
YOMIURI TELECASTINC
CORPORATION
DETECY VEL ON AW
COMO AOYAMA SHOGAKUKANYTY - TMS
All Rishts Reserved
rove/ of
Just what does this mean,
fficer Takagi...?
You-said so, confidently,
that this would specify the culprit...
Stupid itrs.not the key
that 's"being:checked.
Huh
There's a possibility that the culprit would
comeitoflitakejarevengesoriwanyone
who was involved: with you too.
I'll go see him, after all.
Open the door, will you!
Bye. bye...
LOOK for the-Mark
on-the-Buttoeks---Part.2