Friendship. Romance. M"stery
ecause we cerisa ; em we can con inue
The hint lies with Ayumi and Genta
The key lies in the car
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
On the way back from school in the rain,
Ayumi bumps into a street
ripper:on the run.
She didn't get to see his face but
the mark of what most likely was from that
of the belongings-of the culprit that
resembled the number "5
was left on-the palm of her hand.
And the same mark was also, found
on Genta's rear end
D.Don't tell me that it's?!
This!! This mark!!
A blood stained shape of a key was
on the sleeve of Ayumi's clothes
This serves as proof that the culprit
grabbed the key with hands soiled
with the blood of the victim and fled!
So. that.he could drive away
on his. car immediately
and flee as far away as he, can.
This means that the culprit
will not show the police the key,
which he knows will
display haematological. response!!
(13 ha)
Huh? Only three?
A.Are you serious? Inspector Megure!
Yeah...
One that was stopped at the checkpoint
and two others that were driving
around in the vicinity!
They're the only ones who
are residents that live in the vicinit
have no alibi and who are saying that
they've lost their master keys...
I'm going to have the three people
go over to you right now...
If you got alimpse of the street ripper,
I'd like you to make a confirmation too!
Yes. sir'I understand
The:three suspects are on their way
here right now!
\ ell
It's as if we've already
arrested the culprit!
Ayumi heard the culprit's voice...
So. he'll probably go pale
when he sees her!
Yup. I'm sure!!
I'll do my best!!
I'm against it.
Huh?...
It the culprit is really among the three.
You meet him and he gets arrested,
that's fine...
But what if he's acquitted
because of lack of evidence?
The culprit's going to hold a grudge
»n you for putting him in a fix
come after you and
may take revenge on-you one day!
If he's a street ripper who's killing people
at random the more so.
Y.You're taking your imagination too far,
I'm trying to say.
Don't go taking a reckless risk when there
isn't sufficient evidence yet!
But; I'm the one who saw the culprit
at the closets range.
So I may be able to tell who the culprit is
if you make them wear raincoats, right?
You can confirm that just looking
at pictures too. right?
As for the voice,
you can listen to the recorded voice
There's no need to go any further and
Ieave a stronger impression
on the culprit than you already have.
Just as Al's pointing out,
it's too risky to meet the culprit directly.
But, it's vexing to let the three suspects go
off just like that-after questioning them too
There's no guarantee. that
theydl be no more victims either.
Maybe it's better to just keep a distance
and peek in secretly for now. huh?
Okay. this way. this. way.
Stop!
Please get out of the car one by one
tell me your name and what you do.
Please also tell me
where and what youwere doing
at the time of the crime. around 14:00.
First, from.you.at the far left.
Ghads. I came here voluntarily,
and you treat me. like I'm the culprit.
I'm Hiroshi Enomoto.
I'm a university student working
part-time at a sushi shop on 3-chome!
Did you buy this car with the money
you made from working part-time?
No. ..l leeched off my parents.
Bug your:
I see...
If throughi:smoked glass,
they can't see"us from their side.
And. does the voice of that man
sound familiar?
it-sounds-familiar and:yet:doesn:t...
It's my day off today.
Last night my boss blasted me
so I was feelin bummed out
and decided to get it off my chest
by going to the mountains,
when I was nabbed at the checkpoint.
You were going to the-mountains
to get it off your chest?
Well, the scenery in that area is nice,
so I feel refreshed...
No wonder the body of the car is soiled
and full of scratches
Next! You. in the middle!
Oh, yes...
He...
Don't you go banging my car around!!
1. mm sorry...
I'm not really:good at driving...
but I'm good making repairs
Which means you work as a...
Oh, yes...l work at
a automobile repair factory.
My name is Naokazu Fukuchi.
The factory is closed today
but my car was not in the best condition,
so I was confined in the factory
from morning repairing it.
But, there are reports of
you being seen driving;around town...
4 was just.driving around
the shopping arcade to check
if the car was totally repaired!
Is.ls anything wrong with that?!
Oh. no...
Next.
Yeah...
My name:s-Toshiaki:Degawa.
I'm a locksmith.and my'shop"s located
onifiéchomezén
How wretched of me despite
being a locksmith, to lose master key.
Your car, unlike the other two
IS sure nice and shiny.
Yeah,
I go get a car wash each time I go out.
This car is my heart and soul. you know.
Which means you went out
this afternoon too?
I gotiarcallisaying that
the client:lostiher house key
and wanted me:itoiunliock the door.
But, sinceSheididn't explain
her address very well,
I was goingiiaround in circles
ookingifor the house.
I didn't get to see her at all, however,
because she called to tell me that
her boyfriend who had a spare key came,
so that I didn't have to go...
Did anything dawn
on you so far?
Nothing at all...
They're not shouting besides...
All three of them are about the same
height and have the same kind of physique
Hey. over there!
What're you whispering about?
Oh, well...
Officer Takagi
I've got a little favor to:ask you...
What is it? .
What could! it be?
I'll go see: them:after all.
What?
If I go closer and take a look
I may be able to make out the culprit.
No! Didn:it IFjust tell youithat
if'thezculprit doesntiget arrested
something terriblef~flmayfihappenfito you.
B'But.
Not.only you.
There's a-danger of anyone who helped
you becoming.the-culprits target.
I know, how you feel about wanting
torpunishrthe-badrguys~Butg™
to hold back your feelings
no matter how-strong...
and keeping out of the picture
alsorequiresza lot-of courage too...
Yes . this is the right thing to do...
For yourself as well as for all the others...
That's the story...
Huh
Will you call the forensic officer
and get us a minus screw driver?
Yup.
I think everything will clear up...
And we'll all find out Who /
the big fat liar street ripper,
that is resorting to cheap tricks
to hide his crime is...
Yes, it's him
Well, at any rate.
You're going to have to leave your cars
at the police station for a while.
There are a lot more things
we'd like to check on so...
Hey. hey. you've gotta be kidding
I came here to Beika Police Station;
voluntarily, you know.
Why are you taking things so far as
to keep my car in police custody?
P.Please give us
a convincing explanation too.
On why we were summoned here
as suspects of a street ripper case...
If you called us:in justibecause we don't
have an alibi during the time of the crime,
I'm sure there; are a lot of
her. people 00...
First of all, it's your car!
They are all of the same make and model.
Y.Yeah...
Moreover, all three of you say
you've lost your master key.
When the street ripper fled.
He dropped the car key of this car
with the emblem of the maker on it.
We already have reports that the culprit
picked the.key,up with hands
smeared with the blood of the victim.
We also know that he came back
to the site of the crime to confirm
whether the police had a lead on him.
We know too, from
the testimony of a witness
that the culprit is very likely a'resident
of this vicinity
who Knows he'll be in hot-water
once the police start checking on him.
That is, we know that the culprit:is
among you three
because you own this car model,
have no alibi,
Iive nearby and
cannot show-us your master key
because it is smeared with blood...
what?
'Told ou lreall ustlostm ke...
Well, a simpleicheck
by those forensic officers
will clear all of that in no time at all.
Ch.Check.)...?
What?
We're just going to check
for luminol reaction
Officer Takagi. please have them-begin
Y.Yeah
Please do as I told you to
over the phone then.
Yes, Sir.
First start from Mr. Enomoto"s car
n the far left...
Hey. hey,
PR dd
don't tell me that you're going to search
the inside of the car for the master key?
Even if you're the police,
you couldn't possibly do something
outrageous like that, can you...
Don't worry.
We won't check inside your car.
H-Hey, Conan?
What on earth are you-going to check?
If'I'were the culprit.
I would've thrown.the:blood stained key
away-long time ago!
Silly, we're not checking for the key.
We're checking the keyhole
of the.door of the driver:s seat side
that the culprit stuck the key in
when he fled.
I see! Blood should: be=there too. huh!
B.But, even if blood.were found there,
it would be a.very:small amount...
Will you really .berable:to make it out?
Of course.
Luminol reaction is
verysfssensitive and can detect
the slightest'amountiof blood...
Yeah,
the culprit went.out;all out
as to think.uprarcheaputrick
and lie in order;to/hide:the fact
Lilia
Allie «Cheap trick?
Try: and remember
at the three. said..about wh
they were doing: at the time of the crime...
Mr. Enomoto was headed for
the mountains to take a drive...
Mr. Fukuchi drove around the shopping
arcade to check if his car was repaired...
And Mr. Degawa was going around
Iooking for the house of the person
who said she lost the house keys.
Why does that make them liars?
Then, take a look!
The car of Mr. Degawa. who says his car
is his heart and soul-is sparkling clean.
Mr. Fukuchi whoa.says-he's a lousy 'driver
has his car parked really near the next-car.
And the speed racer Mr. Enomoto-s.car-is
full ofiscratches and soiled.
Youtunderstand. now<;don't you?
Not at all!
Gentailhow didplyouipractice
ridingithe:bicycle?
I practiceditogetheriwith mom...
it tback roadwhere
not too many people were...
Because it'd be«dangerous
bumpingiinto?people...
Ohlil'see!
Mr. Fukuchi is lying!!
If he's not good at driving
he wouldn't even try driving through
a shopping arcade
where there are a lot of people!
Besides at the time of the crime it was
raining:and vision was poorer than usual.
It's the worse course to try out a car that
yousrexnotzeven sure is working right...
Moreover, Mr. Fukuchi parked his.car
completely parallel to the car next to, his.
That's only proof that
he's an extremely good driver!
If he's not good.»
he's car would be a biticrooked...
Then, the culprit is
Mr. Fukuchi and he's the:liar?
1 Co,
he parked his car very close to
the next car
to make checking the keyhole
of the door difficult.
But-it-s all over now...
Becauseslook,
the car next to his was moved.
So the keyhole on the driver's seat side
IS In clear view.
I'm sure there'll be:a-response:if:luminol
Is sprayed. onto the:keyhole
A bluish purple colorshould: be emitted
when it chemically reacts to blood...
Huh...no reaction
Hume!
Huh?
Otfikliflbrwr 1
R.Really...?
Hey,
just what's going on, Officer Takag!?
You said confidently that we would be
able to figure out who the culprit was...
Oh, well...
it was supposed to work out that way...
Huh
Excuse me, could you lend me
minus screw driver...?
Huh? A minus screw driver?
Here you go.
Thank you.
So. are you satisfied-jnow?
Since all three cars showed no reaction,
can we go now?
Now you know that
we're not the street ripper. right!!
Please calm down...
What's going on. Conan...?
It's not like you said at all...Huh?
Huh? Where's Conan?
He went that way just now,
after taking a minus screwdriver
from the forensic officer...
What?!
this: keyhole;moves like a slime
when: pushed 'from, outside?
Huh
I"'wonder-what it is?
Oh. hey!!
Oh. hey!
H.Hey: sonny!!
The key cylinder is fixed in place
with vinyl tape!!
I see.
He changed it on the spur of the moment
with the cylinder of another car,
thinking that the police would check it out.
Which means
that the real reason why he parked
his car really close to the next car is...
to hide this.
Unless you open the door this way and
remove the cover,
you can't.cheCk how the key cylinder is
on the inside...
Then, then, don't tell me that...
Conan had foreseen
Il this to begin with...
Oh. well... This key Cylinder
1s really the one for this car!!
1.1 goofed when trying to set
it up and broke it...
It's just a temporary measure until a
replacement arrives...
Will you show us the key
to this car, then?!
As well as the car number
that is carved into it!
You should know since
you're an auto mechanic...
that there are numbers on the key cylinder
of the driver's seat side of the car.
If we compare the two, we can tell
whether it's the same key...
Or would you like us to spray luminol
on to the key cylinder
of the ignition beside the steering wheel?
I'm sure blood reaction will be displayed.
Because the key cylinder
f the ignition is sealed
and cannot be changed in a
hort period of time...
O.0Okay! "if show you the key number!
I'm sure the key is
In the dashboard compartment...
Oh. hey!!
Hey. open up!!
This guy confessed later that
he did what he did because
he wanted public attention...
It seems he was just seeking stimulation
in his mundane life.
Although we cannot really say"that
it was fortunate
that no one died in thus:incident...
It turned out-that this stupid
attention seeker just jostled the area
around the Beika'iPolice Station a bit...
and the case was closed...
I'm sure glad that
the culprit-was caught though!
We don't have to. worry about Ayumi
being pursuedfby the culprit anymore!
I-doni-t mind-being pursued!
Huh
Why ?
Because I know Conan will protect me.
Hey. hey...
Of course I was counting on Mitsuhiko,
Genta and Al too!
I know I'd be totally fine!
O. Oh
Excuse me.
Huh
I have something I have to do.
Bebe...
b e-b el See ou.
Ori1eanal Comic Books By.
SHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONQ@
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I10OKA
Saripls By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHIIA
YUICHI HI@GURL
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Direalors.
MASATOMO SUD
HIROTOSHTTAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWA A
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMU A
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUIANI
Directors Of Photlooraphy .
TAKASHI NOMURA
IRONOBU HO
TAKAHISA O
Recording Director
KATSUYO HI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN]! KODAMA
Fr OO) f LIC: - & of > Y
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, dD
in assowation with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETICTINTL ONAN
u ("THING AOYAMA §HO6AKUKAN1YIV1M§
\TIRi1oh » Res uve d
My. how nice of you...
to come visit me...
Heave. heave...
If If I let time pass by.
I felt.like I was going to change
my mind, that's why...
0. you've made up your mind...
as to whether to accept the witness
protection program or not...
Yes...
of course,
Of course...
I'm declining.
It's probably true that
I'd be safe if I change my name and address
and-become an entirely different person...
But. I'd have to go over the
same thing again anyway...
I'll be living a vicious circle
of fear and hiding.
Then becoming another person
when the danger of my identity being
revealed comes around...!
Besides. there is no guarantee
that I can completely trust
you FF. B I. agents...
And...besides...
although I understand how itsfeels to
want to punish the bad guys...
and keeping out of the picture
also requires a lot of courage too...
B:But...
But...
But)...
don't want to run!
I can't win just running around!
I can never win!!
I. don't want to run...
@nh.
SO, you've decided against it after all...
You're not going to
try to convince me otherwise...
Well...
I'm against your idea
as an F B.l. agent but...
since I experienced somebody coming
after my life when I was still a child...
I'd like, you to cherish how
you feel right now!...
Hang in there
See you...
Ghads...
It's like I'm watching you as a child...
It's. like I'm watching you as a child...
You, who kept denying to accept the
witness protection program...
And in the end, shouted defiantly
to let you join the F.B.I.
in exchange for accepting the program...
Wrong. James,
she seems to already have
what I lacked back then...
[RIC Ye?
Yes..-something that is very dangerous
and capable of breeding disaster...
But yet a very warm thing
that gives you courage...
There's something that feels familiar
about this place!
Nostalgia. as they say...
Beware of fire
Huh? Where's Ayumi?
WwW. Wait, don't leave me behind!
Here ( oes...
Whaaaa!
Don't tell me that...
(BI¥R)
Don"t-tell me that...
(BRIER)