Friendship. Romance. Mystery
Because we cherish them we can continue
An old nostalgic mansion
In the countryside
Among the tourist attraction is
a'feeling of a new case
He sees through,the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
This is really a charming place.
I feel like I'm back in the old days.
You feel nostal sick or something, yeah.
Huh?
You mean nostalgic. Genta.
Since when did they change it?
Just how old do you think you are,
nyway...?
It certainly looks like a.place
that is talked of a lot since
It's going to be selected as an Earth Heritage.
Recently there's talkiabout something else
What us that. Conan?
What's that something else?
That is...
The ghost story!
Ha ha ha.
Oh. you meanies. all of you.
Hee hee
Are there talks. about a ghost?
From about half a year ago.
People started saying
they witnessed~a child ghost.
And the rumor seems to have spread.
Don't you guys know this tour is a gift
for solving a case?
Why don't you try
to get a taste of good old Japan?
Indeed. For god's sake.
Ill try to get a taste good old beer. ha ha ha.
Come oniinmsir I
Ha. ha. ha. That's him alric ht.
(Bi%R)
This place really makes me feel
as if we've time warped.
So. we will stay here for the night.
This place is an earth heritage
and inn for tourists.
This is really good old Japan.
Oh. There are three floors inside.
SO it has more rooms than it looks like
it has when seen from outside.
There must have been a large family living here.
Huh? This is...
What is it, Conan?
Well,
the stone and the soil around the stone are new
For a hundred year old house of heritage,
it's strange...
They are going to stay with us.
Hi. good afternoon.
Hi, nice meeting you.
Oh, the inn with the high rooftop.
IF Rumiko: is very impressed!
So isiKanako that's me!
Tsk. What an old stinking place!
Can I take a'hotbath?
How about air conditioning?
I guess you can't expect these things,
ha, ha, ha.
He's awful.
Hush: /Rumiko'/He;ll hear.you]
Did you say something. sisters?
Eek!
You stogtit! Don't be childish.
Yourre embarrassing them.
Huh? What did you say?
I'm embarrassing you?
You said so. didn't you ?
Stop it. Stop. how unsightly of you.
«sa 0
Stop? Who are you. dirty old man J Co
If you want to address me at all. you can call me,
Kogoro Mouri.
Mourn?
e means that...
The sleeping Kogoro, the detective?
They call me by that name. in spite of myself.
Did you hear that? In: spite of myself!
So theatrical.
No, I didn't.
This is gorgeous!
Little Rumiko is so impressed!
So you're a famous person, pops!
Stop it. ladies.
You are making my beer spill over.
Ha. ha, ha.
My name is Shoukichi Sakamoto \
and I'm honored to meet you fr. Mourn.
I'm Kazuaki Kuwajima. Glad to meet you. sir.
An. And I am glad to meet you. gentlemen.
Hun! What a bore!
Excuse me, sir.
Huh? What?
Excuse me,
but your inn is located a block down,
at Ishizuka house.
Why didn't you tell them sooner?
How delicious! This pot of wild boar!
This iwana fish is so delicious too.
Delicious. delicious.
The aroma of this misossoup-is so fine.
Yep. It warms your body.
Well, It's best for winter, this.hot sake.
Take one. .please.
2 Oh. Thank you. sir. I will.
Lay off!
Oops. Huh?
They made it up and put it on the magazine.
It's not real and you won't see it here
Hun!
Dear!
Don't you be rude to our guests.
Excuse me. we are very,busy right now.
Huh? What was that all about?
It's this, Ran. This article in the magazine.
Oh.- What about it?
Wha! Ghost seen at the Earth Heritage site"!?
Unexpected busy business bewilders
people of the district.
Off-the-wall but it sells?
We don't need any ghostihere
What a nuisance! {
I see.
It should be.
An earth heritage is the pride of the world.
So much so that
it is an asset to all mankind.
Exactly. and we agree with you.
How dare they use it to attract people here
as if this were another tourist attraction
for a crowd of curious people?
It really is
Now this is for you.
I'm just doing my share to welcome you...
That's Mr. Mourn!
Your words.are precious to us.
Now you can drink to that.
Well, thanks to you. I will.
Wow.
Ah, you're the one to enjoy drinking.
Off you go with more drinks.
Hey. Now they started\...
Well. we are leaving now...
Thanks for everything, guys!
Good night.
You've done your share. guys.
Now.lets drink up once more.
It-is-so delicious!
Conan, we should be going now.
That's right.
What are we going to do? Sleep?
No way.
How can we go to sleep before making sure
if the ghost is real or not?
Of course
Sure. We are here to search for facts!
Aren't we. Conan?
Oh, me?
It suits you, Conan. Go with them.
I'll - ass.
I'm staying here
and going to read a book in the room.
Ha. Haibara. you.
What's the matter with you, Conan?
Oh. Uh, it's nothing.
By the way. let's go take a walk for a while.
At this time of the day?
It's not that late.
Besides, I get to see the attraction over there.
Beware of fire, everyone!
I'm scared but it's beautiful!
It doesn't surprise me
if it comes up in this setup.
They do it every evening.
Each house sends someone
in turn for the night watch.
Fire is the biggest enemy
to a house with thatched roofs.
The best they can do is take precautions
against fire for themselves.
The whole village takes
and shares responsibility...
In a way, this is very reasonable.
All's well.
Good and thank you.
Click, click.
Watch out for fire, everyone!
Who... are you?
Hey. who are you?
Watch out for fire, everyone!
Huh?«Ayumi is not with us.
She was with us a moment ago.
Ayumi!
How on earth did she get lost?
Ayumi! Ayumi!
I'm sure she was with us here.
I say she got hungry
and went back to the inn alone.
No. She is not like you. Genta.
Are you sure?
Mmm. What's that?
What?
Did you find her?
Oh, it's Ayumi's scarf.
I'm sure it is.
Wait, wait for me.
What's your name?
Who are you?
Wait for me. Don't leave me alone.
Waa.
Wait!
Oh? Ayumi's lost?
I'm sorry
I guess we weren't careful enough.
We decided we should come back
and search for her with more people,
SO we came back.
I see. Let's all go look for her together.
Mumble., mumble.
Gosh!
On. I see dad can't help us.
My man, too.
He never stops drinking once he starts drinking.
Let me call the villagers
to help with the search.
Thank you.
And we thank you, too.
I'll help you too.
Yeah.
Hey! What's the matter?
Is something wrong?
I'm gonna help you.
You can't and don't.
What's the matter with you?
I'm not trying to sell anything to you.
Pfoo!
Ayumi!
Ayumi! Ayumi!
We've found her!
She's at the root of the Water God cedar tree.
Ayumi!
Come, on: Ayumi!
- - 5 Y
Mmmm
Oh. Conan?
Ayumi!
Are you alright?
Oh. everybody.
Do you feel any pain?
You appear to be free from injuries but...
I'm alright. No pain at all.
Can you talk a while?
Yes.
What happened?
It Sw...
It's...
Did you see a girl?
I did.
She was about 10, bobbed hair. and
earinghka red skirt.
Can't be!
It can't be.
Mr. Nagakura...
She came to see Efiji. Mami did come
Mami
That-girl. Her name is Mam:.
Yes.
Mami and Eiji had been friends
since childhood.
Mami was a year younger,
and they were very close friends.
Yes. lim sure it's her.
Mami believes that Eiji is not guilty
and came to see him.
Not guilty?
Cut it out!
Young lady
you've mistaken something else for her,
I'm sure of it.
Huh'?
But how do you know?
I'm sure I saw her.
Do you doubt her, pops?
Ayumi is an honest girl.
She doesn't tell lies.
Calm down, everybody!
Well. why -are you certain that she saw wrong?
Mr. Nagakura?
But of course.
Because both them...
Eiji since last month
and that girl since ten years ago.
Have been dead.
What! .
Died ten years ago. wow.
Then she was...
A ghost...
Aaah.
I, I can't stand that kind of a story
Ha. ha, ha.
So it's true.
So they appeared.
I'm scared...
Don't you worry, Keiko.
Huh
What's the fuss all about?
Where have you been:tall this time, dad!
Huh
You. you all,... who's behind all this ..7?
Dear...
Huh
I got it. They are behind all this!
The. ?
You can't fool me with such a trick!
You won't have your way with me, never!
A s&s oo
And:Eiji. That fellow is not my son!
Keep that in mind!
How can you say that!
How cruel, Eiji just...
You hold your tongue!
Calm down, Mr. Nagakura.
The sake took hold of you.
That's right.
Cool down and have more hot sake.
And you'll be...
Leave me alone!
I smell something.
This village has something 5
other than a ghost.
Yeah.
It seems worth investigating.
Yep.
Was that a ghost?
That Mama...
QJ) TY
Es CS
The house of Otsuzawa.
Mami had been living
In this house with her parents
She was the only child in the family.
Hey. Ayumi!
Mami died of a disease.
And then the parents moved out
to some other place.
Are there any photos left?
Maybe not, it's been 10 years now
With a photo of her,
we can tell if what Ayumi saw was real or not.
That's right!
How well your mind works, Au.
Real? You mean the ghost?
You of all people start talking like that...
Don't you believe her, Conan?
Dont you know I'm the detective
who is making his way
with logic and reasoning.
There is no place for a ghost in...
I'm not asking anything of the sort.
Huh
They're both asking you
if you believe in Ayumi.
A. Ayumi!
Yousllspay for this. Conan!
What the...
And now we go for Eiji.
Huh? Oh, yeah.
Suicide? Eiji Nagakura killed himself?
Yes: There is no doubt about it.
Since you asked me,
I checked on Eiji Nagakura
in the crimerarticles in the newspaper,
and I found one.
It took place half a year ago
in the town of Shoujin.
It's right next to this village °*
you are staying in.
They found his fingerprints at the scene.
He was wanted.
And he probably gave up on running.
Eiji Nagakura is a jewelry robber
who committed suicide.
But his mother believes him to be innocent.
That's why the village people
were reluctant to talk.
Conan.
Mmm
I didn't tell a lie.
I really saw her. Mams.
Ovo
I want you, Conan.
To believe me.
So I want you to 1
You want him to investigate. don't you?
Yes.
Of course he will do it for you,
and just for you.
Aibara, are you serious...
Conan Edogawa. are you ready?
This is one place that's eerie
even in the daytime.
I saw her over there and
she acted as if she wanted me to follow her,
1p to the large tree.
Then,
Then? What happened then, Ayumi?
She disappeared.
Disappeared?
She just disappeared into darkness.
And she never appeared again.
I got tired of calling her
and it seemed I went into sleep
at the foot of the tree.
Uh-huh.
Where did she disappear?
Exactly where?
Mmm.
The mist was thick...
It was there beside the tree.
Huh
It's still new.
It says 'Tama.
It could be the inn across the street.
Oh. That's the story.
Thisikimono was blown:away by the. wind.
Ayumi saw it-and thought
it:was the girl by mistake.
What are you talking about, Genta?
Clothes hung-out to dry,
won't come flying this far.
It's not a mistake. I actually saw her.
1. I believe you. Ayumi:
It must be some coincidence
Hey. Are you insisting there's a gho...
huh
I saw him yesterday...
What on earth is he doing?
Beware of fire, everyone.
Footsteps?
It's walking!
So it really is a ghost after all!
But a ghost doesn't walk on foot. Genta.
You're right! Then. it means...
You stay here!
We'll go with you.
Then, keep quiet.
Shh.
All's well on this floor.
It's on the top floor.
Darn it!
Who is it?
You!
What were you doing?
Ugh!
Augh! Mr. Nagakura!
Call an ambulance.
And the police!
Yes. will.
Yes, will do.
The culprit is not far yet.
Ran!
Oh. there...
Mami! So she was real.
Where are you going?
I can't believe it.
A ghost attacked Mr. Nagakura!?
Orioinal Comic Books 'By.
SHO AOYAM
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO sumo
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I10OKA
Saripls By.
KAN]! KAKSHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KG U HI
JUNICHI MIYASHIIA
YUICHI HI@URLE
TOSHIKI INOUF
Animition DirceGlors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI'TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AON
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Jdircalor.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUIANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
I RUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJI Kr DAMA
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
In assoslation with
YOMIURI TELFCASTINC
CORPORALION
DETEC JIVE CONAN
WV AHISHO AC YAMA SHOCAKUKAN:YIV - IMS
AY Riohits Reserved
I see. If you insist,
I, as they call me a great detective,
has to take up you case.
It can't possibly be a ghost.
Conan. you did see Mami, to
Now I understand. I see why.
I'm sure of it. The real culprit is that person.
Who will show up at that place tonight.
(12%)
(ifi £5)
Ce=F37),
(1£ $I)
(1£ t=)