Friendship. Romance. Mystery
Because we cherish them we can continue
An out of season mystery
Everyone's feelings solve the case
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Don't let up, dear. Come on, please.
Don't you give up, dear.
Take it easy. Mrs. Nagakura.
Oh. Wait a minute!
This is not a mark left
by hitting or scraping...
What is it?
Don't get in the way, young man.
Oh, oh.
Excuse me.
Red and unconscious... serio
Questioning at the hospital
would be difficult.
Well, I didn't notice anything.
I drank too much and was fast asleep.
Oh, excuse me,
but Mr. Mouri can solve cases in his sleep.
Oh. ah. Well. Ha. ha, ha.
Mouri, it is.
You are Mr. Kogoro Mourn,
the sleeping detective, aren't you?
The great detective, yes.
Oh. excuse me. Mr. Mourn
The higher ups gave me their consent.
SO please help investigating
with us on this case.
H. You've got...
From your higher-ups...
Umm.
That's something.
Ha. ha.
(1523k)
We are expecting this village to be
registered as the Earth Heritage soon,
and we do not want any incident
Iike this happening here.
As a matter of fact. I'm from this village.
And I hope the case closes
as early as possible.
So please help us on this matter,
Mr. Mourn!
I see very well what you mean,
and I, Kogoro Mouri, the detective
of repute, will give a full hand in this.
Thank you very much, sir.
Ha. ha. ha.
So rest assured and don't worry.
This is sudden. Mr. Mourn,
but who is the culprit?
Huh
Is it a ghost? It can't be!
What are you talking about?
Of course not.
Huh
Oh. I'm speaking to the other party.
Then that means the culprits...
Yes. of course.
It's him.
But, you saw her, Mami. too, Conan.
No...
something made you think you did.
NN \ ?
VAJIUA VAR on WV Yaa Wan Y
But because Ayumi saw something
it helped us to find out
which way the culprit fled.
This way leads to... a dead end.
He leave the village.
That means!
The culprit is yet to go out of the village!
And at this time of the day.
He wouldn't choose
to come from outside this village.
That means the culprit is
one of the people in Onizawa village,
and includes the tourists too.
Ho on earth are you to...
Oh. don't bother yourself over them.
Any layman can think up
what they just said.
That's right. Stay out of it, all of you.
Furthermore,
there's something more important thing
that you should note.
And what's that?
The culprit hid the rope there
in the daytime,
during the sightseeing tour,
and used that rope at night
for breaking into the house.
Gosh!
Hen it means that...
the culprit is somebody
who is not from the Nagakura house,
where the Mouri party stayed at,
but is definitely among one of the guests.
Just as expected, Mr. Moun!
I'm so impressed!
Ha. ha, ha.
Oh, no. It's just one of the things I do!
That is that,
but the issue is what the culprit...
Was doing there.
That's more important.
Don't push me, Genta.
Hurry up. One more floor to climb.
Maybe he was just a thief after all?
But what was he trying to steal?
Then, did I imagine what I saw?
If Conan says so. he could be right, still...
He was not exactly stealing something.
But I'm sure he was looking for something.
What was that thing he was looking for?
Huh. huh.
What's that?
Nothing.
I just thought from here,
you can get a good view of the scene
where Mr. Nagakura was stabbed.
If you 'can get a good view from here,
it means this place Is
in clear view from there.
Of course! That explains it!
Huh? What did you say?
What's with Conan?
Sey!
Just as I thought.
What's wrong with this?
Keep off!
You'll get a rash if you touch it.
A lacquer tree. isn't it?
I remember the hand
of Mr. Nagakura got...
Yeah.
That shows Mr. Nagakura passed
by here yesterday.
Murderer!
We won't tolerate you.
You gave yourself away at last
Turn yourself in
You made them do it.
You lied.
Liar.
What is this all about?
He is the one that was rude to everyone
the day before yesterday.
Could it be that he did it
to Mr. Nagakura?
But then,
why are those villagers at each other?
I can explain that.
Oh? Why?
I read an article in a magazine
on the way here.
When applying for the Earth Heritage.
The villagers were separated
Into two opposing groups.
One side said there would be no need
for more tourism, and they opposed.
The other wanted to introduce
the existence of this village to the world,
and was for promoting application
for Earth Heritage.
If I remember correctly
Mr. Nagakura represented the group
that wanted to promote application.
That's why.
Mr. Nagakura was trying to say...
You, you all,... who's behind all this...?
Dear.
I got it. They are behind all this!
He meant the opposing group of people
when he said them
Calm down, people.
Let the police take over,
and please go home.
We can't.
Let's decide now.
That's right.
Hey. he is getting away.
Don't let him get away.Get him.
Stop it everyone.
An investigator?
Uh huh.
He said he was sent-from the committee
that is involved in accepting applications
for Earth Heritage.
I heard 'before that
there is a special undercover investigator,
who makes a-fair-evaluation
« That's right. But in his case,
he is the official investigator...
You took bribes from those municipalities
as resources for promotion,
as resources for promotion.
Didn't you?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Cut it out.
Suits for damage have been filed already.
And we've got the goods on you.
You asked Mr. Nagakura for commission,
but was turned down.
SO you got mad at him, lost yourself...
And did it. didn't you?
Stop talking nonsense!
Sure, I talked about money.
and it's true that I was turned down.
That's why I gave up
and went to bed early
cause I decided to leave here today
I stayed inside the house.
You are an old dog at this business,
and you gave up just like that?
Do you expect me to believe you?
I'm an old dog at this business,
that's why I gave up!
My experience told me the sooner
I quit the better.
I know when I can't expect money!
Look at this!
Its Mr. Nagakura's
watchman s record book.
The record says for the night
All's well up to the ninth house.
Mr. Nagakura was found on the way
to the ninth house.
It's very close to the Ishioka house
where you spent the night.
I don't know anything.
I didn't choose to stay in that house
Is there anyone who saw you asleep?
I was alone in the room. so no one did...
But it's not me!
I didn't do a foolish thing
as to stab a man.
Later,
Kensaku Kawaji was taken to the police
as a material witness
for extortion and attempted murder.
But he totally denied attempted murder.
He also-denied charges for unlawful entry
into the Nagakura house.
So. the case looked to be closed.
Yr EY
Thank you very much for everything.
Thanks to you, Mr. Mourn,
we were'ablesto get Kawa)
Na. ha. ha.
How about drinking
to the success of getting him.
You ll never...
I would like to say sure...
But .
We have to start questioning him.
Of course.
Ha. ha, ha.
Nagakura went through
a series of misfortune, so far
It's good hat the case was closed,
uh, rather,
it looked as if it was going to be closed.
A series of misfortune?
His son Eiji Nagakura
for one thing.
1a a err: ,e nng o 1appen...
I'masure of it. Mami.
She came-to see him
because.she believes in his innocence.
And Eiji. Tihatfelldw lis not:my son!
Keepithat.in-mind!
Well, because of these things,
ten days ago.
They renovated the rooftop after 30 years.
And they moved the whole house
to the present site.
Oh! Moved the whole house?
What is it?
Theyrmoved that big house?
That's it. That's why.
That explains why the foundation
Iooked so new.
It sure surprised me but that's not all
What
- The.:Nagakuna house.was here
until a half month ago?
Yes.
The house was moved
from here to where it is now.
This Otsuzawa house had been over there
and they exchanged
the houses all together.
Why did they do that?
They said they did it for complete
reversal or something.
It's probably because
the place over there commands
the best view in the whole village.
As a representative of promotion
for Earth Heritage application.
He managed to do it.
At least some people say so.
Well. anyway. they really look alike.
It sure is identical.
You mean to the Nagakura house?
At night, you could easily mistake /
one for the other.
If, the motiv Yof the culprit
had nothing to do
with the application
r the Earth Heritage...
That is, if the culprit simply
made a mistake
and took one house for another...
Hey. Conan!
What happened to him?
Conan!
Stop running.
Just as I thought.
They are identical inside, too.
When he was in the Nagakura house
he was somewhere
around here looking for...
Mmm?
I, I've found it.
What? What did you find?
Wow. Great!
Terrific sight to see!
Beautiful. very beautiful.
Are these 7?
Yeah. Most likely...
Hello?
Oh, it's you. Shin'ichu.
What's that?
Tihe jewelry stolen in the robbery case .
Where are they now?
They are still missing,
Police concluded that
they had been disposed of long time ago.
Speaking of missing.
When he made his escape from the shop.
He took a jewelerhostage
and the hostage is still missing.
They say that the hostage was killed
when he was no longer of any use. but...
Ouch! It's hot!
Ah. it's not... it was...ah...
It's nothing.
Nothing to do with you at all. Ha, ha
Are you alright, Conan?
Are you alright. Conan?
That thing. you know.
We d'better give them to police.
Keep. your voice down.
Well, thanks. ladies. Well, well.
Ha. ha, ha.
There's no mistake about it.
The real culprit is that person.
And he will come to that place tonight.
I've found it.
We've been expecting you,
grandpa.
Ugh!
We've been waiting for you.
And you can't run away this time.
What're you talking about?
I just couldn't sleep and took a walk
but got lost because
the house was so much alike...
Then, what's with that jewelry you have?
You broke into the jeweler's shop
in the neighboring town
and took them. didn't you?
I don't know what you re talking about.
You can't fool us. grandpa.
You are
the principal culprit of the jewelry robbers
who killed Mr. Eiji Nagakura
and made it look like suicide.
Mr. EL Nagakura,
He seems to have been in debt.
That's why he was made to watch out
So it was you alone
who carried out the jewelry robbery
and murdered the watchman.
I know nothing.
What you're talking about is beyond...
When fleeing.
You visited this Onizawa village
as guided by Mr. Eiji Nagakura,
You hid the jewelry
you robbed in the Otsuzawa house
which was vacant at that time.
You never dreamed that
the house itself would be moved
in half a month.
Then, you pinned the guilt
on Mr. Eiji Nagakura alone,
and killed him making
it look like he committed suicide
Then you came here as a tourist
to retrieve the jewelry you hid.
That's the jewelry in your left hand,
isn't it?
That night,
you were looking for the jewelry
as you assumed Mr. Nagakura was away.
But, he saw you,
SO you got out through the window.
That means that you didn't break
into the house
but were inside from the beginning.
Mr. Nagakura saw you
when he was on watch
and hurried home.
Yahh.
Ugh!
Wooh. uh.
The watch record shows that
something went wrong with the order
in which the seals were stamped.
I. I'm just an old man
and a tourist.
I just found this by accident.
You are not just an old man
and a tourist, and I knew that
when I noticed the mark
around your right eye.
\ That mark isithe trace of a loupe
The jeweler who was taken as hostage,
murdered, and missing
IS none other than you. Mr. Sakaki.
Surely...
but suppose he kept hiding himself
in fear of the culprit,
Iong after the culprit killed himself,
and now he conjured up enough courage
to come out to retrieve the jewelry,
what do you make of this, kids?
you admit that
you were looking for the jewelry
on the third floor
of the Nagakura house last night.
Well. I wouldn't be so sure.
Then you went out through the window
and inured Mr. Na akura. is that ri ht?
Oh, that!
I was drunk with sake and sound asleep.
So I couldn't possibly have done it.
Then, when and where
did you get the rash?
When you were drinking sake together
with Mr. Nagakura,
both of you had no rash
or reddening on you.
The people who were with you
at dinner can easily prove it.
But the red rash on both of you is
evidence that
you were at the same place
at the same time.
Mr. Nagakura!
Call an ambulance!!
The only place the lacquer trees
are growing in the village is that place,
there is no other place. That settles it.
You! Who are you to press on me?
Conan Edogawa. a detective.
And we, the boy detectives.
You are talking rubbish!
Get off!
I not going to get caught
for all the effort I made.
Give me back...
Give me back myiEiji..Eiji.
Give me back.
Keep off, you...Get off of me.
OK! Now!
Get this!
Waaagh.
Ugh,
Du ouch.
Shriek!!
You've done well, Ayumi!
That's what true-to-real act is, Ayumi.
TL "You are worthy of an Oscar!
What?
Act?
I was just standing there all the time.
Ut. then what was that...?
Look at that!
Mist, it's the mist.
Look close.
Huh? Mist?
The Brocken specter.
The one you look from time
to time out of a airplane or mountain top.
I see. That's what it was!
Yes.
There is nothing in this world that
you cannot solve by logic and reasoning.
@rieinal Comic Books By.
SHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATfiMO sum)
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
\ KAN]! m HIWABA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHIIA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHITAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWA A
ATSUSHI AONG
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUIANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWACGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OK DA
Chiet Director.
KEN]! K0 DA MA
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, [TD
in assoaiation with
YOMIURI TELECASTINCr
CORPORATION
DETHCHIVE( ONAN
« {HIS44O AC YMA SHOCAKUKAN -YIV - IMS
All Riohts Rs rv
Jrw ass
Mr. Mourn!
Thanks for the call yesterday.
Huh? Call?
Thanks to you, we got to check him
before he tried to escape.
Mr. Mouri, I really respect you, sir.
Respect!
That's right, sure it is.
Sure thing
Ha, ha, ha
Ha. ha.
I wish I could see you
even If justefor an-instant.
I don't mind if youirea ghost. Mama. ,
Hurry up Ayumi
We rergoing.
I'm coming up.
Wait for me!
And the two houses that
have been moved were returned
and placed back
to where they originally were.
He did it because Mr. Nagakura thought
that the spirit of the girl,
who had been a close friend
of his deceased son,
had revealed the truth
about the death of his son.
Of course, I, the detective of logic
and reasoning didn't believe it =.»
Two months later
4 Onizawa village was officially registered
as the Earth Heritage.
Detective is my business,
and I fight against the darkness
of the society they call crime.
What's pops doing. anyway?
Kill
If he didn't do it means he is sloppy or ms
Or he foresaw
that somebody else would find it
at the sound of telephone bell
and hid it here on purpose...
Well
3.000 yen!
Hat could be...
(BI1%R)
Forgotten Cell"Phone