Friendship, Romance. Mystery
Because we cherish them we can continue
Beneath the office is cafe Poaro
A.forgotten phone starts a case
He,sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
My name's Kogoro Mourn...
I run a detective business that
fights against the darkness
darkness of society called crime...
Conan, sonny,
Iets go have breakfast!
C.Conan. sonny?
Hello!
Two morning sets. please.
Although it's a daily repetition
of investigating extra-marital affairs
and searching for people...
there are times
when I'm involved iwbldlodylcasesnm
The many, sa Nincidents
that are in the*papers everyday. gr
oglin I
YMotives vary from
revenge, money matters,
complications in love affairs
complications.in-love affairs
revenge, money matters »
and so on forth...
It sure is:a sick/world...
I come-her fSttengy
when get sickland tired-of alljthe bonds
involved in the detective business...
Than «you for waiting..y
Yes...
this cup of-warm coffee is indeed
what relieves my heart
that is exhausted from all bonds
I have in life...
Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!!
FoohLFooh!FoohU
WW... What. I tell you Pops...
(Bi1%R)
mn Cell Pho
How unusual of you
to come here from morning...
Are you going.to-be meeting
a clienttodays'
No. no.
Ram's gone to Karate Club Camp
from yesterday...
So. we're having a late breakfast...
Besides, today is Sunday.
I figured I should take a break
from the heap of cases
that come avalanching in everyday...
People!!
Good morning!
I'm Shuhei Baisho! Shuhei Baisho here!
I will do whateversissin"my power
and work for you
PM?!
LO-N
I will do whatever-istinnmy power
and work for you
I will do whatever: is infmy power
with my entire heart and soul!!
With your valuable ballot.
I Shuheil Baisho will work with you
to-create a quiet town!!
Huh?! Work?
Yes!! Mouri Detective Agency...
Wake up~~~Hiroshi
Uwhm~~~come on,
it's already 800 in the morning
You're going to get me. Yuka.
In trouble if you don't get up...
You're the one
who's still groggy and not awake!!
Check the number
before you make the call!!
Uh=excuse me...but could itabe that...
Huh ?!
B,business is...slow?
AY -—
we didn't get any calls-all this week...
T,The thing is...Oh
I wonder if it's okay to ask
a detective to do something like this...
Huh? Is something troubling you. Azusa?
Two days ago...
A strange thing was forgotten here
and I was wondering
if you could locate its owner,
who is a customer of our shop...
Oh, a search for somebody...
What is it?
That strange-thingathat was forgotten .
NY Lye.
Oh ..yep.
It's this
A cell phone?!
It looks tosbe an ordinary cell phone but...
I guess...yes, the pattern is prett odd.
Other than that.
It isn't really all that strange...
If the person who forgot
this cell, phone is really looking for it
I'mesure that person will call...
Well. someone did call...
three times...
Three times?!
when I answered the phone...
this is what the first person said...
Oh? I'm sorry,
I seem {0 have made a mistake...
A mistake?
Hmm.
What about the 2nd time?
The 2nd time this is
what the person said...
That's strange...did you hear anything?
It seemed like someone else
as beside that person...
Right after saying so,
the phone was cut again...
Oh!! I'm sure that...
the person was.looking for the cell phone
But, since he was looking
in the wrong place.
He couldn't.anything and thought
that he had dialed<the wrong number!
All
B.But,
it didn't sound like this person was
the owner of this cell phone...
Huh 1
Why not?
Because with the 3rd call...
that person's tone of voice
suddenly changed and.
Hey. you!! Ill bet you're his broad?!
Get him on the line!!
He shouted saying,
I'm going to kill you!
Kill 2
What did you tell him, Azusa?
W...Well...
I hope you explained
the circumstances to him" Did you?
I was scared...
so I switched the phone off...
Oh... I see...
Please show me the cell phone!
I fold the master about it the following day,
and was scolded.
So I kept the phone switched
on all day since then,
but the phone hasn't rung so far...
It's no wonder nobody's calling back
on this «cell phone.
Why do you say that?
Because this phone isn't working!
Huh
See! Even if I try to make a call
I get the busy signal right away. right?
Truc
I get it?!
The owner of this.cell phone probably
couldn't pay his phone bill
and so his'phone was cut off!!
Which means the rude one
who called
was a money collector!!
In other words,
he called the owner
of the phone thinking he was living alone,
but a woman answered
so thinking he made a mistake,
he hung up.
He checked the number and called back
ButOhe [probably blew his top
at the third call!!
But, he probably blew his top
at"the third call!!
Then...
why did the one
who called™the 2nd time say,
Did"it anything?
It's most likely that...
when the collector went to the home
of the owner of this cell phone
and called him from
in front of the apartment
he didn't hear any sound
from inside the apartment
so he thought it was odd...
Do you remember what kind of person
who forgot this cell phone was?
Yup...
He came here a little: after noon...
He was a chubby man wearing glasses
and his hair was parted on the side...
He was eating and touching
that flashy cell phone
all the while
so I remember*him very well...
The phone rang for the first time
about an hour after he left...
The second call came right after the first
and the third call came in
about 30 minutes later...
The number of the one
who called was notHisplayed...
On top of that,
the record of calls made before that,
as well as the call received records
are not saved at all...
Oh. . there were a lot of
names and numbers left on it
What?!
Then...
why don't you try calling those numbers?
They all seem to have been
random numbers..«and...besides
the names all séemed™o be fake 100...
It's true...
\ and strange that all the names
are in "katakana characters...
As to the phone numbers...
I see. this is strange...
There are no 10 digit numbers
that start with the number one...
Huh /!
What's thissblack mark
on the side of the names...
There are some names with black marks
beside them and some without!!
Oh...
True,
there are mankson some
and none on- others
Don't tell me that...
that all these numbers are
all some kind of code?
How annoying!!
19.8
where was this cell phone placed
when it was forgotten?
Oh...
Oh:...
Over there.
Hmm???
Under the sofa
where you're sitting right now, Mr. Mourn.
He probably dropped it accidentally
when he tried to put it in his pocket.
Without realizing he dropped it...
he kicked the cellphone with his foot...
That show think it got there; but...
Like I just explained
I found the cell phone right after
the man called the first time...
The antenna was sticking out besides! 3
What?!
Was the cell phone
folded in two like thistback then?
Y Yup
That's why I thought he dropped it V
when he tried to put it in his pocket.
Don't you think it's odd?
Uh?. What is...
Because if he folded the cellphone
to put into his pocket,
don't you think he 'd-naturally
push the antenna back in too?
Right!
Because you don't want
the antenna to break!
He probably didn't do so
because he's either a very sloppy.guy .\=s
He did so and deliberately hid it...
wanting someone to find it when it rang...
What do you think, Pops!!
Yeah... I was just about to say so...
Hmm...
but if so. for whatever reason...?
You can't figure out who the owner is...
after all...?
Huh?
Oh if it's the owner of this cell phone,
\ Il know who it is!
\ Huh}! But how?
Every cell phone has seal
with its product number written on it...
If we give that number
to the manufacturer,
then find out
where the cell phone was bought,
explain the circumstances to the shoy),
we can get the name of the owner
of the cell phone!!!
WwW Wow!
Fuh fuh, fun.
Youtake off-the back cover
of 'the cell phone
And under the place py
where the battery is removed...
Agh!!
N Not inside?!
The seal...
Is peeled off!!
W. Why?
Can you tell us more in detail
about the customer
who forgot this cell phone?
More in detail...
Even the slightest detail
even if it seems trivial Anything!!
Well...Come to
think 'of it «
That customer ordered...
fried noodles, spaghetti, fruit parfait,
tomato juice and Caesar's salad
and paid exactly 3,000 yen!
Uh?! T.Three thousand yen...?
Uh?! T, Three thousand yen...
Huh 21
Well, ordering the 5 items
he ordered is the only way
to come up with a total of
exactly 3.000 yen,
so I was sort of impressed...
Since Conan said that
any trivial detail would do.
I thought I'd mention it
the guy sure is a big eater,
eating § items from\noon...
Right. he seemed to be on the job
and yet I thought to myself
he sure can eat...
On the job?
Because.
He...
asked for a receipt.
Receipt?!
W. What the name on it?!
F course. "Customer...
Oh, I guess so...
I'll be waiting for your ballot for me!
I will do my best for you all
Is IX
as I have been doing so far!
ell! LB
But...
1 If he was eating alone
and still wanted a receipt...
The probability of him
being an ordinary office worker
becomes quite unlikely.
If so:then...what on earth...
He is most probably an office worker
on a business trip
or a man who owns his own business.
He could be a[person
with that kind of habit.
If so...maybe
he's'a. journalist or a detective!...
Even the police ask for receipts.
Police officers in police boxes
ask for receipts for meals they have.
Oh...no. no...
Hello...Agh?!
That only goes for police-detectives!
Ope you on min mesjoining you.
When: they go asking around.or
on a stake out,
or have to follow the suspect
for transportation fee
and'fobdsand drinks needed
during the investigation...
But, we officers in uniforms rarely use
investigationsfeex
O.Oh., you're the one
who's always hanging!
Around with Officer Takagi...
What brings you here. Yuma?
What brings you here. Yuma'?
What else but to
urge Mr. Detective here
who takes forever to pay
for his parking ticket to pay.
Oh, well,
I was thinking of going to pay today...
Today is Sunday!!
Agh?! EeeeeKk...
I'm only joking...
We're looking for a man...
Huh)!
Dooco
this is the only clue we have...
Three?!
Three thousand yen?!
Is his by chance
wearing glasses
and has his hair parted on the side?
A chubby.man?!
Do you know where he is?
Well, sort of.
I'm glad!!
I can finally give the cell phone
back to its owner
Huh?! What do you mean give back?
That man-forgot his cell phone here...
I also got strange calls too...
so I was really concerned.
Oh...
But. you can't return it to him...
Because...
he passed away the night before last...
Pa. ..Passed away?!
Huh'!
OO... Oh no.
Don't tell me he wastkilled?!
He was run over by a truck
at the 3-chome intersection.
Aicar-accident?
Yeah...
I remember.
They aired that accident on the news...
Yes...
The accident occurred
the day before yesterday
just before 14:00...
He was taken to the hospital immediately,
but he didn't make it...
He passed away... .that night.
He passed away...that night.
He passed away that night
That's why were investigating trying to
identify who he is.
Wait a minute...
Don't tell me this was a hit-and-run case?
The driver of the truck that
hit the man didn't flee.
Nor was: he under the influence
of alcohol
According to testimony by the witness. +
the man seems to have
suddenly come running
out from behind,a parked car...
Which means this excludes
the possibility of homicide...
Don't tell me?!
Could it have been suicide!
That's very unlikely
because he seems: to. have asked for
directions at the convenience store
near the accident site:before he was hit...
He seems: to-have been
in a great bigsrush and asked,
Do you know where a shop
called Poirot is?
If he was planning to kill himself
Why would he need to ask
about the location \
of a shop that is 2 kilometers away?
True...
But. I kind of have an idea
why that person rushed out
into the street.
Yeah...
In other words
({ the man wanted to go back to the shop
to retrieve the cell phone
he had forgotten there.
And was run over by the truck...
No..lwrong...
The dead man-s lips are sealed.
We're back to zero again...
The cell phone was folded in two
with it's antenna sticking out
and left here as if it were hidden here...
It's like the cell phone, was ringing
just so that somebody would find it...
Those strange names and numbers
that were saved in the cell phone...
What were they anyway?
What on earth was that man
trying to do here?
But two days have already gone
by since the accident.
It sure took you long to get here...
We couldn't help it
because herhad nothing on him
that would givesus a clue to who he was...
Oh, right...but he did have
all these receipts on him.
All these receipts ornhim.
All of these here...
He sure meticulously kept
allithese receipts...
iaido...
sen en as il...
He's gone all around the city...
Right.
We checked those]receipts
in order of, the dates.
We checked those [receipts
in order of the dates,
We checked those receipts
in order of the dates.
) and it took us one-whole day...
But. we finally got here...
There were people
who remembered him too, however wus
nobody knew who he was
or where he came from...
but. things as they are.
There's a possibility that
he was being pursued by loan sharks too.
Loan sharks.
Yeah...
There seems to have been a call
on the cell phone
that he forgot
from a dangerous sounding man
shouting,
If you don't put?him on. I'll kill you."
Really?
Oh...yes,
three times. about an hour
after the man left.
At any.rate,
I'd advise you
to go check the loan sharks.
If he did borrow money,
he would've left his address
and name with them too.
Aha. ha. ha, ha. ha, ha!
Huh? What?!
I think you can easily:find out
without doing something like that.
Huh...
Because the dangerous man
who called knows
the number of the cell phone. right?
If I were him and the phone didn't, work
I would give the number
to the telephone company
and have them check on who the man is!
And?
If you call the phone company.
You'll be able to find out
If the dangerous man called!
Fuh...
Fuaaaah!!
» Unless you're the police
or something the telephone company
would never give out
the name and address of anyone.
35/7
understand Conan, sonny!
Phooey...
Oh. but...
there are times when we panic
and rush to make a call, don't you think?
Huh 2!
There-was a time
when I got lost going to my friend's house,
and when I tried calling her,
her cell phone was switched off...
so. I called the telephone company
and asked for her address.
I asked them'if they could find /
my friend's addressifor me I)
from her cell phone number.
Right, right
Huh ?!
Does everybody often do things like that?
And?! I
Did they find~her address for you?
No. they didn't...
So. I had the police officer
at the police box §
Iook up her name for me.
Well. it's true though.
That if the man was in a rush to look for
'e owner oe pope
he would've tried calling
the phone company,
despite knowing that it might not work...
Ms. Numata, will you please look up
the number of the phone companies too!
Okay!
Let's try each and every one
and ask them
whether they got a call or not...
It's. nice...
that the police get to ask
anything-they want...
7 Some
I guess so!
Although it may'take a while
to get throughtthe red tape...
So long as we have the phone number,
it's as if we've already got
his address and name!
Yes...
as long as we kept that e-mail address...
we could've gotten to them...
if we had what the lady had entered
on her cell phone.
We would've been able to find
the hide-out of the boss
who controls them all...
Yes. 1
from about day before yesterday.
S...that s right. Yes.
Yes, yes...l understand,
thank you so much.
How'd it go?
I don't know yet.
I've got*to wait for them to call me back.
I'll try elsewhere too.
Azusa.
Please serve the customer
on table #1 another cup of coffee.
Oh, yes, sir...
Thank you.
No problem.
Hang in there and keep up your studies.
00000 °0
the address. name and phone number
, Did you-get anyjcalls=asking
for personal information on a man...?
Did you get any calls asking
for personal information on a man. 2?
Would you like-another serving?
tr 4%
Yes...from 2 days ago.
00000000
This rs on the house.
Thank you!!
I leave it here
Oh! Thank you.
SO very much
Here you go!
Orange juice for you. Conan!
Wow!!
Thank you. Azusa!
I'm sorryato have got you
involved in something like this
on a precious Sunday,
your day of rest...
Will you show me that cell phone
that was forgotten one more time!
Here you go.
Thank:you.
Ha. ha. this is funny!!
The clue that's left on the cell phone...
A mysterious 10 digit number
that begins with the number "17.
hat begins with the number...
And the unexplainable black marks
that are beside the names...
What on earth do they mean?
Thank you for your support!
Shuhei Baisho!
Will . do, my best for thisitown
with all my might!
Thank you!
Yes... hello...
Yes...hello...
S....that's right. Yes! Ye.
Did she get something?!
A clue on the man .--41
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA/
MASAHITO YOSHI@KA
Background Music
KATSUD ONC
Character..Designs By.
Story Editor.
JUNICHI HOKA
KAN]; KASFTIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASAYOMO SI/DO
A HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYO@SHI KOBAYASHI
ow . - - <<
IL CHELOT
Chief Direct ¥¥
KEN]! KODA MA
I IMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CON
u (IMHO AOYAMA SHOCAKUKAN-YIVJMS
All Rights Reserved
Three...people called ?!
T.Three people called,"
The telephone numbers
that are in this cell phone
all start with the.same four numbers'/
All the numbers are similar.
Maybe they all live In
the same neighborhood!
This
U Ye, atbe coo
they said that they heard a loud sound
of the on the other side...
A sound loud
enough to interrupt conversation...
Forgotten Cell phone Part.2