Friendship. Romance. Mystery
Because we cherish them
we can continue
Searching through
the cell phone memory
reveals an unusual case.
He sees through
the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Rd.
Forgotten Cell Phone Part 2
Thank you very much!
Yes...
I see. Yes...
Ram,
I understand
Yes ..thank you
And
I found three prospective people!
They called from day
e ore yes erc: ay o \ 0c ay...
Three people?!
And? What did they have to say?
The first one...
said he wanted to go the interview
site of a company
but forgot the paper that he had
written the address on at home
and said that he may be
excluded from the interview
if they found out...
NF py WU
And asked to somehow
have them give him
the address...
The second call...
was from a man
who said his daughter
who had run away
from home had called
and that he wanted to specify from
where the phone call was placed...
The third-call...
was from a person who said
that the cell phone of a person
who he had befriended
during-his trip
was mistakenly mixed up.
In his bag
He wanted to thank that person
as well as return the cell phone
so he wanted the name and
address of that person...
He's the one!!
He's the one!!!
He's the only one
who mentioned cellphone so far!
Y-% FY)
On top of that,
only this last person asked to
ve the phone number too...
And. what's the number?!
Well...since they were going to
refuse answering him,
they didn't take his number down...
Besides all three
seem to have called from outside
and not their residence,
so they don't know
who called at all...
From outside?...
One called the day before yesterday
from the platform of Beika Station.
«the next one called yesterday
at noon from sports shop Aollo
and yesterday at sundown another
calledifrom Restaurant Colombo...
The problem is...
they don't remember
which person it was that asked
for the cell phone number...
Oh, right...
Tiseems that only the person
who asked for the phone number
suddenly hung the phone up
«from his side.
Suddenly?!
Yes...
They say they heard a sound on the
other side of the line at that time.
A sound that
interrupted conversation...
A loud sound...
it seems to have been
so-suddensthat they didn't seem to
have time to make out
what theasound of the was...
I guess we have no choice
but to get in touch with
the place that these three people
I've passed one of the universities
that I applied for although
it's not my-first.choice
Oh, I'm happy for you!!
Thanks...
I guess you're relieved.
Here's your change
Now, for the first one...
Yes...
ATION
What?!
The public phone on the platform?
ATION
What?!
The public phone on the platform?
ATION
What?!
The public phone on the platform?
ATION
What?!
The public phone on the platform?
Tithe night before last...
There were many passengers using
the phone so...
Hmm-~~I.thought so
I mean I understand
Hey! Could it be-that guy?
Huh 2!
You know that person who was
standing in front of the phone
that looked to be contemplating
whether to call or not...
Oh=Come to think of it, yeah...
Uh She was wearing
this expensive looking coat.
With a frightening and taut look...
He comes around to
the station recently...
Didn't you hear a loud sound
in the:background
wheniithis:person was
on the phone?
A loud sound?
Yes...
Of course, all the time!!!
Huh 2
Because thisfis a train station
after all. you know!!
See!
The announcement at the tain station!)!
Hello?!
It's true that you can hardly hear.
Hello
Huh?!
Did you hear that?
« That's:the loud sound.
Thank you...
I understand very well now...
But, do
you happen to have any other information
on that frighteningiman?
Yeah. \maybe I'll. see him again tonight.
I see him a lot
recently on the platform.
Well, if you see him please contact us!
Yes alliright.
Thank you for your help!!
Aaagh~~=Yes! Yess!!
Yes...
About -nooniyesteridny
mo ye
there was a man: with a short hair cut
that came here asking to
use the phone: He's the one, right?
He said that the battery of
his cell phone went dead...
and that he had no loose change either,
so he wanted to borrow the phone...
Huh? A loud noise?
Yes...
Was there noise loud enough back then
that you had to stop talking?
Yeah...I'm sure you're referring to
the sound of the construction...
that's been going on for about a week
in front of the bank...
See! It's started again!
Huh 2!
It's like this intermittently
from a little after noon time!
The sound of construction...
- Oh... About sundown yesterda
He must be one of our customers!
He's reticent and always wearing
Iight colored sunglasses...
He unusually seems/to
have forgotten his cell phone
and asked for loose change
in order to use the phone.
$0, I remember him well...
Huh?! A loud neise?
Yes, didiyou/hear:a noise loud
enoughithat
you had to step talking?
I wonder...
This road is known for being quiet...
Hello. everyone!!
I am Shuhei Bausho!!!
I. ShuhefBaishe with your ballot.
With you voting for me
will work along with you
to create a-quiet town!!
Did you hear that loud sound?
It's like this every noon and at sundown.
It'seems thatéthe campaign car usually
takes this route...
A political campaign car...
When will that customer
come to your shop again?
He comes everyday
so when he comes again,
I'll give you a call.
Thank you.
I'll be waiting for you to call me then...
All of them sure sound suspicious...
All of the three cases seem to ~~
fit the description.
?!...T-This is?!
Huh
What's this?!
This cell phone is strange!!
Look at it, Pops!
See!
Kid!
Don't tell me
ou broke it?!
The phone.numbers that are saved
in this cell phone!/
Most of them start with
the same four numbers!
Co Te es me es
10287...
10257...
Almost all the figures are similar...
Maybe they all live in the
same neighborhood!
Stupid!
I just told you that there are no
10 digit numbers that start with 1.
I'm, pretty sure that the owner-of
this cell phone, that chubby man
are".
who got-to know: people
on the job or something,
whougot to know people
putenumbers in order
besides their names...
Hey!
Among those numbers
which are the newest ones?
This is it.
1000. he sure knows a lot of people.
Yeah... maybe he was a door to door sales man
and just numbering his customers...
£5 ~-
007y
Then/what is thesnumber
behind it supposed to be?
C- Cw
And this! What about this black dot?
Some are marked and some are not .
Maybe he marked the people
who are prospective buyers
with the black dot
The number towards the end like
150" and "600"
could be number of products he sold, or...
If so, that's strange?!
Huh
Because there are no people
before the numbers
1022 that are at the start of the
all the numbers, and see look carefully!
There are two people with
the number 1031"!!
Hmm» /
Two...
True.
And. this too!
There's a person numbered 1101
but why isn't thereranyone
with the numbers 1032 to 1100
If he was numbering everyone in order
why does the number jump suddenly
from 1031 to 1101
Uh...could it be that...
it's a calendar?
282425282728
IS ea Fon eu?
232425262728
Calendar?!
1031=0ctober 31st
1101=November 1st and so forth
I seell
Everything falls in place that wa 7 N
Hold it...
If this number stands for
the end of October last year
and this other one the 1st of November
it's just about the time
the Tohto Congress election was held
Besides...
back then it was a pretty busy time
with the community baseball tournament
and preparations for the autumn festival
and all...
SO, it's for sure that this guy's not
from this community
Hey! T That's:not the point...
I'm sorry.
No problem...
if the four digits at the top are dates
the numbers behind them could be
the time that he made the visit...
150" =1:50, "600" =6:00 sharp.
sly To
Then why
aresthe surnames written in kanji
and the names in katakana?
Because when he visits the house the
surname is written on the name plate, but
he can only get the name of the person
after he talks to them...?
He can only get the name of the person
1028000
he can only get the name of the person
fter he talks to them...?
RAY?
1028000
he can only get the name of the person
fter he talks to them...
It could be that the-person was
angry at the guy
for selling him something
he didn't want.
What?! Who?
Ow...the guy who called us
a number that was not displayed.
The one who. shouted for the owner of
the cell phone-to take the call.
And the same one who called
the telephone company asking
for the name and address of
the owner of the cell phone.
The man with the frightening face.
If we can find out who and where he is,
we can get the phone number of
this cell phone from him
and figure out the identity of
the chubby guy
Damn!! We wouldn't have to think
so hard if that guy didn't die
I wonder if that's how it really is?
Huh.
It's strange after all
The; place where that cell phone
was forgotten.
It's strange that it was folded in two,
with the antenna sticking out
and under the sofa
That's true, that it's strange.
It's, as if the cell phone was asking for
someone to find it.
Talking of the phone ringing,
[the gruff person who was the
2nd one to call said,
Didnit rim ?"
Maybe the chubby man made
the gruff man call
and was planning to secretly
give him the cell phone.
Don't be silly!
Then, why didn't he call the gruff man
over to this shop?
If ithe phone rings.
The employee of the shop
would find it first
and he could never give it away
secretly, could he?
Exactly! It's just as Pops says!
Right?!
He would never come back for something
he was planning to hand over secretly!
He couldn't have made mistake as
to the place either...
Mistake?!
You know,
Iike always make a mistake too.
Come to think of it,
before getting run over,
the chubby man asked for directions
at thexconvenience store...
Il see!
That's right...
If he wasn't familiar with this place
there's a possibility of
him making a mistake...
Then. the most suspicious would be...
Apollo!
He could've made a mistake
because this/shop Poirot
sounds similar to Apollo
the sports shop?!
I see!
But. Azusa. I think it's hard to believe
that he'd 'mistake a sports shop
for this coffee shop, don't you?
I...I-guess so...
Um. Azusa!
Why is the name of this shop
called Poirot?
Yup...l wonder if you know,
Hercule Poirot?
The master likes him,
that's where we got the name!
@Oonan, do you know Poirot?
The man's that a bit plump.
Yup! I've seen him on TV!
He's the one that always says,
You know, my wife she ."
The detective that's,
wearing the wrinkled up coat, right)
No! No!! He's not Poirot, but Colom...
bo...?
D.don't tell me!!!
Maybe he made a mistake because
they're both detectives?!
Besides, €olombo is located on
5-chome like we are
So, if that chubby man
remembered the shop
it's understandable that
he would make a mistake...
Let's go!!
Huh?! Where to?!
Where else?!
The-other detective's shop!!
Wait!
» Hey! I'm going too!!
Me 'tool!
The identity of the chubby man
is becoming.clear!
The man with the sunglasses that
I told you about over the-phone gg
hasn't.come yet
oh... could we wait for him here. then
Yeah.
Are you going to be all right, Azusa,
taking off from work like this?
Yes...
Master's there and as long as go back by
sundown when it'll start getting busy...
I'm so concerned that
I can't work this way anyway...
Hey. mister!
Huh
Did that customer ask you something?
Yeah...
From just a while age, each time
he comes here, he keeps asking me...
whether anybody found a forgotten
cell phone here...
ust as I thought...
There seems to be no doubt about it...
Right
Oh! There he is
Welcome!
it's him.
But...what did you want with him?
Oh . just a little something.
I'll go talk to him.
If I talk to him, I'm pretty sure I can tell
whether he's the person who called or not.
No!!
I'll go first!
Huh >1
In times like this. men should go first.
Nuaah!!
Haah! Haah!
Haaa
Huh 7!
What's the matter, Mr. Detective?
Aren't you going to go talk to him?
Talk to that man
after you hear my deduction out.
First for the strange names inskatakana
that were in this cell phone.
Although its made to look like
names of people at first glance,
these are actually,
the short form of a certain name...
A certain name?
Please show me the cell phone.
Just what do you mean...?
There are names that are saved
on:the cell phone
that are very unnatural as
names of people, aren Athere?
Could you be referring to
Sho Kenbashi and Chiyo Daitoma?
True...
I've heard of places named like that,
but not so with the names of people.
Right!
Those names are probably
e names oO e groups
that belong to the name of-the place...
For example Sho Kenbashi stands
for Kenbashi Shopping Arcade
and Chiyo Daitoma stands
for Daitoma Community.
That it falls into place if so...
Ken Aida stands
for Aida Construction Company,
Seisaku Ishizawa stands
for Ishizawa Manufacturing Company.
Furthermore...
the 10 digit numbers that are registered
together with the names...
The 4 numbers at the top are dates.
The numbers after that denotes cash,
and the black dot shows that
the company in question is in the black.
In other words. it's about income.
The ones without the black dot means
just the opposite-That is. expense
If you consider that the dates are focused
during the election time of last year,
there is just one answer.
It can't be!
Under-the-counter accounting
book of election campaign funds?!
Exactly...
I have no idea how the chubby man got
a hold of the
under-counter accounting book, but...
there's probably no mistake that
he was extorting money for this...
(He probably put the copy of
the under-the-counter accounting 'book
into the cell phone to show
the one he was extorting
that he really had the info...
Which means that the man is...
Most probably...
some man hired by congressman Baisho,
who runs his election campaign
car through this area...
What?!
He probably wanted-«to get back the
under-the-counter accounting book...
That man hung up part way calling
he telephone company...
Because he heard the Shuhei Baisho's
election car coming...
He didn't want people to think that
anybody connected to Baishe was
searching for somebody
who had information
on the under-the-counter account book,
$0 he hung up without thinking.
The one who chose this shop as
the place to get the info,
IS that man wearing sunglasses,
who frequents this shop...
He was supposed to ring
the cell phone here
and secretly get hold of the information
but the chubby man made a mistake!
But, I wonder why the chubby man
didn't call our shop
after he realized he made a mistake?
Probably because...
He realized only after...
the time he promised to
ring the cell phone...
Because if it worked out the way
it should have,
the Chef of this'shop was supposed to
have found the cell phone
and the man wearing the sunglasses
was: supposed to come pick. it up
as something 'he-forgot.
Even if he went to the wrong shop,
if he calls the cell phone,
the guys could come pick it up at Poirot.
But he didn't want the guys
to hear his voice...
So. he probably carried everything out
using faxes and e-mails,
because he didn't want the guys to
get anything on him,
including his face and voice
that would identify him...
That's why he even ended the contract
with the cell phone company
and peeled off the product number...
Then why did the chubby man
rush back to Poirot. .?
He wanted to confirm whether
the man wearing the sunglasses
really got hold of the cell phone.
Because if someone picked it up and
delivered it to the police,
his plans for getting cash
would go down the drain...
But, under these circumstances,
that man wearin the sun lasses
would probably refuse to talk no matter
what we ask him.
Don't worry, there's still a way.
Huh /!
Okay...Conan!!
Yup!!
Let's go, Azusa!!
Huh /!
Hurry!
C.Conan??!
Hey. Azusa!!
I wonder who forgot that cell phone?!
If the:owner can't be found,
give it to me, okay!!
This is the first time I've seen a
cell phone with such a strange pattern!
Huh? There are many strange names
and letters in it!!
Conan...
Hey you!! Kid!!
20...
Oh...I mean, sonny.
You see, that's my phone...
What?! Really?
Then, show me proof!
PP... Proof?!
Yup. if this is yours, you should know
the number of this cell phone, right?!
I'll call it with my cell phone and
see if it really works. I
Will you give me the cell phone number?!
Cut out the blabbering, hurry up and
Agh?! There's a policewoman!!
Huh 2!
I think I'll give this to that policewoman
H. Hold it...0 Okay...
I'll give you the number now...
I got hold of the chubby man's
phone number,
and from that number the police
tracked down the apartment
where the chubby man lived...
The man seems to have been
a journalist...
and a copy:of the
under-the-colintersaccount book
was found buried below
asheap-of receipts.
The names, dates and amount of cash
were clearly written in it...
and twas more than enough to
serve as evidence. {,
All the people who received meneyyyy
I= from or who were given money
from congressman Baisho during...
the election campaign
were arrested ..one after/the other...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA¢
MASAHITO YOSHIQKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO.
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNIGHI 11OKA
Scripts By
KANJI SS IWABARA
NICHI MIYASHA]
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
I pa aby
ANTI aAaulUIr > 71 CU. Ck
SUDO
AK! 'AWAMURA
TAK SHI HYODO
Art Director.
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Recording Director.
Editor
TERUMITSU @OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJIsKODAMA /
Product By.
I TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
In as.oclation with §
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CURKIFFURKATIWIN
DETECTIVE CONAN
(> COSHO AOYAMA ll SHOGAKUKAN YTV TMS
All Rights Reserved
Welcome!
I'm KogorozMourt...
A cup of hot coffee please!
I'm an unknown detective thatyis, fighting
avrenown detective!!
Hello!
Thank you so very much for yesterday.
If anything should ever come up again,
make sure you tell me, okay:.!
Yes, sir!
I cannot solve
Take for instance, thatTstudent...
He has successfully passed
the university exam,
and doesn't have to come here
to study anymore,
and yet he comes-here frequently...
I'm sure that something else is
blossoming inside him now...
?! A case!
Es! This is Detective...
Hello...dad? It's me...
Yup. what is it?
I think I'm going to be a bit late
because of club practice today,
so could you go shopping for me?
Yes...of course.
Uh potatoes...
Carrots. onions, pork. and apples!
Yep. I figure...
We're going to be having: cusry tonight?
Bull's eye!
- Just as expected of a great detective!
Okay, got you! It sure is
an important case!!
I'll head off to the site immediately!!
Oh no!!
What's the matter. dad?!
Hot, my coffee! My coffee! Fooh. foo. foo!.
Business sure is slow, eh, Pops...
During this season,
I'm' sure the bass are waiting for
bait in hiding at the shore side.
I'm sure the bass are waiting for
baitlin hiding at the shore side.
A person died there 6 months ago.
This is no coincidence!
(8) #R)
Fishing Tournament tragedy--Part 1
(B1iR)