Friendship. Romance. Mystery
Because we cherish them
we can continue
Proclaiming the catching of a big fish,
Ieads to hooking of a strange case
m 05
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. ofian adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Wow!! It's fantastic!
What a 'beautiful lake!
Okutani Lake lis' called the sanctuary
of bass fishing.
If things go well,
they say you 1, ay even be able to
fish one as heavy as 5 kilograms.
Huh?!
F.five kilograms!
Okay! I'll eat to my heart's content and
we'll win the match!
Chuckle
Genta. I think you've got it wrong?
No, I don't! You're talking about
he big-eaters contest, right...?
Oh my...
Hey. hey...
Ran and.
Are invited'to attend
a bass fishing contest
that is sponsored by
Sonoko's father's company.
Genta and the others who
hear of this insisted that
they wanted to participate
in the contest too.
So. here we all are...
HA RA
(51%)
Fishing Tournament Tragedy" Part 1
TA RNA
(51%)
OKUTANIKO
Oooh, there you are...
Ran!
Sonoko!!
Good morning!
Good morning! Thank you for
inviting us here today!
What's this. what's this?!
You guys know how to say
your greetings!
Okay! Give;it all you:got today, mm
you groupof little shrimpies!
WiWell, I'm se sorry
that we're shrimpies!,
Oh~~The brat with the glasses is here. _q
with you today too!
Well, sorry...
Mina!
Sonoko...What kind I do-for'you?
These Children are going to be
entering the contest too,
SQ, could you please register
them right away?
Yes, all right
Please wrote your names and addresses
Aha...
This is Mr. Minai from the head office.
She's my bestriend, Ran.
Nice meeting you.
Oh! How do you do. I'm Junichi Mina...
Nice meeting you!
I'm using this!
1:1 take this, then.
Am E>
What aboutiyou., Conan?
7/74 MN
This one!
- THmm=~=<--"This one!
and is gross
But, Ayumi, it says here that
these soft baits are better for this.
Wow bthis is interesting, see!
See, it looks just like a frog!
I didn't know there was bait like this!
Really. It sure looks like a real frog.
Oh, are you guyssgoing to be
entering the contest 100?
Yup, we're going to win for:sure.
H...you two sure look strong.
A.,are you going to enter the contest too?
Of course!
I registered long before at
the reception desk already.
Don't be too hard on me, okay...
The champion and little fishermen.
Thanks for the great picture.
See you gliys, good luck.
Y.Yes, we'll need it. Ahaha...sigh
I shoo Sher hand...
Maybe I shouldn't take a bath tonight. y
Okay, okay, shrimpies!
The contest will start soon.
What did you talk about with that woman?
Oh. . She told" usSanot to be
too hard on her. <
A After that's Xgrabbed
NY nd firmly my ha
Ms. Ayukawa talked to you children?!
Yeah... firmly, like'so
She sure 'is beautiful.
Do you know that woman?
She's the winner of last year's
fishing contest.
She's that famous
Yeah, that person who just came is the
next candidate for winner of this contest
alled Takuya Masubuchi.
He won the contest the year before last.
The time now is 10:00 a.m.
We will be starting the first day of the
Suzuki Cup Okutani Lake Tournament.
TRE a
Please bring the five bass
that you have fished
to-the contest-headquarters
BY: 16700 today.
Okay. let's give it a try!
We'll give it our best shot!
I wonder how this is going to work out...
Aha, haha...
Maybe a boat-would've been
better after all?
Bass are usually hiding where
there are algae and fallen trees.
Cnr Cr - SH > :
Okay, let's fish here!
Are you sure you know
what you're doing, Conan?
O@h, it seems she's going to fish here too.
See. Eventhe candidate for
winner thinks this place is the point.
Come on..let's get to it.
Okay. just leave it-to. me!
No good...
No luck.Rere...
Maybe using a boat would've
been-better, after all?
How're you doing. little ones?
Any luck?
A oil BB
Not at all
None
Oh I'm, from "Gekkan-Bass' .
I.write articles for this magazine.
My name's Funaki. And,
mind you, it'sbass, not bus.
Ha. ha, ha.
Give me a break. 3 ~
WwW. We know
I'm interviewing because
I'm going to be writing an article
AA S00 »
on this contest next month's edition...
Right! Let me take you pictures
and put it in the magazine!
Line up. all of you
Okaynheréigoes
Oneiplus two: is
you and me!
Huh'!
Agh!!
Agh'!
Ms.-Ayukawa seems to be doing good.
I guess I'll go get a picture of 'her.
Hey. if it's not the place that's bad.
It must be the lure.
Ilguess so.
Huh...?!
Don't
Don't...
We're just going.to take a look at
what kind of lure she's using.
You stay here. Ayumi...
My goodness...
She got all kinds...
This is it! If we could only have this...
wonder if we can fish with this--
Of course...!
No, you can't fish with that!
Whaaa!!
W.We're sorry!
Try fishing with this.
This lure has a certain smell.
I'm sure you'll be able to
fish something if you use this.
0.Oh
Thank you so much!
Mugh!! /
It.it.it's being pulled. ..It's' beihg:pulled!
Talk about strong! ~=
Huh-1! Whaaaa
Oh! Oh! Oh!
NM:Mitsuhiko .-keep cool
M Mitsuhiko. keep: cool
M.Mitsuhiko, keep:.cool
Cool head! Calm down andwind-the reel.
The. other way!
Right, that's the way, keep it up!
It.It's big, heavy,
my hands are going numb
A little more, right. Wind it slowly...
Now!!"There!ll
Sh. my!! py
Buff»! Ha. ha. ha'."h'a.
Aheh, aheh, aheh.
Agh...Ouch!
Are you allright?
Show it to me.
N Jibigdeal.
Let me: clean your wound for you.
Does it hurt?...
I've got bandage so hold on, okay.
But, before that let's sterilize
the wound first
Okay...
Conan, you're late:
I was worried about you.
Hurry and get your fish weighed:
What's the matter?
Aren't you feeling well?
Don't tell me, yourdon't have
any fish to weigh!...Is that it?
Y.You couldn't fish even one?
All four of you?!
4 times 0=0 fish?!
Buh!
Sonoko. don't laugh!
But- Wha. ha. ha. ha...
We'd like to announce the results
for the first day.
In first place is Ms. Saori Ayukawa
who fished a total of 13524 grams!
All right!
Wow!!
We moved places...changed lures...
All that's left is
All that's left is luck! Yup...
Let's turn luck in our direction tomorrow
and aim for a counter win!
Okay!!
Huh 24
I wonder if it'll go that well?...
Just what are you talking about!
Cut out the stupid talk...
Ha, ha, ha, it's' nothing to get all
worked up over, is it?
Ha. ha, ha, it's nothing to get all
Excuse me.
It's really huge. don't you think?
My friend fished it...
The person who fished this is
Ied Mr. Kanie...
Yeahs? Mr. Kensuke Kanie.
Me was a skilled fisher.
Ny Muy fay
How can you fish a big fish like that?
Because we've been fishing
since we were kids.
If you start from now, Ayumi, I'm sure
that by the time you become an adult,
you'll be a great fisherman.
Really?! Maybe I should...
Saori,
why did you decide to start fishing?
My father used to fish,
sO he used to take me along with him to
rivers and lakes since I was really little.
That's why I never went to amusement
parks or zoos until I entered high school.
What?!! Poor thing...
Oh, there you are, Ms. Ayukawa.
Wanna drink with me,
in advance. celebration of your victory?
No, thank you'd rather not.
Oh; are you saying
that you don't want to drink with me?
CO oO
Are. you sure about that?
Are you sure
that's what you really want to say?
Ha, ha, ha...I'm just kidding, only joke.
The thing is,
{ "want you to tell me something.
Ql thought that while km here anyway,
I'd go and finish my work on
Rail Mania too.
You know almost everything
about this place, don't you?
Not really...
Please tell me and help me.
Please Saori...
Okay...
OR, that'll be-a great help.
I'm indebted to you.
Thanks so much... Ha, ha, ha .
He said, Rail Mania
I bought that magazine before.
He's a free-lance writer,
so he's writing for
many different types of magazines.
I see
Conan, let's fish by boat. today.
During this season
I'm sure theibass are hiding
behindthings 'hear the shore
and waiting for bait.
No matter what your reasoning is
we were IS Inga -ay near es ore
yesterday, and caught nothing!
So, today...
Right! We're getting on the boat today
in order to win.
I'm going to-fish on land after all.
I'm thinking of going
some place else today...
What about you. Ayumi?
Hmm What should I do...
OhlMs. Ayukawa!!
Good morning!!
Ms. Ayukawa,
where are you going to fish today?!
Hmm... I'm planning to Kutanisuji today.
May l.go along with you?
Hmm...It's dangerous there,
so I'd rather you don't
Oh& A
I'm sorry, Ayumi. Goodluck, all off you /
Kutanisuj }
Mitsuhiko, let's take the boat-and
And beat her to the at-Kutanisuiji!
Good luck, all of you!
Let's.go, Ayumi.
Okay.
M.Miss Ayukawa!
Huh? Where...Oh, true...
Ms. Ayukawa!
Deheh. heh. heh...
Aaah...
I shouldive gotten on the boat too...
Agh. a trolley!
Hey, hello
What?! We hit something...
There-was definitely-a sound...
What.could it be?
Could it be something used
when fishing?
I've never seen something like this.
He's Mr. Masubuchi a candidate
for champion, right?
Which means. this must be
a good place to fish.
But even if the place is good...
Oh, but it's the 2nd day
so I'm sure Conan and the others
have fished a lot today
I wonder
Uh, what's that?
Huh ?
I wonder what he's doing.
Maybe he sulked out because
he can't catch fish and sleeping...?
I doubt it.
Gyaaah!
What's the matter. Ran?!
A.A person is... lying on the ground!
Ayumi, wait here, okay!
Oh. okay.
Mr. Funakiu...
1! Mr. Funaki...
Kerosene?!
If he slipped™and hit his head
there should .be blood on the rock.
Search for it!!
What is the estimated time of death?
He's still warm.
I'd say it's between 15 to 30 minutes.
HmmA
H.He's.sorscary...
H.He sysorscary
H.,He's so scary...
Oh, the ones who found him?!
Huh?...You guys are...
If I remember correctly...
You're smo « Kogoro's...
You mean$Sleeping Kogoéro.
@fficer Yokomizo,
thank you so much always
Hmm.
And. you are?
I'm a junior at Teitan High school,
Sonoko Suzuki
I'm the presenter of this fishing contest
and here on behalf of the chairman
Oh, you're the one
who thrives on attention,
the daughter of the host of this contest.
Buh.
Kuuugh...
Will you explain the conditions
when you found him?
Sonoko and I were at the contest
headquarters but,
we came walking along to check on
Conan and the others,
then. we found Mr. Funaki over there...
So, the victim's name is Funaki?
Yup ./He said he was
free-lance writer for magazines
and was saying-that he was going to
write-an article-of this fishing contest
for a magazine called "Gekkan Bass.
Where were you kids?
I was upstream about'30 meters from
here together with Ayumi and fishing
When you were there, didn't you hear
his scream or something?
Nope 2We.-didn't, did we?
We didn't hear a thing
Uuugh...
Inspector,
may I have a moment with you...
Yeah.
Did you find it?
Well. Awe searched all over
but didn't come up with anything
the victim couldrve hit his head on.
What?! You couldn't find anything!
\ 00o ,
yu00
Lwa Xnear 'Otakeiwa
between 10:00 to 10:30...
Do you have anyone
who can prove that for you?
I was right near him all the time.
Both of us were fishing together
from early morning at Otakeiwa.
Where as this Otakeiwa?
Around here.
You may both leave
Thank you .
Yikes...talk about gruffO,.
- - Only 30 Minutes had past
since Mr. Funaki had died.
It takes 20 minutes
from the contest headquarters
to where the corpse was found.
Without 'using a boat,
the only way to cross the lake would be
to use the path above the dam.
It wouldftake more than 5 minutes
to cross the dam,
so it would've been impossible
for anybody
who was on the right side of the lake
to commit the crime.
You're Ms. Saori Ayukawa?
Yes, Sir.
Oh, are you saying
I you don't want to drink with me?
Are you sure that's what you want?
Will you please tell me
where and what, you were doing
between 10:00 and 10:30?
Yes.
I was going up
the opposite way to Kutanisuiji
from the crossroad of the main-trail.
Is there anyone
who can prove that for you?
W Caw her!!
Huh
We were on the boat,
but we definitely saw Ms. Ayukawa
go into Kutanisuji.
Yes. we waved goodbye to her.
Yes, we waved goodbye to her.
No: doubt about it.
Okay:..you may go back to the contest
Thank you.
What about us?!
You:guys can go too!
Huh?!...
You don't need proof of our alibi...
No. I don't!
I don't have time for kids...
I What a surprise. He's the one
who took our picture for us, night...
I wonder if that place is cursed...
Mr. Mina,
just what do you mean by that?
Ms, half ye
The things: half a year ago.
somebody died there too.
Since there was no one
around«back then,
the case closed-as an accident.
Who-died?
A person calledMr. Kanie,
who was very. intimate with
Ms: Ayukawa and Mr. Masubuchi.
Kanie?!
Kensuke Kanie,
he. was a skilled fisher...
Then, he was a candidate for
champion too?
Yes. Just like Mr. Masubuchu,
he was Ms. Ayukawas's
father's student too...
Ms. AyLikawa°s father?!
He already passed away
but Ms. Ayukawass: father is the person
who spread sports fishing in Japan.
He established a fishing club
and taught bass fishing...
Somebody died there 6 months ago.
This is nocoincidence.
The murderer. is most probably
one of the two!
Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MIG ITHIKO SUWA.
Bacl'oround Mush:
KWsUO ONO
Charadater:Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNIGHI 110OKA
Scripts By.
KANJI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Anim Lion Drrc
IROTOSHI TAKATAN
ebb \
AKI KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
» oN »
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Directo?
KATSUYOSHT KO@BAYAS HI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN JIsKODAMA
Produced By.
AMS EN Al MENT AT
in association with:
YOMIURI TELECASTING
I ll '4 \"
DETECTIVE CON
('OSHO AOYAMA /SHOCAKUKAN-YTV - ms
All Rights Reserved
Conan, what«are we going
to do in a place like this?
Let's go. home...
A trolley?
Ol Seelr
Mr: Funaki wasn't murdered here \
Never mind. let's"go!
Isn't that Mr. Funaki'sy
This is the real.crime scene
but how?
Fishing Tournament Tragedy--Part 2