Friendship. Romance, Mystery
Because we cherish them
we can continue
The point is in the fishing and trolley
we: reveal the truth
that-goes against common sense
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the IPQ. of an adult
with the I.Q. of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Invited by Sonoko,
we all come to ,3 bass fishing contest
held at Lake Okutan.
There, we meet the candidates
for championship
Ms Saori \ ukawa and
Mr. Takuya Masubuchi
as well as free-lance writer
Mr. Toshihiko Funaki.
The competition for the 1st day ends.
It's a bit of a concern that
that night, Mr. Funaki and Mr. Masubuchi
get into an argument,
and sure enough, the following day,
very near the place we were fishing
Mr. Funaki is found dead
from a stron im act to his head.
I wonder if that place is cursed...
Cursed?!
Mr. Minai, what do you mean?
The thing is, somebody diedithere
6 months ago too.
Who is the person that died?
A person called" Mr. Kanie.
Who was also good friends with
Ms. Ayukawa and Mr. Masubuchi.
A person died there a half a year ago.
This is nocoincidence.
The murderer is probably one of the two!
(152 #4)
(1521)
Fishing Tournament Tragedy" Part 2
(15214)
Okay,
Iet's start with you, Mr. Masubuchit...
Please tell me where you were
between 10:00 to 10-30...
Between 1000 to 10:30...
I was under the steel bridge
at that time...
The steel bridge?!
On which side of the steel bridge!
On the side where the road is!
What. the side where the road is?
Yes, that's right!
he steel«bridge is...
where Mr. Funaki was killed!
He was found«in.a grassy area
about 100 meters upstream.
He was found in a. grassy area,
about 400 meters upstream.
It Seems so. I was surprised at
thefigreat number of police there.
Imm.
I think that he would've had to walk
behind you\to-get to"that grassy area...
Didn't you notice Mr. Funaki
walk behind you?
No. I didn't because...
I was absorbed in fishing...
Is there anyone
who can testify that you didn't move
from under the steel bridge...?
No alibi. eh...
Mr. Masubuchi was near there...?
What is it?!
May I go now...?
O.Oh, yeah...l may ask you
some questions again later
S.Sonoko...
Hmm.
Nobody heard any scream...
The rock where he hit his head
cant be found...
Conan,
are you going to quit fishing-already?
I don't feel up to it anymore.
But. if you guys want to. go-ahead
Yes...yeah...yeah...okay.
Inspector,
we checked the alibis/of everyone,
from those who broughtitheir own boats
to those who rented boats: but.
Nobody seems to have gone near
the place the corpse was found!
So. the boat wasn't used...
Which means it's somebody that was
alone on the left shore of the lake.
A Vi 7,
¢ 'HH ray. ,
Which means it's somebody that was
alone on the .left shore of the lake.
Ta Imspestoénst right
I went 10 the inn that the victim
stayed over at last night,
and I was bothered by something
that one of the guests said.
Bothered?
Yes,
he says that the victim and Masubuchi
were arguing in the bath room
I see! Okay!
Hey. kids, .it's not for you to listen.
We're fishing
SN TA
we figured if the candidate for champions
Mr. Masubuchi picked this place to fish,
we maybe ablejto get a large
catch here too...
Yeah, something as big as a whale,
kyaha, ha. ha...
If we fish something, that large,
we won't be able to take itthome
If we get to fish something like that,
we'll be able to boast about it in school...
All talk you, kids, I tell you.
So. how about it. Mr. Masubuchi?
Silence could work against you
because a lot of people have:seéen you
and Mr Funaki arguing.
Mr. Funaki...
r. Funaki...?
Mr. Funaki said something ridiculous
that's why I couldn't help shouting at him.
Something ridiculous...
Well...
Hie insisted that...
I hiked Ms. Ayukawa...
and that he'd play go-between for us.
That's why I sort of blew my top!
Oh. is that all?
Mr. Funaki said that Ms. Ayukawa
would never refuse any offer from him.
Ms -Ayukawa would never refuse
any offer from Mr. Funaki ?!
- - Come to think of it. even last night
she followed Mr*Funaki
despite looking very unwilling...
A person also died here 6 months-ago...
Conan, what are
we going to do in a place like this?
Thelpolice already came here
and searched,
so I'm sure we won't find anything here either
Let's go home...
Mitsuhikoss right.
The murder weapon wasn't here.
Moreover,
we didn't even hear Mr. Funaki scream.
Trolley... .train...7?
The smell of kerosene...
The stain on the vest...
I get it!!
Genta! Mitsuhiko!
Let's trace these tracks!
What?
Mr. Funaki wasn't killed here!
What?!
I dm a...ke a ea
Théeyplace where Mr. FunaKi was Killed
IS: somewhere along the tracks!
Let's go!
How far-are we goingtogo...
There's nothing...
Tia "aw
Okutani Station soon
We 're~going-to:reach
Okutani"Station.soon...
We're goingrto.reach
Okutani Stationsoon.?.
I'm sure we'll find something...
Isn't that Mr. Funaki'sy?
The actual murder site is here!
But.how...?
Excuse me, did anybody come on
this bridc e between 10:00 to 10:30?
What about a.camera man?
Yeah, at about 9:50,
he came from the direction of the dam
and went down the steps
that you all just came up
that you all just came up.
Did anyone cross this bridge after that?
Not one person until the police cars
ame and this place got boisterou.
Early in the morning Ms. Ayukawa
came and went down the steps. though...
Ms. 'Ayukawa did!
Yes, at about 7:30. I think it was.
She came back after
about 10 minutes though.
So, Ms. \ ukawa did come after all.
T how...
Conan, I just remembered,
We gotta return the boat.
We gotta return ithe boat
Genta. you said that you saw
Ms Ayukawa go up opposite Kutanisuji.
But which side of the lake was she on?
She was on the left when viewed
from the lake. so maybe-this side?
After climbing back-up from this side,
in order to throw a.stone at Mr..Funaki
from right under the bridge that is opposite
the bridge
she would have to cross
this bridge once.
But... the guard says nobody crossed.
But...the guard says nobody crossed.
But, if he was killed here.
Why was his body found where it was?
How was it carried there?
He fell into the lake and
naturally drifted to the shore there,
where he came to and climbed up.
He then passed away...
No, Mr. Funaki's body was not wet,
and he wasn't using a boat...
It's unnatural that hispbody was
where it was after all.
But, I'm certain that he was killed here!
Conan.
We're going tobe charge extension fee
if we don't return the boat
We're going to be charge extension fee
if we don't return the boat.
What method was used?
Conan. the,boat...
Y.Yeah, ljknow.
Are we going to ride it to the boat house?
I guess so.
Genta*Shall we throw this:away?
What sf that?
We pickedlitup.
Where?
Around the place where 'Kutanisu;
merges with the main stream.
Oh! That handkerchief....!
What's up»
That handkerchief is Ms Ayukawa's.
What?!
I see. I got-it!
The winner for the contest is
Mr. Takuya Masubuchi
with a total of 30500 grams!
Ms. Sonoko Suzuki will present
the championship trophy on
rehalf of the chairman.
Please give her a big hand everyone.
Any comments... rs
I was lucky to have beenrable to
fish at a good spot.
Ease give wera -1g an: everyone.
If you're the killer I promise
I'll find evidence to nail you...
The winner of 2nd place is
Ms. Saori Ayukawa
wit Ya totaltof 22680 grams
Anything to say?
I was hoping for two
consecutive wins but...
§ unfortunately I've lost to Mr Masubuchi
I would like to take that
big cup home with me next year
Let's give the two winners
a big handjonce again!
We would like to conclude
the - 17th Suzuki Cup Lake Okutani
Tournament. Ladies and Gentlemen,
thank you all so very much.
Fueeh
Aaagh. she's doing the same thing
as the Sleeping Kogoro!
What?!
Please wait, Ms. Ayukawa.
I still have something
I'd like you to tell everyone
I'd like you to tell us
why you killed Mr. Funaki...
Huh 2!
What?!
What?! You mean Ms. Ayukawa
I'd like to know why you did what you did
at this tournament where I'm serving
on behalf of the chairman.
Come on. please tell us!
Just what; do you think you're saying?!
She was in Kutanisuji on the
opposite side of the lake back then.
That's not the point...
Because Mr. Funaki was not killed
where he was found.
What?! That can't be!
Conan, please show her the stuff.
Okay
We found this camera
beside thewrailftracks of Kutanisuj.
This is Mr. Funaki's camera.
He took pictures for us
yesterday so I remember!
What?!
The camera of the victim was
found in Kutanisuji...
But. why was it in a place like that?
We found it under Kutani Bridge!
And these are the pictures that
were printed from the film that
was in the camera!
Were printed from the film that
Hey!
Oh#yes, sir...
There's a picture of a trolley there, right?
The place that picture was taken from...
The place where the leg of Kutani Bridge
touches the shore,
a very small flat area.
I asked a railroad buff and found that
the place is famous for getting
the best shots of the trolley.
Ms. Ayukawa,
I hear that you were invited by Mr. Funaki
to have a drink with him last night.
At that time you gave him
information of that place
when he asked you for information
on where he could take pictures of
the trolley for a railroad bufffmagazine
B.But Mr. Funaki was found
3 kilometers away,
opposite the steel bridge.
I just said that's not the point.
Inspector Yokomizo,
didn't you notice the black stain that was
on the vest that Mr Funaki was wearing?
Now that you mentioned it...
The forensic officers reported so.
The substance seems to have
been oil and soot...
Yes, it's the exhaust of the diesel steam
engine that pulls the trolley along.
Exhaust?!
Mr. Funaki moved from under Kutani
Bridge to the place he was found...
On the roof of the trolley
What?!
Huh 21
Carried on the roof...?!
You threw a rock at Mr. Funaki
who was waiting for a chance to
take a picture of the trolley.
The rock hit him on the head
and he fell on top the roof of the trolley
from the impact of being hit.
Then carried on the roof of the trolley...
he crosses:the bridge
until the: sharp. curve
where he is flung off the roof...
and his body thrown to the place
where it was found...
S.Such a coincidence exists...?
It's no'coincidence.
There is a train that leaves
Lake Okutani Station at 10:50
Ms. Ayukawa calculated it so that
Mr. Funaki would fall on the roof of
that train and killed him
Then, she knew ahead of time that
thelbody would drop where it did too?
It's most likely...
No way...no matter how much
he was off his guard,
that Funaki would never let
Saori kill him that easily.
If she dropped something.
Be it a rock or something
rom on Op 3 'fge...
the guard at the station at the foot
of the bridge wouldve seen it.
I confirmed with the security guard
and he said that no one crossed
the bridge between 10:00 to 10:30.
If so. Saori couldn't have
committed the crime.
It would look to be so for everybody.
But, this is a carefully planned
murder committed by Saori.
It can't be...
Because she told me that she was
in Kutanisuji, but opposite the tracks...
That's right. isn't it, Saori...?
Yes. But at'around 7:30 in the morning
the security guard told me that he saw
Ms. Ayukawa go down the steps
at the foot of that bridge.
Her going there at that time has
nothing to do with the murder, does it?
Conan.
Yes~~~Il
What's this?
It's just: wplain wooden board...
That's...a board that Genta and Mitsuhiko
who were on the board picked up.
They found it where Kutanisuj
merges with the main stream.
\ Ms. Ayukawa used that board
How 4
Ms. Ayukawa who-went there at 7:30
placed that board right above,the place
that Mr. Funaki wouldybe standing.
Half:of it. was suspended
in-air-and.balanced very precisely
so it wouldn't fall over.
She then placed a rock on the board.
At 10:07 Ms. Ayukawa appears at
the pedestal opposite the bridge
and threw a rock towards Mr. Funaki
who was taking pictures of the trolley...
Gyaah!
- 4 dd
That's just your imagination.
Do you have evidence to prove
that it's a fact?
Mr. Masubuchi, didn't you think
It strange that
Ms. Ayukawa was going to Kutanisuji?
I hear that Kutanisuji is not
a good {fishing spot.
Why did Ms. Aukawa who was aiming
for championship go there?
Besides the handkerchief that is attached
to the tip of that line is Ms. Ayukawa's.
You can find handkerchiefs
Iike that anywhere
Please check that handkerchief.
You should get luminol reaction from it.
There are no blood stains on it!
Ms. Ayukawa
when Ayumi hurt herself yesterday
you used that handkerchief, didn't you?
A slight amount of Ayumi's blood
should've rubbed off
on the handkerchief back then.
Of course there is no blood stain
anywhere onrit now.
But, Ms. Ayukawa,
do you know that once a handkerchief
Is stained with blood\
no matter how clean you wash it there
will be luminol reaction.
How long has it been since you washed
Ayumi's wound for her with it?
Ms. Ayukawa!
Why did you kill Mr. Funaki?!
He's been\blackmailing me
since 6 months ago.
10g,
Saon. .!
Six months ago,
a man called Mr. Kanie...
was found dead in the same place
that Mr. Funaki was found.
Mr. Funaki was probably
blackmailing you
because of something. to do
with that incident, wasn't he?
I had no intention of killing Mr. Kanie.
WwW. Which means you killed
that guy called Kane....?
Wetwere walking along Kutanisuj.
I have no intention of getting marned
for a while yet.
4¢So, you like Masubuchi after all,
don't you?
How about it? Please tell me straight!
Whaag~~~~I1]
Mr. Funaki saw what happened.
And he blackmailed you...
Is that it?
Ha.ha.ha...
I'll keep it quiet to the police, but
for doing that...
I'm in a pinch right now, could you
Iend me about 200,000 yen
This new model camera-costume
close to 1 . 000.000. yen
Yiou knowfwhatilimea
I paid him three times up to now,
total of 7.000.000 yen...
Then about a half month ago...
I hear you signed a contract
as a Pacific Sports Adviser!
How much was the contract fee?
T's none of your business...
Oh well...
Please give me 10.000,000 yen.
You know what will happen if you refuse,
don't you?
Since he told me then, that he
wanted to take a picture of the trolley,
I figured if I showed him where it is,
so he would surely take pictures
under that bridge.
As long as the timing.isiright,
the corpse would fall on
the roof of the trolley
and carried to the same [place
where Mr. Kanie's body was found
That's what you thought, is that right?
I figured if things went on as is,
I would be blackmailed
all my life by that guy.
Hen everything ahead of
me went black...
I'm really sorry that I spoiled
your important tournament.
More than for me. I think this contest
was more important for you. right?
I'm sorry..-Father.
Ms. Ayukawa, I'd like to hear
about everything
in more detail so please come
with us to the station.
Yes. sir...
Saori...
I'll: wait for you no matter
how long it takes
PS TY I
I'll wait for you no matter
how long it takes...
=o rend)
I'll wait for you no matter
how long it takes...
Saori...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
ducers.
MICHIHIKO SUWAy
MASAHITO Y@SHIPKA
,_¢L k
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Chara «er Designs By
MASATOMO SUD Q #
Story Editor.
KAN]; ASHTWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
CHI MIYAS
YU CHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Dir TOTS
MASATPMO SUDO
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director?
KENIkKODA MA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, TD
in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING:
- > » > \.
NS Re rs wd a. - ~~ 7
DETECTIVE CON
« COSHO AOYAMA / SHOCAKUKAN YTV - TMS
All Rights Reserve
« Sea =~ ~~~
Didnét you think lit was fantastic...
Sonoko's deduction.
You can say that again!!
Really. when did you check
all those things out?
W Well...you see...I've got my ways.
Its a cinch for me.
I wonder if I did something
so fantastic...
What do you mean you got your ways...
By the way, how 'd\ ou guys do?
Did you at least catch one fish?
1...U1...we...you see...
Catching bigKfishis-more difficult
then solving a case!
Next time IF come., I swear
I'll catch asbig one...
Isn't he Kazuki Kinukawa
the popular child actor
who acts in dramas and movies?
Wow. he's even cuter than
when.you see him on TV!
What's with this brat...
It could be that Kazuki's mother-is,
working here under a different name.
T. .This is?!
A mole on the woman's breast!
Yaaaaaaaah
(5 #R)
The-Little Client" Part 1
(as $5)