Friendship, Romance, Mystery
Because we cherish them
we can continue
The client is a famous child actor
The search for a mother leads to
a hot springs
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the 1. Q of an adult
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
If I get married. what are you going to do,
Kiichi?
So. you're going to get married after all.
I try so hard to stop you,
but you just won't listen.
Dad...
Why you
Agh!
Aaagh!
Ah. Pops...
Dad!...
Hey. Dad. are you listening to me?
Shut up. be quiet, will you!
This is Yoko's best scene, you know.
Kiehi, I will never forget you...
This is the scene of the beach in Atami
where Kiichi and Omiya appear
in the story "Konjikiyasha. right?
Just how many times
are you going to watch that video....!
Agh!
Hey. Ran!!
Never mind the video
Tell me why you refused
Mom's invitation to go eat together!
Oh, yeah...
11/!
That day's inconvenient for me
May I ask in just what way is it
inconvenient-for you?!
Who cares!
I mean it's not that she's dead or
anything and we get to see her anytime!
Konjikiyasha...
Was never completed because the author
died while he was still writing the story...
So the two characters in the series
Iost their way to happiness)forever...
Iost their way to happiness forever
In our case...
We're going to see. it through...
and make it, no matter what...
I hope you re not thinking...
of trying to get Eri and me
back together again, are you?
Of course I am!!
It's only natural for kids to want to live
happilywith both their parents. isn't it?
That's nonsense
Huh 7!
There are people who abhor even looking
at their parent's faces. you know...
And. I'm one of them...
What's with this brat...
Huh?
You sure look familiar...
A.are you by any chance...
The child actor that is famous for acting
in dramas and movies,
Kazuki Kinukawa?
Y.Yeah. I am...
Wow~=~You're way cuter than
you look on TV!
And? What does that famous brat want
with our detective office here?
I want you to look for somebody.
I want you to look for somebody...
A woman called-Atsuko...
whowkeeps sending me
postcardssike these...
TA NA
(BJ #)
The Little Client Part 1
TA RA
(BJ #)
It's true that
all there is here is the name of the sender
and no address.
Wait a minute.
Aren't these fan letters?
It's full of comments about
the dramas and movies that you acted in!
She seems to} be
a really great fan of yours...
She's sent you postcards
once every month from spring
two years ago to winter last year...
But all of them are stained
and wrinkled up...
You should*putthese away nicely
if they're fan letters
You should put these away nicely
I can't help it, can I?
They gave me the.creeps so I just kind of
Ieft them lying around...
Give you the creeps?
Because they're not fan letters.
They're postcards from my mother...
Y.Your mother?
Yeah...
They're postcards from a stupid lady.
Who 6 years ago.
Abandoned me in front of the door of a
church as if I were a piece of trash...
Oh...that's why you mentioned not
wanting to see your parent's face...
But if you want us to look for her, it
means that you want to see her after all...
Don't get me wrong.
Huh
I just want to see the lady and give her
a piece of my mind!
I want to tell her not to claim being
my mother at this point just
because I'm famous now!
Ha...ha.ha...
Oh...
It's amazing how you,figured out
It doesn't say so anywhere and yet...
4 I can tell!
Because the name and the handwriting
on the postcard are the same as
they were on the memo that was
Ieft with me when she abandoned me...
Looking for her is not going to be
easy though...
The postcards are stamped from
different places,
gr -- .
all the way from Hokkaido,to Okinawa
You can tell that she really
Iikes to travel, though...
Oh...
Never mind then
I'll go look for another detective
that will search for her
I think that your mother's in a hotel or inn
some place in Atami
Where is it written?...
Look at this postcard.
There as something
that looks like the hand and head of
a statue on the bottom part, right?
Doesn't this statue look familiar?
Hmm. . Oh!
Hmm. Oh!
Now that you mentioned it,
It does look familiar
Mugh...Mugh, mugh...
Oh. I see! It's this!
It looks just/like this'pose...
Which means it's probably the statue of
Kiichi and Omiya at the beach in Atami!!
She probably:-used the top part of
the postcard set
which is made:;up of four postcards...
Phooey...
It could be that she used something
that she bought as a souvenir too...
But, there are three other postcards
Iike it too
And they're all the upper left ones?
If she's, rich enough to travel to
Jinns throughout Japan,
I think she would send
all four types of,postcards and
I'm sure that postcards of other places
would be mixed among them too, right?
Of get it!
I think your mother didn't want you to
know where -she wast
kn wswheredshe was,
SO she sent only thegpostcards
because they're the ones that are
the hardest to tell
that thus as the statue of Kiichi and Orniya!
She probably used postcards
that remained after everything else sold
out from the shop at a hotel or an inn!
Then she probably gave it to the guests
that came to stay,
asking them to send the postcard out
after they returned to their homes.
I see!
People from all over Japan
come to hotels or inn,
if we check the hotel roster.
We can figure out where they came from!
Which means
your mother is an employee of
hotel or an inn...
Um. why don't we take a drive to Atami!
Either way!
Well, I don't see why not...
But if we find her,
I hope you're, goingsto pay the fee?
Yeah...a whole lot!
Unlike that lady. I'm rich...
Come on. let's go and get it over witht
My schedulejgjopen
only today and tomorrow...
Nast kid...
You're kind of like Conan...
Huh? How dare you...
No, I have no idea...
We don't carry postcards like these here.
I see...
Thank you very much.
Ghads...
We come all the way to Atami and...
We're sweating it out here
without even going to a hot spring...
Maybe a postcard didn't suffice
as a lead after all 7?
Uh, Ran...
Carry me please!
Oh, if you're tired,
I'll piggy back you.
I want to be carried!
I want to be hugged'.not piggy backed!
Hey, you...
My goodness...
Talk about spoiled...
This is just about where
that lady/has a mole...
Huh 2
I remember going to sleep and seeing)
he mole in front:of my eyes...
Oh.dbut I was much>smaller back then
so maybe it was further down...
Hey. hey. further down means...
Uh, will you carry me one more time?
O-Oh=okay...
You don't hayverto:do that
because we already have an idea
aboutwjust where it us...
But. I want to be sure. .
You don't have to! We already know.
A VOL LOA 0 elf Xe?
You mean this postcard ?!
It was a:limited product that was
onlyrsold. here
but this set of four postcards
didn't sell too well...
so having no other choice
we divided it among ourselves...
since we couldn't return it to
the publisher either...
Wow! It's just like you said, Conan!
Uh. please excuse me:for asking
this inappropriate question but,
IS there a woman by.the name of Atsuko
No...there's no person
by that name here...
Oh, is that right...
\, o0'\
U.Uh...are you by chance that famous...
Ohwyes... Detective Mourn...
Kazuki Kinukawa?!
Huh /
My. just as I thought!
Come over here, Ms. Bessho!
It's Kazuki!
H...Hello...
Strange
and she's a fervent fan of yours...
I wonder if she's shy...
And? What's up today?
Did you come to spend the night here?
Ohx:well, the thing 1s.
Kugh. kugh. kugh...
I'll bet you came to look for her.
Your mother that...abandoned you...
H-Hey. who are you anyway?!
A.guest. you hear, a guest...
I'm Kamoshita the one
who reserved room 205...
I came here just to check things out
but I guess it's my lucky day
to have the entire cast out here today
This is sure going to make a great:story!
How come he knows about the mother...?
U.Uh...
Will you be spending the night here?
Oh, well...
Uh. why don't we stay?
Maybe Kazuki's mother is"working/here
under a different name.
Phooey .. I
I don't needi'you to telll me what to do
I was planning to stay.anyway!
Good! Then,
I can stay a while longer with Kazuki!
Y Yup
Uh...okay, then. Ms. Saegusa!
Please show them to room 308
where we had a cancellation...
Yes,...
This is room 308.
The yukata (pajamas) and mattresses
are in the closet so help yourselves...
Hey. hey
cantfyou be a bit more explicit...
Quiet!
We're so busy as it is that we can't be
bothered with extra guests you know!!
Don't push your weight around
just because you're a bit famous!
Phooey!
Is that the attitude to take
towards guests?
You gave me your word, editor...
Keep a page open for me, okay...
If this isn't duff gen. the book will sell...
Because it's about the number one
kid actor. Kazuki Kinukawa's father
being a killer...
Ah. I'm really full ..hic!
Oh, goodness. Thanks to you,
we end up taking a bath so late!
You drink too much beer...
Sigh... Huh?.
What's the matter?
Oh: itrsithe lens cap of'a camera
Kamoshita..
Isn't this the guy we saw a while ago?
Now that you mentioned it...
I'll go give it to him!
I'm sure he said
he was staying in room 206.
Oh... Hey, Ran,
sleet him be! He's so weird...
I tell you, she doesn't give a hoot
about anything I say
bout anything I say...
Guys and gals get to go in together?!
I hope somebody*s inside.
Todd
Silly, at this time of night,
I doubt anybody is.inside at all...
Huh!!!
Whoopie!!
Kyaaah!
Oh, good evening.
Huh
oh. 4well... excuse me...
Please come inside!
Being able to take a bath with Kazuki
will be a memory of a life time!
Oh. but...
Quit being a prude...
Oh...I just noticed that all three of you...
have a...se « mole...
Do you always take a bath at this time?
Yes... because we wait till
all the guests are done...
By the way,
where's the girl that was with you?
H...my daughter Ran
went to Mr. Kamoshita's room
to deliver something he dropped...
Kyaaa!!
Ran?!
Ran... MN
Ran. .!
Don't tell me that guy had the nerv ton
Hey, what's up?!
T That.
- - VY
He drowned?...
No...the trace on his neck shows
that he was strangled...
Hey look! A cell phone's on the floor.
What?!
A picture seems to have been saved
ust a while ago...
Don't tell me the killer's picture is
This is?!
A This is?!
A mole...on the woman's chest?!
I see...so,
I see ..80.
you picked up Mr. Yasuhiro Kamoshita's
camera cap in the corridor...
you picked up Mr: Yasuhiro Kamoshita s
and delivered it to his room, where you
found Mr. Kamoshita dead. is that right?
Y...Yes...
Just as Mr. Mouri had said...
it seems he was .choked with
a thin string:like thing
780;
was the body put inside the bath tub
to complicate specifying t
he estimated time of death...?
But, the killer could not deceive me,
Kogoro Mourn!
Just what do you mean?
It's in this camera!
Oh!...
Inside Mr. Kamoshita's cell phone...
Oh. wait...
Ont...
Oh, uh...l don't think...
you should say that yet...
Huh? Why not?
Huh?
You're the one who appears on TV a lot...
I'm Kazuki Kinugawa.
He came withflus togthis inn
because of some personal matter!
Oh...
So. you kiddies go back to the room.
Okay!
Inspector Yokomizo!
According to the people of the inn,
According to the people of the inn.
Kamoshita called/one of the waitresses
and said something weird!
Kamoshita called one of the waitresses
Kamoshita called one,of the waitresses
and said something weird!
Kamoshita called one, of the waitresses
Kamoshita called one; of the waitresses
and said something weird!
Kamoshita called one of the waitresses
and said {something weird!
Something weir...
Somethin: weir...?
Somethin¢ weir...?
He said, "If 20.000.000 yen sounds
familiar to you. come to my room
If you don't, I'll disclose everything...
Hmm... don't have any idea
what 20,000,000 yen is about,
but Mr. Kamoshita must've had
hold of something
but Mr. Kamoshita must'vé had
10) QF SOREN)
the waitress wanted to keep secret
If so. it's like we already have the killer!
We can look at the picture 1
n his cell phone!
We can look at the picture
n his cell phone
All we have to do is find a waitress
who has no alibi at thetime the picture
in here was taken!
Oh!! This is indeed a picture of
the murder site!
See, it shows below, doesn't it?
Il.'-+()...
There is a mole on the chest
of the woman
who is choking Mr. Kamoshita's neck
fromibehind...
Ghads! Bummers.!
No doubt about-it!! The killer is a woman
with a mole on her chést. Mr. Mourn!
Oh, true...
Oh. true...
Huh'...
Which means the killer is
The killer is my...
Agh...
IP nil
Aah...
Kazuki?!
Kazuki?»
Wipe yourself...
Kazuki, where are you?
You came to this inn to look for
Kazuki Kinukawa's mother...
Yeah... The clue to his mother was
that she has a mole on her chest but
I didn't think that there'd be a mole
on the chest of this killer too...
I mean, it's obvious. isn't it?
The mature is. rtawe and the face of
who really took this picture?
The picture is static.:and the face of
the killer is conveniently not taken!
It could be that the killer took
this picture deliberately
and rigged the time and date on it
to create an alibi...
I don't think so
Huh?
Not him again
Because the killer has the string
around the man's neck
and is pulling the string with both hands,
right?
The killer can't press the shutter
with both hands full!
If the killer took the picture,
I think the killer would.wear clothes
so that you can't tell
if it's a man or a woman!
The killer probably didn't know
that a picture was being,taken!
Right! Pops?!
Y. Yeah
Why did Mr. Kamoshita have
his cell phone on him
when he was being attacked
by the killer.
Maybe he was talking to somebody?
Then, why don't you try
the re-dial button?
Why don't you keep your mouth-shut...
Agh!
It seems he was talking to someone
10 minutes before he took the picture!!
What?! Kamoshita was?!
Are you serious, officer?!
Yes...
If you don't. mindfil-d like you to give me
your:name and tellkme: what you do...
I'm .1Zumiya, the editor of
Weekly*ot" magazine.
Kamoshita is a writer who brings us
a lot of scoop articles.
He called to say
that the woman with the scoop story
came to his room a little after 23:30.
Pi] nw
Hejsaidjthat the woman is taking
a shower in his room no"
and to not worry
because he'll make sure that he takes a
picture of the woman with 'his cell phone.
And who is this woman with the scoop...
The mother called Atsuko,
who left the kid actor Kazuki Kinugawa
in front of the door of a church
when he was a baby!
She seems to have been a devil
threatening Kazuki's actor's agency
to dish out 20,000,000 yen yen if they
didn't want her to publicize the fact
that his father is a fugitive
for having killed somebody.
Although-the agency didn#t really believe
her story at first.
She knew the name of the church
as well as the characteristics of
Kazuki's body in detail,
so they deposited the amount
into her account...
Since allitheif dealings were
carried out by e-mail
he had no idea of what
she looked like or how she sounded...
Kamoshita,
who smelled that there was a scoop.
Wentstointerview her in-person.
That's why he brought up
the 20.000.000 yen
to see if anybody would come up. front.
Inspector!
The waitresses that have no alibi
after 23:48 are here!
You a
You ar
Oh...hello again...
And? What do you want with us?
Did something happen?
There was a murder...
A person called Mr. Kamoshita.
Who was staying in this room
was strangled...
What?!
Oh, no...
No joke 7?
I'm going to have to check
your bodies a little bit...
Like the killer whose picture was taken
when she killed Mr. Kamoshita!!
Hey, wait a minute? Are you telling us
to strip naked right here?
What?!
Oh... No
of course arwoman police will be here
and you'll be checked in another room...
O, Oh, okay then...
Then hurry up and get with it,
because we still have work left to do!
There's no need for that!
See! I have no mole.
MH. Hey... Ms. Bessho?!
Right...it's not like we're going to
Iose anything so why not.
Oooooht!
Go on! They're going to suspect you
if you don't, Ms. Kusano!
Oh. all right...
Oooh...
Cool it: Pops...
Huh... 7? (
Y. You have a mole on,your chest!!
Take a good look. will you!
My mole is on the opposite side 4
when compared to the picture, isn't it?
CA Rooo
Rather than checking on our moles,
why don't you go check the fingerprints
on the murder weapon
You found it, didn't you?
The-black string that was in the picture
a while ago!
Oh, well...
Oh. well...
We've been looking for it for a while...
but we can't find it anywhere...
The black string that is
thought to be over 1. meter...
Right. the problem is
the murder weapon...
and that mole...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
() cf C { or : S
MICHIHIKO SUWA7
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUD ONO
Chara «er,.Designs By
Story Editor.
He'll Je)
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHTWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
MATTIE al J) be 1 UR wk .
mAsllxro/wit) sumo
. «Dd ,
44 tA
AR SU D8 FEE QA TI VS
TAKA "HI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
4  44
Editor
TERUMITSU OKkSDA
Chief Director
KENJI-KODAMA /
S ENT : TAINMENT 4
in association with:
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPOR TON
DETECTIVE CONAN
« COSHO AOYAMA ll SHOCAKUKAN -YIV - TMS
All Rights Reserved
What?!"He came in?
Donny tell me you peeked into
the woman 'stbath?
I see...so that's the story
Kazuki?
The sound of my mother...
Huh 2!
I get it...
Which means that the most suspicious
person is the one who tried to hide it...
The-Little Client Part 2