Liar...
Thief...
S.Sonoko...?
All the programs for today have ended.
Thank you very much
for your patronage
Sigh
W.What's the matter, Sonoko...?
You're the one who wanted to
come watch this thief movie, right?
Part 1 was really good so I expected
this one to be even better...
But, they're just doing
the same thing over again?!
Talk about a meaningless Part 2!
O.Oh I see
I kind of enjoyed) it
Kind of isn't good enough!!
Well,
most second editions are like that.
How I wish that somewhere,
an incident
so incredible would make my heart
beat so badly that it would
erase all the sounds around me!!
S.Sonoko...
SSonoko...
Come-to think of itl haven't seen
that guy around recently...
Today's suspect is Kaito Kid.
Even if you fool everyone's eyes,
the jewels and dreams will be protected
He sees through the one and only truth,
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
This is what I wanted to see...
Huh?!
Huh?
Huh?! Hey!
Huh.
Hey! Wait up. you!!
When you bump into people
you're supposed to apologize!!
H.Hey. Sonoko...
Sonoko, your bag...
Aaaagh!
M.Mugged?!
What?!
Sonoko. stay here!!
I'm not going to be ordered
around by that glasses boy...
Agh! Hey. wait!!
Huh /
Go get 'im. Lupin!!!
I.Lupin?
Whaa!
Grrr
SS. Stop it...
S.Stop it...
Huh
=r LS
Thief Kid's Wondrous Sky Walk"
Ow, ow, ouch...
Phooey!! How dare you snatch
the bag of a fragile lady,
you!! I'm going to write about you
In a corner of my biography!!
Ow. ow. ow...
Hey. young lady, hurry and
contact the police, please.
Oh, yes! Thank you!!
\ ] ~~
Thank youitoo~ doggy!
Well,
even if Lupin here were
to let him get away,
with my Ultra Classic
1500 cc Twin Cam model
function rigged to this motorbike too...
Hah, hah, hah, hah!!
Uncle?
Aren't you Uncle Jirokichi?
Huh? Oh! You're Shiro's daughter!!
The last time I saw you, was at
the Seven-Five-Three Festival!!
T.They know each other?
Looks to be so.
He's my father's cousin
and advisor for the Suzuki Financial
GroupOPUncle Jirokichi Suzuki!
Gah: has ha...
H.How do you do?
But, uncle when did you come here?
I heard that you went out.on
a trip since 6 months ago...
I just got back last week...
I went the world over and finally
found it so I came back...
The best bait in the world...
Bait?
Fuh, fuh, fuh...
There are so many!medals
and trophies here!!
The European Golf Open,
The US Cup yacht race
and worldwide fast
hamburger eater contest!!
And. all of them are first prize!!
this oldkman's won
the Savanna Rally too
Wow, check this one out!
Around the world on
a man-powered plane!!
The pastime of a rich man...
Huh 2?
Was this statue here from before?
Yeah, it's
the Golden Goddess that was decorated
on the bow of the Sea Goddess
during the Grand Navigation Era
when the pirates used to raid ships!
That thing that she is holding
up in her right hand is
the legendary aquamarine,
which is said to have turned
Into a gemstone fiom
the tears of a mermaid
It has the power to
event disasters at sea
and is known as
the miracle of the ocean
Blue Wonder!!!
It is valued very highly
as an artistic work
and I had a hell of
a time bidding it off.
I finally got hold of it last week...
Then,
don't tell me that this is the bait
that you mentioned just a while ago...
Exactly.
This is the bait
To fish that guy!
Fish what guy?
Its been 72 years
since I've come to this world...
and there is not one time that I,
Jirokichi has ever let a prey go in my life
I've gotten every award
that I've gone after
and realized ever dream
that I've ever had...But,
there Is just one thing in this world
that I just couldn't get a hold of...
That.-guy
slips through the tightest security
and the most armored vaults.
He is 2 white sinner who magically
breaks through everything in his way
4 en - «
flying off into the night sky...
H.Hey. wait a minute...
Don't tell me that you're referring to...
Yes...his name is...
The Thief Kid 7?!
Making a declaration to the Thief Kid!
The big jewel that you;so-desire,
The miracle of the ocean'.
thas-been placedson-the roof of
If .yourwant it come and?get it
Adviser for the Suzuki Financial Group.
Jirekichi Suzuki.
Wow!!
- \ 10 declaretsomething like this on
the front pages of the papers
Rich people sure are something.
But... it's a bit exciting!
YouilFool!
He won't show up.
A super rich dude is sending
out a challenging
. demand like this full of confidence!!
Who in the world would fly right
into a trap that is so well set up
Exactly...
But. Sonoko was saying.
That just a while ago
er nce Iro Ic 1 go
and okay mail'from the Thief Kid
on his cell phone.
O.Okay!?
W. What?
WwW. What?
It seems
that he's going to come to check 4
the place out this Saturday or something
See. here's that mail
She forwarded it to my cell phone too!
Let me see.
I shall respond to your challenge.
I will go to get what I want
April 12th at 20:00.
owever, re ore. a p ease orgive
me for going to check the place
out on the night before.
Thief Kid...
He sure has a way of putting
on airs like always.
Uh, what's the PS after the mail...
Huh. post script?
Huh, post script?
Just asstheinamohast ita-
I shall walk over and appear...
H.He's going:to 'walk over?!
Fuh. fun, fun.
Fuh. fuh. fun.
Just what're you doing?!
Never mind. Get on with the check,
go ahead and check!!
Make sure that all the roads
eading to this museum
are blocked and officers
are standing guard
Don't let one suspicious
thing get through!!
Understand!!!
Ghads!
Those choppers sure are noisy
Huh 2!
W. What?
You don't know how you should
Identify the Thief Kid 7?!
Pull on his face! His face.
His face!
What?!
In.Inspector!?
Not softly!
Strongly. like this!!
Firm and tight...
Understand!
Inspector Nakamori...
IS really into this...
rr ns os I
Huh 2!
So. Sonoko!!
Aha, ha. ha
ta flashy appearance....r
Hey! Hey!
Did Thief Kid appear already?
Nope...not yet...
This man with the slight
mustache is Ran's father.
The Sleeping Kogoro!!
S.Slight mustache!
I've heard a lot of rumors about you...
OO. Oh is that so...
ey!! Are you the one...'?
Who started this riot to begin with?!
What?!
Do something about
your helicopters up there!!
They're in getting in the way
of the police choppers!!
There's no need for
police choppers is there?
The Thief Kid announced he was
going to walk over here after all!
Huh
Then why do you have sO many
helicopters up there like that?!
Those helicopters are up there
to film my autobiography!
F.Film an autobiography!
WwW, Wow
It's like a outside broadcast
van of the TV station...
The helicopters aren't
the only ones shooting the film
All the images that are filmed by
the cameras that are set in 100 places
all over the museum
can be viewed here!!
H.Hey!! Hey!!
There's nobody inside the museum!!
What?!
There were too many up to now!
Since there's nobody there,
even if he were to
disguise himself and sneak in there.
It would be plain for all to see right?
Since it's possible to open and
Iock all the doors
of the museum from here
even If he were to get to the roof
where the Golden Goddess is
the most that he'll end up
doing us get locked up...
That is
if he shows uprjust
as he said he would!!
Gah, ha, ha. ha...
Ont!
Huh! ?
I think he's here...
What?!
W Where?
Oh!!
Huh 2!
Can't we get a larger view?!"
Over here!! Right here!!
H.Hurry it up!!
Y.Yes: sir!!
So, he's appeared...
Thief Thief Kid!!
Hey!! Which one is it?!
Kyaaah!!
Which helicopter
My darling Thief Kid
Is the image coming from?!
He came, he came to see me
Which helicopter is shooting the film?!
I tell you, Sonoko...
SIE rt rultt eimai nprisc ui,
I think
B.Behind the museum?!
Okay!!
In the back!
Oh!! C,Conan?!
Oh! C, Conan?!
W.What shall we do?
Shall we move the Golden Goddess
inside using that device,
just In case.
Come on!! Cool it!
He's just checking the place out
tonight...He won't steal it yet!!
Besides. he announced
he'd come on foot...
Hey!!
"Hey, 'haven. "
Outta the way!!
Let's watch how the
great thief, thexso=called illusionist
under the moonlight
will make his appearance...
H.Hey!!...
W. Where is the Thief Kid?!
Well,
after he went across between
the buildings...he hasn't come out...
Come on out... Thief Kid!!
You can't walk unless you
come down on the ground.
Come on out... Thief Kid!
Huh
W.What the?!
N.No way~! No way
Wow~~~!Darling Thief-Kid.
He's floating in air.
Fantastic!!
No way! That can't be!
A human being defying gravity
and floating in the air is impossible!
Don't be deceived!! This is a trick!!
Thief Kid is
just riding a black
blimp or something
with his body suspended
Nn air with a wire!!
Any helicopters that are nearby,
film his head and confirm!!!
C.chopper # 7 here. There's nothing
above Thief Kid's head...
WwW. What?!
Thief Kid sure is amazing.
Don't you think.so...Ran?
Y.Yeah...
Nugh. nugh...
Chopper #7 here!
What shall we do?
Don't move fromuthere for a while...
Roger!
Nugh. nugh...
That Thief Kid, just what kind of
trick is he using anyway.
There's no way he can float like that.
Look for the rope.
Fuh, fun, fun.
Already making such a big fuss.
The show's just begun.
If he's not up there...
The side?!
I get it!
The wire is hooked on to the
buildings on both sides
and he's suspending
himself with it!!
Okay
Il go to the building on the left.
SO you go to the one on the right
and look for the wire on the roof!!
Y Yes sir!
Darn!!
That Thief Kid!!
How dare he play around
* - my e-
Phooey. it's nothing more than magic,
plain illusion...
Just you wait, Thief Kid...
All I have to do is see
through your trick...
N.Nothing?!
There's no wire anywhere?!
There's nothing 'here!!
T.There's no wire anywhere...
Inspector Nakamori!! There's nothing
on this side of the building either...
It can't be?!
Then how the hell is he up there...?
How is he floating in air...?!
E-hem!
Ladies
an... er emen...
Wow!
So. on this day before my actual
feat will be carried out,
please watch to your heart's content
the miracle that my legs will perform...
He's walking!
Huh 2!
H.He's walking...?
WwW. Wow. he's walking.
This is chopper #3, Thief Kid is
still walking in air...
It can't be...
What kind of trick is he using anyway...
Huh-21 H Hey.
My darling Thief Kid is walking!!!
WwW. Wow...
I see, so that's what he meant by
he'll come on foot to get his target...
Detective Mouri, never mind that,
but please tell me.
How is he performing this feat
that goes against all laws of nature...
This is chopper #3.
Thief Kid is now walking over
the skies of Shiodome Park...
If he goes on as is.
He will reach the roof of
the Suzuki Museum where
Blue Wonder is
in less than a minute...
Aaaah...
Thief Kid will reach
the Blue Wonder in a few seconds...
U.Uncle...
You mean we can't do a thing
but just watch him steal
the stuff right before our eyes?
That Thief Kid...
How is he planning to flee,
when there are police officers on
the ground and choppers in the air...
Advisor,
don't you think it's time
we start the device?!
We've got no choice...
0. this will be all for the show
the night before...
I will see you again tomorrow night
at 20:00 at the same place...
Darn!
Didn't I tell you?!
That you're going to be sorry if you
underestimate Thief Kid!!
Nah- Iiwon'tilet him steal it...
Because I went all Over the world
to look for it and finally got hold of
the "Miracle of the Ocean
Blue Wonder...
Why is the Golden statue inside
and moreover, upside down...?
This is how it's rigged...
fl SEQ,
It rotates so the real one is
exchanged for the fake!
Phooey...
Thief Kid will see through a childish
thing like this right away...
Of course I don't intend to:deceive
him with something like this...
If so, leave everything to
the police tomorrow
And keep your helicopters from flying.
Stay put and stay still
m doing just-the. opposite...
The opposite?
He vanished saying let's meet at
the same place tomorrow night...
If he so wishes, I will do exactly
that and ambush him!
Uh...what do you mean
by ambush him?
I'm going to rent practically all
the buildings in this area and...
be prepared for him with
a helicopter squad
and security guard unit even
greater than tonight's!!
I don't know what kind of trick he's
using to walk floating in air but...
If he dares come out again
I'm going to nab him
and add him on to the final episode
of my autobiography.
Whaaa?!
Huh?!
Huh 2!
D.Don't, move!!
Don't move!!
Stay still!
Kugh kugh. kugh
WwW. What's happened?
Never mind and just don't move!
If yo move you'll never
walk before me again!!
W,Where...Where.is it?
Don't you dare:move.
Bow -wow
Whaaa!!
Oh, there it is!!
W. What's with this dog?!
Woof
Just as expected of Lupin
He will never let a prey
that he is after go...
Woof woof.
Contacts?
I didn't know your eyes were bad,
Uncle Jirokichi?
Well, at 72 years,
all parts of my body are refusing
to work the way they should...
Your body seems to be
working just fine...
I would at least like to nab him
while I'm still alive and kicking
What makes you want to pursue
Thief Kid as much as you do...?!
Kid,
Thief Kid.
The sound of that name itself.
The one who stole everything from me,
that Thief Kid...
I'll never forgive him...
Listen,
I, Jirokichi Suzuki will nab him!! I wonst
Iet anyone get in my way!!
I won't:let your have your way.
Kid, just you watch!!
I promise, I swear...
the many honorary; gifts and
awards-l have won so far...
They veralways covered
the headlines of the papers!
All except for one time...
D.Don't tell me that's
why you're going after him .
Yes, exactly!!
That Thief Kid not only stole
the headline from me
he also stole
the 2nd page from me!!
My article of having flown
the world over on a manned plane
was pushed over to a corner on
the 3rd page because of him!
Do you understand
how humiliated I felt!!
Can you understand how sad I felt!!
A bit, I guess...
When I do get my hands on him...
I. Suzuki Jirokichi will be once again
be the center of all media attention!
Aha! ha! ha! ha! ha!
Ha ha ha...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
FProdacers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA?7
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Chara {er Designs By
MAfiAifOMé $1100»-
tULy . Qt
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHTWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
CHI MIYAS
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Dir TOTS
MASATOMO SUDO
sm HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
KIO KAWAMUR
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
In war 1
Chief Director.
KENJI- KODAMA
ENTERTAINMENT
In association with
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CON
x, COSHO AOYAMA §HOCAKUKANYIVJMS
All Rights Reserved