A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
His name is"Detective Conan
oh Ws TEA ws
- Wa Em Yh
Really look at the huge
number of helicopters.
More than the helicopters, the number of
onlookers is even more surprising!
They should've put up a KEEP OUT sign.
Uncle had them come in deliberately
because he wanted the arrest scene
of the Thief Kid
to be complemented by genuine extras.
Come to think of it, the advertisement for
introducing that large museum
as well as the special programywas
really flashy and filmed from the air...
But, wouldn't it be difficult
to find Thief Kid among this large crowd?
Don't worry,
he has special seats reserved for us!
Ms. Sonoko Suzuki,
we've been waiting for you...
Thank you!
Please follow me,
everyone to the seat over that way.
Hey. hey. is this for real?!
This is the roof!!
Wouldyou like anything to drink?
We'll leave it up to you...
For the first time,
she kind of looks like a richlittle lady...
This certainly is the roof of the building
near where Thief Kid appeared,
because the only ones here
beside us are the security guards...
I still don't understand.
I looked through the image
the helicopter sent afterwards,
but there was nothing strange in it...
Moreover, he vanished: in midair.
Just.how on earth didlhe: 27
Kyan!
I'll go get it!!
I'm sorry
A scratch?
It seems like something got stuck here...
And it's still new!!
Do.you see what I see?!
A-multitude off helicopters are
practically{covering the entire sky!!
And look at the many security guards
that are positioned all through the vicinity!!
This is it deed a handpicked
unit of security guards
that. the Suzuki Financial Group
has gotten together
with their heart and soul
to maintain their prestige!
Will he really appear under
such tight security?
The one who forewarned that
he would steal Blue Wonder
that is decorated on the roof
of the great Suzuki Museum...
Thief Kid!
He'll come, he'll come
of course. he'll come!!
It sure doesn't sound like a remark
that would come out of
the, mouth of a little lady
of the Suzuki Financial Group
whose treasure is the target of a theft...
But. he's the Thief Kid.wyou know!
/If just this once
I'd sure like to see himsin person!
I actually wanted to hold
the Golden Goddess statue
with a lot of gemstones on it
that is on the roof, but
Uncle Jirokichi wouldn't let me!!
Of course: he wouldrilt let you
Don't tell me you wished that.he would take
you away with him, gemstones and all...
Right. exactly
and Makoto would come to rescue me,
who is being held captive...
Il. Sonoko wouldn't know what to do @
with two men fighting over me
Har ha...
I guess all this abnormal security
around here can't be helped...
After all he declares that he is coming
to check the place out last night
and appears by the building
right besides this one floating in midair.
He walks in midair and closes In
Nn the museum...
Then. he suddenly vanishes...
I guess it's understandable, since he is the
great thief that they are all trying to arrest.
Really, he-was walking in midair
as though there wereyno.tricks involved
I'm sure that there are
tricks and magic.involved.
Huh?
Because if people can
so easily walk in midair,
it would:surprise the birdies. right?
B.Birdies=he says...
My. what a cute-thing to say. Conan.
Maybe the-remark was a bit too childish...
Phooey! Brat, let Thief Kid's magic
surprise you and the birdies!
H.don't Know what trick
he used yet, but the marks that
he left behind when he set up
the trick. may be found.
See! The scratch on the wall over there
Iooks as if something was hooked on!
The scratch is still new so it could be
something that Thief Kid left behind...
iawand + sdunanfntne ong ignited
Well?...
Huh? There's one over that side too?
Are you sure that there's a mark that
Iooks similar on the
building on your side too?!
Es, a brand new scratch...
But. I wonder what the mark is?
Maybe he hooked a wire up from
this building to the other?
Thief Kid probably did so to put people
under the illusion that he
was floating in midair!
No way! Inspector Nakamori who climbed
the other building last night said that
there were no wires or anything like that!
Besides, if he's suspended
from something like that,
he wouldn't be able to walk.
Oh right!
Hey. maybe he set up a device
to project a 3-D image?
And. that's what left the traces?
See, if he projected from two sides,
this side and that side...
Impossible. He couldn't have
done something like that
with the technique of this day and age.
It's impossible to project such a
clear moving 3-D image
In a space where there's nothing!
Then, do you know how
he carried out the trick, dad?
Sort of!
What kind of trick did he use?
When people think that something is not
there, they have a way of not being
able to see it because of the influence
of preconceived ideas, even if it's there!
reconceived ideas...?
And?
And just what is that something
supposed to be...
'l':
Wellsfor example...
A super huge hard glass!!
He placed it over one building
to the other and:walked on it!!
Inspector Nakamori
probably didn't notice it
because he didn't think
that the glass was there!
It could be that the scratch was made
when the equipment that held the
glass in place was removed...
If such a glass were there,
somebody is bound to have seen it!!
T.That's why...
In the first place, how would
he have brought something
as large as that along. and
then put it away as well?
T.That's why I said. It could be that...
Not being able to see it because
of preconceived ideas?
Kid. Kid, Kid...
In.Inspector Nakamori, so many
people are flowing in that
it's impossible to keep checking them!
It seems that the Suzuki Financial
Group passed out a leaflet saying,
Welcome fans of Thief Kid ..*
Passed out leaflets?!
If things are left as is,
a riot may break out...
It can't be helped let them through
without checking them!!
Roger!
He's probably going to come
from the sky anyway!!
Darn!! The security structure
of the police is a mess,
thanks to that attention-craving old man...
You're the owner of the Miracle
of the Ocean, Blue Wonder,
the advisor for the Suzuki Financial
Group Jiro Suzuki, aren't you!!
Indeed!
It's an hour more to go before
the time declared by Thief Kid,
but are you more than
prepared to take him on?!
It seems that he put on a
cheap magicishow last night
but tonight I shall be
the one to put on a show...
I'll show you all a dramatical arrest that
will make Hollywood movies
Iook like child's play!!
You seem so confident...
will make Hollywood movies
Iook like child's play!!
You seem so confident...
Gee. Uncle is-really out for the kill
Lets take a'short commercial break then
The new talk of the town that has opened
in Shiodome, bringing along with it
the fragrance-of history and culture
is the Great Suzuki Museum.
We invite you to come visit.
Hey, hey, even the commercial
is about the museum?
It's a tie-up. you-know, a tie-up.
Uncle never misses chances like these!
Even this-aerial film is abut and paste of
what he used in the special program
Though he may not look it.
He's quite thrifty!
Oh, please come quickly,
my dear Thief Kid
and please steal my
passionate heart away!
What's the use seeing him
a noisy placelike this.
\besides...the wind's so strong too.
Wind ?
What's the matter?
I'm going over to where
Uncle Jirokichi is for a while.
Huh ?
I just realized something interesting!
Just what is that interesting thing...?
It's arsecret!!
What?! Show you the film
of yesterday's Thief Kid again!
Yep, Mr. Mouri insisted that I
Iook at it no matter what...
Sonny! You watched it more than
enough last night, didn't you?!
Besides. it's already been sent to the staff
that are making his autobiographic movie.
What?!
Well. but the film will eventually...
be submitted to the police afterwards...
After all, Thief Kid has never come to
check any place out like he did last night,
ever before in the past...
Come to think of it, he's right.
I wonder why Thief Kid
put on such a demonstration?
It's less than a.minute to go before
the time declared by Thief Kid.
The Thief Kid fans who have gathered
here are starting to countdown!!
Let's all watch this
miraculous moment too!!
Phooey. he won't come.
Huh /
No magician would ever let
any viewer up on stage
before the show starts and
Iet them surround him
Because he would-be revealing
the secret of his trick that way.
Although he declared
that he would appear
again tonight between
those two buildings.
Where the eyes of all the spectators are
on him and the wind of the helicopters
are going to blow his hand
glider out of control,
he willinot appear!
Well, if-he's a long-nosed
goblin or a mountainhermit,
32, 9
it may be a different story.
Aha, ha, ha, ha. ha.
Huh 2!
T. Thief Kid!!
It's Thief Kid. He's appeared just now,
as he has declared he would!!
Kyah~! Thief Kid!
I\ll .
H.He's come!!
He's really floating in midair?!
It.It can't be. How and where on
earth did he appear from?!
Oh no. It's started to rain.
Cover the equipment!
Rain.
Hey. oh no?! Rain.
What a time to rain?!
Despite the sudden rain,
the call for Thief Kid goes on!!
Hey. what's the matter?
Chopper #7. hey?!
What is it?!
The image from chopper #7
was suddenly cut off.
This is chopper #7.
Everything's under control here.
The image probably temporarily
went static due to the rain.
0... maybe Thief Kid is making one of
his henchmen send out jamming waves,
and is up to something again.
Huh?! Does Thief Kid have henchmen?
Yeah. It is reported to be an aged man or
a young lady or a lot of other characters.
But it's certain that he has at least
one person helping him!
Hey. can you hear me all men in the
vicinity, this is Inspector Nakamon!!
Check on the double if
there is anyone among
the crowd that is holding
a jamming device!!
That person may be
Thief Kid's henchman!!
He's walking!!
Just like last night,
Thief Kid has begun walking!
Advisor, please tell us what to do.
If things are left as is,
he will surely steal the object this time!!
Phooey! I'm not going to let him steal
anything right before my eyes...
Put the Blue Wonder inside for now!
Yes. sir!
It's his intelligence against mine!
Scratch.
Preconceived ideas.
Wind.
Henchman.
I see. That's the story.
I've figured it out, Thief Kid!
The trick that you used to appear
in midair. walk and vanish!
I've also figured out how you plan
to steal Blue Wonder now too!!!
Advisor! We've completed putting
Blue Wonder back inside the museum!
Turn off all the lights inside
the museum right away!!
Huh?! All the lights
Yeah, he could be monitoring the
image within the museum, right?!
Hey. doing something like that is just
what Thief Kid would love you to do.
Then, Inspector Nakamori, do you have a
better idea on how to stop the great thief
who has appeared out of nowhere
as would a mountain hermit,
and close in on us walking in midair?
But just what do you plan
to do turning off the lights
of the museum and taking
the treasure inside?
In other words. the point is
preventing him from stealing it.
If the Miracle of the Ocean,
Blue Wonder stays out of his reach,
I win.
I'd like to make a proposal.
In exchange for giving you complete
command of this situation,
I would like you to lend me a few of
your men who can be trusted?
My men?
I'm accepting his challenge.
It's a secret strategy that
I stayed up all night thinking up
My dear Thief Kid!!
Shoots!
The helicopters have finally gone to the
other side giving me a good view of him,
and with the wind out of my way,
I get an even better view but
Too bad he's so far away.
Huh? What the...?
Huh? What the. ?
Thief Kid's less than 100 meters
from his object of target Blue Wonder!!
Hey. how're things on your side?
Perfect. I'm sure that your
strategy will outfox Thief Kid.
Shh!
He may be wiretapping us,
so that's enough.
There's nothing to worry about,
the tricks are more than well set!
All we do is watch how everything
turns out. ha. ha, hat!
Hey. wait a munite!
In.Inspector! There's something
strange about Thief Kid this time.
Huh, what is it?
You see something that looks like a string?!
Really?
Yep. a thing that looks like a thin
string is shining at his shoulders.
Hey. jhey. if that's true then
Thief Kid's not walking but
rather is being suspended
from the helicopter?
Isn't there something strange
about Thief Kid?
His legs are moving but it looks like
he's being suspended to something.
Hey. chopper #7 that is right above
Thief Kid's head respond!!!
Chopper #7, hey, chopper #77?!
He vanished. Thief Kid, just now
He vanished right near the museum!!
It's chopper #7 after all!!
His henchman that was
on board chopper #7
picked him up from within
the curtain of smoke!!
Hey. I hope all your
choppers are numbered?
Oh, yes, sir, near the tail.
All the choppers patrolling
the sky. do you hear me?
This is Inspéctor Nakamori from the
Metropolitan Police Department!
Thief Kid's on board chopper #7
with his accomplice!!
Report the position of
chopper #7 immediately!
Surround it until the police choppers
arrive and don't let them get away!!
This is chopper #14.
Opper verre 0 e wailing
at the main entrance of the museum!!
Okay!! Keep an eye on
it and continue pursuit.
Roger.
This is chopper #35, chopper #7 is
currently right above Shiodome Park.
Hey, hold it! Shiodome Park is
behind the museum. isnt It?!
Chopper #28 here, chopper #7 has gone
a long distance off from Shiodome
This is chopper #9.
I verify two chopper #7s in the
foregroOund of Shiodome Park!
Hey. hey. what the hell 1s going on ?!
Well...
The number "7" is written on almost
all the tails of the helicopters around!!
Thief Kid probably did this beforehand.
Idiot!! That can't be.
If such a thing were to be done, somebody
would've noticed when boarding!
In.Inspector!
What is it?
There are strange silhouetted figures
in front of the entrance of the museum,
not just one or two figures.
Huh
They're my subordinates that I let
into the building a while ago!
Don't tell me that Blue Wonder
IS In the case that
the officer in the middle is holding.
Hey! What do you think you're doing
It's like you're letting him
know that you're carrying it.
Hey! What do you think you're doing,
Iet them in nght this minute!!
Don't worry, sir.
This case is empty anyway,
and we're just decoys.
Decoys?
Blue Wonder was taken out from t
he back door of the museum
in a trash bag by Jiro Suzuki
disguised as a sanitation man.
Huh?
Fuh, fuh, fun...
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
What's so funny?
111181 'KT
What a crazy thing to say.
I laughed because I was able to ¢
protect that treasure from Thief Kid.
You fool! I saw right
through you the minute
you came to the museum
today on this motorbike.
It's the same today. but you didn't have
your goggles on, back then either.
It would be pretty difficult
for one wearing contact lens
to ride a motorbike without goggles.
The wind would hurt your eyes
and you'd be in tears.
That is, even if you had a windshield,
it would be difficult to ride a motorbike.
Well, despite being super rich,
the old man goes riding
around on this flashy motorbike
without any bodyguards.
You'd have had more
than enough opportunity
to put him to sleep somewhere
and switch places with him.
By the way, I took the dog Lupin
that was riding in this side car
to a shade in Shiodome Park.
I'm pretty sure he's still asleep though.
Because of the sleeping
drug you made him sniff.
Ha, ha, ha
how could I be Thief Kid!
I was right beside you when
Thief Kid appeared just a while ago too!
The same goes for last night when
he miraculously walked in midair!!
That was no miracle.
It's a simple trick that can easily be
carrie ou wi Yan assis an .
Although the men are efficient members
of the Suzuki Financial Group,
they're not from the police or the military!
It shouldn't be too hard to mix
one of your men among the
bunch of professionals that were
hired on a temporary basis.
You suddenly appeared last night
in midair between the buildings,
and brushed away our doubts about
you having been suspended
by something by making ashelicopter
past over your head.
After that, when the police and I
ran up to the roof of the building.
All you had to do was make us confirm
that there were no wires connected
between the buildings.
Since it would really make it look
as if you werelfloating in; air!
But.if. the.pilot of.the.helicopter.that flew
over your headwere your assistant.
It's super easy to explain!!
First of all, you fly on
board the helicopter,
over to the two buildings you'll
be using to carry out your trick,
and hook the tip of one side of the wire
onto the roof of one of the buildings.
Then, with the helicopter, you land
on the roof of the other building,
hooking the wire onto {
he roof of that building.
You connect the wires from
one building to the other,
then use the pulley that is attached
to your body, and move to the center.
Then you take off the black outfit
you were wearing together
with the curtain of smoke. and
dispose of it. Then Thief Kid appears!
Your henchman comes immediately with
the helicopter and flies over your head.
The fish line-like thin wire that you
connected yourself to the helicopter
with before; getting off.is:pulled
until it is taut and wound! up!
After.that you removed the
pulley from your+body:
and made the helicopter swiftly collect the
wire that you hooked onto both buildings.
As a result, it would look
as if you're floating in midair,
whether viewed from the top or the side.
Then, all that's left for you to
do is to pretend to walk
together with the helicopter
as it moves forward.
You used a tape recorder to
create the sound of footsteps.
Matching the sound
from it with your stride.
In order to deceive people from thinking
that you're being suspended.
You used exquisite body performance.
After walking a while, together
with the curtain of smoke
you abandoned your white clothes and
moved the position of the searchlight.
The helicopter pulls you up on board,
so it looks as if you vanished in midair!
Well, tonight's Thief Kid was
merely a walking doll
that caught the attention of the police.
You were probably just
pulling the doll in and
together with the curtain of smoke.
All it was doing was hanging in air,
so it was more than obvious
that it was just a doll.
But, you already climbed the building
that Thief Kid was on, didn't you?
If something was suspended
from the helicopter,
no matter how thin the string.
It would've been seen
No. because of preconceived
ideas and the wind!
Talk about wretched. The moment
the helicopter flew above your head,
I was convinced that
you weren't being suspended.
I was flustered when I didn't
find the wire on thelroof,
and didn't notice that string
But, the marks were surely
Ieft behind on the roofs of the buildings
The marks left behind by
the hooks that you used beforehand,
when the wires were
collected by the helicopter
But, you saw the image of Thief Kid
Iast night time and again, didn't you?
Although it also depends
on the resolution.
If the string is as thin as a fishing line,
you would have to be very near
moreover, view it with the naked eye.
It'd be virtually impossible
to view it on the monitor
The only way the string would show
is the DOWN SHOT image of Thief Kid
and the only one who could've filmed this
Is helicopter #7 piloted by your henchman.
If you sent the image that was used
for airing a museum special program
and you added the
image of Thief Kid onto it
and made it look as if helicopter #7 sent it,
the string wouldn't be there
That's why when it began to rain your
henchman stopped broadcasting. right?
Because on the aerial image back then,
there was no one using umbrellas!
The flashy stunt you put on last night
was to make everyone think
that you were coming from the sky
and loosen the tight
security on the ground.
You probably did so since you planned to
disguise yourself as Jirokichi Suzuki
and come through with no check
But. you goofed
when you came with no goggles on
and that image was on the TV screen.
No, it's not that I came with no goggles,
rather, I couldn't put them on.
Because my disguise would come off!
Aren't you worried about your comrade
that's on board helicopter #7
I'm sure the police have
surrounded his craft by now.
No need to worry, because
the police is probably panicked
They're probably flustered
by all the #7 stickers on the helicopters!
All the stickers?
I see... You stuck the stickers
of the real numbers of the helicopters
over the #7 stickers.
Uu wesic erso we rea num ers
were pasted on very lightly
so that the wind would blow them off
Yeah.Therefore, the pilots of the
helicopters go on board
unaware they would be mistaken
for being my henchman and chased
In the meantime. my comrade splits
amidst the commotion
Indeed the great escape of
the miracle of the vast sky. Blue Wonder
The vast sky?
The blue of Blue Wonder is
the blue of the ocean, you know.
It's the same thing.
The blue of the ocean is
the reflection of the blue of the sky, right?
It's the same as the detective and the thief
We seem as different as
are heaven and earth.
If we trace back to the roots
we both force open the door
to what people want to keep secret,
using the key of curiosity. We're both
nothing more than two rude men
You fool!
The sky and the ocean are blue
Aa wk
(ue 00a yl eren quai ies
of the dispersion and reflection of light.
They're not to be thought of as the same!
As proof of that, the water
in puddles is not blue, is it!
You got no romance
I can't see through the truth
chasing after dreams, you see
Are you really thinking of nabbing
me with that tranquilizer gun?
If I fall asleep at this speed,
we re going to have an enormous crash.
Don't worry, I won't shoot
until this motorbike stops.
And, as for your custody,
I already contacted Inspector Nakamori
who should be on his way here
Phooey, I'm not stopping!
Beside, remember what Gramps
Jirokichi was bragging about?
This motorbike is rigged with
an acceleration function!
See you...great detective!
I'll leave that treasure to you!
I wasn't after that treasure
to begin with besides
All I did was
take him on because he challenged me
DETECTIVE CONAN
CO GOSHO AOYAMA / SHOGAKUKAN YTV - TMS
AI Rights Reserved
You've got no dream
You've gotta be kidding... do too
I've got dreams I want to
realize too, you know
Huh? Uncle Jirokichisis
angry at Conan now?
Right
Why? Conan's the one who
protected the treasure, right?!
So, this is why
How dare he...that brat, to take
away the headlines fromime
If I keep believing. he'll come back
It can't be...
There;s something wrong!
It's impossible for her lover to
have killed her!
LHlusionary Spring Lover