Due to the off-season ghost
scare at Teitan High school.
Ran begs Pops to solve
the mystery of the scare,
but-he refuses, saying.that.it is nonsense.
Therefore, out of my consideration
for Ran whom I know hates ghosts .
decides to participate
in solving the mystery
After school, when we were
checking out the school building,
we find a desk that is very
inappropriately on the campus grounds.
My grudge...has not yet vanished...
(132 #h )
Teitan High School Ghost Story Part 2
I was on campus in the rain...?
I haven't gone, outside at all today.
3» HUN?
Besides. I was at a faculty
meeting while it was raining.
We were discussing the ghost scare!
By the Way. Dr. Nude!
Thanks to the health
crxcrrcuso you taught rm.
My back pains 'have gotten a lot better...
Oh I see
Hey. what on earth is going on?
Don't tell me that the
upper classman is lying...
No Way!
Somebody probably mistook
someone for him?
Why don't you ask Kazumi's friend
who is resting in the infirmary, then?
The ground is visible
from the infirmary because
it's right in front, so he may
have seen somebody. right?
No...beats me...
After I left you guys,
I was asleep in this bed here...
Besides...
See, take a 10Ok!
Even if you were to look outside...
it's virtually impossible to see anything
on campus from this floor. right?
What kind of'gardenswas the principal
thinking of making anyway . 7?
So. even if someone suspicious
was to be loitering
on the ground, I don't think
I would've noticed...
By the way Nwhereis:the: nurses
She left for the day saying
she was going to driving school...
She told me to hurry
on home and go to-bed
becausermyghouse
IS really close to school!
Afterithe wailingsin the storeroom.
Of the'gym. 1s the grudge filled library.
The cursed stairs, and now
the chair and desk on campus...
Poor Hosaka...
Um...
I heard that you were
childhood friends with Hosaka...
Yeah
I was with him from
elementary-to Jr. high
but after we entered high school,
I hardly got to see him...
because I gointo an accident
riding my motorbike as soon as
I entered high school, and was
hospitalized for nearly half a year...
Then, you didn't know that
he fell down the stairs and...
No, not until I was discharged from
the hospital and came back to school
And? .
Was there anybody who was all
worked up over this ghost bit?
Those guys who're making
a big thing of this ghost scare
are the very-ones who
probably made this all up and
are having their thrills
Iaughing inside. right?
What? You mean me'?
Ha. ha, ha. hopeless case...
One other person I can think
of that was making a fuss over
it is the guy confined in the art
room all alone drawing pictures.
Don't you think he's suspicious?
Even the guy we just
saw in the infirmary
IS JUSt as SUSPICIOUS.
Because the storeroom where
the.desk was is near the infirmary...
Moreover, if you use
this slated drain board
you can go directly out to the campus...
Then, the suspicious
nes are those two .
Not really...there's one more person...
Kazumi is also to be suspected!
Huh?! Why!
Well, if she went to the restroom,
it means she left the library, doesn't it?
Guess so...
Now that you mentioned it,
I wonder why she came when
we were checking the
storeroom of the gym?
It must've been by chance and besides,
If she did play-such a prank,
wouldn't she'have left for home?
Not really...
Before I went out to campus
to go 10 the desk with Dr. Nude,.
just a while ago, I went 10 the shoes
box to get my shoes but despite
the doorway and the school building
being wet with ran, I saw no footprints.
Which means that the person
making up the ghost scare is...
still within this school building...
Yes.
If the same person Is
making up all four ghost scares
it's extremely likely that this person
knows about the student called Hosaka
who accidentally died two
years.ago. as well as know a lot
about.the scene of the accident...
Hardly. ino:one, passes through,
this: corridor: after school-:and moreoverO
if the teachers-were all gatheredtin.the
teacher's room_ having a:conference...
whether it be from the
infirmary on the first floor...
the art room on the second-floor...
or from the third floor library...
the person could secretly
without being seen by anyone
carry the desk and chair out
to campus. It's not impossible...
The problem is, how were the
desk and chair placed there without
Ieaving any footprints behind,
and for what purpose...
There must be something involved...
A reason for causing the ghost scare...
Huh'...
I wonder what this is...
on top of the drain board.
It looks like traces of someone
having splashed water...
I wonder if ther were
water traces like this'
when we passed here a while ago?
D.Don't tell me that!!
Agh!
Conan!
If that's the case,
the traces of#it should be
somewhere.on the campus.
I found it! This is it!!
Gee whiz!
You're not-supposed to
go outside with slippers!!
To think that didn't notice how
such an easy trick was carried out...
But, this trick can be carried
out by any of the three...
In order to get the evidence,
although it's a bit reckless...
Uh, Ran!
Will you all wait for me
in front of the art room?
I've figured out a way to get the culprit.
What?!
Hmm. .H He's llate!!
How long does he
intend to keep us waiting...
Oh. there he is! 7
Where were you?
Yep. well...
I hope we're really
going to be able to figure
things out here, about
the culprit of the ghost scare
Huh? H.HEY! You glasses kid...
Agh...!
Huh
Hey l.thought I told
you 'not-to-come inside?!
Uh, are you getting ready to go home?
Jn, e070 $00 JORing) Ge - 7 Go gO homo?
Getting ready to go home?
Yeah, I have everything here
so that I can go home right away...
Hey There! Sorry to intrude on you...
S.Seko?! What brings You here?
This brat told me that
if I come here. I'll get to see
who. the one that's causing
He said that it may
take a while so to prepare
myself for going home before coming...!
My...
Same here
K:-Kazumi?!
Agh...
Aah. .
Your umbrella's all muddy...
Right!
I was watching the weather
forecast this morning and /
in my rush I picked anwold umbrella
that I used to use when I was a child
Cough, cough.
Hey. stop dusting mud off here!
And? Did you figure out
who the culprit is?
Nope. it seems the
show's going to start now...
) HH...
Hey...
are sure everything's
going to work out.Conan»."?
No doubt about it... after all...
That one's the culprit...
And?
Where's the one who
caused this ghost scare?
You said that we'd all find
out if we came here, right?
@onan...
\ l"!
That ghost scares rumored to be
the doings of the spirit of the person
called Hesaka who fell off
the stairsstwo years ago
and died, right?
Y. Yes...
The, stairs is the one near the art room...
If so, let's just wait forever very quietly!
W . Wait for what?
What else .
but for the ghost of Mr Hosaka to
come dripping wet down the stairs...
\...
Hey!
Kyah...!
Ow:/owi ouch!
Phooey!
Listen, we're trying to.-find
the bad one who-s trying-to
make everything loo like
the doings of the ghost!
Mourn
sorgyr but I think I'll head for home.
I guess I will too...
I'm leaving too...
I can't possibly concentrate on
drawing with you guys around...
It's only starting to get
interesting now. and then...
Thanks to the glasses kid
I can't seem O come up
with any inspiration. besides...
The fun of it all is disappearing,
so I guess I'll start hedding home too...
Sonoko?!
Oooh...
Sonoko!
Did the usual come?!!
The usual?
Oh, Sonoko.
Like my father, gets this way,
when she figures out a case...
No. the way she fell
jus NOW was Not normal!
Let me check her.
Oh no!!
A-h...
Don't touch me, okay?!
Huh
Because l... deduction queen Sonoko
IS about to start a deduction show now!
Oh, so it came after all.
Yes, I've figured it out...
the identity of the one who started
all this ghost scareywhile sneaking
and hiding behind the scenes!
As for you- I think you need
to hide a bit of something.
Talk about showing it all!
Sonoko... 4 our panty's; showing...
Sonoko... your panty"s showing...
Sonoko...yourpanty's showing...
Oh. my, I'm sorrk
Since I've figured out the
Wtruth. I seem to have
gone weak, and relaxed.a bit too much
Gee, whiz...
LAUSE (UL WU Eu Yun
to such a simple trick...
S.Simple...
Then, you've figured it out?
The mystery-of the desk and
chair put out on campus
without leaving any footprints...
The piece of paper on
the desk was not wet at all...
Right...that piece of paper...
I was thrown off by the
paper that wasn't wet
at all and had completely
forgotten about something.
Even if the desk and chair were
carried out while it was raining,
the footprints would
be erased by the rain!
The footprints may disappear but,
won't the piece of paper
on the desk also get wet?
If you don't want to get wet,
what would you do, Ran?
I'll wait somewhere until it stops raining...
Or, wear a raincoat...
Or...
N.No...
Right...
All the culprit did was cover the paper
so that it wouldn't get wet
using an umbrella with a long
string attached tot!
After it stops raining,
the string attached to
the umbrella is pulled and
the umbrella is retrieved
to the school building
thedlumbrella is retrieved
-t...
This wey; oO oof 8 eu oR
behind on the wet, muddy campus
This way, no footprints are left
and the piece of paper is still dry!
The traces were clearly
Ieft behind on campus...
The traces of the tip of the frame
of the umbrella touching the ground
when the string was
pulled to take the umbrellatinly
On the drain board that
is placed from the campus
grounds to the entrance
of the school building
there were traces of
water being splattered.
This serves as yet another evidence...
The water that was splattered
there was from the umbrella
that was retrieved and shook
to shake off excess water...
OO Ete off (FLEES WET.
But, that's not enough to
shake off all the rain water
The more time passes
the more water:sinks in...
Then,
then, the person who
caused the ghost scare was...
Could it possibly be...
Yes, that's right...
The culprit is the one
who owns the umbrella
that has rain water flowing out of it...
You... Kunishige Seko!
You were; slegpingtiin
the infirmary saying that
you weren't feeling good
just to carry out this trick...
The weather forecast said
that there would be a shower
from around noon to sundown,
but you didn't know exactly
what time it would be...
You carried the desk and chair that
were instheistoreroom of the gym
out to the campus grounds secretly,
covered the desk with an umbrella
with string attached to ittand went
back to the infirmary forlthe time being. «
All you had to do now is wait
for it to stop raining pull the string
and retrieve the umbrella.
B.But,
8.8111.
What if someone saw
the umbrella 6nithe desk .?
The campus ground cannot
be seen from the first floor
because the trees a e in
the way, and if viewed from
the 2nd and 3rd floor, it
would just look as if someone
IS standing in place in
the rain with an umbrella...
Then: do you mean that
the principal I saw was...
You just made.a: mistake because
the color.of the'umbrella was the same
as«the one the principal -who'used to
go. out into the:grounds everyday had...
Hey: hey:
you're going to call me the culprit
just because my umbrella was wet?
Since my umbrella was
really dirty. I washed it off
at the faucet just a while ago,
that's why it was wet
Besides,
if it's a trick like that,
Monobe and Tsukamoto
could've done it too. right?
» NO. you're the one!
It's interesting that if you are the one,
the answers to all the other
ghost scares fall into place!
The library of grudge,
the cursed stairs, and the wailing
in the storeroom of the gym, that is. -
the three ghostly phenomenon!
First for the library of grudge,
where the four books that Hosaka
had borrowed, being left out without
being put away for 4 consecutive days .
But, isn't THAT something
that anybody could've done?
If you look at the library card,
you can get the names
of the people who borrowed
the book In the past...
Do you remember
the title of the four books /
Huh? The title?
I think it was electric, something...
Theory of telecommunication.
Report of the Destruction
of Tropical Rainforests.
The History of the University System.
Analysis of Rock Destruction Sound"...
No ordinary person could
search and find these
four books that virtually no one
would bother to touch at all.
But, you, Mr. Seko, was
his childhood friend
and knew his hobbies very well.
Then, what about the cursed stairs?
$0 you're saying $eko 1s responsible
for the bottom of the stairs being wet?
It's there at the bott
of the stairs. isn't there?
The dent, in which to
put the fire extinguisher in...
Mr. Seko probably got ice ready and hid it
behind the fire extinguisher after school!
The following morning. he wanted
someone to find the water soaked
floor because of the melted ice,
which he prepared during the night.
That's why you: put'wax on the floor
right:beldw:the-dent. right?
You used the wax as
a water repellent. so that
it'wouldn:t. ook as if water
flowed out from the dent...
Mr. Seko, whose house
IS near the school is the
only one who could've
done.something like this .
I see...
He went home to get
the ice after school...
But. why?
Why would you, who used
to be Hosaka's childhood friend
do something like this...?
Depending on your answer,
you re going to get it...
The whole thing probably started with the
wailing in the storeroom of/the gym...
Huh?
The wailing that the
students who came for
early morning practice
heard was Mr. Seko's voice...
If Mr. Seko's ping-pong d Yalso
had early morning practice that day.
It's natural that he wouldsbe
in the storeroom of the gym.
Maybe he noticed Mr. Hosaka's desk
and chair for the first time that day.
It's not strange to think that
Mr. Hosaka's death was no accident...
Yeah-=that's right.
It-dawned.on me right away
that Hosaka was bullied and
killed-while I was in theshospital!!
What the 7!
You mentioned just a while ago,
that I knew what kind of books
he would borrow because
I was his childhoed<«friend: right...
Actually:'that's not it...
Those four books were
the books thatiiHosaka
brought with him when
he came to visit me everyday
at the hospital.
In. order to..Cheer me up
he told me about the
funny and interesting stories
he made up after reading those books.
But. he suddenly stopped coming.
I thought that maybe he found
a girl he liked or something.
I didn't think he had died of an accident...
After being discharged from the hospital,
I investigated on his accident
but all I found out was
that he fell from the stairs...
That is, until I found his
desk with his signature
on it in the storeroom of the gym!!
That's whyal wanted; to find the one
who hid his desk into=the storeroom...
I wanted to find the one
who pushed him off the stairs...
WwW. Wrong...
Hosaka didn't fall off
the stairs. nor was he bullied...
I'm to blame!!!
What 7?
That day, early in the
morning. two stone statues
were scheduled to
be delivered to school...
0th Hésaka and I were
weekly. monitors that day, so...
we secretly carried the two statues to the
art room early in the morning .
We were planning to place the statues
by the door to sunprise-the art.teacher...
But because we were rushing to set up
the statues before the teacher arrives
we went past the 2nd floor
art room to the 3rd floor...
Since Hosaka told me this,
I rushed to turn back.
And tripped...
and tripped...
Hosaka tried to protect
me from falling and
was crushed by me and the statue...
That's why Hosaka wasn't being bullied.
T That's a lie!
Then, why was his desk
put in a dimly lit place like that
and{ covered with dust?!
No matter how you look at it...
We didn't want to erase the signs...
that Hosaka was coming to
the same school as we were
man EE Val An 6 Lai ANAL aa.
His signature was written in pencil,
so If left as it would've
rubbed off eventually, right?
After the accident, the drawings of the
the faces of all 'his classmates was found
in his notebook..so we got sad...
and asked the teacher afavor... That is.
To put his desk out in
one of the classrooms
on the day of our graduation, so that
he canigraduate together with us...
At first the teacher gave a sour look...
but we asked the teacher
to let us keep the desk
and chair in the storeroom
of the gym after
the class collected enough
money ta buy them.
We should've told you about it too.
But we found out that
you were childhood friends
with Hosaka only after the ghost scare...
I see...
That's why you were
at the storeroom backithen...
Yes,
I thought maybe Seko might be
where Hosaka's desk was .
Then...
Then, he wasn tullied
or had a grudge on anybody...
NO...
If anybody, I'm the only one
he'd have a grudge against...
After all. I'm the one who
thought up that stupid prank too...
No...
I'm sure he holds
no grudge against you...
Well. Iawas the first one to be called
to the site of the accident...
Back then. he kept mumbling...
That maybe the teacher will be even more
surprised if he fell to the ground as is
Phooey...just as expected of him...
Original Comic Books By
I roducers
IE DO FF O3rdd 2.5-\
rm, O
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDQ~
Story Editor.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCH1
JUNICHIgMI ASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Dirc
MASATDMO SUDO
Loe re SLY, »
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHT KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJIsKODAMA *
Ir. TAINME
- Vg No § = ~~ Cy yy -
I... AdSHYUL IAQ vviuwn
' > » \
DETECTIVE CON
O COSHO AOYAMA I SHOCAKUKAN: YTV TMS
All Rights Reserved
Just as expected of you. Sonoko!!
Yawn...
Your deduction was+superb as always!
Y Yeah, I guess so!
Y. Yeah, I guess so!
Y.Yeah. I guess so!
I don't remember, though. like always...
Hmm...
But, what a surprise)
it was to hear that Dr Niide
heard the last wordsy
spoken by that student...
Oh, well
The truth is, he was in
no condition to talk at all...
But, I figured at that time,
it was best to say so.
To make those seniors feel relieved...
I couldn'tghelp lying.
Oh...
Dr. Niide, you're really so kind!
HUN og,
Well, what a relief
that there were no ghosts.
Yep! I won't have 10 worry about
being monitor next week anymore!
Okay. maybe I'll go talk to
the newspaper club about
my deduction and
give them a scoop article.
I think you shouldn't do anything.
There'll be no ghost scares anymore...
and besides. rumors vanish with time
« Nr - RES. o
Oh: I'm sorry. I've got an
important phone call.
Oh. we'll be 'on our way then.
Bye bye, Dr. Nude!
Hello...Oh... Yes,
(Niide here .
Oh... I'm happy for you...
PW that you got yourself smoothly into school
without anyone being suspicious...
s...thanks to you
Since you:told 'me how the imposter was
going-around"in school...
Then, this is thesdast time
I'll be calling You...
Forget me completely...
Uh. there's one thing I'd/llike to asksyou...
The person who was disguised as me...
You're a push-over. as-always, Br. Niide.
Was that person really...
Before the worrier doctor
takes me: to the hospital...
Thanks tr» the health
exercise\ ou taught me
my back pains<have gotten a lot better...
Was that person really...
Dr. Niide, you're really so Kind!
A bad erson?
Every time I get in touch with
the students or teachers at school,
he just doesn't seem
to be a bad person...
what a fool!!
What a fool
A.person who can.smile when Killing
someone can never be a good person!
All that woman.
Was trace your personality
in order to become your imposter...
And, she did so frighteningly accurately...
That's all...
No. there's got to be a way.
City Crows