Today's stage I's an ordinary
Lapartment complex
yooh
Is it-an,accident or a homicide
A blind spot that cant be
be seen easily
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case iskleft unsolved,
with) Detective:;Conan
Move it, You, get out of here.
You crows sure a nuisance, I tell you...
Shoots...Phooey:'there's not
much of anything here, rats...
A.Agh... 1!
City Crows
I think something happened...
I wonder what kind of case it is?
Hey. heyd no\.stand back...
Oh. what's with you kids...
Officer Chiba!
No...
T.That's...
A homicide?!
Homicide? Just as I thought!
How frightening! /
N.No. It's not a murder case,
its an accident
An accident?
Hmm...God .
It's true. someone is missing
Egami Tatsue, a grandma who
used to live here alone.
When she was coming back home
A flower pot happened -
to fall and hit her.on the head
That fell on her head?
But where did it fall from?
That dangerous isnst it?
Its not strange if it fell anytime
That's unacceptable, what kind
of {person is livingkthere?
Reom 4045: It's;the apartment. Egami
Tatsue lived in.
So that grandma got hit in the
head by the plant she was growing?
That is what we believe happened
That's too bad for that Grandma
It's true that its bad for her but...
Officer, Chiba, how was it?
The neighbors knew of those pots
They asked her to put the pots inside
but she didn't listen to them.
I see. so if she had listened, this! wouldn't
have happened because of crows
Crows?
Don't you see them??
They're everywhere
Don't you see them?
Since it's on the 4th floor,
it's' not likely that a stray ¢at did it.
One of those probably dropped
the planter with either their beak or feet...
Sigh... Crows sure are strong. aren't they?
I wonder if the ¢row is
really the one who did this? ,
, There aré no witnesses.
Since it was early in the morning
there seems to have
been no one around too.
Maybe someone who lives. /
opposite here saw something.
Agh?!
Right.:as you can see; it's impossible.
To. be, Killed..by-a. crow.
I'm starting to feel more
and more-sorry for granny.
There are people
making sarcastic remarks *
Iike a crow was killed by a crow.
A crow Killed by a crow...
It seems that: Tatsue Eue was called
grandmothericrow behind her back.
Grandmother crow?
She used to go out early in
the morning to make her. rounds
going through the trash
that other people threw out.
Moreover, she seems to have
always worn only black clothes...
That's why she was called,
grandmother crow, huh...
She had a pretty"bad reputation too.
They couldn't standsher going through
their-trash and invading their privacy.
There.even-seems tothave
been people who moved out. ,
She was disliked by everyone
in the apartment complex
But. why did she do such a thing
as go through other people's trash...?
Yeah. well, what'triggered it was...
My. how messy...
IV. a oo - -
The lottery ticket she found happened
to be one for 3rd place or something
So: she seems to h-"Ve
I thought she could find
Something valuable again...
«a That seems to have been the /
beginning of her reason
Ll for goingAnrBugh trash.
Dream come to me once more"...
She hoped. I guess.
They took on revenge on her because
she went around looking
Inte other people's trash.
Revenge?
The crow got mad thinking that
she was going to take away their food.
"What's why the crow
dropped the planter ll-see.
The crow took revenge
because it invelved food!
It's possible, because ¢rows are smart.
The old lady seems
to have made her rounds
of the trash dumps this morning too...
And when she came back to the
1st floor doorway in order to return
to her room, the planter
seems to have fell from above...
Uh? Isn't it funny?
The old lady camgyhome
from outside. didn't-sher
From that side then
this way. like this. right?
Then she was going
to enter that entrance...
Yeah...
I wonder how she came from
in front of the entrance. to this side?
Come tothink of it, you're right...
True. If she did go this way,
even If the planter
True If she did go this way,
even if the planter
Tue. If she did go this way
cven if the planter
came falling it wouldn't have hither.
The fact is, We thought thatiwas
strange too. the minute we got here.
The refrigerator which: was. put-outside
as trash...l mean. because one: of
her hands was inserted under it, and
she was lying dead-in a strange position....
But, we figured the reason out,
after we looked under the refrigerator...
1 any
In other words. when she-came back...
In other words, when she-came back...
and tried to retrieve her coin...
the mischievous crow...
dropped the planter...
Judging from the circumstances,
this is probably what happened...
Convincing.
I really feel sorry for the old lady
I wonder if, such a coincidence exists
She happens to drop her coin
and i. just happens towroll under
the refrigerator that is put out as trash
Right above her is a row of planters
are hned up And just as she
are lined up... And just as she
tries to retrieve her coin the crow
just so happens to drop the planter...
Oh...
Hey I cy 1 PE
-% Fy a
can't make it out to the roof... If
What's up. Conan?!
The only way it can be done
is from that room on the 5th floor...
Y.You re...
Ms. Imai... Thank you just a while ago.
Thank you for doing your rounds.
Have a nice day.
good morning.
O...Oh, good morning...?
Ayumi.-do you know her?
Well. she looks very familiar, but...
Um: she lives right above
that old lady's room. right?
Yeah, we asked her if she saw anything
during our investigation.
Does she live with her family?
No. I heard she was living alone.
But. is something about
her bothering you?
Nuhuh, I'll bet you
fell in love: at first sight with her
Po you likewolder women like her?
I wonder who she is...
I know I met her seamewhere before...
This 1s not an accident.
B.But a homicide...?!
If the crow hooked
its feet onto the planter
it would have fell
upside down or diagonally.
Naturally, if the planter fell on
her head it would crack to pieces...
But that planter was cracked
as if it had fallen bottom first
Which means
it came falling straight down...
In other words, the planter
was not hooked by the crow
but rather, removed from
the fence and dropped.
Only humans can do something like this!!
But... then who killed granny?
The person living on the top floor...
She's the only one who could've done it
She's the only one who could've done it.
I checked and found that
nobody can go out to the roof...
The one who can hang a planter
from granny's window is the one
who lives on the floor right above her...
No one other than her could.
Its true that you can't
do it from a lower floor
Please wait, Conan. It's true
that she can hang a planter. But...
You're going to ask why
granny was under the window, right?
Yes, because granny went there only
because she dropped her coin and
it rolled under the refrigerator...
In other words: it was a coincidence.
Right!
It's true'that, that part was a coincidence.
If so. your deduction
won't work out, Conan. because
your can't possibly bring your
target to the place of your choice
144 of )
Yes you can
How?
Well...I've been thinking
from morning. but I still don't know.
But, I'm certain...
Wrong. Conan!
She's not the kind
of person-who would do
a frightening thing like that. She's kind!
So. do you know her after all. Ayumi?
She wasn't wearing the usual uniform
&X AAU) ~~ IDA WE - >
but now I remember
If I'm not:mistaken:-she:works at
the bakery sin front of the station.
Oh.-:80, you're still in 1st grade.
Yep. I go to Teitan Elementary.
You're really fantastic
being able to run errands.
Oh. no, not really, anybody can do this.
Here you go. thank you, for waiting.
When I was in 1st grade,
I was kind ofrdense.
Same here... That's how
mostiofeus are in 1st grade.
Right: that's how most of us are.
I was so embarrassed, so
I haven: ttbeen to that. shopsince then...
She was nice enough to remember me.
I don't see how you can suspect
someone as nice as her.
It's not a very good to suspect people
right off the bat like that. Conan.
Ayumi!
Conan!
Aha. ha...
No matter how much you thinkO&™
here is no way to lure
the old lady to come
right below the window
The poor granny was accidentally killed
by a mischievous crow, after all...
No. there is always some way
Oh. hey. sonny. it's dangerous?!
Aha. could you wait a while...!
So. that's the story...
What's the matter. Conan?
I'vé figured out how she lured
granny to. go below the window
It's this.
What's that?
Don't tell me that this is
Yeah,
it's the thing that Grandmother Crow
wouldn't miss for the world...
Conan and the others really get me mad.
How dare they suspect
such a nice and'kind lady...
Agh?!
Gee whiz, they're still
investigating something on her!
S== 4
Excuse me, about that lady that
works at the bakery over there.
Gt?!
Oh. Ayumi...
You know..Conan how sad
do you think a person would feel
if sheis«suspected when
there's no proof?! Cut it out. already!
W.Well. you see. Ayumi
We've found the evid Thce...
Huh No.
Did you want anything with me?
Um, about yesterday...
Um. can you show me your lottery ticket!
You bought a lottery ticket yesterday.
Didn't you? Just one ticket
at the lottery ticket sales booth
near the bakery Please show me that.
You have it. don't you?
Please show it to us.
You have it with you. dong you?
It's okay. already \ umi.
Yes.
But...
It wasn't an accident that
the planter came falling and hit granny!
Although you insist
that it can't be. Ayumi...
the only thing thinkable is that
the lady living in that room above did it...
She hooked up granny's
planter and got hold of it.
Next, a long string was suspended, right?
Then you stuck the-lottery ticket
that you bought on the tip of the string
and put it by the entrance
and waited for granny to return.
When granny tried to
pick the lottery ticket up...
Noriko pulled the string...
When granny tried
to pick up the lottery ticket...
I don't think you could see granny's head
because of the over-sized refrigerator.
All you had left to do was
retrieve the lottery ticket, right?
The 500 yen was something
that you had put there
to begin with, to camouflage
an unnatural situation, right?
I couldn't figure it out at first,
but when the trash collectors
came a while ago
I noticed the traces of a string
underneath the refrigerator.
Moreover, the ripped part of
the lottery ticket was found there too.
the lottery ticket was found there too
With the torn piece of lottery ticket,
I'm sure we'll find your fingerprints on it...
It's okay, you don't have to go out
of your way to look for the fingerprints
But. why, why did you kill granny?
She made me look like a fool,
at the bakery I work for
See, see
Iiread your letter.
Af: What-allaugh this letter is. LooK at it
Why do you have that?
I ripped it and threw it away!
you're grandmother crow.
You got it from the trash.
Give-it.back'to me!!
Hah; ha: hadha,
just:.what do.you think:yousre doing. 4
Talk abolit being:scatterbrained:
I'mYgoing to enjoy myself
with-this letter for a while.
He's-ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha. ha.
It was a le ter of
goodbye fromimy boyfriend.
How cruel. I was trying to forget him
But she had the nerve to-go out of
her way to pick it up and laugh
about it on top of shewing It to others
But...
You're stilljlittle, so
you may not understand. But,
you'll eventually find out
that there are things that
people cannot forgive even
if it seems to be very trivial...
But...No matter.how unforgivable.
You're not supposed to take
other people's lives, Noriko!
You're right.
Will you please accept this.
I can't possibly take it with me $0.
ANY 4
pd . NO
What is it?
Wow!
I understand how sad you must've
been at that time even if I'm a child
But,
what's bad is bad!
Exactly, Ayumi
City crows . sure are sinners .
Original Comic Books By
Pr 0 du C e Y S
MICHIHIKO SUWA/
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KAT WO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO ~
Story Editor.
JUNIGHI 11OKA
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHTWAB/ARA
KAZUNARI KOUCH1
JUNICHIgMIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INDUE
Anima ion Dirc
MASATPMO SUDO
HIROT SHI TAKATANI
97, Naf
ATSUSHI AONO
Am?) KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Re ording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHT KOBAYASHI
LUIWOUIL ,
Chief Direct FE
KEN]! KODA MA /
I TS ENTE TAINMENT, ATD
- Sq yvre
YOMIURI TELECASTING
PORA
DETECTIVE CONAN
¢ COSHO AOYAMA / SHOCAKUKAN YTV - IMS
All Rights Reserve
the persomjust now was
that person we saw a while ago!
Whi¢h means...
The two cases must be different cases
with no connection to each other.
It can only be explained:
as a case of synchronicity.
If Takehike was really*Killed.,
it would have nothing
to do with the Béika case.
Right, everything fits in too well.
(BI #8)
A Case of Synchronicity! Part 1