Today's casetis a very oddone.
Identical twins arerkilled at the
same time in. different towns.
Such a thing is just not possible
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the l.Q. of an adult
No case is:left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
P.Please wait! Please!
Just a while longer....!
I've waited and waited all thisstime.
I can't wait any longer. .--
Ugh ugh +e
Ask your kid brother for help.
If only I could do so...
Ah NA
(51 %R)
A Case of Synchronicity! Part 1
Oh, what shall I do... What can I do...
. BREE ISR
Mania-room.
Yes...
Oh- Dad
Ohh, Ran...
Dad, what about lunch?
Do you think that you'll be coming home?
I'm still working
Okay; I'm going with Ran to the
Super Cheap All-You-Can Eat Buffet"
SO keep up your good work, Pops.
Shoots, t. the Super Cheap
Shoots, t, the Super«Cheap
All You Can Eat place?
He sure is taking his time...
Agh. don't tell me he got away?!
W.What the?!
He seems like a totally
different person from a while ago...
Ugh... (Oh. well.
Dad...
Oh, you two. What brings; you both here?
I mentioned it over the phone. didn't I...
You know...
Oh: it wasYover here...
Oh, I mean: this 1s
no time for something like this.
Excuse:me
Fm Minamisatoof room 1050.
In...40 you have something
for me from a Mr. Anzai...?
No. ma'am.
It can't be...
because I got a call a while ago saying
that it was definitely brought there .
Please check carefully once more.
We don't seem to have
anything for-you after all...
Oh...I'see...
It's good.
I feel bad for dad. though.
It can't be helped because he's working...
W. What the?!
A.A person.
Kyaah!!
What is it?!
A man fell.
Conan!!
It was'...the man
we saw just a while ago!
Which means that...
py, 4
This sucks.
This sucks...
and I was tailing him.
Shoichiro... Hitomi age 45.
I've been tailing him since this morning
However, please do not ask
me who asked me to do so.
What on earth happened?
Let me explain...
Kyaaaaaaah!!!
I didn°t want him to know
that: was tailing him but...
\ aaaaah Noooo" Don!
What's wrong! Is anything the matter .;!!
D.Don't tell me that?!...
Agh 7!
Are you okay?
You're...
Oh, oh...
S,Sorry...l don't know
what's come over me.
Just whatiare youstalking about?
Never mind that hurry and
get down from there!
N.No.
Please overlook this.
Agh!!
I don't know.
Huh..\.
I'd like to ask you"that "question myself...
H.He tried to attack you, you know.
What do you mean you don't know...
It's true! I really don't know who he is'!
Ms. Kaoru Minamisato...
Yes. sir?
That's the name that's
registered on the guest list
but. isn't your real name Kanako Hitomi?
but, isn't your real name Kanako Hitomi?
And, who's that supposed to be?
The wife of Shoichiro's
younger brother Takehiko.
No. inspector, I've seen
Kanako in a picture but
why did you think so?
When"! checked the history of
incoming calls on Shoichiro's cell phone,
the last personshée had
talked to was Kanako Hitomi.
Calls....? What time was it?
11:20.
Oh. if so...
He went in at 11:10
and came out at 11:30.
I guess, he called his wife from
¢ inside the toilet during this time...
Uh... may I be excused. now?
Yes...
Irm.sorry, I'd like to be left alone.
The name was Anzai. wasn't it?
Huh?!
You knew, the name you mentioned
at the front desksa while ago...
You know, the name you mentioned
Is there anything
for me from a Mr. Anzair...?
Ill know Mr Anzal...
Is anything wrong with that?
No...
What an outright lie to say
she doesn-t- know Shoichiro...
Maybe she really doesngt- know him.
No darn way!
Huh
What happened?
Pops. don't you think this is strange?
What is?
Because Shoichiro had
a cell phone, didn't-he?
Then why did he use the public phone?
Maybe his phone was
out of the service-area.
It doesn't seem to be so
True.
Mr. Mouri! Bad news!
W.What's the matter?
Ook at that TV over there...
This is thessite of the crime, Haido Condo.
The man who was killed is
It's T,Takehiko,
Mr. Shoichiro's younger-brother...
The same age... Huh?
You mean.... they're twins!
The estimated time of death is
around 12:15 in the afternoon today...
N.No way. 12:15 is the
same time that... .Shoichiro!
Huh? No way: :.Is something
Iike that possible?!
What?! Tithe one that asked
you to investigate on Shoichiro
was his younger. brother,
Takehikorwho: was killed at Haido?!
What!
And. what did Takehiko want you to do?
To check on his behavior.
According to 11akehiko, Shoichiro,
because of the fact that.
they were.identical twins
who looked exactly alike
may have been posing to be him
and doing fraudulent business...
Oh, and what did you come up with?
Othing definite yet...
However, it does seem that
he had a huge amount of debts,
and someone came after him
this morning too, demanding him to repay.
Which means
that Shoichiro came
to Beika Hotel because
he came up with some
good idea to pay the money back?
Synchronicity!!
W What's: with you,
shoutinglout.of the blue?
To think that the older and younger brother
who were twins died at the same time,
seems to be a coincidence, however.
Maybe that's not all there is to it.
Maybe there was something
more fateful involved there...
You mean that's synchro?
Synchronicity.
That's the theory that
psychologist Jung came up with.
You- know, maybe it's the same as
how we ran into you-at this hotel. dad...
I see. I guess you could say so...
There is a possibility of it
being a coincidence, but I wonder...
Right... but. everything fits in too well.
We've got to scrutinize that
two cases a bit more closely.
The;door was locked.
There are no signs: of the door
being forced opened either. %
Oh...
What an odd looking key hole.
Wawouldntibe easy to make a spare key.
Was he killed here?
AS you can see, thewindow
IS cracked from the outside...
It seems to have been a robbery...
Hmm .
someone who broke in to rob him,
it would*have nothing
to do with the case in Beika.
Could it actually be
a mere coincidence... after all...
You returned home
around 2:00 in the afternoon.
Saw your husband dead,
and called the police?
Yes, sir...
And. where did you return home from?
Beikacho.
Huh...
Beikacho?!
BBeikacho...
Is anything wrong?
Is this supposed to be synchronicity too?!
Uh, we were at Beikacho
just before coming here
Uh. we were at§Belikacho
Oh...l see...
Shoichiro fell to his
death from Beika Hotel
Huh
Sh.Shoichiro did:...
Oh no. is that true?
It's true
Could it be that you went to
Beikacho to meet Shoichiro there?
The thing is, we found after
checking the outgoing calls
that he made on his cell phone,
that he had called you
Yes...
Please tell us what he
wanted to talk to'y about &
JI ~OI1OIC.THIT CO) T1111 orice Cl =
that he wanted to make up
with my husband and asked me
to act as their go-between. . &@
with 'my husband and asked me
to act as their go-between...
Oh. make-up...
Yes... .the thing is.
Shoichiro and Takehiko had been working
at fathemws company for quite some time.
And there were times wheénithe subject
of who will be succeeding father'came-up.,
However, just about then,
father suddenly passed away...
Why is its ou. Why are you,
my kid brother, the president!
Don't ask me. it was in father's will!
Well! it's not that ll don't understand
;why he decided so. though.
WwW. What?!
I hear your wife went
back to her home country.
Didn't you realize that
she was onl after your money?
That's what father
based his decision on...
ugh...S,Shut up!
You're fired. Get out of here. this minute!
Shoichiro then started
a company of his own,
but it didn't work-out
either and went bankrupt
Ieaving him:deeply in debt...
The several nights ago...
I apologize: Please: I was wrong.
So. please...
No. I beg you. I. I need money...
Rhooey
Ii don't owe you anything.
Kugh
If only...
If only you weren't here...
I wanted them to make-up and become
the two brothers that I had know before.
Therefore, Just in case, I secretly
gave Shoichiro my cell phone number,
as well as the
spare key to the house...
On the other hand, Takehiko
thinking that Shoichiro being
as cornered as he was: may
scheme up something using his name,
asked me to keep an eye on him.
To think that both of them
would die at the same time...
Is this a coincidence,
or rather. some work of fate . ?
Uh. what did Shoichiro want
when he called you, Kanako?
She just said that
He-wanted-to make up ,
Rather. please. I'd like to know too.
Could you tell us more in detail
hat the call was about...
what the call was about 7?
Yes. sir...
Yes?
Is Tvakehiko in?
Yes: he is. would you like me to getthim?
No. never mind.
R.,Rather. I'd like to discuss
something with you, Kanako...
I'd like to make-up with
Takehiko, but I wonder
if you could act as go-between for us.
Really, my, that's great.
Yes. of course, I'di'beThappy to!
Will you please come
meet me at Beikacho then?
Where in Beikacho?
Beika Station at 12:30
in front of the wicket. Bye.
gikA
although I waited for quite some time,
Shoichiro never showed up...
I had no idea that things
would turn out this way...
Hmm .
I wonder if he.was 5
gplanning to-see her after *
he finished: what he
had:to:do at-Beika Hotel.
I guess so...
Only, that's if we believe Kanako's story
I don't see any reason why we shouldn't.
For instance
for her.to sneak? into: Takehiko's
house using that tree over there,
no matter how you look at it,
It's impossible for"her to do so.
I guess so,
which means that
it is a robbery case after all.
If so...
the two cases.are not related
to each other in any way
It can only be explained
as a case of "synchronicity.
But, just to be on the safe side,
Iet's check on Kanako's alibi too.
If Sh@Oichiro didn't die...
He would've met with Kanako and
they would both have d)perfect alibu,
This would exclude them from the
suspect list of Takehiko's omicide case.
But,
Shoichiro fell to his death in Beika...
And, another character Kaoru Minamisato
comes Into the picture
Although this case involved
a simple relationship between
two brothers and the wife,
the appearance of Kaoru
makes the structure of
the case even more complex
Karou Minamisato...
who on earth is she anyway?
But really: dofstknow who he is!
How can you say you don't know him?
He attacked you. didn't he. Shoichiro?
He must've hand a grudge on you
or jealous of you or something.
You don't know him. That's something
that is totally unbelievable
Just what do I have 10 do.
to get you to believe me?!
Please tell Us the truth!
It's true, I'm not lying
Why would IRlie to you after going
through something frightening like that!!
God. you tell me!!
Why...Why is this all happening to me!!
012°
The incident in Haido is a homicide
so Investigation will continue
but this incident can probably
be closed as an accident
Huh... is this a mere accident?
Well, it's true that the fact that Shoichiro
falling to his death was an accident,
but what about the fact
that he attacked Kaoru?
But what about the fact
Assault and battery...maybe
it's a case of attempted homicide!
Assault+-and battery... maybe
Assault-and battery maybe
It's a case of attempted homicide!
Assault and battery...maybe
it's a case of attempted homicide!
Even $0, the case is closed
through the death of the suspect
and when the necessary
papers are turned in.
Oh no .
Hmm, I'm sure shess
hiding something, though.
Wonder if she's
trying to protect someone?
I'm sure the press will pursue
this case though as-an odd case.
In which twin brothers died at
the same time in two 'separate places.
Maybe it's synchronicity after all.
Wrong. that's not it.
This is not a case of synchronicity.
The line that connects
Kaoru with the others...
If I can figure out what that is,
the mystery would be solved.
Why did Shoichiro attack,
rather, try to kill Kaoru...
{For what reason?
For what reason?
Original Comic Books By
MICHIHIKO SUWAy
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
[-oround: Music:
NATYUUV WINW
Character.Designs By.
V + 0 \
Story Editor.
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHTWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
1EVILY
TIOSHIKJ INDUE
Animation DircZrorss
MASATOMY) $1100
ATSUSHI AONO
KI KAWAMUR
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHT KOBAYASHI
fF 0.180) 1
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KENIIKODAMA
ENTE TATNMENT
In associatioh with:
YOMIURI TELECASTING
o>.» -
DETECTIVE CO
« COSHO AOYAMA ll SHOGAKUKAN- YTV - TMS
All Rights Reserve
\ 8aaaaah!
Dad. nab him.
Okay!
EEecerl!
Gyaaaah!!
Oops sorry!
It's the answer to solving both cases.
In other words, a frightening
perfecticrime was being schemed...
P.Perfect crime?!
A. Case:of SynchroniCity=-Part.2