Today's caselis:an unimaginable one
that has no connection what so ever.
One clue however,
solves the mystery perfectly
and connects the
seemingly unrelated cases.
WmHe.sees through the one and
only truthA child in appearance
with the l.Q. of an-adult.No case
is left unsolved with Detective Conan.
-e WT WE YE. e,, ~
Pop's Is tailing somebody.
A person by the name of Shoichiro Hitomi
falls to his death from the Beika Hotel.
At the samertime. his twin kid brother
is found killed by someone
Could this have been synchronicity
a so-called fateful coincidence?
Wrong, that's not it.
This is not a case of "synchronicity."
The line that connects
Kaoru with the others...
If I can figure out what that is,
the mystery would be solved.
Why did Shoichiro
attack. rather. try to kill Kaoru.
For what reason?
A Case of Synchronicity Part 2
Um, Pops about this picture...
What about it?
Ms Kaoru Minimisato
went to the front desk
after Shoichiro made the call, right?
Right.
Back then. what was it that Kaoru said...?
Huh? Uh.
Uh, did you receive anything
for me. from a person called Anzai...?
You're not going to ask
Kaoru about this Anzai?
Shutyup!
What seems to be the matter, Mr. Mouri?
I'd like to talk to Kaoru once more...
Agh, wait dad!
Pops!!
@h, w.who are you?!
\ aaaah!!
What-was that?!
I-think it came from Kaoruss room.
What?
Kaoru, Kaoru!
Kaoru!
They just fixed the door awhile. ago.
and yet gee whiz; notiagain
I have. no:choice
Kaoru!
Dad! Nab him!
She's still okay. get the ambulance!
I was going with Manabu Anzai
when I was living in the Kansai District.
We were also going to
get married. but 6 months ago...
I haven't had contact since...
I see
Well. I'm sorry to have suspected you.
I'm sure the man
was only after your money
Have you filed an offense report?
No. I wanted to see him and
confirm things-before doing.so
But, if you don't even knew where he is
Well, I came here because I was told
that he was seen in To « 0 somewhere
But, when I came looking for him,
I had no idea where to start looking
Other than! his name Anzai
realized that I didn't know where he was born
or where he"worked.
I didn't know anything. about him.
He didn't say anything
deliberately Which means
it's doubtful whether Anza
us his real name or not either.
The only clue that I have # *
IS a picture off him.
What?!
Maywerhave a look at 1t?!
I met Mr. Anzai on a diving trip. SO
I figured he'd be diving over here too...
So, I looked here and
there with the picture and
contact number of Beika Hotel,
Iooking for him but.
Agh~H He's!
What's up. Conan?
Pops. show me your digital camera.
OO. Okay...
See, it's him.
2° on
OR -=- ~11}
Please try to remember dad.
Wasn't there anything between
this man and Sheichino?
Hmm=NO...
Not that I can recall. I think.
Uh. where is that'? I'll tr,yand go there.
No. let us handle this...
I'm a detective so
I'm used to looking for people.
By the way. the man that attacked
you-arwhiletagoxwasn t he Mr. Anzai?
' In. vad J, UW am ke
Oh no... I, 1 don't know...
It's this man In the picture...
Oh. you mean Mr. Tanizaki.
Tanizaki...His name .is not Anzai?
Yes, I'm certain that this-is Mr. fT anizaki.
He was using .an alias after all...
Well, who knows if Tanizaki
Is his real name either though...
Mr. Tanizaki...
Rather. should! call you Mr. Anzau...
h...May I ask what this is all about
You know Ms. Kaoru Minamisato,
don't you?
W.Who's that? No. I don't.
Please don't play dumb with me.
I'm sorry, Shin-chan.
For:making:«you wait.
Oh, who is that lady?
Who is this man?
It's nothing. He's got the wrong person.
Hurry up and get in.
Okay.
Right~I just got mail
from daddy saying that
he'd come up with the money for us!
Oh... thanks, you're a life-saver.
It's okay. anything for you, Shin-chan.
I see
just as I thought...
I hate to say this, but I guess
he had deceived you.
I seefit'SYpot all there
is to it. One more man...
Whatever his Bme IS. Tanizaki or Anza
that guy is involved in this case...
Kaoru's probably not the only
one who'd been deceived by this guy.
Including the woman
that we saw a while ago
he probably deceived
several others more...
If Kaoru found out, she would indict him.
That's why he wanted to shut Kaoru up.
In other words...he has a motive...
Shoichiro and that guy are connected
to each other with the sports gym...
but.this can be brushed
away as mere coincidence.
Shoichiro's accidental death.
And Tiakehiko's*homicide
which occurred at the same time...
And Kaorru's assault and battery case...
I've got to figure this one out $8
after all Huh
WwW. Wait a sec...
I get it...so that's the story!
Ran.
What is it. Conan?
Props told me to tell
you to take3 pictures of
Pops told me to.tell
Vat] (tO) {E130 [of oflk- SCAT
Pops told me to tell
Voit rfl it Set
these diagrams because
he'll be using them later.
sud Bile
Mr. Mouri, everyone's here.
Yes. sir, thank you all for coming...
And, what is this?
What'reiwyou going to start?
I'm going to unravel
the mystery of the two cases.
Cases...
wasn't Shaiehirds case an accident?
Whether it was an accident
or had to do with synchronicity,
everything fit too well into place
In other-words
a frightening perfect murder
was being schemed...
P.Perfect crime?!
Yes, If it worked out
the way it should've...
Ran, is the monitor ready?
Yes.
To be honest, I was concerned about
something from the very beginning.
Despite owning a cell phone, Shoichiro
made a call using the public phone
in the lobby of the hotel. and-the place
was not even an out of service range area.
He did so because he didn't
want anyone to know who he was calling
Why didn't he want anybody to know?
He didn't want to leave
any-evidence behind. Just in case
he:had to justify himself and
the evidence would work against him.
Oh, and who was the person
on the other side of the line?
Most probably...
the woman who was staying at this hotel...
Kaoru Minamisato.
Kaoru::what were the contents of the
phone-<call that you received back then?
Well .that he received
something from Mr Anzai
and had taken it to the front desk...
But I was told that. the front desk
didn't have anything for me...
Why did he lie and make that phone call?
Because he didn't know
Ms. Minamisato's face.
Who didn't know...?
Shoichiro. That's why
he called Ms. Minamisato
Toconfirm what she looked like.
And...
Kyaaah!
Aaagh?!
He ambushed Kaoru, then attacked her.
However, I happened to be there.
Shoichiro, who attempted
to flee from the veranda. +
Whaaaa~~~aaa
But. why did he attack me,
who he didn't know at all...?
Because it would be
very convenient for the culprit.
Huh 7!
If.he didn't know you at all.
He would not have a motive.
In other words...
He would net be suspected either.
Uh...l don't really understand
what you re trying to get at.
Kanako, do you know
why Shoichiro called you
to tell you to come all the way to Beika?
Huh. $0 that...
my husband wouldn't find out?
No, he used you for his alibi.
To establish...an alibi?
Shoichiro 'has no motive to kill Kaoru.
However,
You:re fired, get out of here this minute.
He. has a motive to Kill Takehiko.
But, he could've established
his alibi any other way...
Yes. But the fact was. he had
another important purpose
It was to make Kanako
Ieave the house and make sure
that Takehiko was
at home alone After all,
it would be troublesome
to have Kanako at home,
iffhe wanted to murder Takehiko.
What . ?!
Please try to remember,
the call you received from
Shoichiro His first question was
I's Tékefiikoflrfr?
Yes, he is.
He wanted to know where Takehiko was.
Andhe made sure Takehiko was home,
he 'went on to say that
he wanted to see you .
Can you comeioutito Beikar?
Okay...
In front of the station at 12:30. See you...
He called you on his cell phone
from the restroom of the gym.
I'm pretty sure that there was
one other person near him at that time...
Shoichiro probably
checked on the whereabouts
of Takehiko, as well as lure Kanako out...
Ran, can you display the
relationship connection diagram...
Okay
At first glance. it looks to be a case
that is complicatedly interwoven. but
If we omit Kanako. who was
justiused to carry out the murders...
Hmm, it's true it starts
to look way more simple.
But, who is that character
to the lower right?
Tiheregs Shoichiro who has
murderous feelings towards
Takehiko and as for Kaoru
the man over there...
who uses an array of aliases had
murderous feelings towards her.
I guess we'll just call you
Mr Anzai for now
Murderous feelings that would
never had intersected and
a plan to carry them out was
established, when Shoichiro and you,
Mr. Anzaprencountered
each other in the restroom.
A.plan for exchange murder!
You must've really panicked Mr. Aza,
when you succeeded carrying
out your part of the deal,
and Shoichiro goofed,
on top of getting himself killed.
Because of this, you ended up
having; to kill Kaoru with your own hands.
Therefore, you head off
to Beika Hotel in/person and ==.
Ma. ha,
An exchange murder?! Say what you like.
Ws SN
Do you have evidence, though?
Some kind of definite proof?
Dad...
Well, of course,
that's an understandable remark.
Inspector Megure, were
you able to find the thing
iln.question in the vicinity
of Takehiko's residence?
Yeah, it came out of a trash can...
Of a nearby park.
Oh. that's the key to our house...
Kanako, that's the key that you
gave to Shoichiro, isn't it?
Yes.
Strangely enough, this key was
not found among Shoichiro's belongings.
He had given it to Mr. Anzai Since
he had no intention of getting"it back,
SO maybe it's more appropriate
to say, he gave it to you...
As foriyou, Mr. Anzai, although you used
the key to-go into the house, figuring that
it would:only serve as evidence if you have
it on:you, you decided to throw it away.
Why was the window cracked. then?
Of course it was just to make it
Iook .as if a robber had broken in.
There was no meaning for him
to leave the key back in the room,
so:he locked the door and left.
Amazing how you deduced that far.
Lease think back to where
Mr. Takehiko was lying on the floor...
It was night by the front door, wasn't it?
If the window had been cracked first,
even though Tlakehko
was in the living room,
he would've headed for
the study to check out what happened.
However he in fact, heard
someone come in from the front door...
He ran into you; Mr: Anzai
as yourcamerin, and was: Killed.
Phooey. did you find any
fingerprints on the key or what?
No, you must've wiped;,it off
before getting rid of it.
It deesn"t matter either way.
If you have no-evidence,
sorry. but I think I'm leaving.
Then: how about something like this. Ran,
can you take out the picture please.
Yes...
W. What is) it?
Looking for a mistake.
Will everyone here look very carefully.
The picture to the left is Mr. Anzai
before he goes into the restroom.
The picture to the right is
Mr Anzai when he comes out.
Agh! The key!
You have no way out at this point.
Admit your/shameful deeds.
When I was shown the
picture at a diving shop
used to frequent,
shivers. went through my spine.
I somehow: made it through back then,
but when I thought of the time
that Kaoru eventually finds me...
It was: just around that time...
Ugh! Damn, that Takehiko.
He can just drop dead for all I care...
Ugh, he can just drop dead...
How about it? What do you say
e commit exchange murders...?
Even if we do get caught,
we would have no motive,
and besides. we'll have a perfect alib...
Let me sleep on it.
I've gone as far as tell you this much,
I really don't want you
o refuse this offer...
- - He was not all for it to begin with,
but after I convinced him
that we would never be caught,
he decided to do it.
So. you're the one who
talked him into this after all...
By:theiway, Shoichiro seems
to have repented after
realizing what a serious
crime he had committed
Brn sorry...
I don't know what's gotten over me.
Please forgive mel!
He was probably cornered to no end.
That:s-why he was conned
into going along with your plan.
A disgusting crime. You're really
going to have to make amends
Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Pro dzfcers.
MICHIHIKO SUWAy
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUD ONO
Character: Designs By.
VOY DRY DY
Story Editor.
JUNICGeHHTI I1TOKA
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHVIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCH]1
[UNICHLZMIYASIWTA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOU
MAS Yip . SPPO
HARD OOGCGAWARA >
AKI KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
{I rLurtar.,
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJIsKODAMA
I T™™S ENTE TATNMENT, ATD
In association with:
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATI N
DETECTIVE CON
O COSHO AOYAMA I SHOCAKUKAN-YIV IMS
All Rights Reserved
After his-face was seen in the newspapers
people-claiming that
they were-:victimized came out
onerafter the other.
He must've been-a real villain.
Villainzis: just enough to
describe-his-abhosrence.
Thatisswhy he comes up with
Th ideallikerexchange murders.
Ihwonder if this was
a case of synchronicity toe
Huh
Because the fact that dad was tailing
Sheichifo. and dad bursting inte thé room
Shoichiroz'and dad bursting into the room
when Shei¢chire attacked
Kaoru were alllicoincidences. right?
You gotta remember when Kaoru
was attacked by that man too...
that if I didn't say let's go back,
she would-ve been in serious danger.
I said that Pops!
Oh, well. who cares.
I wonder ifithis=issynchronicity too...
What:is-Conan?
Whenever Pops successfully
solves a case,
we're coincidentally always blessed!
What!
Dad...
This is all thanks to
my wisdom and chance...
Dad!!
Aha, ha...
You got a catch!
- ab > -
[£1 IQ)
Mr. Ejiri?!
(33 bf)
Tragedy at a Conspicuous Pier Part 1