The stageafor today's episode is fishing.
A breakwater out at sea in clear view
But, a murder is committed
without anyone noticing
He sees through the one and only truth
Achild in appearance
with the 1.QYofgan adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective €@onan
-- WE en, OP, ee SE
wiih Wh Tm En
Haw Wc yyeurs & a lofyou...
Wow::the wind. feels so good:
Listen all of you! We're'going
fishing out by the breakwater!
V Be careful not to get too carried
away and fall into the'ocean: all right?!!
Yes: sir!
How unusual to go
wut fishing to the sea...
Oh. yeah
What's the problem! Every time
we decide to go some place,
(All Tr
it's let's go camping to
the mountains. so I'm sure that
Doc wanted us to
experience something new!
W-Wel=.sort of... Aha<=ha...
I'm not complaining or anything...
I already have a hunch
that since I've been avoiding going out
to distant places with you guys...
going out to distant
places with you guys...
you figured instead of taking me to the
mountains where there are blind spots
it would be better to take
me out to see where the view
IS Nice and clear, thanks to
somebody's great idea. right...?
Darn you...
she hit the bull's eye
I guess it's not a bad
idea for a change of scene
scene to come and feel
the sea breeze of this vast ocean.
The mother of all creation .
Well, but from my point of view,
he should've just
minded his own business...
What a super snob!!
Al. is this the first time
you're going fishing
Oh come. come-regardless
of her remarks. I can tell that TW
Al. 1s this the first time
you're going fishing?
JAitis-pretty-happy
about this, you know...
Va can
Avis pretty happy
about this, you know...
I wonder about that.
And, like she says,
the ocean is the source of life.
The source of life...
It's a great place to relax. besides...
Huh, come to think of it, today is...
My. are youzall goingato
fish at the breakwater too?
Yes! We are.)
Only untitafter noon. though!
Then. would you like to compete me
and see how many
fish we can catch by then
How many fish we can catch?
Compete...?
Let's bet one side
dish from our lunch box!
Lunch box. 22One side dish...?
The crab<«cream Cc oquette
that I make is delicious. you know
Right. Kanetani!
Yeah...
You re always a great help w-
Just as expected of
a fisherman's daughter...
You're tops when it comes
to making dishes using seafood.
We're all luc «
we get to eat the food that
this beauty makes you Know, Kids.
Oh. cutsit-out- Kanetan.
But. we're.only beginners...
You should have
Ida give you advice then.
Ida?
He:s the one who's navigating this ship,
a'fisherman actively in business!
He's a super veteran
that knows everything about fishing]
Aha, ha...
No way. no. can do
NO matter 'how much advice you get
you won't be able to fish anything.
You won't be able to fish anything
Because you're (bozu)
no catch to begin with
be it your brains or your age...you get?
Aha, ha, ha.
No catch? (bozu)
Aha, haO ha. ha.
a ou ot cat ¥a™ 5 BAYAE
The word "bBozu means
no catch in. fishing terminology...
It's a pun, a play on words
No need to trouble yourself over it,
it's just an old man's joke...
Darn guy.
Okay! Let's ask the fisherman I
all kinds of questions
and fish up a lot
of yellow tails and tunas!!
Okay!!
You can't fish something that big...
TA RA
(5148)
Tragedy of the Conspicuous Pier Part 1
Okay. I'll see you guys then
Ill be back in 3 hours
Good luck.
If somethinc comes u)
call me right away. okay...
I'll come:for you in 20 minutes!
Yuk!
Huh? What's the matter?
Why are you doing that...?
Because. Right?!
Yes!
We went to ask him about fishing then he
Treated us too much like
Wile kids that we really got angry! I!
And. what did he say?!
He said don't make
Ioud noises with your friends...
Fuh, fuh. fun.
wm That's right=ilgs exactly
as the fisherman says...
That's right<it's exactly
as the fisherman-says
Why Is he, fight
If loud noises are made,
the sound of footsteps and
such travel along the breakwater...
into the watersurnprising
the fish and make them flee...
So, that fisherman was
probably trying to tell you that
If you make too much noise your
footsteps will keep the fish away...
Right. exactly. I tell you!
Did he say anything else...?
Well
Oops. there. okay.
There!"Oops!
Dangerous...
doing something like that.
What if the children copy him
( as)
The place where the
tetra pods are over there is...
Mr. Ejiri's usual fishing spot!
WHe 's' not contented
unless he gets to fish there. that man...
Ally
But. it's strange that the tetra pod looks
to.be above the surface of the water...
Although it's so out off shore like this,
it's pretty shallow, isn't it?
VBooo
The rocks here a patterned
In complex fashion so...
That area over there
IS very deep, you see...
well. but-thanks to that
this place is hard to enter for fishing€
thatinot too many
people know of this place.
So. this is an extremely
fantastic hidden fishing spot
I thanks to Mr. Ida's navigating skill.
See that's why there
aren't other fishers around.
Fuh, fun, fun...
Let's give it our best shot.
After all, our lunch is"at stake too...
Fuhs fun. fun...
» Aha ak!
But, are you sure we can
catch;fish in a place like this?
Yeah...
For fish, the breakwater
is like an artificially
made hotel with a restaurant.
There'll be loads of fish!!
There re lots of theme
But-that's during the period of time
when there are a lot fish that is...
Oh no!
But that's during the period of time
when-there are a lot fish that is...
Oh no!
IWeimay catch a bit too much mm
We may catch a bit too much...
This. cooler box is so small! mam.
We didn'tsfigure things out too well. /
- - What if we can't fit all the fish in. /
Don't worry. I'll eat them all up
What a thing to say, Genta, come off it!
Ig! -aim:for the record of
youngest big. catcher then
Oh, just great.
I'll open. up a fish shop then!
4m wet»
Yep. yep. good idea.
You're not listening at all, you guys...
YAWN
No fish at all...I wonder
if the fish are asleep...
Yeah. it's not even budging.
And it's such a clear day...
4 she fish donrtibite
because it's a clear day.
Huh, what do you mean?
It's not good if it's a fine day?
No. because the water us only this deep
on a fine daywhen
the water is transparent...
fish get suspicious and are on guard. -
So its actually better if
It were cloudy or drizzling a little!
But this is a good place. neverthelé&ss:
so if we stick it out .
The fish will eventually, start biting...
Well I'd advise youffiot
to get your hopes up too high.
What?!
What it all. boils down to is,
only patient people are suited for fishing...
That's not true!
There ane quick tempered.
People among fishing experts...
Exactly impatient people are
said to be suited for fishingsbecause...
They're constantly. concerned
whether the -bait's not-too good.
Whether where they
are fishing is not good.
Whether their tools
aren't good enough. So,
they read up on fishing
books. exchange information
check out the tides Pp
of the day.and so forth
They do a lot of research as well as
try each and every kind of thing
sO impatient people are said
Well. to become a good
anglers experience is what counts!
The more effort youlp
put in, thesamore reward
The more effort you
put in, the more reward
you get to receive from the sea.
That 1s, you get to catch better fish too.
Well, as for me. I haven't received
such a great gifts rom
the ocean yet though.
7 ony
Hey Conan, you said there are/,
many differentikinds of fish here, right?
Yeah...
Then. can we catch sea bream here 1007?
No.l\Impossible
I'M:
Why not? Why us it impossible?!
There are no sea breams
unless you go to a place that's
more out to the sea with
a 'depth;of 30 to 70 meters.
But, since the sea is
connected. a sea bream
may(go astray and come along. right?!
Remember! There was
a sea otter that did that too, right?
Aha, ha .
2° Yeah, all we have to do is oo
atch fish that come swimming astray.
H Hey ..7?!
H.Hey...?!
Hee. hee, hee . I guess
we can't fish for whales though... &
Well, we've got lots of time, so I guess
we'll just have to stick it out, right, Conan
JEW aA
O Oh, yeah, let's do our best...
Agh.
Huh? Didl'you catch something?!
Oh, no...my bobber drifted awa 1.
Really. it's because you didn't
push it in nicely into the bobber rubber...
But .
What is it now?
I.Look, Air's bobber is moving!
What?!
Ca...
Caught a fish!!
Keep your cool. Ar!
Pull! Pull!
Hang in there!!
Don-t rush! That's right,
you-re doing good!!!
She did it!!
Huh
It sure is tiny. though.
A tiny girella?
Well, I guess it's better
than not fishing anything at all...
Aaagh...?!
What do yourthink you're doing?
It's fishing manners to
return trash fish: into the sea. isn't it?
I. guess'you re right...
What a waste.
But the next time you
put the fish back into the sea.
It's better to cool*your
hands with the water
in the bucket before throwing in the fish...
Huh?
Because-the body temperature
of humans is too warm
for the fish and it would get burned!
You sure like to pick on people. don't you!
Huh 2!
1.1 just said that it
would be better to do so!!
But. now we know that
we can fish here too!
I'm going to change places
and go fish over on that-side...
H.Hey!
A Ad al + Sum
I want to fish for sea bream!
Don't run!
Oh, right. Sea bream, sea bream...
I tell you, no way...Aha. ha...
Talk about not being
able to fish anything
You can say that again.
Who was it that was saying {_
Iet's fish for yellowtail and tunad_
Talk about not-even budging
Wellwto become a good angler,
experience is what counts!
Okay. experience is
what it takes, experience...
I'm going to go over to everyone
else and see how they're doing...
Please don't run
how. I know
Ha, hatha.
Their fishing manners have improved.
Fantastic, amazing
Thank you
Good luck!
Fuh. fur, fun fun...
I wonder\if she'll become a
professional angler when she grows up.
Ha. ha, ha...
Ayumi, did*yousleann anything?
Uh, he taught me how to hook
the bait on and a lot of other things...
Maybe I'll have him teach me too...
There seems to be a lot
of fish below and I wonder
why I still can't seem 10 catch anything?
He told me that the flow of
the current is not good right now...
I see {the flow of the current. huh...
I'm going to catch a fish today,
no matter what it takes
If I cant fish anything
today. when else can I?
No fish...
You can say that again.
Well-but the veterans over there
haven't caught any either so
I guess it can't be helped...
I'd like to at least catch one fish...
True, if we don't catch any,
the man will really make fun of us...
Aaaah... I'm getting sleepy again.
It's come!
Huh?! Really!
N.No "doubt about it. I've caught:one!
Hang in there, Mitsuhiko!
I-did it! I"finally caught one. Finally.
You did it! Mitsuhiko! You did it!
Oh~. You did it. Mitsuhiko!
It's a nicely; shapedrmackerel! 4
Genta. I caught one! See!
Huh? You:caught-one? I Really
See. look. look. it's this bug.
Mitsuhiko caught it.
1.I'm happy for you!
I mean. it's so small... As for me...
I'm going for the big one-A sea bream!
You did it, didn't you. Mitsuhiko!
1Y- 2
You did it. I've lost the bet.
Is this your bobber...?
Oh. my bobber?
Thank you. It drifted away...
Why do you have it?
Fuh. fun. fun gmake sure
you keepin on tight next time
Okay!
The crab cream croquette
she gave us.sure Is good...isn't it?
Eating in a place like this makes
Iunch taste even better-doesn't it? =
Yep! It's delicious!
Nothing yet...
I guess Conan was right
about no sea breams being here...
This is the worst time of day for fishing.
Morning or sundown is way 'better.
It seems everyonegjs
having a hard time too...
No bite what so ever.
Maybe I'll try changing the-bait.
How about you? Anything?
No. Nothing at all!
wr on
I wonder If the bait is on all right?
Huh?
Huh? What's this.
I feel something pulling.
T.it's big...
It. It's big!
C.Conan,.
1.7 whale. I can't ft it up!!
It smnegakar:...
Negakari?
Is there a fish called negakar?
T's not a fish. Your line got caught
and stuck to seaweed
or a rock or something.
Huh? It's not a fish? Then what do I do?
Don't pull too hard,
but rather, loosen and pull.
I.Like this?!
Right. good...repeat the process...
It. It's come off!
/hat's this...
You sure fished a big one.
Sigh...Aha, ha...
Shoots. bait gone again.
Fuh. fun, fun...
Even the expert angler
Ejiri is having a bad day today
They seem not to have luck either,
maybe the current is bad
Genta. aren't you going to eat luiChr/
Yeah. I'll eat in a little while!
I can't believe that
Genta us still not eating...
Yep I wonder if he wants
to fish sea bream that badly
Sea bream...is-Genta"s dream.
Please let:zhim fish a sea bream
Ha. ha, ha. ha...
Doc!!!
Gee, but am I hungry
Should eat my lunch
or fish for the sea bream!
Will it be lunch or the sea bream...
It's lunch first after all!
Eatingslunch while bathing in
sea wind makes lunch tastier after all'...
Donet-you think so todo. Air?!
Aren't you glad you came?
Vier
wv 2"
Ir @&\
"Bake" your time and eat...
Take your time and eat...
Take your time and eat.
I've got"'no time to lose. you see .
I've got 'ho time to lose. you see
I've 'got"'no time to lose. you see
I'm done!
o! 4 ow
Talk about fast... . 2!
A record high eating speed.
Okay, I've finish eating my share.
Now all I needqis for
the fish to eat my bait.
Come on. my dearesea bream.
Genta...
Oh, it's the ship!
It's that time of day already?
Shall we get ready to go. then?
Right.
Oh, he's already come for us. How soon...
O Next, it's curry party time
atdyour house Dr. Agasa
That's right.
Besides. maybe we can have
mackerelOsashimi..Rather,
I guess it's¥too small for sashimi...
Mackerel. slash me...
Doc!
How'd you do. caught anything?
Of course!
We caught nothing
as empty as no hair on my head...
Ha. ha, ha... Well, that's too bad...
How about you guys?
Empty here:too.
I caught one small. mackerel...
Big catch, big catch...
I say: we should change
fishing.spots from this afternoon.
True. .*» 1
But>..what about Mr. Ejir...
He said that he's going to
stick it out here till late in the day today.
Oh...I'll go talk it over with Mr. Ida then...
Hey. Genta. give up already.
Werre going home
Okay...
He says he'll go around
over to where he went before...
Oh, that's good.
You're going to change places?
Yes. this place is no good today.
(Sin
There's another spot nearby
where we. fished a lot before.
We-re stopping by for a while.
Well, werre in no rush. So,
wesre all going home together then...
No. Mr. Bjiri's going to stay there.
Huh? We're going to
Ieave him behind alone
Ha, ha. ha. ha. ha...
No need to worry
because Mr. Ida's boat
will come for him again at sundown...
Fuh. fun. fu.
Mr. Ejiri really likes
that place, doesn't he?
Fuh, fuh, fuh, it sure was
a lot~of fun. I'd like to comelagain
Yes, next time I'd like to come after {
doing some research as Doc.suggested: ."»
Samoan.» ggnnvl
Hey. we're going home!
Mtnsgpamis mang *
Shoots. I wanted to fish...a sea bream...
Imi@esamnjwn
Inn-um tin-Quill
Shoots. I wanted to fish...a sea bream...
I IYT1117 (TIT a
All I fished was seaweed!
Huh'!
Huh? Another false call?
Okay. we'll beron our way then!
Good luck!
No use calling out to him...
Once he starts fishing, Mir=Ejiri is
reticent and hardly ever talks!
Right. he was saying that *
he's going to stick it out
today too, until he gets a big catch...
But he sure makes a lot of
noise when he gets a big catch...
Fun fun ab. SANUS
so excited that he almost fell off.
Fuh, fun, fuh. . he sure is
He's probably in deep
thought or something.
So. shall we get going...?
Gugh, gugh. gugh...
The pole's being pulled.
You seem to have gotten a bite.
Agh...
Agh? Yes. he'sfgot a bite...
You mean he doesn't realize it?
Mr. Ejiri, you got a bite.
Mr. Ejin?!
What's up? What's all the racket about?
That man seems to be asleep...
Asleep. you mean Mr Ejiri? No way...
Huh?
What's ithe matter with him?
Mr. En?
) 1/1
Hey. there. Mr. Ejiri, Ejiri...
Huh... . 2!
Mr. Elin?!
Huh? What's upry
What s-wrong?!
What's. going onrdjg,
}) Mr. Ejiri!!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Pr od uce r S
MICHIHIKO SUWA¢
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUD ONO
- I LN
Chara «er Designs By
MAsATQMZ») Sit/Do»!-
Story Editor.
JUNIG@HI 11{KA
KAN/I ms JWABARA
A * NL. » o
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MASAYQMO sumo
HARUO OOGAWARA
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKSDA~
Chief Director.
KEN]JI KODAMA
I IMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
In association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CON
CC COSHO AOYAMA / SHOCAKUKAN YTV - TMS
All Rights Reserved
We've got to take
this man on the ship right away
and head him off to the hospital!
Hurry!
You!
Dont move!
Don't touch anything and stay still!
FHiHey. hey-what's up?
W.Who the hell are you, sonny?