Today's'stage is also at the breakwater
The place was'in such
clear view and conspicuous
, 4 Yet the crime was very inconspicuous
Fish up the trick and the culprit
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
No cases. yet unsolved
with, Detective Conan.
Hey. Mr. Ejiri?! Get a hold ofwyourself!!
Snap out of it!! 4
Ugh...Ugh...
His lips are turning purple,
cyanosis is starting...
This is proof that he cannot
breathe as he should.
Still I can feel his pulse by touch,
and his:heart is beating.
Quite okay: which means.
A possible brain damage or...
neurotoxic poisoning!!
Huh Artificial respiration
Please carry him on board the ship
right away and take him to a hospitallk
Y.Yeah...
Hang in there, Mr. Ejiri, okay...
Hur!
Here goes...
DO Dear...
Don't move!!
Huh?
Ites extremely likely that he was poisoned!
And the one who poisoned him...
IS possibly someone
who 1s here at the breakwater!!
Until the police get here,
don't touch anything. and stay still!
H.Hey. hey... what's up?
Who the hell are you, sonny?!
Conan Edogawa...
A detective!!
(BR)
Tragedy of the Conspicuous Pier Part 2
First, let's start with hearing about how
you are all connected with each other...
We-all belonged to the same
fishing club since our university days.
Including Mr Ejiri, who
was carried off a while ago too.
Dosyou come to fish
at this breakwater frequently?
Yeah... .on boardthe
ship of the fisherman called Ida
Which means all four of you know each
other quite well from some time back..
Yes...especially Mr. Iday
and I because our parents
who are fishermen also
know each other well...
We've'/known each other 4
since our childhood,days.
I see! You were saying that
you're the daughter of a fisherman...
Yeah, she's really
knowledgeable about fish and
was really popular
withsimen in the club too...
Moreover, she's a good¥CooKk...
She"ssalso beautiful so she was
the Madonna of the fishing club...
P {4 BX
Oh. please cut it out.
Let's not talk about something
so long in the past...
Is that why someone
attempted to kill Mr. Ejin?
Huh?
Because Ms. Shirane
was taken away by Mr. En...
WW: What the hell are you talking about!
Just a while ago,
when Ms. Shirane was about
to run over to him. she called him "dear."
Unless they have
an intimate relationship,
she wouldn't be
calling him.that way. would she?
Then, therone who had to
go through a broken heart
Then, the one who had to
NT 39,
Then othe one who had to
go through a broken heart
held a grudge against
him! Mr. Kanetani!!
You did it. didn't you!
D.Don't be ridiculous!
Besides<if that was my motive...
the fisherman Ida would
also come up. as a suspect
Mr Ida
Because Mr. Ida was
Ms. Shiranés fiancé...
Fiance...?
Besides. that's not possible...
Why not....?
Because Mr: Ejiri and
I~Ngot a divorce 3 years ago...
Huh? Why?
Well a lot of things, were involved...
But, the fact that we both
Iike fishing hasn't changed
$0 on holidays or on oi day off...
We invite Mr. Kanetani
and come fishing together...
And? You always made everyone's lunch?
See: this lunchjthat Mr:!Ejiri ate; the sise
of the lunch box and the-handkerchief
it's wrapped in is the; same as.-the
one Mr. Kanetani got from MsgShirane...
It's truesthatiitzlooks
just like Mr. Kanetani¥s. lunch...
Don:tdellsimerthat the I
Iunch was«poisoned...
4 would never do something like that!!
Besides, as far as §
that lunch is concerned.
I got it from
Ms :Shirane on our way
The lunch boxes are exactly
alike and nobody knows:who:ll get it.
How can poison be
put in something like that?
How. can poison be
T. That's true...
T.Tihat's true...
Huh?
The pole standfis.in the water...?
This is one of the two
) that Mr. 'Ejiri had erected...
The other pole stand is: still
standing okay. and yet why 7?
Hmm, this.case sure is hard to grasp...
Maybe the poison was smeared
on the hook and swung around?
I see. the wa the do in lure fishinc...
That can't be Besides,
it would be to difficult-to pinpoint
the part where the
skin is exposed in one fling...
If it works. it'syjust mere chance!
And if the poisoned
hook. is. soaked in water
for-some time. the poison would drift off.
So: .the-lunch was poisoned after all...
No. it's very unlikely...
If poison were to be in
something that was chewed-on
I would've been poisoned too
because I performed artificial respiration...
I see!
@h...which means that you knew
he wasn't poisoned from the mouth
No...
I just got a glimpse of where the
poison was insewted. but I didn't know...
All I knew back then was that
I had to perform astificial respiration...
Or he. would've died there...
Hey, you!
Can't this ship go any faster?!
Please don't be impossible, officer...
Huh? What's. this smell...?
'Fir
Hey. isn't smoke coming out'!
Well, you're the one who
keeps telling me to go faster, officer
The police sure are late
They sure are...
Well, I gucssyevenything-ll be okay!
The culprit is one of the two anyway!
As long as we keep are eyes on them...
Right, the fisherman wasn't
here with us all this time so .
You can't be too sure...
Huh?
If he made Mr Ejiri drink some sleeping
drug with delayed effect:beforehand...
When he came to pick us up,
he could-ve gone up to Mr. Ejiri
to check outtwhat was.wrong and
jpoke:him withrarpoison needle then...
Hey. wait!!
You mean you let a possible
killer and Doc go together?
Yeah. There was no other
way to save Mr. Ejiri'slife...
I did give Doc the tranquilizer gun though,
just in case something comes up...
Besides, if anything
happens. Doc's going to call...
T.The phone?!
Hello. Doc?
Hello, Doc?
Oh, Shinichi!
I just got Mr! Ejiri on thesambulance now!
And. how: is he?
T's hard to say yet The type of poison
hasn't been specified either. so...
Maybe if a doctor were
to examine his left wrist
the type of poison may be:specified...
Left. wrist?
Right! Although it was
hidden with his sleeve
there were traces of scratches there.
I'm sure that's how hewas poisoned...
Incidentally, there was something
that looked like paste on the sleeve!
Paste you mean the glue type?
Yeah... That stuff is not
used for fishing. so isn't it odd?
Well, I'll give you the
details when I get there
Later, then...
H.Hey. Doc...
P.Paste...?
What did Doc say»?
He said he got Mr. Ejiri on ans
ambulance so he's coming backihere!
That's great!
[ That's.great!
I guess everything-srokay for now...
wonder who the culprit is though...
He taught me how to
put bait on my hook...
And, the lady. see! She picked¥thiis
bobber that got drifted away up for me.
She said she saw it-floating in the
water so she picked it up.with a net.
The fisherman seems to
have taken Mr. En to where
the ambulance came to pick him up too...
At first, he seemed to be
Iooking down-on us
because we're Kids. but...
Oh ..you mean when he told
you Not to make too much noise?
Yes we may be kids,
but we won't dance /or
carrymg around portable
shrines in a place like this!
Right!
Dancing and-carrying portable shrines?
Hey... tell me exactly
what the fisherman said!
Um~~~he said don't
make too much noise
with your friends and start a festival
1"told him we won't start
a-festival. then he said
go ask the other people
Oh, "Omatsuri (festival )
is fishing terminology...
Paste...
Paste
bobbe...
and omatsur:...
see...so, that's it!!
C«Conan?
Don't tell me"you've
figured out who the culpritiis!!
Yeah...
I figuredwout who was trying to fish
Mr. Ejiri's life with a poison hook...
as well as the way it was done!!
as well as the way it was done!!!
As well as the way it was done!!!
Sea bream!! Sea bream!!
This is sea bream for sure!!!
\ Okay, all of you, enough for
the detective thing already. right?
You're saying that so that
you can-hide the evidence, right?!
Listen...it's true-that
Mr Ejiri didn't look all that great...
But, we're not even sure If he was
really poisoned or not yet. you know?
But, we're not even sure if he was
really poisoned or not yet, you know?
In the first place, the Ida, who took
Mr. Ejiridto'where the ambulance
was is also a suspect, right?
If he's the--one. then the evidence
would"ve-been,disposed
somewhere sin the sea long time ago.
1.1 guess so, but...
That's no problem, because
Doc who went with him
IS keeping an.eye on him... Moreover...
the possibility of Mr. Ida being
the culprit has drastically decreased...
now that we know he safely took
Mr. Bjiri to the ambulance. and is
heading back this way with Doc again...
Huh?
Is.Is that right, Conan?
Remember what I said?
I said. if Mr. Ida were the culprit... .-
He would vewhaduto run over to
Mr. Ejiri that he put to sleep beforehand.
And poke a poison needle into him...
heypoison.that was used
as p)'i'.db.ably?-'~neb rfc>tbxic=;-'p"6i'Son...
He wunidehave diffieuity Hredthdhgd
but he would Be» riarareafiiftauswa
If someone poked a poison needle
into him. he would know who it was...
The culprit would never.rush;
such a person to the hospital .:right?
Even if he would've done
SO. Not to be suspected
he would've fled off somewhere already...
Because when thespoison
wears off and Mr. Ejiri
1S able to talk. the culprit
would be revealed
I seeswhich means that the suspect
IS either Shirane or Kanetani
Hey. how long is it going
to take you to make repairs?!
Please don't rush me like that, Officer!!
N... We still have no 1
what kindof case it is, and yet...
Are you saying either Mr. Kanetani or I,
one of us is the one
who poisoned Mr. Ejin?
D2Don:t be ridiculous...
It's true that we were fishing
on both side! of Mr. Ejiri >.
But he was fishing
on the tip of the tetra pod\.
SO he more than
10 meters away from us...
How could we have poisoned him...
Omatsun!
O.Omatsun?
Omatsuri is a fishing
terminology that 1s used when
two lines get tangled with cach other
You know what to do
when that happens. right?
I see! The culprit took advantage
of him wanting to untangle his line
in which he would bring
his fish hook near his hand!
So. the comment of the isherman
Don't get too noisy as-if
it were a festival(omatsuri)...
Was not an insulting remark at all
Right...
the culprit deliberately got the
fishing line tangled with Mr. Ejiri's.
And, when Mr. Ejiri tried to
untangle the line. 'it's slightly pulled on...
and the poisoned hook
would sink into Mr. Ejiri's hand!
But: you did also say that \
if the hook smeared with poison
is soaked in the water for some
time the poison would dissolve.
Yeah...if the poison was
just-smeared on to the hook.
Then the poison would dissolve,
but its a different story if paste is used
P Paste?
Yeah...
if poison is mixed into the paste and then
smeared onto the hook and dried hard...
It would start to dissolve
when soaked in salt water...
and by the time it gets
tangled with Mr. Ejiri's line...
it would be gooey and just.
Right for use... As proof of this...
Doc just told me on
the phone that there was
Doc just toldifime on
paste on the left
sleeve of Mr. Ejiri's shirt...
He also mentioned that there were traces
of scratch marks on Mr. Ejiri's left wrist!
That's probably why Mr. Ejiri's
pole stand was in the water too...
His pole stand?
Yeah!
When the fishing line was
pulled to sink the poison hook in
When the pole itself
was pulled. the pole stand was
pulled at the same time
and fell into the water as well...
But, can you really do something
Iike deliberately getting
your own line tangled
with somebody else's...
Of course you can!
You use a lot of hooks with poison
smeared on them and use light sinkers...
Then you let it drift along
to the flow of the current.
And it gets tangled super easily
If the poisoned hoo as
a fly hook. when it is pulled up...
even If there were to be
many hooks attached to it
nothing strange would be thought of it!
And? Which of them
did that...?
I just said, didn't 1?
That therling was tangled using
the flow of-the current. right. . 7?
Remember she picked up you, 1
bobber that drifted away. Ayumi?
Yes!"She did...
* in other words.
If Ms. Shirane who was on the
right edge picked up your bobber
the flow of the current
was from left to right...
And if the culprit took advantage
of the flow of the current...
Right, the one who was fishing
between Mr. Ejiri and all of us.
Mr. Kanetani!!
You're the one who did it. right?!
H.Hey. is that true? Mr Kanetani...?
N.No,way. No need to take
what kids say all that seriously...
Besides
whit makes you think 1'd do sotnaeth
Iike that at 2 breakwatar lithe this
I mean, there're only so many of us.
I mean. there're only so many of us.
JJEC ORT fits
No. the suspects were narrowed
down-merely2because of coincidence
Backathen- if the fish didn't bite
his line. and if we didn't go over to him we
thinking that something was: strange
because he showed no reaction...
he would've been left as is,
and time would just pass by...
The estimated time of death
wouldve been expanded
and there would've
been a lot more suspects...
And, you're the very one
who said that you wanted to
change fishing spots
because no fish were biting...
I see...so, Mr. Ejint who said that
he wanted to stick it out here till night
would've been left behind alone...
And, if everyone else
moves to a new fishing spot...
it could've béensmade to
Iook as if someone came along
in a boat and poisoned Mr~Ejiri
who was fishing all by himself...
Yeah. besides, there are many
people here that would testify
that Mr. Kanetani never
once went near Mr. Ejiri too...
B.But if the hook poked him
he would at least let out a cry .
So. you set the timing
for when-to hook-it on. right?
That as, to the sound of the
ship that came torepick us up...
Oh, Doc.
Oh. Doc!
I see! He erased the
sound of the scream/of pain
when being poked with
the sound of the of the ship!
Moreover the direction
the ship came from was
opposite the direction
that everyone was fishing...
Everybody attention
would be distracted from Mr. Ejiri
so it would be like killing
two birds with one stone...
{ vs =
B.But. sonny. you don't even have proof...
Jour
This pole of yours is the evidence...
The bobber us sunk
so. it should still be there...
Mr. Bjiri'S pole that got tangled
with your terminal tackle!
Uuuugh...
The paste that was mixed with poison
Is) probably almost completely dissolved.
But... THAT would not dissolve so easily...
Mr. Ejiri's blood that is
on the hook that scratched him...
MM Mr. Kanetanu...
Mr. Kanetani, may I ask why
u did what you did to him...
We just went drinking the other day
all three of us together. didn't we?!
The reason is his remark
when we went drinking...
When: ou left the seat, I asked
him why you both got a divorce...
A.A lover?
Yeah... I just started a new
business back then and...
I was going throughua lot of stress.
She+found:out that
I was having-an-affair and left me...
H.He said that...
Yeah...l had no intention of
saying anything about the fact
that he got a divorce ofdthad a lover, but...
I just couldn't forget
what he said after all that.
Well. I guess what it:alllboils*down 10; is.
Be it a company. fish or women...
the best part. s:when,
they are alive andikicking
Don't tell-her this: okay.
Yeah. it was like he had shattered
the dream of my younger-days...
just couldn't take it in...
+ Because you were really our Madonna...
Don't be silly...
He divorced me... for my sake
Hung
Back then, his company \
was on the verge of bankruptcy?
And he couldn't save his employees
unless he started a new business
But. in order to. do so, he had to
take on an enormous amount of debt
He got on his hands and
knees.begging me to divorce him.
He begged me saying that
If the new business fails
I'd end up having to
face the collectors too...
I wanted to overcome the
situation as husband and wife...
But. since his stubborn and
not too strong taking on pressure
And -as for me: I wanted to continue
my job as a cuisine essayist I agreed...
So. that thine about a lover is
a story he made up to<put on a front...
I don't like that comment
he made of women
who are alive and kicking. though...
No, there's no need to get angry...
Because he was referring-to you when
he said women who
are alive and Kicking
Huh?
While sailing on the swaying boat,
Mr. Ejiri kept repeating to
himself over and over again...
A fish that is truly alive and kicking is one
that can freely swim through the ocean...
He asked me if I thought so too...
What an idiot...
Oh. no. my God...What on earth...
What on.earth have I done...
Don't worry! He seems to have
recovered quite a bit already...
Beside dust before we go there,
I got a call from Ejiri, who sounded okay.
He asked me to relay a message>to-you.
He said for you to get
super fresh fish for her today...
If you do, he says he'll
forget what happened today...
He said he would tell the hospital
and police that he was poisoned
by a balloon fish that
he cooked and ate on his own.
SO to not come back
until you get big catch.
Is today a special day or something?
My? Come to think of it,
today is our wedding anniversary...
Your anniversary ?
If I'm not mistaken today is...
Don-ttell me you) forgot?
Happy Birthday. Doc!
Huh?
Genta, which means
that you were trying to...
Yeah, fish something
for Doc's birthday present!
No Genta! Don't say a word about it!
We've been keeping it a #
secret from Ai too so that
we could throw a sufprise part...
Oh. sort I sory...
I see...that's why these
children were planning
to have a cunpy part at my:house tonight
Thank you all so.much...
Don't-cry, I was trying to
fish you a sea bream but
ended up fishing some odd black fish...
Iey...Isn't this 1s black sea bream,
Iack sea bream...
The King of breakwater fishing,
black sea bream!)
It's. an.expensive fish!
WwW. Wow!!
T's too much for Doc. then. - I 4
I'd love to eat it I
So now ités-your turn. Mr. Kanetani!
Get-me a big one that is just
as good as<the one he 'fished. okay!
Because I've got to show him that...
Huh?
That even if fish are caught,
good fish is good...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
yd - I S.
MICHIHIKO, SUWA,
MASAIITTO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character..Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO #
Story Editor
JUNI@H! ITOKA
KAN]! KASHTWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYAsFilrA 3
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Dir COTS
MASATOMO SUDO
»° eh + 2 (
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKSDA
Chief Director.
KIN]! ITODAMA
I TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONA
COSHO AOYAMA SHOCAKUKAN- YTV TMS
All Rights Reserved
Well, although there were
an array of odd occurrences
wasn't coming to the ocean a good idea?
Yes...now I understand how fish feel...
Huh? Just what do you mean by that?
The body temperature of
humans is .too warm for fish...
Right. it's too wa m for me too
that I feel as if 'm going tor get burned
Hey. hey. it's still not repaired?!
Hey. hey...noskidding!
We were used just like that, huh...
But you're not having it your way...
The Witch in'a-Candy.House