Vok-y¥'s Sin a oan
Trick, syrup. sweet, sweet trap
Once, oufget'in, there's no way out
He sees through the one and only truth
Archild in. appearance
Witfi the, go" 'bf an adult
No case is'left-unsolved
with:Detective, Conan
SO. it only costs 500 yen
to get in to the museum
And what s more surprising s
you can eat Ecriture"s cake 3 thalf price!
You're gonna regret it for the rest of
your life if you miss this opportunity!
Wait Sonoko!
The cake isn't gonna runaway!
Well, I wanna run away.
Hereit's here!
Yahoo!
Now. let's go! Ran!
Oh my...
Oh my.
Come on, Ran! And you toowy
kid! Now hurry up!
Wow! It's jus (like the candy house
in "Hansel and Gretel. isn't it!?»
Wow! It's just like the candy house
Nn "Hansel and Gretel. isn't it!
in Hansel and Gretel, isn't itl?
Oh my god! It's all made of cake
and candies!? I can't believe it!
-- A «> qgey
ook how many sweets are here...
Alrighty! Now. the morfAing part begins!
What do you men the morning part?
Ran. do you know
This event is has, two parts:one in the
morning and one in the afternoon.
I guess Sonok wants to eat now: just to
get her stomach ready for the afternoon.
No way... man,...
I wanna go home... .really...
The Witch in a Candy House
ca Qobolioc
oh am a an an of AS 20 LP
Each chef has his own booth. en
Which one I should start off with
Is that him... in this picture?
4] ,I\
ran AR AN
My god. How can he make
three cakes at théfsame time!?
This is like fighting rather than cooking...
Oh, you didn't know? He is actually
called fighting patissier by people.
So he is the one in the Iron Patissier™?
Right.
The one in the middle is
themPrince of Sweets"
See the girl in the back?
she makes candies just like magic,
so people call her Candy Magician.
I see.
Kyaaa!!
What the...he is like an idol!
Would\ ou like to make one
What!? M..mej
What! Yes! Yes! Yeeeees!
Come on...l will help you.
It sounds fun. Do it. €@onan.
No, I'm wk...
Yes! Here!
Here! Here!
Don't worry. It's simple.
No...Ran. why don't you try?
Me? No. I'm ok You go ahead and do it.
Me? No. I'm ok. You.go ahead and do it.
It's the last partaEverybody can do it.
I will give you this one after it's done.
Ah... heh. heh
All you need to do rs put the
chocolate cream on the roll cake...
Make it thick
Now. tryst.
With a fork?
Fuh. fun, fun...
You gotta learn tO@ make cake if you
wanna be popular with girls these days
Well done, Conan!
Right. Sonoko?
Nah. it's so so...
Heh, heh, she's still upset...
I will finish the rest so
I can give this to you.
+ Rep
TN aE -
Are you going to sta
here for the afternoon too
O@h. yes! Off course! Right?
Ah...yes...
Wow . these candies look so alive. huh?
Candy Magician, she is!
Looks like glass art, isn't it?
Thank you!
Here you go!
It tastes better when it's fresh!
It's my dream to win a contest
with these candies, someday
Ms... I like this!
Thank you!
@ht~I don't know which to choose
a Dew 6
What are you talking about?
It's simple: "Eat them all
What are you talking about? y-
It's simple. Eat«them all
All of it?.
Eh Rx An, dn.
Ah. haha...
Here! Hold this will you?
This one... AND
this one too...
You want.me to get some for you, Kid?
I...I'm ok! I will get it myself...
@k...
Then, I'm gonna get some more.
Oh my goodness .
Oops!
"Pix... No... Yes
Oh, are you ok?
I'm sorry!
I'm SO sorry...l just wasted your cake...
Doesn't matter .
As long as it tastes good...
Well, it does matter.
How it looks, and how it's made...
Looks really matter when
it comes to today's sweets
# Hey Maedamawhy cantiyou
act more sociable,
Iike Fujino does, you know.
Yeah I would, if .sociabilit,
improves taste...
Oh, Hi Conan What took
you so long to pick your cake?
Ah, well
Alright!
I'm ready for the second round!
Well, I'm getting thirsty.
I'll get something to drink
I'll go with you, Conan.
Ok;Can you get me onejto too; please?
No sweets for a while, seriously
y I~ hoa Aman
Shinichi would say
Something like, What have you
been eating while!I was away!?
He wouldn't say that!
Why do I have to do that!?
I'm a chef! And not a magician!
That's the way it is...because
that's what the customers want.
Please, let me act as a chef!
You, simple mortal...
you know how many fantastic
sweets exist in this world?
Cake and chocolates are
dominating the sweets scen
but your candies have
got really*popular because of
my marketing skills, and
not because of how they taste!
There was no "Wood chocolate making
trial when I came here yesterday
But today. we have it! We're so lucky!
What!? You came here yesterday too?
No wonder you know
so. much about this place!
Oh, there you are
I've been looking for you. Here!
You know; it's the wdod
chocolate you made. Howsis it?
Heheh-It's-been-nicely-fixed
Han?
Without.the decorations, it's just the
same as the one In the store. isn't 1t?
It looks so, deli¢ious!
AN Ine
Oh my god...
The morning part ofithe
event was finished past twelve,
a the dead body was
found around twelve thirty.
And where were you guys
during that time?
I was in the kitchen making
candies for the afternoon.
I was there alone since
I let the cashiers out for lunch.
I was in the kitchen as well, but came
out just to give Conan some cake.
Hmmm
Ok .So, you saw Ms. Hashigaki.
What was she doing?
She was doing some counting work.
She was working hard,
ol didn't talk to her...
She was'working, hard,
so I didn't talk to her...
Mr. Fujino left the kitchen
to give a cake to Conan.
During this short period,
the suspect murdered Ms. Hashigaki
{ - == 7)
Mr. Maeda. you were outside
the candy house too, right?
I was in the office from
N22 TO UV Jo SX ¥80 wes
12:25 to 12:35 since I was told
I was in the-office from
V2 WO U2 SineaO [I wears lo)
Id Lian
that somebody was on
the phone, waiting for me.
That somebody was on
You seem to remember
the time precisely.
Ah, well, it's... my habit to keep my eyes
on the watch when I do something.
Ah, well, it's...my habit to keep my eyes
You know, because
we use stuff like the oven...
Who else was in the office?
Only myself@The other staff
were out to lunch, I think...
I See.
So, after Mr Fujino left thissplace="
somebody murdered Ms. Hashigak#
So, after Mr. Fujino left this place,
somebody murdered Ms. Hashigaki
and Mr. Maeda found the dead body
when he-came back
from the office. Am I right?
Yes.
Ms. Morimoto. you
were the only one here.
Didn't you notice anybody coming in?
IN. mo...
The back of the victim's
head was severely injured
There could be a murder
weapon inside the museum.
Search throughout the museum!
Yes sir!
One of the chefs must
have killed Ms. Hashigaki
Then, the type of the»weapon
and how it was disposed of ,
would be the key to finding the suspect.
I think either Maeda or Fujino
must have killed Ms. Hashigaki.
What are you talking about!?
Yeah, it's gotta be, :because
you both were having trouble
with &hief Maeda,
owed her a lot of money,
and Fujino wanted to go independent.
Well. we aren't the only ones who were
having trouble with the Chief, were we?
What do you mean
She wanted to.quit the
candy-making performance,
because she was too confident
in the taste of her candies.
You were having an argument with
Chief right before she was murdered,
werenst you? I heard your
voice all the way across the hall.
It's true that Ms« Morimoto was having
an argument with Ms Hashigaki
Let me act as a chef!
It's possible that Ms. Morimoto
murdered the chief
Each kitchen is divided with partitions, so
nobody can 'see Ms. Morimoto from here.
But the same applies to the other
chefs too. The big tree gets in the way.
So. nobody can see what's going
on here'fro'm Ms Morimotds kitchen.
That means. the other two chefs
could've murdered Ms. Hashigaki as well.
You left here right after I left, right?
Don't you think it took
too long just to find the kid?
The east space is huge.
It'senot easy toxfind a person there.
Let me ask you then...
Don't you think it was TOO good
timing that you got a phone call?
The phone was already
cut when I answered the phone.
This us got-ta be a setup!
You could've been the one who called
and told yourself to come to the office.
You bastard!
Weill find out who killed
Ms. Hashigaki when we find the weapon!
Just to let you know, you are
the one who could kill Boss the easiest.
Right!
Ri ht!
The cakes are almost gone, huh? It's crazy.
HMM 7
A piece of wood
Sir! No weapons were found
Hmm. nothing was found...
Ah. the weapon isrgoneybecause it's
been eaten-already.
Can we think this way?
What do you mean by that?
This is a candy house.
It's possible that
the weapon was made of sweets.
Who would eat stuff
that was used to kill somebody?
But if we think that way,
the typesrof sweets would be limited.
It's not cookies
They would break
Not pies or tarts of course.
It can't be my chocolate.
Mine as well. is pretty soft.
Now what!
You're saying I killed her with,my gandy
and ate the sweet bloody weapon?
- - q 4
A candy as a murder weapon...
It's too big to.eat...
- - AA
Oh. I'm sory...
Maybe; shelmelted the candy.
What?
She put the candy into a pot
that was heated up beforehand
Is that what you are saying?
Didn't do that!
She could be the one
who did these things
because nobody could hear
or see what she was doing.
I. 1 didn't do it! Please!
Well
we'll find out. whether it's true or not,
after the identification
$s she the killer...
It's my dream to win a contest
with these candies, someday...
NO./Zit canst be...
Yeah, She cannot be the murderer.
This is...
How come pieces of wood
are in the kitchen?...
There was no
Wood chocolate making trial
when I came here yesterday.
I got it!
80 she W 'S being used...
But...it's not gonna go like that!
No...the murderer ls...
on ..an...
Hm! 2?
SS. Sonoko!?
Not, Ms. Morimoto.
Sonoko! That thing again!?
She was trying so hard) to, make
candies for the afternoon to convince
the chief that-she was good enough.
There are candies in her kitchen
for tasting. if you wanna see.
Ran, could you show everybody
the thing in my left hand?
Hm? OK...
Yes,
\\ looks like it is for tasting...
That piece of candy tells us
how-mueh she wanted
to be a chef andOnot a magician.
I just wanted her
to taste this one more time
Then,
who on earth murdered Ms Hashigaki?
The real suspect is...
The "Prince of Sweets
Mr. Fupino! It's you...
First of all
you called Mr. Maeda by phone
just to let him out of here.
Then, after making sure
Ms. Morimoto started using the blender
you left the kitchen.
From-this point. you can't see a thing of
what's going on
in Ms. Morimoto's kitchen.
Mr Fujino used this blind spot!
So are youisaying killed her with candy?
it's the wood chocolate!
Really! My wood chocolate?
That soft chocolate killed a person?
Let me explain!
It seems-that-this candy-house
IS totally made of sweets
the truth is that this is a wooden house
that's coated with sweets.
This was how he came.up with the plan
hiding the murder weapon
under the sweets
What!?
So he hid the weapon under
the wood chocolate, am I correct?
Right!
A piece of wood was
used to Kill the chief!
You are a very careless man.
You hid the piece of wood
that's smaller than-your wood chocolate
in your kitchen beforehand.
And then, you brought
the wood chocolate to Conan,
with the piece of wood hidden
under the tray.
You hit the back of the victim:s head,
with it.
Show Me the evidence If you say so!
The evidence
Iies in Mr. Fujino's corner over there.
Conan,
would you get the wood chocolates
for me, please?
Ore - + 8
Let me help you
Thank you, Ms!
Conan,
give everyone a piece of wood chocolate.
I'll pay for them.
give evepyone a piece of wood chocolate.
Sonoko,
there's something In the cake.
I can't cut it.
What is it?
There a real piece of wood in the cake...
Hmmmm!?
Fujino hid the murder weapon in the cake
put it on this trays
then...
as promised to Conan
He took the! real wooden chocolate
and 'went-outside
Chief was literally like a witch
that's on the wall of this candy house. >
She promised me to give me my own store
if I win a contest and
work with her for three years
So I wen a contest
with my wood-chocolate
and worked. for three 'years
I never complained at all
even fl had to-work like a bee.
as 'soon as "became popular.
Hashigaki took back
what she:said-before.
Sheevenswent as far as to say
sheswouldrtake the wood chocolate
away.fromime
Finally
sheisaid.there was no promise
made between us at all!
I, I just...
Let's talk at the station: yes?
The dream of becoming independent,
and his wood chocolate
that was a part of his life,
were both taken away by his chief.
For him,
Ms. Hashigaki was a witch,
who was trying to cage and eat him,
just like the one in Hansel and Gretel
Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA¢
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
w) (E
Background Music.
KAT WO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
UNI@HI 110OKA
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHVIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNIGHI'MIYASHITA #
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOU
Animation Dircctors.
MASATOMO SUDO
4, NY.
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWACGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHT KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA O
Chief Director
KENJIsKODAMA /
Produced By.
MS ENTE TAINMENT. LTD
in association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING:
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CON
( COSHO AOYAMA / SHOGAKUKAN: YTV -TMS
All Rights Reserve
Oh, no!
Oh. my chocolate cake!
No! What a waste!
Oh my god!!
You can eat it.
Its gonna be the same
when it gets to the stomach.
That's right!
what are you talking about!
Oome on!
{ You just need to find another
good chocolate cake:"store, right?
Hmmmmmmm
Oh yeah!
I think there's a delicious cake buffet
restaurant beside the train station!
What!?
We gotta hurry!Come on!
H. hey. \Sonoko, wait up!
Oh manO not again...
heres no flaw in my deduction.
Something is" gonna" Happen pretty soon!
But I won't let it happen!
"Ill not!
Next Conan.
Lucky Mans Suspense