Beer, camera. money.
The lucky man gets.whatever he wants.
But his luck makes others envious.
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I. Q. of an adult
No case is.left unsolved
with DetectiveyConan
Hmmmm...
Red for the first prize!
Blue for the"second prize!
Yello" Xfor the third prize!
Please, at-least the third prize...
Come om! Come om!
Nooo!
W. white...
There goes the winner!
Here you go!
Sigh
Come on!
Forget about ityGental
Yeah. it's just bad luck. It happens.
Yes. it happens.
Yeah, but...
At least,
wane a -iglia camera...
What!
Here goes the winner! The third,prize!
Oh, he's...
Mr. Owada..:isn't he?
Wow...he won a prize again...
So you know him?
He is the doctor at Beika Hospital
Oh, he's'a doctor!
No, he is a GREAT doctor
Heis enthusiastic,
and talented
He's kind to everybody toe...
Who would say bad about him Nobody.
Right...
Why:don't you see that doctor, Conan
Yeah. you:should!
It's ok! I'm healthy...
Ayumi?...
You said he won a prize again...
Yeah.
I think...
So beautiful!
Hmm?
He won the lottery ticket...
Really.
The lottery ticket too. huh...
He must be lucky.
He's too lucky, man!
I think
it"was last week that he won
Union Beer too, Mom told me.
I heard he's got tons of beer.
he won money, Union Beer,
and a digital camera within a week...
He won money, Union Beer,
he won money, Union Beer,
and a digital camera within a week...
ALL within a week!
What is going on? *
I'm home!
Yes!
Yeah!
Beer for a year!
I got it!
Hm!)
Oh. come on Union Beer...
You can't do this!
Pops...
What happened:to them?
I thought I got this letter 'cause I won,
but it was actually a letter of apology
that the drawing had been.postponed,
damn it!
The drawing had been postponed?
Yeah. truel!
But then...
What did Dr. Owada win?
THE LUCKY MAN'S SUSPENSE
Dr. O@wada didn't win the prize!?
Yeah
It AN Not be true...
Because the drawing is
postponed till next month...
oure right...
If this is what's really happening
then the rest of the prizes
cannot be real too.
WW; At do. ou mean?
ba? LU 4
it's true that he On the lottery. I saw it!
think it's also true
that he w 7 the digital camera!
We saw it, right!?
Es, ll did...
And you guys all saw it too...
BUT. not the exact moment...
(Eh. cheatingr
Hey. can you stay here?
OK. this way...
I admit. that I
cheated a bit...
Ildid it:.
Alright. go ahead!
Here goes the winner! The third prize!
So-it was
cheating
Its not fair!
Just as I thought...
Oh, but the doctor doesn't know this!
#iThis was actually,
Ce his wife's request...
What!?
The doctor's wife's request. you said?
Right
She asked me to give him
the third prize when he came over.
She said she wanted to cheer him up
since he had lost confidence
as a doctor...
Dr. Qwada saved my life before,
so Irwanted to: help him too
So you did it to return the favor...
But'it's still cheating!
That digital camera could have been
given to somebody else, right!?
Well.
Actually: the doctor's
wife.brought the camera,
when she came over to the tent.
What!
She brought it herself?
So that means.
Mrs. Owada gave you
the digital camera she bought.
And you gave itt ) Dr. Owadayamiisight?
Yeah: Nobody was victim,
even if it was atcheating.
Then...
This isn't a crime. is 1t?
I asked him!?
NO, I didnate
I @idnrt-ask Kim. to doithat.
the guy said the doctor's wife came...
Ok. first.of all. my husband is
doingipretty well at-work.
Hmmm,
e lost confidence as a doctor...
No. It can't be!
Why is it so different...?
It's weird
Yeah, it is...
I heard that you won Union Beer.
Is that true?
I heard there's been a rumor like that,
but that's not true either
because neither of us can drink.
There's no need for us
to send the letter in the first place.
Notieven the letter. "huh?
I think somebody has justimixed us up
with some other Owada
What's going on- 7?
She really asked me. trust me!
She was the doctor's wifé!
Em net lying!
She said she was Dr. Owada's wife.
She was a tall. slim, beautiful woman.
What's the point.of telling you a lie!?
I gotta go. I'm busy.
She was a tall, slim...
Beautiful woman...
Heh.,he...It can't be her...
It seems we're getting somewhere...
It seems to be true that
Dr. Owada won the lottery.
But the digital camera was a setup.
And, the Union Beer
wasn't even given to him.
It was a total lie.
Probably...
The tall, slim, beautiful woman
Is probably trying to
make everybody think that
Dr. Owada is a super lucky man
But what's the point of deing so anyway?
Yeah, she even bought
a digital camera herself.
It«s that!
What's waiting for her, after making
the doctor a super lucky man?
Here's your grand prize, a pocket tissue!
There's gotta be something...
Some kind of reason to it...
We never, win a.prize, do we?
But you know
Dr Owada at Beika Hospital
Yes I heard!He won the third prize. right?
He also wen the Union Beer.
Sounds like the doctor ,
IS sucking up fortune from us.
Yeah.
SO SO body was saying that,
too much luck ean actually
make other people envious,
and that could bring
about misfortune on the doctor.
Making others envious....?
That's true.
Envy IS a scary thing...
Yeah...
People envy others
when they are too luc +...
Maybe the purpose of that
woman s~action is...!
Or Owada is an amazing guy, right?
What? Yeah. he is.
I told you, nobody says bad about him,
right?
Yup!
He's not a guy
people hold a grudge against
He is not...
and maybe that's why
the woman has been acting that way.
What's the matter...Conan?
Maybe that woman is...
trying to make a forest.
A forest?
What.do you mean by a forest?
So then...
There should be many other luc « stories
about Dr. Owada. There must be.
Other lucky stories...?
Yeah,
andralso stories
about people envying him.
Perhaps the tall. slim. beautiful woman
IS where all those stories are coming from.
We're-gonna go out separately
to findout:who this woman is!
I'll do it-by"using some other route!
What. wast, all of a sudden?
If my deduction is correct,
then something is gonna happen
pretty soon!
Whaaat!
Huhuhuh...
He told me to find out who,
but where should I go???
Hmmm...
You mean Dr. Owadaiat Beika Hospital?
Yeah!
O. Owada?
I heard he found tons of gold coins
when he was digging a hole
in his bac \ ard!!
Really? Oh my, he must be lucky.
It's not all good stories though.
His tremendous luck is
actually making many people envy him...
Ah, excuse me...
About that story,
where did you hear about it?
About the people envying Dr. Owadal!
What!
A hundred million yen (a million dollars)!?
He founda big bag
with a hundred million,yen in it!?
Dr. Owada did?
I heard $0,
when he returned
the money to the owner
he received 5,000:000 yen
from the owner as a reward
He s a luc « guy. really.
From who.did yeu hear that story!?
It was one.of our customers, I think...
Wasn't that a woman
with a tall, slender body?
FT ee . *
Hmmm...
But why
That's ah...
I really don't know
but I swear some terrible thing
IS about to happen for sure!
- WA person who hates Dr. Owada?
It's a woman...
Tall and slim
I don't think there's anybody
that hates Dr... Owada in this world.
Dr Owada is loved by everybody
Not only by the patients
but also his co-workers
Fifi OU
Be...
Good afternoon
Oh. Dr Owada
How are you feeling today?
I-m quite well, thank you
That's good!
But take it easy, 0 «
Thank you, doctor.
Ok. take care...
There's nothing in the hospital...
Auch
Hiro!
I told you not to run inside the hospital!
I, I'm sorry.
But I'm glad that you can run now.
Yeah!
Having a fight with Dr. Owada?
Yeah...
Who would do
such thing to that great doctor?
It was a... woman... was shocked!
What!
Ah... Excuse me!
About what you just:said
a woman was having a fight
with Dr. Owada?
Hm? yeah. .
When?
It was about a'month ago...
Mrs. Shiina! Mrs. Shiina!
Please calm down, Mrs. Shiinal
Please. Mrs. Shiina
So she was called Shiina?
She was...
tall. and slim...
That must be her!
I think she was dressed in black.
Dressed in black...
It's me.
I found her
I found the woman!
Mitsu
Conan...
She's the one on the right.
She's living in
an-apartment around here.
Her name as Akiko Shima...
Shiina!
So you found her?
The one on the right.
I think I've met her before...
You're it, Mom!
Hey! Wait!
H, hey, Conan...?
I'm glad that Mrs. Shiina has got better.
Yeah.
I thought
she would never get over the shock
when her husband passed away.
Excuse me, Ms...
Shiina. .lose her husband?
Es...
A month ago. Mr. Shiina was hit
by a car. It was, a hit-and-run...
The ambulance came and took
him to the hospital right away, but...
Is that the motive?...
I heard
it was already too late
when the ambulance came to
1e scene O we accicen...
$0, it's not the doctor's fault?
What the heck is she trying to do?
Looks like sheers a Kind modther to me.
Who is she?
Conan...
What were you asking?
If!"
Now I remember!
I knew I saw her somewhere before.
She was there
He won the lottery
How can you laugh, you....!
As if nothing happened at:all...
witheut-moeurning'the'patient's death...
Hew could you act like that!
Now I see...
Perhaps
that was when she
decided to make the plan.
Let's go home...
What?
ou said something
IS going to happen soon...
Nothing is going to happen
I think. I was just imagining things .
Imagining things!?
Then why was
that woman making all those rumors
That's right!
The mothers told me that
she is a habitual liar,believe it or not.
A habitual liar...!1?
What a troublemaker
Man, you're the troublemaker.
Even you make a mistake sometimes,
Conan
Yeah.
3, 2%
Heh, heh. Now, let's go home!
FN ~~ 7
vs Lay!
I won't let anything happen.
I will not!
Where the heck are you going!? Conan!
To Doc s house!
I left my stuff there... Heh, heh.
Be careful!
Does it make you feel better,
if you kill Dr. Owada, Mrs. Shiina?
I'm Mouri,.a private detective.
I heard some strange rumors
about Dr. Owada
so I did some investigation
and ended up with a person...
you, Akiko Shiina.
I heard your husband was hit by a car
A'month ago
When the ambulance
arrived at Beika Hospital
Everybody knew that nothing
could be done.it was too late.
But it was
Dr. Owadawho was on duty
that night.He did his best.
You're gonna be just fine! I'm gonna
save you, so don't die!
Come on!
He tried the best he could do,
to save your husband'sife.
Of course it was Dr. Owada's fault.
And you knew it too.
You knew it, but.
How come:you couldn't save him!
Why! Why!
As a matter of fact
The driveriTWhQ hit your husband [is * \
the one to be hated,
He ran:awa
so there's noiclue whatsoever
about who he is...
Dr. Owada was the only 'one.
Whom you 'could: vent your:anger out on.
Evenrif'you knew that it was wrong...
Then,
\ your irrational anger against
the doctor reaches its peak...
after a half month passed.
How can you laugh, you...
As if nothing happened at all...
without mourning the patient's death...
How could you act like: that!
You felt it was unforgivable...
and:you-even:felt:that
you-wanted:to Kill'him.
You, however, knew that
Nobody hates or holds a grudge
against Dr. Owada.
If you just murdered him,
It was obvious thatgyou were
going to be the first suspect.
Because
people witnessed
you having a fight-with Dr: Owada...
You wanted to kill the doctor.
you cannot be arrested no matter what.
If you get arrested...
there will be
no future for your little children...
So you came up with a plan...
TheJrumors
about Dr. Owada as a man ofigood. luck.,
umade them up...
Dr. Owada is so lucky,
he's almost too lucky.
So: there are many people, envying him...
That's'what:you wanted
to make people-think.
They weren't just simple rumors.
You changed them
to make them sound more realistic.
This circumstance made it is safe
for you to murder Dr. Owada,
since the police would think that
one of the envious people murdered him.
Moreover, it would be impossible
to find out who actually did it.
You created a fake situation
in which there were a lot of people
with motive of killing the octor.
That way, you would
just one of those people
who might be envious
enough to kill the doctor but didn't.
It's like hiding a tree in a forest.
If there's no forest, then you can just make one.
You made up all those rumors
so they would disguise you
But Mrs. Shiina...
No mattenhow well you try,
t's just a matter of time.
A criminal attempt
can never be-kept hidden.~...
But...
It's not too late...
Because nothing has happened yet...
Nothing has happened yet...
you can always still turn back.
Now, please go home,
before. your-beloved children wake up!
MM... Mr. Mourn...
I will...l will never do this again.
I Know
It's gonna be alright.
You will be able to get over it
I guarantee it.
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Froducecrs.
MICHIHIKO SUWAy
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
By, ¢
Bacleround Music.
Character DesignsSBy.
MASATOMO SUDQ~
Story Editor. *
JUNIGHI 11OKA
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHTWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCH1
JUNIGHI MIYASHITA
YUICHIMHICURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
mo an » org O
Arnnnnir or Jif tf UL
AK! " AWAMuM
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJIZKODAMA
S ENTERTAINMENT, LTI
in association with
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CON
w cosno AOYAMA / SHOCAKUKAN-YTV - ms
All Rights Reserved
Good morning. everyone!
Lord, please give them a peaceful day!
1 ef]
Good morning!
Nothing has happened»:
Nothing...
I .guess I did:-something without realizing it,
didn't 1?
Oh well, it's all good! Hahahahaha!
The luckiest guy
in this world may be himwy
Gadlinlw
A gun!
What's going on!?
Hurry! We gotta get outta here!
Genta! Come on! Harry up!
It's game over..isn"t it?
DERAISE 2 EE 510%
Fugitive TV Game