The members of the Youth
Detective<Squad are today's hero
A boisterous racket breaks out
Right before the game soft
appears on the market.
9 He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I. Q. of an adult
No case is*tleftc<unsolved. ~~
with DetectiverConan
Hey'-Look!
It's-there!
1. So that's where Gadlin is made, isn't it?
Wow! Itss amazing!
Yeah. IskAGW!*,
FE 1sdTe 2
Kya?!
It's so cool
I really¢canyt wait...
So, is that it?
Is-that the TV game
you all got hooked on?
That's
a...Ga...Gad... Gadl...
Gadlin!!
And! This is where
the awesome game is being made!
Fr or ee».
It's. Shining!
How can you forget, Conan!?
Gadlin is. a-million=seller TV game,
you Know...
This is episode one!
I think you are the only one
who doesn't know about this TV game...
Haha
I don't care...really...
Episode two 1s gonna come out.
Finally next week!
There were seven mysteries left
unsolved in\episode one,
but everything is{gonna to be solved A
in the secondlone.
But everything is gonna to be solved
In the second one.
Man!
I really can't wait!
What's waiting at the end!
1 Gadlin! Please, tell me!
H. hey!
Where do you guys...
think you're. going?
Hey, wait!
What the....!
Shoots...
Oh. no!
FUGITIVE TV GAME
Ah. guys. can I he'! Nou?
What! Oh!
Ah, yes
Actually, ah
Could you do us a favor!?
Could you tell us the seven
mysteries in Gadlin Il, please!
You don't have to tell us everything.
Just a little! Please?
I cannot do that
Ok then, what about a hint?,...
Yes?
Fuh. fun.
I'm sorry...
Yeu have to wait until it comes out
Mr. Genta Kojima,
from Teitan Primary School!
What!?
Do you knew my namely,
Off course!
You are famous...
Fuh fun
Rat's not s0000 true
You got your name tag
on your backpack...
What!
Bon.
Hm----Oh
Man. I gotta go!
I gotta go to washroom...
What!
Washroom!?
OR, please, Genta!
I really can't hold it! I'y; in danger!
I'm gonna use your washroom. oK!?
Oh, hello!?
What the!
Genta!
Oh my god. Where is it?
Hey. what are you doing here!?
What!?
You can't come up here!!!
Man, I'm gonna pee in my pants!
Let me use your washroom, please!
Genta!
Hey. you! Wait!
Oh no! Don't tell me it's a dead end!
Come on. hurry up!
Washroom. ..Is it this way?
Kids, where are you!
Let's go. guys!
Where's the washroom...
Which floor is the washroom!y
eo . --
O, "TV
Come in...
President Michiba!
The subscription sales of Gadlin ll
have gone over two hundred thousand!
It's gonna be a huge hit.
Even bigger than the first one!
Of course...
For Gadlin II
I worked my ass off.
Aldtwn
It's got to be a huge hit...
U Ill In
Norikazu Michiba.
A genius game producer...
AND, also a genius scenario writer...
Wall,
Iet's do the final check...
You can never be too sure, right?
See you later
Michibal
Gadlin is
my idea. Both the first and second one!
It was what I wrote when I was in college!
It was all in my notebook!
And you just stole, them all,
without my permission!
So...What are you trying to say?
I'm gonna tell the media
that you stole my ideal
See you in court!
Gosh Darn it!
What the!
You think. I'll let you do that, bastard!?
Uh Ugh...
Kobayashi was murdered
two nights ago...
in this room...
Who the hell are youl?
I'm a detective hired by Kobayashi.
Kobayashi had been
searching for evidence of plagiarism,
In order tO sue you.
So for his evidence searching
I was hired to spy on you
with a hidden camera
Yeah, it was worth doing it...
With two hundred, million yen
you can buy this disk.
What are you talking about!?
Hey! Stay right there!
Sorry, I just don't wanna be shot
Iike Kobayashi.
Oh yeah. before I forget.
If anything happens to me,
the master tape of this movie,
will be played in public, just so you know.
Now again, it's two hundred million yen.
You earned tons and tons of money
with Gadlin I.
This much meney is nothing to you, right?
But remember,
I am not here to negotiate with you!
Ok.I'll givesyou-the money
Aha... Yeah, that's my friend...
Mr. President...
Mr. President
But in Hell!
Oh, darn it!
No! You bastard!
@ough, cough!
O No. don't!
Where the heck did they go?
He's gone...
Hey. where's Genta?
Ugh...
Where is the master tape?
Say it!
Gh...
Or, you wanna die, right now?
Now I'm back!
It was close though...
What...Where is this!?
Hm! Hmm! Hmmmm!
Ugh sez
Looks sO nice. Whose room is this...
Hmm!
Oh... ATV game?~
Gadlin...two...
No way,
It's Gadlin II!
Genta!
Where the heck were you!?
We weré+worried about you!
QQUGF- IS SI O0 mg OI US.
He's mad.
Look what yousdid!
We gotta get-outta here right now!
Com ten¥Gentali Hurry up!
Guys?
Ahhhhh!!
M sorry
ait!
Its nothing!
Kids, stop!
Here youare!
Mr Michiba!
Get them, go!
They stole Gadlin II!
What!
A e esairs. e coming 00.
Yes, sir!
I'm over if that disk goes public!
Come on, hurry!
Oh my god!
Hurry up!
Conan!
Now. hurry,
What the.
Wait!
Where did they go?
Outside! Outside!
Man!
A gun'?... What's going on?
Alright
Oh! I'm so sorry!
What are you doing here!?
Is that your friend!
Forget it!
Get outta here!
I'm sorry. I couldn't catch them.
What!
They all had a bike..ll could never imagine
kids sneaking into a.huge
building and stealing things!
You! gotta be kidding!
Whe the hell are they!?
Sorry...
He is...
He is.
I remember his name is Genta Kojima,
from 1eitan Primary School.
Teitan Primary School....?
Genta... Kojima!
Should I call the police?
No. don't! I'll go!
You guys go back to work!
YGSLrlSiE- - -
Those kid's think that the disk is Gadlin ll.
They'll play it as soon as they get home!
I must prevent it, or else, we are over!
Search the address of Genta Kojima
from Teitan Primary School!
Now I see what us' happening.
When you get the info, go to his
house before:-him..got.it, Bee!?
Be {7 Is that the name of his partner?
For kids. it would take
30-minutes to get:ito Beika Town.
If they don't come home
within 30 minutes. then...
Darn!
What bad timing!
The bug is broken!. Man!
They are in danger!
Genta!
Mitsuhikol!
Fumi!
Beika. Beika.
Please do not forget your
belongings when leaving the train.
What are we gonna do?
Those guys looked mad
I just used the washroom
What's wrong with that?
I'm so hungry since we ran so hard
Well... This happened because you
went inside the building all of a sudden!
Hey. are you listening?
What the
What?
What as it. Genta'?
Ah. yeah...
Actually...
What? "Ce
I got something...in my bag...
T. this is...
@adlinill, lish it.?
I can't believe it!! a
It's real! Although
this is the dummy version,
it's the real Gadlin II!
Hmm . Hahahahaha!
Yeah I know...
But Genta, howron
the earth didayou get this?
Well, actually...it was
just inside my backpack
ur... Backpack. you said all
How?-How on-earth did I get this?
Ah... It'stthe fancy room!
No wonder they were
trying so hard to catch us...
I see..So this.is the; reason why...
Genta! We are [inja pretty
serious situation, right now.
That's right.
Although it'wasn't intentional,
this is still stealing
Although it Wasn't intentional,
this<is still. stealing.
Plus. the game is not in store yet...
fir
Stealing? 7.
MR ,» ,.
ET Tra,
YeahODid you think jig
those guys'wére chasing
US recause you usec * 1@ was room.
TIE 4B 3
Finally, the suspect. a primary school boy,
Genta Kojima, has been
arrested by the Police!
% According to the Police,
it's been found that the suspects
1s involved in many other 4
crimes other than the Gadlin ll 'case.
G, Genta!
Re BR
Genta!
Genta-Kojima
Weé've.got all the evidence already!
You-re the
who broke the headmaster's vase,
aren't you!?
I knew you didn't do your
homework three days in a row
and also skipped your cleanup duty.
We've got a witness
saying that you didn't wash
your hands before eating your lunch
Come on! What are you, a beast!?
Have you forgot your own language!
We know you did it!
Come on, spit it all out!
Genta Kojima!
Waal! I'm. sorry!
Waa!
Ugh Ugh
I think you sh 01d tdirn yourself in, Genta!
But before that... I wanna eat grilled eel
Tonight's supper is
grilled eel... Mom told me!
It's notitoollate yet-right?
What the
It's been an hour already...
Those Shining people must think that
the kids have'seen what's in the disk.
They:re. seriously in danger!
Hmm?
They're back!
Hey!
What the!
Hmm!?
My god!
Everyone!iMove!: Move!!
Oh no!
Ouch... Hmm! »
Man'. That guy is seriously mad! Let's go!
Ayumi! Hurry up!
WwW. wait-!
M \ wv / » Yo  {
\ Vo A - rt.
Take this!!
Ugh...
Hey! Wake up!
Take that gun...and kill them! Bee!
Go...Now!
That was his partner, Bee.
Bee has a gun and is
chasing everyone now
Genta!
Mitsuhiko!
Ayumi.
Where are you all?
It's possible that they went there...
Hurry, Genta!
I'm starving... I can't walk anymore...
2. fl Rn
Be a man! You're the one
who caused this. trouble!
Let's just go and put the game back.
And.apologize
Let's go!
No one's here...
It was here...
Then, put it there...
LIK 7...5,
I'm sorry!
I hope our apology 1s accepted.
I hope so too...17?
Gental?
Hey! Can we watch Gadlin ll
just a little, before we go?
Oh, no!
Don't! Genta!
What are you doing!?
Only the seven mysteries. Just a little...
The seven mysteries!
Just a little, yeah?
Gadlin is my idea.
Both the first. and second one!
What.is this.%:.?
Not a chance!
Oh! You. bastard!
You stole my Gadlin!
Now you're stabbing me in the back
Just because you can't beat me! Michiba,
you haven't changed at all
since you were in college.
Silence!
How hard .do=you think "worked
on creating this software?
Ugh!... You... filthy... bastard...
No way!
It..It-s the woman
that-was at the front desk!
Yes. it was me.
What!
You saw what's in the disk.
Now I have to kill you all...
uh, fun...
No. Please:.don't!
No! I have to eat mom's grilled @el...
Really. That's too bad. Genta...
As I suspected, it was you
Yukari Hachisuka
Conan!...
When Michiba-called his
partner "87. it dawned on me that
B" stood for Bee, an in
In Japanese, bee is "hachi...
Hachisuka...Your last name
has also the word, hachi in it,
so I concluded that
Bee was your code name.
I guess you are in a relationship
with Michiba, aren't you?...
Yes. We are gonna get married; soon.
And in order to protect
our promised future,
I would do anything! +
Anything, literally...
Conan!
Ms! Please, don't!
Did you know?...
That all this conversation is
being recorded by the police
C. cellphone!
Yukari Hachisuka! You're under arrest for
attempted murder of Conan Edogawa!
It's game over...isn*tit...
Yukari Hachisuka and
President Michiba were, thus, arrested.
The blackmail detective was found alive.
Also, the kids seemed
to have learned that
their stupidity had caused a lot of trouble.
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKCTSIUWZ?
MASAHITO YOSHIOKAY
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
Ala -
Story Editor.
UNIG@HI 110OKA
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHTWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHIEMIYASHITA
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Dir (TOT
vias NER 2
HARUD OOGAWARA
ATS "SHI AOND
TAKASHI HYODQO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWACGA
Recording Director
Ia NR v  A 4d >»
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU GKADA
Chief Director
KENJIgKODAMA
} IMS ENTERTAINMENT, A TD
in association wythr
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CON
(> COSHO AOYAMA / SHOCAKUKAN:-YIV IMS
All Rights Reserved
If I didn't-go to the washroom
the murder case would
have still been left unsolved am
Yeah, you are right!
Good job. Genta!
You're the man. Genta!
Hahahahahahaha!
We are gonna fight the evils.
We are the ones to save this town!
Yeah!
Youth Detective Squad. Banzai!
Oh, man! Haven't they
Iearned the lesson!?
Oh, shoots!
Hmm? That is...
A uniform of the Jaguars...
Police!
How did you know...?
The Silent Seaway Part