Today, an out of the ordinary talk
show between a baseball player
and Pops in Okinawa
Turns into a murder case.
He sees through the one and only truth
A child In appearance
with the I.Q. of anyadult
No case is left-unsolved
with-Detective;Conan
You haven't changed. have you, Nose...
The way vou tilt vour neck to«the
right when'yolG*run... that-habit-of yours...
Mo.Motoyama~
What brings you here?
It's lorily just past 9:30 yet?!
Bi told. ou over the
phone last night, didn't I...
That I'd fly overiiffor you...
Huh?
Like Hideyoshi... would...
HA AA
(ma)
The Silent Travel Route Part 1!!
What?! We're going
to Okinawa tomorrow?!
You didn't tell me about it at all!!
You know him, don't you?
The King of Save; Toshizo Nose of
the professional baseball team', Jaguars!
Nichiuri, TV. has asked me
to have-a chat session with himil
But, I wonder:why they chose you, Pops?
A professional baseball player
and detecti. don't seem
to have much in.common...
Huh?LH
Are you dumb or w atl
Nose is known as the b ah pitcher
player of the baseball world!
It's his sharp-eye of
discerning the habits and
type of ball the batter will hit
against my power of deduction!!
Naha, ha ha, ha.
Are you sure you can handle it?
I hear that Nose is a very
difficult person to deal with.
Don't worry! I hear that this sport
talent who is on good terms with Nose
Thank you very much,
we re counting on you I
Don't worry! I hear that this sport
talent who is on good terms with Nose
Thank you very much,
we're counting on you. ll
will join in on our conversation too.
( Pleas
Will join in "Th our conversation too.
So:'that was Mr'. Kigure
training here in Miyazaki!
(ho eons O Ho all Suiitexie!
A straight victory for the Falcons!
Thank you very much.
Then, Mr. Motoyama, you're
scheduled for a talk show
with Mr. Nose tomorrow
in Okinawa, but be careful
not to let him talk your
ears off like the:player did today...
I'll be fine!. Nose is
my best friend and besides,
renown detective Mr. Kogoro Mouri
will piteh in to 'hélp me tomorrow too!
See]
What time is your flight tomorrow?
I think it's departing at 6:35 in the
morning from Haneda Airport tomorrow... 4
because Nose's seems to
only have the morning open.
What?! Which means we
have to get up before 5:00?!
BAvih 2
Then, we'll have to get redy and
hit the sack early t&dday. too, Conan!
Okay!
Hey. hey, I'm going alone...
Right, let's run over to the convenience
store now and pick up stuff that we need!
Okay. let's! Lets go!
We've got hurry, 'cuz we don't have time!
I tell you, Dad, you
should've told us earlier.
Hi there, Nose! Did you
watch the program?
My corner that was aired a while ago...
Yeah ..yot'Ymean the news
program-oniNichiufi TV
that's aired-at around.
6.30 in the:evening...
Right'...
Sorry...l was out eating and missed it.
I'mygoing out drinking with
someryoung players who are
training here with me now
Pidyou want anything?
No. alll wanted t@ say was
see \ ou at the tdlkishew tomorrow...
Same here, and help me out
if the detective Kogoro Mouri
digs in*too deep. will you!
By the way, Motoyama.
Don't miss your flight tomorrow!
Youire.notithatigreat:getting
up inithesmorning*youirknow...
I'll be fine: sincefimy;flight
Ieaves at.8:155inithemorning...
You know I'll fly over if for you right...
Just like Hideyoshi would...
Hideyoshi?
Ha, ha, ha, then 'm I supposed
to be'Nobunaga or something?
It's:true that I'm the one who got
you that TV job afteriyou retired but...
I only did it out-of goodwill
because we entered/the team
gat that same time! No need
to feel obligated or anything!
OR, the"young ones are here, gotta go...
See youitomorrow!
Yeah». . .,Don't drink
too miuch!-You've got the
Japan record career save
on your shoulders, you know
Yeah!
Phooe
IiYou. Nobunaga?
Ou're Mitsuhide...
@f all things...
they've come along with me after all
What's wrong? When you
called the TV station last might,
they said they'd pay for
Conan and I 100. didn't they?
Thanks to you guys: my seat was
ranked down to a regular seat, though...
Oh, the Okinawan food that I ate
Iast time I went was really delicious!
My plans of having a ball over
food a drinks with an Okinawan beauty...
Darn!
Don't*worgy! I'll just take pictures! with my
digital camera:and won't get in your way
Huh? Did you have a digital camera?
Yep.
Rememberdthe one that
you won at the yearn end party.
Kyah!
oh! fi'm so sorry!
Oh! l.I'm so sorry!
IFm-sorry! T,Thank you very much
Why did you bring tennis balls with you?
Well, a boy in my class that's
in the baseball club who was watching
the program last night, asked
me to get him Mr NosO's autograph.
I told them that I didn't
have the card to write
autographs on'gthen they
said anything is okay: so...
I brought the tennis
balls that Sonoko gave me .
The bll'that dad used for
the community baseball game
was all soiled and dirty besides...
Do&? foun balls mean
there are four members
In your class that are
in the baseball club?
There are three boys and
the other one is for m.me...
Oh, It's Eri, isn't it?...
She used to be a Jaguar fan...
Right! So dlease. will you
get his autograph for mother?
No darn way!! I don't
want to stick a tennis ball out
at a baseball player
and ask for his autograph...
Ha, ha... true...
Thank you for waning, Mr Mourn
WM oan Teramshir-otdNchiun TVAOKI aw. lee
Oh, hello. I'm here with my daughter!
Huh? Daughter? Where Is she?
Agh?!
Hey! Where do UU think you're going?
I'm going to go see
if they sell autograph cards!
I tell you... By theyway,
how's the you know what?
Oh, you mean at night, night?!
Yes. I've reserved a great place!
Oh! No
Oh! No...
We're canceling that!
I'm talking about the other stuff
O.Oh... that
OO. ON... that.
I.asked Mr. Motoyama who
will join in on the talk show
today. and he agreed just like that...
That's good to know!
And, Mr. Motoyama has already
arrived here from Miyazaki?
No...He'll be on the flight arriving at 9:50
so we'll have to wait another 30 minutes.
That's the only. flight there is from
Miya-aki to Okinawa
Then, shall I take my
daughter and the boy
to the hotel that
Mr. Nose will be staying at?
I guess so...but I don't think
Mr. Nose is there
Huh? Why not?
He seems to routinely do rond work
from 9:00 to 10:00" the moerming...
Sor lem surcathat he in the nudst of
running along a road
somewhere near the hotel...
You know about it, don't you?
The "great revenge of Hideyoshi.
That is, Mitsuhide who: wanted to
kill Nobunaga and rule over the world.
The superhuman act of Hideyoshi,
going from Okayama to Kyoto
in as little as three days to take revenge.
E...l hate to say this,
I'minot letting. you. get to the top.
Whatithe?!!
Hey, how long are you
going to keep searching?
Mr. Motoyama's flight
should be arriving soon!
Well, I can't find
autograph cards anywhere!
@kay!ljigl get autographs
for your friends for you, then...
Really!! You'll get
mother's too then, right?
No way
Wow, what's wth you!
Um, do you know where
they sell autograph cards near here?
Autograph card? Let's see...
The nearest place is...
Oh, There he is!
Motoyama. over here!
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting...
How do you do?
I'm Detective Kogoro Mouri!
I'm Masaharu Motoyamal
I've heard allot about you...
h I'm his daughter...
I'm sorry!
We don't have much time, so let's
continue the introductions in the car...
Oh. all right -
Shall we get goingithen.,
Okinawa sure 1s a nice place
Too bad it's raining. though...
Huh?! Hey! Let's go.sonny!
Oh. okay...
Oh, okay...
Mr. Motoyama seems
to be a kind person so
maybe I'll be able to ask
him for Mr. Nose's autograph...
Y Yep... guess SO...
It seems that Nose hasn't
returned to the hotel yet...
Maybe he 'got.tired: on
the way back andliis resting
somewhere? After all,
he's not all that young...
I mean yousknow...
Aha, ha, ha...Huh?!
Huh?! That's...
iden, SAP exam (xe)
sleeping in a place like that!
I oo 1 TREE
the uniform of the Jaguars...
Ugh!
H. Hey. Conan!
Hey! Isn't he Mr Nose?!
N.No?!
Mr:-Nose?!
Yeah!!! MM My God!!
H. Hurry and contact
the police and get-an ambulance!
The police?!
Hey! Isn't he Mr. Nose?!
N.Now!
Mr:- Nose?!
Yeantt:-M My God!
H,Hurry and contact the
police and get an ambulance!!
The police?!
There's no nee
to call an ambulance...
Huh?
Mr. Nose has been
stabbedsin the stomach
with something and is already dead...
O...Oh no...
» Ran! You brought a digital
camera along, didn't you?
Y. Yes...
Let's take a picture of the
scene before the police get here
ddogoy
WC Agr a ganglia...» gv catwita...
Uh...
The digital camera...Digital camera...
Oly, Goo 18 Bs
HeyjpRan! You haven't
found it yet? Hurry it up, will you'll!
Oh. okay!
Farst from night above
take two or three pictures...
Be careful not go inside the grassy area.
Huh? What's wrong. Ran...
WV Well...
I was thinking of getting mom, a picture
of Mr. Nose. posing a guts pose...
And yet I end up
taking this kind of picture...
No cove O Voodoo
Sorry, never mind already...
I'll take the pictures
so you go back inside the car...
Okay
Hey, hey... This guy's
Nos of'thevdagldrars!!t
saw on fTV'that he
was trainin .over here...
The estimated time of death
is around- 9:30 this morning.
The cause of death is loss of blood from
being stabbed in the
stomach'with a knife...
The weapon hasn't
been found yet though...
And. where is' the person who found him? \
Oh, uh, I think 1t was...
Uh. who 1s the one that found the body...
Us. We coincidentally
happened to drive by and
found Mr. Nose lying on the ground!
He was probably stabbed
%If"
DY someone wil @ roac wor Ing.
Huh? If I remember correctly. you're .
Yeah...
that renown detective...
Oh, d'Yyou know me?
Mr. Kogoro Mouri...right?!
You re the talk of the town in Okinawa!
Yes yes yes, yes!
You're highly valued for your
tremendous appetite!... Right?
Well...
Hull?
Come to think of it,
Pops entered. 31 big-eaters
contest in Okinawa with Hattori...
So, it's almost as if the
case has been solved then!
We're counting on you!
I wonder if they really believe so...
I know somebody you can county
on more than Mr. Mouri, though!
Huh...
Sports talent. Mr. Motoyamal!
Huh?! Just what are
you talking about, sonny...
Because when we found Mr. Nose.
His blood was drained in the rain
and unless we went
up close to take a look.
We couldn't tell that he
was stabbed in the stomach!
Besides, if one knew
that Mr. Nose was road working.
Wouldn't it be most natural
to think that Mr. Nose fell ill
and was lying on the ground?
But. you said to call the-police.
Without even getting off the-car...
Hurry call an ambulance
and get the police!!!
Even Holmes can't
beat you as a detective!
How did you know that it was murder?
Come to think of it, bef re
I checked Mr. Nose's stomach
and mentioned him being stabbed you...
T.TeléPhone!
Tel@pHone?
After the TV appearance
Iast night, he mentioned-that...
a strange man claiming
to be an anti Jaguars
was troubling him with crank calls
Well, when I saw Nose
Iy ng on the ground,
I just felt that something was: wrongs
I's that true?
Well! guess it'll do you no
good to suspect me anyway,
because I couldngt
have committed the crime...
Just*what do you mean?
Because Mr. Nose's estimated time
of death is about 930 this morning. right?
Just around that time I was on
the flight that left Miyazaki at 8:15
and scheduled to
arrive in Okinawa at 9:50...
@Oheck the passenger's list!
Yes, sir!
Oh, uh,
I'm not onthe List...
Huh?! Why net?
km pretty:well known,
you know...l don't like people
making a fuss that I'veqalways
bought my tickets under an alias...
Besides, I was slightly
disguised wearing a hat and
all that I don't. think anyone saw me...
So. what was the alias that you used?
Huh?! Uh...
Yamada...no, maybe it was Tanaka?
Well, if Mr. Motoyama was in
Miyazaki last night. he has an alibi...
Because that's the only fight
that flies from Miyazaki to Okinawa...
Please go ahead and ask the hotel
in Miyazaki that I spent th night at.
YA/ANI
NCESS
"it.
Ah, the Miyazaki Prince Hotel. room number...
YAZAK
NCESS
TIL.
Ah, the Miyazaki Prince Hotel. room number...
I called Mr. Nose on
my cell phone last night
SO please check the outgoing
calls record of that room.,.
@Okay. hurry and check it out!!
Yes, sirl
Okay, then everyone. could I ask all
of you to come with me tosthe station...?
Darn, it was supposed to be the
great chat show of all three of us...
Great chat show?
Oh, he's from Nichiuri TV
of Okinawa, and was scheduled
to have a chat with
Mr. Motoyama today. but...
Who would've even
imagined we'd run into
Nose's corpse while
heading ever to his hotel...
Well§we'll get to the
details back at the station ten...
Oh, Inspector!
Huh?
We found. this near the corpse...
A time table-and can of tennis balls?
Oh, they're mine!
I'm sorry! I seem toihave
droppedsthiem when lgottoff tlhe car...
Inspector! It's been confirmed!
About the phone call...
Itys true that Mr. Motoyama
called Mr. Nose from
Itys trye that Mr Motoyama
his hotel in Miyazaki
at 19:20 to 19:23 yesterday.
Sea'?...
Well, even without it , I appeared
Iive on TV from Miyazaki last night...
Viewers all over the nation es
will prove my 'alibiforime.
Come to think of it, that's true.
And? Have you heard of
any characteristics of the man
who was making crank calls to Mr. Nose?
No...all he said was an odd man.
An odd man...eh...
It sure is strange. though...
I confirmed with his
other teammates. but
none of them seems to have
heard of any crank calls
heard of any crank calls.
Most naturally.
Nose was the much feared
guardian of the Jaguars,
SO I'm sure he couldn't
mention anything about
being frightened over 'a crank call,
I, however, have been
best friends with him for a long time
and there was nothing we
didn't talk about with each other...
Now that you mentioned it,
you entered the team
at the same time as Mr. Nose, didn't you?
Y. Yes.
You were awarded King of Save
and Best Rookie the first year...
But, I damaged my
shoulder the 2nd Y8ar.ee.aNJ
underwent an operation.
However, I never regained
my pitching velocity
and resigned in my 5th year...
I gave in te the 2nd-year jinx, and was
no more than a one ime cluteh player...
I was planning to tell
the young players who are
training here with
Nose here tomorrow. but...
Under the circumstances
I guess it'll be better to cancel
the interview of the young players
we were planning to hold tomorrow...
At any rate, please arrest
the murderer as soon-as possible...
The devil who got in the way of my best
friend making his Japan record of saves...
No. not right...
He s the killer
Oh, can I make a phone call?
I'll be done 'in a minute.
Sure go ahead...
But, he has an alibi
Why en earth...
What?
What the...
What is this?!
What's this thing that I feel?!!!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Pr od uce r S
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHI@KA
Backoround Music.
Vi SUO ON 3
1. AS
Charadter Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO #
Story Editor.
JUNIGHI 11OKA
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
TOSHIKI INOU
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
> oy A - ) CZ. q
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWACGA
Recording Director
Editor.
TER MITSU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN]! KODA MA \
Produced By
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in association with
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CON
Cc GOSHO AOYAMA / SHOGAKUKAN YIV TMS
All Rights Reserve
Conan...Conan!
What's the matter? Are you all right?
\ARER = leaning) Yoel!
you have on your face...
Hat was that....?'2
I found the seat, but you
can't go straight. okay. then...
Well.-that's natural too...
because you killed him...
The Silent Travel Route Part:2.