Today's stage is also Okinawa!
An alibi trick that gees through the sky
See. throug! \the cae
with deduction:from a different angle
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
+ No case is¥left.unsolved
with Detective Conan.
- Ae em"
ae TS a "Wm 9h
WA TV program is to be aired
with professional -baseball player
Toshizo Nose.
Sports: talent"Masahanu Motoyamn,
and Pops in a talk show
0 We all head oft to Okinawa
We join Mr. Motoyama at Naha Airport,
and go to see Mr. Nose, however.
Mn the way...
Huh?...
That's
the Jaguars uniform...
IW. 4
FF Ugh~~~11 »
Ugh~=~=~{?
Isn't that Mr. Nose?!
H.Hurry call an ambulance
and get the police!!
P.Police?!
At an rate
please arrest the murderer
1S SOON as possibilc
The devil who got in the way of my best
friend making his Japan record of saves...
No. not right...
e's the Killer...
He's the killer
Huh?
What the...
What's this?!
Uu.ugh.
(152 #)
(152%)
The Silent Travel Route Part 2
(132 #3)
Conan!!
What's the matter...
AO So ell) nie
What a frightening look
It.It's nothing...
Oh...
I was surprised too...
Well, I'll tell you the details
Well. I'll tell you the details
n later
What was that just now...?!
Oh. right!
Please lend me, the car key.
Mr. Teranishu,
I forgot something in the car...
Yikes!!
May I ask you something?
WwW. What is it. sonny...
The key of the hotel of Miyazaki,
that you just had
Isn't disposable, 1s 117?
YAZAKI
NCI'SS
AA JIC 3) GX
it to the froritfdesk
when you checked out?
1.l haven't checked out yet...
I've got another interview
in Miyazaki day after tomorrow...
you were: planning to have
an interview tomorrow too, right?"
Going back to the hotel in Miyazaki.
Then coming back again,
isn't that a waste of plane fare?
You couldn't have known before hand
that the interview tomorrow
was going to be cancelled,
did you?
I This brat...
Did you find what you forgot?
It must've been my mistake...
Thanks for this
bash
By the way...
why are you all here?
Well,
they say they re doing
another circumstantial investigation,
where Mr Nose was found dead.
Well
It's just to be sure .
Um. excuse me.
Are you left handed?
No...
But your caught the: key;
with your left hand just a while ago...
Oh...
It's a habit!
I used to be an ace number 4 player
of the baseball club until high school...
And...
Huh?
Why did you use such a back street
to go to Mr. Nose's hotel?
The main roads around that area
are crowded just about that time of day...
That's why although
it's the long way around,
we can get to our destination faster
using the back road.
Huh?
Wait a sec...
. (P=
If ll remember correctly...
Hm sure that sure that...
This IS it!
I get it
So. that's what it was...
It's not that
He couldn't...
No doubt about it...
The killer is Mr Motoyama
He-<s the one who killed Mr. Nose.
He used the back road of the sky
to his advantage
Hmm...
Inspector!
I've finished asking around!
And. did you find any witnesses'
Well...
there was no one who passed by here...
just about the time
Mr. Ncose was killed around 9:30) am.
Hmm-nNnoe
witness. weapon nor evidence. eh...
Let's take it easy and take our time.
Inspector!
There's still a lot of time before it's time
for us to board our plane for Tokyo.
besides
If you think carefully
you may come up with evidence
that the killer inadvertently forgot
to get rid of!
That the killer inadvertently forgot
0 Oe 6) Uf
that the killer inadvertently forgot
to get-ind of!
Yo Fat. cut out
your irresponsible comments...
Ha. ha. ha.
U.Uh pi
I'm sorry...
but could I be excused
to get something to eat?
TI haven't had a bite since I'vejcome here.
Growl...
True...
Ne problem,
I'll wait here,
$0 go ahead.
ould you like to some along to<
I guess so
I guess so...
Let's take my car,
and go all together then!
Thank you...
This is a restaurant that I come to often,
and it's quite delicious!
Oh...
Let's eat and return
as soon as we can then!
Huh?!
@ops, it's from
the producer of the TV station...
We'll
wait forityou inside the restaurant then,
so .when you're done
couldiyou lock the car and come...
78-49
TE -14
We'll go on ahead...
18-43
Conan!...
O.Okay...
Hello. Motoyama here.
What's up?
Ll Ye
00 xt er eal Oo tu) 0 Om fon)
that rang once and hung up.
That's why I'm returning your calls...
thoughththat maybe something new
came up regarding Mr Noeose's case...
I thought that maybe something new
came up regarding Mr. Nose's case...
Oh, sorry
I think I may have mistakenly
pushed the button...
I'll contact you if anything comes up...
Goodb e.
What are you doing. Conan?
Oh. well
I was just thinking what a great detective
Mr. Motoyama is.
Fool!
You re talking about him sensing that
Mr. Nose was killed
Yourre talking Bout him sensing that
just as soon as
he saw him lying on the ground,
right?
Tl at Mr. Motoyama sensed
It because he knew that. somebody
had been threatening Mr. Nose!
Lal)
Remember,
what Mr. Motoyama told me at the airport!
What?
Let's go. sonny!
Huh-7?
Huh
Let's go. sonny!
So why does that
make him a great detective?
Because I was away
from you and*Ran back then
and talkingto the security guard.
Huh?
But you still could tell that
I was supposed to be with you.
That's what you call super deduction,
right?
C.Come to think of it...
That's strange.
Because this is the first time
we ever met...
Well,
I guess we can talk
it over having a meal...
Wow!
The place is packed!
I wonder if there are
an ..empt seats. ..7
E .en one!
This way! Over here!
He's found us seats.
But it's hard to get straight over there...
Okay. then!!
The back road!
There. I'm already here!
Taking the longer way,
got me here faster!!
Te 8 Re
As long as I get rid of this.
Nobody will ever be able to see
through the crime-that I...
I'm sorry,
but will you please
get the timetable from my bag?
I forgot what time our fight is.
3 fils
1. Thank you
Oh. that's right!
An acquaintance asked me to get him
a souvenir from Okinawa...
Will you tell everyone
to go ahead and finish the meal
without me,
because I want to go get
the souvenir first?
Well, after I'm done.
I'll buy some bread or something
and join you all...
Oh. all right!
Fiih
Kugh. kugh. kugh. kugh. kugh...
Ha ha ha. hall
Ha. ha, ha, ha!!
My. my...
Ha ha...?7.
Ou seem to be enjoying yourself a lot...
Your best friend passed away
and you look to be quite over
the grief already...
Well,
I guess it's only natural...
because you're the one who killed him...
D.Don be ridiculous...
You even said I have an alibi...
Nose was killed.
If I remember correctly...
at about 9:30 this morning...
I arrived on the 9:50 axm. flight
from Miyazaki to Okinawa, you know...
Moreover,
that is the only flight from Miyazaki.
And I was on the program that
as aired livein Miyazaki. wasn't 1?
So. how could I have killed Mr. Nose?
It's true that you couldn't come directly
from Miyazaki but...
But if you take the long way
around via To «0...
it's possible for you
you to set foot on Okinawa
before 9.30 in the morning!
Yes...
You avoided thercrowded main road.
And took the back road
which got you faster-to your destination...
You took the 8.35 pm fhght
from Miyazaki to Tokyo
and headed for Okinawa
on the 655 morning flight from Tokyo...
This woukfillow you
to arrive here at 9:20!
you went with that rental car
from the airport
to.Mr. Nose's road working course,
ambushed and killed him.
You returned to the airport by 9-150 am.
And pretended that
you just arrived in Okinawa,
then. came to see us!
WW. Wait!
I came out of
the Naha Airport arrival gate
this morning at 09:50. right!
Let's say I did come in on the 09:20 flight
and left the gate going outside once.
How was I supposed toaenter
the arrival lobby-again?
Well...
That's true...
See...
He...
M.Mr. Mour...
Wescame here because you said
you figured out who the killer-was.
Oh, well...
Talk about hopeless
Right. right. that'sright...
Why were the people
in the store a while ago
giving us strange looks?
OX WE
We went into therstore
sat down and left
without ordering anything...
Igllabet you're hungry
Would you like my juice?
Oh, yes, please!
You went into the store
and left without ordering anything...
Come to think of it,
the embarkatiOn and arrival floors of
Naha Airport are connected on the inside?
Huh?...Yes. that's right
Which means...
you could've just bought any ticket
and go inside from theembarkation gate
and come out from the arrival gate
without boarding the plane...
T. That's right, exactly!
Which means,
you still not being checked out from
the hotel in Miyazaki suspicious too...
If you came from Miyazaki to Okinawa
on this morning's flight,
you would've checked out
from the hotel in"Miyazaki...
If you also have an interview scheduled
in Okinawa tomorrow,
KE 3 Oh ee Laue dl) wow YR)
to spend the night here
But. you couldn't do 50
because you were alrend, away
from Miyazaki at that time...
Isn't it because you were on board
a flight last night and already in Tokyo,
which IS mules away?
A.Any evidence?
Phooey! Of course we've got evidence!!
Right.
Mr. Mouri!
Huh? Aha. ha ha...
Now. what was it?
Let's leave the rest up
to the renown detective!
E hem!!
Huh 2
You want juice. don't you?!
What the?!
Right!
That's right...
AA GE »
Please check the flight
from Tokyo to Okinawa
ANGE »
{ANGIE J
that Mr. Motoyama
used to carry out his trick.
AN GE >
that Mr. Motoyama
used to carry out his trick
because we were on
beard that flight too...
My daughter happened
to spill tennis balls on board this flight...
The passenger in the next seat
elped pick up the balls...
He was among the passengers.
A suspicious man that caught
the tennis ball with his left hand...
WwW. Was that Mr. Metoyama?
But. isn't he right handed...?
A habit...
since he caught
so many balls with his left hand
protect is right hand.
That's why he used his left hand
without thinking.
So. please give it to me.
He stuff that you took: out
from Ran's bag and hid.in your pocket.
The stuff that you took out
from Ran"s bag and hid in your pocket.
Mr. Masaharu Motoyama.
The baseball player who in the past
was awarded
he King of rookie and save...
J.Just what are you talking about...
You're sweating!
You must be ho ¢
How about some juice!
Yes...
younsfingerprints on the tennis ball
that you picked up back then
IS evidence that you are the killer...
IS what I'd like to say: butithat's not how its
The surface of a hard tennis ball
Is fluffy making it difficult
or fingerprints te remain...
And. even if it were found on the ball.
It would only serve as proof that
you were on the same flight as we were...
It won't serve as proof that
ou killed Mr. Nose...
That's why
we deliberately made you steal the can
of tennis balls and made you swim.
flu? j
Because we figured
you would undoubtedly lead us
to the weapon
ou used for the murder
and the place you hid
the clothes splotched
with blood when you killed the victim!
This is unmistakably
immovable evidence!
how amazing that
you saw through everything
just by watching him catch
the can with his left hand!
Well. well.
I happened to remember that
Mr. Metoyama.
Though we met for the first time
called out to.this boy knowing
that he was with us
and everything fell in place!
I figured that maybe
Mr. Motoyama saw us all together
somewhere before seeing us
at the airport...
Well, even a snotty kid like him
can be of use at times...
I should've put him to sleep
with the tranquilizer gun after all...
Phooey... talk about ironic.
To think that my habit ended
my-baseball career,
and again with this habit of mine,
I dug my*own. grave. ry. sm»
Nose told me,
You've got a habit when pitching.
on my first season off
after I received the King of Rookie
and King of Save...
I checked myself over and over...
To the point of going neurotic...
Butfi-'Fmcouldnilafindiényghabitm;
Not only that
I damaged my shoulder
because of ever, pitching
during, the off season...
@O I thought:that it was strange
that after I resigned.
Nose suddenly became very friendly
and introduced me to TV jobs and such...
Then last mo; th.
After-coincidentally seeing the VTR of
a sports variety program before editing.
+1 finally understoodwhy he did so...
WALLA
Are there any other interesting stories?
Mr. Nose, please tell us!
It's easy to get rid of a young pitcher...
All I did was whisper
that héghad*a habit
and he self-destructed...
What...
Cut the part out!
Cuz ll don't want trouble...
Are you. serious?!
No, it's something
I heard from somebody: else!
NOS,
I never had a habit to begin with...
! } JA
I felt obligated to him
and swayed between joy
and sorrow for his actions
as the guardian of the Jaguars
Jaguars as if they were my own...
hat I'm so vexed and wretched...
Is that why yeu killed him.
Yes...
I kept him {from making
his Japan 'save record...
Using Hideyoshi'swgreat revenge trick
All I did was let him know
that I was the one
who was supposed to win the fame!!
No...
you would've never made
the Japan record.
What?
I feel sorry for the fact that
ou were deceived but...
a stopper is
the last stockade for the team.»
Even if you're beaten and battered
no mattered if you're'jeered at or-what...
If your turni'to:play comes up.
In the next game.
Yousve got to stand on the mound
as if nothing happened! -
I don't think:'a guy who: loses himself
and'commitsgmurder can
shoulder the fate of a team...
Ugh..Ugh...
Ghads
Im the one who wants to cry!
Thanks to you doing¥fsomething like. this...
er I went all'out to... Da
forget it...
Do the rest of our reentine
behind bars...
What were you going to say. dad...
It's nothing...
Darn.
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
ee FD
Background Music.
KAT U0 ONG
Chara doer rs S1 DIS By .
70) ho :
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCH]1
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Dirc: tors.
MASATPPMO SUDO
010]
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASH] HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWACGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN] 'ODAMA
Product By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
mn association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
DETECTIVE CONAN
GCOSHO AOYAMA SHOCAKUKAN YIV IMS
All Rights Reserved
I went out of my way to get it and then.
av = 855 a.
Now,
I can't give to her even if I wanted to...
INo.;wait a sec...
if this is going to.be his final autograph...
This. is be a super rare item...
DO»ad?
That's a red-back spider, and poisonous.
Don't touch it!
You've got to leave it
that way until the police get here.
This is... NO acciden
Pops was saying that
It's strange that only the serum of
the black widow spiders not around.
Deadly Venom Spider Trap