Today s case has te do with spiders!
Vertical strings and horizontal strings
The locked room trick
Open a hole In the tangled mystery!
He sees through the one and only truth
A childin appearance
» With the 1.Q: of an adult
No case is'left-unsolved
with Detective Conan
Come on=let's hurry and play soccer
Let's do so after we go to the library.
New books have come in yesterday.
Shoots
I came because you said
we were going to play soccer .
Hey. say something. Conan
I Kind of feel like reading too.
What?
You're the one who said
you wanted to play soccer.
You traitor!
Oops.
Really. talk about childish...
Hey. just what do you think you're doing?
Shh!
You're going. aren't you, Mr detective?
Deadly Venom Spider Trap
Why don't you try calling the professor?
My hands are full just yet .
Why don't you call?
I will.then...
Oh. its okay.
Pl ey]
It's the signal of lunch break
for a near factor
He's not answering.
Will you call him: later.
@kay.
A red-back spider.
Agh...!
Whaa. oh, no!
Genta, d.don't push me.
Agh!!
Ouch. ow.
Just what are,you doing?
It's because you guys left on your own...
It's no fair
It's no fair.
Heh, heh, heh...
Ayumi too.
Just what aren ouwguys doing...
MitsuhikoP!
Do you know him?
Y.Yes...
He's Mr. Itogawa
who lives next door to me.
SISTA IG SEE HRW ISEie TEE 18 IH TE!.
spiders at the universi...
A red-back spider. ist
Y.Yeah
that's right.
It's amazing that you know, sonny...
Some ears ago
it was discovered in Japan
and was big news.
It's called the red-back spider
Because its back is red, see.
It's a poisonous gnakcithat lives mainly
in Australia and Central America.
Wow,
you mean a venomous spider is
in Beika Town?!
Pu. fu fu...
no.\
We're borrowing this yard
to take pictures.
I'm a jeurnalist...
We're making this magazine.
Wejre doing a venomous spider Special
In our; next week edition.
See...
OF a, ih Ps
Then. that spider.is...7 ¥
He's my pet
P. Pet?!
Although I may not look it,
I'm quite well-known
as a "venomous spider freak."
I have a variety of venomous spider pets.
We're leavingito interview the Professor.«
so call him. will you?
Yes.,'yes, ma'am...
Hello
Oh» Professor Shinno,
thispis Urazaki.
Whaaaaa!!
WwW. What's the matter.
Professor!
It bit me! d
; The black widow spiderdbit me!!
What!
Please Inject yourself with't e serum?!
Professor!
The serum. therserum!
D.Damn! It won't open.
O.Damn! It won't open.
Oh, the spare key...
Professor!!
All of you stay here!
Oh, okay
Oh.nn..he's dead...
Professor's...dead...
WwW Why
Look,
there is no sign that
he injected the serum...
NUNS...
Mr: Urazaki,
hurry, call the police...
Oh," eah...
\ aaaah~
He . he!
Just what do you think you're doing. Miwa!
I.Look!!
It's a venomous spider,
the one that bit the Professor
I I'm telling you, stop. it!!
Ac ht!
It's already dead.
What
That spider
has nerve venom that is several times
stronger than that of the red-back spider.
B.But
not strong enough
for a human to die instantly.
D.Don't touch it!!
We've got to leave it that way
until the police get here...
on, yeah...
1. Hey...
Let me.borrow it a while. okay.
Hello. is this the police.
Yes,
Which means he was... bitten here?
Agh,
It's gone.
The serum for the Black Widow Spider
IS gone.
It's always left over here and) yet.
Hey. take a look.
It seems to have escaped from here.
He never:ever forgot
to close the lid before.
Were only human,
so therejare times we forget.
This is
Don't come in during investigation!
What's with him!
We're witnesses to the case too...
If you chase us away,
the case won't be solved!
The ones who have the key to this room
re Professor Shiino...
and Mr. Itogawa. his assistant?
Y.Yes, sir...
Mr. Urazaki, you were acquainted
ith the Professor...
Were the door and windows
always locked?
Yes, Sir...
because a varietyjof venomous spiders
are.being
Hmm,
to think that he forgot to close the lid of
the breeding box of venomous spiders...
Are ou bothered?
Oh, then go ahead
and think like that forever...
Huh?
I saw something.
1a ¢ IC you see.
There's a scratch
on the Professor's ear.
As if he brought the receiver
to his ear without realizing
that the spider was there
and was bitten...
It seems to be rare that someone
who is bitten by this spider
dies on the spot...
Agh,
Conan.
I just told you not to come inside...
Hmm /!
Oh, j.just a little bit...
Isn't this medicine for the heart?
Did the professor have a heart problem?
Really?
I didn't know.
If so, it was an accident after all?
You're the one who called the Professor,
Mr: Urazaki?
Yeah,
but Miwa called himibefore I did...
Nobody answered the phone at that time,
right?!
Oh. Conan!!! Be careful with.that...
I have to:.call Pops...
Mr. Urazaki's call is here
If you need to make a call,
I'll lend you my cell phone.
Huh?
Oh. it.it's okay.
I already got through.
Hello. Pops?
I'm-going to be a little late
This 8...NO accident!
What's the matter. Mr. Itogawa?
I have to...
attend a academic, conference tomorrow.
I'm going to have to deliver
the speechyin place of the Professor.
What?!
How:can you talk about a conference
at a time like:this?!
B.But,
it's an important academic conferenceand
so long as I have the documents,
even I can deliver the speech.
The truth is...
It's your research isn't-Wt; Mr; lltogawa?
What?!
Is.Is that true?
The Professor was delivering.speeches
on the results of Mr. Iltogawarsiresearch
all this time: as if it were his own.
so he snatchedsaway
the works of his assistant.
Eh... It's the usual stuff that goes around
uh. Which mean.
That youlhad a grudge against
the Professor, eh, Dr. Itogawal!
Speak:for yourself. Mt. Urazak I
What?! Why you!
Come, come...Mr. Urazaki...
do you have something against him too?
No: I don't.
If you've got something.
Will you show it to us?
No. it's nothing...
It's nothing. tell youl!
Then. please show it to us,
Mr. Urazaki...
Darn
Those are
all rare spiders
that aren't found in Japan.
Just what does this mean?
Mr. Urazaki was
buying the spiders from the Professor.
Spiders...
VE8o
Saying that it would be used for research,
he Professor was able to get
a hold of rare and valuable spiders
from all over the world...
And he's slyatoo.
He picks on our weaknesses
and raises.the price.
Uh, fun. fun...
Moreover,
you had a grudge against the P ofessor.
Absurd
this is an accident.
He was punished for playing (round
with my passion for spiders.
Pops sa s
Ny a-
he's figured -out who the killer 1s!
Onan...
You mean you re still here!
He says that this Is not an accident?
Right
me says that its strange
that only the serum
the Black Widow Spider is missing.
Hmm.
It's true that everything fits in too well.
If it isn't an accident...
Mr. Itogawa.
You're the only one
who has the spare key.
Yes...
Mr. Itogawa,
as well as Conan and the others
heard the Professor scream
it the same time...
Pops sa s
to check this telephone carefully.
The receiver...
Huh?
5 \ na
There's something shiny over here.
What?!
Hmm.
Something is definitely
inside the hole just
where the ear is to be placed...
It's a needle...
So. this is what was inside!
The tip of the needle 1s broken off
What's up Conan?
The toilet!
The tip~of the needle-is-broken off
Wiso you can't tell
from the exterior of the receiver.
Which means
thatgthe thing that poked
the Professor's ear is this needle.
Then.
Why did he shout,
I was bitten by a Black Widow Spider?
Yes...
Oh...Mr. Mourn!
I've heard about the circumstances
from Conan.
The killer poked a Black Widow Spider
on to the needle point
of the thumbtack that was rigged inside.
Huh...
Take a very close 10Ok 1
using the magnifying]glass
at/that dead spider over there.
(Hey...
Hey. Takagi.
I.] see!
1. TakaqQ.
hurry and explain it to us too...
Hey Mr. Moun!!!
Just what are you trying to get to?!
In other words. Inspector!
This is how it is...
The killer who rigged the needle
into the receiver...
pokes a spider that is killed beforehand
onto the tip of:theineedle
no 'lmake qtheréProfessor
mistakenly think that he is bitten
by a Black Widow:Spider...
Then for the serum
The killer steals the serum
for the Black Widow Spider...
After all isxdone,
the killer replaces the phone
andyust waits
for the Professor to pick up the phone.
0. that's the story...
Which means
that the Professor died because...
Oh, Professor, this is Urazaki.
I've been bitten!
I've been bitten
by a Black Widow Spider!!
Please inject yourself with the serum.
Professor, quick the serum!!
1. The serum is gone!!
Ugh!
G.Gugh, gugh...
All right Mr Mour:,
goodb e then...
Inspector
the Professor did not die
from the venom of the spider.
Which means?
Since he's a venomous spider researcher.
He is well aware of
the danger of spider venom.
He had to/linject himself immediately
withthe serum,
but he couldn't find it...
Since the Professor had a weak heart,
if cornered into such a situation...
I see, if the person has a weak heart,
the sudden stress make nduce an attack.
Yes. sir.
Which means that the killer is
someone who can go in and out
at will from the research lab,
as well as know
bout the Professor's weak heart...
Just what. proof
do"you have:to:say something like that!
Mr. Mouri said.
Look at the incoming calls record
ff the telephone...
WHY...
12:50 Urazaki cell phone.
Made the call
and the Professor answered...
Hmm?.
17:30 university clerk office.
This is yesterday's record
it has nothing to do with today.
Strange
Yasuda should've called the Professor
once before I gave him a call.
The time was 12:00.
Because the lunch break time tone
of the factory...
Oh, I'seemed to have called
the wrong number back then.
Will you please show me your cell phone?
She's definitely called
1 different number...
Huh?
That cell phoneys /
the same as Mr. Itokawass...
Huh?!
Oh...It's Justa coincidence.
Pops said that
Mr. Itokawa is protecting you."
He said that you're going with each other.
What...
Although it's already an old model',
it's unusual that you sot; still use
the same type. but of a different color.
1,0] s@e...
If you two are going with each other
Ms. Yasuda would have the opportunity
to make a spare key from the key
that Mr. Itokawa has...
Oh, and besides.
She's knowledgeable about spiders
thanks to Mr. Itogawa telling her
about them.
It's not all that strange
that she; could've known
that:the: Professor had a weak heart.
WwW Wait
it'sitrue that weire going with each other.
that isnit:reason enough
to be suspicious of:herd
We've got proof...
The seal with the blue flower on it
that's in your pocket.
We saw you secretly pick it up
from the floor Mr. Itogawal!
Will you please give it to me?
That's the nail art seal that you're using,
isn't it?
N. No. see...?
can you show me the magazine
you showed me a while ago?
Huh? Yes, sir...
ts on here...
See.
0.Oh yeah!!
Didn't you drop it today In this room?
If so
why did Mr. Itégawa
try to hide the evidence?
You came here today
before the Professor came, didn't yous
Mr. Itogawa realized that you did...
and tried to hide the evidence.
Iook at the antenna of that cell phone!
Isn't it full of scratches?
Huh,
eah...
now that you mentioned it.
There were scratches on the.telephone
over there too.
Weren't there?
I £88...
She used the antenna of the cell phone
and stuck the needle into the receiver...
That's when the scratches were made...
Kyaaah-!!
Stop it!
You killed the Professor
and tried to make it look as
if he died accidentally.
You made Mr. Urazaki call
because you didn't want suspicion to fall
upon Mr. Itogawa or yourself.
Why did you do something like this?
Whenever the Professor delivers
a speech at the academic conference.
Wt is:Mr. togawa's research results.
Injust couldn't.take it.-anymore.
I was just:hoping
that the Professor would be hospitalized
with a heart attack-or:something...
didn't mean for it:fo turn out this way...
MMiWa
This is a crime that
cannot be forgiven. After all.
You did take someone's life...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Backorpund Music «4
\IS J nit
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUD #
Story Editor.
JUNI] 1IDKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! ASHYWAB/ARA
UNARI KOU
YU CHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation irc Co
MAS:
Kl KAWANMUR
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJI KODAMA 7
Produced By
NTERTAINMENT
n association wit!
DETECTIVE CON
LOSHO AOYAMA QHOFAKUKANYIV-IMS
All Rights Reserve
So. the spider was innocent after all .
Yeah
Because, if you take a 'goodOlook at it,
it's small and cute
I guess you re right...
Conan.
There's a spider on your shoulder!
Don't worry, it's not poisonous
That's \ Rat's the spider that
was In the Professor's breeding box!
What?!
INO!
Somebody do something! Au!
I'm just kidding
A hill, is that it?
What?!
He probably left it here after he was
pushed off the cliff,
before the murderer came down here
Oh no! I lost sight of him!
What is it that's bothering you?
What was that sound...
Shimchi
Don't tell me you...
Stars a Cigarette and a Code Part 1