Today, wou, all (going
but to look at the stars
Wao go out looking for a comaot and
discovor skeleton instead
Salvo thovmysatary of
thawscotleredscifarettes!
Solvo tho myatory of
the'scattercd cigarettes!
Ho sees through the one and only (truth
A child in appomanco
with" the I.Q. of an adult
with tho Q of an-adull
NO Cavan ves Vat
unsolved with 'Detective Conan
Ab. Abnormality obsorvation:'!
N:No, Genta!
Astronomical observation,
astronomical observation!
( Min, (FY ele I
Are wo going torgoiwateh stars frominow I
Yoh, I found a nico pansion
in the mountains of Gunma...
But-why aro you going outside
torwatch: starsat a cold time like this..."
It:s good because it's cold.
Huh?
The colder Its, tho cloforOthe air./
and the better It is to watch the 'stars
Beside. tonight is the new moon!
Im other words It's just the night
to canry out an astronomical observation.
PR A RE ca Lodi
Just looking at the: stars?
Oh come on, don't say that!
You can study the stars, and wo may
BYZCH ANTONE STOVES IHBSEMS WASTES]
If wo do, 1itmay bo namaod after us!
What?!
O, Our names!
A star
We can name It after ourselves?
Es. ight!
Of counse that's nmpessiblo
when it comesito asteroids
mm which tho orbit has to bo obsorvod
repeatedly and verified though...
But thoro is a possibility if the star is a
comet that only requires to be found...
How about calling
Beika Youth Detective Squad Comet?
Sounds nie
Hey. hey... nice, isn't it'?
Nope.
The only star you can give a name of
your choice to is to asteroids...
Comets are named after the surnames
of their discoverers, and moreover,
Val) LAT 48 oh (nd 3 / Yok) plea [on Xogo-
ho -cubiyntteycidt near navemaes thhey ear hie t
can be given to the star,
Re UN
if a comot is found at tho sama timo
all over the world
I's possible that your mame will tac,
- mixcdhwith 1 foreijn€name
threo people Mme. and...
I or example.
Kobayashi, Burgaor, Millon
So, If woe hind a comaot and
cA AN ote IRE couitke 5407, RG rote) £33
YOSe QA
Isuburyaya
roo. - SOL 5... { {
Yeah, right!
Yes, well
Yoshida, Tsuburaya, Haibara... .7
LI How:come my name's not there?"
Includo Conan's:namo: too
Oh.but it's only up to three: names.
Aha.-ha .
Hey. ™Conan. don't you ?!
Hoy Conan, don't you 2
Jubt~'~what um yum (mung, Conan'?
Coll The wey
owe, the Sport, talent
Masaharu Moetoyama,
the ove that killed
the professional baseball playcr
Mr Noso, last-time in Okinawa, right!
You woro there at tho time
of the incident too, weren't you, Conan
WN ARAZEY Torok Ao] tekonetv, soxotan=Ridoge) xe
Bothered about what?
Wel)4 it's not such a big deal but,
I was Just wondering
ho ho would call on his cell phone
durimg an mtorrogation session
The polico alrondy wouldve: contactod
the late Mr. Nose's parents
and family so.
I hank vs Me Motoyaaany'.
Crsonal no tam. ane.
Oh darn!
I should've directly asked him
who he called...
Maybe...
It was basoball player Kobayashi?
The One who aontoraoad tho toaan
at the same time as Mr. Motoyama...
Hay ware on an off" saason
travel program together,
CH S87 ax Gin,
nd seemed to get along well together
There's ov possibility he informed
him of the death of his best friend...
He seems te have succeeded
his parents' Japanese inn
after ho rotirod four years ngo...
If I romomber corroctly, it was
0 A places called Kurayoshi in Tottori...
I saw it when it was introduc
on TV once.
I saw it whon iigwas introduced
on TV once,
but it looked to be a nice inn!
Oh .l see.
It seems to have nothing to do with
'@ men in ) ac
Kurayoshi.
Shinichi...
Don't tell me that you're .
HA AA
(BIR)
Mr. Agasa, nght
Wolo boon waiting for you
'loa8: sign'your namo n ourgue: Mist
Oh, all right...
'gas
Hiroshi
by WA) [Ey Je
He told you to come here too. didn't he?
3) 8A tn
I want to apologize to him...
here (8 Asad?
A.Asao, who is he's
Don't play dumb with me.
Don't play dumb with me,.
A man wearing the same ning
at's a pair with this one...
Asa Kono!
You got an mvitation card
from him to. didn't you!
Ms. Nonoemiya
Invitation card?
Oh, no, you soc,
this is our first visit here
Oh...
Im sorry
Whew was that a surprisc...!
I'm so sorry.!.
Who IS she.
Her name is Etsuko Nonemiya
ne she's an undor classman
of the university that I went to
she was referring to was
1Mse an underclassman of my univorsity
Wise an underclassman of my university.
BWA WUE) Gl Jy fox]
Theywused toicome and stay over
horeq lot togother in th 3 past. but
after they had a big fight
ere a year go...
ho stoppod coming all togothor
Thay last week,
sho seems to have rocoived
an invitation card
asking her to come here.
And she's been waiting here for
the past three days
Since he hasn't shown up at all,
ho's hoen that way
drinking from day time...
But, why would she think that I,
who she hasn't even met bekme
would alse got an invitation card 7?
It's only natlral...
Because wo who don't oven
know him all that wall,
4,40
got an Invitation card
from that guy called Keno'. see...
Well, we met him once
over here a year ago that day...
Being that the subject
in. the invitat on card was what it is,
we decided to at least come here...
May I see the invitation card?
(Cx)
horo
hank you!
As a result of my one year observation,
I haveTcome up with a discovery
that would shake thefbasis of:astronomy.
I would hika your opinion on tho mato
sO please come to Pension Amatsuecht.
Of course I will foot:tho room charges
If you can't come, It can't be helped,
cd <C ]
But please make an effort to be there...
Asa Kono
Well, judging from the fact
that he's not here
despite two days already gone by
it soeams to havo been a prank
hall we head back then,
editor?
E.Editor .7?
Yeah...
Yeah .
We're writing an astronomical magazine
called "Space Sunday...
And, Mr Mikami ere is the editor!
He's no ordinary editor. either!
Oh. come on. {
No big deal
what do you mean ty
Is no ordinary editor...
Wall, you see
he discovered a new comet,
an DQ «= 2 mow
who a star Is named after!
What?!\-
4 You'll
You discovercd-one?!
Where, did you find it?
Tell us where too!
Well, where
that's not an easy question.
Over therg?
Over hero?
I 8 Nhey
Then I suggest you climb up the road
in back of the pension to the hill! beyond!
It's. a sconic viewpoint,
and just great for viewing stars
If you want,
I'll lond you a telescopo too!
For 5000 yen.
Oh... ou're charg nd us for it...
Ou're charging us for it...
Bu mroful
@kay!
SN sli )in \A/SUD (No) our Starr (for Sag Hl
Phoooy, hopoloss amatours
Don't they knew
It's not that easy to find!
Right, editor!
Yeah
NR1»;
who knows.
No matter how knowlodgoable you an
whether you can find a star
or not depends on luck
If you're lucky you can find one
Right, editor
Won't you find him for me with your luck
Won't you find him for mo with your luck
Won't you find him tor me with oli luek
of having found a star!
The guy Who was obsessed by stars
and disappoaraod inte
the darkness of space.
My pruozuoub pull-nu:
W how
Bake
Whew...
It sure Is kind of far...
Come on, Doc! Hang!in there!
Hurry. hurry!
Whow, heave, heave
Is.isn't that the hill?
Kot xu O a Gon Gall
It's more a cliff than a mm
You mean
we're going to climb way up there?!
Lot's tinkouasbronk
Whew
Hey.
Let's' climb-up-theore. before sundown!
Treat the aged with kindness!
Oh gee,
ind you're usually telhing me
not to treat you like the aged.
Shall we rest about 10 minutes then?
Agreed!
Darn, come on, man
1111110000 bulk, 0mm
But, don't ou think that
Invitation was sort of strnamge 7
Huh?
Would somaoebody write somaothing hike,
If you can't como it can't bo holpod?
There must've been somg urgent reason
ho wanted everyone to come here.
Aah...
I found one!
Ky aaaaah
What's up. Ayumi!
A.A skull?
Glhfldb n.no joke'?!
WwW Why Ibo dal ma plo ll oP
I here are some more scattered here.
What?!
The lower J. Ww
the upper forelimb
tho thighbono
Where's the body set 7?
Over there!
WwW. What on earth
Ar a.
T. The person probably fell from that cliff!
Yes, probably.
man m0 nu-m luv. m HHHLH 0)
someone who fell quite some time ago...
The bones may have scattored
due to animals. rn and the wind
«No 7
This Is a homicide case
ind an extremely haeimouss one too.
LEK. limo
Lime has the quality of giving off heat
CH oeneiding ) wie Hepat)
When lime 1s scattered, around the.
Corpse and the nearby area,
has tho quahbt of giving off hoot
after being wet by. rain...
and as afrosiilt, tho paco at which
the body rots is" quickened
Therefore. the bddy skeletonizes
In a very short time
M=Mayba this skeleton is tho Mr. Kono
that ovorybodypwan talking about
hack at the inn?
NOW AY
But, he.senbovarybody
the invitation card. didn't he . ?
It could be the man called Kono
What?!
A ring and a cigarette case
Is under the rock.
The letters carved on the ring are
ETSUKO to ASAO...
It's most hikoly that
Mr Kono left these hore,
before the killer camegback down here,
after pushing him off'the cliff
Hoe loft these horo most probably
'S evidence that he wars killed
But, maybo tho killor Toft thom
herc¢ deliberately
If so. I think he'd leave it on Mr Kono's
finger after stripping him naked...
Why would a killer who
attempts to hide the identit
of his victim deliberately hide
something like that under a rock!
Will somebody
Iend mo a handkerchief . ?
Okay...
"Then. what's this cigarette box...?
If my deduction Is correct,
this is probably
y All there isin here are cigarettes!
Just as I thought
Huh
DJDonfltelfl me that .
Yeah
this Is what Mr. Kono left behind
Its .)dying message!!
Die!
% OYihg message?!
What about this cigarotto
It's very likely that
the man called Asao Kono
Ieft clues Aboukwho
the killer before he was killed
But, isn't it just that
2 cigarettes out of 6 arc torn?
Watch closely
Huh"
The two short cigarettes
have filters on them, don't they?
It goes to show that the cigar atte
were dolibarately torn short
and put into the cigarette box!
And besides. look
If you take a close look under the rock
where the cigarette box was hidden
it's »rett rotted
But the rest of the cigarettes and
the cigarettes that ware lorn apart
then are disposed of! right?
In other words.
Mr. Kono who left this behind
wants {ys 00Ok a
only the 4 long cigarettes and
2 shor cigarettes
he put into the cigarette box!
We've got to go back and tell
thefpbeople at the pension about this
Hold it. Doc!
Uh 2)!
Its (rot a Good icddn to tell the people
of the pension about this!
Call the police first...
What?
Why?
Can't ou tell?
Hat?!
Tho guests at tho ponsion right now
are all people who have come
because they received
Invitation cards from Mr. Kono!
If these bongs are reall, Mr Kono's
it's obvious that
someone el§é sent them, right?
Moroovot
One year ago when
Mr. Kono disappeared from the pension
tho poopla gathorod now
were also here back then.
scattered are not because of rain,
wind or animals, but was scattered here
deliberately by someone
Yeah-n
he eme what? sent out the (mvitation ands
6) (ODD aol) Goel
OOOO WOU $C) Dude (Om [Homo
and planning some ovil schomo
W. What is that evil scheme?
Beats me.
At any rate. call the police!
Hurry and contact them and
have IhQmvCOmQ hue,
fe \Whne R00 Wy), Wes
Oh. well,
it seems that this area is
outside the service area and I can't call...
We've got no choice-then,
but to go back to the pension and
call the police secretly...
Heave, heave
The p,police...
What seems to be the matter
Oh, Mr. Amatsuchi"!
WwW. What brings you here'?
I rocallod forgetting to put tho hoavy
wei ght of, thetelescope in the bag
By tho way,
what sauna to he the matter...?
Oh, nothing.
Oh. nothing.
What the matter?
Agh. ah...
agh., ah.
Dd you find somothing strange'?
Huh?!
B Bones?!
Ugh 1!
Whaaaal
Oh no...
What?!
You found A€é6s bongs In 'e forest?!
B.But, all you found ware,
the bones. rights'
Who knows they're
really Asao's or not?
We found this beside the bones
The purring carved with
your initials that you gave him!
3utd
contd ha tht
1¢ 750 KONO < ¢CSOMGHOCY ding
deliberately put the ring there!
But:tho ring was fo und
Um... Did Mrt Kono have a cavity"?
Mis upper tooth to the right, t
he 2nd one from the molar...
1 upper molar?
Aha, ha, ha, ha...
If so, those bones aren't Asao!
Ha, ha, ha...
Ha. ha. ha...
Hcfdid have 1 cavity all right,
but it was his front lower tooth
Thon, it is hon aftor all.
No doubtzabout it.
- ,-ay...what,
what do you mean
I'm sorry to say that
the dentaljtroatment was
done on the lower jaw central incisor...
In other words,
It's exactly whore you say it was.
He's lower front tooth had a cavity!
Aaagh...
Ho deliberately sind something alse
so thatyou wouldn't\'just agree to
what he said...
I'm sorry...
OO. Oh no
Which means that Asao is.
Asao is...
Whaaaaaa.
A fAlany ate.
Lot's hurry and call the police
B'.'But
the phone doesn't seem working right.
this phone only connected to
Nn electric cord and
doesn't have a module cable.
Aaaagh!
What?!
Strn mo,
I used this phone just a while ago
Do you have any other phones
Or a spare cable
This is the only phone and
I haven't bought any spare cables
Then,
we can't call the police.
You gotta be kidding!
I'm going home by car!
But. editor!
I don't think that's. possiblo oithor...
What?
I just went outside and checked
but It seems all the cars that
are parked here have flat tires...
Somabody probably loosened
the air valveand deflated the tires
So that no one could use the cars,
mm order to keep everyornd
confined here...
T.That's absurd...
don't tell moe this has
something to do with the guy Keno?!
Iimusure it does!
For sure!
Because 'that was hom
Shh!
Come to think of it when I found
the bones you guys were watching. right?
You saw the 4 long eigarettos
ind 2 short cigarettes
on tho handkorchiot, didn't you...
Hey! Isn't that a dying message
N No I wouldnét» say It was.
N.Nb!
That's no dying'message
av,» ~
I'm sure that Asao 1s just pretending
to be dead to trouble me.
He's 80 cute. fuh. fuh. tun
he's 80 cute. fuh, fun. tuh...
Anyway. let's all stay In our rooms
tonight and not go out.
I think it's best to wait until daybreak
Yes .
* '<
XX: te 62) Sofa] off (3 offopsitAfter
4 long ones and 2 short ones!
If the name Is Futagawa,
there is one extra match and
fr thy) namo 1s Amatsuchi,
oNC Moro match stick is nccded
As for Ms. Nonemiya and Mr. Mikami,
their characters cannot be
displayed with 6 matches! .
What It you writo tin katakana?
That's Impossil do-too
Hutagawa would require 14 match sticks
nd Amatsuchr 17
8 {or Nononuy and for Mikami
Ma c res wou e necessary.
What if you try thaoir imtials?
Liko for Haibara Al
it would bo "HA
that's exactly 6 matches.
Fran 2!
Then Yare you saying that
youro tho Killer?! mm
Like I saldMitys just.an example.
Oh, an example!
Come Lo think of It Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko,
TM and Yoshida Ayumi,
YA are also six matchos
True!
Uh, 6) a Gemtaris
How romantic te think that only tho
three of us require six match sticks.
I'm Acjasa Hhireshe, AH and can be
displayed with 6 matches too!
w.what a coing¢idenco
You justumay be fight
about ittbeing initials!
What?!
The killer is Mr Futagawa?!
Yeah...
If those cigarettes
really stand for Initials .
Mr. Amatsuchl Ix ofl is AR,
Noenomiyn Etsuko is N E
Mikami Helhachi Is MH.
Only Futagawaliajimefr 11
can be created with 6 matches, right?
Ce B5eogFe
B.But, I wonder if it's n'good idea
to go sce Mr. Futagawa in 'person
Don't worry, I'm just going to
throw him a catch question
Huh?!
DHuhaMr Al utagawass not here .
ihe cigarette filter is still damp
Not too long has passed yet
since he loft the room...
CONE
Somebody's walking outside.
Oh that's...
Ms. Nonomiya?!
OO. Oh ne, not only Mr, Fuatacawa tout
Mr Mikami and Mr. Amatsuchr arc
nowhcocro in sight oarthor!
Darn!
I told thom not Lo go outsidic!
Mitsuhiko, Ayumi and
will go get Ms. Nonmnomiya back!
Doc: Aranvd (Gantry,
go and look tor the other throg!
O Okay!
Ms. Nonomlyal!
Where are you?!
U.Um, that's the road that leads to
the place we found the skeleton, right?
T. Then, maybe sheswent there to confirm
If the bones were really Mr. Kono s...
OO. Oh no...
WwW. What that's "Md of the...?
M.Mr. Futagawa?!
No good. His nock is .broken...
What?!
He's not breathing anymore.
H.He's holding something...
A cigarette case?
The same d Ing message agin?
No...this time
thoros'one_ moro...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MIG THIKO sUWA
\ -O » - >. «co b . ~
Background Music
KAISUD ONO)
Charaaler Designs Jy.
Wu SAT 0510)
Story Editor.
JUNIGHT 1HOKA
Scripts By
AZU NARI KOUCH
» 0 A 0 ».
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
Mm HIROT SHI TAKATANI
UO O0GAW
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KAISUYOSHT KOBAYASHI
Editor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KIIJNI mm MA
MS ENT - Al MENT. LID
YOMI R TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONAN
GOSHO AOYAMA [ SHOCAKUKAN:-YIV IMS
All Rights Reserve
Iey, hey, easy on the stuff
and don't mess things up too much...
Oh you brought a telescope with you, sir?
How long are you going to keep searching?!
UT elk, do Yaxe) Sia oven fo v YX
murder weapon would be this umbrella.
OKay, the oily one loft as
Mr. Amatsuchi, It's your turn.
I saw hi checking the guest list closely!
Over and'over again!
Wo 1 g.
St avCigarette and a Code™ P