Today's code 1s pret difficult.
The star and the killer
are called by the samc name.
Search and soc.
Through the telescope trick!
He soos'through tho onogand only truth
A child In appoaranco
with tho 1. of an adult
AN child in appoarance
with tho'! (J of an adult
No caso isHoftwnsolvad
with DetoctiveyConan
WO 6m Gunn Lo pontaen
150 foxy Game ad Moet) odo ia
We go over (0 a pension
In the mountainsto observe stars.
Besides the owner of the pension
Mr. Ryoji Amatsuchi,
three people. Ms EtsukeO Nonomiya
Mr. Hajime Futagawa
and Mr Hahacht Mikami are Wore
becauso they received an invitation card
Wao won't to look at tho stuns
When we gotjto 'a Rill nearbyto our surpris
we found a skeletonized corpse!
Moreover. in its hand it was holding
6 clgarettesthought to be a dying mbbbdjG.
And that night...
WwW. What was that sound...?
M.Mr. Futagawa?!
Is It another similar kind of. dying message?
No...this one has .
Ono~Mmoromatch
(1% $5)
Volved!
There'are 7 cibarettes In all!
WwW. What does this mean?!
It's Likely that...
the person thatthe 6 cigarettes stand for,
which Mr. Kono, who ws
killed a year ago was holding and
the: person that Mr. Futagawa
Is trying to describe
using the 7 cigarettes
ma not be the same
Meyhejhe keuller deliberately added
one more just to throw investigation off.
That's not possible!...
We hgandsQmethlngwdropmto.the ground
and wenfyrunning overdright away
There wns no lightawhen
we ran over here, was there.
NINo. .it was pitch dark...
Which means that
me who killed Mr. Kono.
And the one who killed Mr. Futagawa
are two.different people .
Or. it could be that Mr Futagawn
tried to leave some kind of clue behind...
Huh?
There:s;blood on just one match...
There is blood on his hand
that was holding the cigarette case...
Thieve Hood on the othe
cigarette case In his pocket too
It could boithat.
Oh, your dotoctivo badge is beoping...
Oh it:s:me! Ca: ou see me?
Above. Look up!
Oh Doc!
He .Isran bod there?!
No. no,oné In particular...
We dldnltiséé anyone. did we?
But, we did find something on the ground!
Something on:the-ground
A cell phone...
There's a mall that hasn't been sent out...
WwW. What's written on the mail?".
H.He died?!... Mr. Futagawal...
Oh no...It can't be?!
'Hum
Ho foll off tho hf
and I think he died instantly.
Mr Futagnwirs coll phone
was found on the cliff...
A mail will with no "send to" address
was found In his cell phone!
There was: a will In his coll"phomno 2!
This Is what is written
I Invited everyone to this pension because
("wanted to conlossgbofore avoryono
what I did a year duo. hore at this pension
+OWCEEY
Wein. TO Cie) uA [MIC
Mr. Asao Keno a year ago is I,
Hajimg kutagawa
M: ob ko Nomonuya
Ino was his tanc o
I am sorry to have killed
Innk=to XD 180) [or= ofkoxtgy 0 VA)
RyojlAmntqvuzml. Mr Kono
upper classman during his university days
I on sorry for throwing dirt
on this pension that you mana je.
An (TIE ditor Mikami. Mensa CORY On
% Kg?»
e died because
Wad ahh argument with ham
on the cliff and pushed him
He unfortunately fell off...
I was going to confess to this truthfully
and ask for your forgiveness.
But I found it hard
to come up with the subject...
Therefore. I have maimed to" make amends
by kilhng myself before
the police arrive h@re tomorrow.
Hajimao I utngawa
T. Then,
AsAO'S Asae's.really,
ugh, ugh uuuugh
I'm sorry ploaso accopt
my apologies toe, as his superior...
Don't cry. Ltchan
Now wo know why ho suddenly disappoarod
as well as found out who killed him...
But. I wonder
Would a parson who writo
alctter then commit suicide
Ienvo somethinglike this bohind 7?
What? .
The man Futagwa, who fell rem the cliff,
was holding on tightly to these / d jarettos!
'¢ >» =
The man Futagwa, who fell from tha cliff,
was holding on tightly to these 7 cigarettes!
Mr Kono had site, Tatiagawa wag holding
one lonjor ¢igirotte*morq!
. > - A We
If Mr. Futagawa killed Mr. Keno
nd fl ho realized that the message
was about himself
Ieading him te commit suicide?
I don't think ho would imeraas
the number of ¢cijarettos. do you
On top of that, there's blood only
on the one that has:bean Ihcreased.
There was blood on Me uatagawa s hand
and tho othor cigarotto case
that was It his pocket.
Thore wore also traces of lnmOhaving beon
hit on the headdwith a 'stool pipe too.
H. Hit?!
Yap! I think the blood got enlwhen
he touched his bleedifg hoad with his hands.
In other words,
while the someone: onthe chit,
who hit Mr. Futagawa on the head
stole his cell phone
and was keying in the will.
Mr. Futagawa deliberately
took out one cigarette
from another cigarette caso that he had.
And put that extra cigarette into the original
cigarette case with the 6 cigarettes inside it,
and completed the message.
I feel that this 1s indeed a dying message!
IQ 10
Ho probably hid tho ciginotto caso
with 6 cigarettes in It.
To verify whether Mr Kone jsf
dying message applied to him...
WwW. Wait!
WwW. Waitt!
I thera wore 7, doosn't that moan
that you're the killer.Mr. Amatsuchi?
Hay...Mr. Mikami's name Heihachi
IS a 80 Cigare es.
1000y Aron't your initial
7 cigarettes too, Ms. Nonomiya?!
Como, como, lot's stay cool
agra?
Como, como, let's stay cool...
me, come Mel's stay cool.
didn't see him in the forest?
Hen, let us check all your rooms!
Huh? .
L}{]I\'.ll;1l'i. ,
We don't wilt the onc
who hit Mr. Futagawa with the steel pipe.
hiding it somoewhaore.
And come-after us with it, do we?
Hey. hey. don't: mess
things up too much
Oh you brought .1 IUIOSLODU with you. sir'?
Yeah
It's the one that was In the editing room
Alans barralgy stand, 1 lindaor
Way Wpod SS
The lens barrel of a telescope is
not hard enough to hit someone with.
A tripod hike that would probably bend
If you hit someone with it, right?
True...
Huh? You tried a lot of different
ch- arcttes too, didn't', ou. sir?
Yeah I couldn't figure
anything out though .
an thing out though
Hey. that's enough!
Just-how long are you going
todkoep searching around?!...
Fr ~ x
The only thin th\it could serve as a
murder weapon would be this umbrella...
But. it's not bunt anywhere...
Of:courg.0 not!
Because I'm not the killer...
Uh. what about the liquor bottle you had'?!
Oh...ll threw it away in the forest.
When I threw you guys off...
Threw us off?
You came after me, didn't you?
You, the freckled boy and the girl
with the bans!
Shddenly felt nauseated back then
and was throwing up behind a tree!
Nd was throwing up behind a woo!
aah Lhaah
Haah. haah...
You were trying to figure out Mr. Kono's
dying messago too, weren't you...?
Yes But I didn't think they wre
Mr. Futagawa's initials .
I didn't know his first namo bhosidos...
Hen, finally, it's your turn Mr. Amatsuche,
But since this pansion I
in its ontirety like your own room
I guess we'll ask the police to vestigate
when we call them in the morning.
Yes, si
Mako suro you toll tho pohco
'¥ -Tatedi Hthoko die tone Ll
Bocauso if 1 woro tho killor
I'd hide the murder weapon there
Yeas
Hey Al, so how was It?
I searched avery nook
and cranny of Mr. Futagawa's room
tor the thing you told me to look for
but found nothing.
But found nothing.
But found nothing...
That's strange...
If tho killor left such 1 will behind
and killed him,
It should be around somewhere.
while you were Investigating the rooms
I was here watching over
the people who were waiting but
hat man called; Amatsuchris suspicious!
He sure is suspicious!
Why"?
Because ho wi 8 it king o¥or
the guest list over and over!
You, rally carotully, over and ovar!,.
And with : frightening facedlike this!! '3
The guest IIH. 18
Come to think of it. r. Ikami and
Mr Futagawa said that they met Mr Kono
only once
> US (OD-a mn 1
Aftor Mr. Kono's. wiBroabouts
became unknown
these two.man have
been here several times
H Here It Isl!
Its probably this day!
Ic day when Mi Kono died!
Yos. after Mr Kono and
Ms. Nononuya's names come the manes of
Mr. Mikami and Mr, Futagawa.
So. therg's no doubt about it.
Maybo this Is
Maybao this is
I 'see... so that's the story.
Hay. Al come here a minute
Okay! Please
I agree with Ayun toe
Right'?
A Fusnao brand wallot about this $120.
If you get it for me. I'll help you
If your get it for me. I'll holp you
If you get It for me. I'll help you.
Hey. hey.
Ow, ow, ow!
What the?!...
What's wrong?!
Al are you okay?
Oh mo! She may have appendici 6)
What! Boos it hurt, Ai?!
\Adne=k loxeexs (KE Sl
Bul, we've got a problem
Ihe phone won't connect...
And even If wo were torcarry hr down,
who knows how lon it'll take™
It hurts Doc Do something...
Uuugh...Doc . Uuuugh . Help...
HM Hello,
could you send an ambulance up here?!
Oh yos. child?suddenly foll il.
Just as I thought
Hello, please send an ambulance up here!
Huh? No joko! I
[ll Sinem ink Say ima Xe nE 1
cable for the phone was gone
T.Tho addross is...CCunma prefocture...
C.Conan?
We have te contact tho ambulance quickly
or Air will
Just what do you think you're doing!
There's no noed to call one
I was Just acting.
Huh?
In-ordor 1 \raveal IR one
who hid thelmodular cable and
MAROATOME O oy
to confine Us here
DD. Don't toll mo thot
he one who used ASA S nan,
MMC SON out thea amnvitaytiteon eon of
tu gut-hm us" mum Wu!»
you!
Yiougrathe one who loft
a will in Mr Futagawa's cll phone.
Made It look like he commit-tum suicide
and pushed him off the cliff.
Mr. Re oi Amatsucin!!
LO ly N@osb
Wrong.
1... Wrong?!
It's true that Mr. Amatsuchi as the one who
invited everyone here and confined us here...
It's true that Mr. Amatsuchiig {he one who,
Invited everyone herd and confined us here
But. he's, dot the killer
Why not. Conan?!
It Was in the will that the killer wrote.
Wasn't it
that the kqllnfs tho one.
Who Invited ¢cveryone here
If Mr. Amatsuchi was the one
who killed Mr. Futagawa...
wotldn't he have mado it look hike
Mi. Futagawa was the one
who confined everyone here?
And he would've hidden that.modular cable
into Mr. Futagawa's clothes
or hidden it in the room!
IT. True...
Mr Amatsuch) called everyono hero
Mr Amatsuchy called averyona hare
200 hit
Mr Amatsuchiy entlod avaryona hora
ho found tho hones, th§ ring and
(A Any) MESH Jifedlep WAR a alr Pony,
whoso whoroaguts
became unknown a year ago!
he couldn't have been so accurate
just taking a quick glance at the clgarcttes
and ramarkimeg that thore wer
4 long cigarettes and 2 short ones ight
XY YQ.
I sent out theunwvitation to the people
who Spent the night-hero that day
because I found those things...
Idenue xe] fdr £8 IN Sh BAN Gr Skonninxa] ox (dir
nd the bames and the mess
the killer would confess...
But, since Mr. Futagawa:died
I couldn't come out and say so.
Which moans then that the person
who) killed Mr. kuuuawa is, .
Of course! The killer is...
that woman callod Ms. Nonomiy/ right?
W.What a thing to say...?!
I ossiblé
If sho roalizod that, tho cigarottos stood
for Mr. Futagawags initials. ¥
Avenging the death of har*fiane:
that was killed.
That's more: than enough motive.
Ms. Nonomiya said
she passed us In the forest
She colldn'l possibly have gone up
the hill before us,
meet Mr. Futagawa and
push him oft the chff!
But whon Mr Futagawa fell off,
all three of you ran right over..didn't you?
If somaetrody was watching
that from on top of the cliff .
Soon from on top the chff wore
only three little lights the slzc of a bean.
It'sYimpossibla to make out
who the threo of us were
from that distanco!
In other words,
by means of elimination...
the only one capablo of'being the killer 1s,
Mr. Futagawa's boss and editor, you
Mr sHaoihachi Mikami, right?
Ha. ha, ha
If the other two aren't the killer,
you say that it's me?!
Ha ha, ha
But, Mr. Futagawa was
holding 7 cigarettes!
That was a message pointing out
your name Helhachi!
It's only a coincidence...
And, besides. why do I have to go
and kill Futagawa?
If he did kill the guy called Kono
a ear ago. then the more so.
I have no obligation to avenge the doth
of a person that I've met for the first time...
rule
But that's only if Mr. Futagawa had
actually killed Mr. Kono!
WW WAN)
I lookod through the guest hook
and noticed that
Mr Mika's namo was lhistod
mu. Mr Komo s, mum,
[ #97%
Mr Mikanu's namo was histod
iter Mr. KOne's name.
; Ty 3
It dawnaod on me that maybho
Mr. Kong knew Mr Mikami's name I
$y 37
only by sound and
ofl G50 I Cryo,
By soud...
Wall,
tho mi of Mr. Mikami's. name jis. written
mi" which is: alsoupronounced to, right?
Yes. the usual kanji character for
Mlkaml" lévsafland 'the?
Mlkaml" as "sfmyana ue
Tho numbaor of strokes for
the kanji character Is...
Ono two throe
Right
the six cigarettes left behind by Mr. Kono
as well as the 7 cigarettes left behind
by Mr Futagawa are both dying messages
that stand for Helhachl Mikami!
Mr. Futagawa increased the numbaor of
cigarettes to make it easier to understand...
He chose the same brand Hf cigarette
because the killer for both Incidents was
was the same person!
Coma lto think of it, Mr. Futagawa
was laughing while looking
at tho guost book back thon.
That's whon he realized thal
Mr. IMikami killed Mr. Keno...
SQ. when he .
wmmiuridlzzznn IR, linr») my;
probably killed instead, no
Nonsense, where is such evidence?
The evidence Is.
The bag that was found In your room!
If something like tho steel pipe
that killed Mr Futagawa is found
It will serve as concrete evidence!
Hoy, hwy.
You checked that bag a while ago!
Yeah
I couldn't find the steel pipe,
but I couldn't find something
I couldpit find the steel pipe,
couldipat find the steel pipe
but I couldn't find something
couldpst find the steel pipe
I couldn't find the steel pipe.
But I couldn't find something
that should've been there either.
that should've boen there either.
Something that should've been there?
The heavy-weight for the.telescope.
. Lens barreland removed thesheavy-weight!
In order-to keep tho woighlt
what is should be...
So, will you-shew wus the inside
Of hi) Uotrs Jou
No matter how well you wipe it,
We luminol reaction from the blood
that stuck to it after you hit
r. FF utayagawa is bound to be there...
Phooey!
Flllflbjuwfiéb bl(><-1 IS defhiltuly still 'More
So, you're the one after all!
Right
I went out of my way to look after him
and see that he made it to the desk,
yet he had the nerve to say
to pay him 50.000.000 yen
If I wanted him to keep his mouth shut
about the murder
All I did was punish Kono
for not being grateful...
Punished him!
J.Just what do you mean!
A comet
A year ago, that day. the guy named Kono
came to ask me a favor.
He asked me to verify whethor
the comet he found was a new one or not.
You moan tho comaot that
was named after you ..7
It was found by that man and
I confirmed it on that cliff
It was found by that nan and
I confirmed It on that cliff
A774)
Don't tell me that you killod Asao 80 that
you could hog that comet all for yoursclf?!
I asked him to put my name on the comet,
of course. But that go
Talk about ungrateful
No. I can't...
No. I can't .
Wo'va: already decided that
the name of the star Is
AmafsLIciAI, Nonomiya. Kono comet.
What?! I thought...
Com  to think of it
he mentioned that the time's finally,come
I thought that he-found somebody else...
It was a dream
I've held since childhood too!
And yet he refused to listen to me .
Op AEE) WER PE) er ae) er yd 1
before he does
and headed back for the pension
Then, that guy came clinging onto me
80 I brushed him away...
and he fell off the cliff...
Then, later when you came here again
In order to hasten skeletonizing
of the corpse you poured lime ove .it.- ght?
Right.
What.a. surpriso
it was. to find that
Mr. Amatsuchi was the
sander of the Invitations...
I thought It was Futagawa all this time...
Hey. 'hurry and tako out the steel pipe...!
Stop pushing me!
It s.a steelipipe all right...
But. not an ordinary steel pipe!!
SS Shot.gunt?
FShot gun?
Okay You line up there too!
Yikes!
Eeks!
In Futwgnwnlsivzlsu
I just hit him to avoid th'e/gun shot but...
This time I'll finish you all off in a blow...
Ee- eemee.
Uuuuugh
No need to be scared little lady
I'll turn you Into a star in no time.
Huh?
What're you doing brat!
Can't ou see?
I'm wearing my shoes!
Shoes?
Ha ha ha, ha ..you idiot!
Do you think you can get away?
No Yr
Mine's thotsame 1s yours.
What?
[mm is am
not an ordinary shoe
See...
You yo!
Yikes!
Huh?!
Heh-rere
Aren't you glad now that your name
WIEfinally ha bhrandaod
As one owned by a criminal.
1 convicts rathor than comot.
Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
KAILSUWO ONO
Charaater-Designs 3y.
DD 5430
Story Editor.
IUNIGHI NORA .
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
ZU NARI KOU(
JUNI@HI MIYASHTIA #
» 40 be 4 » .
TQSHIK»! INDUE
Animation Dircclors.
MASATOMO SUDO
AR HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARM) OOCAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
AKASH] HYO 0
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
TAKAHISA OWACGA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director:.
KLNJIgkODAMA
IB TMS ENTERIAINMENT, 4 TD
In a. s))oration wit ]
YOMIURI TELECASTING
- > » > \
DETECTIVE CONAN
0 COSHO AOYAMA ll SHOCAKUKAN:-YIV IMS
All Rights Reserved
I wonder why Mr. Kono was 80 obsessed
about the name of thescomet?
I can undorstand hum wanting to namao it
after his fiance, Ms. Nonomiya
but why couldnitO¥nhe lot Mr. Amatsuchi wait
and name it after Mr. Mikami
Then, this wouldn't have happened...
Butxthoy wore upper classmnan and
under classman at the university...
J Lag
+ \ They were probably very good fronds!
'Hess
I dost think that's all there is:to.it.
Bo really didn't want to
Ieave out Mi Amatsuchi
because "Ama",
No".
And "Kawa"
hon you Inn) Hmm up'hnrl'/<onlalll@
stands 1ér Amanogawil,
which means the¥Milky Way...
Ooh!
I see!
Conan, yougre fantastic!
Hey. will you guys b0 :1 llttlo quiotor?
I was going to go to the country
over-to grandma's
and I ll get dispatched so
early In.the morningilike this.
I gfldfiq it'll b0 mwhulo t
iil get to go again
him 'sO@00000 sleopy
Yawn.
Whew?
Where did you callsjust now?
Grandma's 'place in Tottori...
I] HO
Tot-tori'?!
R.Ran!
Hoavo . heave. Who tho hock 1s hao?
Darn. where'd they go?
WwW. What with this siren
M Maybo
Time Limit 15:00"