Today. everyone encounters a real pinch.
The tent is mistaken for another
And Ran encounters an unexpected pinch!
He secs through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
withe-the I . QT of an adult
No (2150 is. loft unsolvod wnt-h
Detective Conan.
We're going driving. driving
it.'sghardlto'b6l nova
twas raining so hard yesterday!
True. not-even: a cloud isin sight.
I guess this Is what you call
a passing t pheo...
Did you: finish roading it?
Yep.
It was so interesting
I stayed up all night reading it.
Oh. I'm so sleepy
Slee ing Princess in a Pinch?
It's a story 1bout
many men trying toe wake a princess
who has been asleep for many years
The one who succeeds in
waking her up gets to marry her.
How romantic...
Well but she wouldn't(bcJalive
if she were sleeping for so many-ycars.
If she gets nutrition through
intravenous drip she'll be fine!
I'll: bet she just pretended to he asleep
all the while. right?
Because no man of her cho ce
happen to come b
Huh, C.Conan. didsyou read je Hook?
éve (00
You ro spoiling*my droam
Time Limit Is 15:00!"
Lots, take the best place
Under the tree 'has been taken.
That's the only place with a 5 ade
That's the only place with a shade...
All -sa.
Misa, can you get that peg
over there for me}?
Huh'? Pa...
What
Tihat little stick to poke inte the ground.
That ONE
Why don't you say so in the first place
After all, this is the first time
I've come:camping.
Oh. sorr . sorr .
Oh sorr sorr .
Never mind. I'll get it myself
By the way,
why do have to stay in such a cheap tent.
Couldn't you get something hike that!
You sce, hike that!!
There are no such rental tents.
That's why I'm asking you
why our tent is a rentedrsone...?
Why didn't go out and buy one?
What?
If you're going to bring me to camp.
Isn't that plain common sense
Go and buy one right this minute!!
She's super unreal. that lady...
You know I can't do that...
Let's go to a pension then!
I don't like this tent
What?! I brow- ht you to camp ,
because I wanted to show you
how enjoyable it would be!
Seems like we've got guests already
Yeah, we've got no choice...
Pct!
wy! WW
SO why don't we SR up ED
somewhere around here.
') Cl
Okay, hurry! Let's go get the rental tents!
Okay. hurry! Let's go get the rental tents!
Oka. . hurr! Let's go get the rental tents!
All done!
Okay. let's set up the tent for the girls
on that side next.
Hey wait up!!
No'! I can't take this anymore...
Come on. don't be like that. Misa.
I'm really going home...
Missal
- - pg /
-- - go /
AN night it seoms, that they're leaving.
All nght it seems that they're leaving.
P50 Sua REY, Yods Cop Oompial
Sigh ..Slave driver...
You really set it up fast this time.
Es. .the second time around is easy
Dong push:-yourself. Maybe
you should sleep for a while?
I'm fine. I'll stick it out until
I finish making the curry.
because I'll bet you're all hungry. right?
Hey. what's up!
How come]a tent is standing. in our place?!
His. is..our place!
You said you were leaving. didn't you?
Miss...
You did say so. didnst you?
Ell. ..l guess I did. sort of...
You changed your mind.
Hey. what's this? No joke.
Thus us our plump"
But. we already«put up our tent
just went to exchange the tent
becausepthere wasxash0le in the one
I just got. Get on with it and
movegyour tents out of the way!
Okay. let's clear the tent. out of the way.
What~~~?1
Well, it is a fact that they were here first.
Okay. so hurry on and get it out of the way
You can leave it as is
Huh, what do you
think yo 1're saying. Misa?
They're saying they're
going to move. you know.
We can set the tent up
somewhere around there.
Mi.» is the bust place them us.
Right umderithis tree!
"So Wh
Tsk!
Darn...
You should cut it into smaller pieces.
Huh?
When you make curry at home, you can
spend a long time boiling the contents.
But. you can't do that hero. right?
You seem used to this
Here let me do it...
I may not look it, but I'm
pretty much 1 homemaker too...
ay tay Say Wy
What happened. to your boyfriehd?
Who cares.
Huh?
It's over with us.
Women! can sensc things like this
I guess this Is it...
Just great
Li': ',-
They sure: have everything here...
these recent camping grounds
Yeah
Oh. I wonder! f she 2lready woke up...?
S.Somebody?!
Somebod . come quick!
Hat seems to be the matter?
Ran was kidnapped!
My god!
Ran!
Darn, where the heck did that guy, go?
They're not over here!
Darn! Why'd he take Ran?!
R.Ran!!
Conan!
I wonder who the hell he is...?
There Is a smell of a drug inside.
It seems she was put to sleep with a drug.
The car that fled was
reported to be a stolen car,
so I'm sure we'll be
able to find it right away.
I sure hope so.
The point is why the
culprit kidnapped Ran
There are so many other people
on this camping ground and yet.
What a thing to say! Mow irresponsible!!
You're the one who said ou wanted
LO Stay over at a pension,
so let's hurry up-and head over.
NA friend of some people
we got to know on the camping
ground was kidnapped! I can't just leave.
Misa. this has nothing to do with us.
Yes, it does.
He's still breathing!!
ISIt-his the sneaker that tine mam
who kidnapped Ran (
was wearing?
No doubt about it.
It's the sama 1s the one
the man was wearing.
Whi€h means that you
caught the kidnapper?
A car fell over a cliff near here...
Thus is, the shoe that the
driver of the car was wearing
His unconscious and in the hospital now...
Huh, then Ran...
Poe. what about Ran?!
I don't know about Ran
The car was a regular sedan,
and Ran was nowhere in sight.
What~~7?!
We found from his driver's license
that he is Masayuki Takada. age 25.
There seems to have been a half written
mail that hasn't been sent out,
hinting that he had committed
the crime left on his cell phone.
The police seem to have concluded
that the accident was caused
probably because he was
eying intmair we « nving.
And. what about that mail?
Osuoms to hava an accomplice
31-7
He seems to have an acedmplice.
-7 r-
I guess Takada was the one who
carried out the crime for somebody else.
{mm [hero scum» to. biianothur hl<.
m...There seems to be afiot-her flu
Doc. will you lend it to, me
Doc. will you lend it to me.
Sneaker .
This is rubber boots used when fishing.
Why's this thing, here?
Why's this thing here?
Ran? No...not so
I see. the tent
It's the tent!
If you insist on going home just like that,
I swear I despise you forever
Go ahead. and suit,yourself.
I don't intend to stick around
with a stuck up like for life...
I'm nothing more to you
han some slave to humor you,
SO eck with you
Why didnlt you answer the call
I tried calling you many times
Ou Ic nNAappcec Ye wrong woman...
Masayuki Takada is
hospitalized now because
the police called from his cell phone.
Hey! Where's Ran?!
I don't know I don'teknow.
I asked Takada to get the weman
who was in the tent under that tree.
But. thanks to 1 small mistake.
Thu plum: was takun by somuonu ulso.
I tried to contact you about it
but Takeda had his cell phone turne. off... 4
his picture is pretty blurred
Depending on how'you look at: it,
it sort of looks like Ran.
What's your connection with Takeda?
One morning at a certain station.
I saw-the man ¢1lléd Takeda,
kick aiman onto the railroad.
I ref xively followed Takeda and
made sure that I could contact him.
Several days later. when
I asked him to kill Misa,
he didn't refuse because
told him I'd pay him 1.000.000 yen...
Why'd you want to do such a thing to Misa?
She was in the way, of me getting a life...
She's selfish, extravagant
and to top it off. a busy-body.
I just couldn't call it off with her.
I wasn't going waste my life just for her.
[That's for Misa to say. You ro the pits.
I don't mind you holding
) crudge against me
But, I won't ever forgive you
for endanger the life of someone
that has nothing to do with us...
Where is she?!!
Bets me...She may already be dead.
I know that Ran's alive.
C.Conan...
Atleast until 15:00.
Written on the mail that wasn't sent out,
it said. the woman dies at 15:00.
Let's go look for her
We've only got 30 minutes!
I.Let's hurry!
Shall we go then
We'll hear you out at the station.
Why are we looking by tho river?
The executor of the crime. 1akéda~ h 115
Iong rubber boots used for fishing
Iong rubber beets used for fishing
Ht was approximately
40 minutes from the time when
he kidnapped Rn to
when he had the accident.
Hey couldn't have gone far.
NOON {
In the mean time. he changed cars and
werc long rubber boots
that went up to 'us chest...
\Whkedn tines IR (ee (10) lox
somewhere around here...
20 minutes to go...
If Takada changed cars,
MS Prod, Cass...
Let's" look. fo dthe 4WD!
Okay!
Don't do anything reckless
Let:me know when you find her!
Where on earth are you, Ran...
A dam?
The reservoir lake of the dam...
Doc. . who-dam
Let's search the reservoir of the dam.
0.Oh~ all right
But there isn't enough time so I'll go.
SLZEB KUET
BRER
SLE KURT
? vs - =
EI$ZPSM
STILE KUET
914E152 KL/fi?
\ ther) No -
y ax -
The water's.going to be discharge. on no.
So this was what 15700 that was
written in Takada's mail meant
I got it.
It's where'the water will be I
rcleased and the car will sink!
Doc. Doc!
No good. fl can't get through
Look atathat!
There's moss on it.
Which means that water
Ievel will comejte that point.
Even cars will sink.
1! There it is!
N.No joke! +
C.Conan!
Cc.Conan!
You guys stay herel!
Stay right:there
Stay-right there
Ran-- Thank goodness.
Ran~ Thank goodness
No good. it's locked...
U: 1061., We {lord
Let's try cracking the glass with this
Its sO hard ~~
Execute periodic water discharge!
Roger! «
W. What's with this siren
N No. don't tell me that
No. don't toll me that
All Fight!
Ran. wake up!! Get up!!
The alarm.
Stopped
Looks bad Conan!
It seems like tho water level Is rising!
Go back both of you!!
B.But...
Never mind, just leave
everything to: me and go. quick!!
Hey. wait up!
Just what-do you think you're doing.
This is an authorized personnel ony sone!
I.I'm fully aware of that.
The riverbank - The children
are at the riverbank. S. Stop the water!!!
W . What?
Conan!
I've got only one? cctvmco
to try and make anrc¢scapc...
Conan's roally in trouble...
It's dangerous here too
Let's go up the bank!
Conan.
Conan!
Now!!
OGRE =z)
Genta~~~1]
Okay. leave it to me!!
Ag ag ™ -~ {1
A Agh
A.Agh...
Okay. everybody. pull!
Okay! Leave it to me
Okay!
Agh~~~hey are all of you all right...
Conan
Conan.
I'm sorry... It's all because. of Mme
Original Comic Boo "Ry
GOSHO A0ovahin
Produccrs.
MASAHITO v + ~ OK
Background Music.
KAISUO ONT
Character Designs 3y.
MASATOMO SUDO
Sty: dit).
RAN]? IFASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI K@U CF!
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
FX » & »
105M110: mow
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUD
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO!/ (TOGA 'ARA
AISUSHILAONOY
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODQ
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUITANI
Ja vo oF Photo many
TAKASHI NOMURA
IKE SADT
Recording Director
KATSUYOSH BAVA
Editor.
TERUMITSU. OKADA
Cel director.
KENJI. KODAMA)
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAIN ENT, LID
mm assowtion with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
TFC TIN IGOR AN
COVE AOYAMA SHOGVRUR TR YIV Tm
Ul Ris: his Reserved
Eo 0 SI LT HAS
fr 3y
Sigh
J lie
Soin
Sigh
Soll
Joli
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry
I guess I really overslept «
Oh...I'd like some curry too
What's wrong everybody...
Nothing. ..we're just pooped.
Uh, Conan...
h, Conan...
Huh. Conan...!
He's exhausted and
asleep in the boy's tent.
Ah, he's always like that
He doesn't think of what happens
after he exhausts himself
playing and sacks out.
Oh. well...
Oh and. why am I wearing pajamas...?
How:come? How embarrassing .
Ha. ha. ha... Hey.
This town is preserved as an«old
do style town.
You guys arc like "Meomotare, right?
- Hh pp
We: can unravel the "Mometarov¥ legend ~~
Let's do it] Letss-dO it!
Hey Heya
He He
pec...
It's Momotaro's peach!
Youggotta be kidding!--
(BI%R)
Next/Conan
(RIFE)
Reach Boy:-MysteryzSo ving Tour Part 1!