7 an ea
IodaY's story has to do with Peach Boy.
Clear up the mystery of the legend!
A dog, pheasant, monkey,
ind even an ogre appear!
He sues through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with detective €onan
Peach Boy!
Thosuisweelstyou Nave hanging ow your
I id hike tO have onc too
Huh?! Peach Boy!
What? aall
>, toe storyagoes#Pe. ch Boy.
Around the middle of the 7th Century,
In order to defeat Ura.
The demon that had come from a foreign land,
to carry out a countless number of atrocities.
The Yama co Court sends out a galleu
and renown warntivr called
Kibitsuhiko no Mikoto
It is said that this story
Is based on the battle between the: two
But that is not fact
I he facts
In the year 663,
as stated also in the Chronicles of Japan.
The Japanese Yamatormilitary that
Iost in the Battle of Hakusukimod
built fortifications one after the other
to prepare against
the attacks of enemy forces.
This story scems to be related 10
one of the fortific. tidns. Kinnojyo"
and Kibitsu, in Okayamn Rrofecture
where the castle us fecated...
DERNSP RIP A»
= ON 2
nd Kibitsu, in Okayamn Prefecture
WANE hee) elke Bs Lotte)
mum-m
4 nd Kihitsu, in Okayamn Prefecture
whore the castle is located.
VINO WA
And Kibitsu, in Okayama Prefecture
wheratharrastisisjoseated
BERG A
nd Kinitsu fin Okayama Prefecture
here the castle 1s located
» PITA
Ea Fis
ind Kibitsugin Okayama Prefecture
WO 0) etetlka Bs I ok
NOB (TA
Nd Kibitsu gin Okayama Prefecture
whore the castle 1s located.
MOXEITA
O TL Oo
I here arc many ancient tombs an Kibitsuygi
MOEITA
ee UY 2
I here arc many ancient tombs in Kibitsuy
MRXITA
O TL DO
TE ER
[hore are many ancient tombs in Kibitsuyjr.
Hi 10) btn t= Be Qt E00 Taos to CTE Ruf)
Buried there are of course,
the cultures Bf hat era.
1s well as with no doubt,
the memories of various people
HA AA
(mm)
(BI$R)
Peach Boy Mystery Solving Tour Part 1
YA AA
(BI%R)
iawcadaaahn!!
When one thinks of Okayama.
What comes to mind is P>cach Boy... night?!
And ..Pcach Boy also brings to mind.
Millet dumpling!
Lveiyihiing is food to you, isin Ww&into
Uh... a dog. right? A pheasant!
Monkey!
Defeating the demon on Demon's Isl.ind!
Well-true. but...
Welltrue, but...
After all this is a weekend trip.
As well as a*history study tour so...
Yes, We studied bhroetorchond for Was
O please reter to more Specialized event
you're night Mitsuhiko
you're right Mitsuhiko
But first of all I'd like to have
a drink along with Mamakarl as a side dish
Nuha, ha
My god! Not you too. Doc!!
Well- Sorry. I'm sorry! Aha, ha
Aha. ha.
Wewe arrivedhin Okayama!
We've arrived in/-Okayamal!
We're transferring
to the Sanyo main linc next!
We're transforming
to the Sanyo main line next!
We're transferring
to the, Sanyornain line next!
Hurry hurry!
Hurry, hurry!
Hey. you don't have to rush so much.
Tho rains already herd!
EN Kurashiki is famous for itsifine sight
Iandscape of white walls.
Yep, it'swh'at'travelilovingydfrls admire.
But. before that . this 1s where I want to go
Flo!
Hello!
Guanah
Chibon Park.
Kya: vi ah
hat's enough! Sciko!
ON Rn makes your think
You can talk to me hike that, Saruwatan
You got to go independent because I wrote
in article and advertised for you, and yet.
Just:how much do you think I had to pay you for...
Oh went out of my wy
to give you classmate discount!
Not) (op Xie) (812) Pkt Me fl
v:_h ll ta
A. Are you all right, JAyumi ?
Look what your oid to Ayana!
I'm sorryl So sorry!
Are you all rig t?
I hope you're not hurt, are you?
Thank you so much.
We'r¢
nd cmbarrassced for actimg So childish
I feel bad \ Aha, ha...
Really, I do too. aha, ha...
I'll4bet you're feullnuyredlly nuclq?!
Hey... Did you both apologize'?
CraQ)
Little Indy, how do you like the ice cream
we bought for you good )\
Yes, it's delicious!
Oh, I'm glad!
[ Hat'sino way to apologize, 1s it?
You're all'fnends=arent you?
I don't think it's good to fight...
Ha, ha. Friends, ch. r
It's true that we're classmates
Ince our elementary school days
But, some live in O@saka
ind others In Tokyo-now...
SO, It's been "bhouti15 years
sine we've. seen. cach other
The last time we saw each other
was when we were Just about your age...
Which means... it's your class reunion?
Huh. sort of...
Oh... I'm sorry, my name Is Agasa
I'm their ¢haperone or rather,
In chcorting the Caldrenfon then top:
Ir Ayumi. Ayummi Yoshida!
Hem! Fin Mitsutnko I suburaya!
I'm Genta Kojima!
Huh. oh, LI'm Conan Edogawa
Nola barsief
the Youth Dotoctive Squad!
Av, ha...
Has ha. ha... what a polite introduction...
I'm Naoto Momo
I'l Yayo Kipma. Nice to met you.
Rd. from this side, he's Kengo Saruwatari,
Seiko Inul
Md Mamoru Onitsura
Youth Detective Squad, eh...
We named our group
SOmae Ing 1 ¢ a 00
And we're gathered because. In.
Il tell you!
After "Ill. M's what I proposed to bugn with.
We got together this time to support Momoly
who's going to be a candidate for election,
nd so to congratulate
his marriage to Yayo!
Wow!
NOU TEREOMEEIO He taney Be election
Congratulations!
T.Thank you.
Peach Boy nd the pheasant
are going to get married
Huh?
So, you noticed too, Mitsuhko?
You're Peach Boy, right!
You're Peach Boy. right!
What's this about
[ heir names, night?
The first two letters) of hcirManics arc
characters that appear in Poach Boy
Rerch(Momo), Pheasant (IKiji
Monkey (Sara), Dog(liu). and Demon(@nn)?
17/ <
>eaeh Mome), Pheasant (IKiji) A
Monkgy(Saruy, Lg), and Demon(On)
Fuh, fuh, fu
Just as expected of the
Youth Detective Squad.
Right, that's why we cted 'out Pench Boy
IN our School play because of our names.
I Talk about old story
How noslalgic.
But bck then,
OSD ERA KR CRW (pe)
SUNY SIERO
Adv vt
Never mind about the past.
By the way, what now
oud did Qo I 2 hacks Cl pL «
IFomorrow we go treasure hunting, right?
Huh? Yeah
Treasure hunting?
I hat's new to mac!
LT expla ityatdehinneratinag
Until then it's free tine. (
I guass that's it for now then
Byc little lady!
Irguess.we should get going too
WOW '1
I his is Kurashiki
How nice!
The Ihandacape from the Edo Period has
been maintained all this time. Right. Doc!
Yeth... Most of those warehouses Were built
by the mcrchants back then. 44
The sed to transport
all kids of merchandise
hing their ships Into Kurashiki Rivor
dow bheavtiful!
Ie The:pasted roof tiles on the east side
UBL 4) CHROOT TU 228 yg
are said to-he one of the
most beautiful in this fine sights-district.
All the thing. exhibited here are thing
that have Béden!ex: .avated from the tombs
and ruins of the districts of Kurashiki,
Klbitsu and the entne tsp-to Inland area
LAAAAA, .
Hmm there sure is a lot to lcarn
Hmm there sure is a lot to learn
Coming in touch with culture of the past...
can be useful
Aha, ha.
Hut. this is the best after all!
It's delicious
Yep.
Hmm it's Mamakari after all
Mama carry the food over to me.
Aha ha There he goes agam. I.
A peach
P Peach?!
P.Peach, like in Peach Boy!!
Wow!
Y.Yougotta be kidding...
There
Ugh!
We've almost got it!
Genta!
Wangan herd!
Ay! Hold on tight!
Be Garcia
I didn't think it would be real, but
And inside we find.
Lnvelopes?
Inside the envelop. 1S >
What's this /
d Maybe it's a-code!
Ac de
(I 8 yy BR 0-6 Conn idl) 0 Gh Clad _wlk
It's elementary school level...
But.it's something worth studying
because we're here!
Weill solve the code and'excavate'a tomb
Maybe weanll he able to find the treasure
on Demon's Island
IR: 2!
W Weilliresolve the Peach Boy'legend!!
Let"  do at!
'Lip-ti b"(1()'ll
AMHey:, hey.
Then: TL go rest somewhere nearby
Give it your best, all of you
I'll leave the rest up to you, Shinichi!
Is this your doing?zDoc?.
No. I know nothing of it;
It's, not am.
But, studying should be fun,
above all.
hove all.
What great educational material
to study with How lucky
See ou
Give mea break
Okay, the Youth Detective Squad launches
Ope ation Treasure Hum!
Mil. Nip hooray
hd Hey!
What's with this picture
On its ¢ye... This eyelash 2
Uh. Fire, maybe
Uh- Con:.
I lull»
Oh. that':s-1 very natural way to look at it
Fire and cy. ™y
pronouncedihi(lite)mc (Lye) stands for...
ire... Lye... Fire and. eye.
Agh!!
L-are and eye!
It's the Hinonu Yagura (watch tower)!
Whew.
Did ou find anything?
No...
Did you hind something ?
'17., ulhib It),
Did you find it. Conan?!
Did you-find it, Conan?!
Y: Yeah
hah ansurd!
Open it. open it!
Open it, open it!
Finan
What's this. It's just filled with junk!
It's out of bittery too
At the least, it's no treasure
AL the leastaitss hotrensure
What aretyourlooking at, Conan!
OGsyears wasfhllotiof fun.
6 years was a lot of fun.
Il except for that, one incident 2!
What does that rector to?
B.Beats me
HBedts ma
Maybe thistisra timc capsule
I%-Inmc capsule 2!
Frm capsule?!
Really? Are,you sure?!
Ifthiglis Ct Xo) Ms flnns) expert,
I wondur ifit's'okaysthatitwe dug it up'?
OO course, its notyokayO... Aha, ha
Ive-only things.
Ilys obvious that somebody
has already dug this up before us...
MET thiSsigO
yo Sey!
Our rival treasure hunters 7
WW So woe cantiotihom heat us)!
Lot's hurry and solve the next code, Conant
Aha ha, ha...
tunel fialne lise!
Me 109 elt SH Co vo, SAYS.
J stwhal does it mean?!
IFeantsmake it out at all
Wellfhthis'is super basic of codes.
So, what is it?
You move each alphabet
10 the front one by one,
Whichmmeans ..It's:beforc- PP.
Right!
He next alphabot before ls cise HE imght!
Lhe next alphabet bhoetove Vol night!
Next.
Ohashi, chopsticks' 42
The one you u:.@ when eating?
No, it's probably the name of a place.
And. somewhere near Kurashiki here...
Oh"?
You children. what are you doing?
Oh I guussiwe meet again...
Well. . we were trying to solve 1 code
Ugh ugh
W.What brings yolhhera?
Aren't you going around
with the rest of your group ?
Yes. well
I'm not very well liked by everybody so.
Yoursawdor yourselves just a while 1qo,
didn't you?
But, why not,
you're all classmates: aren't you'?
Since long 'w1y back in the past,
I could never he.
I wns intending to write 1 article advertising
Mr. Onitsura's company,
DU he We wrote was.
The double aspects front and
behind the scenes of money lendens
Evenwhen:Mr Saruwntan went independent
we) Cox1ng 0] dks Ow UXO 167 x11,
I honestly wrote how good I thought he was.
I mean, I cant help it because he's not good
Then, Yayor...
I ended up fighting tor Mr.Momoi with her
We were going with
cach other tll recently
hum and I...
I see, nts why something about
thom was awkward
STARR ILE RTC MN gt
OWl... You re sure sharp, renown detective!
remember you saying hat
he ws In charge of making tha script and
interpretation Sf the:Peach Boy play that
you put on.
Of course, we would've called him.
Fhe were alive.
\  No
You mean he passed away,
15[Years 10 Ina traffic. hcecident
SO we cou dnt graduate togethe
10 Way
He ws full of justice
ind asrcally good boy
Oh!! Sorry, sorry, it's this dark already.
Hang in there Youth Detective Squad!
Agh!!
Flere ate We ve found it!
O ha shi...Ohashi...plus house!
It sort of sounds like
somethi g in a samurai movie!
If I remember correctly,
this Ohashi residence
If 1 lemeMBer correctly,
this Ohashi reslidcnce
Min;
IMlyinil
Iter the developmentiof Shioda became
1 great landowncr
after the development of Shioda became
a great landowner
This house is said to be
about 200 years old
Wow, Mitsuhiko!
Oh, well, it's really nojbig deal...
I'm glad I did some studying beforehand
Oka . let's search!
INfound)iit!! I found] it!
Nut .lq.nn
t's already been dug up.
Not this again
Old comics
And old station hy
Not "that again...
I'm sure tht
somebody sibeatingas tot!
Okay. next! Next!
I he square face of a...clown?
What wary at called)?
[NERY OF [US EERWI ti wcll lofineas,
NAO tet, (of fog Btn 1:3
Right!
If flo a =r cad, Me 3 OEE ore) WE,
Miss UM 00, and...
[his ssa but I wonderwhy it's reversed?
Lula, (Japanese tor wy) wy.
You mean, ivy, the plant?
Tisuta is ivy in English
I he next word 1s "square *
I got I™Over ther, over there!
Kurashiki Ivy Square!
@velinere"
Ivy!
How spacious.
[ verybody.
Misused Lo HO aspuning factory
It seems that the buildings back then
are, Hemg used as is)
and turned into hotels ind
memorial halls
Okay. let's start
Aye'.
Ahlgoe!
here's nothing thatylooks like
\reasurclanywhere
What the heck is gong on'?
Ha. ha, ha, Lbgotat
Not only the "a" Is reversed.
A it \
LONE dking) Ba ti Ay ME
Abt Bey tn oe A cof Qiks hy £30 LO,
I see! Behind!
I found It! I found it!
Did ou find the treasure /!
Not again...
Not again
I alk about depressing...
Oo bay Gd < GDR
K aaaaahl!
Whaaaa
It. It's that lady
Am, Ambulance and the p.police
No gwod... She's not breathing anymore.
Ad ing message...
O.N,I..Oni...
CO. IN, 1...OOmdb...
O Oni?!
Milka is an ogre Like my Peach Boy!
Oh no!
Uh, soayoure. the ones who found her...
I he Youth Detective Squad!
Huh
I here they go again...
If the killer ran ogi
» Wc'll be Peach Boy»
and punish, rather arrest him! ¥
Good«grief
Goodynef
Excuse me sir,
Is that the belongings of the victim?
Huh. oh, right...
Huh? Over there,
bonnuhnngk» not right. is» it'?
Hat stamp
That stamp.
\Wiy ls 0 AA: 130
Bets no.
So. what?
50, what?
LVI A Gono
Sorry to have bothered you
0. »eing friends of the victim,
the four were interrogated by the police
Oh which mens
that none of-your:has an ality
To put it more cod dBW; I was alone
Like I said, there were 1 lot.of people
at Chibori Park. so there must-be somebody
who remembers seeing me.
Same here.
I was in (he lobby of the hotel
that I'm staying at
There were a lot of people there too.
Unfortunately. it would be difficult to
WAL Eek
I guess we don't have a problem, then?
We were together all the While.
You were walking aleng the
fine sights district. you say?
Yes sir, we were togcather all the say.
The only time we were alone was
when we went to the bathroom
Even so, we weren't separated
{fur more arm b MIHJNBNMMLS...
I don't mon to be rude, hut we can't tailko
the: testimony-ofaa rane just hike that
Moreover, our investigation shows
that you were going with the victim too
I, That's
T. That's...
The other two seem to have'hd
SOME trouble with the victim Loo
Officer Tsuyamn, they're here.
Is thaththo countainer tht
trim peach was lnsldifi
Yep It may have nothing to do with
the incident. butiwe: contacted you
hecquse we'thought we should let you
know, about it, Just in casc
Is not that we wanted to report this,
but we figured we had to cooperate
with your investigation
Is that
Our time capsule
wit 1» the code we entered...
Oh... what a surprise
The code was wht specified
the place in which
hey hid their time capsules 15 year go.
15 years ago, all of them put things that were
recious to them inside a time capsule and
after shuffling, exchanged them,
each person burying a capsule
other than his own
They tried to make it so that the owners of
the capsule didn't knbw where it Was buried.
And. that's the very reason
why they were able to le. ve
behind their true and honest feelings...
The facts, that Inst night the
clemontary school that
you all attended was raided bytsomeone.
Huh?
And we found out that this container wns
also included among the things
that were damaged.
@/) WO)
Then, we received word from them
«that they prokedf ins up.
-
Then we received word from! them
that they picked this up
«rs O »
Then, we received word from them
that theypicked this up
that theyapicked this up
oe , Wh
Then, we received word from them
that they picked this up.
Then: we received word from them
that they pick this up.
7 fey
Then, we received word from them
that: they picked this up
0, vr 1
Then, we received word from them
that they picked this up
Phooey! It must be some work of fate
hat we ran into you guys
what are you going te do stealing
something like that?
That's why you threw itervay, right?
Because you figured it
ont bring you any money
Then. is this how it went, officer?
Seiko,
as a journalist happefied to figure: out
who the culprit that raided the school was
and was killed instead
Of UPL SEE,
We're looking at It from) a different angle.
Mr. Onitsura!
Noll I didn't do it. I'm innocent!!
Don't get me wrong
US POI you're st ony 4major wi ness
Then, why am I the only who
1s beng detained?!
How would you explam this dymg message!
It seems that you were holding «1 grudge
against the victim
since she wrote an article
about you that you didn't
Hey...do you really think Mamoru did it?
Cut it out! Saruwatari!
Could be...
How dare you talk like that too, Momoi...
These da s.
It's not surprising who... kills who...
This is no time to be treasure hunting...
$0, the killer 1s an ogre after all.
I sure wish we could catch it!
Senta your re: holding the silverware
with:iwrongthands'
You're supposed to hold the knife with
yournght hand Ald your fork with your lcit.
What's the diff. After all. I'm right handed
So I wanna hold my fork with my right hand
Ha, ha, ha, ha,
do you want to ask for chopstiOksi ge
Why didn't you do so
In the first place. Doc?!
I see...so that's it
If so, the contents of the
dyl g message would change
Now Irm sure...
The killer is among the four of them!
But in order to specify who it is,
the remaining two codes will
have to be, solved, 1nd the burned
time capsule needs to he found
Original Comic Be#ic By,
moan?) AOYAMA
Producers.
MASAHITO Y( St OK
Background Movic.
KAISUO ONG
Character Designs by.
MASATOMO § DO
Story Fditor
JUNICHI {KA
RAN]? ITASHIWABARA
KAZUNAI'l KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHIIA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKd INOUE
himation Directors. I.
N <O 3 To
HA TY (OUGA ARA
« 1 YO)
so SWITTY AWN Ur
Wi. adv
FAGASHL RIC J
Art. Dire for.
YUKIAIR SHIBUIANI
fr yoy oy
my I/.0CQUULED If 1niuwutla Jin
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Dire (or
KAISUYOSH BAvA
Fditor.
ILRUMIISU OKADA
Chef Director.
KEN] KOIAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT LID.
1 assowtion with
YOMIU I TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DITECTIV EGON AA
CGO THOESOVAMAY MHOGARUR Wy IV TMA
WR hies WT
I knew that the me
capsule was going to be dug up
Vy alton (8 Gi
I wanted to check on something so
I went alone to bookstores and the brary.
Justto be prepared for this...
I. Mtsuiiiko Tsuburaya
brought my notebook along
All right!
Good work, Mitsutnko
(1% 3:5?)
I each"Boy Mystery:Solving Tour~Pant 27?