Fine Capsules come out one after the other
Gathorningrsecrots that
Ire scattencid mere and then
Dig out thesunoxpectod killer!
Dig out the unexpected killer!
He sees through the one and only truth
A child In appearanco
with the I.Q. of an adult
O 11 oltsuinse
with, Detective Conan
Doc, the mobers ofl the
Youth Detective Squad and I
ST JAPAN
Doc, the mambers of tho
YoullmDetectivorSquadrandil d
Doc, the members of the
Youth Detective Squad and,
cama along on a weekend
tour to Klmtsxxji Kunffihuu
inrOkaynmw Pref em un.
To study anceiont histdry
Out of theh poople we met thor,
one person was killod.
A member of the group ends up
being Investigated as a major witness
However. I'hadeamyadcoubr ts.
I see... so that's the story
If so. the contents of the
d Ing message changes
The killer<is among the four.
But:in order to specify the killer
the twoiromaining codes
have to be found and solved!
Peach Boy Mystery So ving Tour Part 2
I don't have conclusive proof...
But. if the motiverof the murder
has to do with the time capsule...
Then
Irot's.continue daeaeaiphernng
the remaining code
OO (IOS (ils whet wa)
0. AOU JD LOroSan0o easue
I, feel likeswe cant-back off anymore!
Me too!!'=sBut... what-re we going to do?
Ihe code was-burned, wasn't it?
Oh .-right.
duh fue, ful,
Fuh, fuh fuh
'o/Ho prepared just in case
Ty ma 1 h
_ IL Mllwu1mlkww1iéufiurayu1. took notesH
All right, Mitsuhiko!!
Good work, Mitsuhiko...
Okay!! Tie Youth Dotic tiv
Squad willdaunch.operation!
This Is... an umbrella...
This Is...the sun, right?
Ha. ha. you tried yout
hest to copy It, Yiln't you
Oh!... think this is!
Yeah... .that's it!!
DO S00 WED
Doc suro is lato.
A > TR_X 7 Le
«I wonder what's taking him so long
C > Cs.»
Ole UO IR Woe 8 or ve?
We don't have ll day. Doc!
Ikm 80 sorry.
UUuOwLIJJIA
where would you lllke me to take you?
To Soja City right next door!
'he so called Kibitsuji!
Roger!!
Kit>ii?
More accurately, called
tho Koumonzuka Tomb
It's a lamousrtomb located in Kibitsuji
Huh?! Oh...l see!!
Tikes ty (KAI
Right Genta! It's anzumbrella!
Koumori gas umbrella
(Ye "on fe) Ky uo Utne Allg
Koumor gasa umbrella
WY GEN QS antuamnore
Koumori gnsa umbrella
rel UR Lid ly
Koumori gasa umbrella
Right Gental (U's ansumbre)lal
Koumer gasa umbrella
rail
Right Genta! It's an"umbrella!
Koumorl gasa umbrella
U till)
Qops. I almost forgot
I's information regarding. the case
Huh?!
It seems that Mr. Saruwnlaro
in plnco of Mr Onitsuin
Is being questioned as a major witness.
Huh?
Huh?!
Of course he's denying the charges
Something about they found out
that there was a change in cast
In the play that was
performed 15 ears ago...
A change?!
It seems that Mr. Onitsura wa
not good at remembering has lines.
So he changed roles with Mr. Saruwatarl
So. tho possibility of the dying message
UNI" being r. Saruwatarl came up.
He doesn't have an alibi
and besides. above all
he was the one who was (
arguing with the victim
t sees he soon ma be arrested
I kind of had a feeling because...
dogs and monkeys don't
get along. Just as I thought!!
BUI Chic a es on BX) he)
work together to defeat the ogre
WER Pet potiy » Sica Sai fo
neo more than a fairy talo after all
It sure Is a bit disappointing.
Anyway 18tss hurgy! We've
QOot TO, Contr «ll to C.A1pPpSUIOS
How beautifull!
There's something nostalgic about this
In ancient times, this area
was called tho Land of Kibitsu
nd was said te be just as powerful
1s the Yamato Imperial Court!
Wow!
Dugout
[his is the large key hol
shaped tomb, isn't it?
I'm sure we .can go inside...
H. How scary!!!
This Komorlzuka Tomb la said have
been built at the end of the 6th Century.
Tanh vol
tombs have also beenkfound.
1% really starting to gel
Iike we're treasure hunting!
WHO erm vf
wo've got lots of work to do.
But, it's 80 vast that
wo'vo gotlots of work to do
Wa capable of finding what wao'ro
Iooking for. that's why we're calle
the Youth Detective Squad
Besides!
Iv tire that at been
dug over againlanyway...
so. It won't be hard toff ind
1 boos IR Bol 1 (awd) kd
Yes. again
S Cc ug ovar again by someone...
UT <3 hss ll (hos neakoke)
What iz. this?
Is it a code nga?
Aha. ha, ha. had
They've got us~Mitsuhike!
That codo's a dummy}!
What?! A dummy
You meat itys fake?
Yeah, lake a good look at it, the'code.
A hall folded umbrella under the sun...
[here's no need to uselit.
What"
I We real code Is this new one hero
Uh, this Is a shrine gate...and what's thisj?
A pot for cooking rico
On @R Bow.
0\ lo
A shrine gate, nee cooker
Nd peach . sounds familiar.
A shrine gate. rice cooker
and peach sounds familiar
It's Kibitsy Shrine!
KIBItSu Shrine?!
Whagaaaaah~~I
It's the place where the hero.
Kibitsuhlko-no-Mikoto. Who
as legend has It. Is enshrined!
You've really studied well
beforehand. How amazing.
Huh, huh .
I seat Tho poach stands tor Peach Boy and
the shrine gate... stands for shrine
Then, what about this pot?
T. That's.
I guess We'-ll..find out if,we go there.
(00 wu (ow Al OF ow Loe,
No fair
Hurry, Youth Detective Squad!!
What~~~7?1 A\Aye!!
I'm pooped
I'm hungry
Okay. lot's go!!
Heyl! Walt Conan
ay Ny ie aw
Lote, take It slow
XIMLJCIL 1+
NO woe
vsee
With the sound olgthe rice cook
With the sound ofpthe nce cookers
we can toll if our fortunao is lucky or Not
££ An
-- gg -
With the sound olithe rice cookar
we can toll if our fortune. is lucky or not.
With the sound of the nce cookor
wo can toll at our fortune is lucky or not.
With the sound of the rice cookor
we can tell at our fortuno 1s lucky or not.
Il? 7
With the sound of the rice cowker
we can toll it our fortune is lucky or not.
With the sound, of the rice comkor s
wae can tell it our fortuno is lucky or not.
'Fifi
With the soundgol the rice cookor
wo can tell it our tortuno is luckyYor not.
With the seoundyol the rice cookor
we can toll it our fortune Is lucky or not...
With the sound of the nce cookor
we can tell it our fortune Is lucky or not
Wow~sounds interesting
Okay!!! It's got to be
somawhere around hero!
Let's search!!
I'm sure it's probably
going to be dug over agam!
V8 Soy QT Ste 3)
guess It's not a dumm. this time
All that's thside Is junk.
That's nO" nice
Yeah, it's their treasure of 15 years ago...
Shunya, please rest in peace...
Shunya
He's the one who passed away
In a traffle accident 15 years 130. right.
in a traffic accident 15 years ago. fight
He's the one who passed away
in a traffic accident 15 years ajo. right...
I see! The.writings tht
we found in the capsules
up to now ware all about Shunyat!
Yeah }
most nobably
Which means that the
remaining time capsule
Are we U-turning back to Kurashiki again?
A flower petal? bhis 1s the pistil.
And this 1s the stem... But... it's scattered .
Oh!! Maybe they're supposed yp
to overlay. one on top thefother?
Could this be
a watet Illy
Right! Water lily in Kurashiki.
I's over there!
Whera?
Over here!
Ohara art gallery?
Water Lily.
Bow ute
So. the capsule Is over here!
\ ETAT (Min { oer
planted here onh reeontl,
NTAORLY
It says. the year 2000 in commemoration
NEAOR&)
It says, theywear 2000 In commemoration
CHE 0 Sat oD Of UI
In other words. the water lily in the code
Is referring to tha drawing
Of an famous artist called Monet
and most probably somewhere near the
mam building whom
that drawing Is exhibited...
talk about spacious
It was so-easy until now, but...
Walk another 25' steps. A
hat's'up?
nether 26 steps that i.
Written .on this codo...
A Ko] IR (oxzheen doo} Wilkes = = =f
I seal It means that in the
place afkteqtqklng 25> more steps
Huhi Huh? Huh?
I found it
Fantastic. A uml
It's;:amazingsthat you figuredsiteout!
Heh, heh, heh
But, how strange
there doesn't.soem to be any writing inside
Just-as I thoughts.
Muh I- What's this?
Something Isstuck to the bottom.
The envelope looks to be differant
from the ones up tm now.
dd -N\ A
T.1Ris Is?!
Well, everyone...
You are all acquaimtand
of that Sleeping Kogoro,
Mr. Kogoro Mouri
MMourl
Kogoro.
I'. That famous...
T.That famous
We just got wordBfrom
Mr. Mouri a while ajo
Lethe Ws Lo gat Ah
details from MI. Ajtlhil.
Telling us to get the
details from Mr. Agasa
Agase
WM ML?
I heamthatiyou ire just, a
good or maybe even better
in makingadeductions than Mr. Mourn.
Who is this Mr. Kogoro?
Just what do you want with us at this point?
MM counting on you. Doc!
Aha ha.
Lhem! Huh, On... well
Here's how It goes... About Mr. Saruwataril.
Wholissthought will be arrested soon...
The fact is. he's innocent.
I he real culprit is. someone else
I kept trying to toll youl!
WwW. What 7! Do you mean
that it Is Mr Onitsurn aftersall-thon 9
You gotta be kidding! I didnat-do it!
Come. come flet me explain things in order
1b years ago . ..you all put
things that were precious; to! you
Inside a time capsule and
exchanged it with each other
You shufflediit and each of you
buried Someone else's capsule
Let me reconfirm something here
Ne Momo hid Salka's capsule
in the KHinomi-Watchtower
Saiko hid Mr. Onilsura's capsule
in tho garden of the Ohashi residonco.
Mr O ilsura hid Mr Saruwatarn,
capsule here In:lvy Square
Mr Sarawatacifhnd, Yae's capsule
or rather a dummy;in Komorizukn,
and the actual,capsule in Kibitsu Shrine
And finally, Mr. Momi's
capsule was hidden by Yae,
you. In the Ohara Art Gallery
Way li Nin Gy edd to Ne of RIREY Ws ay
dug the capsules out
The problom is theuqh,
that every capsule was alnozrxdy
dug over before the members
of the squad got there.
So. like I said, the killer
Just a ted to make it
Iook like somebody broke into school
There, one thing we just
ant seem to understand...
Why was only Mr. Momoi's
capsule missing something In
witting that was ineludaed in
everybody clse's capsule?
Ha, ha, ha, It just didn't appenl
to mo to bury something like that
That's all there 1s to it
NO --=llll"bet It was
actually Inside. You removed It
and got rnd of it. But,
Seiko happened to see you...
Isn't that it, Mr. Momol?!!
WwW. What?!
You...?
INFINRO §
ron] {X82100 WdkekeTu JU
What proof do you have!
Let me explain First I the dying message
The point 1s the
position of the victim's finger.
AY aA
Position of her finger
Seiko, the victim was left handed.
Therefore,
most naturally she would've written
hor dying messago with her right hand.
But. if so, the position of her finger
Is odd. Her finger should've near
the last "I" of the message.
But it was by the first letter...
Neo,
T True.
By the way, left handed peopl:
usually right their letters in reverse
Don't you think the samo goes for this?
That is, viewed from the position
of the finger, it was not written
from left to right but rather,
from right to left backwards
And 1 the part that 1s erased
Is connected with a hneoe
Else
[1 we?
It wasn't "TONIT" but rather.
She tried to write "Momo"!
Exact,!
In other words, "ONI" neither
meant Mr. Onitsura nor Mr. Saruwatarl.,
but was pointing out that
Mr. Momol Is the killer...
1 That's bullshit!
That's all nothing but imagmation!
I oven have an aha!
You wore walking together with Mr. Momo
through the fine sight district, is that right?
You said) you only separated
for 5 minu 8s tO) go to the restroom.
Oh...yes ~
A blind spot, or rather once,
one notices there's nothing to it
but uh, ean you continue
Youth Dctective. Squad?
Od) TRO hay Squire
and tine Sights District
ire actually located back to back.
If you walk on the outside in front,
hay Soom Le Ho Some distance apa
but you walk within the grounds
or the buildings they aro very near!
A round trip takes 1 minute 50 seconds!
A Bund trip takes 1 minute 50 seconds!
He probably mado Seiko
wait here boforehand
Hoe then came to her and
killed her! Then, ran back
N.Naoto?!
N.No! That's a liel
And . after
he killed Seiko, He 'dug
over the capsules in this area
It should've taken him about
an hour
So tho Lime of the
rime would've been.about 14:00.
Wasn't ho out of your, sight for
bout an hour. Yae.,
T. True, ho sind he wanted
to @O check something so
he was go ne te go to
[bookstores and to We Whranyk
You'rd only making assumptions!!
You have no evidence to
support what you're saying at all]!
There is proof... Im your wallet!
Huh?! . . MM. My wallet...
You. the killer. In order to make it look as: if
Mr. Onitsura, the alleged
killer, broke into school,
removed the contents
inside the victim's wallet.
However, since you couldn't
just dispose of it, you put it
Inside your wallet
You still have it with you, don't you?
Tell me will you?!
Just what proof de you
have to say that the money
from Seiko's wallet 1s in my wallet?!
Officer Tsuyama. did you
bring the you know what here?
Oh, es .
The: thang that Mi Moun told
mao about on tho phono,
Officdr Tsuyama'!! Please check
Do you see one bill in there
that has something odd stuck-to it?
Odd...?
IF... This is.
So what about it.
If a bill is «dirty, does
that make nu, Mu, killer?!
Mr. Momoil...
How are you going to explain this...?
Normally at wouldOnly look as if
the stamp of the ticket smeared off
in your wallat there was h
16, other half of he stamp mar
that was found on this
pamphlet of the art gallery.
Seiko probably put the ticket on top of the
pamphlet then put them inside hcr wallet
you left the pamphlet back
_< 5 -
it the site and took only the blll with you.
Thanks to the adnussion stamp, you took
bill that coincidentally "became a pair
It's because that broad Seiko
referred to What happened 15 years ago...
Baocause she started snooping
around nd investigating
what happonod lh years ago
15 years ago... everything [started back then
Momoi, as a boy back then
177?
on this particular day, \
777?
Momoi, iis a boy back then
on this particular day. \
Momol, as agboy back then!
On this particu anda .%
Momol, as a boy back them
on this particular day. »
ifisY
was being forced to shoplift
by bullies, and was seen by Shunya .
Momol
I thought! he was going to squeak on me.
That he'd tell the teacher my parents
That's what I thought.
Boy Momol never spoke of
an one about that incident. But
because of his feeling of guilt,
he impulsively wrote
the truth on the paper and
put it Inside the time capsule...
I was graduating anyway. and
I get to sever ties with those guys too
I thought that we'd never be
digging the capsu es out again anyway
back then...
Threo days ago I got a call from Seiko,
YORI ALES I NC OXS If
going 0 hold an interview
he'd like Lo dig out the
apsules while she's tit...
And. you snuck Into school
just for, that one piece of paper
vYou didn't have to kill her!
All you had to do was throw
that paper away somewhere.
AR on Wee HOO ORO CH OVI WR
Uh, where do you think I am now"
Fuh uh, fun...
You know the capsule that I buried?
When I came to look for it,
it was already dug up
You're the only one who
could've done it. right?
You're the only one who knew that
I was going to dig out the time capsule...
Why'd you do something
Iike this'? Don't tell me that...
I could've written some kind
of scoop article about it...7?
She always used to bluff from before! =g
She just put a leading question to you
I was scared
I felt like . she knew everything
Miss!
Toe 0 Ted IO 0 a Rie = Yo
Yollll =
the station then Mr. Momol.
All NP a
Want!
AMogethor Foie
I'd like to go ll together.
There's a place I really want to go...
You're the one who put this code
inside (hé capsule and burled it. right?
I was asked by Shunya
a while before he died
that he wanted to go with
everybody to bury the capsule...
But, after: the accident I was (oo §
scared to look Inside. and didn't look
hat code 1s an anagram, righty
You, at's epenad in hiragana
thon you lino at up backwards in ordor
Monomokidanon ¢?
Momodanonani~?
Peach Tree Adventure Squad!
That used tobe the name ff our group!
We used] to frequently gathor hero
Yeah, when we had to
wait for each other or even
when we practiced acting out Peach Boy...
His Is...Shunya s
Momoi's Pédach Boy was really cool
Next time I'm going to be
Peach Boy and rescue Momgll
I'm going to make him
stop listening... to those guysi!
But. W31 mt to ba kept
a secret from teacher or
HIS pggents, no matter...no matter what
his parents, nO matter...no matter what .
WL Ref, WO BAR edi) (anti-A NA Re 0
N.NO way
Maybe Shunya ran onto the road
bocause he wanted to help you.
Stop bullying my friend!
If I ohly. ..remembered back then
Kind of know. although I was a child.
That it was no ondlnary tra Tic accldentw;
But, I couldn't say or
do anything... .I'm just as guilty
Your UL UY LOL BI
So. I'm even gulltic
As for ma I didn't {eel 1 hing
As for me I didn't feel a thing
So I'm even gulltie
I...probably looked like an ogre...
The ogre In your hear can ony
be defeated by you yourself alone.
Kugh...Uuuugh...
Kugh ..Uuuugh...
Yes. because ou re Peach Bo...
cinal Comic Books
GCOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MABAHITO ¥ +» OKA
Backcround Music.
KAISUOSONWO
Character Desens By.
MASATOMONUDO O,
Story 'Fditoe
JUNICHI 11(9KA
KANT KASHIWABARA
KAZUNAR! KOU CHI
YUICHI-HIGURE
TOSHIKd INOUE
Animation Dircectobfs...
VV) 49
HIROTOSHI TAKA -1
KAWA
Art Director.
V » » > veo » > 5 PP ~ .
Aft bo 0 Phils many
TAKATIISA AA
Recording Director.
KAISUYOSH mm
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Cel Director Co
HENJI. KID AMA)
Produced By.
TAMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD.
Tr ssa itinn with
YON ILRI TELEGASTING
CORPORATION
130 THC 11\ IGA AN
VT GO TW ETOY SIMAY N11 Go VARA AN YI IV TMS
WERE Tl
Lover's
Lovers
Just come along. come.
All right! Now, you're
m Peach Bo : Conan!
Huh?!
Oh bummers
Then, what about us?!
Genta is the pig! Mlitsuhiko is the water sprite!
VV id "I
I hat's the Songoku
a  He
As for me, I'm as hungry as a bear!
A Kimono I cimale Damon'?
In other words, this is a locked
room closed off by the snow
wonder whatiRan and
the @ hers 150; doing?
The legend of the Kimono Woman Demon.
(m 3:3)
hth Murder in the Hot Spring Inn's 'Part 1
ali Minder in the Lot Spring Inn™ Bart 4