What's happening. at the het spring 'inn?
Is it a ghost or just the
work of some human?
Tho outdoor bath is the
key to this question.
He.sees through the one and only truth
A- child In appearance
with the 17.Q of an adult
No case is left.unsolvned
With Detéctive'Cdna
TA RA
(51%)
The Murder in the Hot Spring Inn Part 1
Yeah My stiff-shoulders.
Are killing me these days...
Our hot springs really
good for stiff shoulders.
Oh: eah?
Excuse me, Mister, is this tonight's desert?
I'm sorry. 'this is
actually, for. the other guest.
I UIR=-X=11) &ANIK=) ID
1 famous writer or something
I see...
Conan! You were gonna ent it. weren't you?
What!?
Welcome, tq Kotoya Hotel.
We've been expecting you
You,must-be:cold-- Nowsplease come in.
MA IR OC x = 20 in RO.
U's 2 Dig garden (00...
Hey! Isn't that Eri Akechi,
Te love romance writer?...
EXILES
Ouch! Ohm .
What the
Oh...
Excuse me. sir. Sorry if I'm wrong...
But are you the famous
detective, Kogoro Mouri?
NM. Mouri ?
You are Mr. Mouri, right!?
Yos... That's me...
Oh Un = Oe 6
Oh my goodness...
I never expected to see a famous
person like you in a place like this.
WY; edn) {he's [1 folk nll [Seek
Im a producer at Nichiuni TV... yes
Oh, alright.
Well. why don't we sit and talk...
Now tell me. what kind of meeting is this?
Actually, we are planning
to make a TV series drama
together with Dwigakukan
Publishing and us Nichiuri TV. So
Pane Ot AW If
over there. to write the story
The story is about three young women
trying to make their dream come true.
So, we've been interviewing
women in different careers.
And this time, I asked
Yoriko to get some people
from her university. Now. here theyare -
Asuka Shibasaki, a model
She's becoming pretty famous
in Paris and the New York fashion scene.
Hello...
Wow! Beautiful!
Now, this is Ema Anzai She's an oil painter
and the winner of the new fate award.
Nice to meet you!
Yeah! @harming!
And, this girl is now causing
a bit of stir in the music industry...
The singer songwriter.
Ms Harumi Fukatsu right?
I'm a great fan of yours!
Ah... Thank you
Well, somebody's getting pretty famous
even though she has only one hit song.
It's not gonna last long...
You know, there are many
one-hit wonders out there.
Well! Very interesting!
You've all got unique characteristics
and are also beautiful
Y. yeah...
His way! ploase
Wow.
Here's a kimono too "4
Can I ask you something?
How come kimonos
are hanging on the wall?
I saw It everywhére in this hotel.
People worship the Spirit of
Kimono as a guardian deit .
You can see those not only In this hotel,
but also in ordinary+houses and homes.
It's custom
flame,
I see
the Spirit of Kimono...
I'm so«exeited "bout
your new stuff. Ms. Akechi
Oh no. call me Eri. please.
Actually
Mysmom: hasathelsame name.
So It feels kinda weird calling you Eri...
The kanji is different though.
Wall, but if you call me pMs. Akech, 6
it sounds like I'm a detective...
It feels weird...
I heardspeople here wr
the Spirit of Kimono. am I right?
Yes This "Spirit of Kimono" 1s
a guardian deity but also has
a dark side of face. People
call it "Kimono Demon".
Kimono Demon...
It's-an old folkloregtold
In this village...On%e upon a time.
There was a young woman,
named Ohana. in this village.
She was a kind, hardworking woman.
One da , Ohana found a samurai,
who broke hissleg. She helped him
As a token of gratitude for her help.
The samurai gave Ohana tons
of beautiful kimonos and sashes.
Being envious of Ghana's' fortune.
The village mayor's daughters
made a false charge against her
Ohana was arrested and
the daughters took her kimonos.
That night. Ghana-was executed
The daughters en oyed
the beauty of the kimonos
All of a sudden,
the lights went out, and
Aghhhhhhh!!
Hearing the scream,
the householders came. but...
what they found were the dead bodies of
the younger daughter lying on the kimonos
and the body of the older one
tangled with many sashes in a pond
Realizing the graveness:of Ohanass grudge,
The villagers built a small shrine and
worshipped her as a
guardian deity of the village.
Ever since then, people in this*area have
worshipped Ohana as
the "Spirit-of Kimono"
20) En RB Wn,
Great -Shrine of the Kimono Spint.
You must've studied this place a lot.
No, I ust sta in this hotel
a lot when I write. That's all...
7 et eet Bl?
You're right. Harumi!
This tree, is called "Kimono Sakura".
It's about 500 years old.
When spring comes, those branches
will be 'covered with flowers.
It looks just'like a beautiful kimono.
So, Harumi, do you know
about this place a lot too?
Ah. no!
( My friend in university
Ioved this cherry blossom.
She told me about this before.
It crossed my mind,
So I came here to sea at.
Hey, Ran
WIR {Re =) Xi
PF ow TIES
Hmm?
Hey kid! Don't run around...
That's actually the shrine for "Kimono visit"
Kimono Visit"???
The Spirit of Kimono is
also a deity of vengeance.
V. vengeance!
It's boen sid that if you wear 1 kimono
and visit this small shrine at midnight.
The Spirit of Kimono
will take revenge for you...
And in dedication of the Kimono visit,
people leave a paper doll in this shrine.
Look! There re new ones!
Thee are a couple of them...
WwW. what!!
So somebod came here
recently for Kimono visit!?
That means there're two people
that this visitor wants to take revenge on...
Forget about it. It's just a prank...
Don't worry about it...Ran.
Yeah...
Hey...Isn't that a shrine too?
Po :d
Oh, (aomu on. it"s. just u guest run-nu!
Actually, it's a shrine
of the Spirit of Kimono too...
Oh, please don't tell me
there're paper dolls in it too!
No way, it can't be
Heheh...Heh
But something's bugging me...
Lease, Dad. Go and check it...
What!? Me...?
I don't understand... Why she's so scared.
There're no paper dolls here...
Right see?
Right...
Here's nothing?
Good! Thanks!
Wow!
It's amazing!
It just looks like the one
On RET ta ley, OE We
Yeah
This Is paradise...
Oh m godly
It's beautiful!
Chee 8)!
NCRaers!iii
IlfGrfiiensllll
Cheers!
, Everyone, thank you so much for
your cooperation with our 4-day interview.
Yb 45
Eri. make my modal character
stand out in your drama. will you?
Well, I still don't know what
kind of stor it's gonna be so...
Yeah. so I'm giving you ideas right now!
Mr Bando
How about if Harumi sings
the opening theme of the drama! ?
What!?
Yeah! That's a good idea!
Harumi. could you do that?
Only if she's around until then though...
No way
It's good. isn't it?
Yeah!
Oh my!...This bottle is empty It's strange!
Yeah, right!
Ran?... Another bottle
Alright! OK...... ok. so oneriirst bottle... yes?
It'll be the last one
No!!
Oh no--! Conan. it's not fairl...
Ah excuse me?
Yes Come in...
<Q AY
'$1 FAQ;
Oh! Hi, Harumi!
Ah, there's something I would
Iike to discuss with Mr. Mouri...
OD. Dad!
Yeas!
Dad!!
Discuss I?
It wns five years 1ge
I was in third year in college.
There was this illegal drug that
a lot of students on campus were using.
Somehow, people started to suspect
a female student as the drug dealer
Although she denied the fact that she was
the drug dealer, the drugs
were!found in her locker.
Wr ry Tw Yn Pane dB1L-BL
Shekilled herself by jumping:off-the
universitygbuilding,
saying.she was innocent...
That person's name is...Sakurako Suzuka I
I told you about her
under the Kimono Sakura
he was a very kind person
who loved cherry blossoms.
There's no way thatsshe was \
selling the drugs It just:.can't be hen
So. please. Mr Mourn! Could you
re-investigate this case again!? Please!?
Hmm, this was five yearns ago though...
Actually there was a
rumor that the drug dealers
were some other female students.
What?
But those students were from,
a family who had a lot of authority
So, no one could go against them...
Them?
The are Asuka Shibasaki and Ema Anzai.
Asuka is a-daughter:of
a parliamentary deputy.
And Em is a daughter of the major
construction firm. Anzai Global
Those two girls didn't get
along with Sakurako too well.
Because of her strong sense of justice
Hmmm.
Alright! I'll see what I can do. ok?.
Oh. thank you so much!
You must like her a lot.
I lost my parents when I was young.
My uncle and aunt raised me
Sakurako also lost her parents by fire,
and so she was very kind to me.
Oh! You guys arc going toe the bath now?
Yeah. You're done already. Ms. Akechi?
Yes llgot a little cold. so...
Then,
why don't we have some drink together!?
I'm sorry...l got some work to do...
Ok, later!
What the... It's reserved...
You're right...
It's locked... Oh well, what can we do?
It's only 30 more minutes.
Why don't we, go upstairs and
play some ping pong?
Alright
Alright.
Somebody's going pretty wild over there...
row up: Ran
Here we go! Yah!
-- Pall
Yes! Hal
You guys already got out?
No actually... we haven't even got in.yet.
It was reserved...
Hey, you're wearing glasses
Yeah, I wear contact lenses usually.
Just took them off for the outdoor bath
It's past 11: 30 now...
The bath should be open by now...
Yes. Lets go.
Hmm! ..Where are you guys going?
To the female bathroom!
WwW what!
Oh...8W I reserved. .
It is locked...
Hm? WI at is this?
Oh, there was nothing,
When we car re here last: time
Ply Q
It's weird. This thing Is kinda cold...
It's weird. This thing is kinda cold
Oh god!
What is this!
What's the matter!
Kimono demon...
De N\
J-QC
JUUIP
IJI'\
- a CD
JE 3 ES
CI -$
10 -or
Je \*
TOD =~
Jo or
Can anybody remove this door!?
Ck Let me do It!
Move, Ran!
Huh!
Oh. no
Oh. oh-oh-oh...
Ugh.
ugh...
Oh. oh-oh-oh...
Oh.-oh-oh-oh
Ouch]
Dad!
Man... This just got me really sober...
Conan! Is anybody there?
Yes...butlin fact...
Asukal
Asuka!
Huh!
Asuka! Are you alright!
God...She's stabbed in he chest...
The folklore of the Kimono Demon...
Oh no...
Hey. Conan! Where are you going!? .
In the folklore. two sisters are Killed...
Oh. hi. What's going on?...
Asu a is.
Ron 3.
Asuka Is...
s~ JD?
What's the matter?
In the outdoor bath
Asuka was found dead...
Actually. it was a murder
ARR OWE @
CITY J!
Where ls Emg! ?...
on. Ema. I think she went over (here.
about an hour:ago...
Are those the footprints of Emma's boots?
Is she Inthere?
Please!lDon't step on the footprints!
Yeah, I know that)!
Did you forget that I'm a detective!?
So it is the Kimono demon...
She's stabbed in her chest too...
Outside, only Ema's footprints
and nothing else was found
In other words, this place was closed
and sealed off by the snow...
Excuse me: siri
I suppose you're Detective Mouri
Yes, I am)!
I am Ogura,
the police officer of this village!
Did you contact
the prefectural police department?
Yes I did. sir!
But the road condition is not good
because of the snow
So I suppose they won't be here
until tomorrow morning
Tomorrow morning
Tomorrow morning.
Alright. .1 guess wé have to do the on-site
investigation on our own, then...
9 < ol
Ah, Miss? Could you bring/me
some bath towels. please
Ah, Miss? Could you bring{me
Sure!
Please. wait in the hall.
Do it slowly, Mr. Ogura
Yeah, there Cover those footprints
Yes. slowly
This pass under the eaves
Ieads to the back door
Yet: there are no footprints whatsoever...
Hmm? Walt a minute
What is it?
Something's wrong
Hey. don't move it!
I don't want the footprints
to be covered with snow!
Oh. there ou are
Sorry, we decided to sit rather than sting
It's was Eri's idea.
Did ou find an thing?
Ell.
Yoriko. You said Ema passed this lobby
around 10:30.
Yes I did...
Did you see anybody else
No I didn't .
Oh. now it's getting more complicated...
What do you mean by that!?
First of all, around the shrine,
where Ema was murdered.
There were no footprints found.
Other than hers.
So...Ema killed herself!?
I don't think so...
There were no weapons found in there...
And 'secondly in order to go to the
outdoor 'bath. where Asuka was murdered
you have tto go through the recreation hall. *
We were there after 10:30,
but didn't see an bod passing through...
What about climbing the cliff and
going to the outdoor bath
I already checked it. There were no
suspicious traces found on the cliff.
Then, Asuka was murdered before 10:307
We found a dagger and
a stungun in the bathtub.
Perhaps, the murderer attacked Asuka
with the stungun first,
then killed her in the outdoor bath.
The«dagger in fact had a nacre
decoration in its hilt
I asked the-proprietress about it
and she said it was the votive dagger .
Dedicated to the shrine in the garden .
The votive dagger?
ANd @gne more thing Emma's bandana was
also found in the outdoor bath.
There was blood on that bandana
I don't get it...
Blood... So what?...
Assuming thatbot Victims) were murdered
with the same dagger
it's plausible to think that
Ema was killed before Asuka was
Furthermore ..Ema waOalive « htil 10:30.
So theoretically,
Asuka was killed after 10:30. db
How did the murderer
get into the outdoor bath though?
There were no traces whatsoever,
in the shrine of the garden too. right?
Give me a break. You gotta be a ghost or
something to do that.
It's the curse...
It's the curse of the Kimono Demon.
Oh, please!
- 4 pr -
You know what I saw!?
I saw a couple of new paper dolls
dedicated to the shrine!
The Kimono Demon's curse
killed Asuka and Ema!
No...It can't be...
A curse: did not kill*the girls. It's obvious.
But what was the trick that
the murderer used!?
Original Comic Bool By
005110 AOYAMA
froduccrs...
MASKSAHITO VY - + 1 OK
Backeround Music.
$31300 J1!) .
Character Designs By.
WAN ob NT Dg OD S10 JC
Story Editor,
JUNICHI I. 1 KA
KANJI KASHIWABARA
I HI MI
YUICHIQHIGURF
oN LN ENE =
Animation 1 rectors.
ar 'Yat BO 2:\%
Jai:
AKI@O KAWAMURA
INCS sd fC FF
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Dircctors Of Photooraphy.
Yh nid)
TAKAR13A
KATSUYOSQ-ll [JAVA
Editor.
IT Uv YW WRAATIA
CMe Director.
KENJI. KODAMA)
Produced By
ERTAINME
fT ssociafipn with
IURI TELEGASTING.
CORPORATION™
¢ GOSHEOAOYIMAT SHOU YRUA VA Y IV IMS
WR TT ved
It's the "Kimono visit"!
It was Sakurako who revenged herself
onlthcse girls with the Kimono visit"!
Oh m god!
Now I see. .
It mustdbe. I know Sakurako wanted to.
Oh no!
My socks aro soaked. Conan
Hey. Ran! Wait.
The Murdersin the Hot Spring. Inn (Part 11)"