Hich genils made this trick?
So complicated and calculated like an art
Find the answer In the snow
He sees through the one and only; truth
A child in appearance
with the I. Q. of an adult
No case\is left
unsolved withDotective 'Conan
(152 #7)
The Murder in the Hot Spring Inn (Part 2)
(152 #3)
Asuka went to the
outdoor bath around 10 pm.
And Ema went to tho shrino
In the garden around 10:30 pm.
These two victims were killed
with the votive dagger.
As this murder weapon was
found mm the outdoor hath
It is plausible to
think that Ema was killed first
Plus, there were no footprints
yutside the shrine in the garden
And also, one must pass thevrecreation hall
in order to get to the outdoor bath,
but nobody was. seen
passing there after 10:30.
Oh my... So these killings were
done in the inaccessib e spaces
It was Sakurako's revenge
with Kimono Visit!
Sakurako!? Who Is that person!?
She's my university friend,
who committed suicide
Fukatsu Harumi
Singer/Songwriter
WR ED (25)
Y= TRA Pm
because they framed her up
or selling illegal drugs
Fukatsu Harumi
Singer/Songwriter
RR ED (25)
YI= 2984S
because they framed her up
for selling illegal drugs...
Ou mean Asuka and Ema did it?
Pa Yes! So. twas. twas her revenge...
Lieutenant Masaki
Hmm? Oh yeah...
In the shrine, we found one of the earrings
of the victim missing
Here... This is the one
Oh, that's an expensive one...
That earring probably costs
at least two thousand dollars
Yasuda Yoriko
Publishing Company/ZEdttioriai Stuff
(EB MF (37)
Als Le 7
ABBEY ERR
Four thousand as a pair!?
It's expensive,
yet not enough for motive to kill.
True
I remember, Harumi, you were wearing
a necklace of the same brand. weren't you?
Yeah... But took them off
because Ema complained about it
Oh yes...We found this in Ema"s.jacket.
We also found that the kimonos and
the sashes at he homicide scenes
actually came from the .loset,
which was not locked at all.
So anybody could take them out.
Perhaps the murderer must
have hidden them somewhere beforehand.
Ok everyone Could I ask you
what you were doing last night. please?
Now. ex...
You went to the outdoor bath around 9.
And came out around 10:00
Akechi Eri
Love Story Writer
You went to the outdoor bath around 9.
And came out around 10:00 .
Akechi En
Love Stony Writer
AA GR WX IR (34)
NABL LADY UM
ZR BR
And Asuka just came in as you left,
Ty ',
Right. After that. I went back to my room.
Oh yeah, I saw Mr. Mouri on the way and
we had a little chat.
Ah. eah...
We did ..Actually you looked great and...
And Yoriko: You were working on
some stuff on the coverage.
So I suppose you saw Eri...
Yes I did. I saw Eri.
And after five minutes or so...
I saw Ema going to the backdoor.
So that was around 10:30. right?
Did you see anybody else heading there?
No... I don't think so
yo =D J
CON 31 SO
Around that time, Mr. Mouri and
the other three went to the .outdoor bath.
But there was a reserved sign-on. the door
of the female bathroom.
The door was locked. so you,
Ran and Harumi went/back
to the? recreation room
That's right.
Mr. Mouri.
Did you hear or see something unusual
when you were In outdoor bath?
We did...
We heard a swash
from the female bathroom.
When was it? Around what time?
I {Fink it was around 10e50.
Maybe that was when the killing occurred
We only heard the swash.
We didn't. hear a scream.
Isn't it strange?
Oh...
Well.
Maybe the murderer stunned the victim
with the stungun before she screamed
It could be...
Yeah! It must be!
Kid. keep out of the investigation...
So. Ran and Harumi, you girls were just
playing ping pong in the recreation hall?
No. I actually went back to my room,
for 10 minutesyor SO...
Just to take off my contact lenses
Alright
So nobodyfpassed through
the recreation hall while Harumi was away
Right...
It was around 11 o'clock when
Mr Mouri got out of the bath.
Around that time, Eri and Yoriko
were having a meeting here...
Oh, ..Where were you at that time,
Mr. Bando?
I joined the meeting around 11:15.
Hmm. And then, Mr. Mouri found
Asuka's dead body In the outdoor bath...
Speaking) of the paper doll of
Kimono Demon.
Wasn't it there when
ou first came to the bathroom?
No... I'm sure it wasn't
after Asuka was found, Ema was found
dead In rm. shrine in the garden.
Why did she go to the shrine?
That's 2 good qQuUoOostion.
Omin Es As
pea BUT
as bo
EEO TIT >
Here's the answer.
NM wit
- »»Y
om 107
nRATH 2
To Ema: There's something I would like to
discuss with you in person
To Ema: Theres something I wouldslike to
discuss with you in person.
I will be waiting Inside the shrine
in the garden Bando
This is ridiculous! I did not write that let I!
Wt in fact. we don't know where
you really were until 1115
Yeah, but what's the motive?
Why would I kill them!?
Hmm... speaking of motive,
I think Harumi is the only person who
might have had the motive to kill.
Noll... I don-t
I know you hate the victims because of
whatihappencd to your friend Sakurako.
Plus,
NWO LRAWO BED SC KEt@RY.O Ul TENOO
to take off your contact lenses
During that period. you don't have an alibi
No...I didn t kill them!
Whoever is the murderer,
we have to find out
how these killings happened
In the closed space first.
If the victims were killed
with different weapons.
A«possibility of what
could've happened: still stands.
But why did the murderer make it look like
the Kimono Demon did it in the first place
csmlmnanksla mu
We got it!
Oh. ou mean the necrops report?
Yes. Both victims were killed with the
same murder weapon. the votive dagger.
I see...
The same murder weapon, huh?
Now we are stuck...
Oh. Now I know...
What?
The bloodstain on the bandana was
found 10 be Emma's blood.
Other the that. we could 'Foot find anything
that's related to the suspect from the items
at the murder scenes
185 INC UCe ee paper co s
and the mcmo found in Ema's jacket
Alright. Thank you very much
You're welcome, sir
I will now depart.
Now what are we gonna do. Mr. Mouri?
Hmm...Nothing is found Eh? .
Next. yesterday, we were
at the Kid Sleighing Contest...
Hey. move! Move!
Huhuh, looks like) fun
Hm? What?
Itss the kids... The kids on the TV.
Come on! Move!
I got it...
That's what it was.
Now I got the trick!
It's about 6 inches hora...
And here it's about...
3 inches under the snow...
6 inches and"3 inches... but why her?
0 Nel An 10 Q QQ 0.
Ah well.
I just went out for a walk #)
Iok 0 Hajime?
Oh its Mr B: ndo .
Wait a minute...Maybe that persen is...1?
Wow Conan! Your socks are soaked!
Why don't we take it
to the fireplace and dry them?
Ah. Ran!? Wait...
Now I know who did it...
It must be that person?
But...why?...
We have to figure out how and
when the paper doll was put here
If we suspect that person as the murderer
Hm? What is this? §
Oh, there was nothing there
when we came here.last time
It's weird. This thing is kinda cold...
- 42°
Ok. now I see
als this Takagil? It's me. Mouri
Actually I want yoy to do
some research on 1 person
Can you do-that?
Oh, Mr. Ogura!
2 a. <>
There's something Uncle Kogoro
wants you to do...
What? Mr. Mouril said it?
If I'am right, then that person
musttbe the murderer.
Mr. Mouri, you told us to come here
Now what is it?
Of course. We are going to find out what
really happened in this hotel.
So you know who killed the victims?
Who is it! Toll me!
Ok, let me explain in the order of
what happened. Now first,
it's about Ema. who was killed in the
closed shrine in the garden.
Lieu enant Masaki
could you please turn gn the digital camera,
that's on the tub.
IN Eex=iy Willie) OFOQuR H0 DIAuO
of the footprints around the shrine
because there was something
that kept bugging me.
And this morning,
I finally figured out what it was.
So... what's wrong with this picture?
The footprints are not deep enough.
What?
Yesterday afternoon.
When I walked around the shrine
In the garden,
my feet sank down
about 3 inches in the snow
about 3 inches in the snow.
It kept snowing the rest of the day.
Ute, [on €No Bao Wo oR {0
the shrine around 10:30 pm,
Emma's footprints should have been
IL least 6 inches deep or so
However, It was about in fact only:4 inches.
It was too shallow
I see. but then, why?
Those footprints were pressed from the top
Pressed!? From the top?
Es."indeed.
Her footprints wee found
from the backdoor to the shrine
Ogura nd I covered every single
one of them with bath towels
in order to preserve them.
But what if those bath towels were
solid boards or something?
You could walkson it and
move around the shrine
without leaving footprints, right?
It's that simple?
Hmmmm .
It seems that the tricks are always
complicated. but actually they're really not.
Perhaps, The murderer's got a couple of
wooden boards w ich are about 3 feet long
and moved around putting those boards on
top of Emma's footprints one after the other.
After killing Ema this murderer went back
to the backdoor doing the same thing
This way, the footprints are maintained
as It was before
Except they get bit shallower.
But how did the killer
get to the backdoor. Mr Mourn?
Yeah! Nobody passed the lobby. right?
The killer walkedrunder theveaves
doing the same.thing...
NS ts SAW NVA NS NOINSRNO
witnesses or.footprints.
This morning,
I checked the pass around the backdoor.
Onithe right side of the pass, the:snow was
about 6 inches deep. but on the ether hand.
The left side was only 3 inches deep.
Meaning that the killer came from a room
along the left side of the pass.» »
Soul checked the leftiside of the pass
and-found a-place where
the snow gots deeper again.
WwW. where. .is it?
Yes...It was right in front of your room!
What!
No way...
Cr did it?
Last night, Er left the outdoor bath as soon
Asuka came in. and went back to her room.
And thengyou went Up
to the shrine from the*backdoor.
Using the tricks I just explained.
You gave Ema a fake letter
from Mr. Bando beforehand.
So she'd come to the shrine,
then you killed her.
Sure That way, I could kill Ema
But it's impossible to kil Asuka. isn't it?
That:s true You cant use the same tnok
in the outdoor bath on the cliff.
Plus. nobody passed the recreation hall
Well, the triith is,
it was Asuka who was actually killed first!
What!
Eri stunned Asuka with a $ ungun
She removed Asuka's clothes,
and killed her with the votive dagger.
Then threw the dead body in the bathtub
with kimono 'sashes.
She probably stole
the dagger the night before.
It doesn't make sense though, because
Asuka was murdered first yet the dagger
and Emma's bandana were found
in the outdoor bath.
That's right. That paper doll thing is too.
Oh. that was a trick using dry ice.
By using a small piece of dry ice
Eri~glued the-paper doll
onto the crack"of the ceiling.
If you know how long it lasts,
its possible to drop the paper doll
whenever-you want to.
That's why thefpaper doll was<kinda cold.
Rn asked the general manager.
to get her a cake everyday, Y
because she'wanted the dryiice,in:it.
I understand the dry ce trick.
But what about the dagger and bandanai?
I didn't come to the bathroom
Well, it's possible to move them
without coming here
Let me show you how Row
Yes Sir.
My god...
These boards came downafromsEri's room,
whic Bis on.the cliff rightwp there.
Now I want you guys to think about the...
The votive dagger, which was
used to kill Ema.
And the bandana'with her blood on it...
This way, you can move these things
without leaving the room
Perhaps, Mr. Mouri heard the swashy sound
When the boards got into the water.
That's right Using this trick,
Eri tried to disguise the order of the murder.
In order to establish her alibi.
OK, but the question is,
where did the boards go?
Aah /
Here it is. Mr. Mouri!
WER (9 (re (0
Oh, these were the sashes left inithe closet
They are froze ¥hard though.
Sash becomes like this if you soa
and leave it outside for a night.
Es. She used this frozen sash to hide
her footprints in the snow!
I see. When they are put in the water
they just turn into normal sashes...
It would look odd if t ere were just a dead
body and a couple of sashes in the water...
Thus,
she put some more sashes into the water,
and spread tons of kimono in the shrine.
That way the scene of murder looks
more like tho folKlere of Kimono Demon.
wumac ua y pm 0s we secre o \e no .
That's 'a: very clever deduction but...
Where Is tho evidence ?
Show me thetsole of your fool.
Show me. would you?
Please. Er
Alright
I think I stepped on a nail or something.
I don't think so
You actually stepped on Ema's earring
which actually dropped
in the middle of the fight
Last night, I told you guys to wait In the hall
while we did some on-site investigation.
However, En said it was better to
sit on a chair rather than on the floor
SO you guys moved to the lobby
thts becuse your foot was bleeding
wasn't it?
I a0 oY,
you have to take: off your slippers.
But you didn't wanna do it
Do you have evidence that this
a wound I got from the earring?
I found the missing earring!
Here!
Conan!
This brand name earring is
worth 200.000 yen a piece.
Nice! If her blood is on it,
it will serve as evidence!
It's amazing that you found it...
Actually +. This Is a pendant.
I borrowed from Harumi.
AA RL
Ok. :I-give up.
I killed Asuka and Ema...
Why did you do such a horrible thing. Eril?
Her name is not Eri It's actually Chieri.
She's been hiding her real name.
Your last natmo. "Ake" is a-very.rare-name
So people think your real name
Is Akechi Eri. rathersthan Ake Chieri.
I asked my friend at the Metropolitan
Pol ¢e to do some research on you.
Chic you are the real
sister o Sakurako Suzuka
who killed herself five years ago. right?
What! Eri and Sakurako are sis ers!?
Iad of, 4
As you sisters lost your parents in a fire
Sakurako was adopted
by Mr. and Mrs. Suzuka.
Ok, I:ll tell you the rest...
When my younger sister,
Sakurako, died. I was in Boston.
Trying to become a famous wri er.
Soil £28 acliualiiy Ay earlier wir n
I heard that she Killed herself
She was a very naive girl. And because
somebody framed her up selling:drugs
she had to kill herself...Poor Sakurako...
How come she didn't tell me about it?
I'm her sister.
I'm the only family for her in this world...
What Asuka and Ema did to my sister
was totally unforgivable...
So one day, I came up
with the idea of revenge
I asked my university friend
Yoriko to invite Asuka and Ema
to this hotel for coverage
of a new TV series.!.
It was a perfect opportunity to take revenge
disguised by the folklore
of the Kimono Demon.
Ok, but do you think
Sak 'Take-is. happy about It?
There was;:a person among
the three interviewees that
your sister actually trusted
from the bottom of her heart.
It was Harumi Fukatsu. If she wasn't here
I wouldn't have known
about your sister's death.
And therefore, would not have
suspected you as the murderer.
To me, it just feels like it was
Sakurako's will that you two met.
By meeting Harumi. it's most likely that
she hgped that you'd
stop committing the crime. /
Harumi...
Maybe you were possessed
b the Kimono Demon. dunno.
[up (Mam exp 2) Qa OO Pan's
what your sister wants!
Original Gomic Bool:s By » ¥
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
STII IKE
MASAHIIO Y + ~ PKA
Backoround Music.
CNIS )) nl)
Character, Jesions By.
UIAIAL IN] D DY JC
Story Editor,
JUNICHI 111 KA
KAN]? ICASHIWABARA
YUICHI-HICURE
TOSHIKd INOUE
Atris 12160 Directors.
Isl DD
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO'SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photooraphy
TAKASHI NOMURA
Le" 2% JIC
Recording Direclo
KATSUYOSHI. KG BAYAS HI
Editor.
TERUMITSL/ (on/rm
wk leaet
KENJLKODAMA)
Produccd By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, LID.
In ssociyhion with
YOMIURI TELE ASTING
CORPORATION
1350 THC 1101 ~GOOA IAN
CGOVIHIEAOY MY AHO WURAN YIN TMS
All Ri%hyi heseravedl!
Hm?... Mmmmmm...
What the... Why the heck... am I here... 1?
Oh... This isn't good
Oh... This isn't good.
Oh not
Oh well#'Relax:and enjoy your
Iuxury moment in the hot spring
Hahaha...
How!
Maybe they just forgot the
combination of the safe.
Sea?
The president actually
Ieft a dying message here.
The door of the safe is
Left wide open...
Then, we should work on the
four staff who found the opened safe
What do youzmeanw?
Well... Sleeping Kogoro
always stands up for the weak .
TherDeduction.-Battle (Party