The truth lies in the building blocks
But who will find It first
Is it Heljior Sleeping Kogoro?«
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I. Q. of an adult
No case Istleftwursolved
with Detective Conan
d 7 LZ XY
Here's your Detective Samonji. File. 44!
Testament With the Devil's rap. Part ll!
4 yy,
Testament With the Devil's Trap. Part (1!
What the...
Oh god. .Oh god...
I knew you wantediit so;had
so I 'kept one:for, you.
Really!?
RranQyQu. so much. sir!
Oh yoah!
E@ been walling this for so long
Oh eah!
1 I" O been waiting this for so long.
Alright! I gottaieat supper real quick...
Sol can finish the book
before going to bed!
And-tomorrow morning,
I'm gonna read it all over again!
Oh: Iican't wait!
I justican't wait!
Ii back!
Welcome home!
Hmm!?
What!
DA RA
(81%)
RA RA
(BJ)
Deduction Battle! (Part I)"
RA RA
15),
welcome home!
Alrighty! The kid is back.
Lets go out and eat
at a fanc restaurant? right!?
Sure. It's kinda early
so I guess-we could go
a little farther than usual.
Hey: kid. how about it?
What.do you wanna eat?
I pass!
Pass?
Pasta?
H!... You mean Italian foo
Hmm!?
Oh I remember! I heard there's a
new fancy (taliap restaurant in Haido Town!
Alnght, then let's go there!
Yeah. It's not so far from here too...
Phew!
Man, that was got
It's nice to have real«spaghetti
once in a while
Yeah! We made the right choice: didn't we?
Yes lultewas fantastic!
So...why are) ou guys here. @zuha and...
Is AnnYnnte 000
You...son of a...
What the! Hey! What was that!
What the heck was that!?
Well. you came here without telling me
an thing beforehand
I mean you know. I've got a schedule too! /
Oh yeah, speaking of schedule,
that's the reason why we came here!
We wanted to ask you about your schedule!
Schedule?
Ycah! We want you guys
to come to Osaka again.
There are many nice places that
we haven't shown you yet.
What do~you mean by nice places?
O course!
It's the symbol of Osaka!
Koshien Stadium!
Takarazuka Revue!
Koshien St dium?
Takarazuka Rev e?
Heheh... These are not in Osaka. people...
Hey. what's this about Koshien 'Stadium!
We didn't talk about
Takarazuka Revue either!
Noha,
God. have you forgot already!?
I toldyyou I was gonna get the tickets to the
Takarazuka Revue from my neighbors!
Oh yeah
I remember you said something like that .
Alright, then why don't we go to both?
It's*the final game of the
high school baseball tournament
that's really wanna watch
with you guys. $60...
Oh no!
That's No good... We cant go to both...
Kazuha, what's wrong?
Hey, don't tell me you got the tickets
from the five crazy ladies
did. qm
Who are thosetladies:. am
They are enthusiasticsfans of *
Takarazuka Revue.
They save their money throughout the.year
and spend all of it for the
Takarazuka shows during summer time.
I heard they go to every single show,
but there is one show that
they all~¢annot go to .
And:... That's the day of...
Tho final game of the
high school baseball tournament!?
Those ladies are working
for the same company,
and their boss is @ huge fan of
high school baseball
O every year. a le wor ers go anc
watch the final game of the tournament.
And that's why I gottthe Tilakarazuka tickets
for the show playing
on the same day*as«<the final game
Iusee--Sorit doosnd matter whether the final
gets postponed te another da or not.
It's still.gonna.be the same day
as the final game anyway
\. Well, I feel sorry for you: Kazuha...
But I think you should forget it this time
What?
Takarazuka Revue playsathe
samesshow many times a year.
But the final game of the highsschool
baseball tournament is just once
and that's It I can't miss It
What are you talking about!
wmThose baseball games are « n the
sports news and stuff
You can watch them many times!
What are you. stupid!?
You gotta wateh it live!
Whosin the world\likes to watch
only the result of the games on TV!?
But I have to watch the
Takarazulgg show live too!
They are amazing.seats?
You'll never get seats like these again
If you miss this opportunity.
Hey. Ran! You wanna watch the
Takarazuka show, right?
Y yeah
Hey kid
You're a man You love baseball, night?
O. of course... Haha...
Ok. then what about you, Mr. Mouri?
Let mesa
Well, I love the seriousness and
excitement of baseball games!
But at the same time,
I love the beauty and gorgeousness
ff the Takarazuka shows too...
Make up your mind!
Wow .Ok, how about this?
Whoever wins a deduction battle
gets to see what he or she wants...
Deduction...
Battle!?
At the end of last month, there was
a murcerin ye 0 Ice 0 a.company.
O#This murder case need
sfurther investigation
Oune SOAR Or 1URS Roe
iskoed mo for help -onat
That company is actually in this area...
and+I was thinking about
going there after dinner...
Although it's unethical to treat
a murder case like this.
I thought you guys
could come and help us.
Well ites Not so bad because we are
helping to solve the murder case. right?
Alright so Kazuha,
you and I are going to, fight!
That's not fair! There's no way
I'can beat you in a « eduction battle!
Definitely, I. the Sleeping Kogoro,
will be on \. our side. Kazuha.
You can rely on me .
Yeah!? Scriously?
Thanks 3101'. man!
Oh, well
Sleeping Kogoroe is always for the weak...
I know what's raally in your mind, old mar
Ranmlineed=your help, please?™
Sure! Why not! Let's beat them and
watchathe Takarazuka show! ¥&
You dummy rat.
You got two peoplé on your side.
Oh well, what can I say?
I guessOI*have to take this little kid with me!
Haha...You are the dummy rat, Hell...
Hey. Mouri...
Thanks for coming.
No: problem
Let's go inside. hmm?
Hi there...
H. Helji?
Ah, hey you.
You're not allowed at the murder scene...
Now...
the forensic officers are done
searching the murder scene; right?
Well. yeah...
The victim 18 the owner of a
toy production company,
Kenji Tsujiya. 53 year old
He worked and also lived here
The estimated time of death was the
29th of last month, Sunday. around 5 pm.
The dead body was found on the
30th. Monday. around 10 am...
Who found it?
Four workers in this company found it
Four workers...
These four workers always come a
Iittle early in the morning.'and
eat breakfast in a coffeehouse down there,
then come to the office together...
I see. That's why it's four people .
- OK, and these four workers
found their boss.
Who was tied with a rope and
beaten-to death with a golf.club.
How.do you know. Helji?
You see the ink spot
around the victim's back?
Yeah.
Perhaps, the ink spilled over
when they were fighting...
But the murderer\didn'tscare and
just tied the owner up with a rope.
I saw the marks of the rope
all over the floor
So I thought he was wriggling on the floor
with his hands tied behind him.
Ok, but what about him being beaten
with a golf club
Ae, [one AE Xs =Aoxonrge Got [ox=ilinge) [ox=r=§g=1m
with a golf club?
I saw the blood on his had
Andralso, see the thin marks
on-the floor near his head?
These are from iron clubs
T Yo m rderer missod
the head and hit the floor
when he or.she was beating the owner
who was lying on the floor.
But why did the murderer tied him up first,
andfthen clubbed him?
I think the murderer wanted to get the
combination to the safe... .Look!
You see the safe over there?
It's left open...
I see...
Some outsider committed the murder
for the money. is that it?
\ "don't know whether
it was an outsider or not...
But it's certain that the.murderer
tied the president up first
And THEN
the murderer clubbed him to death,
because the president saw his or her face.
Something like that, right Inspector?
Ah . Yeah.
Hey. are you gonna be alright.:Dad?
Hmm?
The boys are dominating
this deduction battle!
Oh, are the ?
Well. it's not a hard thinguto do
With this scene«of murder.
Cven a policeman can
make a deduction likeuthis
Oh. thanks...
This isn't everything, right?
We must'vergot something else .
What?
Hey! Let it out!
Oh, alright
We found these on the floor
around the victim's deadibody.
These four building blocks
TY A 200 RO ORC TR x) DOE VY
near the Ictims dead bod .
Actually, we found the victim's fingerprints
and also ink on those four blocks.
Ink!?
If you look at the ink: spotted side
of each building block
Nd this is the last one...
Omoecha To ?
Omocha To 7?
M1 Lilt
Omocha To 7
No. Is it Omogchiya (Rice cake store)
I think it's Omochiya, doni you think ?
Right
If 1it really means "omochar,
then whoever made this
could've picked the
other block to spell it right...
We. Inspector}
Can you tell me specifically where
the four blocks in the pictures were?
Sure...
Sure
This 18 how it looked when
e found the dead bod
guess this guy is he
Yeah.... He's the victim the president of this
toy production company. Mr. Tsujiya...
From the stack of the building blocks
by the victim's dead body.
We found the four blocks with characters
'mo. chi, and "ya".
Each of them had the victim's fingerprints
and an ink spot on it...
The Ink spots on the blocks
and the one that's on the victim's back
came from the same bottle...
The problem is, who put the Ink spots
on those four building blocks...
Right...
We found the victim's fingerprints
on those blocks but...
it.could be that the murderer made the
president hold them to hide something.
What
These are really the only ones that
have the owner's fingerprints?
Ah, actually the fingerprints are
on some other blocks.
But we found that
these four blocks have fingerprints
all over them. I mean on every single side,
even on those characters.
So. I guess+itys possible to think that
those four blocks Ar Sa
the owner's dying message
What? What makes you think that?
of the murder scene.
Hmm ?
His"hands are tied behind his back. right?
You can hardly sce and touch anything
if your hands are-tied like this...
Uti) ug Xe (Glo Y30 Er Of CVO
«Single side of the four blocks
because the victim was
searchingafor the correct blocks
by reading them with his fingers
e touched some other blocks.
But notso: many fingerprints were
found fromsthem.
Think that's because
each block is designed to have
five characters in the order.
So it's not so hard to
find which one's which.
I 888 .
That's why we found so many fingerprints
particularly on the four blocks.
In fact
Fingerprints are made of sweat and skin oil
and that's why they remain on things.
But once people die,
these things stop coming out
So even if you try to leave
fingerprints of a dead body.
You ¢an only get one or two solid ones...
Perhaps, when the murderer wasn't looking,
this guy took the four blocks
with his hands tied behind his back.
And then, rolled his body and
put the ink on those blocks.
And then, he rolled his body back again
to put them back to where they were.
I'm sure his hands were full of sweat
becausc of fear of death,
As a matter of fact the marks of the rope
all over the floor prove that.
So it's possible to think that...
The feeling of danger actually made
the owner choose the wrong block
This Is a to production compan .
If you think logically
the-dying message-must be "omocha
Rather:than "omoechiya. don't you think?
Oh my god. We just got here
How could you come up with
SO many things in such a short while
Yeah, I know, eh?
That's my bo
Oops .
This.isn't good, Ran!
He's dominating us mentally!
This is a battle between Heiji and us!
It's either the baseball game
or Takarazuka show!
Y. yeah!
To win this deduction battle,
we gotta find out what the
dying message really meant first.
Maybe there are some hints
in the other toys
No, we found no strange toys
other than the blocks.
Are: ou sure?
We checked every single toy in this office
Iooking for some other dying messages
that could be hiding
Then! ma be he d ing message
hasta different meaning
What do you mean?
Different combinations of
four the characters. youfimean
omoyachi, ochimoya. ochiyamo
Oyamochi, oyachimo, mochiyno...
Ugh! Doesn't make sense at all!
Alright. what else have we got?
/we found only a golf club andi
Ieather coat with the victim's blood on it.
BE TT
we found only a golf club and; in
Ieather coat with the victim's blood on it.
We found only a golf club .and a
Which we assume the murderer was
wearing during the 'murder.
But the golf club and the leather coat are
the victim's belongings.
So they didn't help us
determine who killed him...
What's more confusing is that
the murderer was wearin ¥that leather coat.
Hinm 2
You know, the bloodstain,
it's faded only around the left shoulder...
It's got rubbed against something...
Actually, that's another mystery...
XEN: o {Hugo NOhxex id {inte
DER ool 00 SIS
where the bloodstain got rubbed against...
The murderer,may have touched it
when he or she took it off...
You haven't found gloves
or something like that. right?
Speaking of blood...
there's a strange bloodstain right here!
Where is it?
Right here!
Oh. there: ou: go.
This Is It...
Hold: on:a sec!
You have to look at it really close .
You sec tho part whoro
the bloodstain ends unnaturally?
Maybe something w 8 here,
don't you think?
Could be. What kinda thing
» would you put here though?
Hmm!?
Yeah
(Ni, what's BS 5000 Wn 1 §.,
Don't touch them! We have to keep
the desk just like the way it I$
It's external input only,
So then... Maybe a video camera was
here until the victim was murdered.
The video camera was
in the president's room.
, OK, then call the: forensic officer to check
if there's any bloodion it. will ya?
Itgs strange...Let's assume that
the video camera was here"...
But why would the murderer move it
after killing the owner?
The murderer connected the video camera
to the TV just to watch the president
after tying him up?
No. then why did he remove it?
The owner was dead.
Also .
Something's been bugging me
ever since-l~got here.
Right here,
In this office.
Theres something odd
something unnatural
Hey. Conan...
Hey!'What's up. Ran?
Could you do me a favor?
What?
I really want Kazuh1 to win
this deduction battle...
I think she i1s really looking forward to see
the Takarazuka show with us. 7
So, next time you come up with a good idea
omwsomething. I want you to tell us quietly.
VERN
I'll give Dad your Ideas
ind Sleeping Kogoro will
ke care of the rastlike alway
Yes?
Please!
Please?
Conan, please
Hey hey hey!
This idiis mine!
So stop headhunting:-him will you?
Hey! Of course. you respect a guy's
friendship more than one with girls. right?
Friendship?
I'm en your side only
because ou ga e me no choice .
Ah, doesn't matter. man!
We gotta: win. this the: battle anyway
We got &.watch the final game!
Oh. what a guy
Oh! How was the identification?
We found it...
We found the victim's blood
even though it was very slight
I guess the murderer did not realize it
But why was the,video camera
herelanyway?
Perhaps the murderer connected
the camerarto the TV
And watched-the owner until
he spit out the combination to the safe...
and,watched the owner until
he spit out the combination to the safe
Yet.
Why do something round about like that?
Why not just tie him up and
wait in front of the safe
intil he spits out the combination?
He left the video ¢cmera on,
to keep him from moving around
because he was ransacking
the other rooms!
As a matter of fact, the murderer didn't
know the victim left a dying message...
Well. now it more likely that
the murderer 1s well acquainted
with this office and also with the victim
What do you say?
The president left a d. Ing message
So that means,
If we get it night it's possible to find out
who the murder is...
Then, we should investigate the
four workers who found the dead body.
Oh, Takagi is asking them
about their alibi right now.
Inspector Megurel
Yeah?
Just finished the interrogation!
Ok. And . how was it?
They are all designers
but also do some other types of work,
Iike NaoAikQ; whw does accounting.
June 29th around 5 pm,
when the murder occurred.
She was out fishing alone.
Atushi Hasami, the salesperson,
as watching a movie at home.
Isao Nakagami,
Hajime Iw1tomi,
the vice president,
was out, watching the-final round
of a golf tournament
Ma aN
az CL s 7
All very vague alibis
Yes... Right now,
Chiba is verifying their stories and
Iifthere is anything hiding
behind the stories.
It seems nobody Is able to
prove:their alibi. Not even one.
Hiding
Behind .
Wait 1 minute... If the situation was...
That dying message on the four blocks Is...
Ohman it was so easy)
How come I didn't realize this?
Kazuha...I'm sorry
This battle...is mine
What the!
Ka...
Kazu 8
Original CoTic:Books By.
GCOSHO AOYAMA
Pr 0 du G 0 v S
Bickoround Music.
CALI nil
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor
KANJI KASHIWABARA
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI.HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUI
tnmmalicCn Directors.
HIRO TOSHI, TAKA ANT
HARUCIOOGAWARA
AISUSHT AONO
VarJ.: Lb
TAKASHI HHYC DO
Art Director.
2 e SHI
Directors 'Of Photosoraphy
TAKASHI NOMURA
boo Ny b » » > N
TAKABIISA OWAG AW
Recording Dir: fo
KATSUYOSHI BA¥A
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKAIA
Me. Director.
KEN. KODAMA)
Produced By.
TMS E TERTAINY ENTLTD
in assocratipn with
YOMIURI TELECA TING
CORPORATION
DETECT 1+ TA WW
CONE AMAL VHOGARUWUAAN YIN TMA
\ll Riv his Kevervid
Now all we need 8 hat thing
The thing that.connects the pieces of
the mystery all together!
KazuhaO?
Sorry, Ran I need silence
The mystery is about to be solved...
Kudo...
Hmm?
I got it... \
What?
His must be it!
Ihe murderer is...
(12% )
'luv
Next Conan! Deduction Battle (Part Il)"
(12 #)