The answer lies behind he message
But love and hate twist the path to the truth
Who is to win? God only knows
He seas through the one and only truth
Ac ld in appearance<3
with the ll- Q. of an adult
No case isVleftsunsolved
with Detective €d6nan
Somabody visited us to Invite us to
the final game of the high school
Somebody visited us to invite us to
baseball tournament and Takarazuka
Revue show. all the way from Osaka.
It wi s Helji and Kazuha
However, finding out that both
events will be on the same day.
The people from Osaka
started to have a fight.
In order to decide which one to watch,
Kogorno comes up "with a suggestion.
A.deduction battld begins!
Deduction Battle (Part Ill)
Kazuha...
What's wrong, Kazuha?
I'm just eon-fused
This dying message is killing me... «
If we canst figure out what it means,
were gonna lose this battle.
No Takarazuka show...
Just don't wanna lose. so...
Battle...
Come on, there are no winners
or losers in deduction...
Because
what we. have tg do is, tom
find the 'one:and only truth...
Huh.
That's true .
Yo, Heiji...
You got it too, right? The true meaning
of the dying message. I mean...
Nope...Not at all.
How come we don't have the actual blocks
that have the ink spots on them?
If these were the actual
blocks. not thggpictures.
We could've looked at them like this.
Maybe there was something
hidden behind them...
What the...
Well. too bad we can't see the backside
of thetblocks because these: are pictures...
Hmm?
I 888.
I get it.
I get it
It seems that The president
was having a hark Itime
putting the ink on the blocks. huh?
His hands were tied behind his back.
Plus, heihad to readjthe characters
on the blocks with his fingers
in order to choose the right ones, right?
Look at those blocks. Each of them
has different characters
and also a picture of an animal on it
I would be confused and
pick the wrong block. for sure.
If It wasn't blocks but
pieces of Japanese chess...
it would be so much easier
cause there's only one character
on each backside of the piece!
Kudo .
OOnly one character... on the backside...?
What? That would be even harder. stupid...
The pieces are:not big enough to see
it was the. victim s dying
message or not
Oh, are they'...
Yeah. Maybe the President just dropped
\the pieces on the ink accidentally
We'll nevor knows right?
Maybe the dying message
Is actually on the .
So. you did find the motPé to kill from
the four workers who found the victim.
Ah, yes
Ah... First...about the
accountant. Nao Aiko...
She was the forme
wife of President sujiya.
She had an affair with another
man and got divorced...
They were having problems with alimony...
Atsushi Hasamtmmsales clerk...
He had been told by the
victim that he would be fired
if this year's revenue
goes below last-ycar'sw
The planner, Isa0 Nakagami
had been told the same thing...
Also, there had been: a lot.of conflict
between him and the victim
Lastly. the vice president, Hajime IWatoml
was not having 1 fight or
anything with the president...
But actually, he is supposed
to be the next pres dent
If anything happens to President T'sujiya.
Hmm...
So all of them have 1
decent motive for murder...
A.Uue.o ui...
There you go... You're almost there!
There had been a lot of conflict between
the president and the workers.
I'm curious what kept this
ompany going so long...
Yeah
The workers had been
drinking in-Mr. Iwatomi's house,
complaining about their boss and stuff...
On Hn) Edn WAN pao
the day of the murder,
the three workers went to
Mr. Iwatdmi's Rouse to drink
Nd stayed over night. On the
mext day. all fur workers came
to the office together 1nd
found the dead president...
Oh. one more thing .
His is a sort of unrelated topic
to the murder but I'll give it 1 try...
Each worker has.a strange obsession...
Obsession?
Ms. Aiko gets cold-esily
so-she has 50 pairs of gloves...
She brings at léastdthree
pairs when she goes fishing.
Mr Hasami is a movie lover
and has 30 sunglasses
Those actually include The limited models
which some famous actors-used to wear...
OgS ME AL
Mr=Ndkagami has at least 40 hats.
He wears them when he goes
» the turf, just for good luck...
Mr. Iwatomi was the victim's golf friend,
and had 30 pairs of white golf shoes...
These are ll exponsive brand shoes
He polishes. .themfall once a week
And lastly, the victim, President
Tsujiya was obsessed with idols!
It seems he had been
collecting 1 lot of idol goods.
Oh yeah. ll found a lot those idol goods
In the president's room over there...
Reeally .
That! See the one on the desk?
Pens and pen stands with the
idol's picture on them and stuff...
I see.
Hey.{Kudo...Have-yous noticed it?
Yeah... The unnaturalness
of the desk. you mean?
LB LO bie Oily) UC go
ht... There's one more thi
That's kinda bugging me...
I suppose this calendar
is also the president's stuff. right?
Yes... That calendar 1s
actually his favorite.
So he kept it even. after that month passed
Hell...
WX 8000 UO XA]
Oh. My mom Iso got»me one
firstithingein the morning*today
How're you doing. Kazuha?
A2 what??
Sorry Ran I need silence
The mystery is about to
be solved in my head.
What as it now
What time do ou think it isl!
Oh don't you tell me you are
still suspicictis about 'us!
Oh, don't you tell me you are
still suspicious about us!
Ry SAR
I heard some money matters
were involved in this murder
It's all because of our vague alibis
We 'have no proof.as to it.
But what can I do?
Was really at the turf that day...
I was at a golf course, watching
the final round of the tournament!
I was watching movies
Actually. three movies in a row...
I'was fishing! I just
happened to go by myself!
Alright...
Sojwho found the dead body. first?
Who...is this boy?...
Could you just tell me
more about it. please?
It's me who found him first...
y I was,going to sit at my desk
when I found him lying" on the floor.
I screamed.
As we heard Mr. Iwatomi's scream
We all came here... and called the police
O HJ]
Right.
\ @Oh, before I forget. ..Is it your boss.
Who rips the pages off the calendar?
Yes...the President gets upset
if we do it because we might ruin itd
So Mr. Tsujlya always rips it off
AND keeps. it in his room like
some kind of precious treasure.
Was:-he also the one who wrote
the schedule on the-calendar?
Ah, yeah...
We were all supposed to play
some golf.together next Sunday...
I can't believe this actually. happened...
We gotta look for something so
Hmm.
You guys do the talking. ok?!
A right! Let's do it!
Yeah
The fact the video camaera
was at a blind spot
From the victim's point of view.
And the unnaturally neat desk.
The bloodstain on the leather
coat the murderer was wearing...
[he suspects estrange collection
AND the president's. dying message...
Yeah.
All we need Is that thing...
The thing that connects
the pieces together!
\AAn 26412 COX OF {hs
suspects got a solid alibi! ?
Yes! I'm at the TV station
right now. checking the footage...
1 ex AIRY
Clearlyl
Kudo...
Hm!?
Ran.
I found it!'it's the June calendar.
I 7 SEN raw
There's a thin bloodstain,
but I can still see it!
That must be it-!
The murderer is...
I got it...
hat?
Ran. I think...
I got the answer',
Yeah? ScFiously?
You really got the answer?
You know the dying, message
t e owner left at the murder scene!
Yeah, the four building blocks
with the ink spots. right?
That looked like a hiddon secret code,
but it was simply indicating the killer!
The killer?
I don't think there's anyaperson
that looks like a buildingOblock... *!
No. nol it's. the mame!
Name?
I don't think 0" "mo" "¢hir "ya" have
wything to do with their name though.
Remember? Heiji was saying the victim
might have just put the blocks on the ink.
And not because he wanted us to read
what's WITH the ink spots...
In other words,
the backside of the ink spotted character
Is the true dying message.
Do ou get it?
I understand But we can't seo
what behind those characters...
I can ask the forensic officers
to bring them here...
No, you don't have to do that!
Look.
The blocks of 0 character
Wouldalook like this
if were to unfold it...
U. e 07
You ll know what kind of character
will be in the blank space. right?
Just in case. I checked the-blocks
over there. As I expected.
The characters are lined up
int e correct order...
Ms AKO... Am: right?
Yeah....each block contains
five characters with the same consonant
and an animal picture in the same _order.
If you know which character is
on which side it is no longer a hustle!
The backside of 0 is "I"
Aocordnm l. ., is "mi" and "chi" is "to".
Right! So the real dying message 1s
I" mi "to"...and what's the last one'...
Hm? Doesn't make sense.
According to Kazuha,
the last block "ya" is supposed to be "yu"
But I actually see "yo- on it.
That block 1s special
Look. You see "wo" on the right side of yo"?
That means this block consists of
If we put those characters in the same order
The animal part will be "'n That's it!
Acco ding to the same rule, "ya" Is "wa"...
0 the dying message is.
I "mi" "to" "wa", do you get it?
" "Ml" to" "wa", do you get 7?
So...that's ah...
Imiwato...lwamito...lwato...!
Thatswight... That's hat the president
wanted to tell us before he was killed
Mr Iwatemil
It was your name!
Il see. You wanted to kill your bess
and take over the company. didn't you?
Ah~no I"...
Oh my god, Ran! You actually solve
the case before Hem!
Yeah! We won this deduction battle!
So that means.
We can go to the Takarazuka show!
Ah cough!
sorry Kazuha...
Mr. Iwatomi is not the murderer.
What?
I had a phone call from Chiba...
The 29th of last month, around $5 pm,
when the murder occurred
Mr. Iwatomi was In fact on TV...
No way...
Why?
Don't ask me why.
You have a twin brother?
No I don't
Hmm...
Sorry to tell you this but,
Kazuha's idea was wrong...
Oh no...
She was right.
EH) op
Tho blocks of all "wa=*"to "mit aro
really the dying. message
the president Tsujiya left
before he was killed!
Hell.
But Heiji...
Mr. Iwatomi has an alibi...
Of course he has!
Because Mr. lwatomi is not
the murderer at all...
What!?
Sorry, you just said that
it was the real dying message. didn't you?
Yeah. For sure. VI did...
Bull didn't say the message was correct,
did 7?
Wow. what are you talking about?
He don't ou remember?
How did President Tsujiya leave
a message on the blocks?
Tr 0 remember that!
1, Well. I think he was tied down
on the floor behind the desk...
Heypicked the building blocks and put
them in the puddle of ink on the floor.
XY fur winx o) HS / da KC
You got that right
The problem is the ink stain
hat's on the president's back.
What's wrong with it?
He got that inkastain when
he was fighting the)murderer. right?
Yeah, that's what I thought at first
But I noticed the unnaturalness
on this desk
Unnaturalness pg
\Oh- it's weird! The chair justOhit itWlightly,
but the pen stand fell
Huh?
Well, the ink bottlesfell off the desk
because people were fighting and
hit. ing the desk hard, right?
Right...
Then how come the pen stand
did not fall during the fight?
That is certainly strange...
This just sounds like...
The murderer spilledl the ink
on the floor on purpose!
No way!! Why would he do that!?
That's like hers giving the president
a chance to wiite something about him...
Oh...
RY 000
It waskxon purpose...
That's night! The murderer dehbernately
spilled thc ink on the floor...
To compel the president Lo leave
a dying message about him!
But it's dangerous
The president could leave the killer's name.
That's only if he saw the killer's face.
Hey, why don't you lie down on the floor
Iike the president was
What?...
OK...
WED YOR oO pate
how the president felt...
H.How he felt...?
I got it! Shoes.
It's the shoes!
The murderer narrowed the
ictim:s scope with this desk.
and made him determine who
he was only by looking at his shoes!
And made him determine who
he was only*by looking at his shoes!
So. the murderer wore white shoes
to make him leave a fake dying message
about the murderer...
That's why tho video camera was
set up in the victim's blindespot!
The killer was watching
the president on the monitor
To make sure that the president
wrote the desired dying message,
And then he killed the victim!
But...Who did it anyway?
Hey. 06k .
Huh?
I fou d this strange calendar
in the president's room...
See
Hmm!?
I thought you might know. what this Is
im? Well, igs got a little st
but other than that...
Oh. don't you get it?
It's been wipodioff but it's a bloodstain!
What!
(EO, CORA {lil IRE 68000 Wig R
the president was murdered on June 29th,
when the: Juno calendar at the murder
15 TIRE!
sett
; Ay &is belly I (hrc PI) got fete
Vo schedule.
On kh™ 30th of the June calendar.
1s T SUN LION
on the 30th of the June calendar
In fact, therors 1 schedule written down
on the 30th of the June calendar.
In fact, there's 1 schedule written down
on thof30th of the June calendar
1 SUB WW
In fac *gthore's a sehedule winitton down
on the 30th of the June calendar.
Who in the world would de that
without any damn reason! ?
He stop there .
The June calendar was ripped, because
someone had to hide the bloodstain...
Wake up, people! We got something
that's got the same bloodstain on it...
Oh! The coat the killer was wearing!
The bloodstain onithe;shoulder
Iooked kindairubbed!
That's why, I made the four workers
stand in front of the calendar...
Stop!
The only. Person who Is tall enough to touch
the top-of-the calendar with his shoulders
Oh. ou moron...
It is' you
Mr. Hasami!
No one else, could do it!
Good job...
When the president
came back to the office.
You attacked him from behind
with a golf club.
Wearing Mr Iwatomi's white shoes and
setting up the video camera
you made sure that the president left behind
the fake messac of about the murderer
You probably were relieved after
killing the president.
And leaned against the wall.
That's when jou got the bloodstain
on the calendar...
You'.didn't notice at until the next day
That's why you didn't dump it right away.
In fact, it's easy to steal the white shoes
from Mr. Iwatomirs house...
People came and drunk
at 'Mr... Iwatomi's [house so often.
You had a lot of chance to steal them.
But the height of his shoulders
IS not enough evidence
to accuse him for the murder.
Actually...the evidence are those shoes!
You were wearing Mr. lwatomi's shoes
until the president left the message.
It's quite a long while...
The smell of your feet are
definitely on them!
The police dog will sense
your smell right away. right?
I guess you had a decent reason
AIR)
or wearing» 00.86 s mes
ym S A y
until they smelled of your toot.
You can tell us about WW ifryou want...
I wanted to Kill the president
yy TAMIAGg TWA OME up or WC mur er,.
I wanted him out of the toy production...
That's all.
WwW. why me?
I don't think
I ever mistreated you or anything...
It's not me that you mistreated me
It's the children
The children who are going to be
playing with the toy
that you and the president were
trying to sell.
I...don't get it
Here. look at this building block
See. we cut the pointy corners for safety.
But to cut down the cost,
they told us not to do it
That includes not only the blocks
but the other to. s too...
They: certainly] look more appealing and
could be more profitable.
But are dangerous for children.
I disagreed with the idea,
but we were gonna be fired
if we did not follow their. plan...
But you didn't have: to kill him.
This company was bleeding financially...
Bleeding financially?
Al...Guess what President Tsujiya sali
Iwatomi! You want money'? I got tons of it
I'm not lying. look at the safe!
What!?
He had money?
Yes...l have no idéa what
and how he did it though.
Doesn't matter. VI just didn't wanna see
the poorly-made toys and deceive kids...
Original Comic Bee <. By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
Grills
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Backeround Music.
AY Al
Character, Jesions iy
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 110OKA
KANJI KASHIWABARA
INARI K@!
CHI MIYA
YUICHI-HIGURE
TOSHIKI IN@UE
Animation 1 rectors.
MAJ 'U J1')! J J!) J
HIROTOSHI1 TAKATANI!
Iatte J) ,\) ey
AI. USHI A N
AKIO KAWAMURAO
IAKASHI HYOD
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBU IANI
I Directors Of Photosraphy.
TAKASHI NOMURA
Io 1"."
vos 1 Ce .,
TAKAHISA OWAGAY
Recording Dire:
Editor.
TERUMITSU (ox/am
KENJLKODHAMA)
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD.
Mn assowalion with
Y IMIURIALELECASTING
CORPORATION
ITEC TV] ON AN
COSHO VOY AAA SHOE AREA IN Yy 1yv TAI
You really got that trick
I'm impressed...
It's because of the novel
What?
My mom got me a novel this morning.
The title gave me the idea of that trick.
You better thank your mom, man...
You won this deduction battle
because of it...
We can finally go to the Koshien Stadium. _.
Oh godly
Con jratulations . Heiji
Oh shoot?
I forgot!
Now I have to practice the boola boola...
Hey!
(NC ley, Yk
Kazuha. I can ask Helji for you
OVO 0 TLTPAL &) SOW
You are the one who solved the
myster of the d ing message
YolWare actuallyyhalf the winner, right?
Orget it...
Yea 7?
What I really wanted to see wasn't the
Takarazuka show or the baseball garmQ
1S... It was Haeljiss smile that he sh
when he solves a case
Oh man... Where-did I go wrong?
You stupid
Yeah It's the Koshien Stadium!
What's: going on?
Why not come 'here and get it?
Why not come here and get it?
What's:going on?
I guess that person doesn't care
whether we catch him or mot:
Yeah!
He said hors gonna die If we can'tyfind
that thing before. the game ends!
Maybe. hess still-around here...