Keshien ball grounds...the dream and
goal of all high school ball players.
Tho Japan summer high school ball game
will start this morning!
This year 4,146 schools have participated
in the nation wide competition.
And 160,000-players have played...
Chosen from among
the winners are 49 schools.
In the indoor training grounds
on the side of 1st base
the players are waiting for
the game to start...
The playerstare, whiting for
The stars...from the south...
we will commence the.
Japan High School Baseball Tournament!
The players will make entry...
Representing Osaka!
Here's Ogane High Schools.
Please pledge .
KNEE Wp) Eo FADE Olin)
Toyama Minami Vocational High Scheol,
Captain Kawakami.
I pledge!
I plodgol
That we the players have come here .
With Joy and admiration in our hearts'
upon this great stage and
WAN etotamiex=R30) Gull 21m) eR 50...
Hits
Woe will (give it our best
ind display the results
Of the of the trauning we went through,
with the sportsmanship of fair play!
Representing all the players here,
Toyama prefecture
Toyama Manama Vocational
High School baseball club
PONE
ELA SN RY,
Captain Tomoya Kawakami.
Koshien
where the chosen high school ball playerse
gather from throughout the nation [pr
to compete using their skills and strength.
It Is the pinhnaclo of one's goal!
It is a sanctuary where the goddess smiles
on thechampions. as wcll as
fightingiarena where
the ball,game is settled.
fighting arenagwhere
the ball;game is settled.
fighting arena where
the ball game is settled
s...Koshien at times entices the
bewitched into unbelievable fate.
Horas 1 hot passionato susponse
in this coldwwinter scason
Today's episodo 1s 12 hour special.
IN 30 ex,
A difficult case on a grand stage.
He sues through the one and only truth
A'child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan
foe.
(( >4t
1330330S 13333f
E Cans 6 ¢ ar Cm
Held on the same day
during =ummecr vacation
whether to go to the bnll:gamesor
to go watch the Takarazuka revue
Haiji and Kazuha decide
to have-ajdeduction match
The g¢ase Is one that
Pops was asked to help out with
The clue on hand are wooden blocks
that the president of the toy
manufacturing company had
Ieft behind as a dying message
Thanks to Hell's subtle hint
Kazu a solves the message.
However, it turns out;that Heiji figures out
wholthe realkiller is and
wins 'the deduction match.
We can finally go to the Koshien Stadium...
On god! Oh shoot! I forgot!
Congratulations ..Heiji.
Now I have to practice the boola boola...
Hey!
Kazuha. wa
Kazuhn can ask He) oy you
to go to the Takarazuka show
You are the one who solved the
yster of the d\ mg message
You¥are actually half the winner. right
-orget at
OL NR
What I really wanted to see wasn't the
Takarazuka show or the baseball gamOW
It was...It was Heiji's smile that he shows
when he solves a case
Wow! Koshlen
MERE QUO thar £6 [x 60 ARO
and everywhere aha. ha... Yoko
I'm sure that hero, there
and everywhere Daha. ha... Yoko.
ZXE MD
I'm sure tht hero, there
and everywhere Daha. ha... Yoko.
11150)
Fig BIR
I'm sure that hero, there
and everywhere Daha, ha...Yoko.
MM -Ii{S Mm ILS BE_IX
ta sat leat, diene
and everywhere Daha. ha... Yoko.
I'm sure that here, here
and everywhere Daha. ha...Yoko.
Yoko?
Oh{ Konan High Scheel is where
the.idol Yoko Okino used to go to...
Huh?
Hey...we're not thcre yet?...
Are you all right. Kudo...
Sigh .
Sigh.
Nope...
By the way .
Why do they call this Koshien?!
Why not Hyogo Stadium...
Or Kansas Stadium...
I think it would've been why better.
The year that Koshien was completed,
WO OQ Judy
that had come around finally after 60 years
that: hac come around finally after 60 years
} when both on the 10 calendar signs and
the! 12rsigns of the Chinese zodiac
thersigns at tho vory top of each calendar
were respectively
Ko" and "shi" meeting again...
You sure know a lot. don't you. Conan
Aha ha. ha, ha.
Roally, he knows nothing applause
about baseball and yet he sf Knowledgeable
wherifit comes to things like these
Well. I'm so sorry...
That's not all there is to Koshien...
The number of the stumps of the
famous ivies growing here total 430
and the dimension of the
Ieaves total 8.000 mats...
Although it's an old stadium it h1s the
capacity to hold a total of 53.000 people.
which is virtually equal to that of a large
stadium that the major leagues play at...
How about it! Fantastic. don't you think?!
You're... just as bad as I am! \
Its going to start
Huh?!
Let's do our best!!
Top of the 1st inning?...
Ostthron number 1 short.
Player Inoue is the first batter
for Ohgane» High School'!
Play ball!
Stila]
Strike two I
Strike batter NW
Juice? Juice?
CTTUZIS
HBBE
fifiufi
gr AA
CTITVUIZ KIN
mum 1
(HBIBB
te SR IR
Iflmi
CTTUZRN
(TNT/JG?
« q'e!
LN \.
BHAA
('TH
IVS NE I
(HBB
CTI RN
Strike!
an <7
Strike. batter out!
TL 3yVv
Striko! \
Strike!
Strike, batter out!
center number 6 of Oh jane High School,
player Matsudais the batter...
<> op
Strike!
Strike. battdr out!
'Ix\
UM Hor I are, payer of a,.
Strike, batter out!
Number 8 catcher. Watanabe...
Strike!
Strike, batter out
End of the bgttom of the 2nd inning,
Konan batter is number 4, 3rd Nagashima.
Listen to this
The roar of the cheer of the people
Ioud enough to erase the announcement!
By some strange czmincldence.
It turns out that the samc players get to
to compete against oach other three times
in a row at the finals of Koshien!
As=«=\Villathesvictor be the winner of last year, wm
Konan High:School?!
Or. will it be OhganosHigh School that
Is aiming to winthe spring and
summer games successively?
The pitcher flings his arms up high
and prepares to throw his first pitch.
There goes the ball!
Strike!
Wow! Talk about strike indeed!
Strike! Strike!
He . Pops .
Huh?!
What have you been
Iooking at all this tithe?
womb
Dad!! The game's over that side!
I'll bet heys watching the
cheer girls of the Alps stand...
Talk about lewd!
We came all the way out here,
sm watch the game. will you! DAD'!
Yeah. but...
Sitting In nght stand like this,
it's so far that
you can rea y wa Cc) 6 game anyway...
I thought we were going to have better
seats-because you invited us
I'm so sorry.
I asked an acquanmtanea of mane who
Iivesah'ere to line up and get the tickets,
SSS IMANBRANSVEXOV ETS lB HS
Ins reactor Ohtakil.
Besides, the game between
Ohgane and Konan is super popular so
unless you come really
early in the morning
itr<seems to be impossible
to get an infield seat!
That's why you should
buy advance tickets...
TihereYgoos tho ball!
Mere. have some ice candy! Ice candy!
I bought one*for each ome of you!
Cold! Y
Thank you.
You re welcome
But. are you sure
its okay Inspector Ohtaki...?
Ciao
But are on sure
it's okay Inspector Ohtaki...?
But, are you sure
it's okay Inspector Ohtaki .?
1 Yougknow, work?
No problem
Me took time off anyway...
Right?
Yeah. I've been watching the game
successively for 3 days since the semi-finals
You like Koshien, don't you?
Of course he does!
Huh?
Mr. Ohtaki. .may not look it,
but he used to play high school baseball!
Right!
Oh, come on, Kazulla, W's no big deal...
Oh really.
How embarrassing...
So. you've played on this
Koshien field too. then?
@h...no... Making it to the best 8
for the preliminary district match was
as far as lever went...
A-ha, ha.
But...coming here and watching
them play brings back memories.
of the days back then when
we pufiour heart and sou finto just...
< vw, »
of the days back then when
we put our heart and soul into just...
«5 WW
going after one
ow. & - Ne
black ball soiled with sweat and dirt...
Just what do you think you're doing,
Ohtaki?!
There!
What 8 tho matter: missing .4 ball liko that,
Ohtaki?!
I guess I don't. have therknack
for playing.baseball.
That:s*not true. Donst*give up...
All you need-to-do Is-practice a little.more...
Right.
Ill practice even more and get better...
Right
Hl practice even more and{get better...
Hey! Freshman Ohtaki!
Yas, sired
You'll be.the number 7 catcher
for the.practice game against
Yakushiji High School that's coming up!
Y Yes, sir
Hey. fantastic. Let's give it our best shot!
Yeah .
Uh Vwondor dy don't have
the knack for baseball?
It's not that...
Don't gnvo up and pram-nee more and more!
If you give up before doingyanything,
W11 .1990 IR
I was really hopeless
when I started off too
but I stayed after school
everyday and practiced.
Then, one day, I realized that
I had become captain of my. team...
You weren't a good player?
NOunoll WE 3 IN (6X)
ATORY OURS CTIO UST
Yes $0 don't give up!
Hey. what's with thatilook of. .yours
All the under classmen don't know: what
to do sincea ou look so:depressed:..Ohtaki. ¢
you're the one who lead the weak team.to
where it is now!
The under classmen are the ones
who are going to Koshien.
Encourage them and make them
feel that can do it!
I hive Ono léslfitfiiflc)
I'd like to say-to-all;of you .
No matter what.
No matter what. don't ever give up!
Yes tl
pi be
Fp LL Cx Dy lds,
that the effort I put in hack
then was worth it...
ait).
I feel that one should never give up...
» I feel that one should never give up...
Really... .Keoshien is really a good place...
HID pPlaLy Wo Lidp. Jud Liayp
You think so, don't you. Hiroshi...
Original Comic Books:Ry
Producers.
MASAHITO YOSHIORA
Background Music
KATSUO
B* 0088 ss SJ I DWE
Character Designs-By.
MASATOMO SUDO
WNW Rg ae
00000 sua) ~
Story Lcrtor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
CI OTL ILL
<SCcripls 3y.
KAN]! KASHIWABA RA
KAZUNARI KG HI
UNICHI MI. + ITA
YUICHI HIGURI
fQSIFflAKl INK/CUE .
Anifhation Direutors.
MASATIOMOSUDO
* HARUD "OO GAWARA
\ "ATSUSHTAONO,
AKIO KAWAMURA
JAKASHI'HYO YO
Art-Dir¢ctor.
gr YUKIHIRDSHIBUIANI
Di ectprs;Of-Photography.
TAKASHIPN O MU RAN
HIRGNOBY HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA-OWAGAS
Recordin; Director.
KATSUYOSHI'KOBAYAS HI
Editor.
TERUMTISU OK, TA
C href Director.
KINI KODAMA
Produced By.
TAMS-ENTERTAINMENT. LTD.
Mn aSsocration with
YOMIURI TIELECASTINC
CORPORATION
DY TIC HIVE CONANT
CONHO AOYAMA SHOCARURANADY IV IM
AI Rights Reserved