BY @ fA RN
It is the top of the 4th:inning. the batter for
Ohgane High School Is
number 5 left. Shigeta.
He hit the ball!
The left line.
(HAN
A Hie caught the bal
He caught it! Hescaught it!
Great play!
Hat 3rd is really fantastic!
Ye).
NA 77
He sure is.
\ KOHNAN
At any rate.let's get with this code!
Before the end of the bottom of the 6th
inning we've 'got to locate where
this numben47.3, 4 indicates
and find the 2nd cell phone
Before that man wearing the white cap
uses the bombi\to commit suicide!
But, these numbers are
hard to figure out again
Not really. I've figured out half ofgit!
What 2!
Because we figured out
that the first code 96.7.13
indicated that the first cell phone
was on the 13th aisle
at the edge of the left pole!
OT 1S the distance from
the home base to the polo.
NO 7 WR ears iii: $01
the number on the back of
the uniform and left of
high sehool baseball.
The final 13 means
the seat on the 13th aisle!
Which means that the number 3
in the parenthesis of the numbers 4/.34
the number on back of the uniform
and the Inst number 4 means the 4th
aisle of a seat somewhere, right?
But we've got to find out
WACO {ne Cone adn 130
The first number 41s probably
A Clie Se eos fee Ya 3}!
There's no doubt
that it is a seat by t-he 1st base.
In"high school baseball
the player with number 3 is at 1st base.
But. Heilchan. the (one wefiring
number 3 at Kenan High School is
CHI:
3rd base
AT ef e-
val ¥Y
foo. 9
Out!
sO you shouldn't be concerncd about him.
But, if the guy made «
the code in accordance,
to this final game
between Konan and 'Ohgane
ma be the game
would be of some concern. 3
@kay. tell you what!'&
I'll ggjcheck the 4th aisle
of the infield stand by 1st base.
So kiddo go check the 3rd base side!
Okay!
What about me?
After you get us into the infield stand
wait for us at the map of the Koshien
outside that we saw a while ago.
That place is right in the center of the
infield stand of the 1st and 3rd base
$0 whether I find the cell phone
@kay, while I'm writing I'll call and ask
my superior at Hyogo Prefectural Station,
if the company Takano Transport
that was bombed and set on fire
by the guy wearing the white cap
had been hated by someone recently.
Yeah do that will you
Mr. Ohtaki.
Strike out-
Eight strike outs in a row)!
The droning ball
shows no signs of*weakening atiall
even at the final!
K ah!
Huh?
Hey. what's with you, kid.
U. Uh
I'm just looking for something
Okay. their really going for it!
Will the 9th player strike out in a row!
Fool! Use more balls and slow down
the progress of the game
What? Is thatitrue?
Yeah.Last month
the truck of Takano Transport
WhAaaa!
\Mi QR?
Whaiaa
Whaaa
Iit.It's a homerun!
N the bottom of the 4th inning.
Thanks to the hit of the big slugger
of Konan High School.
They've taken a 1 point lead!
Oops. NO, NO
I can't be watching the game.
Gotta find it aliick
Super batting just as expected.
Moreover.
He's using a woodon hat
47.3.4
and net 1 metal one. Incredible
Metal?
Metal
Helix)
Kane?
Strike
'eater out.
IB Ubota falls to sanshin and
gets the 3rd out.
}lKubotla falls to sanshin and
Kubota falls to sanshin and
gets the 3rd out.
This Inning Konan's Nagashima hit
a home run and got 1 run
Team ( hgane is trying to make
up that point
The batter is number 8 Watanabe
Go Ohgano!
Sakuraba throws his first pitch
against Watanabe!
A hit! Between 2nd and Short
Konan's 3rd base Nagashima is
playing well this game
Strike!
Inao throws his third pitch at
3 drab!
Strike and ouf{
A swing and a miss.no runs this inning!
Bottom of the 5th and the
scores O01
Only one run has been made by Konan's
Nagashima homerun in the 4th ,/
113$.
Wis tha bottom 61 he 6th inning.
e nd tho batter for Konan Is
number 9,
2nd Michishita.
Oh. Kudo?
How's about it? Did you find it?
I soarched all through the 4th aislo
But. it's nowhere.
And?! how about you?
Same here.
I guess we'll just have to decopher
the meaning of the figure 47
You know, Heiji
Huh?
What is it. Kudo.?
At. Koshien
here's nothingrthat "gold "=Gin is thore?
Well
At Keshien gold wouldibe
@insan."
Huh?! Y You mean 4
there is something called that?
You can see it, can't ou?
Fe vo rout Bok: AA;
the colling™ahindthe back not,
that's it!
Then, there's no doubt about.
The 2nd cell phone is there!!
Huh? Why?
You know, don't you?!
47 Is gold's
[That's right!
47 is tho atomic number fer gold!!
Let-s go outside once
and go.in behind the hack-net
and check the seats in the 4th aisle.
But. I wonder if we'll make it in time?
Tho seats under the Gin san
behind the back net
has 100 seats an aisle.
If we -try checking every seat from now
three outs and that's it
Then. maybe It's '1st base or 3rd base?
Because there's a "3" under "47"
Fool!
You just checked there!
There's got to be something else!
Number 3 on the back of the uniform
that would indicate a seat under Gin-sanl
1.1 got it!
There Is one. Kudo!
Hun
Another number 3.
On the back-of the uniform
Mr. Ohtakl!
Huh? Oh. Hei-chan!
Did you figure out the code.?
Yeah
The first 47 stands for Gin-san,
the next 3 in the parenthesis is
The one wearing the number 3
on the back of his uniform
The Ba Bruce monument!
Which means that
the location of the 2nd cell phone is
The location of this monument is. * »
Slightly left from the center
In other words
Under Gin-sen]
Slightly left from the conter
behind the back net
and a seat in the 4th aisle!
Cheers
W.What,is"it?!
What's up!
The player made 1st base
because the catcher fumbled!
But. we've got to hurry!
It's two outs already
There's only 1 more out to go!
Ball!
UL}!
Two three!
It's the bottom of the 6th inning
It's two out
with a runner on first
base because of a fumble!
Count two three!
If this butter walks
in line 1s Konan's big slugger.
Who scored a homerun
+ Okay. the pitcher gets«athold of - himself
from set position,
throws his 6th ball!
ThellsalixSioeO NE it!
It's 2 foul fly
It's a foul fly.
But the ball flies
in front of the Konan bench by 1st base
The catcher stops going after the ball
The pitcher!
KOH 1
The. pitcher!
OMY I?
The pitcher goes nfier;the ball
and dashes into the Kénan bench!
The pitcher goes after the ball
and dashes into the Konan bench!
The .pitcheregoes after the ball
and dasifesiinto: the Konan bench!
The pitcher goes ffian these} >
and dashes into the Konan b fhchiu a!
Is the pitcher all right?
Bi. Hoe caught the bill!
2 a AR
The fantastic play of the pitcher'and
it's three out change!
WwW. Wow!!!
Talk about reckless.
If wonder if all boys are that way...
wonder if all boys are that way...
Huh?!
His is indeed the finals of the Koshien!
The passion that the players
display towards thé'ball.
Can't help touching
the hearts of all who are watching!
Fun, fuh, fuh.
He . ou stup dridiot!
"Row gong Lo find
the. 3rd cell phoneright away
and get a hold of where youfare,
SO you can look forward to me
getting to you real soon you fool!
Me hung up without saying anything.
Cote foo (ili CAF IR (RICK Gr vi
You know the Takano Transport case
Yeah.
According to what my superior told me,.
the truck of that company ran over
a person a month age in To « 0,
and it seemed one person died
Maybe that accident has fy
something to do with this?
Yeah, but what does that
have to do with Koshien?
1.1 still don't know but...
Well. never mind
Let's just nab the guy
EXnko] Ext lllan elxARA
We already know
how to decipher the code so
W.What's this?!
('1
@Only the number of aisle is written here.
Hiroshi...
Why?!
Why is only. the aisle number
Maybe it's because you shouted at him
furiously -on the phone a while ago?
I'm going to:fipd the
3rd cell phone right-away
and get a hold of where youfare
SO you can look forward to me
getting to you real soon you fool
Darn!
He hung up without saying anything
If the guy's saying that he's going to
commit suicide using a bomb,
it'sot surprising that
he'd get pissed at what you said
um 000G in UM) xdun my
Fool!
If he was one to get upset
over something like that
he would've pushed the switch
for the bomb long ago
, andithe stand"somewhere here
would be in badatrouble!
There's some kind of meaning to it
The blank in this code...
It's Indicating some stand. of Koshien here!
But. what an odd.guy
wibhe really wants to commit suicide
why would heygive out complicated clues
and make people look for where he is?
Maybe he wants somebody to stop him?
Huh?
I'm sure that
person's hoping deep down
in his heart that somebody will stop him
An dimaybe
he doesn't even realize it himself
He wants somebody to stop him?
Because the code that he thought up
cannot be made unless he's
interested in Koeshien or baseball
It's hard to believe that such a person
would want to do something like that
at Koshien
much less use a bomb to commit suicide,
night?
I guess so.
Then. Mr. Ohtaki
Huh?!
Please call the Hyogo Prefect-urea! police
once more
and ask them for more
detailed information
about the traffic accident a month ago
that Takano Transport. the company.
The man set fire
with a bomb to was involved in?
Also want to know
what the motive of a baseball fan
who would do something
Iike this at Koshien is too
Okay
Then, shall we
think about this code
and look through
the seats ih the 13th row?
Just look at each and every seat
until the time limit
when the bottom of the 9th inning ends.
Era) ), [k AP,
Who know whether there.ll be
a bottom of the 9th inning or not though.
I see
Unless Ohgane.who Is
batting first, catches up
or wins the-score
the top of the 9th inning
will be the end of the game.
The pitcher gets into set position
Aaagh. he 3rd runner has dashed off!
It's a squeeze!
It's a short fly in front of the pitchor
It's: a short fly in front of tho pitcher
H He caught the ball!
He caught it!
It's a direct catch by the 3rd!
\ evan
The ball goes to 3rd base
and it-s~a double play!
Home base is far-foriOhgane High School!
It's the top off the 8th inning and
though they've-establish opportunities.
They haven't scored a point yet!
The score is still 0-1.
It is the bottom of the 8th inning
and Konan High School will be batting...
Yes.
Huh?!
+, A high school student?!
Are you sure that
he one who was run over
by the truck. of Tlakane Transport wns
a highschool student?
Yeah!
I was in.change- of that accident
together with a.colleague
who was appointed
to the Metropolitan police in Tokyo
I asked for all Kinds of details
Oh. here it is.
I'm sure that you would know
since you like high school baseball. right?
The name Hiroshi Torimitsu.
In the first game
during the spring selection .
The left hander of
Teito Jitsugyo High school
who threw 18 extended games
along with Ohgane's ace.
But lest by a close game...
D.Donat tell me... it was that boy?
(AR!
Seems to have dashed out into the road
after baseball club practice
and was run over.
Well. it seems that the boy's bicycle was
moving unsteadily to begin with...
Well, it seems that the boy's bicycle was
moving unsteadily to begin with.
'Y1u'nx=idhiiux~1 niinwxllrik 1mm lbw?! lhxwrwm
(ONAN oxt=xef dodge) BESS El
Yeah. come to think of it
the whereabouts of the boy's
father have been unknown
so they were having problems
Not being able to ask gq 1estions
Don't tell me that
Father
I'm going to give it my best- shot
I'm going to do oven baottor
during the summer Koshien
become a professional,
and mam money,
so that you won't havo to worksthat hard
You can count on me
Hiroshi
Hey Kudo. did you find it?
No, it:s nowhere
It seems that it's nowhere in the seats
of the 13th aisle behind this back net.
arm!
Why 1s everything clse*besidos 13 blank?!
The least he could do 1S write the number
on back of the uniform in parenthesis!
Hei)
Maybe it«s that?
See! There's a player with no number
on the bk of his unitormaneat the bench
Huh? Yeah
the ball boy. right?
I thought so too
I checked the seats on the 18th aisle
behind both benches.
But found nothing.
Then, all that's left are
the Alps stand or outfield seats
Strike! Batter out!
Called,out on strike. two out!
Ohgane High School's tie runner
cannot budge an inch from 2nd .base.
Konan High School is only one player
away from winning the championship!
N.No good!
If the game ends
the man's going to blow himself up!
Darn
We don't have time Yo go around
the Alps stands nor the outfield seats!
What Is this?
Why is there nothing written ?!
That fact that nothing is written
Azoro? Nothing? White?
He hit the ball!
An interesting ball that goes up left!
Can he catch it?!
Can he pull through?!
WI I the scores be reversed?!
Will the game end ?!
Don't catch the ball you idiot!
Coie 2283
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIMWKA
Background Moisic
ST hoe PG ¢s CIP) Dw
C 11racter Designs by.
MASATOMO SUDO
WNW sug abe
LOCI. IIIUI
Iory . ciltor.
JUNICHI 11 + KA
A000 SEEM mB
Scr p s 8)
RANI KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUGH],
JUNICHI MIYASHIITA
YUICHI HIGURE}
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation) Dir ctors.
MASATOMO SUDQ@
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO: KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Diréctor.
Ox YUKIHIRD SFIBUIANI
Directo Of Photography
TAKAHISA- OWA AP
Recordins Director.
KATSUYOSHIKWBAYASHI
Forage 8
=» A Fev is BC » . *
2 PJ aed
KINJI KODAM,
Produced By.
TMX ENTERTAINMENT, LTD.
In association with
YOMIURI TEDECASTIN(
CORPORATION
DETECTIVE CONANT
a GONHO AOYAMA SHOCARURANY TV IMA
All Rights Reserved