TA @ fA RN
He hit towards 3rd base!
It's a long ball...
Fast! The one who hit the ball is fast!
Ho left fielder sure Is taking his timd./*\
Iithink the runner's going to
make it to 3rd base. don't you?
(yo! Go!
Go! Go!
Left! Left
Just what do:you think you'rc doing?!
Aalt...
Aah.
on IWII
Safe]
No out third base...
I guess them
scoring a point can't be helped
No. you can't tell yet.
That pitcher sure got guts...\
A cell phone?
Was itthere from before?
Maybe the man who passed
by here awhile ago dropped it...
by Where a~while¥ago dropped it.
Let me see
Oh, hello? Are you the one
who dropped this cell phone?
Yeah
Then come to the rght stand...
Having fun?
Huh?
If'?
I'm asking you
if this place is such an enjoyable place?
Who are you?
If it'sOkay with you,
Iet's play an even more enjoyable game...
it's way more fun than this baseball game.
An exchange of lives
that will make your blood stir...
Well, it is an exchange of lives,
but the one who's going to die is me
kugh.kugh=KUOh¢.
You idiot!
If you want to die. go and die on your own!
Yeah. I'll do that .
But, I can't die alone...
Being alone is much too lonely...
What?!
The rule is simple...
Each time the 3rd. 6th and 9th innings end
avg the cell phono that have Vet
somewhere on this baseball ground
I'll ring the cell phone that I have left
somewhere on this baseball ground...
I will ring my cell phone
that will be the clue to where I am...
I will be near the phone
that will ring 'after the game ends...
I will ring only 3 times...
If you don't answer by then
it's 3 out and game set...
Of course if you gather all the cell phones
* before they ring. and find 1
before the,Jame end's
It's your win...
Hey, you gotta be Kidding,
cut out your stupid talk!
I'm hanging up!
Kugh. kugh. kugh...
you'll find out whether I'm kidding or not
after, he end of
the bottom of the 2nd inning
HM Hoy, just what do you méanby that...?
So. . your first clue as what is written
in the mail of the cé'll phone...
Yes... tell that police detective
sitting next to you
that I'm looking forward to seeing him too...
Okay then...catch you later...
Wait up! At least tell me your name!
Me...?...Me...
The Demon off oshien.
You can call me that...Fuh. fuh, fuh .
T.The Demon of Koshien.
H.Hey. you...
Ay grt
Strike! Batter out!
Okay!
Is the bottom of the 2nd inning finished ?
It still one out!
What's with you Heiji,
aren't you watching the game?
7. 44
The strike out ball just NOW was »
a very fast ball!
I found it!
He oR.
3, 7, le
hat's that?
The telephone number of the whereabouts
of the owner of this telephone...
What's that?
Why doesn't he.come « et it himself!
I wonder what it is'. though? 96. 7, 13 .
I wonder what it is. though? 96. 7. 13 .
It doesn't seem like @ seat number...
ho IR XO Xm MG Fax Lo ne
Enough of codes!
Thanks to anwodd code we ended up
not being able to\go to Takarazuka so...
Hmm~... If it's 8, 1, 2 it's the Alps stand.
A. Alps stand?!
Huh?
Why. dad...?
Because 8. 1, 2 as pronounced Heads.
And Held is
connected With tho Alps. fight!
Aha ha ha, Ra .
Oh, COCH /
Aha. ha. please-dad .
Oh well! Please'hclp us find him then
Oh well! Please help us find him then
Huh? But this is the best part...
Don't worry, we'll be done right away
if you come with us, Mr. Ohtaki!
Huh? Are you going too. Conanr?
Yep! Because it sounds like fun!
V44 I
Well, don't worry! We'll give it to the owner
Pars
and come right back...
oife 7
What's with him?
He's the joneswho wanted
to come here with us
Really.
Fifi
bs W. What? S.Suicide?!
HeLchan?!
Yeah! He saying that
If we don't find it before
tho ond of tho gama, ho's going to dio!
He says he'll kill someone
along with himself too!
But. maybe it's just a prank.
Nk. . It's most likely not a prank
The one who called... ~
didn't chan je his voice...
And tho manufacture number s00!
Was pasted on the cell phone too...
This all means that ho doesn't mind
his identity+being revealed later. 1ight? 4
Moreover, he s doing something
Iike this. knowing that
you're an inspector Mr. Ohtaki,
which means that
this man must really:be desperate!
At any rate. please usu your
police badge. Mr. Ohtaki
and let me In behind he back net!
Huh? Why behind the back net?
On the phone a while go
I heard the referee call out strike .
E could still be there...
Yeah
GQ by
mo. . - -
Canit do. Hei shun. brags not
going to: dig suntil thergame ends. right.
Tho man says he'll show proof
after.the bottom of the 2nd¥inningl
W: What?!
We're going In. Mr. Ohtaki
Agh!!
If the 'cheers that we. heard
just. now was for the 3rd out...
Maybe he 5 already, dong somothing...
No good! Just as I thought
the bottom of the 2nd inning Is over.
'If!
You go down, I'll go up and Mr. Ohtaki,
please search the center!
You go down. I'll go up and Mr Ohtaki.
Please search the centeg!
He's a suspicious looking
man wearing a cap!
Oka.
Yeah
Hp 5 Sr
Damn!! He's not here after all...
But...nothing-s-happening...
The top of the 3rd inning. the batter fc
Ohgane High School is
Seki, number 9 right
nothing...
Ohgane High School is
Seki, number 9 right
Fr exam
The 3rd inning, batter for Ohgane
High School is number 9 right. Seki
Outd!
Whaaaa~~H
Hey. Hal-chem.
What's going on?
Nothing's happening?!
Mange...
The guy who called
said that he'd show evidence
{ 3 *" w Ny . , WN
after the bottom of the 2nd inning ends...
Maybe it's a prank after all?
Who'd do a thing like that
at the finals of Koshien...
I wonder what that is?
'Huh;
See. on the other side of the freeway
Hmm
What is it?
Smoke is rising...
It Woks like fire...
Iteseems to be around Tekiryokumachi
Mr. Ohtaki, you once told me
that you have a
BOC TRE) ER Ae
Hyogo Prefectural Police. right?
Y.Yeah...
Wonst You please call him and ask him?
Okay!
What?!
A BiBomb?!
Is that true Mr. KBZUHibH?
Yeah... .as for the details
I can't say for sure
I see the reportsof the firefighters after
they put out the fire,
but it seems to be so...
A companycalled Takano Transport
seems to have caught fire.
According to what the neighbors aro saying.
Before that place caught fire, a loud boom
seems to have been heard...
I see
Fortunately. that company was off today
SO there seems to have been
no casualties what so ever.
They think a bomb went
AN rere To co ay
came from a building that
was supposediyempty...
And. do you know when
the building caught fire?
Well'!
We Numaita?
Yes, sir?
You know that fire that's
being put out now...
Do you know what time it stanted
I think it was about
Just around when...
Around when the bottom
of the 2nd inning ended!!
Looks bad, Hattori... ..If the
evidence that the guy warned I's~
about over the shone was that
explosion that caused the fire
Maybe the way he's
going to commit suicide is...
M.Moron...
If he commits suicide with a
bomb in a Place like this
with so many people,
It wou d cause a grave disaster!!
Hey."O@htak:...
come to think of it, arenst you
at Koshien teday
How do you know about the fire...
Oh. well
HH. Heli-ehan, what do you want te do?
Do you want to tell the police about this?
The guy who called is saying
he's going to commit suicide
when the ball game ends" We don't
want to start useless commotion here
and end the game, because
the minute it ends we blow up!
I think it would be better to just
Iisten to what the man
has to say for now and solve
the codes one after the other.
Trace the three cell phones
and arrest the man
Eithor way, wel have to
solve the codes before
the bottom of the 3rd inning ends
and find the 1st cell phone that is hidden
somewhere in the stands of Koshien,
or we're finished'.
The top of the 3rd Inning, one out
and runners on 1st and 2nd base.
Theretis asmap of the stands: right behind
the back net of gate number 8 here
I guess I'll go outside, look at the map,
use Mm head and decipher the code...
The meaning of these fumbers*96, 7, 13!!
I'll go borrow the radio from Pops then!
We need to know
ow the games progressing,
otherwise. we'll be in trouble. right?
Yeah! Do so. will you!
Osition number 3...Pitcher...Inao
SUILIQUL JUHRIUTUILI I YD 7 oo J BHU INGE «00 o U0 UT CAWS
All right! Clean up time...
I guess this game is
going to be a long one...
Lets go. Hei-chan.
Okay
It's clean up. but the pitcher
Is not quite an control of the balm
then it'll be one out. with the bases loaded
If the runner getsito'wnlk= I
ARH then comes ther4thibatterll
Sigh
Heiji and the others sure are late .
Maybe they can't find the
owner of the cell phone yet.
If so, wi¥ don't give up already
and hurry on back here?!
The man who dropped
it is to blame. and not us .
TJEFTrMQ
Don't worry!
We'll find that man. ..for sure...
SO wait a while longer...
Conan...
Pops. will you ploase lend me your radio?
Huh?
Searching for that man
we won't be able to tell
how the game is progressing...
Okay? You'll lend it to me, right?!
I tell you...
Don't bréak it
Here ou go...
Hanks ou!
Oh. and If you see a suspicious
man wearing a white cap
call Hell on the cell phone. okay!
Oh, hey Conan?!
They look so much alike
Conan's face just now
Iooked so mueh hike him
back then...
He hit the ball!
This Is = Ok) and
NR d § /
FIOR xa U6 POE lowed)
Wha, ites) coming this way!!
I] think the ball will make it.
Thrust forward by the beach wind
t-ht-J ball flips mm the giqht stand.
H.He caught the ball!!
Ri rather UT anrasy ar sii
The ball goes pass 2nd base
Safell
Both wings 96: meters?
96.713...
3 (0 U8
Where:is it. where is it...?
I'm sure that it's indicating
the seats somewhere here...
Hei-chan, we'd better hurry
or we'll run out of time...
Where tho-Hall is it?!
Hell!
Heijil!
I borrowed the 'radio!!
How's the game going?
The top of the 3rd inning just finished,
and the score's still zero-zero!
Hree outs left...
You know what is there such
a wing in this ball field?
Pp because heard them sa . Koshie
with both wings 96 meters on the radio...
You really don't know a thing
about baseball. do you...?
Well, they don't say
both wings in other games
so I guess it can't be helped. but...
Kiddo...Both wings 96 meters
means that the distance
from the home base
to the pole is 96 meters.
D.Don't tell me that this code
The first 96 means...
the seats by the end of the pole?
But which way. Hei-ehan??
There are poles
on both sides. the right and left!
Then...maybe the next number 7
in parenthesis means something?
1 voooll sonoll, 00
(I sovoll sodel dose
Ov _A nS
hall oth
three strikes and one out!
Kiddo.
Ll ///
turn your back on me!
Huh?
I.Like this?
I see!
You see what... .Hel-chan?
The number of the outfit
the boy's wearing is 55. not 7...
Right the number on the back:of the outfit!
In high school baseball.
Where is the player wearing number 77!
Umber 7 is left field...
H Which means, Hal-chew...
Aaagh! In other words its the
seat at the end of the left pole!
T. Then, what about the last 137
I ool BOER On 10 JOE CHAN
The first cell phone is there!!!
It's the bottom of the 3rd inning
The two batters of Konan High School
struck out three times
in a row and now with 2 outs.
Struck out three times
The next batter Is umber 1 left, Iwata...
He pitcher flings his arms high
IA order to throw his first ball
Strikem~~I
Straight in high!
The pitcher throws his
2nd ball in good rhythm...
Trike two...
Outlaw another straight!
El vooo
d LULL
25...
The pitcher flings up his arms
VOooooo
19...
Three strike outs...
$600000
(QR.
He has thrown the ball)
$1830
Over hero!!
Strike out!!
Don't answer it!" Give it to me!!!
Don't answer I!!! Give it to me!!!
(ROWS Paco JMS
Kughnkugh.kugh.kughH.
Kugh. kugh, kug Wkugh .
Hey you'll What's so funny...
Kugh. kugh, kugh...
It's really interesting...
You kids sure are interesting...
Iang in there a while longe
and entertain me. will you?
I love to see people making
futile effort. Kugh, kugh. kugh...
Hold it. you!
Hey! Hello? Hello?
Barn! He hung up.
He. look!
The next code is onthe display...
Q7/0000
iii,
and 4... eh...
Ny! 00000
futile effort.
There Isn't a tinge of worth!
In making any effort...
In making any effort .
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Pro dac=y
Background Mus ¢
Character DesignsyBy.
00ers SEN O
80000Q¢I SW)! @
fory -citor
WNW Bam an
\ @ . -% » > <
KANILKASHIWABARA
KAZONARI K~
- JUNTCHI MI A_HITA
F Sal hioJ
Anthatiog@irg yrs 9
M SA OM0.5U
7.1.
Art - Dire ctor.
Ox YUKIHIROSHIBUIANI
¥en)
D176 tors:of Photography.
KASHIPN OM
> > TN » 8 > ~ ,
TAKAHISA-OWAGAO
Record img Dire tor.
> , Tr on cw» «e b »> » AY -
- - > 5 v F
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENT KOIDANM
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, ID.
HigrssorTihion wilh
YOMIURI'TELECASTINC
CCRPORATION
DETLCTIVE CONAN
GONHO AMWAMA SHOCAKUKAN YTV IMA
Rig his Reserved