faC6d 0560 a dr
E Clans 6 ¢ ar Cm
Konan High School is only one player
away from winning the championship!
N.No good! If thc game ends
the man's going to blow himself up!
Darn! Waoidont have tine te go around
the Alps stands-nor the outfield seats!
WA = is Roles in Ties (ae: ta Solin) wad Gil
Thatifact that nothing is written
A zero? Nothing? White...
[RIO Wl @o (oll
An interesting ball that goes up left!
Can he catch it?!
Can he pull through?!
Will the. scorn 8 berreversed *!
Will the game end?!
Dont Cn no Dall wow gall
alae
He missed the ball, he missed!
Okay! It's a 'tie!
Missed?
Wait a sec if I'm not mistaken
While the ball goes traveling outfield, I
the batter-runners,go from.2nd to 3rd. base...
Huh?
H.Hey. Kudo?! What's up'...
The runner dashes out from 3rd base!
The ball goessfrom
from hoollwp to back home!
Safe!
AA running homorun
Fantastic. wow!
They reversed the score!
Oh. Hel-chan, what's up?!
D.Did you find out about something?
Ask this kiddo here...
Huh...?!
See. look at this map...
HKOSHIEN > TAD!
See. look. at this map
KOSHIEN STADI
KOSHIEN 1
As to the entrance*of-thexstadium...
there are entrance from number 1 to 24
As to the entrance of the stadium...
but tho numbors 17 and 22 arc missing!
Missing...? Number of the entrance...
Number 17 and...
Number 22...
Yeah. .that's true...
The reason there's no code number
Is probably because of this...
Now that you mentioned it, I heard that
they blocked off gate number 12 and 22
to make some kind of facility...
But which onc is it? 17 ot 22
where do we look?,
We've no choice...
Let's start from number 17...
Wait!
We don't seem to have that much time...
Now for the grand finale...
This is the bottom of the 9th inning
with two out no runner!
Ohganc High School lcads by ono point
The next batter is...
the one known for his three hits
three base hits and one homer.
Number 4... 3rd.
Number 4... 3rd...
Numbor 4... 3rd.
They're going to pick:on the weak point
ind make him walk
rbjsnhe only one who's fiad hits too...
They don't want to risk him striking a hit
and lose the game after all this
AGAR ND Wis =n 200e@O 4 VR
Hey. hey is this the end of the game?
Those two are...just like Shinichi after all
\Huh ? Just like?
Just like Shinichi back in Jr High School
during the soccer championship game.
It was lost time with the other team
Ieading by 1 point...
With less than a minute to go
the other team scored another point
so It seemed to be over
Shinichi was; wearing
when returning the ball to the center.
I looked through the omega glass.
Then I saw him laughing...
Laughing?
Yeap, I asked tho other boys
of the soccer club later and
you know what he was saying
while laughing?
What? What?
Fuh, fuh...
I tell you, that guy
Cool...if we win, we'll be legend...
Wow... awesome...
And? How'd the game turn out?
Right. right!
They lost... after all.
Ha. ha, ha,
Ilfeisawot that easy. you see!
During the Penalty Kick
Huh?!
Which means.
Right.
With a minute left,
and Shinichi's goal and assistance
they somehow made it to penalty Kick
But. in the end"it-was Shinichi
who didn't make-the penalty kick too
ut his rear view
after that looked a bit cool .
bat mow, mind you'd, just aa bat
And... Shinichi back then.
Those two kind of resembled] um
I. mean. they refuse to give up
The childish character
of not wanting to losc
I wonder if Heiji is that way tee
Yep Wm sure he's
Strick two!
He swung at air! Two nothing!
Bad! They've been cornered!
No good. we won't make it
Mr Ohtaki
In baseball, you never can tell
until the very last minute!
If you have time thinking
of something useless like that
hurry and think of the meaning
of the code. will you!
Yeah, but. I mean really
Big slugger of Konan ls cornered!
Will he be able to pull the game
out of the fire?!
Nagashima?
Aright! The missing number!
What?
There was no number in the parenthesis
because it's a retired number!
Retired number?!
Between gates 21 and 23
there is a,booth for "professional team «¢
whos'. home ground is Koshlien
And there's a reference library
where that retired number is displayed!
Hehchan
isrvtftheaazarea between 21 and 23 the plwcej
where we were Lo begin with,
the right stand?
Muh?likant
Darn! You monn: she can hear the phone
because of the applause?
Pitcher Inao!
This Is his 100th ball... There it goes!
Ho hit the ball!
Did it go up too high?!
You fool!
The center spreads his arms out wide
and is waiting for the ball to come his way
Konan High School. is it over for them!
Don't catch. don't catch!
Here goes, Hiroshi
Dont cateh it! Don't catch it!
I'm go over to your place
Dont! catchsthie ball!. Don't catch it!
The pitcher is Inao!
This Is his 100th throw this game
There goes the ball
Up goes the ball!
Is it too high?!
Fool!
The center spreads his hands out wide
He gets ready to catch the ball
MIR « for Wott noo Sokol
Don:t-'catch it! Don't catch it!
Here goes. Hiroshi
Don't catch it!1'"Don't catch it!
I'm going over to where you-are
The Ohgane nine are overjoyed
because victory seems near!
The cantar 1s still in position
to catch the ball
and backsfoff slowly
He still backs off
He made it! He did it! It's a homerun!
W's allel Alle!
[OA REC Snel, F000 offen OF Ho
9th inning at the very last minute
with 2 outs, thanks to their big,
slugger Nagashima
ties their opponent with a score of 2=21
That high fly.
VE 90 Re
NV DN:
What's this?...
What the hell's going on?!
Dead ball]
Two players in a row!
Ohgane"s ace Inao,
suddenly pitches out of control!
Is the homerun a while ago,
affecting him after all?!
That's why they should've
Iet number 4 walk
He puts on airs
gets hit and goes out of control,
talk about getting worked up...
This Is going to be a walk-off homer
- XArtuxaA*s CLUE A fire
All right!
What's with that pitcher .
The game is 2-2 and will be extended!
What's this sound
Oh. behind your feet, Kazuha...
Huh?
The cell phone again
I tell you
Shall weranswer it?
HHeijw!
I found the last cell phone!
Come on, and show yourself!
H.Helji?!
The game's not evor yet.
It's an. extended game
It's an extended game')!
Yeah...
(Demon of Koshien favors
showing itself just before game sets
H He 2
He says it's an extended game
but the next code is nowhere!!!
Darn!
Mr. O@htaki please look for him!
I'm sure hers still somewhere around here!
O,Okay!
M. Mails'
I'll look to the right, so please
take care of the left, Mr Ohtaki
Okay"
Will.
It-s@@O Ss
we don't need to look for.him anymore
Just as expected of the finals of Koshien!
It's a great game!
Phooey
This isn't such a great place
Right...
1 you guys didn't root
cncourago andsechoar him on hike that
If, If this place didn't exist
My son wouldn't have...
Oops!
He dropped the ball #heydropped it!
He dropped an ordinary catcher's fly!
CRREGY AE HIE Sei ANY Wa
the bottom of the 10th
f inning as If possessed
\} by tho Demon of Koshien!
YL AW,
1 Ad»
waft LAN
I acod up against an irregular hit,
fielders choice and error along with
two outs and bases lo: ded
0 exe I) OX Yl
Si Moreover. the next batter is
number 4
Nagashlma!
They're really up against the wall
The Ohgane nine gather on the mound!
The disappointed catcher:who had
dre) ed the ball cannot lift his head
Of course he can't.
Made a blooper
in front of a large crowd like this
The other nine menibers of the team at.
Will hold a grudge against him,
nd the player as well 1s his parents,
siblings and even his rclatives
Will face embarrassment...
Just for something like this
They're laughing
That pitcher's Inughing...
Really?
They split running to (heir positions
with smiles on their faces
Ma ha ha...
it cant be
How can they keep laughing?
Why. at this stage!
Because this is baseball.
You can't play baseball
unless all nine members are there
I'm sure that
the pitcher of Ohgane Is thinking
for himself as well as for the team
and for the catcher who made an error.
That he's going to slug this ball
even if his arms break!
He hit the ball!
» Bul the ballkveceged shghtly
Well, the number 4zthat follows
also probably wants to send, the runner
to home. so he's stepping out
and pitching the ball the way he is,
even if the ball may hit him
Although no one knows
which team will win yet
A Absurd
If they go out of their way ind get hurt
they can't become professionals!
They could be throwing
their whole life away. you know!
BR, v=
What the hell is there to this Koshien?!
Devastingl!"
It's a right this time!!
It's a foul! Another big foully
There's nothing
Of course. I think there are ny any Kids?
Here who want to stand #
tt)?
and become professionals. #
But. that's all before thefgamo
@Once you set foot on the field
and hear the voice playball
for those kids out there
it's a battlefield of
whether you winor lose!
Strike out
With three players left on base,
no points have been scored 4
«e Ne
/NI Hinx=n 2 via m8 8 ko ks Wwdli,, Wad, Ved
«e Le
and win the championship...
They have no feelings of profit
or loss at'this time
It's just a very simple feeling
And, since you've been.
Involved with baseball
you should already know of things like this