Today marks the 10th year
for the Detective Conan Series.
Inthe firstTepisode. of
Ik CORMOmOU IO Ax Yr
of all things,
Pop's becomes the target of a sniper!
He sees through theione and only truth J w=
A childin Z'ppearance
with the IQ. of an adult
No.cnse I1s-left.unsolved «
WI 3p 6 ecCive ~onan
Oops. oops
Are you all right?
Shall I go flag a cab down?
I'm just.
Fine! Oops...
Thanks for the service and goodnight.
Take care and goodnight.
Oops
Aaaghn...?!
Hmm?!...
Huh?!
Hey, watch out! You're lucky it was me,
cuz I was able to dodge it...
The Target is Kogoro Mourl!
Hey!" Stay still...
Ou OY, OW
It stings, Ran! Can't you do it
a bit more gently and softly or what
{m moon"
It's nothing to make
such a big deal out of, Dad.
A little sting won't kill you!
I've got to go and caution the person
In charge of the construction. tomorrow!
Huh 2
Who could it be.: at this time of night...?
Hmm? Oh,
it's mall
What?!
Dad. what's up?
Huh?
1l rn MM EA ho,
I'll kill you for'sure "It snys.
Em , Ce
SP my
#4 Fa
What?!
Does this mean,
that it was no accident. but something
that happened with the intent to kill?
What 1 dirty rat.
The culprit was ambushing me there...
Dad, don't you have any idea
who it could be?
who nil cwuld be?
Dad. don't you have any idea
who it cull be?
No. not the slightest!
Well...l guess you can't really say that
there's no one
who has a grudge against me...
You think someone repaid
your kindness with a grudge?
Yeah, (if so-we'll find.outrsoon who it is.
The:culprit-most .alwaysthas aimotive.
This timeilit's a grudge against me.
If I search for those
who have a grudge against me
it'll inevitably lead togthe culprit.
Hey...this cell phone is not yours, Dad...
What. show it to me .
True
Hey! This jacket isn't yours either. Dad!
What?!
There's a name on It... Kimura
Ingother words, this cell phone is not yours,
but rather of someone call Kimura!
NC YIMeans. 1s mal was no sen oO me.
Which means thissmnil was; ot sent to me
Which means this mailiwas not sent to me.
Oh! So that's the story...No fun!
Hey! Just where do you think you're going?!
Yawn--I'm going to sleep
There you go!
What?!
- - <*
Ouch!
C.Conan?!
What a sight...
Hey... what do you think, Conan?
You mean if there's an thine
besides the fact that Pop's life is in danger
because he mistakenly
ore Mr. Kimura's jacket.
And the killer mistook Pops
to be Mr. Kimura?!
Yep... Right,
Ill-try and call Dad's cellphone!
I wonder what kind of person the owner of
the cell phone Mr. Kimura is...
Theres... NO answer...
This is unmistakably Mr. Kimura's jacket...
Did Mr. Kimura come last night?
He came when Mr. Mouri
was asleep over there.
I think Wt was around 01:00.
And... where Is this Mr. Kimura living...?
I rook, era Olh X00] OTR) Or
recently, so...
AS for me, I found out his name f
rom his signature on this bottle...
Oh. is that so...
Reverb
I'm sure he'll show up sometime soon.
Let's forget about this for a'while,
Do you have the you know what?
The hand-made cheese that
this master makes is super spicy
It blows up your cells,
makes your body hot and sweaty.
If so, one should refrain from eating
too much of it. but that's just not possible
That's how good it is.
See.
So that's why he took off his jacket...
After checking the cell phone
that-sent out:the mall lat night.
We found that it was registered
under a false name.
And, from last night up to
now there have been no accidents
or incidents in which a man
by the name of Kimura has been involved.
It's probably just some prank...
The polic are busy so you shouldn't
cause them extra problems..«Ran.
B.But.
Besides, they're not after me,
but rather a man named Kimura.
The culprit made a mistake
But if the culprit doesn't realize that
he's making a mistake.
he'll go after your life again.
That's what Ran is worried about.
Poof... Officer Takagl don't take what a kid
Iike her is saying too seriously...
Bar "Lemon"... You sure go looking:ifori all
kinds of 'places to drink, don't you ?
About a:week ago. I got this
1 Year Opening Anniversary Free
All You Can Drink Service Coupon.
So I went to check the place out.
They served this super spicy hot cheese
along with the drinks.
Since I've Kind of been hooked on
spicy hot stuff lately.
I got hooked on this place. you see!
Officer Takagi!
Here's been an eye-witness report.
Last night astudontTliving,
near the construction site...
says (he saw a man running from's
the scene right-after the-steel-pipes fell.
He says he didn't..get a good look
at the face of the man though...
However, the culprit seems to have had
a burn wound on his right elbow.
Do you have any idea
who the man could be?
who the man could be
Do:you have any idea
who the 'man could be?
Unfortunately...there were
no other suspicious fingerprints,
or anything elsesat the site
Which means, you'll have to,find Mr. Kimura
and trace things-from therd.
Dad! You're talking like
it's someone else's problem.
But...what it all boll's down to is...
I'm not Mr. Kimura.
This all happened
because you went to bar Lemon!
Pops! Unless we hurry,
the man called Kimura may be
and get into bigger trouble next time.
Mr. Kimura...
Since-the size of this jackét
fits. Dadsjust right.
I think he has the same type
of ph sique-as Dad...
Have you ever kept his jacket for him?
Here no such person at our shop...
I 888...
Huh?!
Look out!
Ran!
D.Darn!
Hold it there!
A burn...on his right elbow?!
So#the truck:-was a stolen onezafter-all...
Which means it was a planned attempt.
I think so too
What's up. Mr. Mouri?
Fu TRY
FL TET
114!
we Owe
[2.0] 3
Inspector! The laundryishopiowner
has completed beingjtreated!
They say he'll be discharged!
In Wo.0Or. ree cays
How: dare he get others
who aren't involved into danger!
Mr. Mouri, just where do you plan on going?
Where:else. but to nablthe guy!
Come on, you dons even know where he's
Just where.do you plan to look for him?!
M.Mr. Mouri...
Wj vo GUBOOD PI (ead) milan Wad Ti Gay ORY
Just what are you talking about!
Please stay in one place
until we find the: culprit!
They're right. somebody's-after-you life, %
you 'know...
I can~t do that!
I, Kogoro Moun, as woll-known as I am,
cannot do such a simpaorning,
whimpering sort of thing...
Come off it! You don't have to
bluff courage... Right. @onan...
Ahaxha...
Huh?! Bluff courage?!
You actually think I'm bluffing courage
or what?! Y.You gotta be kidding!
Somebody's after my life you say?!
Oh! Just great!
What better chance could there be?
As long as we don't know
whothis Kimura guy is.
I'll serve as decoy and lure the culprit out!
Wait a minute! Just what do you think
you're saying Mr. Mouri?!
I'can-t stop him.if I keep on hiding!
Okay!
Huh?! In.Inspector!
But, I'm going to have those two serve
as our bodyguards
iNo:way! Itill.only put the culprit on guard
fhe finds out:and he won't show himself...
No! Going out alone is much too dangerous
"hate to say this inspector,
but cant listen to you thisdime...
I, Kogoro Moeuri: cannot bear and
don't want any more victims
resulting from getting mixed up
in what I am...
But, if anything should happen to me.
DIOERE F190 a= AF wh Roe
to be done after that.
M/Mr. Mouri
Syltsseomed to have the.opposite effect .
He's quite defiant...
So... what we've got to do now is
to find the person called Kimura!
Yes, sir
Let's go! Officer Takagi!
O Okay!
He's been walking!
Around for the past three da s...
Yes. sir... And, what about.this Mr. Kimura?
He's looking for the man
doing everything he can but...
If the motive of the culprit is
a grudge against Mr. Mouri.
I guess he'll eventually get the guy.
But the thing is, he's being sought
after mistaken for a man named Kimura
and her-has' no idea
who or where this Kimura person is.
Moreover, after two attempted tries
on Mr Mouri's life
the culprit left nothing behind,
not even fingerprints.
I really hate to say this, but at present
we re up the creek without a paddle.
Fingerprints... .He didn't want to get nabbed
from his fingenprints?...
So, tho culprit's fingerprints
are already registered
y, Which means, this person has an arrest
record. .'One who knows' Pops well...
He has no motive against Pops
\NA=IR £2) ON
If the culprit knows Pops
and has met himsbefore...
It.It could be that...
This is Mouri...Long time no see.
I'd like to ask you something...
about a.certain. ¢1se that
I solved in, the 'past...
What's all the noise.outside
Come on out!
I"Know that you're hiding over there!
Advise you to come out
before I crush you to a pulp!
There's nothing to think about, is there?!
Resign yourself and come on out!
Or else. vm going to.come get you!
N.No. please don't! Please forgive me!
I'm sorry... Il will return what I stole...
Huh. what the? What's going on?
You're fantastic after all, Dad
It's a robber. good job!
Huh ..Gah. ha. ha...
A case in which luck
and coincidence overlapped...
Why-don't you rest a while, Conan...
I woider=ifsthatiperson-called Kimura
not onlyresembles dad iniphysique.
but looks alike, too...
Because don't they say that
there are three people
=> Ff
WA (ter GIO 0M Orde fling) IR folks Woke?
Aha, ha
Three people with a face like his?
People who look alike .
Yes, I got a call from Mr. Kimura's wife, wg
ind it seems
she finally realized that her husband was
wearing the wrong jacket... l
Talk about.easygoing...
Mr. Kimura seems, to have gone out to
take pictures. which is his hobby. Yes. sir...
And, Mr. Mourn,
Mrs. Kimura just happened to say...
that a strange man
was checking out their house., \
He-had-a wound on higsiright elbow?!
And. where is Mr. Klmura?
Lake Beika?!. Tithe strange man is
trailing him... Okay. it's very likely
Huh, are you going there too, Mr.«Mouri?!
I think that's dangerous...
What a short-tempered man. 5
Money. * ?
Yep! I dropped it
and It went under the car...
Okay! I'll move the car and look for it
Really?! I'm glad... Thank you!
Just as I thought...
Pp WY
Manicure?!
I found it!
Thank you, sir!
Inspector? Tihisvis Kogoro.
Iwe fond out where Mr. Kimura is...
WwW. What'!
Mr. Kimura 'where are you.
Please answer me~Mr. Kimura~!
Hey. it's cold here, so hurry up
and show yourself-Come on...
Yes, this is Kogoro...
Oh. Inspector!
I've found out where Mr. Kimura is
He's by the thicket.
And, Mr. Mouri, take care not te catch cold
>6C8US8l S CO <...
A.Acchool
Hurry! Quick!
Mr Kimura~! Mr. Kimura~I
Mr. Kimura~I
Inspector!
Isn't hat Mr. Mourl on board that-boat?
It's Mr. Mouri. all right!
He's out there in clear view
with nothing to protect-him!
He has no chance against the sniper!
Talk about reckless!
Inspector! On the left side of the lakeside
opposite here. something glittered.
WwW. What?! It's a r.rifle...
It could be the rifle of the sniper
who is after Mr. Mouri's life! Hurry. Takagi.
Yes. sir!
Mr. Mouri~I
Mr: Mouri!
Save Mr Mouril! Hurry, on the double!
Yes, sir!
Officer Takagi. go get the boats.
I'll go ask for support
Mure 1
We've got to save him no matter what!
Will both of you come with me?
Inspector!
Huh?! C.Conan...
Where's Pops? I
Inspector M@gure...
We found this...uh...in"the water.
And?
We could not locate Mr. Mouri. though...
The man from Bar Lemon.
YesOwl suddenly got a call
from Mrs. Kimura.
And co ldn't"-make out
the address she gave me...
I thought I had to relay the message
to Mr. Mouri as soon as possible so...
I had no idea that
things would turn out like this...
Acchoo!
Ugh~it sure gets cold)
when the sun goes down... Mr. Kimura~!
M.Mr. Mouril You're okay!
Huh? I picked this up...
I get it! You put a dummy
on board the boat and...
Yes. yes. you tried to lure the sniper out...
I'm so glad yes,
you are Indeed Kogoro Mourl!
What about Mr. Kimura...?
Did you find him...
aha. Aaaaa...
Inspector,
you don't have to worry about him!
W.What do you mean?
There is no such person
by the name of Kimura to begin with.
In other words, it was me. In order to
camouflage his motive towards me,
the sniper made up a character
by the name of Kimural.
Made up?!...A motive?
Yes. If I were to be killed, the police
will thoroughly investigate my surroundings
and will be able to
trace the sniper from there.
But. if I were to be killed because
I was mistaken for a man named Kimura,
it will make investigation difficult,
because there will be nothing
connecting me to this man...
Which means that
the accident at the construction site
the hit-and-run after that.
And the warning mailiof
murder:to: be carried out.
Were all camouflage
that the sniper schemed?
Do you have evidence
that he doesn't exist?!
Then. who is the sniper?!
Now; hold your horses...
Mr. Inoue, you have a briefcase
In our car. don't ou?
Could we have a look at it?
Y.Yes. go ahead...
I'll go get it...
It's In the trunk...
By the way, Mr. Inoue. ..You used the
free service coupon.and provided only!
With all kinds of services,
and made me frequent our shop.
Waiting for an opportunity.
Huh?!
When I fell-asleep. after getting drunk
you exchanged the jacket and cell phone
that ou had prepared beforehand. for mine.
No. aMr. Kimura really came and.
Came, drank and went home?!
He drank water you mean?
The contents of
Mr. Kimura's bottle. was water...
Inspector! I found it...
he rifle that fired at me...
D.Do you have proof that I fired it?!
In that dummy over there
you can find the bullet of a rifle
In its left chest. If you match the bullet.and
the traces that the bullet left behind...
and if the rifle mark matches
it will serve as immovable evidence.
But, have no motive
to go after Mr. Mouri's life!
You do. You have a-grudge against me.
Please look throughrthe file. Conan!
Yes, sir! Here you are!
What's this...
The grudge that you have
against me for arresting ou.
That picture is of you, back then.
After serving time
you got yourself plastic surgery
and I don't know how you did it
but you also changed your family register
mMnesHecalme 1 d ercn person...
Mr. Hiroshi Ukita!
This is your real name,
If you insist that I'm wrong %
Iet's have youfremove the manicure
you have on your fingers
withiinail polish remover and
tr matching our fingerprints!
I finally got-myself a-girifriend and
needed money to get married to her.
That was the last job I diggbut
I got nabbed by you...She left me.
I swore that once I got out, I would get back
at you for messing up my life...
Cut out; your stupid talk!
You could never become happy with money
that ou had to commit a crime for!
Don't you think that you're a fool
for trying to get back at Mr. Mourn
for your own wrongdoing,
committing an additional crime!!
Original Comic Books 3y
GOSHO AOYAMA
Produccrs
Gli) »
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
SJ) 010!
Character, Designs By.
<¢ 9  Jc
Story Editor
JUNICHI I. KA
KAN}? KASHiWABARA
JUNICHI MIVASHITA
TOSHIKI INOUI
ADhimation Directors
\ * < V Nb
ally. fx
HIROTOSHI, TAKATANI
rit O ye 2 »
AISUSHIA N 7
VJ, cut
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBU 1ANI
Directors Of 'Pho toordp hy
Ir" XSed fwd Ji
TAKAFIISA
Recording Dire 0.
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
KENJI.KODPAMA)
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD.
Hm assowtion with
YOMIURI TELE sASTING
CORPORATION
IF 1FCTIVISGONAN
6 CONIETOY MAT SHOG VAUK AN YTV IMS
ERE ay «0 wit.
You nover know whom ono like me,
being as good a detective as li .
Could become a tarc et of some sniycr
So. that's-the:stor
I tell you, he's"hopeless the one in
the class next to ours, the boy called Kitada.
Agh?! A thief...
Conan. hold my 'bag for me. will you!
Whaaal!
H.He
Huh?pD Dad?!
Huh?!-sD . Dad?!
Huh?! D.Dad?!
What're you doing dressed! like that?!
If you see any suspicious looking guy,
Iet me know right away
You'resthe one who looks most suspicious.
The client is a family of musicians.
There's 1 perfect pitch composer
among them.
Perfect. pitch...
A Stradi arms.
Pops! Park the car under that window
Hurry!
Luh 2?
Huh?
W. Wait. that's absurd...
Vvhaaa!
Cacophony of Stradivarius! Prelude