Today's stago 1s-a. musical family's mansion.
A famed musical instrument plays the
melody of murder that befalls the violinist
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the 1. Q. of an adult
No .case is eftwnsolved...
With Detective: Conan.
What'? THY; .'n'<.-':104051:,- for
Fottori Prefecture 2 What's up?
Vt raeraemad, arandtRa, ant age
the incident that happened in Okinawa,
that I was concerned about the phone call
that Mr. Motoyama was making.
He called ayplace is
Tottori called Kurayoshi...
And in the incident before that
Police Detective'Yamamura...
called a place in Tottori where
his grandmother lives called "Yazu"...
What they both have in common is
hat their area code is "0858".
Which means...?
"Have a feeling it's the same.
As the mail address that
Bellmot sent to her people.
WwW. What?!
Besides, I don't think
it's just some ordinary person.
If I remember correctly, I heard, the words
that she mumbled back then was...
Okay. boss...
Then. don't tell me that the number is...
Yeah, this number 0858 may be...
the mail address that connects to
the boss that controls all of them
Only the top four numbers
seem to be the same...
although the nuMmboers. aro
the same 0858,
I feol there is some very slight difference...
sm home
Oh. hi
Hey sRanT do-you know what this melody-is?
What's that?
Oh. a quiz that's the talk of the town now.
208,
3 PAN
w om . +
To \&
ZOO : \
v FREE
*) PAC
ro (>
Vv om EFT
Qfiivg;
Fa, mi, re, mi. . right?
Oh. maybe it's "so-fa-mi-fa?
Uh, it's ti-la-so-la although I'm a bit off
My. you're really confident, aren't you?
Then tr singing it.
Do~re~ml
Fa so--la-ti-do &
Wow, talk about off key.
But. ym definite that it:s ti-la-so-la: 7...
0. Itis Fa-mi-re-mi.
Come off itl! Cut out the noise!
I'll askithosexpeopleslatemsfor you,
SO cut-out the noise.
Ask. who
The people that I'm going to see after
this is a family of musicians
And there's a composer with
perfect-pitch among them
Perfect... pitch...
HA ¥5 #4
Cacophony of Stradivarius! Prelude!
HA #5 #x<
Mr Kiogoro Mourn?
I don't see Mr. Shitara having
an appointment with anyone by that name.
Well, I was asked to come here
by his granddaughter Hasuki Shitara
Oh" I"sea...
Hasuki is at the annex practicing right now.
Oh~ so the music that's been playing
all this time was a live performance!
How fantastic.!
I don't know what kind of
appointment you have
but please-make sure you do not get
In the way of her practice.
Because she-has an important concert
performance tonight
Uh, which means tonight is
some special occasion .?
It Is Mr. Shitara's 72nd birthday
Oh...
Hazuki
This is Mr. Mouri here to see you
Yes. I'm glad. You really did come
Well, of course, if for a beautiful lady
ike you. Ha. ha. ha...!
Um, are you the one with the perfect pitch,
Miss?
Huh. Oh, that's not me...
Hey, hey, are you sure it's okay, Hasuki,
to slack off practice?
You're the one who s performing tonight,
right? Using the you know what
Oh. es...
If you goof you re going to
get it from big brother.
Genzabure
I woul really like you to let us know,
beforehand If ou're coming home
In Wonk J (OX)
I came all this way after leaving in the
middle of the orchestra meeting. you know
Yawn
I'd llko to take aisnoozfle for a while
Will you wake me like always
when the birthday party starts.
Oh. I hope you haven't touched anything
in my roomwithout my permission?
No, because I don't want to be yelled
at by you like your late wife.
I see. Ha, ha, ha.
Uh, Miss. as that man the person
with the perfect-pitch?
Uh. .nope.
Grand Uncle Gen-zaburo IS
OAR ES Gene edtoly p
but he says he does not have perfect pitch.
The one who has perfect pitch is
NOOO
Oops. I went flat on "ti".
Oh, sorry, an ambulance just went by...
About yesterday's music,
could you make the BPM from 120130
I want it to be a bit more lively
Right. right...
Could lit be him?
Yes. hess the one with the perfect-pitch
He 1s. a genius composer,and in charge of
soundtracks for several dramas.
He's Kyosuke Haga. my uncle
Hmm?
Fuh.are you talking about me?
Yes... U.Uh...
Uh. can you tell me what the notes are?
U.Uh. uncle...
U.Uh... uncle .
How did you like what I played?
It was good
although you were
1/4th pitch flat on a note.
Ill prefer it that way. though.
T.Thank you!
Yes.hello
Oh, you mean that piece. I'd like to break
the notes up a bit more.
Oh, you mean that piece
I'd like to break\the notes up a bit more
Furuto~ Where are you?
Furuto
GS .Grandmother?)!
I hear the sound of the violin playing
Furute. don't hide and come out here
Grandmother not again
Father passed away last year today
have you forgotten?!
Ast. ear toda 7?
N.No., Furuto is still
Hey. Ayane. how unsightly!
Oh, grandfather.
Going after the shadow of the dead
for so long.
Our son Furuto has returned to dust
Don't you understand after all this time!
Grandfather, you were told by the doctor
not to walk around...
Mr Mouri
Yes...
I'm sorry but I'm going to
take care of the two for now.
I'll meet you at the main house later
I'd like to talk to you there
I've got something I'd like-tO. showiyou
Oh thisiviolin seems to have been used
over a long period of time,
Yes, it's been made about 300 year ago
XO LL GRUGIN0 Esueive mow ILL
The one who made it is an Italian
by the name of Antonio Stradivari
Stradh
varl .You mean that famous...
Just as I...thought
Stradivarius?!
D.Doesn't this cost several billion Jen
T.The legendary and famed
musiea instrument
Let go of it. Dd. quickly
M.My bodyis frozen in place that
I~I can't let co of it. Yikes
What. oh come on
Y Yes...Yes
And. what about this legendary
musical instrument
Well
This violin Is what Danjiro Shitara
Uncle Kyosuko Hag1's father
had given as a gift to Grandfather
Choichire. his older brother...
Um, despite being the son
of blood-related brothers.
Why is his last name Haga'?
The thing 1s unfortunately,
on the day of his birthday
Danjiro was attacked By a robber
Robber?!
Grandfather Choichiro and
the others gave in quietly and was tied up
so they were fine. but Danjiro resisted so
he passed away a few days later because
of the blow he incurred during the robbery
Uncle Kyosuke who was left behind.
Was adopted by the family
on his mother's side
and took after the:surname Haga
I 888...
But. it's a amazing that this wasn't stolen
But, it's a amazing that this wasn't stolon.
Ry \J
I mean the robber was probably
after the Stradivarius
The robber seems to have taken
the wrong violin
Since the Shitara Family has been
musicians for generations
There were many violins
It all happened 30 years ago though
Don't tell me that you want me to find out
who the robber that broke
in here 30 years ago was?
MOseduditiR PE) IED) Go Be yom QO
to solve the shuddering incidents, that
have happened within the last two years
The first one is
the incident that happened the year
before last Uncle Genzaburo's wife
who had been very athletic. tripped
on the stairs andspassedsaway...
The other one 1s an incident
that happened last year
My father Furuto leaned
against a corroded:fence of the veranda...
It's unlikely that my father
who was a very careful person
would fall to his death like that.
I just can't make myself think
that something like that could happen.
I would like you to solve
these hideous cases Detective Mouri.
UIUh...
Maybe those two incidents
were accidents...?
No! Both of them passed away
on Grandfather's birthday!
Moreover, at this time,
the two played this Stradivarius...
It is as if they were cursed
by the incident that occurred 30 years ago...
And. this'year. I'm going torbo playing it...
MESH GRAY
something bad will happen to me too.
Then, don't play it
I want to play it!
But, if you can take it out freely
M20 Gos amy Ann),
you can play it any time you like,
canst you 2
I borrowed it from Grandfather
just for today for this special occasion
sO I can practice. That's why...
See. I'm sure he's watching me
Then, you mean the violin that I played
a little a while ago wasn't supposed to be...
Of course it's a secret.
And. what would you like me to doe?
Want you to undo the curse of
this Stradivarius before I begin playing it.
Oh ..A course is not something that
a detective like me can solve. you see...
Wht? I thought that
detectives solve anything.
Huh?
It somehow seems to be bright outside.
Are you» going to have some k
birthday fireworks or something?
No. there are no such plans...
Hmm!
T.The annex!
It.It's on fire!
Mr. Genzaburo (8 over there!
Fire! Open the curtains and look!
WwW. What?!
Where's your uncle's room?
Uh, it's on the 2nd floor right up the stairs...
Hey. uncle, can you hear me?
Dran! The door Is locked...?
We've got no other choice.
Whaaal
A.Agh~Great Uncle!
Don't go inside!
There is no seaving him!
A ane~A ane...
Grandfather!
A.Ayane is still upstairs.
What, Grandmother is upstairs
Where is the room upstairs?
The room at the very end of the 3rd floor...
This is impossible unless we have
a fire-proof suit or something!
Oh no...
H.He .
I can't help myself for being the way I am.
Take care of everyone else. will you.
H.He...
Uncle!
Pops. please park your car
below that window. quick!
Huh?
Do that. okay?!
Oh. hey you! Wait!
Are you all right?
Grandfather. please get a hold of yourself.
Hey Dad. wait,
just what do you think you're doing?
Beats me
Hint kKidintold me to park my car here,
Huh? How come I'm listening to that kid ?
What?!
Aaagh
Hey. get a hold of yourself. Aunty!
Mrs. Where!
I sce he wanted to reduce
the distance of the fall with the car
and used the roof as cushion...
Just what a kid would think of
We were lucky that we got a wagon
because they had nothing else.
It's a rental car, you know!
Who knows how much we're going to
have to pay for repair
The fire engines soon arrived at the scene
but the annex of the Shitara family
kept on burning for a while...
As If it were grieving the postiude
of the conductor Genzaburo Shitara
N. No!
But, we've got to treat you
at the hospital either way...
No. no~I
I'm sorry, but
could you let her have her way. please.
A year ago, our son was taken atway
on the ambulance and never came back...
I guess she doesn't want to
ride the same vehicle.
Could you please treat her
at home just for today?
Thank you, sonny.
I'm sorry for what you had to
go through too Kyosuke. Thank you.
No problem .
Little Kyosuke, are you all right?
I'm fine. Will you please cut out
that Little when calling me.
30 years have gone by all ready
4 The steward Ms. Tsumagari was originally
working at Uncle Kyosuke's house.
# But, 30 years ago after that robbery
when Danjiro and his wife passed away.
AndrUncle Kyosuke who was left behind
took after the Haga family name.
We had Ms. Tsumagari come to work for us,
{and she's been with us since...
What?! Kyosuke's father was
not the only one who passed away?
His mother @hiha, was not
a very healthy person toe begin with.
But she watched ever her husband Danjire
without sleeping...
but she watched over her husband Danjiro
As a result she-felliilltof
extreme fatigue and...
And. what about your mother, Hasuki?
She got a divorce and went back to
her parental home.
Just before Grandfather's birthday
2 ears ago.
That's why Great Aunty Eimi ended up
playing for his birthday.
Since it was Grandfather's 70th birthday
as well as to encourage Father.
She was to play that Stradivarius
that had been sealed for 30 years...
That famed musical instrument
was sealed...?
Yes. When Grandfather received it
from Danjiro. he was very happy but...
My: father:who borrowed; it
when"he:was 18 years-old
and performed/in. a contestiexperienced
the strings snapping apart twice on stage
and was disqualified
Yet. on another occasion,
my aunt who was scheduled to
perform on a certain TV program...
came down with a high fever
right before show time...
And, Great Uncle Geénzaburo, who was,
on his wayito a concert abroad. (» I
came down. with a serious case of
tenosynovitis\during practice...
I see~I can see why you'd want to seal it.
Uh, you think the violin's okay. It was left
on the desk in the room as Is.
H.Hey, if this fire was a case of arson,
it could've been taken
during all this commotion...
No, it wasn't. I put it back
in the storage room right away.
Or. do I look like an
incompetent steward who would leave
such a famed
musical instrument unattended
in a household where
outsiders are walking around?
O.Oh. is that right.
Besides, the fire was not caused by arson,
but rather. smoking while sleeping.
Huh?
It seems that the area around the ashtray
that was in that room
is where the fire started, and the door
was torn off with the key locked.
You're the one who broke it down, right?
If so, the room was locked...
And arson would be impossible...
O.Oh. is that right
Well, please be extremely careful
when smoking
It's best not to smoke though.
But, even if everything were
to be a coincidence. it sure is frightening
To think that something would happen on
the same day for three consecutive years.
To think that somaothing would happon on
the same day for threc consecutive years
Including « osuke's father
) who died in the robbery 30 years ago.
It comes up to a total of four all together...
Taking this into consideration,
I think you shouldn't stop celebrating
Choichiro's birthday from next year...
Aha. ha...ll tell you. he's already smoking
Well, it'll turn out that way anyway,
because Uncle has bad lungs
and has only a h: If a year to live.
R.Really?
Yes. I wanted to at least
celebrate today with him
We can't anymore,
because he's already gone to bed.
The Mrs. has already been treated
and has also gone to bed.
So. since this doesn't:seeém to be a case
or anything. we'll start off home too...
Uh, who's cigare te butt is this?
It doesn't seem to be yours, Pops.
That brand is-the one that
Great Uncle Genzaburo used to smoke.
Come to think of it,_he stopped by here
before going to the annex...
If so then. .this is.
Iff so then. .this is...
Conan?!
Hey, kid,
where do you think you're going... 7?!
Just as I thought.
This Is not an accident, but murder
Moreover, if my deduction is correct,
the next target is...
Original Comic Bool Ry
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MASAHITQ Y¥ + + 1GKA
Background Music.
KAI .LC ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO. SUDO
Story 'Editors
JUNICHI 11 + KA
KANJI KASHIWABA A
KAZUNARI K@UCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YOICHI.HIGURE
hi1 3241
ARhimation Directors.
VIASRUID VI DRY DY.
sh \Set O 33 ST \W/
AISUSHI AC N 7
AKIO KAWAMURA
LLGL if re
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO'SHIBUIANI
Directors Of Photosraphy...
I Li. ll JM JIM
yr o Co» » > »
TAKAHISA OWAGAW
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI]
Editor.
TERUMITSU: OKADA
Chief Director.
JKENJI. KODAMA
Produced By
TMS*ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in assowation with
YOMIURI T1ELECA TING
CORPORAT ON
th FEC TIV ECON AN
GOSNTHISAOYAMA SHOTGARILIAA . YIN INS
Ru he. ved
This could be a serial murder case.
WwW. What?
WwW. Wait! D-E-F-G... then the next target
is Hasuki with the initial H...!
Oh no! She shouldn't be left alone!
Kyaaaaah~I
@acophony. of Stradivarius! Interlude!