The musical tone of the: famed musical
instrument brinc s about murder
The disaster that befalls a family
of musicians takes an unexpected turn!
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in Aappoarance
7 with the .Q. of an adult
No case is:left unsolved
NS WIE h CC CC IVE, Onan.
We were summoned by Ms. Hasuki Shitara
and wentito visit Choichiro Shitara's
residence. Pops. Ran and I
Hasuki had called us
because incomprehensible
accidents revolving
around the famed musical
instrument Stradivarius
have been occurring consecutively
from the year before last.
Her request was for us
to investigate these accidents
However, as soon as we got the «,
the annex went up In flames!
Genzaburo whe was inside. dies
Um. who's cigarette butt is this?
It doesn't look to be Pop's.
That brand...
is what Great Uncle Genzaburo
used to smoke.
COO 10 lil Of IR,
he droppedsby here
before going to the annex...
this is...
Hey sonny. where are you going!
Just as I thought
This Is not an accident
but murder
Morever,
If MM deduction is correct
the next target is...
Ph £58x<
PA ED 8x<
Cacophony of Stradivarius! Interlude!
hh EH 84
What~"?
You mean this fire Is arson?!
Yep. The cause of the fire is
because he fell asleep while smoking
and the source of the fire is
around this ashtray
See. look at this cigarette butt
and this is the cigarette that Genzaburo
was smoking back at the main house
the brand is the same
and there's nothing odd about it .
Agh. there a trace of it being bitten
See...
Just like you Pops
People who work and talk while they smoke
havea habit of biting the filter of their cigarette.
But there is no trace of
this cigarette butt being bitten
Don't you think it's strange?
I see...
In order to make it look
as If he fell asleep smoking. someone...
What you want to say is that
the killer smoked several cigarettes
before setting the place on
fire. right?!
Before setting the place on
Ii, [nil
before setting the place on
fire. right?!
But, the door of this room
can only be locked from the inside
How'd the killer leave the room then?
You've come across an idea of the kind of
trick that may have been used. right?
Oh.no not et
You're just a kid after all
He could've just happened to bite
the cigarette
that he smoked back
at the main house. you know.
Besides.
Genzaburo used to hate
people cleaning up his room.
Isn't It strange that
there isn't even one cigarette filter
that has bite traces?
There's nothing strange about it
Because Genzaburo used to always
throw out the rubbish before going out.
But, it's amazing ho
ou dashed out of the room
Well, the fact is, this kid informed me
But if he threw out the rubbish,
it's strange after all,
that he would smoke several cigarettes
before falling asleep.
You fool~That's not unusual at all
He probably got sleepy
when he was smoking his last cigarette.
That could be it, but
I wonder if it's okay?
This could be a case of serial murder.
WwW. What?!
You shouldn't make such
IN Irresponsi >» e remar...
The name...
The initial of the name of the person
Danjiro who died after being attacked
b arobberis D
Theyinitial of Eimi who diedyafter falling
off the stairs two years'ago"is "E"
The initial of Furuto who fell off the veranda
and died a ear ago is "FF...
MARA TO NW = Of O DO
who. died tonight is 'G
D-E-F
G. it's In alp - abetical order
If what all these.people have in common is
the birthday of thelhead of this household,
Mr. Choic iro Shitara
It could be as the kid says.
There's something fish going on?
WwW. WaitmD-E-F-G
then the person with the next initial
H" is Hasuki...!
Oh no! We can't leave her alone!
What! I'm the next target?
Oh no. no way
alphabetically your name is next In line...
Now that you mentioned it, its true that
starting with Father Danjiro's initial D
it continues E~F=G in alphabetical order
Ah, come on It's just a coincidence,
fun. fun.
I. guess so. aha. ha
But. we have a problem
What about tonight's: requiem?
Requiem?
It's been a. custom for generations I
n the Shtiara family
that when someone passes away,
someone plays the requiem.
Genzaburo played til last year
Besides, Mr. and Mrs. Shitara is
in No condition to play as you can see.
I can't possibly play either!
Okay. I guess I'll play it then.
Why don't you all join us too?
Alive pefférmance by. \ osuke Ega is not
something you can listen to everyday,
you know
Oh...
But, most of tho musical instruments
were in the annex
The only instruments left are
the piano and that...
Hey. hey. not that Stradivari
my hands'll shake
You can use my violin. then...
No I'll use the one I usually use
that's in my car,
although it'll never comc close to that
famed -musicalainstrumaoent
that was made 300 years ago.
It's the only gift that Father ever gave me
When it comes to tone quality
It's second to none...
I don't want to use that
famed musical instrument again
and have something happen.
Besides, if I take it out without
asking Aunt Ayane,
I think she'll be troubled.
Huh...Be troubled?
For Mrs. Shitara that Stradivarius is
her son Furuto*himself.
That famed musical instrument
that Furutorplayed
in front of Mr. Shitara"
just before hissdeath'is
$0. ever since then, at tho stroke of midnight
1 ol MN
Does Choichiro know about this?!
Yes. most likely
The storeroom for the Stradivari is
between Grandfather
and Grandmother's room
I'm sure that Grandmother still sees
my Father Furuto back then, in her heart
Then, I shall begin
Composed by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart,
Requiem
Concerto in D major K-626
How nice!
Yes.
Uncle Kyosuke graduated a music university
in Germany with honors...
Uh. why did he open the window, Kyosuke?
Probably so that Grandfather and
Grandmother could listen to him play too
Grandmother's bedroom Is right above.
Ou mean that grandmother's room
Is connected with grandfather's room
with the storeroom of the Stradivari
in between?
If locked from the inside you cannot go
through from the storeroom
You can gosinside from the corridor though,
with the master: key that Ms. Tsumagari has
Oh, they sleep in different rooms
even if they're marrieds
Grandfather is a heavy smoker
and Grandmother hated the smoke
NXE) GION Y GR Windle) Gg 0 Conk
with lung cancer.
If Grandfather dies who's going to receive
that expensive violin?
Great Uncle Genzaburo would have
Maybe Grandmother?
I wonder what Grandfather will do.
I feel that it Is most appropriate
for a musical genius like
Incle + osuke to have it. though.
Conan, listen quietly, will you.
Hmm... what's that sound?
D.Don't tell me that was?!
G.Grandmother.
Hurry, get an ambulance!
Yes. sir!
Grandmother's name is "Ayane
so her Initial is...
What does this mean?
I won't give it to anybody...It's mine.
Where's the storeroom?
To the right beyond
The door Is locked from Inside
And the chair beside the window...
Could it be suicide after all?
Well. well
Mr. Mourl. another encounter with Death. eh.
Oh come on...It's mere coincidence.
Inspector, and besides
it's the saga of renown detectives.
To become involved in cases
Iike these no matter where they go
Then. I'd rather you stay still at home.
The estimated time of the incident
is around midnight.
The site Is that window on the 3rd floor
It seems to be her bedroom.
Hmm... Where were you at that time?
Yes sir, I was in the room
right below with everyone else
Iistening to Kyosuke playing the Requiem.
Requiem?
Yes,
it seems to have been a custom handed down
for generations at the Shitara residence.
Oh, Genzaburo, who burned to death
was the youngest of 3 brothers
The oldest Is Choichiro
The 2nd son Danjiro,
who dacd 30 years ago as Kyosuke's father
So, famed detective,
what do you think her motive for suicide was?
Well, as to that...l have no idea yet
Uh...ll think it's the violin.
Oh, she's the steward for the Shitara family...
Let's go to Mrs. Shitara's room.
Ooh, T...This is?!
Straduvarius.
Don't tell me that a robber broke in
and Ayane fell out the window accidentally...
But. this room was locked
There are no signs of any struggling either
There are-no-signs of anyone having come
in here either.
The violin was probably already broke by someone
before Mrs. Shitara opened the case
Maybe it was from that shock.
But, would she do something like:ithat
just because a musical instrument broke...
Don't you know,
that violin is a legendary violin
that costs several billions of.yen!
Moreover Ayane was chenshimg it
as if it were the double of her son. who died
If someone broke it
I'm pretty sure thay
she'd feel like jumping out the window re
Wrong
What ..7?
I think she broke it herself.
Not again. this brat
By herself what makes you think so?
See. look at the new scratch on that table
Grandmother probably
threw this violin against it
Y.You idiot!
She's not like Inspector Megure
who knows nothing of violins you know
She would never do something like that!
Yep. I think so too.
But. that's only if this violin is genuine
WARE: 3
Look at the label that 1s stuck to
the inside of the violin
The mark says "GA"
If Antonio Stradivari made it
the label should show "A Sl
Hmm... Huh!
Hmm. Huh!
How come you know something like that?!
Oh, uh 'Shinichi told me so some time ago
You mean that detective kid?!
Come to think of it, Shinichi was
really knowledgeable when it came to violins
Maybe because Holmes used to play it?
[he violin maker who made that violin
was just being playful and put his initial
on the mark that was a replica of the real one.
The replica is also famous
and a large amount had been made
since some time ago.
See. underneath the label
It says sMade In Germany
It's a 100% replica.
He's
Kyosuke that I mentioned a while ago.
Oh, can you tell me who wastdlistening
to his Requiem in the room below?
Yes. sir, Ran and I
that kid over there
Hawks, and the steward, Ms. Tsumagari,
all four of us
And Ayane fell to her death
during this performance
But, why did Grandmother
have to commit suicide
after Uncle Kyosuke risked his life to save
her from the flames .
Save her?
Yes. \ osuke and Conan saved Ayane
who didn't make it in time out of \the fire...
I still don't understand.
Why did she break the replica?
Don't tell me she thought
It was genuine all this time
but realized only now that it was a replica...
That's isn't possible.
Mr. Shitara's violin has been appraised
and is guaranteed to be genuine
But this case is genuine.
Isn't this the one?
Ang
&rafd father
org 7
It was hidden*behind the bed
That Ayane, she dare treat it so carelessly.
Ang
It has the label of Antonio Stradivari.
SO this is genuine.
When I saw it I knew it was.
Would you like -me to play it?
No. that won't be necessary if you:say so.
What we see is good enough
If so. what onfearth Is that?
Maybe another Stradivaii was
placed here to surprise everyone
But, after finding out that it was a replica,
she was shocked and. /
Uswax
so before her husband finds out-that
she spent.a lot of money on trash
she committed suicide
Oh~if so everything falls into place.
Wrong!
When I came into this room-a while ago
When I came into this room a while ago,
I checked the bed but nothing was there!
I'm sure that someone...
came to secretly replace the replica hat was
once exchanged for the genuine Stradivari,
again with the genuine one
Somebody for some reason
came intO this room after I did and...
Conan
Oh.maybe you should check
the fingerprints that are on it.
Well, I'm sure you'll find fingerprints
everywhere though
Mine too. all over the place
Because I was tuning the Stradivari
In preparation for Uncle Cholchlrds birthday
since yesterday afternoon.
In this room?
I handed it over to Hasuki after that . right?
Yes, I played it a little too,
s@ my fingerprints are-also on it...
Was there anyone else there back then?
I was alone Uncle Kyosuke left
taking Grandmother with him to the garden,
so that-she wouldn't bother me.
I was showing Mr. Mouri the Stradivar
when he. arrived a while later
then we saw the annex on fire
And In the meantime,
I took the-Stradivari that was left
And, in the meantime,
I took the Stradivari that was left
as is on the table, to the storeroom
Hmm. which means anyone of you
could've switched the violin.
But, Inspector, that doesn't matter now,
does it?
The genuine one is back ind that kid over
there is just saying what he wishes.)
But.-something's strange about this Ii éident!
What's so strange!
This room was locked.
And the door of that
storeroom was locked too.
Moreover, there is a chair by the window
No matter how you look at it, it's suicide.
Where's the spare key to this room?
Other than what Mrs. Shitara was using.
I have the master key.
Inspector. I found the key among
the belongings of the corpse
Hmm..l see.
Seo. this is not 1 serial murdor case.
Serial murder?!
Well. according to this kid. he says that
the wings started 30 years
ago with the initial of the names
of thggmembers of the family.
D-E-RG in alphabetical order.
But, after the letter 'G of Genzaburo
who died in the fire
Ayane, with the initial "A"
committed suicide.
That Is. there was no connection.
Oh.maybe
it's the musical scale?
What?!
D-E-F-G-A
nritahian tswould Ho Do ROM.
Cat ny (: Lg =A RS (hss 540) a "(O
A-B. Like they say the "C" chord.
A-B. Like they say tho C* chord
DE € \[3
alphabet would-beflB")
But. who has t-he initial "BL?
Benio Tsumagari...
You mean the next target is 17?
Come to think of it:..80:years ago
when I first started working here,
Mr Shitara. mentioned.
If you belongedito our family.
We could go right up:the scale from C.to B"
I see, since Choichiro starts with.a C",
that'll make €-D-E-F-G-A-B.
Tho entire musical scale.
Phooey wonder
If I said something like that.
Well I'd like you all to wait
inside your rooms for now. then!
Inspector, they're her footprints!
From the looks of it, it seems
she jumped down without a tinge of hesitation
Without a tinge of hesitation...eh?
Inspector. I'm sure that,it's suicide after all.
I mean this room, was locked
Come to think of It,
the room that Genzabure burned
to death in was also locked
Before the fire, everyone was at the annex
so the anyone of the four
could've set fire to it But
this room was also locked
m sure there's something to it .
Uh. what's that?
See by the top of the window,
there's: something transparent
That square thing
Is it a scotch tape or something?
There is the same to the right too.
Uh. Mr. Mouri was asking
if you saw anything
strange near the corpse.
Come to think of it
Oh, and one more thing.
There was something
that looked like the tip of a chopstick...
Yeah,
we found something that looked
to be thesburnt remains of a case
Right,
shaped something like this,
and maybe two thin sticks would fit into it
Which means that there was nothing
In the case right?!
Right
if that is used, it would be possible to kill
Ayane .
The only thing left to solve is
the locked room mystery.
I see. so that's the story...
Orieinal Comic Book : 3y
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
M SAITO Y +» KA
Background Miisic.
CNL) alo
Characteridcsigns vy
S [ ) - )
Story Fdirtor,
JUNICHI HHOKA
KAN]? ITAHSHIWABARA
JNARI KG)!
CHI MIYAS
TY » \ ab
Animation-Directors.
Fle & <
HIROTOSHT TAKATAN]
wit J) J GAY
4 <q o lb AY
BE TUDE AINE
AKIO KAWAMURAO*
LAARNADITL TTY JN
Art Director.
YUKIAIRO.SHIBUTANI
I Directors Of Photostaphy. » 2
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HO RiOSHI
TARARIISA
Recording Director
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJIKODAMA)
Produced By
ENTERTAINMENT; I
MIURI TELECASTING,
ORPORATI
Produced By
TMS ENTERTAINMENT TD.
11) d5SSNO( ration wilh
YOMIURI TELECASTING
DEIIDEAINDTY
130 LECTIN IGUANA AN
GON VOY AMY SHOG WRUR YN VIL TMS
MERE O wen avid,.
You've figured out the killer?
The truth of what's been happening'herne
at this, house from 2 years ago
Why would this Stradivarius have
anything with solving the mystery
There's just.one thing I don't understand
Cacophony
a sound very displeasing to the ear
0.03m tell me that.
He.!!
Conan?
@acophony. of Stradivarius! Postlude!