The strings play a murderous tone *
Annoying human relationships
Hat ON ICAO NO SESE Ne
and the case is solved!
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the IQ. of an adult
No case is¥left unsolved
with Detective; @onan
We were summoned by
Ms. Hasuki Shitara
and wenti/to visit Choichiro Shitara's
residence. Pops. Ran and I.
Hasuki had called us because
incomprehensible accidents revolving
around the famed musical
fin'strument Stradivarius«
have been occurring consecutively
from the year before last.
Her request was for us
to investigate these accidents
However as soon as we got there,
the annex went up in flames)
('a zaburo who was Inside. dies.
Moreover, that night,
while Kyosuke was playing the
Requiem on his violin
Ayana falls {from
the 3rd floor to her death!
Left behind are a violin and
SSVaNS IRIS TS SES At I IE St
What is going on...?
What is going on...
Cacophony of Stradivarius! Postlude!
That's no doubt the bridge of a violin
But the bridge was on the replica
as well as the Stradivarius
Which means
there was one more violin
Oh and one more thing,
here was something that
Iooked, like the tip of a chopstick
And that was a tact
The conductor's staff used
in an orchestra.
Yeah
we found something that looked
to be the burnt remains of a case
Right,
shaped something like this,
and maybe two thin sticks
would fit into it...
Which means that
there was nothing in the case. right?!
So. that's the story
But. there is one thing I don't understand
What is the killer so hung up on
Come to think of it,
Mom told me some time in the past
Do Do. Re-Mi-Mi-So
Mi-Mi-Re-Re-Oo
Why do I spread my fingers and play?
Well
there's this thing called a chord.
For example,
This is the "CC" chord
This ls.
This is Oka
Well? Doesn't this, chord make
you feel sort of uncomfortable?
Inspector, it's suicide, suicide...!
The entrance door and
the door of the storeroom
were both locked up.Zyou know
In such a locked room. it's impossible
If Ayane used the chair as a step
and jumped out
Ol? Will, JAdallie= ike) 110 Oikedk JO
hen, doesn't it bother you that
people with the Initials in keeping
with'the musical scale,
D-E*=F=G-A have died...?
It's true that before the A of Ayane
comes Genzaburds .
But. it's probably just a coincidence.
That room was locked too.
And the fire was probably caused
by him falling asleep while smoking
But .
At any rate. I think we should call it a day
D.Dad!
WW.What is it. Ran
WwW. What???
Well, after yawninc and making
a funny looking face.
You fall asleep and starl
your deduction show
A funny leoking faco
Right, right,
and you also make strange sounds'
Iike "hanyah or whatever.
I thought it sounded more like Hohee?
No. I think it was "Henyo" the other day
Nohyoo
Right. right. it's this face. this voice!
H 000
Oh, the Sleeping Kogoro!
He's sure putting on
a haughty pose today
Of course
because after all I solved the mystery ?
That even you Inspector.
Could not solve despite all your thinking
regarding the truth about the
serial killings. that have been occurring
In this house ovethe last two years
But you kept insisting that
It was suicide till just a while ago
Well, it was an instant flash
of inspiration. you see
Please gather the things I ask for here :
After everything's ready
please call the four suspects here
And of course: please don't forget
that famed musical instrument,
the Stradivari.
Okay. what do we bring for you?
No, Officer Takagi,
please wait for us In another room.
Huh. Why?
Youwrll find out later.
Don't come out until I call you, all right?
sO you've figured out who the Killer.is...
Which means you think this is
a serial murder tase?
Are you referring to
Great Uncle GinZaburo
and Grandmother vane too?
Yes, they arc all victims
that have been killed by one person.
It is most likely that Eimi
ho tripped over the stairs
and Furuto who fell to
his death: from the veranda
were also killed by the same person
OO. Oh no...
why would solving the mysten have
anything to do with this Stradivarius
He's probably figured out
who it Is was that switched
the violin with a replica
then came back here
just to return the violin
thought I'd like you to listen!to
a'song I will play before starting
my deduction show.
In other words.
A prelude to solving the mystery,
I guess you could say
What!
H-He Dad?!
Yes,
just like I did in front of you a while ago
Are, ou read 7?
Oh. well
I don't think you should
Of course you shouldn't.
Just what do you think
my Stradivarius is?
Just what do you intend to do
If an amateur like you
handles it and scratches it or something!
Well. well.
El's see what he wants to do
I'm sure he has something in mind.
Or, as there some reason
why you don't want to let him have it.
Uncle Choichiro...?
N No I don't.
Here
I'm all ears
Fuh, fun
$0. it was you after all,
wasn't it. Kyosuke
You're the one who switched the violin
He . he
I To),
I just handed itover:to you
because you said you wanted to play it
If I remember correctly, the people
who handled this violin was
in the order as follows
Kyosuke tuned the violin this afternoon.
And handed it over to Hasuki
When she was showing me the violin
fire breaks out at the annex
The Stradivari that was left .on the table
was taken to the storeroom
by/Ms. Tsumagari
If the one who switched the violins were
either Ms. Tsumagari or Choichiro
who could go in and out of the storeroom,
it would have been switched
after I played the violin/in:Hasuki's room
If my fingerprints are found on the violin,
either oneof the two
would've been-the tine
who switched the violin
Ifr-so.
Hat person would've 'let.me touch
the Stradivari one more time
in order to make unknown
when my fingerprints got on the violin
If it were Kyosuke or Hasuk
1a Cle 2G SWIC WOU ¢ HC 1eYvsame
They would want me to touch it here
If my prints are not found
on that genuine violin,
it would mean that it had been switched
to the replica before I-played It.
And both of you would be suspected
However... Hasuki and
Choichiro. as well as Ms. Tsumagari
objected to my touching the Stradivari
But. ou urged me to go ahead
In other words. Kyosuke
this is evidence that you are
the one who had committed
the serial murders
G.Groat Uncle...Oh, no
B.But, it.couldO™be that
when Kyosuke was tuning the violin
It was alrondy the replica I
That's not possible
With an ear like his
He would know right off
the bat that it's not:genuine.
Well. But what makes you say
he's the murderer?
Ayane's room was locked, and besides
Genzaburo's room that caught fire
was also locked
Iay, kid. show them the stuff
Okay! Here it is
It's the metal piece that was
found in Genzabure's room.
Tako a good look, Inspector,
only tho holo on the topipartiisibent
If the locked door was
destro ed and forced open
the top and bottom
should be bent out of shape
Hmm, rue
When he found that
the firefighter was saying.
That the bolt sticking out of the door.
The top part is the knob
and the bottom part is the lock
So from the looks of the direction
in which the door was opened
it doesn't seem to have been locked
when it was broken down.
But. when, we went back to,
the burnt remains later
the door key was locked...
Kyosuk@.locked it.
Back then he pretended
that the door was locked
and broke it down
No good. it's locked!
When we were all distracted
by the sea of flames
1,] sesO...
But what has that to do
with switching the violin?
He used it to make Ayane jump to
her death from this room...
What?
But during that time he was ina
room below. this one.
«it was also a trap"
to lure Ayane to the window
try to imagine it
the Stradivarius that she used to
stare at:every night as if it were her son
switched for:a replica.
Outraged, she destroys the violin
Can you imagine how she felt.
She then turns to look towards
the window
and listens to the beautiful melody
played by Kyosuke
Hey. kid. show them the other stuff next!
Es, sir!
Yes sir!
Wiwhat is the meaning of this?!
This Is what Ayane saw back then
Don't tell me that Ayane thouc ht
that was the real Stradivariu ¥...?
Yeah.
More so, If the Requiem played
by Kyosuke from the floor below
sounds like
the genuine Stradivarius
She used the chair as a stepping stool
and climbed up the window,
trying to take the violin
But, I wonder if
she'd fall down so easily,...?
Let me show you how it was done.
Hey. kid. go get Officer Takagi
ThenYMs. Tsumagari,
Yes sir
you took the real Stradivarius
to the storeroom...
Uh. did you call me
Um Officer Takagi, while Pops was
explaining the, trick to everyone
a Stradivarius happen to be hanging
out the window
What?!
Since you're tall, you can reach it, right?
Well, I guess so
I hope there's nothing behind all this?
No, no,
but be extremely careful will you,
because it's valued at more than
several billions of yen
HO 1.1., fill.
But. mind you it's not my fault.if I drop it.
Huh? Oops?
Hey. hey...
Whaaal!
Ky hey
Whaaa!
Watch out!
Be careful.- Takagi!
It, It moved,
When I tried to take the violin.
It moved away... Agh?!
Agh?!
I see, a pole was attached
to the window frame on both sides.
Then the violin is suspended
with a string.
Then the more the window is opened,
the farther the violin pulls away!
But. Dad...
What if it gets stuck like that?
There was no violin or pole
anywhere at the site
This is a temporary gimmick that
I made by borrowing a long chopstick
from the kitchen
If the two sticks that were used to carry out
the crime were the conductor's staff
that was stolen from Genzaburos room
they would be very flexible,
so the violin that moves to the edge will
eventually fall from its weight.
Therefore if thé other string that
Is attached to the violin is
stuck on to the window frame
of the room below
after we ran over to Ayane who
we were looking down upon,
he secretly went to collect the violin.
The staff would. still...
That too, .
Since it was only stuck on
using scotch tape
all he had to do was attach a string to it
to collect it later
The sound that we heard)
before Ayane fell. ispthe sound of that
violin bumping inte the wall. I
As proof of that,
a broken staff was found near the corpse.
He set up this/gimmick when he came
into this room to tune the Stradivarius...
This is probably when he switched
the genuine one for the replica too...
I'm sure that the conductor's staff and
violin that he collected are hidden
somewhere in the room below.
Of course,
with Kyosuke's fingerprints all over it.
It's hard to belicve that he hand time to
erase his: fingerprints or to take the things
to another place back then since Hasuki,
ho broke out in tears was there...
It can't be...! That's all baloney!
Uncle Kyosuke-can't Be the killer
because he saved Grandmother
who couldn't make:!'it. out of the fire in time.
If so. then why?!
Tha 8 because of
the rule of the "musical scale
that even you know of as a musician...
Huh...why do I spread my fingers out
when I play the piano?
Because see, when you play notes that
are alongside each other...
Cacophony.
When notes that are alongside each other
are played it sounds disharmonic...
D.Don't tell me that...
Exactly...
I couldn't stand the fact that:
Genzaburo with initial "G" and.
Grandmotnor Ayane with initial A's
die at the sameitime!...
Why you... just what do you
take the lll§of people to be!
Phooey! I'd like you to say those words
to Uncle Choichiro there too.
What?
To that old man over there, who was to
blame for my father getting seriously hurt.
Drove my mother to her death
from the heavy load of caring for father.
30 years ago You mean back
when that robbery occurred...
I had completely forgotten
about it until 2 years ago
when I was asked 10 tune the Stradivarius
during that old man's birthday.
The sound of the, the feel... it brought back
memories of when I was still a child.
The.:sound of the. the feel...
it brought back memories of
when I was still a child,
of when my father who: gave me the-violin...
When I confirmed with Aunt Eimi,
Swe o< mew: valpae ace.
That 30 years ago, that old man over there
borrowed: the Stradivarius from Father.
Saying that he wanted to make Furuto,
his songplay it...
The old man who fell in love with the tone,
didn't want to return the violin so.
He exchanged it for a replica
that looked exactly alike.
But, father found out right away
and the. got into an argument.
On top of that, after father
fell down the stairs
he was seriously hurt...
That old man had the nerve to leave father
who was seriously hurt as is and
didn't. even call.an ambulance.
He then told the four who
were there the following.
Genzaburo
tie.,Ayane. and me up and
ou. go Ss goon home!
What?!
We're going to make it look as if
we, were-attacked by robbers.
Don't you want to-play: this
famed musical instrument?
If Danjiro dies, this is mine
I'll lend it to you any time you want.
Aunt Eimi, who told me everything,
was besides herself and left the room.
Kyaaah!
So you decided to take revenge onuthe four
who agreed to the scheme back then.
When I saw Aunt Eimi trip over the stairs
and fall to her death like Father.
I took it to be a sign from God .
Starting from
my mother China
m. father Danjiro...
Aunt Eimi, they all died
I Kg,
in the order of the musical scale
And if lined the Initials of the ones
who Would be dying.
I figured It would begin
with "C" and end with "C".
Well but after pushing Furuto
off the veranda a year ago
I was sort of flustored when I found out
that the last one on the list with Initial
Gramps Choichiro was
about to die of an illness.
Ugh: ugh, cough, cough.
what took place 30 years:ago.
Was next in line to be killed after all...
No... in Germany after C-D-E-F-G-A
comes the alphabet
it's pronounced "HA".
In other words. it stands for Haga
Hey!
Agh!
Uncle!
Pops told me to do so.
So I told them to wait below with a mat.
Because he said that
\ osuke may commit suicide
But, if it was initial "H"
it could've been Hasuki.
It could've been her turn next.
Since Kyosuke brought the
Stradivarius back to.this room
I figured it wasn't going te be so.
If Ayane didn't break the replica
as she did back then
it would've been likely that
no one would've even noticed that
there was a replica of the
Stradivarius at all.
The fact that he came to return
the genuine one means that
he wanted to leave the famed.
Legendary gift that
his father had given him
o its rightful owner,
to the one that he had thrown into the
same situation as he was thrown into.
When they killed his father...
That is. Hasukl
He wanted to give it to you.
Original Comic Bevis By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Pr O cf UC AC ro SC
110 YOS
Backeround Music.
Character Jdesions By.
MAS/HOMO sw/Uo
Story Editor,
JUNICHI II KA
KAN]? ITASHIWABARA
or aga
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
TOSHIKd INOUE
Animatipn.Diréctors.
MASATOMO SUDO
it J O00 2)
AU UDI AWINUT,
AKIO KAWAMURAO
TAKASHI HY DO
Art Director.
123 JT»
I Directors Of Photoeriphy.
TAKASHI NOMURA
I» co eb
TAKAMISA'OWAGA
Recording Dirz¢ 0
KATSUYOSHI AVA
Editor.
TERUMITSU WKADA
Iraci
KENJI. KODAMA)
Produced By.
TMS* ENTERTAINMENT, LID
11? assoOwlairomn with
YOMIURI TELEC STING
CORPORATTON
ISTIC IV 1 GCON AN
GONHOAOY MAT SHOU VARA VA YTV TMS
AM Ris: his Reverved
uh... .when I asked you about
the melody from my cell phone...
you answered "Me?"
Tell me what the notes are. please
H-A-G-A?
If in German would it be
pronounced HAGA?
That's right.
You've got a good ear too. sonny.
Which means that the
notes are Tl-La-So-La?
Hey. Conan...
Uh. do you know of any song
that begins with Ti-La-So-La?
It could be some sad,
yet nostalgic type of music...
Oh. if so, it's probably...
This song?
Isn't that song...
Crow little crow. why do you cry
Right, Conan?!
Conan?!
WwW. What's this threatening air I sense...
After coming all this way to Kagoshima...
Kogero Mouri will not hide
the fact that genuine
Satsuma Distilled Spirits Is the best.
Oh...doesn't something taste sand ?
It's probably the ashes...
What's the matter?!
This is
(By Hi)
(aim)
Kegoro'is Drunk Over Satsumal Part 1
(BIR)