Tonight's stage is in Kagoshima
Pops goes wild "over a rare distilled-spirit 0
Rice:malt is the aroma
of human relationship
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearange
With the I.Q. of'an adult
No cso Weft unsolved
with Detective: Conan
Well, when one wants liquor the. first thing
that comes to mind is beer!
Super cold beer drank in one gulp
there's nothing better than it
What's so good about it,
1s of course the bitterness.
No, rather, what I want to ask you
about is not beer...
Huh, I thought I was summoned to talk
passionately about liquor?
GI HMIEITETNE MIR SES TH IE TENOR SN
passionatel, about liquor?
N28 A, Vong door, ike tae st foxofomiey
type of hquor that's gong around now.
Oh .Oh...Oh...
Well. when it comes to the charm of wine.
It's not wine...but...
This is an important commemorative
event for our program and
what's with all the gibberish
Il...we asked him to come beca
he Is quite well known and loves to drink
I mean, it's so obvious when Kagoshima
comes into the picture and
it's about liquor...Sigh.
The announcer's cr ing...
Dad come on...
Him.
W What's this threatening feeling I sense .
after coming all this way
to Kages ima
huh 2!
Kagoshima...DrinRing In Kagoshima...
brings to mind.
Oh... 71 No...
WW.Well.
Beer is good!
And wine is also good.
But the fact is. I like distilled spirits best.
Actually, I didn't want any of you out there
to realize. more than you alrcady have.
How delicious distilled spirits are.
That's why you went out of your way
to talk about other liquors?!
Oh. so that's what it was!
But, I, Kogoro Mouri can
deceive you no longer.
Among all the distilled spirits,
this IKagdshima made genuine distilled
spirit of Satsuma is the best!
Viva! Kagoshima!
Gha-ha-ha-ha...
All right. Mr. Mouri! Good job.
We were right to invite him over,
weren't we?
Sigh...he somehow made it through...
Aha, ha. he's an expert at that for sure.
Takakuma. you mean the rare spirit?!
Yes... Since tho manufacturing
of it Is completely limited.
it as very hard to gem hold of and
Is the gem of all liquors.
Y.You mean lFget to drink that?!
We asked the brewery and they answered
If for Mr, Moufi they'd be
more than glad to
Weill tosSihe CTI ofWagoshima
on the ferr and
qo to a place ighigépposite
it called Tarumizu.
I get to drink it, the spirit of my-dreams,
the rare spirit Takakuma.
Aaaaghn,
t's nothing to cry.over. Is it
Sem VVRNNNwy
RN -T aw
s &= anne wan, I
This is how we ended up getting involved
ith that devastating case...
S ow SEaasany yy
HA AA
QC: 58°),
HA ANA
(B13)
Kogoro Drunk Over Satsuma! Part 1
HA ANA
Ca 3+)
Takakuma Sake Brewery...
so this is where it's being made.
I thought it was going to be a
much bigger place.
But, it's beautiful...
The sea is right in front too...
Mr. Mouri, here is the head of the family...
Oh, I'm sorry to intrude on you
suddenly like this. I'm Kogoro Mouri.
Thank you so much for coming,
I'm Shiraishi.
We've heard a lot about you...I'm Fumiko.
This is m daughter Ran!
And...he's a freeloader...
Oh. come on, Dad!!
He's Conan!
Hello
I guess a sake brewery is no fun for you,
is it, sonn 7?
That's not true. right?
I like it very much.
That is Takayama.
I see, that's where you got the
name of your brewery from...
Please come this way to the office...
Do come along
Oh. . thank you
If you will excuse me.
How do you like the Takakumar
Kuuuulgh. 1 ™ §eli€Bus .
There's.no other word for it.
It's onl sake
Now no. this is the gem of all sake
It s splendid.
But, it is our pride and joy to
make that 'mere sake
Preparation for making sake starts, with
steaming the washed grains of rice.
Rice malt is then mixeduin.
The-rice malt mixture that
Is completed is put into a vase,
then water and yeast is added,
and let stand, to ferment.
Add steamed Statsumn potatoes
into the mixture and ferment even more.
The temperature must be kept stable
and 'the contents must'be'stirred-constantly
withra stick torpreyvent the
propagation of unwantedbacteria...
Then, it is left to mature.
Which after, an appropriate
amount of water is added
and the process Is finally complete.
There are companies that
are mass producing using machines,
but as for us,
we have stuck to hand-making the sake.
Limited production,
may sound of the quite nice
but the thing is we can't make more than
we are now if we insist on
making something genuine...
Right. The genuine made by hand.
S no wonder its delicious .
Yes?
I'm Maizono from "Weekly Entertainment
that asked for an interview the other day.
Interview;... 7%
No. I know nothing about it
Uh... \
RS UR ORE 1 d= (of= k=xol Vim fd-Ann
What's the ghjange over the moment
the name Tatsufiwra was mentioned... ?
I came here to film the preparationfprocess
The preparation process?!
Did Mr. Tatsumura give you
permission to do that?!
Just what the hell is on his mind!
How can he make such
stupid"promise on his own...
I'm sorry to say that we cannot show
an one the preparation process.
Ou can't ob But.
The greatest enemy
for the sake making process is
bacterial contamination from outside.
So, no one other than
the one who makes the sake is
allowed inside during the process
Oh...l guess so. It's true that
people are carriers of various bacteria...
That's common sense!
"M sorry, I took on the interview
because I love distilled spirits
Hut how igner nt of me
We're notingny it you
We're pissed at Manager Tatsumura!
Hey. what's all the shouting about. Kosugi.
Mr. Tatsumura...
Well. wellntdsure looks like
I'm not very welcome here...?!
Are you Ms. Maezono?
Oh. es.
I'm so sorry that I'm late...
My physical exam took kind of
Iong you see so...
I'm sure you're surprised
at how small our brewery is.
Oh. sort of
But. we're thinking of re-building it,
so that we can mechanizegeverything
in order to mass produce.
Huh...?! You mean, Takakuma?
Mass...produce!
Mr. Tatsumura, I've told you time and again
that we're ndt thinking of doing something
Iike that. Mass production will surely
bring down the quality of its taste.
AS Ou can see,
we've dot a stubborn president.
Distilled spirits-is the in" thing now.
If we don't mass produce now and
make big cash, what's in it for us.
Pips
Uh, I think it's not 1 very good idea
to mass produce.
Huh?
I'll think about whether
I really want:toginterview this situation...
Goodb. e.
Wait, I figured it would have advertising
benefits and I was counting on it too.
Why don't you try to love the liquor
of your brewery a little more?!
You're not even thinking about possibility
of the taste of Takakuma being spoiled.
I can't allow that!
Okay. shall we all go back to work too. then
Even if W's not brought in from the outsido,
unwanted bacteria is already inside
from some time 'in the past
Unwanted bacteria, talking about me...
I tell you. you're all the same.
, I'm against mechanizing
the making of hand-made sake too.
Hmm... Who are you?
Oh. thank ou fore er thing toda. I
wait up. if I remember correctly .
Mhategpnight! You're the renown detective
flKOQOkOMOUfH Oh. you're just the guy.
W. Wait. please wait!
An image character to
advertise the product?
I was looking for someone
who would match the image of our product!
If you agree to accept to do it,
I'll send you as much sake as you want.
Huh. you mean that Takakuma!
Dad. don't tell me that you're going to?!
Well. uh, but, you see...
Aha when it comes to sake,
he's got super weak will power
That's right, I'll take you around tomorrow
It's my day off,
so I'll treat you to some place good to eat.
Please do accept my offer, okay. okay?
Nya. ha. ha
Mr. Mourl, let me do that for you...
Mrs. Shiraishi...
It's a token of my gratitude for you
Iiking our sake so much.
Please let me take you around.
Hmm well,
I guess a woman guide is more enjoyable
I guess I'll leave it up to Mrs. Shiraishi then
and relax as I was planning to anyway.
Mr. Mouri,
I'll be waiting for a good answer.
Ha. hahahaha...
Dad!
Why didn't you refuse; him flatly?!
Oh! It's Takamori Salgo. awesome!
Goodness.
You always avoid things you can't handle.
But for some reason I don't like that
man called Mr. Tatsumura.
The others don't seem to
Iike him much either.
Ha, ha
Wow, they even forecast the direction
of the wind in Kagoshima...
Oh eah.
I wonder for what. though?
I wonder for what, though?
XA YE) XE enn) Wallin
Becauseashes come falling.
Oh good morning.
Good morning.
The ashes of Sakurajima ride the
wind and fly. so hanging the laundry out
whenlthe wind is blowing
wouldibe a disaster, right?
Oh, so that's why the direction
of the wind is a problem.
I wander if lashes will ,
come flying today too
Fuh, fuh, nob: kno «
because the w ad's; capricious
Wow. how'd they write:it?
Uh, Mrs. Shiraishi?
How come the man called
Mr. Tatsumura doesn't getifired
matter with you. brat?!
Conan!
Oh I'm sorry.
Fuh, fuh, I guess, even a child would
think there's something strange about it.
But, we can't fire him because
we owe alot to him from the past.
C= 21 (a8 60 Rm om TO (ext... @l
Our brewery has a history.
But, were a small brewery
without asname to begin with
so our product? didn't sell too well...
If things were left as 1s, we would've been
out of business long ago...
woe somohow made it to where
we are now thanks to Mr. Tatstimura
\. Who is in charge of sales going
all out selling our products.
Still, we are unable to face up to the
major manufacturer's production ability of
Iow profit-high sales way of business...
We were finally faced with
going out of business 10 years ago.
That was 5 years before I got married
Back then, my father-in law,
the predecessor and m husband.
Who was still an apprentice,
came to a decision...
If this was to be it.
They decided to do as
they really wished to do.
And that was to be really
particular about the ingredients
and the method the sake Is made.
They decided to close
the Takakuma Brewery only after
they made the best liquor
they could ever make.
And that's the Takakuma
Yes. And.
It was recognized as genuine
Everybody's waiting for the real thing.
But, in winter of Inst year, because of
his long years of strain from worry
the predecessor passed away...
Don't you forget What
we decided on 10 ye rs ago=p
Y.Yes, sir!
That'srabout when a change
ame about Mr. Tatsumura...
What. mass production ?!
Customers come asking for
the brand name Takakuma.
They wouldmt know the difference
% TRO Quetify Gu fr 80 Liou O TO.
Business! Business!
What a thing to say. Are you going to
allow him to talk like that, president!
He's going to spoil our liquor
We'd better drive him out of here.
I can't. We were rescued from
going out of business thanks to him.
We're'obliged to him and
I will never forget that
You sure are stubborn.
You sure are stubborn
My husband is not really
all that good at getting ahead
He never forgets what
someone has done for him...
He sure is a man of Statsuma.
He's fantastic.
Mr Mourn, please refuse what
Mr Tatsuma asked you to do yesterday
If a famous person lik? you Mr Mount
cooperate with advertising) the product,
he can't lose.
I'm sure that he will forge his way through
to mechanizing the p ocess and
start mass production
I see .
You decided to take over showing
me around to ask me not to listen to him.
Mm SoOrr
Well I was planning to refuse anyway!
Of course. from the very start .
Aha. ha.
Mr... Tatsumura lives In Kagoshima city...
Oh. I'miiglad. he seems to be home.
6:00...eh.
Does Mr. Tatsumura have a family?
No. he lives alone...
Agh it's open?!
I'll go check inside
Mr. Tatsumura. this is Fumiko.
Agh... doesn't something feel sandy?
Ugh...now that you mentioned it.
The ashes are falling...
Oh no
Oh ino
Agh, his car's not here
Kyaaah
Shiraishi!
What's the matter?!
Agh ..agh...
This is 7!
Its blood!
O.Don't tell me it's...Mr. Tatsumurars?!
I can imagine just about what happened.
When Mr. Tatsumura was relaxing
on hisuday off...
on his da off...
Judging from the circumstances,
this is-a-case of kidnapping.
Hem And, when you all came here,.
the fact that the lights were on means that
he was taken away
some time after sundown.
He was taken away
I can give a more exact time...
When I confirmed the time,
the blood stain wasn't dry yet.
That means the time of the murder was
right before 6:00 when we found him. \
See,
Ohatakeyama,
pursue the car on the double.
Yes sir!
U.Uh. 'weren't yo Ma nurse
at the Chuo Hospital... before?
I wasiiuntli5%ears ago when I get martied
Oh. so you are the nurse I saw back then.
Hurry up 'and .get going!
Y.Yes sir]
Y.Yes sir!
Am sorry I gBllyou messedrup
in something bothe some
You must be worried.
He may have {gen a bit of trouble, but
after all Mr. Tatsumura did help'/you out so
If the kidnapper is after money,
he'll surely call to demand ransom.
When he does. we'll nail him...
However, there was no contact from
the kidnapper the following day...
Hmm, I wonder why
the kidnapper's not making contact?
the kidnappers not making contact?
And, another day went by...
The prefecture! police received
an anonymous call,
saying that Mr. Tatsumura, would be found
at Terayama Park in the city.
Mr. Tatsumura!
This is not asplacewhere people **
would normally set foot in.
The caller.was probably the killer .
The voice see ns to have been
a made-up voice,
in which you could not
make out the gender
Kidnap and murder what a guy
Dead for two days?!
0S, according to therresult of the autopsy.
Ho wns killod two days ago,
that I Yon that day.
2 days having past,
it's hard .to"determine.an accurate estimate,
but there seems to be No doubt that
the time of death is between
sundown to night that day.
The cause of his death was
from a blow to the back of his head...
and he seems to have died
instantly with one blow.
What?!
The figurine that was
on the floor of the living room.
The traces on the figurine and
his head matched perfectly
and the blood stains that
were found. wer "Mr. Tatsumura:s
SO Its No doubt-that.
It is: the murder weapon...
Wait a minute.
If Mrs Tatsumura died instantly
ithfone blow to his head.
It means that the killer didn't strike him and
p 18s him out. then take him away but...
killed him on the spot, took him away
and abandoned his car at the park.
IE) (re or rao. Boll ti Te ip
Wa if dam aeasd ala caw 'ab. ble ao Ya ao als?
killed him on the spot, took him away
and abandoned his car at the park.
Dead body and all...
Then, {woidays later today, the killer,
calls from his side to notify the police of
Mr. Tatsumura's whereabouts.
That's the story.
There must be some reason
why the killer went out-of the way to carry
Mr. Tatsumura: out of the house.
Moreover, the killer notified:the: police of
Mr. Tatsumura's 'whereabouts... .But. why?
And, according the report
by the forensic officers...
b the forensic officers...
all the doors and windows of
Mr. Tatsumura's house had no traces of
being forced opened.
Besides, the locks to his house were
all special types that
spare keys could not be made
Il 50,
how did the killer make it into the house
There Is only one way
That is, the killer and
Mr Tatsumura knew each other.
AS to this case, no cash had been;stolen,
SO It IS Not a case of robbery
The only thing thinkable is a grudge.
Somebody hated him
enough to want to kill him
And, moreover,
It was someone who was around him...
which means.
What?! The killer is among us?!
We can't find anybody who had a grudge
against Mr. Tatsumura other than
NSIREOD ISTO IAI SA TEWE TY
Then, why do I have 10 be suspected too?!
We know that you held ill feelings against
Mr. Tatsumura from the information
we got asking around.
Oh...no.
Of course we had a grudge against him
We all did. but.
He was killed at sundown.
The day before yesterday. right?
Then, all of us here were)
In ithe brewery w king!
I thought I already told you that
everyone was working and...
Hmm... It could be that you re all
matching your story up together too
And, Ms. Maezono,
since you say that you were
in your hotel room alone,
your alibi hasn't been backed up yet.
We don't want to suspect any of you,
but what Officer Shmfuku as
saying abides to logical reasoning.
It's true that no one here
Gays 3 Cleatilko) =H
And. everyone hates Mr Tatsumura...
I'll bet Mrs Shiraishi is in agony,
being that everyone
close to her is being suspected.
But I'm sure the killer is
among the people here!
Original Comic Bool By
005110 AOYAMA %
Original Comic 3oOks By.
22080 A 2/044
Producers
Jam IJJJJJUI .
C\IsJJ) Il)!
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story 'Fditore
JUNICHI II KA
KANJI KASHIWABARA
. \.- ~*
!\/\I (MN/PK! LIL/KG!!!
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
TUILTH MNIITGURLD
TOSHIKI WOUE
Antmation Directors.
Wo NT hd) 5 JD
- a BM eS I ob a. >
xxx 4 Lo -
HARUC'OOGAWARA
\ en » . \ :
AU ud¥
TAKASHI FIYG 1920
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO'SHIBU IANI
Ja 0 Phir rap
s0?0c0 ,aO" a A vs A NN \ ud A
sp Vis MB r ob, ')Y ¢ 4
Recording Direcio
KAISUYOSHI BAvA
Editor.
TERUMITSU WKADA
KENJI. KODAMA)
Produced By.
T™MS ENJERTAINMINI ITD.
In association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING:
CORPORALIC N
drircim 1oe)\ AN
CONTHIESTOY IMA) SHOW AREIKAN YIN IMS
Ul Richie Reserved
Sake Is a "living creature.
Once you start preparing it,
ou can't take our e es off it.
That's why you -can't do something
Iike leave the brewery to go kill someone...
You can't do something like that, can you...
Getting right to the point, that
stuff was not found on his clothes at all
E-hem...
Hmm, well so the killer is...
Pops. thus as your chance to show
everyone your real ability!
I guess
(HR)
(12 #0)
KogoroaDrunk Over Satsuma-Part 2
(521)