[OXOOICRK Go Din $136 el
Hand-made liquor brings about a sad result
Pops us» (hunk but t-hu-oasu i1» solved!
N / nal el ey Ve ved AD VIN . YYILAR thy I (\
He Sees th ouqh the one and on truth
A child in appearance with the l1.Q.
of an adult
No case Is loft. unsolved
with Detective] Conan
- Danaaed
We accompanied Pops and
came to Kagoshima,
and visited the Takakuma Brewery,
the maker of distilled spirits.
The crime occurred
ISt as we«were enjoying going
\ghtseeing guided by Fumiko
just as we were enjoying 90mg
sightseeing guided by Fumiko
the wife of the president of the brewery
Who) velit GRE Hie Chad aly (Ad Wives) Vokes 1
The managing director
Shinsuke Tatsumura
1S takon away from his homo by somoono
Two days later... his dead body is found!
What. the killer is among us?!
We can't find anybody
who had a grudge against Mr Tatsumura
other than the people of this brewery'.
I'll bet Mis. Shiraishi is in agony,
being that everyone close to hor
is being suspected.
But.
I'm sure the killer is
among the people here!
(4%)
Kogoro Drunk Over Satsuma Part 2
(1£ $k)
How was It,
after listening to each one's story?
Nothing gained.
Everyone has a motive .nnd
each person's alibi is not definite
And yet, we don't have enough to go on
to arrest an one either.
Don't ou?
Here are two things to go on.
Why did the killer go trough
the trouble of
taking his corpse out of the house
Moreover.
Why did the killer notify the police of
his whereabouts two days later?
If only both mysteries can be figured out.
Ugh!
Dad!!!
Hat's for being sassy saying
something so obvious.
Why don't you hurry up and
solve the m ster then.
Mr. Mouri,
you're going to ask us questions again
tomorrow. aren't you?
Yes. from morning
If it's okay with you,
please spend the night at our home.
Ms. Maezono says she'll do so
because going back and forth
Is too much trouble.
That'll be a great help. I'd sure love to...
Okay
He's not the killer.
If he were, he wouldn't let 2 dotective
spend the night at his house
The ones who 10Ok most unsuspicious
are the ones who are most suspicious.
T lk about suspecting
anything and everything.
Aha. ha...
This is no laughing matter.
Cuz I don't have the slightest idea either.
Two mysteries.
Two mystorios...
I'tn sure there is am answer...
e) txt WA Goo) tdlilkare ex! fo ¢O xd «
Good morning!
Oh good morning
It seems that everyone Is
already here and working.
Making sake starts
from early in the morning.
My husband gots up at 0430
eink T CIOs lnfO HO SRORXOOm OB 000°
KB 308 (hers) Wn 4
Sake is a living creature.
Once you start preparing it
ou cannot take our e es off it...
That's why you can't do somothing
Iike leave the brewery to go kill someone .
You can't do something like that,
(£110 Woven
I came to tell you that breakfast is ready
Thank you.
Anytime you're ready is fine.
The workers who love sake making
would never leave the brewery.
Ifathat's true!...
Dad.
What're you laughing about.
I figured out thd mystery. both of them.
Huh? Really?
The killer is...
Hitoml Maezonol! I
Why do you say it's her?
Bec1use she's tho only wom an
among the suspects.
LI Rud
The Jest mystery.
why did she go through theitrouble of
carrying the comse out of the house?
Mr. Tatsumuraiisthas arstout physique
SO. everybody would think that
it Is impossib e for a woman to carry him...
That is
it would make people think that
a woman couldn't possibly be the killer.
It was a scheme to deceive others
Oh...
(Fens what bout the 2nd mystery?
Why did she notify the police
of his whereabouts?"
Why else?
Sho wantod: 'the doaditorrastiinipoaco
as soon; asipossible
Hor kind womanly side:took over
Therefore. the killer is none:other thanx
and can only be Hitomi Maezono.
I wish Officer Shinpuku
would hurry over here
I'll let him in on My perfect deduction...
But. Pops
What .
You s1id it's impossible for a woman
to carry him,
EC VAR hake I =O Cl) ef
If it's impossible I don't think she on
In Wo ele) (an)
she may not look it
but she's extremely strong!!
L'mi sure: she'silifting weights:or something
Go take a peek in her room
I'misuro shoe's got 2 supor muscular bod
Dont worry,
, evén If you take a peek.
Since you're "child. she'll overlook it...
N.No. darn way!
Help.me out at work a little.«kid!
Come on, how can you even think of
making a child take a peek!
(op SB
Ugh, no, well,
I'm talking in terms of purc detective work
Whew
UMUWUK) I ["11 5 'YR,
No. it's not that I'm slacking off
I'm taking 1 break,
because we're changing shifts.
At this age we can't help but get pooped
How nostalgic thinking about
times back then.
< == 0
Aha...is that you, sit?
20 years ago.
With Mr: Tatsumura, and
the person in the middle is the
previous president, who died last year...
Oh. and who are those children?
The current president
He has; a younger sister.
She's not his younger sister,
but it's Fumiko. the president's wife.
Oh ..they were childhood friends
Sad. this guy next to me is hor Dad
We used to work hora together...
The previous presidentjonly had ene son... _~
So. he took care of her as fi she were his
own daughter
Fumiko's father was also
Very exponenced woken hu
poor thing ho diod of an illness soon
after RuUuMilko entered junior, high schoolt
But the previous president was
not one to abandon the bereaved family.
He encouraged them and continued
to help them.outzmaking a living
He made-sure Fumiko graduated,
from=highe¢school
He even helped her go through
.hursing school
The previous president was a life-saver,
wasn't he, for Fumiko.
IN, OOO 10 Wali OF IR...
Whial
weren't youiat
he Chuo Hospital lbefore...
7 UNL IESINEIENENS @ OF
when I got:married...
She used to be a nurse before right?
Yep. That's why she used
her connections of the past
to get the managing director
an appointment at Chuo Hospital
An appointment?
AN Exp xolinfinqxtngli
For a physical exam
Oh. he maontionod somaothing like that
the other day.
I:m.sorr ..:sorr. . that I'm late
You see the physical exam took
Ionger than I expected...
If she knew the day before that something
Iike that would happen to him,
I think Fumiko wouldn't have recommended
him to get a physical
Huh. you-mean Mrs. Shiraishi is the one
who recommended the physical exam
to Mr. Tatsumura?
There is a physical-exam. every year.
- But the managing director
never underwentione.
However, she kept insisting.he getone
because he was workingitoo hard.
And, he was murdered the following day.
A physical exam
D.Don't tell me that?!
Is anything the matter?
Oh. no. not really
Okay. I guess I'll go back to work then
I have things to finish before
the police bother me with questions.
See ou sonn
It's not impossible
Rather, If that method was used,
1 EAAROROR WAI 0 Too) ON
But. I have no proof
Sakurajima.
If I remember correctly, back then...
Wh? 3 RN
Oh. Mr. Mourri. »
I was just thinking of heading'that way
Huh?
I.have a.favor to ask you b Ford yoM'do.
4 o=g?
Yes, I would lake you to check
Mr. Tatsumura's corpse for me...
No, what I want to know is
whether on the clothes he was wearing...
Come on,
show your super muscle physique!
Just what do you think you're looking at?!
O@fficer Shinpuku and the others
have arrived!
Yes. ma'am
Goodness!!!
Gotting right to the point, tho stuff was not
found on his clothes at all.
£7 h7. What's this about?
All idht. This is it .
You know,
What you asked us to do a while ago...
Oh, no, Dad. You mean you asked a favor
and forgot what you asked
Huh?
OQ. .Oh. that stuff
Oh. so nothing.was on at all.
He's really good at playing along
And. who is at"?
Who is what
I told you on the phone
That we could figure out«the suspect
if we could confirm that fact.
Who is the killer?
{ Did you really say something like that?
Mico DOME: cor fal)
Hmm. ou see. the killerlis
a woman.
Hitomi Maezono?!
Dad!
My reason for coming
that conclusion is...
Pops. this is your chance to.show
RUS AAED on (0) CAI
» Pops. this is your chance to show
everyone your true ability!
Guess:so.
This MT na1ging Director Tatsumura's
homicide case...
who is t "&killer?!
The real killers.is.
Gh~~~! Sakurajima?!
Is something wrongrwith the mountain?
NO, OC a 0 oz olen,
Agh!
{5 AA \/
Agh. Officer Shinpuku!
Oooh~I
Oooh~!
Is this the famous Sleeping Kogoro?!
What is it. Conan?
WH" he's gone
Conan?
He probabl. went ou. side thinking that
Sakurajima &rupted; or something
Mn. Ona
thus 1s the famous Sleeping I OOgoro.
Excuse mo. I'd Mk0 to Mk0 u pncturo
Excuse me. I'd like to take a picture
Excuse me, I'd like to take a plcturo.
Quiet!!
In preparation for killing Mr. Tatsumura.
The killer also schemed an alibi trick
Alibi trick?!
I had an idea of what the trick is
but I needed proof.
And that's why I asked.you
to do me that favor.
The "ashes" of Sakurajima. you mean?
Yes. If thoro was any found on the;clothes
r. Tatsumura was wearing...
There was nonetwhatsoever on his clothes
Howovor,
I already checked with the Kagoshima
District Weather Station a while ago...
And found that on the da of the incident
In the Kagoshima city area
where Mr. Tatsumura's house is.
Ashes;were falling all thexway through
from around noon to midnight.
Uh. doesn't something feel sandy?
The ashes probably came falling...
Yep. ashes» were fal Ing back then.
Isn't it odd?
We arrived at his house at 6:00
in the evening...
If Mr. Tatsumura was killed and
carried out ust about that time
it's only natural that ashes
would have been on his clothes too.
there were no ashes on his clothes at all»...
In other words, Mr. Tatsumura did not
Ieave home at 6:00 sundown,
but before the ashes came falling'...
that 1s some time in the morning
I seal
No. but then...
Yes, there's-a discrepancy.
It's blood
I wonder whit that blood stain was,
Mrs. Shiraishi.
I was mistaken about one thing.
The reason youswant out of your way
that day to take us sightseeing...
thought it was because...
Mr. Tatsumura asked me to pose
for advertisement of your product...
Mr. Mouri,
please refuse what Mr Tatsumura
ilShed you to do tor ham yesterday
I thought that you showed us around
because you wanted me to refuse his offer.
Wasn't
ou did so to establish your alibi and...
To set us up as witnesses to testify
that Mr. Tatsumura was killed
just before we arrived at his house.
Am I not right.
Ir 30 Sd 5 = nl
MM. Mr Mouri?!
I said aaswhile ago that
the real killer isia woman.
A woman
EO WARN) WO WES WEFAN
I'm talking about...
Mrs. Fumiko Shiraishi.
NOW GHOOA REMY «0
to take us sightseeing.
That morning-you .
Made up some excuse and summoned"
Mr. Tatsumura out to the park...
Mrs. Shiraishi
She probably said something like,
I'd like to talk to you."
andimade him get in the car once more .
Ind put him to sleep...
Getting anesthesia ready and
gettingwblood samples
wore onsy for you to do
for you were a nurse before
Then, after that you came
to pick us up at the hotel.
Oh." good morning!
Good morning
You spent the whole day with us
and cleverly lead us
to Mr. Tatsumura's house
Oh. it's open.
I'll go check inside
Mr. Tatsumura!
This is Shiraishi!
And, you carried out what you schemed
in the living room...
Kyaah!
Mr. Mouril!
Mrs. Shiraishi!
What seems to be the matter?!
Out of the two mysteries one of them.
Why did the killer go out of the way
to carr the corpse out
rather .
Du didn't carr him out.
There, was no corpse
In that house to begin.
But the lights in theihouse were on,
weren't they?
Before you came to pick us up.
You borrowed the keys from Mr. Tatsumura
who was asleep
went into his house.
Turned on the lights
as well as unlock the
ront entrance door at that time
So. that's he story
age. I [goon A
Hold on a second!
Now for tho 2nd mystory
Wait. Wait a minute. I said.
W at you.re saying is strange.
0 It's. totally strange
You seem to want to insist
Hat Fumiko is the killer.
But. she was.with you al day that day.
There's no Way she
could've done it
When on earth could she have dono it?
Right. Dad. when. ?
Right after the you know what,
right Mrs Shiraishi?
I'm sorry to have otten you involved
in something bothersome like this. . "
After youl dropped us off at the hotel...
hats when
You got a bronze statue
just like the one at Mr. Tatsumura's
house beforehand...
n other words. this case occurred after...
he police began investigation.
It was a blind spot...
It cant be helped
No one ordinarily checks for alibis
after the investigation starts
You triedto make usithink
that the-estimated™timeiof the murder
was; justibefore we arrived
at Mr2Tatsumura's residence
Doing so would give you a perfect alibi
Because after a I
you were with us right through.
The 2nd m ster...
Why did the killer notify the police of the.
whereabouts of the corpse:two days later?
Since time passed and
an accurate estimate-time of death
couldn't be acquired.
But if\the corpse was found between
sundown that day or -at night...
The estimated time of death
would come out accurately.
16 Om mmormmm dom 1 emG0 mem lon Somer mmmmus sm omsom
On the other hand
if the corpse 1s left as is for ma \y days.
It would be impossible to figure it out
Either way, would make
meaningless the alibi that is perfect.
That's why it was bet
for the corpse.to be found 2 days later.
Mr Mouri...
When and how did you figure out
I committed the murder
On:-the:da ibeforeithe-incident
you fecommended Mr. Tatsumura
to go get a physical exam «didn-t you?
Oh~ ..that...
What:do you mean?
If you take. a blood sample.
The trace of the needle
would be left behind.
And that would bring about
suspicion during the:-autops .
But. if he gets a physicalthe day before
blood samples would naturally be taken
In other words.
She injected him in the exact same place
that he was injected the day before.
Liseel
I see!
wt. why
3ut. why
Why did you kill Mr. Tatsumura 7?
I was 8a: 4
I thought that if he kept on staying
at this brewery,
one day someone would be
influenced by-him and
stop making sake. the old way
as "1 result dropping t-he quality of our sake
That someone who was concerned
only about making monaqy
would one day come along
No way. Mrs Shiraish
Not among anyone of us. never!!!
Maybe now.
But, people change
when various things happen.
Mr. Tatsumura.
Hn Ing exo to, Cle [hf
I'm to blame
I'm .to blame f&Pall this
I should've fired him,
Not being able to«get rid of somebody
AO NAG) Ad (raAan 8
one of your good points. It's okay.
But, why
why did you.
I just wanted to look good
I wanted to say,
I'm the one who saved this brewery...
Of course she is not be forgiven
for killing someone
But, she did what she did
wanting to repay your {athor
or his kindness...
Io father...
One who never forgets
a kindness received...
Your wife is justiliko you,
a woman of Satsuma for sure.
Fumi... ko
of course we're alike...
We're husband and wife
Yo / 7
Don'tObother seeing me off
You have to hurry back to the brewery.
Mrs. Shiraishi...
Fumiko .
Thoro 2ro pooplo throughout Japan
ho are waiting for the sake that you make...
I'll wait for you too
I'll wait till you come back...
while continuing to make genuine sake
A case was thus, closed
Original Comic Beo. Ry
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MIC TIHIKO SUW
MASAHITO YOSH OK
Background Music
LU) al
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDQ
Story Fditor
KAN]? IFASHIWABARA
CHI MIYAS
YUICHLHILWRE
TOSHIKd 1 TOUT
Amimation Directors.
MAS/DEMO 51/150)
I vat
HARUO OOGAWARA.
AINUSHI A NY
AKIO KAWAMURAO
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBU TANI
Dirc¢ctors Of Photooraphy.
TAKASHI NOMUR.
IRONOBU H@RIIOSF
TAKAHISA QWAGA
Recording Direcio
ditor.
TERUMITSU. WKADA
Chief Director.
KENJI KODAMA
Produccd By
IMS ENTERTAYNMEN LTD
th assow ion with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
mmm un (MU sncfmuvk mm 11m
NURIENISREITTALN,
they don't have it here after all,
the Takakuma
Takakuma, Takakuima
Oh whoe¢ros
LIFjust get anythingsthat s around!
Yiouiresgill BUY Hg?
ABSObDEde
ow \@r ad»
You're still Buying
SOG er
n tam O .
Yaad, MON Any 0
\ BN HN NAN
It's more quantity than quality after all.
Or AGE 021018500 GOR TRO Hot Th
PW'?
son Seon row
Black vinegar is 'good for the health.
Black vinegar is good for the health.
Like father like daughter. really
Good morning! Is there: something
on my-face?
I saw a suspicious looking person
n thesway to school!
(313%)
(33%)
Love Story. at Police Headquarters 6"
Part 1