In today s ¢1se
the suspect is a police.~'<I'e.tectiv¢.QYfruJui.
How far will the love of the two go
After overcoming:the obstacle filled scene
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I. Q. of an adult
No case is*left.unsolved
with Detective « 6han.
An hh wm wm av
Hoaring that he would be
dispatched to hottor
to work on a joint investigation project.
Officer Tiakagi is flustered.
Despite the fact thatethey may
have to be separated for at least 3 years
Officer Sate.remains the same as always...
While all this is going on,
we happen to witness
the suspect of a homicide case.
And.
You're the one who stabbed Hirotoshi
and killed him, aren't you?!
Huh?
Me: commit murder?!
Just what are you talking about?!
Out of the blue like that...
What's going on!
Cut out the noise...
What?!
Hmm... .H.Huh?
O.Officer Chiba?!
Oh-this is interesting...
Love Story at Ponce Hondquarlnrs 6"
Part 2
(15 #3)
Love Story at Police Headquarters 6°
Part 2
(1521s)
Hey. Chiba! Come here...
Oh. es sir .
Ole $08, ll?
WIRE sR
C.Chiba?!
- H Hey! Chibal Is it true
AU? YY
What you said aboultsbomgawith that man
and watching TV. with him
durnng the time of theircrnme?
You're not lying. are you?!
U.Uuugh.
Chib1! I'm asking if you swonr by
this Cherry Blossom crest!
Y Yeas sir! I swear!
"seen.
Sow...
Chiba...
Y.Yes sir...
Being a police detective is a crummy job...
Think. think...
Hurry. the Continuation. continuation!
Next it's finally episode 4!
Yaiba's archrival theiPotate Baron appears!
CC. Come to think of it.
If I remember correctly...
No doubt about it!
The killer Is Mr. Kato!
e deceived Officer Chiba
and used him to establish his alibi...
He twisted the passage of time
with blood smeared hands...
Hmm. I can't find a thing...
Neither can I find the parker .
nor the black knapsack
that the suspicious
Iooking man had on him...
How is it over there
Nothing hero
Nothing here
How about over there?
Nothing anywhere...
Nothing scorns to be around
guess not...
t least not here...
I guess Mr. Kato who is freelonding hore
with you is not a suspect after all .
O Oh. yeah...
Then, who on earth is it?
they saw near the scene of the murder...
I 'was probably another man,
who looked very much like him!
Because during the time of the crime.
Mr. Kato has an alibi
that he was here watching Merning
Live Seven!with Officer Chiba...
that he was here watching Morning
ive Seven with Officer Chiba...
Okay. we'll leave for now!...
We've got to se "the children home too.
Anyway, that's onough for today...
Gees. Megure told me to learn something
from this veteran investigator
but at this rate
Hey. Officer €hiba
Officer Chiba.
Agh!
Will you go get Mr Kato who's
aiting in the police car
WE ERR ¢ oO aia,
without tolling him goodbye. so.
1.1 go get Rim!
I.I'll go get him
85 (XR Le 0 OK E02 Ya
) Rom hee) RO lot)
Tako too long...?
WwW. Wit
if it takes long for this ¢aseto be solved .
Maybe I won't have to be dispatched
to work on the joint investigation in Totton
and stay here with-Officer Sato
You fool! Just what'sswrong with you?!
I'm a police-officer
so I've got te solve the case
15 SOON as possible
\Hey, hey, this is no time
to\be Absorbed in y8ur thoughts...
Don't worry...
I'll make sure I got thus use
solved before leaving {or rotten...
Y.Yes sir
Well. if it's going to take long
all you gotta do is
have someone else take over
It's as simple as that...
T.That's right.
Lverythimg ll go fine
Huh?!
Everything'll go fine!
Officer Takagi...
I don't think'll take that long...
I've been telling you. haven't 17?!
During the time of
the crime from 7:00 to 7:30.
I was watching TV together
with Chiba in the living room!
Uh, Mr Kato!
Huh?
What was that program
you were watching?
IR 17
I.Like I said. Merning Live Seven!
Which one?
Ugh!
Which one but the one aired on NiChiur
TV from 7:00«n the morning?
WP NsN5 4404
Morning Live Seven is also playing
on cable TV from 9:00 in the morning too.
True...
Which means
even if It were to take
an hour and a half by car from here.
He could've killed Mr. Nakamoto
at a little after 7:00 in the morning
come back here.
Wake Officer Chiba up at 9:00
and watch Morning Live Seven.
Playing on cable TV together
It scems possible for him
to establishf fake alibi...
Huh 2!
Chiba you said that
you both drank last night
and you fell asleep
In the living room. right?
QffiQG $5110...
If he made Chiba drink
to make him groggy: in the morning.
And if Chiba who was awakened
in.the morning still half asleep...
He probably wouldn't have realized it
if it were the cable TV program...
WW, WEIR & mllsu EH
WwW. Wait a minute! J
could've been half asleep but...
You ca it trick the video. can you?
Tho vidoo I rocordod this morning of
Morning Live Seven's cooking corner
had the time and
everything recorded too. didn't it?
QO {he bot ne vO Soven
that played on cable TV
thoesidivie avourkdn't besdisplayed!
It's aired two hours later. you know...
That's true too...
Besides,
after watching Morning Live till 8:00.
We watched a 6 hour video.
And like I was saying
he was with me all the while
while we watched
the live baseball broadcast from 2:00.
Ben Cho-san nd ll of you came
part way throuch the game
The only time I wasn't with him was
when I went to take 1 bth
for about 30 minutes.
It would've been impossib e for him
to even make it to the scene of the crime
that would've taken
more than an hour vb car
Well, I took a bath
after watching the video half way.
I think it was about 11:00.
So I think
it would've been impossible for him
to commit the crime to begin with... l
But,
with 30 minutes
there's .1 lot you um do
You can make coffee
watch TV...
Dub videos...
Dubbing!
D Dubbing!
Right! Dubbing videos.)
I see!
If he had set the timer to record
Morning Live Seven before going out.
He could've dubbed it.over
the cable TV program
that Officer Chiba recorded!
Moreover, what he taped was
Yoko Okino's 4-minutc cooking!
Hone are two decks
$030 minutes would he mere than enough!
B But if there's no time display
I think I would have noticed
when I recorded the program...
Oh. I wonder about that?
'Hose memo stickers
that are stuck all over the TV...
If youiroc usod to scoing all these memos
onthe set all the time like that
even If you can't sce the time display
on the upper left. you would just.figure
that's the reason
why you can't see the tame.
And it wouldn't even bother you. right?
You seem to have known that
the cooking corner was
after the weather forecast so
you don't have to see the time to record it...
And, you also mentioned th
the flash news about Hide was
displayed on the screen during
Morning Live Seven. right?
Y.Yeah...
f the program that
you were 'watching was really
the news variety program
from 7:0 in the morning.
I think they would have talked about
that news during the program...
In other words,
even If it's a live program If it's a recording.
New news coverage is impossible?
Chiba!
You said that the news on the video
wasn't mentioned in the program. right
Y, Yeah
I think that sort of news wns on display
when Chiba left to go to the restroom...
B.But. don't forget
we were watching the Kamen Yaiba video
from 8:00 in the morning for 6 hours!
We were watching the Kamen Yaiba video
If you include the time
that Chiba was taking a bath.
It's 6 and a ha f hours!
If we werefwatching Morning Live Seven
on cable TV from 9:00 to 10-00.
Then we would've finish @
watching the video at 16-30!
The live baseball broadcast was until 16-00
so it would've been finished
and you all came here
a little before16:00. right?
In I,
Now that he 'montions it, that's true...
So. I wouldn't have had tho time
Uh, what time did you begin
watching the Yaiba video
OO. hikovyl've been teething you!
At; 800 mm the morning!
Ot ou but them!
Huh?
A little before
we began soarching this room
-aO 7
(Ou 98590
Which moans abouttwo hours have P1sSod
since they started watching...
Right...
Fright.
Hay. you guys...
What 'episode «aro you watching now?
Here goes! Secret techniquo
Yaiba Thunder Gosh Fist!
Hey! Tell me what episode you're watching!
The last scene of opisode #6!
His is the good part, you know!
Stop bugging us. Conan!
Episode #6 .
What is the meaning of this?
If the apisodes are 30 mimates long.
Three hours should've gone byt
Mitsuhiko. quick! The continuation!
Yes. yes.
Uh:the next one is...
It's not only the commercials!
They:can:t.wait to watch the next episode
that they. re:iskipping
the.opening theme song as well as the.end.
Preview of tho noxtiepisode.and
the 'summary of tho previous episode
before the title scene...
So, it only takes them a little more than
20 minutes to watch an episode...
WwW. Were you doing that too?
Y.Yea...probably...
sl hen, watching 12 episodes
would be 240 minutes,
that's only 4 hours!
Between the hours of 9.00 to 10:00
if programs that were 2 hours delayed
were shown to you...
if after that Chiba was shown that video
the discrepancy In time
would be compensated
and you'd mako it.for
the live baseball broadcast at 14:00
Very smart. sonny...
Moreover.
Since Chiba took a bath part way
his concept of time
could've been thrown off a bit...
Even if he were to watch
the baseball game from after all started,.
he wouldn't be able to
tell how much time passed.
SO. LM can be
connectad very Conveniently!
B.But, @hibh1 went te the restroom
and-to the kitchen to get drinks too!
Od you look eR ho « » fo?
NEE Ro) GREENER Cid
there-was anything odd going on though...
So. he must ve rigged it. right?
R.Rigged?! The clock?
He mgged the clock two hours backwands
before waking Officer Chiba up.
He moved the hands of the clock
herein thesliving room and the kitchen...
hile Officer Chiba was
absorbed in watching the video,
Mr. Kato slowly¥moved
the clock back to the original time. right?
The living] room. clock is opposite the TV.
And as for the clock in the kitchen,
if ou c ose the door ou can't see a thing
so it ll be easy
to move the hands of the clock!
But there arc clocks
in the bedroom and the front entrance too.
Officer Chiba fell 8816(4)
in this living room last might...
And when he took a bath,
his change of clothes are here so.
The clock in the bedroom was
probably left untouched.
thinking that Officer Chiba
wouldn't go thoro 1nywny
Then, what about
the clock at the front entrance?
He can't touch the clock
at the front entrance!
When the courier comes
at the specified time.
and thot4ime on the clock Is not night.
It'll be odd!
I.] see
1.] see.
I'm pretty sure that
Mr. Kato made sure that...
when somebody came to the door he
would answer it. in place of Officer Chiba.
Come to think of it.
when we got here you...
Hoy, kid! Where do you have such proof .
Why don't you ask Officer Chiba. then?
W.What /!
Kite...
Kato...
The clocks in this house were
UNSC Hannules carly
So that I wouldn't over sleep
b JON
I just went lo check, but only
the clock in the living room and the kitchen
had been returned to
the original timelby someone...
K,K1to
You're the only one who could've...
Y.You gotta be kidding!
I'm called a killer just
because your clocks were delayed!
If you suspect me, show me
proof that I killed the guy!
Oh I'm suro that
at can be found on thdway here...
beep!
It's been found!
Huh?!
Just now .
Between the scene of the crime ind here
the black.knapsackiwas
found with a weight tied on it,
at the bottom of thc~Teimusu River
Inside, it were 1 blood smeared
shirt and slacks...
as well as a parker smeared
with blood on the inside.
Which he seems to
have been wearing on top of shirt.
Moreover
here and there on the knapsack.
Thoro.secemaoed to be
blackencd red fingerprints
which probably got on there
when he took off his shirt
that wns splattered
with the blood of the victim...
And, of course, you know who
those fingerprints belong to. don't you?
Well,
it seems that thc car you rented last night
was also found at a nearby parking lot.
So we'll check it out later too...
That's a problem...
As for those red fingerprints,
I was going to wipe them off clean later.
That they're still all ever the car...
It was you. after all!
Y.You used me?!
You deccived me to establish your alibi...
Yeah I figured the police would believe
your testimony since you're a cop...
Kato. how dare you.
Sorry
I couldn't think of Any ether way to let out
y anger of having my girl taken away.
I knew that
my girl's feelings for me had waned
whie I was abroad on my business trip so
I wasn't 1ll that shocked when I heard that
she was getting married to Nakamoto.
TYR Ue Ck eta
when I went to give him a piece of my mind
andy was shown the letters
and postcards that I had sent.
He had the nerve to say.
What a push over."
while grinning as he threw them at me...
All th stcards and unopaned leiors
What I had wiltten whalo I was abroad
So. he probably kept them from her even
before she could read them
That's what made me lose my temper:...
I was so furious t at I didn't even notice
all the clocks here were
set 5 minutes earlier...
the sneakers that you saw
inside the shoe cabinet?
Yeah.
The seams of the shoe strings were damp.
While all the other shoes were
clean and dry...
Wouldn't you think it's strange?
If he washed his shoes, he would've
removed the shoo strings at least. right?
So. that's how
you figured the killer was Mr. 'Kato!
Hat he hastily dried his shoes with a. dryer
after he'washod the mud
from the roan off has shoes
right... and after that I dispatched
mvestgators to places
between her. and the scene of the crime
where he may have thrown
the black knapsack away...
I did it all after I confirmed that
Chiba wasn't lying to protect his friend...
I didn't want to think that way
but if Chiba were an accomplice.
They would've thrown
the stuff away somewhere farther...
What.do you moan?
Then. you suspected Officer Chiba too?
Yah,
A police detective is
1 crummy job where you have to
suspect even the nicest people...
I'll bet Officer Chiba-who is facing that
man in the interrogation room right now
is taking the blow right now...
So 10 you
I'll leave the roost up to you...
A. ER
Oh, yos sir... .wo'll tako tho childron homo.
I get to sit in the front seat!
What? again?! That's not fair!
Genta! You should let us sit
In the passenger's seat sometimes too!
Come. come...don't fight and hurr inside!
Oka it's stone-paper-scissors!
C. Conan, coma horo ploaso!
Never mind him!
Right!
Police detective...
A police detective is a crummy job
where you have to suspect people...
Officer Sato. aren't you going to doubt me?
I'm. going to Tottori. you know?!
I might be hit on by some cute co-worker
If ou real! like me...
If you even have a:tinge of feeling for me.
He! Come on. get lin.
You could at least show
a tinge of anxiety or something...
\ ah!
Huh?!
O.Officer Sato...
Who 1s it?! Who's the one
that played a prank like this?!
How terrible!
This is a challenge to the police!
Oh, no. that's what
Officer Sato did herself... Huh?
Huh?
You mean shes a bit concerned? No...
Uh...You won't, right?
Cheat on me...
Huh? Oh, of course not
Even if a super cute mini skirt
police woman or a sexy actress
comes to the station
as one day chief of police?
You really won't?
O.Officer Sato...
I'll go over there...
and become a way finer
police detective than I am now!
So...So..before I go...
So. before I go. p.please...
Please
w:with- me...
E.Engage...
Where are you going?
Huh?
In.Inspector Megure...
S.Sergeant Matsumoto...
Agh.
Huh?
Original Comic Beet. By
065110 AQYAMA
Producers.
IHHIKQO .
VM SAHITOY « ~ OK
Background Music
AKATSSUO «(DN
Character Designs By.
MASATOMOSUDO
Story 'Fditor,
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOS IKd INOU
Anna (pn ADDIrcectorsa
MASATOMO SUD
HARUC ( DGAWARA
ATSUSHI AGN
AKIO KAWAMURA*
TAKASHI HYOCD
Art Director.
YUKITHIRO'SHIBU 1ANIL
Directors Of Photosraphy.
TAKASHI NOMUP
TAKAFI1sA
Recording Dire or
KATSUYOSH BAVA
ditor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Clef Director.
KENJLKODAMA)
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LID.
11 ssoalalipn wilh
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
141 TFC TIVO AN
CONSTI TOY WIAA S1HOG ARR AN YIN TAS
WIRE its hosed
Whaaaaat?! LN
C Che-saws going to Tottori?!
N.Not me?!
You fool!
E can't dispatch a greenhorn
Iike you to another prefecture!
He's going as a representative of
the Tokyo Metropolitan Police after all...
B.But Inspector,
you called me at home this morning...?
Sorry! His name Is Chosuke Takagi!
Since you both have the same ast name
I made a mistake... Aha. ha...
Che-saws last name isuTakagii?
I tell you. that Yumi...!
Acchoo! Oh, no?
I wonder if somebody's talking about me?
Take care of the children. okay .
Be careful taking them home!
Oh. es sir...
Huh?
With me. what...?
Oh. well, you see...
P.P.Please be. be. be...
R.Right!
Before heading home. let's go to Karaoke!
Oh. sounds good!
K.Karaoke?!
4¢ ¢? at
1Ayel
Let's! Let's!
Kamen Yaiba! Kamen Yalba!
Sigh
Would you like something to drink?
What arday...
What on earth was he waiting for?
WwW. What... 7?
What?!
110 centimeters
T. That's a child!
But, how could he do something hike that?
Ihe thing that you waited for, for § hours
1 MreKitamura's president's room.
Mystenous 200Centimeters
Height Discrepancy