Will Officer Takagi make it through today
£30 URE esio Al 0 &g
Will the police be able to outwit the killer!
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I. Q of an adult
No case is left.unsolved
with Detective Conan.
I've to a lot of things to buy:today.
SO be prepared. okay?
At util
Y.Yep...
She sure is in a good mood...
It sure feels good-today!
Y.Yep ..true .
C.Conan?!
I'll be right back!
M sorr to bother ou man times...
I'd like to confirm the time and situation
f when the body was found again...
The time was yesterday at 08-00
Thegpresidentdidn't show up for the
morning assembly before work
SO you went to call him.
Oh. yes sir!
This way. please
The president's room is In
another building...
Yes. it's beyond the office.
You found President Katsugoro Kitamura
Iying there on the floor.
Yes. sir. that's right
President...
Excuse mo
President Is there going to be
no morning assembly today?
President?
President?!
President.
Yikes!
P President!
Mysterious 20 Centimeters
Height Discrepanc
Did you noticevanything at that time?
Did ou notice an thing at that time
Not that ILcan remember...
The culprit was already arrested. right?
Hy are you investigating things again...
You don have concrete evidence?
Yeah... rather...
We found out something totally absurd...
Huh? Whaaaat?!
UR. what's that absurd thing
that you found out about?
C Conan?!
Conan! Conan.
Just what do you thinkgyeu're doing?!
I'm so soni 4
And. what's that absurd thing
that you were talking about?
Vos \Wiwaell »
The ma: im ism: K2 sugars Magma sue 47
He is the president of this factory
The estimated time of death is
between 16:00 to 22:00 hours.
Soon after the body was found
a cordon was set up
The following day. the suspect,
yesterday. that is,
was taken custody at the police.
However,
The-suspect is Yuichi Minamida. age 47
He.is an owner chef of
a smallwcstern food restaurant. and.
I was a classmate of the victim
in high school.
It's true that I went
to Kitamura's place yesterday.
But. ll didn't do it
But. I didn't do it.
You had a debt of 30,000,000 yen
that you owed Mr. Kitamura.
He refused to extend the deadhne
for your giving him back the money.
SO you were cornered. and stabbed him.
That's the stor , isn't it?
Do you have evidence?
Are my prints on the knife
that is the murder weapon?
We detected no fingerprints.
But we found a piece of cloth
In other words the fiygerprints
were wiped:;off completelyr
after the murder was committed .»
Inspector Megure!
Hmm?
Besides. owing Mr. Kitamura money.
you have another strong motive to kill him,
don't ou?
\Mr Kitamuraiwas. after yourishop and
your land.
e spread rumors about
the sanitation standards at your shop.
Which sent you into a financial rut.
He lenty ou 30.000:000 yen 3lmonths ago.
Minamida, after finding out
what. Mr. Kitamura was actually after.
Was enraged and told the people
around him how vexed he was.
On the da of pa. ment,
that is the day the murder was: committed,
at 13:00
Minamida appeared at this office
to see MrKitamura
It's already 15:00!
Just how long do you intend to stay here?
It's already 15-00!
WARREN
Just another, 3 days. no 2 days'll do.
I lent you the cash
because of the good old times.
If you don't have the cash,
give me the deed to the land.
Kkitamulfa!
What the...?
Excuse me. president!
Ware having some problems
with the machine...
Oka! Go on ahead!
Oh. es sir. . Thank ou.
I tell you! Totally hopeless...
W.What do you think you're doing?!
Know just what you're after!
Let go of me!
You schemed it from the very start!
Let go!
You were after my land to begin with!
So what!
Leave your deed here and get ost.
Ou darn oser!
Think those words-made...
Minamida mak Jup his mind
He waited for Kitamurafto return...
Whaaa!
But Minamida...
Yes. he did come back after
about 30 minutes.
I started to negotiate with him oncesagain,
and stayed there until around 6:00
in the evening
but.was eventually kicked out of the room
Huh? A person who can testify&to that?
I don't know.
I 28)"
You've got all the circumstantial evidence,
but no concrete evidence...
Agh..ha ha
I'm sure this is what Pops would say.
Aha. ha... You haven told me
about the absurd thing yet!
Ia! A
The absurd thing 1s the height difference
between the suspect and Minamida.
147 A
Hoght difference
Just what do you mean?
Height difference.
He's pretty tough to handle. Besides...
The strange confidence I sense from him
bothers me too...
Inspector!
I got an absurd report
from the forensic officer .
The height ofathe victim Kitamura is
166 .centimeters.
And Minamida is 186. centimeters.
Minamidq Is 20 centimeters taller
If so. then. what?
In the case that a tall person stabs
person shooter than he is.
The angle of the knife would usually be from
diagonally above.
On the other hand if a short person stabs I
someone taller lha 'himself.
It would be from diagonally below.
The knife that was stabbed into Kitamura's
chest was from diagonally below.
In other words A
it's impossible for Minamida
who 1s 20 centimeters taller
to have committed.the crime.
O Oh no...
So. I had the forensic officers use the angle
of the knife to calculate backwards and
come up with the height of the killer...
And %7
And. .?
Yes. sir! The results came out to be
that the person is 110 centimeters...
Huh?!
110 centimeters?
T. That's the height of a child!
I get it!
If the killer stabbed from below
where there arejstairs
even with Mr. Minamidas*newgnt,
he'd be able 10 stab from below.
The scene off the murder was
a one-stony building.
With no stairs.
And there were no traces of the body
being moved.
Then!iHe probably attacked the victim
when he was off his guard...
Oh! Just what do you think you're doing?!
He sank down low on the spur
of the moment and stabbed?
Takagi... You just stabbed me. didn't you
Agh. aha. ha. "m sorry.
Inspector!
I think that the killer is Minamida too...
But,
the victim was stabbed from the front...
SO. it's hard togbelieve that: he was attacked
When 'he was off his guard...
Moreover. a week before the incident
Minamida sprained his ankle.
I. wonder if he'd be able to sink down low
on the spur
of the. moment-with his leg in a cast.
He would never be able to do something
Iike that...
He may have been threa enedfF ith
the knife and forced to go up somewhere
and stabbed from below...
That's not possible
The victim, Mr. Kitamura 1s
a ranking judo belt owner
Iso he wouldn't be intimidated by Minamida
sticking a knife at him.
Everyone around him. says
Kitamura was probably strong enough +
to attack Minamida instead.
'Rue. no, matter how you look atfit
Does that mean the difference in heights
hat's protecting Minamidar
You've got another picture!
No. Conan!
Huh? This mans wearing glasses!
He's not wearing them in the other picture. 4
on ab
Oh. these are reading glasses.
Reading glasses aro something you wear
when reading something. right?!
Does that mean that Mr. Kitamura was
attackediwhen he was reading something? P
But .
There's nothing like that imthis room...
Right
the thing that Mr. Kitamura was supposedly
reading back then is nowhere in sight.
The problem is that something is gone.
And Minamida took it with him.
Oh! ou're right on, Officer Takagi!
Hat on earth could it be.
We still don't know why he took it
with him...
Uh. are these slippers the president's?
Yeah. that's right
What about when Mr Minamida came
the da before esterda ?
Of course he was wearing them.
Mr Minamida was barefootthoug...
why are the slippers over here like this?
They probably came off from'the im act
when he was stabbed!
Impact?!
But. isn't it strange that they came off
from the impact when he was stabbed?
Huh?
Because they're nicely in place just as If
someone had put them in place. right?
I haven't touched them!
The slippers have been this way
moo the body was found.
The came off...
If not so, Mr. Minamida took them off
after he killed the victim. ?
Wh would he « 0 out of his wa
to do something like that?
- <4 /
2 - -—
You think so. don't you?
Oh. or mayb¢ Mr Kitamura took them off
mes {...
That's it!
But. why would he do something like that?
I can't figure it out!
Stabbed from the front diagonally below?
Height difference?
A ll.ladder?
WW.What... 7?
What did he do?!
President Kitamura
used the ladder...
To do what?
But. wait, why did Minamida think up
something like this?!
Why would an ordinary chef think up
the trick of reversing the fact
about his height
by doing somcthing like this?!
What were you waiting for?!
At first we thought it was-aicrime committed
on the spur of the: moment.
But after watching you,
we've come to understand
that it was a carefully thought-out murder
If so,
there's got to be 1 reason why you stayed
in the president's room: from 13:00 to 18:00.
You had another purpose
iden eng)
10 extend the me of repayment
ORNS & Ht
Five hours in the president's office!
Just what on earth
were you waiting for?
A miracle. I guess.
Officer Takagi...
I've found out something absurd!
But. this is only a deduction.
I need evidence that will lead him
to confess...
Proof
Whaaaat?!
S...Something absurd?!
Another absurd thing. 4
I hope it's not bad news.
' I-- 0
Ec Ts,
there was a series of random killings
within the Minato Police Station.
The person who was arrested back then,
Mos suk a Dalia: Yaadkek )
who was javcompany cmployee!
Although Minamida denied this.
The prosecutor had confidence
and indicted him
But, the evidence that
his lawyers submitted saved Minamida.
That proof was the angle of the stab
wound that the random killer left behind
It was proven that with his height
Minamida wouldn't have been able to stab
anyone at that angle.
Moreover, during his hearing
a new killer was arrested...
And the case was solved.
Which means that
Minamida knew from the start that the
height difference between him
and the victim would serve
as evidence in court?
I see! That's why he thought up this trick.
Right. In thissgase,
a trick involving height difference was used!
A trick >
using height difference is involved ..7!
A And what kind ofétric dis that,
Officer Sato!
I haven't figured it"outkyet...
I'll go report this to Inspector Megure.
Officer Takagi,
go back to headquarters right away too!
I'm going back to headquarters then...
Thank you so very much!
Oh...No problem .
Is Mr Kitamura's height 166 centimeters
tall for an adult?
Huh?
I want to become an adult quickly too.
Because it's inconvenient being a child.
When things are in high places
I've got to use a ladder.
Adults are lucky at that point because
they don t have to use a ladder .
A ladder...?!
That's not real y true
When cleaning the air conditioner
and changing light bulbs
even Dad uses a ladder...
Agh?!
Light bulbs.
If the light bulbs were out at that time...
You mean the lights so conveniently
went out back then....?
C.Conan!
IF WOO) QO SINE VO EY,
Turn on the lights when it gots dark...
Conan.
She used to say that we'll ruin our eyes
If we read in dark places.
n dark places...a book. .?!
Roading glasses and
Iight bulbs.
Slippers .!
I.l see!
You guys get going home too! Okay.
All that I need now, us proof
to make him confess what he did...
Cee Tee
He seems to have hit upon aw ideal!
Mr. Yuichi Minamida
you stayed in Mr. Kitamura's office
for O hours. waiting for.
Sundown" isn't thattit!
S.Sundown?
WwW. Why would I have to wait for sundown...
Because that's when Mr. Kitamura turns on
the lights of the office.
But the chandelier did not turn on that day.
Mr Kitamura who wanted to check out
what was wrong. climbed a ladder
You took this opportunity to stab
Mr. Kitanmura
who is 20 centimeter: shorter than you,
from below
R.Ridiculous...
Are you saying that the bulbs
just"happened to go out on that day?!
Are you saying that I knew
the bulbs were going to go out?!
He bulbs didn't go out...
VO URODSSN EUR
WwW. What do you think you're doing?!
I know what you re after!
Let go of my hand!
From the beginning,
from the very start you!
Lot go!
You were after my land!
Eating, going to the restroom,
If you stick it out for.5 hours
you had all the opportunity in the world
to wait for Mr. Kitamura to leave the office.
You probably loosened the bulbs when
he left to go check on machine trouble.
Mr .Kitamura left the room for 30-minutes
How can you be:sure that Kitamura would
check the bulbs of the chandelier himself!
He's so haughty, it's more likely
that he'd call one of his employees.
In order for him not to do;so.
In order for him not to do so.
You handed over some important
documents after it started getting dark...
is reading glasscs told us so
Reading glasses?
The dead body was wearing
reading glasses...
He was reading something. no rather
It's evidence that he was trying to.read
something...
That something was also very important
to the killer...
It was the deed for the and.
Where your shop is
that Mr. Kitamura wanted. wasn't it?
You've finally decided to give this to me...
Hmm?
It's not a b ack out
Darn! Not again...
Why at a time like this...
You set it up so that he would find
calling one of his employed a waste of time
that he checked the light himself .
Hmm? What's this,
they're just loose .
You admit to your crime. don't you?
His reading glasses and slippers
will probably serve as evidence
that Mr. Kitamura climbed the ladder.
But,
that's not proof that I loosened the bulbs.
Takagi
O.Officer Takagi...
Hey. hey...
It's me... Mouri...
Oh! Mr. Mouri!
I hea d about the case from Ran.
WIF Wed pm!
Did Minamida confess?
A little bit more.
He demanded that I show him proof
that he rigged: the chandelier...
Not having proof is the proof...
Huh? Just what do you mean...?
Yes. .Yes...
Yes .Yes...
I see! I understand. Ill do so right away!
Inspector!
I'm going to check with the forensic officers!
Hmm? Oh. hey. Takagi. Takagi!
Whation earth is on his mind. anyway?
Okay! This is it for now!
F.For now...?
Mr. Minanmida,
Il culprits make mistakes
There was ono more thing
besides the glasses and the slippers.
After committing the murder.
You wiped off your fingerprints
At the same time,
you naturally wiped off your fingerprints
from the bulbs that you loosened.
Yes, the fact that its notsthere may
sometimes serves as proof.
I checked again with the forensic officer
whether any fingerprints were found!
Mn the chandelier.
o fingerprints were found whatsoever.
Mr Kitamura's fingerprints that were
supposed to be there weren't either.
I confirmed with his bereaved family too.
The bulbs of the chandelier
also .went.out a monthrago.
And it seems-Mr Kitamura himself
changed the bulbs.
And yet. no one's fingerprints were found
This is proof that someone
obviously rigged the bulbs.
The trick that you usod of making
MiKitamura climb the ladder.
And stabbing him." om below
that s1mo trick of height difference
ANC AN JC 0 LES QA) WOUNL
that served as proof to your'innocence
10 years ago. Mr Minamida
that served as proo to your innocence
10 years ago. Mr. Minamida
on the contrar
118; time lead to accusing you as the kille
10 years ago. I was innocent.
B.But, my company fired me as soon as...
I was arrested...
My father was the only one
who believed me.
The:shop was the dream of my father
who died a:year ago.
It's his:dream that II had to:take ovér
and protect...
Kitamura tried to take that away from mel,
He's the bad one!
But. no matter what reasons you may have.
What value is there to a dream
that ou must protect
at the expense of someone's life?!
Original Gomic Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIRO ST/WA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
KAISUO ONG
Character Design y.
MAMYIOMO $117)?)
Story Fditor
NIL HI m
KANJI KASHIWABA A
KAZUNARI K@U CHIT
JUNICHI MIYA_HITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUL
AnimditionmdDirectors...
MASATOMO SUDO
- - _ ar fo. » 5 : RH an Qi - » - } >
ix NA
HAL UOYQOGAWARA.
A SUSHI AGN WY
AKIO KAWAMURAO
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUITANI
Directors Of Photovsraphy.
. Of a TR NC MV)
TAKATIISA
Recording Directo
ATSUYOSHI KOBAYA
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
CNet Direalor
KEN]. KODAMA)
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
In assowition with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
[2018 C TIN POON ANT
GOSHEOEAOY AM AY A HOG KURA BY IV IMs
HUI Ries ices crag
What did he just say?!
I don't know!
Yes! I his is the Mouri Detective Agency...
Yeah!
Officer Takagi... What's up?
Yes! Thanks to you. he confessed!
Huh?
Confessed?
We're home!
What
What?
Minamida Huh?
Thank you so very much! Goodbye...
What the heck is he talking about anyway...
Um. what's the matter. Pops!
He says:'he confessed, Minamida and
thank ou...
All right.
All right
Don't tell me something happened agnin.
Without my knowings'?
It's protty interesting» being '1 dotoctnvo!
I agree with you...Pops!
Police...
AXidNIpPING Lasse.
The time limit is 5:00...
There's only an hour anda half to go!
Maybe the real purpose
behind this kidnapping is...
WA nett @hol
WwW. What the!
There's another master-mind
If so something is odd
AMock Kidnap... Oase