Abduction and ransom
Bbennek/ Bes Won Sey colo Yer =
But something Is strange about
today's Incident mm
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance with
the IQ. of an adult
No case is Jeftsunsolved with
Detective Conan
Yawns
2:30 .is the time that I get sleepy
WM WY WUW
There's no need to call an ambulance .
He died on the spot
Ho was going at tr ondous,spood.
He couldn't possibly have controlled
the wheels at the speed he wis gong
Hmm?
Hmm, Hmm?!
Hutu?
W.what's with this load of/cash!
wow --unreal.
Oh. there's8ems to be a letter inside...?
Give it to me!!
Give.it to mall
Here is 302000.000 yen.
I haven't contacted the police.
Please return my father right away.
Domoto
Which moans... that this monoy 1s.
Ransom that was prepared to get back
a hostage...
A Mock Kidnap...Case
The name of'the man
who died is Takeshi Hirano.
THe has a record of being arrested
for threatening and'taking cash.
He's on the kidnappers side for sure
I wonder if he was on his way back after
taking the ransom money...)
If Hirano alone committed this crime...
we've got trouble
Nobody knows where
the kidnapped person is being confined.
On top of that, wo don't havo timo.
Eat-her ma» <1 kidney ailment
RE eek naseolioitionn Gv as) 6G notes.
1) ollll redo FH
SO please see to It that he gets it
HH means that
the hostage will not get this meditation.
Unless we hurry and find the hostage
First we've got to find out
who the hostage is.
We know his last namo is 'Domoto
but Domoto of:where?
Maybe he was visiting a hospital
to get medicine...
This is B8ika Electric Company.
We've come to deliver the TV
set ou ordered. .
Huh. I haven't ordered it...
Maybe it's some mistake?
No-It's NO mistake.
Please verify the order form
We did not order any TV set...
We're the police...
D Dear.
The./police...?!
WYO ORE) Wind 10 SON
Remember I was an upper classman
CR EO Sid URINE
It's me. me.Gaha* ha. ha...
And I'm his son~ll
How do you do?
Hey. how come)you're hore too...
You'll look
Iess suspicious with a child. right?
Grrr
This is a kidnap case. Isn't it?
Oh...Y.Yes
our father...
We matched the "Domotos
tht hive within Tokyo 1nd
visit the hospital for kidney ailment.
And came up with:your father.
Mr. Show Domolo.
Who goes to the Beika Central Hospital.
But why...
We were told that if we report this
to the police father would be killed!
The situation has changed
Why does the police have this?
After we left it
where we were told to leave it.
That culprit passed away of
a traffic accident while on his motorbike
The culprit did
Ploaso don't givo up
We are tracing the friends of this man.
We're hoping to find the place
where your father is being confined from
the hints we may get from them...
To think that this did not reach father...
It says every 6 hours,
but when as the last time
your father was injected?
At 9:00 this morning
Which means the next shot.
Has to be given to him
at 3:00 in the afternoon.
It's way past time!
Inspector...
It's not that he's going to fall into
serious condition right away
but But if t-hero is '3 time span of
more than 8 hours .
The limit is 8 hours...which means
The time limit is 17:00...
There's only an hour and a half left.
Please tell us when and
in what way your father was kidnapped.
As well as how you coped with
the situation.
The more in detail the better...
There are four of us living here
Shosaburo Pomoto, my fathor
who runs a metal processing company.
His only daughter, me.
My husband Akinori
and our housekecper
Masayo
Today 1s the company's establishment day,
so it'was closed
That's why everyone was at home
from morning
I*m also working at father's company .
you have married into your wife's family
And will eventually become the heir
I injected father at 9:00 in the morning,
and went to visit a friend of mine...
I had promised to go see her
from sometime before so.
After that father went out for a walk...
MO elhag ys ox OM fk: op 23 Of?
And. at about 1000
I went into mystudy.
Because I had some documents
I had to get together.
At about 11:00
when I was cleaning the bath tub
the. phone rang...
when I'wAs cleaning the bath tub
the pheno:rang...
It was the voirce of a young man
Gel one of the family members
on the phone.
This is Domoto speaking...
What, k... kidnap]!
In other words,
Mr. Shosaburo Domoto was kidnapped
while taking a walk
between the hours of 09:00 to 11.00.
When ho takes 1.walkidoe-ho alwys
walk the same:courser?
Yes. it's almost always the same .
Can you tell me about where it is?!
Thor could bo «hint leading to
the place of confinement.
I'll go look
I called and told her to
come home right away
I'll do everything I can to get together
the ransom of 30.000.000 en
that is being denanded. so don't worry
As long as we give them the money
father will be all right...
Leave it to mo?
Leave it to mo.
IR OO iv xO
Please. I'm counting on you, Akinari!
Now. everything will be okay
Thank you, Akinari
Hello...
Yes. the ransom
I was told to wait at home,
and I believed what he told me.
I'll return the hostage as soon as
I confirm the cash so wait at home.
I believed him...
I even enclosed the medicine
just in case too
16:00
Only one more hour to go
before the time limit.
Don't ery
I know: father's going 10 coma back safely
Yos. wo d hko to pray that ho's okay.
Regardloss of how we 'usually
feel about him.
Uncle Kogoro told me to ask you.
What did Mrs. Domoto mean
when she said
ind-a
regardless of how we-usually
feel about him... " a while ago?
Well, Akinari.
Always had it tough with Mr. Domoto
Had it tough...?"
Of all things...
-I feel no ambition or:spirit,
from you at all...
I'm trying the best
I can for the company too...
Phooey
VOPFo Just RC SR CURD ERO XRF FRO.
Just looking at you makes me
Iose my appetite
Father!
Mr. Domete is strict te the: point
that.it makes you wonder wh,
he's so hard on AKinarit.
LR TR SEW TORI] READ lta) ER Ane
Iike these. righty? I
whon they:first:got married,
they reallysgot-along well.
But. recently. even Mrs. Domoto .
Aren't you vexed.
Making him talk that way about you
Be:a man!
Mitsuko...why, you too .
Oh~I wonder if it's her father's influence?
22-5)
But. him being kidnapped is another story
Even Akinari will worry about him
and hope that/he is safe.
Aha, that's why he gathered
the ransom with all his might.
I guess so. This has nothing to do with
the kidnapping: .1 guess
It's me.
According to a friend
who goes around with Takeshi Hirano,
he says that Hirano suddenly
seemed to have a lot of money
on him since a week ago.
Which means that
Hirano was hired and paid by someone!
Probably.
But; I haven't got info on
who hired him yet...
But, I hiwven't got info on
who hired him yet
who hired him yet...
But. I haven't got info on
So. you don't Know who it is yet.
Continue asking around his friends
and acquaintances!
If only we can find who it is.
We may get a hint
on where Mr. Domoto is being confined.
There's another master-mind behind this...
Oh but if so something Is odd
Something-s strange. isn't it. Inspector?
What Is?
What is?
The master-mind.
The guy who went to get
the ransom hasn't come back for a while.
Therefore, wouldn't'he normally
call to demand
what happened to the money.saying.
What happened.to the money,
are going to leave the hostage to die"
Or something to thateffect...
I soo. Now that you montionod it
Exactly.
Why does the master-mind seem quite
indifferent to the money
after having demanded it?
Oh. Father!
Mitsuko...
Maybe the real purpose of
this kidnapping is...
< NF BY
TN ee ET
"see.
If SO
Oh, my... What is it now, sonny?
Mr. Akinari Domot@ was: in his study
all morning today: right?
Yes. he-had work to do
Did he.say something to'you back then?
Something?
WW, Uy
Masayo, I'm going lo concentrate on
work for a while
SO you don't have to bring me
tea or anything
Just as I thought...
If 80
Machine oil.
No doubt about it~
I figured out who the real culprit of
this kidnapping case is...
But, I know
that the person will play dumb
even If a press for-a:confession
nd. the time limit will eventually come.
That's the real purpose behind all this
not the ransom
It's 16:00, only 30 minutessmore to go.
Where is the place
the hostage is confined!
Heygkid
what'resyou doing: staring at a map?
I was just wondering .
Where the motorbike was headed.:for.
Whoro cols but tho hide out
wherc the hostage is:confined.
That's why from the place
he picked up the ransom in Beika Park,
to the scene of the accident,
over here. if you draw.a line
beyond itlis...
Most likely. but Conan
) But, you canatstell if
its 10 or 100 kilometers away «#
Huh? there-swa place
with the same name as this house.
Huh?
Domoto... Metal Processing.
Oh. that's our factory
Oh, that's our factory.
But since we moved and built 1 inew one in
East Belka 6 months. ago.
It's closed down now
Which means it's no in use. anymore.
On. so nobody 1s there
or will come there anymore.
Inspector!
It's the idea place for confining someone.
Very probable.
Conan. give me he map...!
Yes: sir~I
T.Then Father is'in that factory?
There's.a possibility he is)!
Y! B  *
Oh, there's only15 more minutes left.
Mrs. Doemoto,
please don't give up until the end!
Pops great phrase
Please hold up
another 15 minutes somehow.
Stop time stop .
Father .
Give it to me. I'll open it...
Eathor
Mr Domoto
Father!
F.Father...
Aghl!
Father. Father!
He's still breathing!
Oh, this is Takagi!
Please send an ambulance over.
The location is
Mr. Domoto. get a hold of yourself!
Your wife will head for tho hospital
You go tool
Y...Yes. sir
Agh. heh--7?
Please wait Mr. Domoto.
Huh. why.
Huh why .
Aaagh!
He's transformed into the Sleeping Kogoro!
Mr. Mouri?!
I believe that Mr. Domoto will be all right.
regardless of whether you hope
otherwise. Akinari...
Hope otherwise...
Just what do you mean?
The minute I found out that
this kidnapping was not
after ransom! realized.
According to what Conan
heard from Masayo. the housekeeper...
You and Mitsuko really got along.
And got married loving each other.
But, after you entered the Domoto family
as her wedded husband
tough days of being criticized by
Mr. Domoto for not being ambitious
OF ROR Olax) RR Or HOH)
an heir continued everyday.
You most naturally hated Mr Domote
and thought.
You d like to erase him from this world
you'd like to erase him from this world .
But you didn't have the courage to do so .
Therefore. you thought up this scheme.
Scheme...?
On't be ridiculous
Just what're you talking about?
I know nothing of it!
Noll The culprit is Akinari,
Inspector Megure.
Whaaat?!
It.It can't be
OX OORO Wk LAoKne ope
taking oa walk...
At that tum) Akmnra was...
Domg work in my study!
I wonder If that's true?
When going into the study you...
Masayo~I'm going to concentrate on work,
SO you don't have to bring me
8021 OF oR y
so you don't have to bring me
tea or an thing
And. after saying so. to Masayo
you wore the shoes
that you prepared beforehand...
.- ve
You 'caught up with Mr. Domoto
who was taking a walk
and got him to gel in the gr.
We av ay
What on earth do you
ant to talk to me about
bringing me to a place like this
I tell you. what kind of man are you...
If you have something you want to say,
get to the point
Uuugh...
Oh no. Akinari. take me home quickly
I...don't have my medicine with me.
Heave. heave
Aklnarl. it's-for you
What, kidnap ?!
And... you acted out the role of the victim.
Hmm...
Of course there Is evidence too
The same kind of machine oil
that is smeared over
the floor of this factory.
Should be found on the frame of
the window frame of your study.
Showing that you went out and
GOEL) DOG IR AU OW ow
Iyn sure that the tissue paper
that you used to wipe it off
can also be found
somewhere in the room...
And. above all your footprints
when you went in and out of your study
are left on the ground.
From the Domoto residence to here,
it takes an hour to « 0 and come back...
It was possible for you to commit the crime
between 10:00 to 11:00, the time
you were confined to your study
Hmm. It is possible
Hmm. it is possible
but he didn't have to do it himself
He could've made the guy Hirano
that he hired do it, couldn't he?
That man was probably not told
that ho was londing a hand to kidnapping...
He lent ii hand without knowing?!
Akinar asked Hiring to justhtwo things
4300)
AKinari askod Hirano tofdo just two things.
Akin 1skod Hirano to do just two things.
Call T1818? 11110033110. and 14:00.
Thon pick up 1 trunk at Boika Park
It s for your bancofit not to know
what's inside the trunk or who I am.
Because if he tells of his scheme,
Hirano would hold his weak point
And, aware that his wife was going out,
he decided tocarr out his scheme toda
What? Kidnapped father?!
Ransom...
Boika Park...
In other words...
he was acting the conversation out alone!
N\ OR Cll) WN) CCR
get into an accident...
Yes. only If Hirano didn't
Tho monoy could bo rotriovod lator,
and the scheme would've worked out fine,
with neither the police
or the detective showing up...
All he had to do was preten
to be worried about Shosaburo and wait.
Exactly
But. the motive is not correct. Mr. Mourl
It's true that I hated him
I did want him to disappear
but, that's not all.
I wanted to show my wife
how hard I tried to get
the money together.
I thought that if she saw that.
Her love for me would
return once again...
Original Comic Beok Ry
(205110 AQYAMA
Producers.
MA AHITOY » ~ 'GK
Background Music.
KAISUO ONO
Character: désion y
MASATOMO *» DO
Story Fditor,
JUNICHI 11OKA
MN]? FASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI K@U CH 1
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
TOSHIKI INOUL
Animation. Dircectors.
MASATOMO SUD
HIROTOSHI TAKATAN
HARU MOOGAWARA
ATSUSHEAOGONO
AKIO KAWAMURAO*
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUIANI
Directors Of PhotoSraphy.
TAKASHI NOM RA
TAKABIISA OWAGA
Re cording Dir: 'or.
KAISUYOSH BAVA
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
CNet ODireddor
KENJLKODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
11) ASSsSOGIation with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORAT ON
IFETTEC 1 IV TIC UIN AN
GOSHOETOY MAT SHOGARA WY TV TMS
RITE cdl
rAaahlfHfs me. Mltsuko!
I'm glad, Father's life has been. saved
I'm s6 glad!
When he regiaing consciousness
I'll tell him
VOW desperate you went-arounc
to gather mone for him
as well as how worried yoy were.
I'm sure that Father will stop deliberately
taking his Angor out
on you: too from now on.
Deliberately?!
In order to make you a fine heir,
Father deliberately took on the hated role
and act U it out.
Because father actually likes you.
He always says.
He's never seen someone
as diligent as you."
I began putting en an act
just like Father recently...
But. I didn't like doing it. I'm sorry .
Hello
Hello... Akinari?
Those who do not fear
the rage of the gods.
In those hands brimming with stones
[E) { 2Exedn oR) (C= 0 im kote) ex
peltyAthie fawn eplitsyenkaiies
A bigyjewel... brimming... from his fist. I
en -» b=
>in La
Adventure at an /Eccentric Mansion