Stars are for some reason are attractive
They: can be the culprit or an actor (star)
The Youth Detective Squad
goes through great adventure
At an eccentsic mansion of tricks!
Off wYgo after the ltreasure!
He sees through the one and only truth
Axchild In appearanco
with thewl=Q of an adult
No case as left unsolved
with Detective Conan
Mountains are for men
Genta. come on and get'to-work...
pr 5.
Rleaso holp us collect firewood!
Huh? I'm not slacking off!
Ghads!!
That's far from
enough. Genta!
Oh ..Aha ha...
But. why isn't Conan here?!
Not again,
Iike I told you just a while ago...
Didsyou catch 1-colds?
Shinichi...
And what were we talking about?
. Shouldn't have asked him...
1 song?! "Tho Sovon Baby Crows
The Seven Baby Crows" it was, yes,
I know the song.
Crow oh. crow why do you cry
That's the song. right?
Yeah that.ssfthe one...
I used to sing it a lot
on my way home from school.
And Jd What about it?
Is it your music homework or something?
No! Remember the number I mentioned
the other.da 08582)
When I use my cell phone
and hit the buttons rhythmically
it sounds like the beginning part
of that song fight
0858...crow oh crow.
Let me sce Let me try?!
T True...
It finally came back to me...
That back then
when Bellmot was sendingfmail to the boss
I fellysomewhat sad and nostalgic.
But it wasn't the expression on her face,
that made me feel that way.
Sit was the sound of the buttons
she was pushing!
What?t T Then are you saying
that the mail address of their boss
is The Seven Baby Crows"?!
It canst be!
Why would the boss use a children's song
for his mail address?
What if they remembered the address
by the melody?
B.By the melody?
Yeah ..then they wouldn't have to register
the mail address inside their cell phone.
Which makes it safe?
For a variety of reasons. right
0858 may sound like "crow oh crow" but...
Why do you cry is not se casy...
Well. it's true that it's not all that accurate
but if wéymake do
with the slight difference in sound...
and put it together
It comes out like this...?
This is the mail address
of the boss of the'men in black!
WwW. What?!
WwW. I What?!
Whaaaa
Kyaaaah
I CRONE XR EX [TEE dm Om
Part 2