Stars are for some reason attractive
They can be the culprit or the actor
Great ad enture at the mansion of tricks
Surprising tricks that are
fangerous enough to take live
NEAR [OXRR=DGEIINL §& 0 Spun
outfox thatsnobbish guy!
He sees through: the one and only truth
A child in, appearance
with the l.Q. of an adult
Ne case is left unsolved
with BDotective Conan
I figured out the mail address
of the boss of the Men in Black
from the melody of "Crow Baby Crow."
But, I decided not to pursue any further
after AI gives me a piece of her mind...
In the meantime
Genta and the others find
1 strange stone box
And there, they find a code
having to do with the Big Jewel,
as well asa strangled.corpse beside it!
And...in its hand brimming with stones...
Hmm?!
Hey, Conan, what is it?
Tell us what follows!
Its hand
brimming with .\
the big jewel!
No doubt'about it
Adventure at ant ccontrie Mansion Trick.
Adventure at an Eccentric Mansion-Tricks
I 888...
I guess this is the start
of diamond cut diamond.
Fuh, fuh. fun...
Huh?
What's that?
It's a proverb of Belgium
In order to cut hard diamond
another diamond has to be used. right?
Therefore, it refers to
he start of a composed et
VICIOUS battle between
the sages and the strong men...
But. who's battling against who?
Fool...
Neither he nor I is something
as great as a diamond... *
He's just a thief who hides the truth
under a veil and enjoys it...
And I'm {just a detective who's
dying to tear off... .that veil...
And? Just who 1s that thief?
Are you talking about the partner of
the man who was sunk into the swamp?
A snobby evil thief who only
goes after large gems
A snobby evil thief who: only 8
A snobby evil thief who only
gous after large gems
Iike 1g Jowols, eallodPThief Kid
Kahl...
Thief Kid~!
Yeah .
I know that name!
Elusive and daring!
Gentleman thief!
Doc has told me...
About your battles...
Our battles?
It seems that
you've been outfoxed quite a few times?
It.It's not that he outfoxed me or anything...
Because he's never sto
an treasure from me yet...
Uh is Thief Kid here?
Huh.
It's just that he could be...
It was written in the man's notebook. right?
That from :now om
Ioan outfox that petty thief...
That petty thief that he was referring to
is probably Thief Kid...
Then. are you saying that Thief Kid
killed that man?!
Beats mec
Rumor has it that
he never takes a person's life though...
But, it's for sure that
Thief Kid as well as the one
who killed that man is
still around here somewhere.
Right.
If the treasure hasn't been found yet...
It's most likely that
it's inside this mansion...
El. it's started-to.-rain...
SO why don't we go Inside the mansion
and take shelter from theirain...
Huh? Then. we're...
Treasure hunting
We're going to start?!
Don't get I me wrong...
It's only until Doc calls the police
and they get here. understand!
All right!
But... now that we're going inside,
It sure is a creep mansion...
Are you sure there's treasure in here?
I'm sure it's hidden somewhere in here...
It bothered me a while ago too. but...
The brand new traces of wet mud
on the border of the wall
and the floor of the mansion.
Moreover,
throughout the mansion there is...
I wonder why?
He . Conan.
Huh?!
Explain the meaning of
the writing one more time!
The meaning of the writing that
was written inside the stone lantern!
Oh. that...
The god's not around. right...?
Right... 3
The resting place of\the gods
Is near the sun...
in an extremely busy location
where the elders get together
that is where gods' stone is...
Those who fear not the rage of the gods
In their hands brimming with stones.
He teaches proverbs
from long ago...
Samizu Kichiemon...
In other words.
The gods sleep in a place closet to the sun
and where the elders gather,
in a very lively place...
That's where the stone of the gods'...
In other words,
the diamond is hidden. right!
But. the point Is the words that follow...
Yes. that's right.
Conan went on to explain it part way
and became silent,
so we still don't understand it
Those who know
10! of the rage of the gods...
Get a hold of the stones that
are brimming out of its hand
and learn from the proverb of long ago...
Hmm~What does that mean?
The god is going to get angry after all.
Yeah 'and the stone Magatama
with the word "fire" carved onto it
that was hidden in the hem of the
dead body that was found a while ago...
I have no idea what
this has to do with the code at all yet...
Huy. Inf, go manic: already
Hold your horse...
Isn't there anything else written
in that: man"synotebook?
There is, but since it's wet ll think
we should wait until it dries.
Otherwise. it'll rip and become unreadable.
We don't have all day. you know!
H.Hey. Genta!
He . Genta!
Don't go inside carelessly!!
The puppet maker Kichiemon
built this mansion, you know!
Ymvaaha.
The diamond is in a place
nearest to the sun, right?
If so. then I'm sure it's hidden
He . Genta!
At the top most part of the house!
At any rate. let's go to the very top!
H.Hold it, Genta!
Yep...
Huh?
Whaaa!
RGentall
Kugh!
Whaaaa~Ugh!
Whaaa
G.Genta!
Awhaaa
What's with you...
Kids...
Hon ara
Genta. are you all right?
Are you guys looking for
Kichiemon's treasure too?
Phooey. well, who cares...
You'd better be really careful. though.
This step is a trap!
If you want to go up,
you have to go on farther beyond...
Puppet maker Kichiemon is
quite a sourpuss you know...
If you move just according to
what you see. you'll get hurt.
By the way, didn't you guys find
an odd looking stone?
Oh. well as to that
We didn't find anything!
Huh?
Oh, really?
Tell me if you find it then, okay?
Okay. sure!
- He , Conan?!
Why are you lying?
He's a good man
who saved Genta. you know...
You never know if he's a good man...
He could acting friendly just so
he can take away the stone Magatama...
Yeah...if that guy's Thief Kid the more so...
He could even be the guy who killed
the body that was found a while ago...
Huh?!
But, it seems that
we'd be safer staying close to the guy
because he seems to know a lot
about the traps inside this mansion...
Also so that he doesn't get away
till the police get here...
I wonder if
Doc got hold of the police already?
Is.Is it still farther away?
That dilapidated mansion...?
Yes. well:-*Aha. ha. ha...
Huh? . -Aha. ha
Now. which way was it
C Come on...
Oh, carps!
There are a lot of them!
This place is like
a high class Japanese restaurant
with the river flowing throughout the house.
I wonder if
it's connected to the swamp outside...
Look,
there's even a bridge!
A pitfall?!
I'm not going to fall
for the same trick this time!
No. It looks like a pitfall but it's actually.
Whaaa!
Vvhaaa!
Wow!
It's just like an elevator!
Conan!
Huh?!
Let's get on, quick!
Oh, eah...
In other words, if we try to go up,
we end up going down...
and if we try to go down
we go up. right?!
Once you get the hang of it,
it's pretty simple
Here we are...
Aha. ha...It was simple. wasn't it
Yikes!
Kyaah!
How silly...
If it were that easy, we wouldn't have to
go through the trouble of looking for it.
Right, treasure hunter with kids?!
These kids are not with me.
And, I don't think you should
be using knives around kids...
Take a good look at the tip of the knife...
P Poison spider?!
Kichiemon was not only a sourpuss
ut he seems to have been
mean quite mean too...
If you want to go to the very top,
it's this way...
Hey. could she be Thief Kid?
I thought Thief Kid was a boy
Oh~Which means that
the Magatama that you kids found
had something like flames carved on it?
Yeah...You hit the bull's eye. Ms
But, I can't make it out...
Forever and "Flames"...
Maybe If we stick those stones
somewhere inside the gravestone,
the gods stone
the diamond that is. will come out?
What makes you think so?
Because it was carved
Inside the stone garden lantern
that the diamond would be in a busy place
where old people get together, right?!
Is this the busy p ace
where old people get together?
Yes. because, uh, what was it .
Resting place of the gods...
The resting place of the gods
Is nearest to the sun
in an extremely busy place
where the elderly get together...
The gods stone is there...
This is it. right?
I guess you want to
interpret the part that goes.
An extremely busy place
where the elderly get together
to this shabby pl e of dead bodies...
Yes...
But those here are the foolish ones who
have been blinded by greed and decayed.
Not being able to find the way out of here .
When Kichiemon built this mansion
none of them were here...
Oh... guess so...
Then you saw the lanterns too. grandma?
Yeah.
They weren't sunk in the swamp though...
At any rate,
I guess the treasures not here...
There seems to be no place, where you can
Insert stones on this gravestone either...
I guess we'll have to find
the other sacred treasure
to solve the mystery. after all...
he other...?
They're called the three sacred treasures.
The mirror and the Magatama were found,
so there should be one more somewhere.
The three sacred treasures?
Yes. the mirror is the Mirror of Yata.
The Magatama is called the Magatama of
Yasakani. it's shaped like a comma,
and the remaining one is...
the Sword of the gods.
The Sword of Kusanagi...
that got its name because
it Is said to have saved
God Takeru Yamato.
Who was in a pinch,
by slashing down the grass
when fire was set to the field.
Whaaaat?!
The Sword of Kusanagi?!
Original Comic Best 3y
055110 AOYAMA %
Original Comici3voks By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHTITITKO SUWA
MASSAHITO YOSH OK
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASAIOMO. SUD?)
Story 'Fditore
JUNICHI 11 KA
KANJI KASHIWABARA
NA UINZAAKT KUUUU TT]
JUNIGHI MIYA. HITA
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors I
MASATOMO SUD
HARUGIOOGAWARA
AISUSHI A NO
AKIO KAWAMURA
IAKASHI HYCD(»
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUIANI
Directors Of Photodsiaphy.
TAKASHI'NOMUI
MND or
TAKATIISA A
Recording Mirco
KATSUYOSHI! KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU. DKADA
Ce! Director.
JENJILKODAMA)
Produced By.
IMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD.
In association with
YOMIURI TELECASTINC
CORPORATION
TECITIVISGOR AN
CGO AMA SHOUARAANY IV IMS
Ris his keshwved
Hah... Heave...
Brat?!
Lost ones,
offer the sacred treasure to me...
Whaaa. kyah...
We'll be washed down
to the valley below by the water.
Adventure at an-Eccontric Mansion
C we Closed