Stars are for some reason attractive
They can be«the culprit or the actor
The treasure of the god Nioh
Is finally found!
Did Thief Kid get it, or
did the Youth Detective Squad get it?
He sees through the one and only truth
788 WnSbuesoiven
with tha ¥=Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
Wa care admin ta
camp tagathoer with =r Avasn
We came long to
camp together with Dr. "Agasa...
<4 Gonta and tho others find <
a mysterious looking stone
near a suspicious looking mansion
TRere are codes. concerning
the Big Jewel there.
And besides it, we find a body of a man
who had been strangled to death!
We. then enter the mysterious
Iooking mansion of tricks +
where we encounter 2 treasure hunters
and an queer old woman...
We've got to find the other sacred treasure
or we won't be able to
solve the mystery after all...
I he other...?
They're called the three sacred treasures
The mirror and the Magatama were found,
so there should be one more somewhere.
The three sacred treasures?
Yes. the mirror is the Mirror of Yata.
The Magatama is called the Magatama of
Yasakani-it's a stone shaped like a comma,
and the remaining one is
the Sword of the gods.
The Sword of Kusanagi...
that got its name because it is said to
have saved God Takeru Yamato.
Who was in a pinch,
by slashing down the grass
when fire was set to the field.
The sword of the gods...
The Sword of Kusanagi...
Adventure at an Eccentric Mansion
Case Closed
Oh. I know about that Sword of Kusanagi!
It's the fantastic sword that
comes out a lot in games. right?
The Sword of Kusanagi...
If we look at the writings on that sword.
We ma be able to fic ure somethinc out...
Before searching for the treasure.
I think our priority is
to get out of this basement cell.
If it's getting out of here,
he should know how to...
Huh?
Unless you already came here once and
read the writings on the gravestone...
you wouldn't be hiding that
stone mirror that you have on you...
Yes, yes...let me show you the way...
What a large house...
The basement is strangely large...
Huh? The floor's starting to get wet...
Yes...
Water is flowing in from somewhere...
Oh. there! Over there!
What's that trace that looks
as if something had moved out of place...
Oh, now that you mentioned it,
there was an earthquake a little while ago...
That's why the house moved a bit,
and water from below flowed out.
Ho.ho.ho!
Just as Kichiemon says,
maybe the god Noh is angry...
telling us to quit treasure hunting
and hurr on home...
Hey, the notebook that the man
who was found in the swamp...
It's dry now and legible...
It seems that he was killed by his partner.
I've teamed up with a dangerous guy...
I've got to hide this stone I found,
or he'll kill me...
Poison rat says he's going to kill me
and take the treasure all for himself...
After that...it's ripped so I can't read on.
Huh?!
Wow,
wow!
Whaaaa~!
[his smoke. 1s it a hot spring or something?
Yeah
Kichiemon probably dug it up.
To hide this entrance with steam...
fl we
Fantastic ¢
What a red hot spring...
I wonder If it contains a lot of iron?
He , brat!
That's not the exit!
Brat?!
Conan?! What's up?
Are you all right?!
Hey. do you know?
Do you know where
the Sword of Kusanagi came out from...?
Huh?
Sure you've all heard about
the story of Susano
the kid brother of Ametarasu Oomikami,
making a monster drink sake to get it drunk
and eventually defeat it
in order to rescue Princess Kushinada.
And the sword that came out of
the tall of the monster was
the Sword of Ameno Murakumo,
which later became know as
the Sword of Kusanagi!
D.Don't tell me that monster is the one that
often comes out in stories of long ago...
Its eye are«flaming red like those of-an ogre
and its stomach is inflamed with blood.
Although it has just one body
It is the legendary eight headed dragon
with eight heads and eight tails.
Look at the basin of this waterfall...
Doesn't it look very similar...
To the eight-headed dragon!
I 888
The waterfall 1s the dragon's neck
and the branches its tails...
Which means that the sword is
in one of the branches...?
Yeah... According to the egend.
The sword came out
of the tail in the middle...
In other words, the Sword of Kusanagi
should be up ahead of this branch!
Don't tell me you plan to
dive throughithe hot water?!
Forget it! Don't! There's nothing there!
What if it's the bottom of
the valley up ahead?!
But. we came this far, so I want to sce
what there is up ahead...
Mugh!
Whaaaa!
Huh?
Something rising!
The water level is decreasing!
Ooooh!
Now we can go through the hole!
All right!
Oka I Let's go!
H.Hold it. Genta!
Out of my way!
Vvhaaa!
HHe Grann ?.
Darn!
Hah. hah he's-heel
Ooooh!
That is indeed...the Sword of Kusanagi!
Huh?!
H oeeeh!
So. you wore after
the treasure too. Grann
What a dangerous trap...
When you try to get close to the sword.
Weight bears down on the floor and
blades come flying from all directions...
I guess he doesn't want it
to be taken. does he?
No...it's not just an ordinary mean trap...
Huh?
Blades come from all directions.
C.Conan!
And the blades settling in all four directions
only goes to show that,
the timing is slightly. synchronized
so that they won't bump into each other...
Moreover...
The fact that there as a handle
Iike this on the blade.
Is telling you to use it
to go over to the sword!
He ~I
He got to the other side!
Conan's fantastic!
WwW. What's written?!
What's written on the sword?!
Dragon...
D.Dragon?!
Dragon?!
Forever, Flames and Dragon...
Ho hoho
hyo...Just as expected of Kichiemon!
It probably means. suffer in agony forever
as If being burned by
the flames of the dragon!
So... let's forget about
treasure hunting and go home!
Maybe there was no treasure
to begin with anyway...
What's with you... You were
going all out to get it just a while ago.
Those who are lost,
offer me the sacred treasure...
Forever...Flames...Dragon..»
Offer me...
To me!
Hey. Conan!
Conan!
He's coming back this way.
You look satisfied
So. you've figured something out?
R.Really. Conan?!
This look on my face is
a wretched look that says.
Let's hurr up and head on home..."
Huh?!
Ara you s0Mous...
Hey, Conan?
Are ou serious about heading home?
After we found the mysterious
three sacred treasures.
You're going to forget about the diamond?
Yeah
The words that are carved
on the sacred treasures
Flames", Forever and Dragon.
As far as the meaning is concerned
and as to the meaning of
the writings in the stone lantern,
I don't have the slightest idea...
I guess I'll get going then...
Hmm.
I guess I'll check this mansion
a bit more too. then...
Whew
We finally made. it outside
It seems Dr. Agasa hasn't come back yet.
Doctor?
Dr. Agasa¥is suppose to bring:
some police officers here
Oh...then. Yuess
you'll be able to get out of
these mountainseven without me...
If you don't want God Nioh to curse you.
Don't dilly dally and
head on home right away!
Now that all the people
you don't want around have left...
Iead the way. will you?
Huh?
Huh?!
To where the treasure is...
What?!
Come on. Conan...
Then, ou...
You figured out the code after all!
It was written on the gravestone
in the basement. right?
To the lost ones,
offer the sacred treasures to me. .*
The "me" here refers to Samizu Kichiemon.
In other words it's telling you
to add the kanji character "MIZU"
to the characters of the sacred treasures
The words that were found on
the three sacred treasures
were "HONO" for "Flames" and...
El" for forever
What happens
when you put"SANZUI" alongside it?
Hmm 2!
Hmm?
The character "HONOQO™" for flames becomes
AWA" as in Awaji Island!
The character "El" becomes "EI"
the character for the word swimming!
The character 'RYU becomes
TAKI" the character for waterfall.
Hmm ?
Does it mean to go swimming
in the waterfall of Awaji Island?
It said on the gravestone in the basement
The lost ones. right?
That was a hint for those who couldn't
figure out the code of the stone lanterns!
The writing on the lantern said.
A place nearest to the sun
where the elderly gather,
a very lively place.
When you put this
oge er wi 1 Ye ree Cc arac ers...
The place nearest to the sun is Mercury,
the first planet in the solar system.
The elderly refer to
1e carps wi 1 wis ers.
The lively place means a place
where the sound of the water never stops.
In other words. the stone of the god Nioh.
The diamond. is hidden near the waterfall
where a lot of carps swim in fresh water!
Wow. Conan!
It's the waterfall in the basement!
Where the eight-headed dragon is!
Too bad...
That's a hot spring and not fresh water...
Maybe it's the river that was in the house?
Yeah, there were lots of carps
swimming inside too!
But. there was no waterfall.
O. Oh. that's right.
See. listen carefully
You hear it. don't you...?
It's leading us to where the treasure is...
That sound of the...
I 866]
IU at the faust swamp that we saw!
Let's go!
Okay
That body . us» gum,
Yeah...
The killer hid it again
after we entered the house...
What're you talking about?
A bod...
Do ou see an thing?
It's dark and I can't tell unless
chive in there or something
Too bad...
Huh?!
He seems to have gotten there
before ou .
Sarina.
Just when did she get here...
Look behind the waterfall...
Behind the waterfall?
There is a card or something up there!
Thanks for the stone of Nioh... Thief Kid?!
FE NIB
28 Er
Thanks for the stone of Nioh... Thief Kid?!
FE DIvlE
pA XE
Thanks for the stone of Nioh... Thief Kid?!
FE NDIo
1 NEE
Thanks for the stone of Noh... Thief Kid?!
23 Eo
Thanks for the stone of Nioh... Thief Kid?!
Pp Rx O
FAX /F
Thanks for the stone of Noh... Thief Kid?!
pA %/F
Thanks for the stone of Noh... Thief Kid?)!
Ii-JR
Thanks for the stone of Noh... Thief Kid?!
1 TORS
OO. Oh. mo...
No joke!
No kidding?!
Hyo. hyo...
He is indeed the great thief
under the heavens!
Well, if the stone was taken by
the great thief that deceives the world...
VUGID PUP PSL HHIAGRTE INL NGO
cotldn"t have asked for more...
Granny, I thought you went home... Gee...
Whaa!
Huh? What's up?
MMItsuhiKQ?!
Huh?! Aaaagh
Puha!
A.Are you all right?
Let's pull out of here!
There seems to be nothing here...
Cough. cough!
I.I found something!
It was hidden in the mud...
but there was definitely a stone
that was shining at the bottom
of the swamp...
It's mine!!!
H He...Don't take it!
Those who fear not the rage of the gods
In their hands brimming with stones.
Ho toachas proverbs
from long ago.
He teaches proverbs
from long ago...
Oops... Don't move!
Who would've thought
it was hidden with mud...
I didn't search
that well and was about to ovenlook it.
Thanks to that card .
Go on. line up on that side!
When that man comes out from the water
holding the treasure,
I'll give you all
a good dunk in the water together.
Phooey.
You've finally shown your true identity...
Thief Kid!
What?!
S.She is?!
Huh? Me. Thief Kid?
Don't be silly. I'm...
You're the poison rat
that killed your partner
in order to hog the treasure
all for yourself, right?
Ugh...
You were saying.
When that guy
showed the stone mirror...
then there must've been the word "Flames"
carved on the Magatama that you found.
Isn't that right...
Back then, all I said was...
I found a stone sacred treasure .
So. how did you know?
That what we found was not the sword,
but the Magatama...?
You knew because you're the one
WI10 Orc o Cc page
from the notebook of the man
that you sunk to the bottom of the swamp...
You took the diagram that
that the character "Flames"
was written inside the Magatama!!
How did you find out what was written?!
Yoh!
The notes were written in pencil.
SO you could see slight traces on the paper.
Oh. so ou're a bit smart
But also careless. sonny...
to come close to the gun. barrel
from your side...
Yeah...l had to...to do this...
I wouldn't He able Lo hit you
withthe tranquilizer
1 Ian tvellyve tna 18ay
was actually the thief kid
actually. kid is...
I got the diamond!
I go! the diamond!
Oh no!
H.Hurry, put the diamond back
where it was!
What?!
Otherwise you'll drift down to the bottom of
the valley together with the water!
Ht. there it Is.
It's that mansion!
Ont. -sthoroitas
Oh!. there it is...
It's that mansion!
Huh?
Vvhaaa!
That diamond was the switch
to this huge trap...
He had no intention of letting anybody have
the treasure to begin with...
Yeah....diamonds,
because of their impenetrable hardness
once used to be called adamas
from which the word adamant,
meaning utterly unyielding was derived...
Therefore,
He teaches proverbs from long ago
means the treasure shall never be taken...
Well, when the Shogunate collapsed,
not wanting the ones
who overthrew the government to confiscate
1S 18SSC SS. SMOS I Cy wa (cuemon,
who was supporter of the Shogunate
thought this up...
That's why you stole it once
but decided against it, right granny...
)r rather.
The greatest thief under the heavens...
There he is!
Thief Kid!
Exactly... Good work...
The wall of the mansion that was
slightly raised. and the basement passage
the was slightly out of place
where the water came gushing out...
Contraryto what was written on the card,
the jewel was not taken...
And shouting: "Donst-take it!
all points-to'none other than the fact that
granny is Thief Kid!
Bingo!
Well, I didn't take it also
because it was not what I was after...
That's why you said, let's forget
about the treasure hunt and go home!
But, you knocked me down
and tried to take the sword!
That was to rescue you, Genta...
Huh?
If he didn't go in there before you .
And make you realize there was a trap there
you would've been slashed to pieces...
So. he waited for us in the basement
so that we wouldn't
get caught b the traps?!
My, my, what a heart warming
and touching thief...
I'm truly honored by your words, little lady?
Well, I'll let you go for today since
ou rescued m friends from danger...
I'll expose you to the hight of day
for sure someday. so don t{orget that
I'll peel off that cape of your
as well as make you show yourself...
I advise you not to...
Pandora opened the box because
she didn't know what was inside...
Knowing the contents before opening
the treasure box is...
Aaaagh?!
No fun?!
You fool
It's the work of a detective to find out...
what's inside before opening the box...
Original Comic Bool Ry
COW-IO AOYANM
Producers
Vo, MY, ok )...
Background Music.
KATSUO OND
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Fditor...
JUNIUHI 11WKA
KAN)! KASHIWABARA
- » hb
]UNI('HI MIYASHITA
TO HIKd INOUE
Animation. Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
TIAN BED LINE
AISUSHI AGN )
KIO KAWAMURA
IAKASHI HYC)(»
Art Dirccton .
YUKIHIRO SHIBUIANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKABIISA OWAGAO
Recording Din-rm
KATSUYOSHI KWBAYA_~I11
Editor.
IERUMITSU OKADA
CNe! Director.
KENJI. KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS*ENTFRTAINMENT, LID.
In assowation with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPO ATION
iN PECTIN ISGOA AN O
CO THIAOYIMAY SHOT AMAAN Y 11 IMS
WU Ris: his Keserved
So. what now?!
Right!
Since the jewel was returned,
It seems the water is receding...
I guess we have no choice
but to wait for help to come...
Oh. whatever happened to Dr. Agasa?
Yeah...
Yikes~!
The victim 1s the person who: lives here,
Ms. Fumie Ozawa. age 24.
Who workod for a financial institution
Manner mode? At ome?
Either of the two. Etsuko or Mr. Shimizu...
Pops. what's this?
Spicy\ Bitter and Sweet Flavor