Stars ane for some reason attracti'e
They can be the culprit or the actor
Today's case has a slightly different taste
Solving the trick consistingfof three flavors
Let's taste the joy of prob m solving
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I'Q* of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
sf» 4
Sigh
of Sa
What s with ithatfsigh 2!
Didn t sigh
Irs Ahmed ward pe) Ke = We foliage) ely
1 the tournament
Of course she's okay!
I mean she practiced as much as she did.
And went: to sleep early last night too-
She's doing just fine!
1. guess so. aha, ha.
Hum?
= nr )
Like I've been saying for some time now.
It's the owner of the sweets shop Yuzuki
So, I'm saying that's not it
The police officer is Mr. Kinoshita...
Uh~.-what seems to be«the matter?
Mr. Mouri, what good timing.
Huh?!
Mr Mouri, please hear me out!
Huh 2!
Mr Mourn,
we're having trouble coming to terms!
H.Hold it. one at a time please.
I have this uncomfortable premonition...
Spicy. Bitter and Sweet Flavor
So. what you're saying is...
Etsuko, you saw a man coming running out
of room 105 on the first floor of this condo
The time this happened was
about 2 hours ago at 9:00 in the morning
And... Officer Kinoshita, you came here
after Etsuko reported this to You
Yas, sir
Then you found the corpse of Ms. Fumie
Ozawa. the woman renting this room,
and concluded that she committed suicide.
Listen. I saw the scene with my very eyes.
There was a suicide note
and the room was net messed up...
1313ut
Besides, there are no other eye-witnesses
GRO AAS GE) YOU) OW
But. I saw him fer sure...
Come on! Please tell him 100, Mr. Mourn,
to Investigate the incident mere thoroughly!
What?!
Come. come...
and is there a possibility
that it was made to look like suicide?
I had the medical examiner come over
and investigate. just in case but...
Judging from t-he degree of-postmortem
rigidity.
The estimated time of death«issthought to be
between 6:00 to 8:00 last.night.
If the man she says,she witnessed
committed the crime.
He would've had to stay withethe dead body
in the room for more than 13-hours,
after killing the victim and
Hinge) who Win Go
It is unthinkable under normal terms.
I'm getting nowhere talking-Ho you!
Let's have Mr. Mourl decide.
Go ahead Mr. MourilT
Please tell us what you think!
< AY 2 BE : 3
Well~I...I'm sure in,a fix
You don't leek to be in a fix to me.
Officer Kinoshita!
This is the man I saw!
There's no mistake about it.
Oh, don't touch/it!
B But...
ihe victim is Fumie Ozawa. age 24
of this room.
The victim is Fumie Ozawa, age 24
of this room
She works for financial institution
When found the body.
She had 1 wire that was suspended)
from the shower nozzle around her.neck,
with her body leaning against the wall
and sitting down.
What a strange place to choose
to commit suicide. though...
Mr. Mouri. please look over here
a There Is a will written using the computer.
ChairmansShimizu of the toanydopartment
Itam Sorrygfor.the*trouble I have caused
I will takewmy life
SO please accept my apologies.
The contents of the suicide note is
that she had embezzled more than
30.000.000 yen of company money,
so that she would like to apologize
by taking/ther own life...
This she addressed to her superior...
Embezzlement. eh...
She sent this mail out yesterday
at 5:45%n thecevening.
I think she.died soon after that
You stay out of this. brat!!
£0, airy
Manner mode?
At home?
It,seems, that this will be concluded
as suicide ust as Officer Kinoshita sa s.
Please look at the calendar!
She's got a dentist appointment!
C.Calendar?
Its true that she has a dentist appointment
written for today.
You sure have good eyes. Etsuko...
You mean you can see
what's written from there .
Y.Yes: .well, sort of.
A calculated suicide
to the point of getting a wire ready
Would such a person make
a dentist appointment for today...?
Wait a sec.!!
Officer Kinoshita!
This may possibly not be a case of suicide!
So was she killed after all
by the man in that picture!!
No. I can't really answt hat,yet .
Officer Kinoshita, was this roo locked or
unlocked when you came here?
Yes sir: the door was not locked...
Which 'means she committed suicide
without locking the door
Rather,
a person.who commits suicide would
probably be.reluctant to be found in the act
The picture that was found atsthe front
entrance-was peeled of! from here.
H.Hey!!
Uh, Pops!
This man looks to have been intimate with
v6 VIC rm.
TR IA EAE OQ SEXO ne = ONCE YOO
Huh. .?
Pops. I wonder what this is?
There's some kind of white powder here
Ouch
It has no smell and is dry...
I think this powder is edible...
1 fol 5 Folks 00 GOLLY LXE « 1)
What else can you use cornstarch
for ether than cooking?
Well... for making Japanese sweets. Bi)
Rice cake filled with sweel beans is also
covered with cornstarch.
Inspector, the money that Ms Orawa
was in charge of at her company
a sum of about 30.000.000 yen Is missing
Her superior Mr. Shimizu is off teday.
Which means he doesn't know
that Ms. Ozawa committed suicide.
And, we've also come up with'something
unexpected.
This man who isVleading the cooler box is
where she sent her mail to.
He's her superior Mr... Shimizu.
You mean her superior was going with her?
Nobody in the company
seems to have known
that they were going witif*each other.
Moreover.
It seems that this man Shimizu liked
gambling and invested a lot of money into it.
Inspector, sounds fishy. don't you think?
Excuse me. Inspector.
It's him!
The one who came out of Mis room!
Tell the truth!
What are you talking about
and excuse me for being rude,
but who are you...?
Please get out of the way
and don't interfere.
Inspector!
He us Mr. Shimizu.
He was resting at home.
But. I asked him to come
Getting right down to business
did you know that Ms. Ozawa
who -was working under you
ahad-embezzled a sum of 30.000000 yen? 0
who was working under you
had embezzled a sum of 30.000.000 yen?
0. the officer informed me of it...
Oo, WO (cern ormec me o I...
No. the officer informed me of it...
I was utterly surprised.
Weren't you going with Ms. Fumie Ozawa?
If so, it would seem natural that she would
discuss the matter with\ ou...
We weren't going steady or anything!
Oh. you're .raforring to that picture
{4 » nr=K8 NAN] [nY- Je
Well, Ms. O@zaw1 sid that she wanted to try
EK J Sibel) Canes,
$0 I took her fishing with me.
Where were you this morning,
a little after 9:00?
What do you mean?
Someone saw you come fleeing out of
his room
No use playing dumb!
I saw you clearly with these eyes of mine!
I'll be straightforward with you.
Didn't you come here this morning at«9:00
and kill Ms. Fumie @zawa?
Are? ou tr lng to sa that
I, used Ms». Ozawa to embezzle money
from the company and killed her?
Yes, after you sucked sweet honey,
and sucked it all. you got rid 'of her, and...
Walt,
I didn't do it!
I had a class reunion with the classmates
of my elementary school days
and was in Hiroshima yesterday...
So at about 9-00 this morning.
I was at the airport in order to board
the plane headed for Haneda.
This is the cut half of the plane ticket.
Then, where were you last night
from 6:00 to 8:00?
was In the midst of the class reunion
This is the name card
of the person in charge.
Please let me have it for a while .
Oh...sure.
Go check on It!
Yes: sir!
Mr. Shimizu has an alibi.
But, Etsuko insists
that she dfihltely saw him...
If this Is not a suicide case...
[4 [4
How was it?
Wasn't what that man said<an outright lie!
It was just as Mr Shimizu had said.
I confirmed with the chairman of the class
reunion as well as the airline company.
Etsuko probably nustook someone else
to be Mr. Shimizu
But Etsuko has good eyes. doesn't she?
Because she was able to see the words
on the calendar from far away. right?
Then, are you saying that she wanted toe
sct Mr. Shimizu as the killer?
For what?
It's totally Greek to me...
Where's Officer Horita?
He is questioning a courier at the entrance
of the condo
because the courier seems to have seen
something...
SiffOe my alibi's been established.
I guess I'll get heading home then.
No you don't!
Don't let him go! He is a killer!
Etsuko...
What a woman
Do you have a grudge
against me or something
Do you have proof that I'm the killer?
I knew her since she was a little child.
She thought of me as~her mother...
and told me everything about herself.
She told me that she was going with
a person called Shimizu.
She also confessed to me that she
embezzled money from the company
Under his orders.
What a thing to say.
It's ticklish...
Stop It
It was «On vibrator,
0 gosh that was ticklish...
Yes. this is Mourl.
The thing that medical examiner asked for?
She has no bad teeth?
You mean Ms. Fumie Ozawa?
But. she had a dentist appointment.
Oh. no. thank you very much.
Nothing is wrong with her teeth,
and et she had a dentist appointment...?
I don't want to be a bother, but I don't think
this is Ms. Ozawars writing on the calendar.
Since I'm her superior,
I used to see her writing all the time...
WO GAR FY OF YO
until we get it evaluated but,
it does look different
Thon who wroto in tho calendar?
From what I hear, this woman here is
the one who first found the body?
I see, VI understand now.
It's not unusual for the first person
to find the body is the killer.
Well, it's too bad that Etsuko is the killer .
Just what do you mean. Mr. Mouri?
Etsuko wanted to set Mr. Shimizu up
as the killer.
'What's why she set it up so that it looked to
be as if Fumie had a dentist appointment.
She also peeled the picture from the album
and put the picture at the front entrance
for all to see
Etsuko, just in case, could you write
the word dentist for me. please?
It's that woman over there,
but are you sure?
Yes. I am.
She hid it here.
Inspector!
What is this?)
What?
Etsuko, you came into this room a little
after 9:00 this morning today. didn't you?
NEKO
The driver of a courier saw
you come out of this room.
Moreover, you seemed to be in a rush
and bumped into him
here's 5.000.000 yen here.
Can you explain
where this money came from
and why you hid it in the gas meter box
I-brought the money from my house.
I hid it becauserwhen I went to report
Fumie's death to the police
I'didn't want to drop it just in case...
You've come-mm 'this mom after all!
No. I haven't!
You killed Ozawa yourself
and tried to set me up as the killer.
Just what do you think you're saying!
Mr Mouri please don't hsten to
what this man as saying!
Well. what a predicament...
It's a lie. One of the two Is'lying.
Etsuko or Mr. Shimizu,
which of them is the killer.
What's this?
The scale of a fish?
Why would something-like this be here...
Maybe...
,see...So. that's the story
I did write-it
and I am the oné~
who put the picture there too.
Was it to put the blame of the crime
on Mr. Shimizu?
No. that's not it.
I did it to have Mr. Shimizu
who is the killer arrested.
Ihtaame to this». room thiswmornlng.
I was going to accompany Fume who sad
she'was going to turn herself into the'ipolice
I brought money along with me
thinking that returning some money
would make what she did a bit lighter.
I just knew
that Mr. Shimizu was responsible
for the way I found Fumie.
She told me that she was goingito confess
everything to the police.
But there is 'nothing in this room
that hints that Mr Shimizu didsanything.
ADORE Liki JON) OUR & = OsinO
in the front entrance
and schemed writing
what you did-on the calendar.
The killer is Mr Shimizu!
But. Etsuko that's your side of the story
ind we 'can't believe it completely.
After all. Mr. Shimizu does have an alibi...
We'd like to know where you got
such a sum as 5.000000 en too
so would you please come to the police?
Mr. Mouri. thank you for waiting
This is Mr. Inoue,
who works at the ice making shop.
Ice making shop? What's this about?
Just as ou had assumed...
Ice had bee, bought.
Officer Sato and Horita, take her to
the police and hear her out, will you.
Yes. sir.
Inspector. please wait.
Hmm?! What is it...
Oh! Mr. Mout! Did it start!
Let that person go right away.
The one who needs to go to the police is
you. Mr. Shimizu!
Why do I have 10 go to the police!
Mr. Inoue. when did he come to buy ice?
Yesterday afternoon.
He came to buy four blocks of ice
totaling 15 kilograms.
I remember him because he brouc ht
a large cooler box along with him.
That's it. At this time of ear.
How long does it take force to melt
and disappear?
At normal room temperature,
about half a day.
Thank you for taking time out to come here
Oh...no problem...
Thank you very much...
Officer Sato.
There are fish scales under the lid
for the bathtub
Take of the wire and come this way
Fish scales In the bathroom?
Mr. Shimizu. yesterday afternoon
you probablyfput:Ms. Ozawa to sleep
using sleeping pills
Then. you carried her into the bath tub
You made her sit on the bench you made
using ice and the lid of the bath tub and left.
As the ice melts the bench lowers
and chokes her neck.
At the estima ed time of her death
between 6:00p.m. to 8.00 p Mm.
Half the Ice would've melted
And. this morning. when Etsuko found her,
the ice had melted
and the floor of the bath tub was dry
It may have been stuck to the cooler box
that you loaded the ice with.
A fish scale was on the lid of the box.
D.Does that serve as proof that I killed her!
Listen, Ms. Osawa sent me mail at 5:45
In the evening.
How can a person who is asleep with wire
around her neck do Mmcthing like that?
Conan, will you put Ms. Ozawa's cell phone
in the open space of the book shelf?
Stick about half of it out though
Okay
Oka .
The cell phone is on manner mode.
Officer Sato, please call
Ms. Ozawa's cell phone...
Oh... es sir!
If you look at the history of incoming calls.
You will notice that she received a call
a little before 5:45.
No. but I didn't do it. I was in Hiroshima...
You sure are obstinate!
Officer Sato, please look at the place
where the wire is tied.
You'll see hair stuck to it.
Don't you see hair other than
Ms.Ozawa s hair that is dyed?
There is
Something that looks like
straight black hair...
Mr. Shimizu. when you carried Ms. O- awa
your hair got tangled with Ms. Ozawa's hair.
However, you did not realize it.
Mr Shimizu, it will be obvious once
we get it evaluated by the forensic officers.
Whose hair it is
I'm sorry.
She said that she couldn't continue
any longer.
And that she would turn herself
in to the police so .
That's why I
You drank a lot of sweet honey.
So from now you're going to have to drink
a lot of bitterness.
Orieinal Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
froducers.
Background Music.
CNIS) nl
Character Desions ty!
Story 'Fditor,
JUNICHI 11 + KA
KAN]? ITASHIWABARA
' PE at Na » '2
I / v4 AN
TOSHIKd INOUI
Animation -Dircectorss
JidelorO dD 3)
ale latt JD JAY 40
AISUSHI AC NO
AKIO KAWAMURA?
AGL ier @
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBL IANI
TAKASHIENOMURA
»  > > » » »
TAKARISA AA
Recording >
Editor.
TERUMITSU WKADA
Chief Director.
KENJI. KODAMA).
Produced By.
IMS, ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
1 « ssowatinn with
YOMIURI IELECASTING
CORPO ANON
710 CIIV I=IN AN
GONMIEOECOYAMAT SHOU SRUWRAN DY IV TM
ARIES wed
Well~ You sure were fantastic!
Mr. Mouri, Inspector Megure was saying...
that your plan of letting Shimizu suck
sweet candy first
then giving him the blow
was utterly splendid
That a pinch of salt is necessany @ bring
out the full effect of sweetness...
D aybe I should shake a little salt
on cu too?
It's sure ringing a long time
Wo Geo Jz yeas eV
There was an incident that happened
12+ ears:ago
a was very simi ar 0 us casc
It's Ran=~I
hen, don't tell mo...Don't tell me that...
Oh no
(BRIAR)
Alike)
Request from a Queer Family Part 1