Stars. are for some reason attractive
They can be the culprit or the actor
A secret-filled cell phone
There are tricks everywhere in the mails
as well as the conversations
D An entangled baffling:case!
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance;
with the LO. of an adul
No case is left unsolved
with Détective Conan
sf A
I know that... I shouldn't send this
Maybo I should just take my time
ind see what happens?
I know I may)n1ve a chance to come
in touch with their boss eventually.
Anyway .
Conan!
You're still in your pajamas...
I told youito hurry and get changed
because weirO going out. didn't. 1?!
Lid
Come on. never mind the cell pone.
O.Okay
Gee whiz...
Oh, right. I guess.!'ll send Shinichi
rr mail before going out
Because he may show up
ut of the blue. while we're out.
We're going to accompany
Dad today to cover a case...
If it turns out to be a tough one,
I may be asking you for advice...
That's Conan's cell phdnc ringing...
Oh...he just got mail...
Hmm. don't tell me it's the mail I just sent?
2 WORE
+ WORE
I can't be becauséll sent mine
to Shinichi's address...
But, the timing is too good for it
to bg)a coincidence. 4
LA RA
(BJ#R)
Request from a Queer Family" Part 1
Did,you look at the contents...?
N.No. I didn't...
It sounded like you got incoming mail,
so I just wondered who it was from...
I. m sure it's from Doc!
Oh... just as I thought
5 '1 ,1»:
PB s repwmng
the Youth Detective Squad badge...
Ugh. it's from Ran-!
Which mean, oh, don't tell me...
don't tell me.
Talk-about trouble
Give me a break
I mean, do you guys have to tag along
Iike this. each and every time.
But your cliont requested that you come
along with family.and all right?
Besides, we may come up with some idea
that may help you out¥again too.
Right:- Ran?
With a fantastic deduction
that is just as good as some great detective
that is usually god knows where
Going all out like that...
There's something fishy about
that mail that you. got a while ago.
H's probably taking measures
30 that the mails that I sent him
wo t'be seen by someone
he doesn't want them to be seen by.
- - SN
He told me that he couldn't give me his
phone number because he's bus
and can't answer the phons,
but he gave it: O Conan after all.
If he had been g¢gntacting Con:™n
all the time.
Conan's fantastic deductions
and him, for some strange reason,
knowing things about me
all fall into place
That Shimucchi. taken; advantage
of a child how dare he
141" never forgive him!
Oh: tho-coll phono?
Yes. I'd like you to find it for me
If possible. by today...
If not. I may end up
not being able to stay here-anymore.
Oh, and why would that be...?
Well. the thing is...
What, you'll be getting mail from the one
you're having an extra marital affair
with tonight ?!
You're the one who needs to hush up,
gee...
I'm worried that the mail may be seen
by my jealous husband
by my jealous husband,
my strait-laced father-in-law or
talkative younger brothers...
Then, why don't you contact your {HM-HOV
Immediately
and tell him not to send you mall
Well, he's the one who ¢ ill.) me
from his side all the time.
And his number is an unlisted number.
He 1lw1ays sends me mail
over the weekends
but he rarely looks at the mails
that I send him from my side
I have no way of contacting him
from m side.
He sounds pretty selfish
But there are egotistical people
Iike that around....!
Right, Conan?
0.Oh~?!
O.Oh~7l
And. where and when did you lose it... 7 «rr
I don't know.
I just realized the night before last...
But, I'm pretty sure that someone
in this house has it.
What do you mean?
} called my cell phone as soonas lost It.
After about 10 rings or so,
somebody answered the phone
but said nothing and hung up right away
But I heard the sound of my father-in-law
% ky WEAR xo) L=tanloo0) WLR,
on the other side of the line.
Listen to this.
He sure.sounds terrible.
Moreover, he only plays-the flute
in his room...
So, the fact that this sound. was heard
on the phone means...
{Loe=C dix=yicor=Alll MO MENSEFSOIMSW MO Ne
in this house...
But no matter how many times I called after
that. I get no answer and the phone is cut.
Hon... why not get everyone in the house
together and...
YzYes. of course I already asked everyone
Butithey've all told me
that they don't know
I'm sure that they're waiting for me to goof!
Somebody probably .doosn'tilike me
and wants to chase me out of this house...
If divorce comes up god knows how much
alimony will be demanded of me...
Why don't you call the phone company and
have them stops your phone service... 2
Even so, I wouldn't be able to
erase the mails
that he had sont me from the memory...
10 (mallee 1. @d lem sew.
That he had sent me from the memory...
I dewhave it locked just in case
SO NO one gets to look at them.
AMA stop the phone,
it:wouldiprobably breed: more 'suspicion
and the lock may be undone.
Hmm. But. how should I go about looking-for it?
Ou're her friend from
your Jr. High School days.
Oh. yes sir! I'm" Mouri...rather, Goro Mori.
Mr. Mori will be building a house soon
so he wanted to see this house
that you designed for reference...
Oh, I see, please help yourself
and look around to your heart's content.
That's why 'sho 'asked him
0 bring they family with him.
I'll let.you:listen.to my flute
Oh, uh, I really don't think...
Can you tell if you hear
your cell phone ring?
Yes. but it could be on manner mode...
Okay. ring it.
NY this age.
ou need to go to the restroom
so often_that it's a bother.
Lxcuse me for a moment.
Don't tell me that father...
I=don't think so, because whoever
answered the phone just now
hung up right aOay...
He sure doesn't look to be
such a strait-laced person.
He looks that way,
but is actually veryafrightening...
Even the incident
that happened 12 years ago...
t wasebecause of father to begin with...
12. .yoars ago?
@Oh. well... never- mind
- Se-All) WO ke x AX SW.HER GR N@ Mi?
Oh~your classmate?
You mean your ex-boyfriend or something'?
Of course not.
Oh. so you write novels?
Yoah: I'm still unknown
but in three months
ou ma. be hearing my name
whether you like it or not.
Shigehide Kariya. You mean you're the one
Who writes those pure love novels?
So, the rumor about your novel
being aired on TV/ Is) true.
But. I expected you to be much older...
On. your novel's going to the dramatized
How-wonderful.
Hey Ran. make the-call.
Qu ed G50 BRO DUI 1
Yes. hello...
How about it?
No, he isn't the one
,1, because it hung up right» away again.
Yes. a meeting from now?
[Isis
Il meet you at the family restaurant
in front of the station then...
What timing-though,
a while ago and even now,
talk about asstring: of coincidences.
R.Right. coincidences happen a lot.
Oh, things that seem to happen by chance
are called coincidences
because they don't usually happen
I... guess you're night.
ButsMrs. Kariya,
if it's this type of investigation
you may as wellsgel yourself another cell
phone and try callingsyourself.
Are you saying that I go out and
ge myse sano -1erce pone.
I don't have much money
that I can use freely.
I decided to hire a professional instead of
relying on my friends
(). Oh
So. your husband is an illustrator.
He doesn seemrte-be : dung, though.
WN RIO WR eeu), Gaia I 3 one ROE,.
See. coincidences don't keep on happening.
This picture sure looks familiar.
This picture sure looks familiar...
Oh, that's it, the painting of Tsugutaka
Kariya that was popular some time ago.
Or. so. you're familiar with my painting
Just who are you all?
Oh. dear, he is.
Oh. so you're Tsugutaka Kariya.
I expected you to be a lot younger...
Phooey, I guess you could say the paintings
of the young people are like e-mails,
where as my paintings are letters.
The depth of color differs.
A guest?
Leave it be.
I'm sure it's the publisher that's come to
pressure me to hand in my work
It's been ringing for quite
some time already
Uh. wasn't it a guest?
W. Well, I went to answer-the door
but there. was no one there.
Do things like this happen often?
Sometimes.
Mrs. Kariya says it's some child
NERA) 2) (Ott
What're we going to do
There no place to look for it. anymore.
Mr. Mourizwno Weed to worry
As you can seell'vesfound my cell phone.
WA =X¥2l
Thank ,you so very much
I'llamake sure I deposit the payment to you.
Talk about a stupid case.
Yeah, there are people deceiving people
behind their back too.
Talk about stupid.
Um. may! stay over at Doc's house tonight?
Huh, you're going to play
games again with Doc.?
4NO. because I have a lot of things
wan 0 a over wl 1 you ong. .onan.
4 Okay, then, can we justistop by
for a little while.
Because mm badge is repaired
Oh~Shinichi. what's up at this time of day?
Bummers. I'm in a fix.
Tonight at around 7.00,
It's seems that Ran...
called my cell phone...
a woman's body was found in a car
parked along the Teimusu River I
Vie aid)
The woman has-been identified
from her belongings as
Mrs Tomoko Kariya, 39 years old.
Aihousewife residing in Haidocho.
Thopohce have concluded this
to be a murder case...
W, Whatcthemd
The victim is Mrs. Tomoko Kariya.
According to the medical examiner,
she was stabbed in the stomach then later
hit on the head with a blunt instrument.
She was stabbed then later assaulted?
Yes sir, there's a possibility
that there could be more than one culprit.
Because it's unnatural to think that
the culprit wound stab someone
then use another weapon
to attack her again
Wall 2266.
I think there was similar case like this
in the past...?
Her bag and cash are nowhere in sight,
so it ma be arobber...
We can't be too sure. Officer Takagi.
Oh, Mr. Mouri?!
Hey. hey, this is work
for the police toshandle!
I wish you passersby outsiders
Keep out of-this.
No. no. Inspector!
I am no outsider to this case!
The fact is,
that woman asked me to do work for her.
What?! Mrs Kariya was having
an extra-marital affair?!
N.No way
Unfortunately, it seems to have been so.
Then, did her partner killer her?!
No. we don't know for sure yet .
Would you have : ny idea
who it could've been?
Come to think of it, 2 guy with 7" mustache
accompanied by a child came around.
Right, I think his name was Goro Mer
or something like that.
Goro Mori?
Well that's...
It's him
How dare you-—!
You've got me wrong...
Kogoro Mouri. that renown detective...!
Yes sir
When I came, this afternoon I couldn't reveal
Mm name cause of certain.reasons...
Does that mean that you already arrested
the one who killed Tomoko?
IN Cs Juno Ot
Excuse mg, where were you today
at:around 7:30 in the evening?
Huh, me? I was here all the while,
right Mr Nakamura?
Oh yes sir, he was blowingshis flute from
a little before 7:00 when everyone came.
All the way to about 8:00...
All the way to about 8.00...
He stopped blowing for a little while
around 7:30 when I served him dinner.
Did you actually see him then?
No, when he's blowing his flute I am told
to leave his dinner outside his room
SO as Not to interrupt him
But maybe he smelled the aroma of curry
outside the sliding paper door
Oh, it's been a long time
since we had curry for dinner...
Yes, around 7:30. 4.1 was here.
I came back after the meeting ended
at 6:00.
And was confined]in this room
working right through.
I think the two over there can testify to that?
Is that right?
Yes sir, that's correct...
Ever since the lights &f'thé-room was
turned on around 6:30
Shigehide's silhouette was in view
from the sliding paper door...
Even when I brought him his dinner...
Which means you didn't actually see
him in person
No, because I'm told not to enter
when he is working.
Is at really true though,
that Tomoke was killed ?
that's why we're investigating the case.
Then hurry.on. with it and get .going home
Since you all came and keep calling out to
me or going back and forth the corridor.
I cant seem to. concentrate on my work.
What's with him? That's no way to talk.
Which means
the only people left in this house
that we haven't questioned yet
Is Tomoko's husband.
Yes, sir
His dinneriis still left outside...
Mr. Tsugutaka Kariya, please answer us!
What's up?
Well. he won't say anything...
Well. he won'tisay anything...
Asked If I'have-anyidea: if I don't I can't
possiblyranswe ithat question
It wasn't in me to usually
talk to herlinyway:
It exons Goes om evem
your dinner too...
Are you feeling sick or something...?
NO, I was absorbed in work
that I simply forgot.
When you brought dinner to him,
you didn't talk to him?
N.No well...
But. I'm sure he was in his room
because I could smell
the sweet aroma of his pipe...
Okay, now that you're done,
get going home!
His wife's been killed
and he's still going to work.
Those three have .an alibi.
Es sir
It would take 20 minutes even if you went
fin speed from here to the murder site...
hey couldn't have committed the crime.
Which makes the man she was having
anjaffair with the most-suspicious.
But, we have no idea of who,
or where he is...
Shall we try tracing him
starting with Mrs. Kariya's friends?
Yes. this is the Kariya residence.
U.Uh, there's a phone call for Mrs. Kariya
Hey. hurry and put Tomokoxonsathetline
Tell her to answer my mail
This is the police
What is your relationship
with Mrs. Tomoko Kariya?
Huh?
What?
- - en. -»
He's innocent.
Huh?
He seems to have been
at a pub in Hokkaido
He says he called in rage
because she didn't answer his mails
nor answer her cell phone today.
Then, he didn't know about the incident?
But, Inspector, it only takes 1 or 2 hours,
to Hokkaido by plane,
so if he flies straight to Hokkaido
after committing the crime...
No. there were several of his colleagues
b Rim
who said that, they began drinking
about 8:00
So. he couldn't have committed the crime...
If so. who could've killed her?
How strange though, that all three people
eat their meals In a different room.
Yes .
But, everyone used to eat together
until 12 years ago.
12 years ago?
Yes, when the 3rd son, Eisuke was here,
everyone always ate together...
Right...
Eisuke...?!
Eisuke Kariya...
I get it! Now I remember,
it's that case that happened 12 years ago!
Inspector?
There was n incident 12 years ago
that seemed very similar to this case!
The one who was killed was Eisuke's fiancé,
Ms. Motoka Aida.
Like Tomoko, she was stabbed
then later struck to death.
Back then, Eisuke who had disappeared
was also thought to be a suspect but...
a large amount of his blood was also found
near the phone booth.
Moreover, after the incident, all the cash
from Eisuke's account had been withdrawn
So, we thought that Eisuke
nC = of, xed)
and killed after the money
wad taken from him...
The murder site was a lonely place,
and there were no witnesses
Investigation was at a deadlock...
Come to. think of it, there was a call
from Eisukes friend last night.
For BEisuke?
N.No.
Fer Mrs. Kariya
Something about the caller, Eisuke and
Tomoko all used to
belonglto the same drama club
of the university they went to.
Back then she seemed to be very annoyed.
I didn't call! Cut out your stupid talk!
Something sure smells fishy.
Do you know the phone number
of that persons'
Oh... Is that so. I
Okay, if something comes up
I may get back to you. thank you.
How was it?
He's innocent. He has a perfect alibi.
He seems to have received silent phone
call last" night. so he checked
the history of his incoming calls and found
that it was Tomoko's cell phone number.
He tried calling her back many times,
but couldn't connect
so he decided to call her home phone,
Strange.
En Br
Mrs Kariyass cell phone disappeared
the. night before esterda .
Fe I 5
and-it-was supposed to have been locked.
D.Don't tell me that the person
who had the cell phone
unlocked the phone and made the call...
\ If so, could that have been
the motive of the culprit?
Several calls from her extra-marital partner
were found saved in her cell phone too.
In other words. that person is the killer...
But, you found her cell phone right away,
didn't you?
No. Mrs. Kariya is the one who found it
and I don't even know where she found
er... I didn't bother asking
Okay, Conan, we got
all the information we need.
You're going to call Shinichi, aren't you?
Go on. and call him!
Right once you call him:ythat s it.
I'm taking that cell phone from you ind... 4
talk"to him directly myself
You can't possibly do something like that.
What can-t.you-do!
Because toilock the cellphone
ou need to enter:4 digits.
There are 10.000 R@ssi » lities
from 0000 to 9999".
I couldn't possibly try
all those numbers out.
Well, maybe if I were 6 bored
and had nothing to do
and moreover, was an invisible man
unseen b an bod . then ma be...
An invisible-many
W's true that)
If it were to take 3 secondsgto try it once,
that would add up to 30:000 seconds.
8 hours.
Whew. I'd give up at that point
Which means the one who unlocked
the phone would be someone
who can stay without being bothered by
anyone for a long period of time
In other words, the three who are
usually confined to theirreoms4d
7 Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO A@GYAMA
Pr 0 ( {luce yr S
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITOWOSHIOIZA
Background:Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Storygtditor.
Maul ITO
Story Editor.
[Um/lam 110m
Scripts By
KANJIgkASHIWABARA
KAZUNARIKOUCHI
JUNICHI$MTY SHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSFTIRIJNOUE 1
\ui 2ilon Dirzeiar
MASATOMO, SUDO
Mod Jr
IAKASHI(HIYOD Op,
Art Diréator.
YUKIHIROQ SHIBUTANI
YWKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photograp
+» TAKA HI'NOMURA +
HIRONOBU HORIROSHI
ISA.
Recording Director
KATSUYQSHI KOBAYASHI)
idditor
TERUMITSU OKADA
Chief-Director.
KENJI'KODAMA
odudced By 7
TMS ENTERTAINMENT; LTD
Inf ssocralion with
\) r~r~qAu-\q
ITROJIVIEURAD TCLLUADNTIING
CORF ORATION
[ELA IV I cal AN
Colla NO VY NTO VR TR, UN DAA ANE
MI 22nd tes wrsvd
I'm going to send that mail once more...
and this time for sure...
Thon Wwhatraboul the pipe 37?
Are you saying that there-was double
or something-around?! »
A double...
Thanks to you police people
I haven't been-able concentrate.
SO my work's not-moving 1long-at.all.
The only thing thinkable is...
Conan himself is...
Shinichi!
Shiniehi!
Request from a Queer Family Part 2