Stars are for some reason attractive
They can be the/culprit;or.the actor
Sense of vision. hearing and smell
n alibi relying on these three sense.
The clue to invalidating the alibi
IS a past incident!
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case 1s left unsolved
WI \ 'O UL IVO UOHdH
of 404
(IR 7k)
Request from a Queer Family Part 2
In other words. the suspects are
Daisaku. the head of the household that
was confined to his room blowing the f ute.
Tsugutakn, the oldest son
who was illustrating...
ind the second son, Shigehide
who was writing a novel
These Lures men
No...up to now
all the deductions were made based on
Conan leading everyone to them.
It's as if the thoughts
that cross an innocent child's mind
coincidentally serve as hints
to reaching a conclusion,
but it can only be done
because he is secretly having Shinichi
make the deductions...
Even up to now, I've never seen him making
phone calls before coming up with an idea.
Which means,
there is only one thing I 'can, think of...
That this child
That Conan himself
Is Shinichi.
That's why all the calls from Shinichi
come in with no number display...
So that I can't call him from my side...
But...
During the school festival,
they were-both togcther.
Am I taking my Imagination too far after all
No. don't be deceived!
I'm sure Shinichi used some kind of trick!
What's the matter. Ran?
Oh no it's nothing.
Oh...?
I've got to mako sure...
C.Come to think of it, right after
I sent the mail to Shinichi
Conan's cell phone...
I'l send that mail once more...
And this time for sure
I'll get held of conclusive evidence
that he can't get away with!
It's not . responding.
A visitor?
Were you expecting somebody?
N.No...
It says my mail's been-sent...
So. was what happened 'this-morning
a coincidence after all?
Well, I guess so
Conan couldn't possibly be Shinichi...
No...it's Shinichi!
He could be using seme method that Is
unthinkable for ordinary people to think up
If you're going to be that way.
Mm Not going to take my eyes off ou.
Not even for an instant,
until you expose yourself...
So. you'd better be ready,
Shinichi!!
My... wonder if it's just another prank?
A prank?
There are times when the doorbell rings
but therc's no One there
Xe BFS GOO [ex] ody,
013% Iuuerflxylhvqgxxanmaeil gmxsuvil mess
It usually happens only ence a week
But. M's already this, time of day
to be a prank by children
One of the three probably rang the
door chime using some method.
And rigged up some alibi trick
while the door was being answered
It's true that the alibi of the three 1s being
supported b the housekeepers
who have brought the dinner and placed
the dinner tray outside each room
during the time of the crime,
which was around / 30.
But. they did not directly sce
any of the three...
If so, the most suspicious would 'be
Tisugutaka: 'the husband of Tomoko
who had been killed
If he saw. the mail in her cell phone
that came from the one
she was having an affair with.
That would be a motive too.
If Mrs. Kariya was having an affair.
(Conf it is Bal Ben soon Wega)
overlooked it
Why do you think so?
12 years "go whon tisuke, his 3rd son s
flancd was killed in the phone booth.
They:were actually on a date...
THO FER PRON AN YE 3 FOR Heli)
asking him if. it was 'okay toilet.
Motoka:spend,thernight over at the house
becauselMotoka had missed the last train
Mr Kariya who was in the living room askody
for Motoka to come on the phone.
He thenitold her that if 1 slut like her ever
ares to come through the doo
of the Kariya residence,
he'll see to it that she does not live!
Was Motoka alse having an affair?
I don't knew how Mr. Kariya found out but
Yes<«1 think thcy both stayed at the phone
booth
withoutsheing able to make it home and
was killed there
Was the police notified?
I only know that there was 2 phone call.
Shigehide told us that it had nething to do
with the case.
So that it wasn't necessary to report it...
Which means that. .the only person that
0 HONG) GO COG TOTO Wen
Shigehide...
We heard Tomoko and Shigehide arguing in
the corndor ay month ago.
Something about "It's ternblo to
Mf. to,
AVES rop...
It was about the dialogue of the parents of
the main character that
appear in the novel which is to be
dramatized soon
being very similar to their own .
Mr Kanya was outraged sayimg that
if the dialogue is not changed
before the dramatization, shewould sue
him...
s a result, Shigehide agreed to change
the dialogue
and everything seems to have been
settled .
What. you're all still here?
)id you find the killer...?
Oh. well...not yet...
By the way. at around 730 when your
dinner was delivered to you
you answered through the siding paper
door that.
It's been azlong*time since we've had
Curr
But. how did you know it was curry?
Tae aroma ." Théssliding door was slightly
opened
Um... what's this used for?
I use it to...listen to my flute teacher play
and practice
I'm making process day by day!
Now that I don't go out often,
playing the flute is my only favorite
pas ime...
Oh~so you hurt you leg at work and you
haven't gone out much since then...
Yes, since he used to stay at home all
the time,
he found out that his wife was having an
affair with someone else.
And the like...and got a divorce .
I sce. that's why he 1s very sensitive to
extra-marital.
Curry. was one of the dishes that his wife
was good at making...
Curry was one of the dishes that his wife
That's why you didn't make curry too often?
Out of consideration for Mr Kariya...
Yes. we were actually thinking of making
beef stew. but...
we decided to change it to curry just
10 minutes before serving it...
Hey. come on! hat'stlenough!
I just finished telling you that I was in this
room at around 7430!
When you were served dinner, you raised
your hand and responded.
She saw your silhouette through the sliding
paper door
but she didn't actually see you in person...
You mean you think I rigged it so that Ay,
my silhouette would be reflected on the 7
paper door
I don't think that's possible...
I can tell whether it 1s actually
the silhouette of a person or not...
0 see
So, now that you'ne«one,
go on home. will you!
Thanks to you. the police coming here
I haven't been able to concentrate nd
haven't made any progress in my work!
One of his family members has died
and yet he doesn't shed a tear at all.
It's a wonder
he's a writer of pure love novels.
He sure doesn't look to be one.
Talking about not looking to be one.
When we first met them you were saying .?
He . Ran?!
Huh? What?
You were saying that you thought he
was much older...
Oh, that's because the peop e who come
out in his novels don't dye their hair...
Even if people with dyed hair come out,
they're treated as delinquents...
That's why I thought he was pretty old...
Besides
His story usually has scenes in which the
main characters are at the place
the 're supposed to meet, and et,
they don't get to see each other
because a pillar IS In the way. just lake In
some old movie...
It's so sad watching the characters waiting
and worrying ~
concerned about their loved ones that
don't show up
They're so different fromisomebody I know,
that's«always close by? yet insists on
secretly watching his partner...
You think so too! don't you. Conan?
Loan t really tell because I'm just a child.
You think so. don't you?
\ res...
nough I have nothing more 10 say than
that I was here. right through
But, smolling the aroma of the pipe
when dinner was brought here
Is not enough to serve as proof of an alibi...
Then. who was smoking the pipe?
A double or something?!?
A double
You ate the curry
By the way. d d somebody come again?
I heard the doorbell ring a while ago...
No It seems that somebody played a
[Ar al LY An,
I think that Tsugutaka is quite upset over
this prank...
Each time he returned from outside,
he used to ask if any pranks were played...
When we told him there were, he used to
get into a foul mood
Oh, and he used to get really upset over
crank calls too
Yes. it rings once. and hangs up.
TL rings tor somo Lime and thon hangs up.
We got a one today too!
When you came. a little after 8-00.
Was it an undisplayed number?
No... the thing is...
although the phone call came In it wasn't
displayed in the incoming call history...
Don't tell me that the chime we heard just
a while ago...
Uh, Ran!
What?!
You sent mail out a while ago. didn't you?
You did. didn't you?
Yes?! I did!
Bug ou?
Bug your
Did you verify the address?
I didn't have to verify it because all I did
was re-send the mail
I sent out this morning...
Huh? Oh. no?! Who did I mail this out to?
(Just as I thought after all...
hates why she found the cell phone «.o
Caslily.
Which means that person is the killer...
The killer used the case of 12 years ago to
hide his shadow within the dark...
So that he alone could continue to stay In
the light...
I guess it's about time we call it a day
then...
Yes. I think it'll be difficult to undo their
alibi unless we use some sort of magic...
Magic?!
I saw a fantastic magic show on TV
the other da!
This lady 1511 a reotangular-box.
Her face, hands nd legs are sticking, out,
but her body splits into-three!
Talk about shocking!
You fool! There are three people in there!
Oh, really?! I guess you can t deceive
people carrying it out alone
but if there are others to help you
it's possib e!
So. what'!
Mm If one of the three helps out,
then the alibi trick will work?
It's not possible, because the meals were
delivered to three rooms that are apart
Forgsome reason Mrs. Kariya finds the cell;
and as soon as she does so she is killed...
The three men who live in this house are to
be suspected. that's for sure...
Yes... «the cell phone was also missing from
the scene of the murder...
But. Ran...
Don't you think that the person who is
hiding that cell phone is really stupid?
Huh?
Because while we were looking for the
cell phone.
no matter how many times we cal ed.
The person on the other side kept answering
andishanging up right away. right?
Of course.
Heecause once his voice 1s heard,
it would be obvious who he is!
But. if it were me. If I knew that such an in
convenient phone call would be coming
would swit€h off my cell phone.
Which means that Shinichi did have
his cell phone switched off!?
You Fool!
He was waiting for Tomoko's man
to call or mail her.
That's why he didn't switch off her phone!
If so, he could've adjusted the volume of
her cell phone
v because ho was getting repeated calls
4@r, was it that he didn't know how to
operate the phone?
I'm sure he knew what he was doing
because he knew how to unlock
the cell phone!
But even if the cell phone were to he
Iocked. it would be obvious
that 4 digits would have to be entered
In order to unlock the phone
herefore, even If the killer had no ide
how to use the phone.
So long as he had lime, I'm sure he
would've been able to unlock it...
Using a cell phone Is not all that hard, so
just touching a little here and there
would give anyone an idea of how to
work it...
It took me a while to get used to at
though...
You're talking about back when you first
bought your cell phone. aren't you?
Right, right, there aren't too many people
who do not know
know how to use a cell phone in this
da and age
If that person were to be locked up
somewhere
for about 10 years or so. well, maybe...
10 ears?
Come to think of it, the use of cell phone
became widespread about 10 years ago...
Hey...wasn't it about 12 years ago?
That the 3rd son Eisuke's fiance was killed
and his whereabouts became unknown...?
Could it have been Eisuke that had
Tomoko's cell phone?
Don't tell me that he's somewhere In
this house?!
Which means that one of the three was
hiding him. .?
It's understandable
that after being separated from
the outside world for 12 years
he finds the cel phone and becomes
interested in it. and takes it away...
It was after all, Eisuke's friend who got a
call from the cell phone that was lost...
If it were him, he probably had a lot of time
to figure out how to unlock the phone...
And, when he went to return the phone,
Tomoko found him,
so he killed her along with whoever was
hiding him in order to keep her from talking
The alibi would become invalid...
Okay! Go get a search warrant!
Eisuke could be the killer of the incident
that happened 12 ears ago!
Yes, sir!
The problem is. who's sheltering him?
I think the most suspicious is the head of
he household. Daisaku...
There was a radio cassette recorder in his
room, right?
He probably recorded his voice, "It's been a
Iong time since we've had curry *
And. at the time of the crime around 730,
he made Eisuke that
he was sheltering push the button
in order to establish his alibi...
I think I'm kind of hungry
Would you like to have some curry then,
because there's some more left. «+. 7?
Oo It was supposed to be beef stew,
right?
And you changcd it to curry 10 minutes
before you served it. right?
10 minutes ago... means about 7:20...
It takes more than 20 wnutes to the
murder site from here...
He'll have to leave by a little after 7:00
to make it in time
Then, it's Tsugutaka who was smoking
his pipe in the room
and illustrating In his room!
As for the aroma from the pipe ll he had to
do was make Eisuke smoke it VY
Oh, well, curry as my favorite. so maybe
I'll have some after all
Huh?
In fact I was, thinking of taking the curry
that was outside the man's room
Somewhere and eating it...
But. I decided against it...
Because if the plate of curry disappears,
it'll be easy to figure out who ate the curry!
Waits isc
If Tsugutaka made Eisuke stay
in his room to serve his double
why didn { he make him take the curry
into his room?
That would make it 10OK more like he was
in the room...
He probably couldn't come out because
he's someone that shouldn't be around...
Even so. Tsugutaka would've noticed the
dish after coming back
from the murder site and would've taken
it inside!
F he left it outside his room,
it would only-give way to suspicion that
he wasn't in his room during the time of
the crme...
Besides, sugutakahad eaten:the:wcurnry
after it had gotten co d:
There as no reason why he wouldn't
take it into his room...
If so. the remaining suspect would be. the
one who was writing a novel in his room...
Shigehide...
I killed Tomoko?
I'm sheltering my kid brother Eisuke?!
You've gotta he kidding!
But. if so. everything falls into place...
You made Eisuko have his hair done
Iike yours
Then to make him respond through the
sliding paper door isn't all that difficult...
- - - 3)
r. Tsubouchi¥from the oditing section .
I'm sort of busy rightanow.
Yes...I'll call you back .
You're mean. aren't you, m ster...
Because you use a cell phone.
yet you don't lel the characters
in your novel usc it!
Why don't you lctathcm use It?
[tS fio nae yo aman t Kew gout ter
phone. right?
C.Can't be?
So. /
Were you makinc your kid brother write
the novels 7?
Rs. /
Were you making our kid biether write
the nove 8 .
Were you making your kid brother writo"
the novels 7?
That's why there weren't too many people
who dyed their hair in the novel...
12 years ago not too many people uscd I
to dye their hair yet...
Which means that
s true that the dialogues of
Mrland Mrs. Kariya were used too
T's true tht the dialogues of
Mr. and Mrs<Kariya were used too?
If he lives In the attic
I héYves In the atc.
Lay g
If he lives in the attic.
If ho hvos In the attic.
he'll be able to hear ll the conversation
that goes.on n the house.
He'll:-be able to hear all thc conversation
that goes+on in the house.
Longer!
He'll be able to hear all the conversation
that goes on in the house
kg all
he'll be able to hear all the conversation
that goes on in the house...
gL. «5
hell be able to hear all the conversation
that goes on in the house...
he'll be able to hear all the conversation
that goes on in the house.
Oh, well. that's...
It's okay. already...
It's enough.
Shigehide...
YOU ro
Yes... I'm Eisuke Kariya, who killed my
fancé 12 years ago.
And was beingsprotected by my older
brother all this time.
Because of the words of my father that I
heard back then through the phone...
If a slut like you ever dare ¢ome through
the door of the Kenya residence.
I ll see to it that yousdo not live!
We got into an argument, I lost my temper
and killed Motoka...
Was pp Inning o 1 mysoe 00...
But I was in shock and found myself
at home. when Shigehide found me...
Shigehide. I'm in trouble. I... killed Motoka*
Don't worry! I'll work something out...
And 'you've stayed in the attic ever
11%)
Yes I thought of turning myself in many
times
but just couldn't find the courage to do so
I had no intention of killing her...
Then, why did you hit Her after you
stabbed her?
You hit her. didn't you?
No...l only stabbed her...
So, it's you who killed 'Motoka
12 ears ago...
What the
WéWait! Why would Shigehide kill Motoka?
Maybe because he was the one who was
having an affair with Motoka?
I see! If it's ah affair within the same
household. it's understandable that
Daisuke who didn't go out often,
would find out about it too...
Yes, "1nd you killed Tomoko
who found out about it to shut her up
Using the same method you used
172: years ago
You figured if push came to.shove you
would put all the blame on Eisuke!
That's ridiculous.
Shigehide protected me for the past
12 years 1.
No. . he protected youvbecause
If the police 'arrested you
everything would bo disclosed!
The facts that tafter yousEisuke «
stabbed Motoka.
he killed her with a finishing blow!
1. That's not true. is It. Shigehide'?)!
No...Why would lifdo something like that?
Oh. I remember Mrs. Kariya saying...
that the ringtone of the cell phone was
1 strange one
Bo quiet!
If you want to set me up as the killer that
badly. show me proof that I did it...
If you want to set me up '18 the: kllléf that
badly. shew Me proof that I did it...
Guests again?
O. I think It's the sound for incoming mail
Remember, 'Mrs. Kariya disappeared while
Iooking for the cell phone?
She had my cell phone at that.time...
So 'she sent mailmo her cell phone
repeatedly
and found her cellphone
with the sound of incoming mail!
L's@e...
No matter what button I pushed,.
I couldn't stop this sound.
I got all flustered when Tomoko showed
up at the attic...
I was able to std} the sound
of the cell phonesbut...
The ringtone is the same as that
of the Kariya family...
I see If left that way,
no matter where in the house you are
you have an excuse to eave,
SO you can answer the call or ee mails
from tie one. ou're having an affair with...
From the one you're having an affair with
from the one you're having an affair with.
And the fact that the sound as ranging
NOW means
that the cell phone is somewherewnsthis
room...
Shigehide, the cell phone that you carried
away from the scene of the murder...
Tomoko s cell phone...
You should've thrown it away immediately.
He wns probably (00 scared to throw it
away
until he confirmed whether or not she told
anybody about his kid brother...
Well, the truth will come out as soon as we
check out the fingerprints
on the murder weapon and the blood on it
If only"she didn"t-say what she did
Where do you think:I found this cell phone?
Your very curious kid brother had it.
Huh?
The one inside the dark attic. made to write
novels to past his time away.
So that his;older brother could get, all the
glory 'that poor kid brother of yours.
Okay, to start things off, give me
10.000.000 yen...
We'll talk over the, details thoroughly
in a different place...
That's why you told me to write the novel
here tonight and went out?
Yeah... Momoka 12 years ago too
I first went to see if she was okay
because she was stabbed...
Her wound was not serous. so I was going
to take her to the hospital... But she said...
Take responsibility, will-you...
Take responsibility and get married to you?
You idiot! I would never marry into a house
with such an old fart living there!
Money
Now that things turned out
the way they did.
I'm going to leech you till you die and suck
YOu Lo Ihe Hones. SO He prepared!
Shigehide...
Phooey. I'm not worthy of being your
brother...
If you didn't have the writing talent you did
I probably would have killed you the first
chance I had...
Ik Olek
Wellfguess I didn't do so
because , myself wanted to read the
continuation of your novels most of all...
Oriomnl Comic Books By.
GOSHO AGYAMA
Pro ducers
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIQ@KA
- - Ba
Producers:
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
BicksroundiMusic.
KATSUO ONO
s> Character Desiens By.
MASAIOMQ) $000
Story Editor.
JUNIGHT I1OKA
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
AZUNARI KOUCH
YUICHI HI URE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors,
TJROTOSHI TAKATA
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director .
YUKIHIR@}SHIBUTANI
Art Dircwtor.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUIANI
rectors Of Photograph,
TAKA. HI'NOMURA
HIRGNOBUFTORIROS HL
\ LN 'y
Recordine Director.
KAISUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
I Chief:Dircctor.
KIN] KBDAMA
duced By
S ENJERTAINMENH;
- Inf association with
YEA. URI TELECASTING
ORATION
Iota (al IVE tat NAN
(ald 10 VY AE ATO GARE RAN 311 TAT
AH der TER Cs tr Cf
But. what.a queer family theyswere...
You were really fantastic. Pops.
You solved the case in no time at all!
Well! It was really no big deal...
You're fantastic yourself. Shinichi...
Acting out a slightly intelligent
grade school child. splendid...
You're a big center forward
manipulating a small mid-fielder...
A fantajista who sends accurate passes
and leads the bal to the goal...
But why?
Why are you doing what you are?
Why won't you tell me the truth?
I mean we're so close together...
Yet. why...?
Finally home...
EAN Teta)
Hurr up and get off!
I've gotta go return the car...
O.Oh oka.
You too. hurry it up...
Make sure you have the bath ready!
He knows after all. ?
That I know who he really is.
Nice couple'...
Uh if it were you,
what number would you prefer, Shinichi?
If I remember correctly.
What did Shinichi answer?
I can't remember...
There's only one way I can find out...
Suspicious Ran