Stars are for some reason attractive
They can "bathe culprit or the actor
Ran's suspicion has finally
come to the truth,
The password brings her
even closer to the truth
Its a one-on-one battle
between love and deduction.
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan
I'm done
It was delicious.
Okay~then, hit the sack right this minute!
Its already after midnight...
Yes, sit
Oh. wait.
Huh,
What is it... Ran?
What is it Ran?
Huh yeah.
Well. you know
Brush your teeth and go to sleep now.
Y. Yep. I know. Heh. heh. heh .
What's with him? Ho sooms oddly jitory
I'm suspicious of his true Identity
Shinichi...
Oh, no...l may have forgotten
to lock the dodr of the office!
Make sure you lockdit before
going to bed then.
Boy, am FSIOODY. ..
Whether what I suspect is true.
There's only one way for me to check .
Suspicious Ran
I'm going to return the car...
Agh...
Conan's cell phone...
if the mail that I sent is inside...
it'll serve as definite evidence
that Conan is Shinichi...
Just as I thought the cell phone
is switched off so that
the sound of my mail sent out
to him won't ring.
But, you've no choice already,
once the cell phone's switched on
everything will become clear.
But. wait. as thldwlfii you really want?
What if Conan is really Shinichi...
How are you going to face up to him?
Tins Day 8.
C.@uto.
Ugh ..M.My heart
Ugh. MM My heart
He's always been mean since his-childhood
days and always full of confidence
He s a deduction freak. whose always
there in time of need &hd courageous.
He's cool . and I like Shinichi
more than anyone else
I. can't sleep!
It was sure a lot of fun
washing each other's back. wasn't it .
Ugh?!
My. your nose is bleeding?
Maybe the water was too hot?
Maybe I should just wait until he decides to
tell me from his side after all...
He must have a reason,
and besides, it's not nice peeking
to other people's cell phone...
But, all I'm going to do is check whether
the mail I sent is inside or not...
If that's all I'm going to do. it's okay,
isn't it?
Sorr . Shinichi!
Oh I see! So. just as I expected. .
But, most times I guess the password
would be his birthday or something...
BAH =
I guess, it's not all that simple...
Now what?
There are 10.000 possible matches
for 4-digit numbers,
and it would take at least 8 hours
to try them all out.
What other possibility could there be...
Oh ma be m birthday...
How silly, of course not...
Impossible...
Hmm No way!
But, I guess there's no harm trying?
Yeah.
Uh. mine is .
But, what shall I do
If it Is, what should I do .
=7" My
Oh. so. it's not after all! HMM.
What number is it. then?!
Tell me what it is.
Rats
No. Ran. cool head...
It seems they both went to sleep
Nobody will bother me here...
and a slight sound is net audible...
I've got all the time in the world too.
20362037 .
Yawn
No good
At this rate. it's going to take me till morning
I guess I'll just have to try to figure out the
numbers that Shinichi is most likely to use.
He likes Holmes
Maybe the number is the year in
which Holmes handled a case...
No, that can't be it,
because I just checked all the numbers
from 1 to over 2000 just a while ago .
Oh! Hush
Oh! Hush...
46-49=Hello it says...
What a jerk at this time of night.
Come to think of it a while back
fa SH
Love ro rance movies are great after all...
They're really touching
Pla... giarism,
Touch... up.
That actress was really beautiful
Hg 'Y
What?! Ugly?
No. maybe it's "big brother goes
Hey. just what're you talking about,
Shinichi?!
Huh? What?!
Oh. the number plate of that car!
AM Vem emmmiron mma Y"Ommenlions
What?!
10-39=pronounced "tosaku
meaning plagiarism
and the car after that as 23~19=prorwounced
busalku meaning ugly
or pronounced "nnsan aku
meaning Big brother goes
In other words, equivoque or play on words
with the number plate of the cars!
What are you doing something like?
Exercising my br: in being
that I'm a detective...
It also serves as practice for solving codes
Ohm!
342 stands for "misshitsu
meaning behind closed-doors,
9389 stands for "kusayakyu
meaning amateur baseball.
Hm 48-641
Pronounced "yowamushi meaning weakling
89-31
fy oF NY
Pronounced "hakusai meaning
Chinese cabbage.
It's amazing how you can think it up
one after the other!/
The one that-made me laugh the other day
was despite it bemg a flower shop vehicle
tho number pinto wws 80-83
80-837. Oh, " ao a-san
a vegetable shop?
Yeah! A flower shop should be 87-83!
You can say that again
Oh. wait. meat shop is 29-83.
And. 3783 fish shop!
There's still more, Ran!
A bath shop is 26-83!
And bean curd shop without the
san at the end would be 10-28
In recent years people get to choose
the numbers they want to use for
their number plates
as long as they request it,
but before this law was passed. there
were no numbers ending in "42" or "49".
Oh why not?
42 pronounced "shinin
means dead person...
And 49 pronounced "shiku
means death and suffering.
Lad poopla ? Daath and suttoringe 2?
But. people in recent years don't seem
to be bothered by things like that so...
See, look at that! 46-49="yoroshiku"
meaning hello seems to be quite popular .
The numbers that are
really popular can't be acquired
unless you win the lottery for the numbers
For instance. 1122
Pronounced "iifufu meaning a
married couple who gets along great
See. look over there
A married couple who gets along great...
I sure would like Dad to use a number
Iike that If he ever buys a car
Nah. your Dad«s: tastorwould-bo:somaething
Iike ..1170-or 8109...
Nah, your Dad's taste would bec something
e 11/0 or 8109
1170...81097
Pronounced 1 onn
LC) 7 CK
or 8109 pronounced 'hairegu meaning
high cut revealinc outfit!
My! How rude!
Uh Shinichi,
what numbers would you prefer?
Huh?...
41-910, for Shinichi Kudo...
Huh?
There's one extra number there
I get it! 10-41!
10-41, that's great!
Right
But too bad!
Huh?!
Hiragana characters can't be chosen
Moreover, the hiraganas that are in the
A"and "KA"rows of the Japanese alphabet
cannot be used for cars for private use
O.Oh...7
Well, if I were to choose. it would be. .?
That car... 7
Shinichi?
What about that car?
H.He!
Watch out! P.Please sit down!
S Shoots!
Driver, can you...
Of course he can't go after that car
We ll be stopping at the next stop.
Hey. what's up
Shinichi...?
Shinichi...?!
Shinichi?!
Darn!
Officer! A car with a
fraudulent license plate just went by...
A fraudulent license plate?
It's a black sedan with the plate number
Shinjuku510-shi 15-64
Hmm, but how do you know that the car
has a fraudulent license plate number. 7?
Agh... .15-64="hitogoroshi which
means murderer
Huh...?! Ha. ha .
I mean you guys, just because
the number can be read "'murderer'...
The point 18 not the numbers,
but rather. the hiragana character.
There should be no license plate numbers
with the characters'shi and "he"!
Going around like that with a fraudulent
Iicense plate numbers goes to show
that the ones who thought out
a crime are about to execute it...
You've got to go after them!
Okay!
Leave it to me!
Ou go on home!
S.Shinichi
Yes. the Mouri Detective Agency
Oh. Shinichi.
So. what happened after that
Yep. I was worried
Sorry sorry Those guys fell under the
categor number "510" and not "15-64".
Huh?! 510"7?
510-"goto" which means robber!
But thanks to my deduction
it ended in just an attempt .
So they were arrested!
1... Those w ss:alecks used nu
that symbolized robber 1 Yd "murderer"
tochallenge the police...
[UH 3) (eke =n) On Hh meimnlex=x
Ue 80) wt 3 RR dig) IR er Galt (x0) 1-1
By the way. about your father,
if he were to choose a number plate,
how about 55-457
55-457
I'll see you at school tomorrow. then!
Agh Shinichi...!
Gses...
Hey. Dad if you were to buy a car .
Quiet. Yoko Okino's coming on air soon...
Oh. Yoko-chant
You viewers out there get to see my
Iive concert on your sets today!
Go! Go! Yoko!
Let's go. oko!
Yoko...Go-go...?
Oh. "55-45" (Go-go™ Yoko).
5545.
I'll try it, just in case.
I guess not. after all he's not Dad.
Oh. but back then. if I remember correctly
Well. ..if I were to pick a number
I wonder what Shinichi was trying to say .
If it's a four digit number,
he could be using it as a pass code...
But. a play on words. could be it.
For instance...
Like, 4062 for Holmes
Per tz,
-- we ay
RATES
Per dz;
Berd,
Frye
- o/ a my
No good. . it's still ocked...
Bortz,
Lock...
Right, Holmes' first name is Sherlock.
4869... Well, I guess I'll try it.
Pert,
'14-54
What?!
No joke? It opened?!
What shall I do... What shall I do?!
Oh no--! I unlocked it!
I...I've got to check...
If he got my mail.
I've got to check!
Huh? My mail's...not here?!
See. he deleted it just in case
But that won't work cautious detective!
All I have to do is re-send
this morning's mail to find out...
Huh? It's not coming in .
WwW. Why?
Why?!
Strange,
The mail address is correct.
Strange
T.Telephone!
Telephone...?!
Oh. yes. hello?
What is it?!
What?!
Sending the same mail over and over.
What the heck's the matter with you!
What?! Shinichi?!
Just what time do you think it is now?!
It's in the middle of the night you know!
W.Who Is it?
I'm working day in and day out on cases
and am pooped. fast asleep.
Then you call and wake me
CC. Bran?
Do you know where my cell phone is?
I've been searching for it for a while.
ARs LON
Think about me too, will you
Oh! S.Sorr
I picked it u» in the car,
a.and forgot to tell you about it...
It was supposed to have been locked...
Uh. did you look inside...
Um, nope, Ib I didn't look inside but,
why are you- so concerned?
Bocause mails from the girl
I ike are In here too...
Oh. I see! Right.
Lot mo givo you 1 pioco of my mind, hoy
Goodnight
Okay. goodnight
You've always been like that...
I see. that's why Conan was so flustered...
Hey. are you listening or what?
I see. that's-why Conan was so f ustered
I'm sleepy. you know.
He didn't want me to see the mails
he received from girls.
He \didn't want me to see the mails
he received from/girls...
ou eep on'repealing te same Ling
over Ind over Nd over
74 Ra
Toll mo onco and I: got-the-mossngo.
Hey. Ran. are you listening or what?
What was that mail-about-anyway ?!
What was that mail about anyway?!
I.I'm sorry, Shinichi
I must've been mistaken about
something again...
I'm sure glad Doc's cell phone was
the same type as mine: *
You can't tell the difference between the
two after the straps are exchanged...
It, sure took a while
before I got mail from Ran though.
I locked the cell phone to buy time,
but maybe the pass code 4869 "Sherlock"
was a bit too difficult.
(Ax \
But that's the only play on words I could
find that was common for both Conan and I.
I'm sO happy I got to hear Shinichi's
voice after such a long time...
Because even if I want to hear his voice
it's hard for me to get a hold of him
from m side...
Oh, please don't get me wrong!
There's no deep meaning to it...
You fool! take a good eok™
at your cell phone display.
Huh?!...What
T This Is!
Y Your phone number. Sfihinlchl?!
You mean you don't mind giving it to me?
I may call you at the wrong time. you know?
No...but I'm so busy that most times
all you'll get is my answer phone...
I figured that sometimes there are things
that can't be relayed correctly
un ess they are spoken
Yep...right
It's a bit risky telling her
what my number is. but...
well. if U's this kind of risk.
It's worth it
>» Ora ZI1n WM Comic Books By.
COSHO AOYAMA
'€ La
Orel Comie'Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Cera Crave 5200's
CG» Vv
sr "1 i7 7 /\ <UivE/\
Prag
Pm ('1 u f firs
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO "OSHIOKA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
BackgroundiMirsic.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDOg.
JUNJGHI ITDKA
JUNIGHI 1IDKA ,
Story Editor.
JUNIGHI 1TOKA gy,
STript By.
KANJI KASHIWABARA
Jet BPD Te Tr RL Lode RT rT ye Te
YUICHI HIGURE ,»
TOSHIKY INOUE
OAT O
ANT 4 «8
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUIANI
Art Director +
YWKIHIRQYSHIBUIANI
Art Dircolor.
Directors Of Photography
TAKA HI NOMURA
HIRONOBU 1ORIROSHI,
TAKAHISA. OWAG Ax
Recording Directoy
KATSUVOSHIWOBHVASHH
Editor.
[ERUMITSUW OKADA
{ Chief Director.
KENT KODAMA
Produced By
TMS ENJERTAINMENT; LTD
Inf. ssocrafion with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
IDLE IV) (ald \ UN
a NTE AY AINE STTOTGOVR LE RAINY TL TRIN
MI sthafnds Seaver sed
Hey. what 8 with you two
Didn't you guys get enough sleep?
Yeah. well sort of .
I couldn't help reflecting on the case
that happened a halfia year ago...
A'half a year agor
A half a year ago 7?
Oh, what's the license number plate
of Mother's car. Dad?
Eri's?I
I think it was. "Shinjuku.
36-go 87077
What?! The hiragana ge .
LOR Res po Lr e
See! Geh. what a revolting woman!
Dlbwdi!
Well, I guess they'll continu ing
separated for a while yet...
22-97="tsuzuku na", meaning. will continue
Conan! Just what did you say right now,
about something continuing!
What?!
H.He smiled
(BR)
(mag)
Jewel RobberiSuicide" Part+1