Stars are for some reason attractive
hey can be the calpnt or the actor
A robber steals and runs away
When he is cornered
He disappears beyond time and space
He sees through the one and only truth \
A child inmappearance with the I Q
ofTaneadult
No casoys left unsolved with Batective
Conan
Here!
Tell Doc this cell phone saved
my life. will you?\
It really did.
So I guess she didn't find out,
who youvare. huh?
Yeah. that was close though.
Seems Ran no longer thinks I'm
Shinichi Kudo \
Well, I'm-pretty sure could hide it
Who would believer story about
a guy who got shrunk by a drug. right?
Hey you batter thank me!
You made it through because
I sent you so manyle-mails
\ ta: your cell phone so thatvRan
would believe that you were Conan...
Yeah...
Are you really sure that she's not
SUSPICIOUS about you anymore?
That actually made my morning ene big
hull...
Vigy Conan, I didn't know you were
Tr R Rend)!
Or like.
Here! Extra rice for the future Sherlock
Holmes.
Or like
Conan, ou gottasear this!
It SE NIAICH (BAVEITE
You've reached Shinichi Kudo.
I m not-available right now
Pleas: leave a message after the tone...
Or like .
(Fut?
You told her the.cell phone number?
Hey. don't worry!
I'll"turn 'on the voicemail
[ when I'm with her. ok!
Whatever youtsay, but. you gotta be
care u ..%
If she finds out who you. are. then
Yeah. I know! I know what I'm doing"
I'll keep her away from the men
in black no matter what...
She's a strong girl, you Knew mere than
OW (li,
No. don't move. Stop!
Strong. you mean. as in Karate
mAh CHORAL that
r » en
What lis lit?
Detective Takagil?
ah...
Detective Takagi is acting
somewhat stra, ge
Looks like he's having] a hard time
There must be something 'going on!
Definite!!
Look" he went inside the jewelry store!
Oh, don't tell me he's gonna rob that
store.
What are you. stupid?
There's only one reason guys go to
jewelry the store. Buying a present.
It could be for [iiis mother. sister wife ¥,
or somebody else .
But his face was all red and looked restless
when he went inside.
90 probablyit's for his gintridnd I think \
Oh 1" »
Sigh:- . 800 dollars. eh
God. it's expansive .
I still have to pay the loan for the ring
bought last time...
That must be it!
Trust me. She was staring at this broeche.
She wasn-t even blinking at all!
Oh. But.you didn't hear this from me. ok?
Look, coincidence makes girls believe
in destiny and that's where the love begins!
Love.
Love...
Sir? Would you like to take 1 look at it?
I can take, it out for you
No, Anes
Is it a present for your daughter?
What? Daughter. .!? What the!
How about this? The one with
Iots of diamonds Jwhat do you think.
Well, I think. it's too gorgeous for Detective
Sato.
Guys. how did you know that
I remember Dctective Sato was saying
her birthday was in April!
The birthstone of April is diamond...
When, rm» one lb perfect
Guys... Who said I was buying Ms. Sato
a present... Hm!?
Oh. So you're not.
Sorry. I am...
Hehehe .
Sorry . Actually, could I sec that broche,
please?
On, sure...
ere ou Co
Wow!
Is is pretty damn good!
It's got a nice design too! ,
Oh. Im. jealous:nowl
You think so
Ah AA
(BI) %R)
HA AA
Jewel Robber Suicide
dA AA
(RY HR)
Jewel robbery!?
What are you waiting?
Use your tranquilizer gun
I can't .
Hers wearing ahelmet and a heavy coat
'he needle wou dn-t:go through. Plus.
We don't know whether itvs asrcal gun or
I can't use my high power kickinlshoes
in this situation either.
Now, guys. go .
Do ti
Yes! Now
Police! Our officers arc around here.
Doing their job!
So give up and put your gun down!  1
Or you dud
What, smiled
Hey. Walt!
Whore aro your ofticors? I don't soo any!
Stop. stop! Of course, there's no officer.
What!?,/
Shh! lém off duty today
That was a total bluff.
Where did he go!?
There! He's on the Stairs
You ro not gonna got away!
You guys stay here. ok!?
Oh. ok.
There's no*way out...
Now. Give up and drop the gun
What the!
Oh nolkOh god...
Oh...no
Bid something fall?
Yeah. what was that huge misc'?
You see anything?
No...
Moy. somobody: go up and chock it!
Police. .This truck, is yours?
Ah, yeah
What happened
It looks like something fell onthe
container...
Yeah... Actually
What's going en! What was that noise?
Sp 8 WOO Cadi
What!?
That's what happened $0. until
the ambulance and the police come.
please do not move anything including
the furniture
Furniture too?
Yes... We have to maintain the scene
thesway 1t Is. so.
Oh no. you can't do that! Look
we have'to move all the furniture in by
toda...
Ok. we'll wait until the ambulance comes. (ii
but after that. you let us to do our job'? ;
Alright. why don't I speak
to your client. then?)
Ok. Mr Nekota should be in his office
Hey. get him over here
Sure.
What is this? What's going on? p=
Ah=Mr. Nekota? Somebody's here for yow... (&
ou've barely moved anything yet
Come on. hurry up!
Actually, a man fell on our moving truck,
so we had to stop
A man...?
AN WON Daa rN yl YON \!
could stop moving your stuff for a while
Ok. fine. Call your friends and do what
you have to do.
Just be quick! You're not the only one
who got a schedule. ok
I guess It's our fault. isn't it?
Yeah ..If we didn't chase him down to
the roof of that building
He wouldn't have had to jumpoefll the.
Buillding™
♪ to.
Pr -~
Hmmm #<
Come on... Wexgot n officer with no.
Ww "weapon 'and+five Kicism 'm ¢
Even if we did corner-on the-roof of
the building...
he had a gun and he could've used it,
at least to threaten us
and run away. Not to jump off the roof.
So you are saying that man planned to
commit suicidesfrom the beginning?
Yes...Or, maybe he wns absolutely
confident that he was net gonna die.
Onetheless=Ithink...
Thus us not a simple jewel robbery
This is not...
This is not a simple jewelirobbery
Is Is mak
This is not a simpleéYewel. robbery
Tks fs tx
Neither is it suicide
So. ou are sa ing.
You were chasing this guy
who happened to rob the jewol stow
that you were in .sndithen he jumped off
the building and killed himself?
Yes ..'He went over the fence on the roof
of this building. and...
On this truck night here
What were you doing
Aw. god!!
The media is gonna attack us again...
A reckless chase of a. here wannabe
officer led to an unnecessary death...
Oh no...
Oh no.
We weren't just a hero-wannabe!
We were chasing him "ll the way
from the store.
We were doing really good
unti we cornered onfthe roof
It happened all of a sudden
There's no way we could stop him!
Right Conan!
Yeah He jumped off
the/building without any hesitation.
As if the planned"to do it
from the beginning...
I see...So...
You guys wore there when the robber
broke into the jewelry store. correct?
Yes! We saw Detective Takagi
walking into that store. so...
Wow, Takagl goes to a jewelry store I
)n his day off...
For...what kind of occasion...
Huh?
Ah, no, actually.
That was... for...
Hmm.
I didn't know you Wed jowelnias and stuff, «
Taka yl. It's surprising!
It- was for you! Ms. Sato!
So. did you find any jewelry you like? {
Huh! Actually...
The robber took it justfbefore he bought it!
Lidropped it on the floor and then
The robbor took it away
Yeah dHe pickedkit up
and put it in the pocket of his raincoat!
Then that thing 1s supposed"
be in his pocket still
Yeah but the thing is!
I went onathe truck And checked
his pocket before you guys came
But the broche was not the O at "ll!
Brocho. huh
It's a present for your mom, isn't it?
No. that's ....a presont for you!
Oh no. no way. Hahaha
Well, perhaps,
the robber threw it away or dropped it.
@r. maybe it just popped out of his pocket
when he fell.on the container...!
In-cither case, I think you should forget
about that broche... Huhuhuh...
I ven if it's found. prosecutors will keep it
for a while since it's material evidence...
Who would want a jewelry
that has a bloody past anyway. right? €¢
That's true...sigh .
Well. I wouldn'timind at all...
Even if it's got someone's blood on it
you can just wipe it off
Jewelries have nothing to do with crime...
Yeah that's what I thought!
Oh, also
There're some other strange things!
Really?
The robber was wearing a helmet... 7
But there's no way 'he could bleed
that much on his heady
Unless he removed his helmet
while falling down
seed.
And ono moro thing.
Dotective Takagr sad police
to the robber in the store.
When he said it...
He robber actually smiled...
As If he was whiting for
the police officers to come!
Smi ed?
Are ou sure?
If he did smile... then that means
he was well prepared forahis getaway...
Maybe there was somaothing
that supposedly granteed his life
even after jumping off the building... Yes?
So: removing his helmet while falling down
was actuallyta part of his escape plan?
I don't know. Anyway,
we have to identify the dead body first...
Sir. you can't come in!
HMM! ?
No. hetlooks-like someone that I know...
Yeah, he IS Mr Atomural
What?
I own a restaurant over there, and
he was one of the regu ar customers.
I think he s working
for Mr Nekota's company
Nekota!?
Do you know him?
The robber fell on the moving truck...
which was carrying the furniture:of
Mr. Nekota. the man over there.
Oh: Mr Atomurat!?
He's Mr. Atomura!
Why did you.../
SO he is one of our staff, right.
Yes. . Untilillast week though
\) «in
Untilillast week?
He had been working for me
Since the company was established...
but we're facing
some financial difficulties nght now.
ISO-l. had to lbmke him leave unfortunately...
It was necess ry because
our-company needs to scale back...
But I didn't know
it was gonna end up like this...
So the fact you're moving today
1s Also for the scale back?
You got that right
This building's got a smaller room
but also a cheap rent. so...
Where was the previous office by the way?
It's the building
Right across this one. on the top floor...
It's rea close.
Then,
shall we go and see the previous office?
Ah, why do you need to?
Leena: 1 RO oo OX.
to commit the robber .
Fem fio mel xo Om = Mine of doe
about his plan in your office. right
I understand...
Hi, sir?
Have you met these officers before?
No. Why would I have?
Ws I've never done. something bad bofore!
This is Mr. Atomura's locker...
This is Mr. Atomursfs locker...
And this is
the desk he was using before
I see .
You got a lot of things in this office still.
Yes.
To make a clean start. we decided to buy
new lockers, desks and chairs.
So that'siwhy things are still here.
It seems there's nothing
that's related to the robbery...
There s nothing mm his desk too
But. it's kind of*strangc. I think
This iman wns fired week ago,
but a lot of his stuff Is still in this office.
Why is 11?
Why is it?
That
I didn't want the workers
to be upset over the dismissal
So I decided to keep it secret
until our new company gets stable
I told them he was on a business trip...
Ikasked him to comerand-get his stuff
after moving-theroffice.»secretly...
Isn't that the truck that the guy crashed?
Oheyeah. it is!
We, can-see the truck
imsfront-of this building.
Thatimeans thisgplace 1siiight across
the buildinthat-thesrobber jumped off
Maybe Re was trying
Whatido\ ou think,
That's impossible
He was holding a bag of jewelries.
Remember?
Even the world class long jumpers
Can go 9 meters or so
A-normalisperson wouldneteeven
think about jumping off.
Unless ho was like youn.superhero,
Masked Yaiba.
Wih1t's wrong with you!
Masked Yalba will never-steal things!
Yeah. you're night...
MH. hoyOguys. Look, you can't go there
Hey. can ask you something?
Where wen: you
when the moving people got here?
I was in my room that's below this room...
Your room??
Below that office is his living space...
That office 1s four stories above
which is the 9th floor...
So this room is on the 5th floor .
What is this?
It's @ strange he met. isn't it?
Is that for a sports bicycle?
Ah, es
I was into triathlon when I was young...
Are you-cone now? Look.
We knew each other for a long, time but
there's nothing that belongs todhim in here!
Oh, Ill get it...
Oh, hi...How can I help you?
Oh no. people told me
that detectives are here and ah...
SS 2 & *
Something happened?
So 3»
You know, there was a jewel robbery
over there. right?
I just thought
that this is something about it...
My name Is Isaka
I'm living on the 6th floor...
Three days ago. around 2 am midnight...
I woke up:hecause I heard this noise
from the window.
And when I looked atlit.
- There was a shadowy
I guess:a thin long stick. on the curtain! I
So I woke my husband up right away.
He chocked tho terraco.
Where I saw the shadow.
but nothing was there...
My husband said it was just a dream
but I thought
I should tell you guys about this...
Is your reom right abovethis room
Yeah.
It's room-605, just right above.
Then, did you hear the same noise
when there was the robbery over there?
Because I was watching Iv...
Honestly. I didn't even know about the
robbery until I heard the police car siren...
SOFT
Yeah...
It ok if we start moving the stuff now?
Lod WOW wn YOO ERA
three more trips to move everything
Two or three more tips?
From the old office?
Ah yes .
We got a lot of stuff because
the whole 9th floor was our. office.
We got storage,
meeting room and: all that...
Hmm.
Eon O Ah domo
WARE Rony ICY O win),
but it seems it rcally was a-suicide...
Trunk.
We got the pictures of the scene
nd the fake gun the robber
used to threaten people.
We also got the jewelrics back
Except-that broche.
So I think you can start moving now...
But you leave the cover on the container
You can start now
but once you're done
the police is gonna take the truck
forrarwhile. ok
Alright,
Iet's get to work!
Hey. wait! Hold on!
Huh?
Where did you guys park the truck,
whenyou were moving the stuff
from the old office to that container?
My Le
xO Ht
we parked the truck
at the back.of this building.
& id Wo
cD FL
we parked the truck
at the back.of this building.
>ScOO™ It
we parked the truck
at the back of this building.
STOO ext
we parked the truck
at the back of this building.
Judo xt
we parked the truck
at the back of this building.
%0O I
hat's where the back entrance is...
LED IL
tH RH
'hat's where the back entrance is...
LED EL
I hat's where the back entrance 1s...
IRR LU SOD = JsL
GLa tn
>STI>EX
hat-s where the back entrance is...
SI LED EI
ST OD $x
hats where the back entrance is...
AR LA. OIL
That's where the back entrance is...
WELD IV
'Tfihatls where the back entrance is...
IAB LS tZIL
We used the back street
when we carried the stuff
SWMRALSDOY)I
just to avoid the crowd.
Just to avord the crowd
[Did you hear anything
when you were there?
Yeah... lTheardra noise...
WwW. what kind of noise!?
Hat was jackhammer from
the water supply work
they ve been. doing since last weck.
Oh that was annoying.
Fl safe
Noise of water supply work...
28<%
And the back street Is narrow
Md does not have many passaoarsby
as well...
What's also annoying was the Nekota guy.
He toldMus what to do
Iike a kindergarten tecachcr!
Yeah. He told all of us.
Including the driver, to come upstairs.
Just to teach us
which thing goes first and stuff...
We also had to wait for a while
in front of his office. you know...
Plus. he canceled us twice in a row...
Canceled"?
We were actually supposed to do
the moving the day before yesterday
but he called us that morning and
said he can't make it...
Yostorday was too It was a nico day
Actually, a perfect day for moving,
it really was...
Well, he booked us for three days
just in case he might have to cancel.
& CF,
Sure the pay was good but...
We don't wanna work for a guy
Iike him ever again...
I get it! It's the rain!
Thank ou so much!
Good luck with the moving!!
He. »Conan)!
Where is the bodroonm...
I found it!
3 [ROO
If my doduction 1s correct,
Then. probably...
If my deduction is correct,
It's wet!
Just as I thought, it wasn't a suicide!
Mr. Atomura was murdered
by Mr. Nekota, who disguised
the murder as suicide...
With the.time lag and the gap
between the buildings...
Original « 0We ook§-By.
GOSH AGYANM A
» Oral ComczBooks By.
GCSHO A@YAMA
Original Comic: 30Oks By.
COSHO AWYAMA
Pr 0 q fu 2 r \
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
BackeroundiMusic.
KATSUO ONO
s Character Designs By.
MASATOMG) 50004
\,\4v
Storystditor.
JUNIGHI IIOKA
JUNIGHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
+ KAZUNARI KOUCHI
TOSHIKI INOUE
nation Jirzeisg,
Art Director.
Art Dircalor.
Directors Of Photography
mm. +n NDMURA
HIRONOBUJITORIWOSHI,
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYQ SHISKOBAVAS HI
I'sU (ADA
Chief Director.
KENJI KODAMA
roduced By:
TMS ENTERTAINMENT; LTD
infassocrafion with
YOM RI TEIECASTING
CORPORATION
db tad dV (ato NAN
D COMO OLY UN TI SHOCASU OGM TTY Lui
AI Ras his Ives veel
How come you don't get mad at us'
We're kids. you know.
Talk about a trick
that is unbelievably reliant on luck.
It's a childish shallow deduction...
I can't believe you actually trust them!
Wesare important witnesses
to the robbery...
And the broche I was gonna Buy proves WY
(122 Jw)