Stars.are for-some reason attractive
They can be the culprit or the actor
When the children come together
Teleportation is possible
Find the broche and lot Tagaki's love begin
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance with
the I O. of an adult
No case 18 left unsolved
wit WOPelective Conan
After school. on :the way home
we saw Datective 11kag
walking into"a jewelry: store
We followed him and went
inside the jewelry store out of curiosity
Surprisingly. we bumped
Io apewel tobber inside the store!
Detective Takagi and we chased the robber
But he.jumped off
the roof of a building and died!
Do you know him?
Yeas
The robber fell on the moving truck...
which was carrying.the stuff
that belonged to
Mr. Nekota. the man over there.
Have you met these off cers before?
Just curious.
o. Why would I have?
I've never done anything bad before!
Hm mm .
Below that office is his living space...
That office is four stories above
which is the 9th floor...
So this room is on the 5th floor
What is this?
It's astrange helmet. isn't it?
Is that for a sports bicycle?
Ah, es
I was Into triathlon when I was. young...
Wham ls tho bedroom...
I found it!
It's here!
It my deduction is correct.
Then, probably...
It's wet!
Just as I thought, it wasn't a suicide!
Mr. Atomura was murdered
by Mr. Nekota.
} who disguised the murder as a suicide...
Taking advantage of the time lag
and the gap between the buildings
(1£ RF)
Jewel Robber Suicide (Part ll)
Anyhow...
It's a concrotd fact that Takagi bumped
into this robber in the jewelry store
and chased him
Chased him up to the roof of the building...
But Takaci just let him jump off
the building-and die right in front of him!
Right .
It seems more than
just a coincidence though.
He robber crashed onto a moving truck
which was helping
the office transfer of the company.
Nae? Taal - TVR, rofl SN
he uscd to work for but was hired recently
Yot, it seems there s no doubt
ibout that suicide.
Yet: it seems there's no doubt
about that suicide.
Then...
I guess that's it for;today
Sorry, Mr. Nekota, we need you
to come down to the station later.
What? Why do I need to?
Well, we need to ask you some questions
because you were Mr Atomura's boss...
You know, what kind of person he was
whether he had) financial problems.
Ind all that.
I understand...
Down!
Down::a little!
Justia little: more!!
It's cold!
Guys. what are you doing?
No. nothing!
«By the way. I have questions...
Questio s?
Right.
NA couple of question for Mr. Nékotae.
For me...?
I remember what you said
to Detective Takagi
when you hrs! mrno to
the scene of the suicide
You said
call your friends
and do what you have to do'.
\.> (\
right?
Hm? yeah...
I'm wondering why you said that.
Well. you know... I got a schedule and...
We're not talking about that!
We are asking...
now did you knew that this Mr. ordinary
with thelboring polo-shirt...
Was actually. a detective.
Was actunlly a detective.
That's what the question means!
Yeah. I mean. why not!?
A person:udied. right?
MR RAO OAc
that the cops are here?
but remember what you actually said?
You said. "What's going on}
And you also said that
you never met Detective Takagi before!
Voor
You didn't know about the situation,
and neither ever mot Takagi before.
It's something that
you knew that 'he was a detective...
That was robabl. the atmos here
that made me think so!
You know, somethi« bad happened
so I just felt the police were here
LOUIS XRT OTN al
- - Huh?
It's been awhile since we got here.
But why!
Why are you not getting. mad: at us?
Ules?
We're kids. you know?
You might have thought that
we re detectives If we're adults...
we're kid«and youijust let us in
without saying anything to us
A normal person would say
Who the hell are those kids?"
I hat
You didn't say anything.
Because you knew us
right?
Youlknew that
we were important witnesses
of the jewel robbery.
Is that true?
Wait a minute...
You knew that I was a detective...
And you also knew that
these kids were invelved in the robbery...
oh. no...
Oh, no
Ihe jewel.robber...
It was you. wasn't It . 7?
It's possible...
Maybe it was you
and the answer
to Mitsuhiko's questions would be...
Pleassl
be tan.,
Don't ou remember?
The robber jumped off
the building=opposite here
and crashed onto the moving truck!
Let's say I was the robber.
Then where did I go
after jumping off the building?
Thenywhere,.did/'l 'go +
after jumping off-the building?
\Q Pp
Who was the dead person that
was found on the moving truck?
Also Tm Hl
Do you think I have the body
to pull away fromia detective
andiirun up to the roof of a building?
Don think so.
IHUOBUN
Triathlon .
What
I yourre still.into that iron manrace
then that's. probably nothing to you,
right?
Is that you. Conan!
I was wondering where you were...
Now: were are you. Conan?
I'm in the building opposite!
Now right.
I'm at the stairs .
Going up to the roof
where the robber jumped off!
There's something I wanted to try...
Sol told them to throw
the questions until I'm ready!
Whatyisiit:then?
{-» (oo)
Can ou see me from there?
Yeah. I can see you
But what are you exactly trying to do?
He . don't ou remember?
I mean. about what
the lady living right above that room said...
Midnight.2 am, she woke up because
she heard a noise from the window.
As she looked at the window...
there was a shadow of
thin long stick on the curtoan
I think I got the mystery behind it.
Andi now I'm going torshow that to you all!
Cc. Conan...?
Ok, that's enough!
Mm helping you guys because.
It's my staff who robbed and killed himself!
Note! -
It looks like these kids
really want me to be theurobber...
But it's only kiddy shallow
cleverness after all.
I can't believe
you're actually listening to them!
Again. likeil said!
F1'?
Again. likeil:said!
If I was -theirobber
then how did I vanish,
after ljumpingroff'the building!?
It's impossible!
There's no way I could've done it!
Unless I have supernatural powers
LO use teleporntationyorssometthwng
Huhuhuh
you can
What?
0 CO RUM o 0 & ERLE)
Just like that!
C. Conan!?
How did you get here!?
I just used thi Yrope
I 'borrowed from the moving people!
Rope?
First of all. you measure the length
from the balcony of the old office
to the one in this room.
Next. you get a rope twice the lengths
and put it through the handrail of
the balcony in the old office
and then tie both-ends~to make a'locop!
After-that.
You connect a little loop to
the ropeiso't can-carry your body.
You throw the rope-with the little loop
from the balcony to the roof of
the building opposite.
Then all is set!
All you need to do is
to rob the jewe ry shop and pretend
that you are being chased up
to the roof of the building...
There,
you cover the rope with the long raincoat.
With the little loop around your waist,
and then...
jump off the roof
[his brings you straight down
to this balcony.
After which you can put Um rope away
by untying the knot)
I 888
Im actually surprised that
you are not hurt at all.
The impact must've been violent
when you landed on the balcony...
Just like the robber.
I was wearing a helmet.
Ind also... right before the impact.
I blew. up 1 soccer ball with
this ball=cjection belt Doc invented
DN es 0 a oll
this ballejcction. belt Doc invented
I blow up 1 soccer ball with
this ball-ejection-beltiOoc invented.
In order to 1absort) the impact
That's why I'm totally fine!
In Mr: :Nekota's case
he set the bed mattresses in the balcony
in order to absorb the impact...
Mattresses?
Yeah, they were wet
when I checked them a little while ago!
I seal
+: Because they were
exposed to the rain. right?
The, Mrs. Isaka saw and
heard the shadow:and noise that night...
because you were rehearsing this trick...
Wait a minute!
Therc was a dead"body
on the moving truck
when you guys looked down right
after the robber jumped off.
Right?
How would you explain thus? ma
He was on the moving truck
from the beginning
hates
The truck was parked
in the back of this building
in order to move things
out of the old office above.
That was when
you put him on the truck...
Probably...
You told Mr Atomura to help move.
Or something like that
Then you pushed him over
the window of our-old office.» 1
Yeah. I remember you said...
the whole 9th floor was
your old office. so
SO It was-possible to drop him on the truck 3
even if it'was-parked in the back.
Well, whatfabout the noise!?
Well, someone would hear the noise...
if.-a person falls on the truck. right
Because there 1s water supply- work
around here
and it doesn't end until .eveningieveryday...
It's likely that the the water supply
work shut off the noise...
m sure there was to the truck
when the body fell.
So some movers may haves
noticed something...
Yes.and that's why you told ovenybody
including the driver to
come up to the office. rights
Because you wanted to te I them,
which things gofirst and stuff...
The moving people told me that
they had to wait
for a while in the doorway...
That was probably when you pushed
Mr. Atomura over the window.
INA threw the rope 10 the-other building.
And them, you closed tho blinds!
So that nobody would see the trick
when it came in to the office!
to sum it uu»).
First of all,
you told the movers including
the driver to come up to the old office;
whichywas on the top floor of this building.
Then, while you kept them
waiting in the doorway...
You pushed Mr Atomurn
over onto the moving truck
which wns parked
in the back of this building.
Next, you threw the rope to the roof
of the opposite building.
And then, while the movers were moving
the stuff from the old to the new office
DIN (
you robbed the jewelry store!
Then Detective Takagi chased you
up to the roof of the new, office building.
All of these were done just
to make this incident look like
tho robber committod suicide
after beingschased by a detective!
You got that night!
You got that right!
Also. when he jumped off.
He dropped the bag with the jewelries
and the spare helmet which
he left on the roof beforehand.
AS these things hit the truck,
the peoplc would notice that
something fell on the truck!
That's probably:why
the helmet wasn't on Mrs/Atomura's.head!
$0 the robber smiledwhen [told-him
that I was from the police.
Because he needed someone to chase him
and witness the suicide on the roof...
Yeah...
If you weren't there,
he would've probably waited until ether
police officer came to the jewelry shop...
As a matter of fact,
this trick could not be done
without your luck.
Don't ou think?
Until you jumped off the building.
Surprisingly no neighbors or passersby
actually saw the rope or the dead body
Well,
I guess il was the sloppiness of your plan
that mando I possiblo to solve van for kids.
It wasn't just his luck that
people went blind!
What?
7 It was because of this-weathen!
Youjmean the rain!?
I get it!
Nine (ve raining.
People put up-their umbrella
ind stay away: from balcony.
As long as people hold,their umbrella,
they won't see what's» above their head *
Likewise.
As long as. people stay away frombalcony, ~\
they won't see what's below
Plus.
The mover used the backstreet
when they moved the truck
and there were not
many passersby on that strect...
Under this cireumstiance
you would have been the unluckiest
person to make people see those things
That's true...
Yeah but still
it was a coincidence that
he took action on a rainy day.
Right?
It wasn'ta coincidencec!
You canceled moving twice and
postponed it to today.
Right Mr. Nekota?
Now. all we need is evidence...
That, I think isssomewhere
In this room or around this building
I'm pretty sure!
Because Mr. Nekota showed; up
1t the scene of thesuicide soon
alter the robber jumped-off...
So it must be somewhere. around here!
The thing I was going to buy
the broche...
Now, it's whether you hid them
or dumped them...
Then-hinge» wre somewhere
in the same place altogether
since you-didn't have enough time
to go far...
We'll probably find the raincoat
with that broche, as well.as the helmet.
with yoursfiggerprints and hair on.it...
Mr. Nekota...
Think it's time you confess
I don't understand...
Why did you have to take that broche?
Redemption...
Redemption?
My company was heavily in the red...
It was necessary tg fire those
who were close to their retirement age
and those who were on a decline work-wise
He happened to be one of those peop e...
Sorry ?
I will spill the secret if you fire me
The things this company has been hiding...
You know
about the deceptive food labeling .
All I'm asking is for
you to let me stay in this company
intil my retirement age...
a hfe in which I can afford a broche
Iike this for my wife's birthday...
Well,
my wife might ask me to buy her jewe ry
that is more expensive than this.
After my retirement age...
But for now.
You don't need to worry about that,
President...
That's why you killed him
Yes...
I thought I would be in a morass
if I let him keep blackmailing me »
But. wh that broche?
I was thinking of givving it
to his wife on her birthday.
saying it was a present that
he left withpme before his death...
gh CE
In tact,
Ta) .
it's true that he'd been working very hard
since the company was established
nd not only have I made such person
a criminal but also killed him.
I just wanted to run. away
from the sense of guilt.
So I impulsively took the broche.
The brocheo wast supposed to help me flce.
But it actually helped you. guys:.arrest me
Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO AGWYAMA
J I € < )D - * 1 -
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIQKA
NR Cree TA
Background Music.
KATSUO GONG
Character Designs By.
MASAIOMG) sumo;
StoryeEditor.
JUNIGHI 11DKAYy,
[UR/loam H0101
Scripts By»
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
TOSHIKI INOUE ya
An radon [rect
HIRO" OSHI TAKATANI
ianas 1. Yul wgy
Art Director.
Art Dirg «tor.
Directors Of Photograp
TAKASHI NOMURA >
HIRONOBU H1ORIKOSHI
CHE).
111 UNMITSU (C¥ADA
{ Chicf Director.
KINJBHKODAMA
yduced By:.»
MS ENTERTAIN MEN); LY
inf ssoctation with
(ONH JR) TREC LTD
ORATION
PETER Tad NAN
NTT VOY AM ST GVRE KAN YT TAS
jiKyioals Reserved
Alright
So where is the raincoat with that broche!?
Ah... It's in the closet in my bedroom...
Did you hear that'? Detective Sato.
Please go and check!
Ok...
I found it!
This wet one. right!?
I'm pretty sure you'll like it!
It took at a long time
foyDetective Takagi to decide!
It looks [amazing even without diamonds!
I'm surprised hevhas pretty'good taste.
Why don'tiyou take a look!
Ms. Sato... Please. take a look!
Ms. Sato... Plcase. take 2 look!
Ms Sato Please take a look!
That must be t!
Rust me. She was staring at this broche.
She wasn't even blinkingeat all!
T's a perfect present for her. isn't it!?
It's aiperfect prosent for hor. isn't itl?
Oh. But you didn't hear this from me. OOk?
Coincidence makes girls believe
in destiny...
And that's where the love begins!
I. let us begin!
Our love story
This Is...
A broche
1 (SY SEthEIB eC h RU Mm RWantaall
Huh?
Yumi wanted?
Yeah. She wns hyper
when she saw this in a magazine
Speaking of jewelries.
I think Yumi was wearing a bracelet
that looked just like the one that
I gave you a few days ago...
Ohithat! I lent it to her!
Causc she¥snid she'd..been looking for
a brace et justMlike that...
I'm not interested
in those shiny things at all...
Hahahah
Wow! this mockinco looks fabulous!
Wow! This necklace looks fabulous!
Whe 0s nocbden 3 Mob eb
ARKox AC Wilks tx wher Cow dello, I 8
h\%\
Won Ullsodeca boot tipi 30°
A SINE
A ead Vn ots) DER
Fuh uh
[hak=g 7 Cotmetll Crotnngz) entre lucas [deft os Al
We qgotra client
for the Youth Detdctive Squad!
Just come...we got a nice one
Hehehe
Watch out!
Guys! Off the floor!