Qrs are for some rcnsmn attracts
They can be the culprit or the actor (star)
A smile less "ngel 1s the client
To get her smile back
The brave children go into a labyrinth
He sees through the one and only truth
A childean appearance with the I. Q
offan adult
NO c1se is left unsolved with
Detective Conan!
Look at this lonely girl
Hey Conan! Come over here! Right now!
WE xk e) client I x dhe Yous Dooce
Squad!
Just come... we go a nice one...
Hehehe
Mchoehe
What...?
She's real cute, isn't she?
She gives.me high motivation. man.
Eah...
HA AXA
Cay FR)
Labyrinth in the Angel's Mansion (Part I)
One day, this man named "Clock" came
to me.
Clock... You mean. that ¢c ock?
Yes .
He doesn't have either a first or last name
1st "Clock" .
He as your mother s grandfather.
And our great-grandfather
He 1s your mother's grandfather,
ind your great-grandfather
His namc is Gozo lsegawa...
My great grandfather
great-grandfather...
I didn't know I had a great-grandfather
With his shrewd instincts and guts.
He dominated the Japanese stock market
after the war.
Eople called him "Raging Bull
He was a legendary market player
who achieved numerous wealth in one
generation.
Unfortunately however
Last winter...
Clock...
Yes.
Master
Huh...
Io whoever solves this question
However...
I the Raging Bull, shall give my entire
fortune.
However. the time limit is 24 hours
Once the<time is over.
One will lose the right of both inheritance
and challenge forever.
Tho challengers\will be restricted
to my sons, wife, and grandchildren,
with the ones with-closer blood relationship
flit
I Andi] want you to see it through.
Oh please. you're not dying. Master...
Huh.
In the end. nobody ever visited me.
Well. one gets what one deserves. huh
I know that, but still, dying alone 1s a
Ionely thing.
What the hell is my family for!?
Please, calm down
You should completely rest.
The Raging Bull was 1 miserable cow
after all
So. that was my great-grandfather's end.
So! that. was my g eat-grandfather's ¢nd
And...
As the secretary and executor of
Mr. Gozo Isegawa
I'm here to tell you something.
Ms Yuriko Matsunaka.
Ah, yes
You are the one with the
17th right of inheritance. Now it is your turn.
Me. .1?
Me...17?
Of course you have the right to, "bstain
is up to ou...
By the way, I have heard that the
Youth Detective Squad.
The smart kids are at the same school
ours...
That's why you asked us. huh?
So he is actually trying not only Yuriko,
but us to solve the question.
What does:your family say about that?
My father died in a car accident right after
I was born...
$6 as my mother with a sickness last year
So I'm the only one left
Oh, I'm sorry...
AW my relives disagreed wih my parent's
marriage.
So they eloped and got married.
So I really-don't know: imy- relatives.
ERE YON EF Ee ORY Oe Ne Ll « A
Ok. How do you feel about it now?
Kind of afraid.
But if I cha lenge to solve the question.
I can see the house that my mother and
great-grandfather once lived together
when she was young.
R. Clock told me that...
That house is
Called the Angel's Mansion.
Yuriko. and the Youth Detective Squad.
Mr. €lock!
You're the O€lock...
Pleasure to meet you ll
It's pretty far, isn't it?.
That Angel's Mansion...
It's not far once we get out of this forest.
Oh yes... I told your parents that
you were going to be camping tonight, and
I have already got permission from them.
What!?
So you've done a research on us already
It's there. Look.
That's the South Angel
That's the West Angel
That's the East Angel
And that's the North Angel
They are named this way
since they are located in the four cardinal
points precisely. And also...
I've heard that the statues faces are made
to look like Mr Isegawa's wife
who happened to die young
My great-grandmother...
Yes He spent all of his earnings,
just to see his wife's face agdin
Probably he looked like a cold father to his
00S,
Theygleft.the house as soon:as-they
became. adults.
In the end. he was the only one left in the
house .
Sure his sons visited him sometimes,
but always ended up with a big fight...
t was very snd that the people couldn
understand 'him well...
raws U0
See the house with the South Angel?
We call it the South Mansion.
That's where Mr. Isegawa spent his last
moment.
Nd the East Mansion over there.
As mainly his workplace...
And that North Mansion was where his
sons and housekeepers used to live.
No one lives there now hut it looks prett, .
Neat still.
I'm tryinc to keep 1t clean all the time.
Hat about that one though 2
fiheJEasiVichsientis]likeJalhalntedEhe Sex
Actually it is Mr. Iscgawa's will that
nobody goes in there, &
How come?
I have no 'idea...
Hey! What Is that?
Oh! It's Minotaur
Oh! It's Minotaur.
Minotaur!?
It's an imaginary monster, half human .
And half bull .*
He had been ca led "Raging Bull"
What else could decorate this hous
better?
Oh yeah. Everywhere is
Bull and
Bull!
In sthesstock market, the bull 1Is_a symbol of
power.
You can find statues of bulls in
Wall Street. New York,
which is the center of the stock market.
Bulls are like guardian 'angels for market
players.
Hat the heck?
It's one of the security systems
Mr. Isegawa made
It switches on at sunset. on its on
Even after Mr. Isegawa passed away?
Right. Until somebody solves his question
and finds the treasures in this mansion...
the security is going to be on.
And so am I...
Oh. it's scary. The-angel...
Lo -P h X
It's an angel's mansion under the daylight
and a witch's mansion under the moonlight.
I guess.
Don't worry! I'm with you!
MM. Me too! Kind of.
We are at? the center of Mr lsegawas
propert .
Here is the fifth mansion,
the Mansion of the Raging Bull
So my mother was living In this house,
right?
Even after her parents left his mansion...
I heard she cared about Mr. Isegawa,
so she used to visit here alone often.
Hey. Mr. Clock.
I think it's time for you to tell us about the
question Mr. Isegawa left behind.
Right. That's what we're here for.
I'm sorry but it's not time yet, so please
I guess time really matters in this question,
doesn't it?
Well. it's time for me to serve you dinner...
To he North Mansion, please
Phew! I'm stuffed!
Yeah, it was delicious.
Now it's time.
Here is the question Mr..dsegawa left
behind
V QQQQHO
What.
When the bull's horn disappears and the
tail becomes the head
AN angel will come down and
play the flute
v , doe
Lr ee 00!
"Firm song of the angel as my very
weasfé"...
That's all?
Vv 0 Oo0° *
VES.
When the bull's horn disappears and
the tail becomes the head.
An angel will come down and play the
flute.
And ah.
The song of angel is my very treasure.
24 hours from now
Sc the time limit ls 9 orclock temorrow
night
More importantly, which bull is he talking
about
Now. please. be careful.
Some of the security systems are actually
quite dangerous.
I've seen the previous challengers getting
severely injured.
Some of them have never returned
Keep in mind
We Hats Meson 18 a Tuo lo dati
Keep in mind,
this Angel's Mansion is a huge labyrinth.
That must be it. That humongous bull gotta
be the one, man!
That must bo it. That humongous bull gotta
DO Hho On = 0
Yoel BR «oulkc) DO
but shouldn't we go with everybody else?
Hey. you'll never beat Conan if you're like
that
That bull's gotta be the one in Gozo's
question.
I don't know. man...
That bull looks to be raging. you know.
I'm gonna find the treasure map inside
its horn and then...
Genta..you're amazing!
Hehehe...
Ah... I don't think its that simple...
We should go with the boys
It's dangerous
Yeah, but did you see Yuriko's face?
She didn't show a smile. not even once.
She's really sad.
I want to solve this question her great
grandfather left her.
So she can smile again.
Alright then how come you are not
checking this bull?
Because I'm scared...
When the bull's horn disappears and the
tail becomes the head...
The bull's horn disappears.
It disappeared!
What... . 7?
AI. you're fantastic!
Oh I get it!
It must be the West Angel
that's coming down. isnt it?...
Sigh
Ayumi and Al are saying that the
West Ange is the one
Hey. we are men of iron bill!
I don't really get what you m
Oh, you don'tiknow?
It means to achieve the original intentions.
Oh. you mean.iron will. not bill.
Oh « od!
I smell something fishy from the
East Mansion.
It is Mr. Isegawa's will that nobody goes
in there, so...
Maybe the question is a lie, and
the treasures are In the East Mansion... l?
G. Genta...
Man! This thing Is too smooth!
Thank you, Mitsuhiko
(Hews.
Plows
How should we
make the angel
come down...?
That is what we are
tr Ingi'to find out.
Atch out!!
Electric shock...
Ail?
I guess we better go back.
So. here's the East Mansion. I suppose?
The treasures Is somewhere in here...
This bull has no horns!!
When the bull's horn disappears...
The tail becomes the head"
The tal is the head.... Head?
Why aren't you moving? You! Cow!
Inn!
Ha! Hmmm!
Oh god
H. help!
Somebody help!
Hello. anybody?
Is anybody here?
An===I
Oh god!
Mitsuhiko!
Mr. Clock?
You gotta believe this
ounce auamedan Hones In ero...
Bones!?
Is that true?
I guess that's how rats end up in this
Iabyrinth.
Yeah, but aren't you supposed to call the
police?
Certainly. I will...
Now YOU, focus on what you have to do
Time is money.
here's everyone?...
They said they're going to the washroom.
It's boon too long.
Phew.
Ah I can't sleep. So
I'm gonna go for a little walk, ok?...
LN ooo JUG
Don't worry. Just for a while
In the end, nobody ever visited me
dying alone is a lonely thing.
001 __
Oh~? Where is this?...
Conan.?
Oh! I'm gonna pee in my pants!
Mr. Clock. where's the washroom?
- Nat
I don't know sf we should trust what
Mr. Olock told us. man.
What do you mean'...
You know. this Gozo guy left the question,
Yuriko was the 17th challenger
Things like that...
Yeah I know...
There have been 16 challengers in the
past few months.
But nobody left a memo or whatsoever
It IS strange...
Yeah
Maybe this question thing is a lie
and is something he used to get Yuriko
LO come here.
Getting her to come here. and then what?
Yeah.
Actually...l don't know
I don't think Mr Clock was lying
Just m guess.
'2 S One sure ung...
Even if the previous challengers left some
kind 0 hint to the question,
that Clock guy could've cleaned them
all up.
For the sake of being fair to all the
challengers?
Voile I
But the thing is what does he gain from
doing so
Hmm 2?
Shoots!. .10 hours left...
I'm so sorry...for causing you a trouble.
Maybe I should just.
Don't you worry. Yuriko.
There're still many other bulls to soc!
We got 10 hours! It's long enoug wfor
me to break all the horns!
Wait a minute Why is it the Bull
And why does it have to be the horn... 7?
Simple Yuriko's great, grandad was
called "Raging Bull
And. there's a bull with horns.
Which Genta got HANGED ON last nigh!
In the Mansion of the Raging Bull
And there's a gold bull with'no horns In the
East Mansion
where Mitsuhiko pissed in his pants. right?
W. what are. ou talking about,
I didn't pee In my pants!
The "bull" in question cums not refer to any
of the bulls in this mansion That's...
A character?
The bull's horn disappears
That means...
Sheep!?
Oh. please. Genta!
It's "Go". Like when you write noon
in Japanese
In the Chinese zodiac, it means "horse".
Horse? There's nO horse in here...
It's not just animal. This "horse" also»
indicates a direction.
And one more thing...
Shoots!
The South Angel
Horse is the symbol of the south
You gotta be careful
There's an electric shock security. system. a»
NO, naxx 3 GO AOS had OA IF Pan Gi Rs
BEsEMeO Ao AnenEsEr OF Mors also
(YX. Yn 22 FAR.
NO Woy
Guess what time. it is Tight now?
It's opened!
It-s weird It's glued onto the floor. Why?
Is that the Raging Bulls: treasure?
No. this black crystal is the key to solve
the next question
The bull's horn disappears
and the tail becomes the head
It means the opposite of "horse"
which 1s rat, and the direction of the rat
is north!
There must be something in the
North Angel Tower!
What are you doing!?
O kod"
Oh god!
Guys. off tHo floor!
Yuriko!
Original Comic'Books By.
GOSHO A AMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
rr far CC. €*2°.5 wu
Show
3ackeroundiMusic.
KATSUO ONO
(Character Designs By.
MASAIOMO SUDOg.
StorygEditor.
JUNIGHI 11DKA
fir
Story.Editor.
JUNIGHIT 11DKA
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
ZUNA 1 KoUC
JWNICHIMIY SHIA
YUICAT HIGURE.»
» » y [og]
Antthation Directors
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHIJAKATANI
ATSUSIIIAOWO \
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Dircator.
YUKIHIROAAVIIIBUIANI
hUklHIROmgflilllUfA NI
Dircttors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI#
TAKAHISA OWAGA *
Recording Director
KATSUYO HI¥KOBAVASHI
5J)%
Chic Dircator.
KENJI KODAMA
oduced By
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD,
5 inf association with
YM UR{I{ ELECASTING
GO . ORA TON
DETECTIVE CO is 1
OD IH IN INIA] SH J) SANS LA L111)
\ av his Reserved
You found human bones
in the East Mansion. rght?
Which direction was the headlfacing?
Maybe the thief wandered through
this tunnel and ended up there...
uhe time is over now, isn't it?
No. just solved the second question
You wanna fight?
Stop!
1% Ff)
(1% 7)
Labyrinth-in. the Angelis Mansion (Part 11)"