Stars are for some reason attractive
They can be the 'culprit or the actor
With the treasure and the girl's smile
The angel comes down to us at last
It is time for us to get them all
Ho soos through tho ono and only wth
A child in appoarance
with the I. Q of an adult
No case as left unsolved
with Detoctive Conan
We the Youth Detective Squad.
We tho Youth Detective Squad,
got a client
er name as Yunko Matsunaka
a student in the other class of our grade.
She visited us because she wanted us
to check on her great-grandfather
Gozo Isegawn
who left a strange message
t was-a riddle and
he wanted: Yuriko to solve it. And so.
We decided to help her
A mysterious guy named "Clock" took us
to a place called the "Angel's Mansion To
solve the riddle Gozo Isegawa left behind.
Now It 1s time...
V  roe!
,4: ,, n
Icase listen to what I say now.
What
When the bull's hern disappears
and the tail becomes the head.
An angel will come down «
ind play the flute
V M5500
HOP"
The song of the angel.is my very treasure
What are you doing!?
Oh god.
Oh go I!
Guys. move!
Yuriko!
(1% 7)
Labyrinth in the Angel's Mansion Part ll
(1% RF)
Jg...Ugh
Ug...Ugh
He . go s!
Are ou (cu s ok?
Yoah, I'm ok
0 WO Al {oll
Genta...Genta?
Hey, something's wrong with Genta!
He! Gentai? Genta!
Nmm... Another grilled eel. please...
Ahaha...
Hey. he hasn't slept since last night. right?
1here:sionly49 hours left until the time limit!
Nya...
WwW. where is this? Where. are we!?
Remember what Mr. Clock said?
Keep in mind,
this Angel's Mansion is like a labyrinth
A labyrinth...
ou mean, maze!? Oh man,
we are all gonna die in here, aren't we?
Oh god!
No...this can't be happening...
So we can't get outta here?
Sigh
Huh...
Mitsuhiko. it's all your fault.
What? It's not my fault!
Yeah it is Us because you were
trying to be cool in front Yuriko.
You're not that kinda guy
You shouldn't have acted like that.
Ok. but you were doing
exactly the same thing
saying "I'm gonna beat Conan,
weren't you!
Al and Ayumi. you girls were too!
I just.
I just wanted to...
You too, Conan! Look what happened
after we got into the Angel's Mansion.
You should've been more careful!
You guys:should-ve-been waiting outside.
YO. man!
You're saying Yuriko was kidnapped
il because of us, not you!
Yeah. you wannaifight!?
Why not!
Ah. why not!
Oh...gh
Stop it.
Guys. no fighting. please!
We're all friends. right!?
Yeah. but they're saying it's all.my fault.
For God's sakes,
who else is gonna get Yuriko back
If the Youth Detective Squad split up?
She's alone...rightsnow,, at this moment...
S. sorry. I was wrong.
No. I was wrong!
No... was wrong!
Did Conan just apologize?
E (IC
Welk everything's going be fine!
This mazes hike nothing. as long as tho
Youth Detective Squad 1s together. night?
Yeah. that's right!
Sigh...
It's tough to motivate kids: isn't it?
Oh quiet.
Hoy. Mitsuhiko
Yes?
You found human bones
in the East Mansion, right?
Which direction was the head pointing?
Direction. eh .!.Let me think
Iere's the South Mansion.
And I went into the East one like this. so...
It's that way
The-dead. man was lying on
his stomach. facing the fireplace...
I guess that's where the thieves ended up
in this maze. like Mr. Clock said...
When a man falls down on his stomach,
the head shows where he was heading...
Mitsuhiko already saw thatethe fireplace
was"connected to where the bones were.
So, this maze shou dglead us I
at least to the East Mansion.
Great! You're my man!
Yeah, but more important is how we get
there before we become bones. right?
The labyrinth of Minotaur...
What?
Hey remember? The half man half
bull monster in front of the mansion...
In therancient Greek myths,
Minotaur is a son of a king.
Who incurred the God's displeasure
And the God made Minotaur
half-human half-bull.
S nce Minotaur became
awfully violent asllhe grew up.
The king decided to putedhim In a
huge maze. so.he could never come out...
So that monster is somewhere in this maze?
Oh, come on. No
What's important is after that
Every year, the king sent
seven Athens kids to the maze as tribute.
As Athens here Theseus heard that stor
he slayed:the monster,
and came back from the maze
which people thought impossible to, escape.
Hmyymim.
Hmmm...
By usimg a ball of string
A ball of string
A ball of... string?
Right.
He tied the string to the gate of the maze,
and pulled it while walking inside.
On the way back,
all he needed was to follow the string.
I see.
Then, we should do the same thing
Yeah. we should
Oh, you ladies do not have to do it
Right Conan?
Right.
Hey look,
I think we passed here once already!
Ok, then I think we should've turned right
on that corner. not left... ha... Hachoo!
You're alright. Mitsuhiko?
You're alright, Mitsuhiko?
Yh, don't you worry In fact,
we should focus on how to get outta...
Kerchoo!
Don't know if this is enough
Well, I think it's showing
how close we gotsto the exit
Let me help you guys!
What!
Oh. Sorry. go s
Dona worry man'\
Our"job as to-'mnd 'a way to get outta here.
Your job, is to solve the riddle.
Sodjust keep thinking.
Genta.
Hachoo!
Achoo!
That's right! Every man has
his own specialty I right?
That's night! Every man has
his own specialty. right?
Mitsuhiko...You guys
What's wrong?
Is it time already?
No. I ju st solved the second riddle. But .
Hey. guys. look!
There. that guy.
It's just straight up ahead!
Yeah!
Gosh. we're alive!
Gosh. that was scary.
Hachoo!
Yuriko!
What
What?
Yuriko. are you alright? Are you hurt?
You bastard. You plannedttoskidnap} her
from the beginning. didn't you...
Oh, certainly not. I just kept Ms. Matsunaka
away from the pitfall. That's all.
I just screamed because
he grabbed my arms all of a sudden.
I'm so sorry for causing you
really don't know what to say
Ah. actually. itfwas pretty fun, wasn't it?
Oh yes. It was just a little adventure,
kinda thing Jou knew Right. Conan?
Hm?...Oh, yoah it was
Conan, I remember you were saying
you solve the second nddle
eah. But we got only 3 hours or so.
We can no longer sec the treasures
ww FF
(VY VAT Ot
WRY*not?
Thewnil becomes thevhead is telling us
to head to the direction of "rat",
which means the North Angel Tower...
And also. rat means midnight.
So in order to open the North Angel Tower,
we have to wait until midnight tonight,
but our challenge ends at 9 pm tonight.
No way!
Noway!
Mr. Clock, you knew the answer
of the first part of the riddle. didn't you?
What?
Wht! ?
That's why you just saved Yuriko and
Iet the rest of us fall into the pitfall
after finding the black crystal
You planned to get in our way. didn't you?
Less than 3 hours left, though
I'm still hoping from my heart that
you to solve the riddle.
n=¥?
One more hour left
There must be a way to open the gate
of the North Angel Tower somehow...
Everyone is trying hard. Think... Think
When the bull's horn disappears
and the tail becomes the head...
An angel will come down
and play the flute
The song of the angel is my very treasure.
Is niin pen ¢
It's scary. the angel...
No way... but that's:so. then...
Oh. I see. Now I got it!
A ladder!
Somebody. get me a ladder!
Yo. man, where's a ladder!?
Ou need it at the North Angel Tower,
the direction of rat. right?
No. I need it in the East Angel. East!
East?
Be careful. Conan!
8 I owing
the wait is over. here comes the flute!
Now. what am Vi gong to see:whaon this
Iight hits the; Angel in the direction of "rat"
An angel will come down and play the flute
of the black crystal to show us the treasures
Hey, it's over there.
An angel has come down to the forest!
What!?
GAT you senous?
It's the shadow.
The shadow of the angel. playing the flute!
The song of the angel 1s
my very treasure, right?
It's on the hill where
the: charcoal burncr's lodge is.
That's where
HOO Soy ) KF weal Gr GO C
it! We still got 30 minu
Now let's go!
Mr. Clock! ?
It is Yuriko's treasure!
You're an adult¥,
Good adults~don't steal things!
Mr Clock .
No. it's not that. Yuri...
Do not interrupt me. There's no time.
Oh no! No more maze. please!
I can't see!
This is Mr Goro Iscgawn's Yunko's
great-grandfather's treasures, isn't it?
Inet (8 nel?
The game as over!
Mr. Clock. you tell us your story!
I knew you were trying to get these
treasures from the beginning.
You were Mr. Isegawa's secretary
You heard and solved the all the riddles
before anybody else. right?
Solved everything...?
Yeah, but ipsthe same way as I did.
In the wrong way.
The fact that he told us the riddles
In the evening shows that.
I'm sorry but it's not time yet
If he presents the riddle at 9 pm
the challenger has to wait
until the neon of the next day.
To get into the North Angel Tower
Thore. the challenger maybe able to
rcalizethe second question,
in which: 'he has to gotinto
the North Angel lower
Bul the ear iest he can get Into
the North Tower is the midnight off that day
SO He HERR Tex OWA FON TY, Aes
NO Way you can break it within 24 hours
N. no! It wasn't me...
But If he really wanted tho treasure,
he could've tried his deduction and
realized the flaw in the riddlc¢,
don't ou think?
Sure ho could,
but he didn't! Because it would be a crime
if he snatched someone s treasure!
He w: ted to have the treasure officially
WER Pin fig O ey - ROB To ano
with the 18th right of inheritance
It makes sense that he was watching us,
werfering with us. erasing all the clue
the previous challengers left,
because he was waiting for his turn.
No'!.It'wns Master's Mr. Isegawa's
will te sct the riddle time at 9 pm.
Yeah. right. Who would believe that?
I would! Because
Because that knife wasn't to hurt us
but to make us realize the presence
Aha lag voltage current
Tho footstops sounded hko it was an adult
He is the only adult in here!
I don't think he was trying to
monitor or interfere with us.
I think he was trying to
protect Yuriko and us...
Now, please, be careful. Some of the s
ecurity systems are actually quite dangerous
I think so too
Mr. Clock isn't a bad person.
hen db was in thal room...
Ok. I air gnough.
Yuriko's parents gave up on
their grandfather éwnduft the house
Hey Al. I don't think that's ah...
Because of his nature of hating people.
There's no way such person would
tell his secret to a stranger
even if he's the secretary
So. Mm point is,
Mr Clock is related to Mr. Isegawa .
Hdb related to my qroot-grandfather .!?
But at the same time, he was also
someone Mr segawa hated so much
so that he had to lose his name.
Execute his master's will, and remain In this
mansion until someone solves the riddle
There's only ore person
we can think of here
Probably. you are...
OK, that's enough!
It wasnfl the gold blocks Mr Clock we»
trying to reach! It was that.
Yuriko) .
No man! It's Mr. Isegawa's
granddaughter. Mr. Clock's wife!
What!? So that means,
Clock is Yuriko's father?
Right! He's someone Mr. Isegawn hated]
The most but also related to him.
Yuriko's father must be thc
one 'cause he ram away with his wife!
Mr. Isegawa loved his granddaughter,
uriko's mother so much
He said she reminded him of his wife a lot
So. he was desperate to get her back
when we ran away from him.
Around that time,
he had a lot of connections
with the underground community
didn't know what
he would do if he got mad...
$0 I decided to leave my wife and Yuriko
who was just born. to protect them.
I made a deal with Mr Isegawa
I work for him so he leaves my family alone.
To ease his anger, it was necessary to
serve him with all my heart and soul.
Master. it's getting windy now
MM... I know. but ll like doing this...
And one day I realized.
He truly loved his family
from the bottom of his heart.
He didn't know the:way:'to;show it well...
Raging Bull was a difficult but
kind old man who valued his family
And it was last year that
Mr. Isegawa started saying that
he wanted to settle with his granddaughter
or Yuriko's mother all of a sudden.
So I looked for my family
and found out about my wife's death.
Mr Isegawn collapsed rapidly with
disappointment and died with the riddle.
Presentation of the riddle is 9pm.
If the nddle is solved. you are fred
Forgive me. Matsunaka.
I'm Yoshihito Matsunaka. Yiuriko's father
Your mother made that
riddle when she was a ¢hild
Mom made it?
Lu iw
Great grandad chose that riddle
because there was only one person
T= TA
who would know the answer.
Cv Cy
It's you. because you're her daughter.
It's you, becausc you're her daughter.
Dad!
Yuriko...Sorry. I'm sorry!... Yuriko...
Orieinal Comic:Books By.
TOSHO AGYAMA
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO ODSHIQKA
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO Y( SHIOKA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
S Character Designs By.
MASATOMG) 50004.
JUN]GHI ITDKAwy,
StorygEditor.
JONIGHI 11OKA
JUNIGHI 11DKA
JUNIGHI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN]? KAWJTIWABARA
AZUNARI KOUCI
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors:
MASATOMO SUDO
SHIT
AKIO'KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO#
Art Director.
Art Director:
YUKIHIRQ@YSHIBUIANI
- - Ca.
Art Dircctor.
YUKIHIRO 'SHIBUIANI
Directors Of Photography
AKA. HI"'NOMURA
HIRONOBUHORIROSHI
LANA IDAVU AU Ar
Recordinoe Director.
KAISUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
HHRUAMITSU (CYADA
! Chief Director.
KEN] KODAMA
oduced By
ORATION
[20:11 (ad IV! Cala) VN
(CDNTIED AV DOY AAI SET GTVRITRAAIN DY 1y- TALS
AN 223i Jtesursved
Later, Mr Clock. decided to change
he Angcl'siMansion into a theme park
of bulls and maze simply
because Yuriko said
it was her great-grandfather's dream.
I think so too.
Probably, Mr. Iscgawn made
that huge maze secretly. to please his kids.
And also. ta rebuild his family relationshap
Now. his dream has finally come true
A peice sign?
( Tantinf@ Slit le
What the heck is this?
Smiley Peace!?
Is that:a:dying message?
He was saying Mr. Mizuhara-was
more important than his own life. I heard.
More than his own life. huh?
[fethat's so,
then that dying" message makes sense.
The ManWho Called the Ambulance