Stars are for some reason attractive
Tiheyscan be the culprit or the actor
Detective, Takagi is onstage
Care is the key to therdying message
Solve the case with smile and peace
He sees through the one and only truth
wchild in appearance
with the I. Q. of an adult
Neo c1se is left unsolved
with [ étective Conan
sf - 4
Hmm!?
Ah, hello .
Are you) sleeping?
You're gonna catch cold...
Hmm!?
Huh!? Oh god!
(ig OIlowa Ni Nooo)
Ok! I gotta call the ambulance!
Ah. I found a man lying on the ground!
He's bleeding from this head!
Oh. the place? Ah. I thank. I
What's taking them so long.
Why can they just come right away...
The hospital is right
in front of the train station...
Hmm. since they are not coming,
"should go and get them!
The Man Who Called the Ambulance
Yen dthats what I meant
he JuysWho found thesvictir
URI?
Ho disappoared from tho sito of murdor!
Hmm? The first person
to find the victim disappeared?
Hmm!? Tho first person
TO He) fie We LC EOL (NE
64a. , > M,
Hmm!? The first person
to find.the victim-disappeared?
I told you! He ran.away!
Right after hecalled 119.
Yeah .Uh? What!?
Uh? as it actually me
that you are talking about
EXO LAU EX En) Om WAX {Ox
the victim first. Where were you hiding?
Well, I wasn't hiding or anything
I left here to get the ambulance!
Did you really?
I don't think you needed to, because
the victim was already dead long ago...
What!
Wetter ela) Witinx WR RY
after being clubbed in. his head...
So, I appreciate that
you came here all the way but
I got it!
You left here to: get the ambulance which in
fact was unnecessary. It's strange. isn't it?
Name!?
What are you talking about?
How could I know that he was dead...?
Name!
What's your name!
Oh. it's Hiroshi Hiromatsu
H~ ha ha...
VINE EX) EX Fink XA) WO oof
Como on! Your name, address, age. job!
Write everything down on this!
Hmm?
Hiroshi Hiromatsu, huh?-It's funny
Your name,is {like a tongue twister.
Boa As PR
What can I. do? It's my name!
Hmm! You're a comedian. huh?
I've never heard of your name before
Well. I'm not a pepular one, really
Your name is funny,
but you know what's funnier?
I've never secon something like this before.
Peas
What the...Smiling .and peace
What does It mean...?
Oh. Ara you done. ?
Let's we...
Hmmm!?
Uh, what is lit...?
Hey. lwal and-Hlfatwo'!
Yes, she'?
Go and poke around now
Go to convenience stores Witnesses ote
What! ?
What! 2
You got It! 2
Yes, owl
Sir. did I write something wrong?
[kp Is Letigehve Lie
em - - 1
ME cv fa
Vile v Wo og ant
bog! Welerw
POLI
I'm Takagi*from the metropolitan police...
M8 RM 24
Peele Nerguacet
Nagti Wataru
POLICE)
I'm Takagi from the 'metropolitan police...
I'm Takagll from the metropolitan police...
Oh. Mr. Takagi!!
Hiromatsu?
I'm Sakurada from Belka East Station.
Do you know. him»?
Res, he actually helped me catch
shoplifters before. So. why are you here...?
It happened to be ma.
Who found the victim first...
You are the first one, huh...
Well, maybe there was
something else he did as well
What do you mean by that?
He, is suspicious about Mr. Hiromatsu...
Conan.>
So. what is it, Mr. Sakurada?
You think Hiromatsu is the murderer?
Suspect the:first man who finds the victim!
It's the: basics of investigation
But I did not kill the victim)!
Look. I know what kind of person he is
us can Ke Wm...
Ok, the reason I think
he is the murderer is!...
Iigot'a phone call from the police...
hm Yukiko Yasunaga,
the owner of Office Yasunaga
I'm Sakurada of Belka East Station...
And you
I'm Sakurada.of Beika East Station
And ou?
You're Mr. Ryoji Mizuhara... Right?
I've seen you a.Jot on TV drama and stuff...
Oh yeah'. You're the actor!
I'm Mizuhara.
Ohkubo was the manager
of Mizuharna, actually
Ohkubo?
Mr Iwao Ohkubo...the Victim...
I need you to identify the victim. so please. % >
hat the heck Is this
AR SRO sv ve O
A peace sign!?
Is it him?
Is it him
Yes. it is him.
Heiwas my manager, Mr. Ohkubo
Hiromatsu... what are you doing here'?
It's a long story...
Do you guys know each other?
We're living in the same apartment,
right next to each other
Il 300., 0 UmxTkumiYulnCI
Last time we talked, yoursaid
Mr. Ohkubo was workingJlate last night...
He was actually in my room,
It was just a while ago...
It was late last night
when he came to my place.
We ware talking about
my future plan as an actor.
Went on until midnight...
Then to catch the first train
He left my place around 4:30 in the morning.
So, he left your apartment
and headed to the station
and this was the street that he took...
Ohl!
4:40 am
It was 10 minutes
after he left Mr. Mizuhara's, apartment.
I assume the murder weapon was 1 steel
pipe although we haven't found it yet
I assume the murder weapon was a steel
OK then, after 20 minutes. which was $ am
Ok then, after 20 minutes. which was H am,
you found tho victim
on the street while you were jogging
That's rig it.
ALAA apd NE
You guys are living on 4th street...
The train station is this way...
hospital is located before the station.
The train station is this way
hospital is: located before the station.
$0 it'll be like this
though its a rough sketch...
Mr. Takagi, since I was interrupted last time,
now it's a good time to tell you
the reason why. I suspect Mr. Hiromatsu.
He killed Ohkubo
Did you?
No. I didn't!
First of all, you were the
first ome to find the victim
There's a possibility that the murderer
Ieft his belongings at the crime scene...
But if he pretends that he is
the first person to find the victim,
then he can make an excuse.
Saying that these things
were there when he found the victim!
Yeah. but...
Second of all...you left
the murder scene to get the ambulance...
You know, people usually don't do that...
Perhaps,
u left for some other purpose. didn't you....?
What's that supposed to mean?
I or example...
Sakurada...Um?
The murder weapon was found?
Yes sir. I'm pretty sure. sir
It's got some hair on it as well
as ,bloodstains which dré still wet.
Yes . We found it under...
Kwml Tnkfldw Bridge .
Just as I thought. Good job!
KannrTakada Bridge...
Just as I thought \Good job!
Kami-Takada bridge?
Oh, that's a bridge located
between this murder site and the hospital...
So, the reason why you
headed to the hospital was...
not to call the ambulance...
but to dispose of the murder weapon!
Give me a break! Why would. I
have to kill him in the first place!
As to that, I already have a clue!
What?
You said you are a
comedian but not popular at all...
You knew Mr. Ohkubo
was Mr. Mizuhara's manager.
And you knew-he visited Mr. Mizuharaloften
so you begged him to give you a job...
You got mad. and then...
Walt. hold on...
Wait, held on...
And you know what!?
The dying message the victim
Ieft is telling that you are the murderer!
Dying message?
What is it?
It's how Mr. Ohkubo died. Wasn't it strange?
Smiling with a peace sign...
That was the dying message'?
Exactly, that was the murderer's name!
Iivu
Take a look!
Smiley Peace?
I knew you were a comedian but
I didn't know that your stage name was this
Yeah, but I didn't Kill him!
Believe me. Mr. Takagi!
Hey. what about his alibi?
Oh, alibi?
If Mr. Ohkupo-was killed at 4-40,
then I was still in my apartment...
I left t ere a little before 5:00
It was: right after
I started jogging when I found the victim!
I wish you-could prove-that.
Yeah, but how can you prove
that a man living alone was in his room?
Oh. I remember. after Mr. Ohkubo left
I set thesalarm clock and went to bed
Then, I heard the sound of.
the toilet flushing from the room next to Mine.
And that was 4:40, right
Mr. Mizuhara?
I think so.
Now you have an alibi. Hiromatsu!
Yeah!
What's. that look on his face?
Sorry... May I go home now?
Um'!?
Ohkubo was like a father to you.
You must be shocked.
I think you're done with Mizuhara. right?
Elk I will have to see you
some other time, but today. yes...
Uh...May I go home too?
I haven't asked you about the situation
when you found the dead victim. have I?
Ha ha ha...You're right.
Yeah, Uh ha...
Are you sure'?
Got it! Thanks.
Bad news. The alibi you stated is invalid.
Huh?
What the!
IL knew you were hiding something.
So I had my officers investigate: this:area.
Searching for some.kind.:of;clue...
Yiu Wore opine .socurly
camera of the store on rd street
It was taken at 4.30am!
I'm sorry!
0 (oc)
I left my apartment 10 jog before 430).
Hiromatsu.
Well how could I tell you the truth?
I could've been arrested for the murder!
So that was a lie out of « ésperation. huh?
That's why you had a strange -
Iook on your face.
Maybe that was Mr. Mizuhara's
Imagination? I don't know.
But that was totally
out of blue that he said so...
So it was just a coincidence
that you lied about your alibi
Is that what it is?
WM. there's noineed
to lie if yousirezitrulyinnocent...
Now, I needi'you to come:to the station,
Mr: Hiromatsu
Oh sorry. it's Mr. Smiley Peace!
R. Takagi...
The motive of tho murder,
and the disposal of the weapon aro.
All Mr. Sakurada's idoa...
The dying message is the problem. right?
Smiley Peace...l didn't knew it was him...
Pn oon ole YA Way /
Mr. Ohkubo kpew that name.
I didn't even know that was a stage name
Mr. Mizuhara knew the name,
only because they were neighbors. right?
I haven't seen Mr. Mizuhara on TV lately,
But he used to be on
a lot of TV shows. eh...
With a never-smile but handsome face.
He was cool...
ARERR OF eEwke SINQRRUN TeX The) Ae,
Me was Cool.
Mun xe iliac) EXE [Mooing faa, 10
I'll go and watch the interrogation, ok?
Smiley Peace.
Snriile Wit-he: peace Sign
Smile
Maybe...
Oh Uh. you're
I'm Conan Edogawa
IAlright:Conan, 'what's up? I
Detective Takagiltold me
to. asks ou something...
t's about the conversation Mr. Ohkubo
had with Mr. Mizuhara.last. night
Oh, you mean the future
plan about Mizuhara's career.
Yuan, Mr. Takagi wants to know
more about this future plan in detail.
OK. so this future plan means...
ORR 1 AOORR RYO een
what the dying message means!
And
The real murderer is that person!
Ms. Yasunaga? You-mean. the-female-owner
ofatheaproduction company?
Yeah. She told me to tell you this b cause
she thought it might help to solve the case.
The future plan means smile
Smile?
We sold Ryoji Mizuhara as 1 cool handsome
actor that never smiles
But that style doesn't work any more...
So, Ohkubo told him about switching
to a handsome actor with warm smiles
That's why he visited me last night...
I agreed with that plan,
beeause Mlzuhara looks so sexy
Switching to a smiley actor?
Yeah! But I'm pretty
sure that Mr. Mizuhara...
was surprised since
hclw.as told so out Of the luc
Umm, he was me angry
than surprised. I think, because...
he was suddenly toldste be an acter
than was totally opposite...
what he used be. right?
Oh no!y
Also, Mr. Ohkubo treated Mr. Mizuhara
as if he were his own child: I heard
Ohkubo had a sickness actually...
What?
The doctor told him that he
had only 6 months more to live
SO HO Alexa oO
been resting in the hospital
but he refused, and worked hard instead,
just to make his boy Mizuhara
make a great comeback on TV once again,
while sacrificing his life.
He did it all for Mizuhara.
Sacrificed his life.
Then, I think I got the meaning
of the dying message!
Really?
Yeah, If my deduction is correct,
then this case is a really sad one.
Right. This is not a funny. case at ll
Not.at all.
What is this? Why are you calling
everyone to the murder scene?
Listen Mr. Sakurada,
Hiromatsu did not murder Mr. Ohkubo!
The murderer is somebody else
First of all, about the
disposal of the murder weapon!
After the murder, the killer fled
from here as ou cansimagine
But which way did he/she run away?
Iva.
KamrTakada bridge, where the
weapon was found. is that way...
414 )
Then, the murderer ran that way too?
Not necessarily...
Maybe he went that way!
Criminals try to divert police attention
opposite the direction that they flee.
Very simple trick though.
I see. The real murderer is
someone 1a -siwvingarounc ere...
Wait a second Mr Mizuhara. your
apartment as tnaswvayd Isn't It'?
Yeah.
Second of all, about establishing the alibi...
Perhaps this criminal
act was a compulsive one.
Perhaps this criminal act
as a compulsive one.
Thus, the murderer was not
well-prepared! I assume.
But that person camo up with 1 good idea.
You lied about your alibi
out of desperation. right?
The true murde er tried to use that lie
I don't get. it
Fy «>»
Don't you remember? There was one
person who was drawn into your lie...
Rv oft Mizuhara!
Yes...
You murdered Mr. Ohkubo!
+ then heard the sound of flushing toilet
from the room next to mine.
That was neither your imagination
nor misconception, right?
By saying so.
you tried to fabricate your
alibi that you were in your room
Last night. «Mr. Ohkubo made a suggestion
about the futurezplan of your career
It was about switching your character
from a smileless one to a smiley one
But (you had "lways liked being a cool,
handsome actor that didn't smile
Mr Ohkubo s suggestion
was nOflbdwé) of? your options
And then you thought Mr Ohkubo was
gonna force you to change your character
No way! Am I wrong?
Huh...I'm Ryoji Mizuhara. You think'l am
gonna laugh like a teenage brat?
Mizuhara,
You murdered OhKubo?
This morning. after he left your apartment.
You followed Mr. Ohkubo...
Huh=?You are darn right, Mr. Takagi.
But then, why did the victim die In
such a strange way Explain that?
Of course, as you thought,
that was a dying message
But it wasn't "Smiley Peace". It
was smile and "V(Victory) sign.
It was Mr. Ohkubo=s last message to you.
Whom he treated like his own child.
R. Ohkubo said to you...
Mizuhara:,: senile
mile Is your new' style.
You.look'amazing when you smile
I did't how that.
This can't be true!!
Who in the world would encourage
someone that's actually trying to kill you?
But there are people like that
That's how much
Ohkubo,cared about Mizuhara
He deeply cared about you.
Idn't you know, Mizuhara...
He had only 6 months left to live?
But he decided to
sacrifice. his valuable time for you.
Mr. Ohkubo!
Mr Ohkubo was thinking about
you until the last moment of his life.
You should pay for your crime
and live right for him. Mr. Mizuhara.,
Alright
Let me hear your story in the station, ok.
Mr. Sakurada!
Huh?
Could you...
Please, apologize to Hiromatsu!
Huh!?
Please, apologize that you suspected
Hiromatsu Yes. he did lie about his alibi...
And lying Is not a good thing...
But. it's partly your fault because you put
too much pressure on him
so that he had to lie!
Am I wrong, Mr. Sakurada?
Suspect the first man who finds the victim.
It is the basics of investigation...
But there's a flaw that people
tend to ignore in this principle too...
This applies not only to you, but me as well
That is:.[police officers
must be free from prejudice!
No matter what!
I'm sorry
I was wrong.
Uh, no
It's OK.
Thank you so much. Mr. Takagi!
! CT OOu at yd Is 4
ou're a ma... Detective Takagl
{OO id
CO) f a] &
MICHIHIKOWUWA
ASAHITO YOSHI KA
Pr 0 d ucCg op S - :
MIGHIHIKO 'SUWA
MA AHITO Y( SHIOKA
[tn SA
sackgroundiMusic.
KATSUO; ONO
»Character Desiens By.
MASATIDNM@D SUDO
JUNJGHI NOKAY,
StoryqEditor. +
JUNIGHI TTOKA
StoryuEditor.
JUNIMHIJIGKA ,
Scripts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHIIMTY SHITA
YUICAT HIGURE
TOSHIKI IN TUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
a » - Lo Av 3 - o Pp NN
ATS URN! AGWO
AKIOYKAWAMURA
TAKASHI*HYODO
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Art Director
RQ SHI
Ari Diretdor.4
YUKIHIRQ S11IBUTANI
SUKIHIRQ SHIBUTANI
Art Director. « ~.
YWKIHIR@SHIBUTANI
Art Dirg Glos
YUKIHIRO, TIBUTANI
Cf > or
FLINT CR QUI DY JIT 11puu "1711, &
TA-KASHPNIJMURA
HIRONDOBUSTORIROS HI
7 KA. $A OWAGA
Recordine Director
KATSUYOSHI'KOBAYAS HI
Clio.
TERUMIISU OKADA
{ Chicf Director.
KINJI KODAMA
roduced By
TMS ENTERTAINMENT; LTD
infassocration with
YO 1URI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
1414'! min I "Mum \\
O CULM AVA I WHO AOR BIT I
AL Shain deswr sud
Well, I thought my life was over when I
heard that the name of the murderer was
Smiling with a peace sign. seriously.
Oh, you should've
thought about itlin the first place.
Yeah .ll don't think Mr. Ohkubo knew &g)
comedian called "Smiley Peace" anyway
People of the same; industry
don't know my name
That shows how unpopular I
am. deesn't;it? Oh man!
Don't worry. Hirematsu.
IV MA