Stars are fer some reason attractive
They can bewhe culprit or the actor
The Osaka due watch a magic show
On stage, 1 breathtaking magic show is
taking place
Off .stage. however, a life-taking trap.is
set up
He sees throughi.the one and only truth
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an
adult
No case is left unsolved with
Detective Conan
yf 414
Yeah, 80 we're gonna go see that
with these people right now,
Really, that sounds amazing!
OK. to go to that hall,.
you need to go straight down this street
and then...
Why? Why ?
Man, it's stressing me out...
(dante
Darn...
Guess Who I am?
Hmm! ?
NO Re--AN
It's me!
Aw! Stop it! I'm serious!
Kudo!!
Kudol!
Ouch!
Sol mean... it was
Huh!? What?
H. hey! Mat drill
Oops. Uh, Judo!
Y:, you want me to do the Judo throw on
oul?
H. Helji...?
Hmm. Ha ha...
Hmm. .Ha ha .
Huh. .!"
He . Hattori...
Conan and Heiji's Deduction Magic!
(PART 1)
I'm so sorry, Ran!
For asking you a big favor...
Don't worry.
Yo. Hattori. what brings you here?
Is it the Dogo Hoshikawa's Super Magic
Show?
Ha ha
She said "I feel like watching miracles
Nuts. huh?
So I had to come for this stupid girl's
stupid tricks
Don't call me stupid, stupid!
Oh!?
Kazuha they are over there...
BC Lone
Now. let's go! Ku. ku, Conan A
Hey, it's here. Here's your seat. Ran
There are a lot of girls here, don't you
think?
Oh are there?
Oh, come on!
So. this guy is Dogo Hoshikawa...?
That's right! Don't you think he is
handsome. Ran
He's not just a handsome guy but also a
great magician!
I bét
qffflfi Ma ES
4S10 ages
Hey! She's a hot girl. huh.
Yeah...
What? I thought he was hanging on strings
That's what I thought too...
\\,\
Wow.
It's amazing.
Nope.
4H4 Am
(7 FN
Nod.
Oh no!
No way...
He vanished...
It's unbelievable
He must be a wizard
Are ou stupid?...
Huh!?
There's no such thing called a wizard
I think so too...
That cage looks impossible to escape from,
but it actually has a door in the back.
So, after the cloth covers the cage.
He goes out through the backdoor...
We didn't see him anywhere on the stage
though!
The girl assistants on the stage are the
key to the trick...
Inside, the cage. that magician probably
changed his clothes
to the ones thatthe girls are wearing in?
Order to camouflage himself
Nobody was counting how many assistants
were on re's age
so we wouldn't know whether it was 8 or 9
assistants on the stage. right?...
By walking closely with the female
assistants
he disappeared into the wing.
While people are watching the clothes
burn up. he comes to the audience seats!
Yeah.
But you thought the levitation magic was
amazing. right!?
It looked like he was really flying!
I didn't see any wire at all...
For that, he used a bar to hold his body In
place,
and there was a crane behind the curtain
to move the bar.
The curtain can be cut lengthwise and
sideways.
The audience only believes that the
magician is being suspended by a wire
and therefore is only paying attention
to the magician up in the air.
Enough!
Both of ou stop speaking!
For God's sake. You're the ones who
wanted to know how the tricks worked...
Now . It's time for today's/last illusion...
It's just a LITTLE dangerous magic,
Escape from water"!
With both hands and feet handcuffed
>
he will try to escape from this aquarium
which is sealed with a chain.
Please give a big applause \ If ho makes
it through!
Axel dig) ks Wot ))
Hasn't this been too long?
Hey. Ran...It's been
almost 10 minutes since he went into the
water, right?
Uh, yeah
Over! It's over!!
Somebody. bring an axe!
Uh, there has been a minor complication...
Please wait for a moment...
That's what the legendary magician
Harr Houdini used to do.
It's classic, man...
Yeah...It's the most common escape trick...
Let's go! Ran!
Yeah!
What!?
The 're gone... Hattori...
I saw that...
Excuse met?
You can't go in!!
Uh. excuse me.
Let me in!
Ran!-Break the aquarium with your karate!
Got it}
Heal!
Hahhhhhaaa...
Yahhhaa!
Huh?
Huh?...
Ouch...
Somehow. I made it. With my luck...
and who made this show even more 4
exciting
» my e™-
these two brave ladles...
Huh?
» al)"
Please. give them a round of applause!!
ay, man...Hattorl
Yeah, what?
We came here to watch this today huh?
I believe so
Huh...
Uh. I'm so sorry!!
Uh, I'm so sorry!!
We just thought you were gonna die.
[ido In, 410
ell I
Pin QO
Don't worry about it...
In" fact, I'm still alive partly thanks to you
Really!?
I heard you...
I heard your voices when I was half
unconscious underwater...
Your love brought me back to life
Yoah?
Did you really?
Really?
It's obviously a lie.
Ha ha.
He wastprobably hiding a pin or something
\ in his'mouth to unlock the handcuffs.
I guess he*was out of the aquarium way
before. What do you think?
Yeah, by initially showing the audience the
aquarium with the door open
and sealing that door shut with a chain.
Then obviously the audience will believe
that it's impossible to open.
But the truth is, some part of the cover has
no chain on it. And from that space
It is possible to escape...
All he needs is to wait behind the curtain
until the audience starts to worry
As the staff goes berserk, he pours water
over his head and shows up...
Now, the great breathtaking escape illusion
Is done!
Well. well, it was great, Hoshikawa.
Uri Vpn
I was just thinking. about you and I.
Doing some collaborative performance?
What do you think 7?
Sure... Ifat's ok with you...
O@h! That would be a great help
since you're a popular man now...
Really.
Really,
would you mind if I Joined you guys?
We should make clear
which one of us three is the true heir of
our sensei, Mr Masakage...
Mr. Masakage
He was a mysterious magician whe used
to be on=TV and stage
but disappeared all of 1 suddon abeut
10 years ago
I heard he's still alive somewhere...
Mr. MasEkage.
I never knew these three people were
Mr. Masakages -pupils...
Oh. eahl
If we wanna perform together,
then why don't we get Kazumi Sanada
since he's as popular as Hoshikawa,
and name the event "Dream Collaboration
of the Four Magic Kings"
Kazumi Sanada?
\whottkelnO™t tanlimcly
I don't know if he'd be up for it though...
3! p-
True
We actually never met him before although
we were in the same field.
Hey Ran, you've met this Kazumi Sanada
guy before. right?
Uh, yeah...
First, it was when Sonoko invited me at the
cruise part
for the Suzuki Zaibatsu's 60 anniversary.
Kid sent us a letter
So for the entertainment at the party,
Sonoko's mother hired Mr.Sanada
to disguise as Kid
I met him\for the second time:when
Motoyasu Tsukumo...
A geniusymagician's wife asked my dad to
Investigate the cause:of his death...
Mr. TisiKumo had three pupils and
Mr. Sanada was one of:them...
Reqlly, you never know who's connected
to who. huh.
Then, we should ask this lady to get in
touch! with Sanada.
Now, I think we should head to sensei's
house and talk.
How about you guys?
We could show you a simple magic show
Wffter dinner of you like
0 Ohgnro you sorious
Can we do that?
But why his house?
For God's sake, have you forgotten?
Today is the day sensei disappeared
Oe oo
He may just decide to return home today
you know?
Ts 40
Oh, hello there!
Dim-jib it Tenko and Heshlkawa back there?
Hello .
Long time no see!
It's been quite a while. I guess it's been
what. 10 years?
Oh, sorry. who are those people?
They're our special guests tonight
Nice to you meet you!
Alright, then I guess I should go and
get some more grocernies: for tonight...
Oh no, don't...
We thought $0. so
Herel
I see. So you've been visiting here the
same date every year.
Yes. in anticipation that sensei might just
come back
Unfortunately. we ve heard nothing from
him these past 10 years
FY S ay
Well. this brings back memories. eh...
Yeah. we used to live here together
and went through senses intensive
training together...
Well, Hoshikawa, even before my husband
decided to have pupils
I think you used to stop by here, right?
Then, Mr. Hoshikawa is his first pupil
It doesn't even matter who's first and
who's last
What matters is, who s surpasses sense
as a magician
Hey. hey. Tenko...
If we're really going to do a show
together!...
The highlight of my magic will be
Witch Reborn"!
What?
Um gonna place a huge cross in the middle
of the alidience
and tie myself to it.
I'll have the audience fire il up, and before
the cross burns out
I'll vanish...
Next time you see me as when I emerge out
of the ashes...
What do you think?
It's breathtaking and exciting. isn't it?
Yeah
Well, I should start preparing dinner now...
Ok. let us help you then. Yeah?
Sure!
I think I'll look around the.house
since it's been a while
That's a good idea
Actually,
I'm gonna go to my room and take a nap.
I had to wake up early this morning.
TW mm,
I had to wake up early this morning
I had to wake up early this morning.
Alright.
We'll call you when dinner. is ready.
Hey. Hattori...
Hey, Hatter:
Ha rR GREECE) We climes «200,
didn't she?
She did...
Whit???
You want me to call theymngician,
azumi Se'! ad'é! >
I can't do that!
I don't even know his phone number!
True WC only met him twice
0 x WR Nnngorer x0, LON 6
Hey Ran, what the hell are you new!
I'm starving to death!
Sorry dad, I think well be late.
Whit GOR $00 OB ff (POI?
Mo ,
2, B irs) yon) boll) oof
Sorry ?
Huh!? What?
Hey! Hello!
) Just can't hendlo tile We o = Rory
What! ?
Where is Mrs. Masakage
She went out to get some seasoning
because we ran out.\
and although it's been quite a while,
she still hasn't come back.
I was gonnafask the boys for a help. but...
Man. can't do this...
This knife ism 11 as sharp
as Mm deductions are
Well
IN CO 1e8IveNness 1S a necessary ac or
wher it comes to &ductions...
Phow, I guoss we did alright...
I guess I made you two do all the work...
"In SO sorry...
UT PS AR
Right?...
Yeah.
How's it coming
imm{? Wow! It looks yummy...
Hey. where're your friends?
They're treating their wound in the kitchen.
\AAnx=%
It seems one of them cut their finger
with the knife...
Ok. I'll go and wake'Handa up.
I think he's In the room*way In the back of
the first floor. where He usually is...
Hoshikawa,
would you please go and, get Tenko?
Sure... ok.
She's most probably in that room
that)! think she's in?
Which room?
Oh. I mean Mr. Masakage's room
There're pictures and instruments
for old magic tricks there.
There are many memorable objects
in that room.
Hat!?
Old magic tricks?
Would you like to take a look?
Why not
Mr. Masakage designed
and built this house himself
I see
His room is on the second floor
It's a narrow hallway .
It's Kinda dark and scary too...
That door on the right is sensel's room...
Maybe the light bulb burned out...
Oh no
What is it?
A blackout?
Where's the breaker?
I guess It's not in this room.
Hi. Mrs. Masakage. Where's the breaker?
It's In thesanext room. In the bathroom.
Ok: I found it.
Ah, Ah
Co : »
Hattori!
Yeghl.
What is it!1? What's*goingion!?
Original Comic hooks By.
GOSIHHOA AMA
ICHIHI . U
Background«Music.
KATSUO ONO
; Character Designs By.
MAS TOM SUDO
[uh/mm 1mm
StorysEditor.
JUNIGHI TTDKA
StoryaEditor.
Scripts By
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
+ KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNTCHI-MIYASH Ta
YUICATHIGURE /
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
WHIROTOSHI TAKATANI
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Bircalor
YUKIHIROQ SHIBUIANI
Arf Director,
Directors Of Photography
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBUL TIORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Director.
KATSUYOSHIT KOBAYASHI
{ Chicf Director
WY) IK@ PAVIA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, TD
In AssSoOGIalron: with»
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPO ATION
DZTECTIYVE CORY
CONTE VY ANI TIO GARE KAN TA TRI
AM i23esils Jtesyrsed
What the heck is this...
Ell me. what is this room?...
Our master
Mr. Masakage traveled
all around the world.
Those are the documents on magic
that he collected.
This must be it.
This is the Christmas tree magic.
Screw you. man!
Don't you call me kid. you.goddamn brat!
This picture...
Hmm?)
A picture of his three young pupils...
Maybe this is...
Next~-Conan.
(Conan and Heiji's
Deduction "Magic (Part 11)"