JENS = = 0 GURY HOLE Jin = = off
They can be tho culprit or the actor
They can be the culprit or tho actor
A killing ocgurs In
a magician's huse Magic.
Ghmmiciivorrtracvfih
Conan and He) solve {, both together!
Me gees through the one and only truth
Awchild in appearance
with the, I. Q. of an adult,
No casc Is loft unsolved with
Detective Conan
Aftor going through somo incident
it Dogo Hoshikawa's magic show,
We were invited to Mr. Masakage,
a legendary Magician Ss house.
Also,
It happened to be the day
Mr. MasakageSuddenly disappeared
it happened to be the day
r. MasakageSuddenly disappeared
it happened tobe the day
Mr. MasakageSuddenly disappeared
10 ears ago
We were at Mr Masaknange's house
with his pupils
If we're really going to do the show together
the highlight of my magic will be
Witch Reborn"!
What?
MM gonna place a huge cross
1 the middle of the audience
and tie myself to it.
I'll have the audience fire it up.
And before the cross burns out.
I'll vanish...
Next tame you see me as when
I emerge out of the ash...
Maybe the light bulb is burned out...
Ok: I found it.
Br ANA
Conan and Heiji's Deduction Magic!(Part Il)
Oh god. What was that scream?
Was that the second floor!?
What's wrong!?
Tenko's in trouble!
She's bleeding from her head.
Shes not moving!
Are ou serious!?
Her body's a ready cold...
Oh no...
Tenko!
Ohm god...
It looks like it's been more than 30 minutes
since she died...
So. you two found her?
Well,
Mr. Hoshikawa was with us too.
{Hepjust went to call the police and
ambulance
in that room...
Will you please hurry!
Ok? Please hurry!
Yeah.
Fin
Hey Hattori. look...
The window Is open
If the murderer did jump out the window
and into the SAT bbery
they could've easily escaped from the
rear gate...
Hell. com over here)!
Himm!?
What-'is It'?
You gotta€8ee what happened to
the room next Lo the one
Tenko was found lying on the floor!
What! 2?
What is
Handa. what is this room?...
Ohrit's our sensei,
Oh its our sensei
Masakage's reference room where
he kept the documents on magic
that he collected from all over the world...
Is there anything~th t's really important
in this room ?
No...
It's mostly clippings from books
Nd magazines that
and magazines that
you can find in any bookstore
He uscce to show us those clippings.
If any
it wouldebe the file whic even
I wasn't allowed to see...
It"is Mr. Masakage's notes on
all the gimmicks about his original tricks.
E call it Masakage's notes" .
Masakage's notes
Hey. look who's here.
Hey. look who's here
Cl Jest thiol extolling
Cos OE TO SOO
a magic show today
I feel hke watching some miracles
or whatever
because this stupid girl said...
Wo ab
Don't you call mo stupid
you stupid!
ANAM, (ioe [ved det eho ex 0
MN] - dhuon) 1  E1 Bu! ,
Alright. So why were you in this house?
We met three magicians at the magic show
and they invited us to their master's house.
which is here And then
ne of them happened to
be murdered b somebod
YX Dooy
the lady who was murdered
was Also a magician. 2
Her name 1s Tenko Hymemia,
She was pretty famous outside Japan.
We were just planningsto
have a collaboration magie, show
all the three of us together
But I never thought
it was gonna be like this...
Ok. So who found her first?
Ne em TO - = ay
Me. and
those ladiesover there...
Dinner was ready
so we went to call, enko...
This Is her sensei's room.
E thought she might be here...
When we came up here,
there was nothingilin the hallway: at first
But when ll turned on the light
since: it. was dark
the breaker went down
and after the light turned back on...
Tenko was lying at the end of this hallway,
just over there...
I see...
The fact that this hallway was dark
was part of this homicide plan
I think.
The Killer loosened!
The light bulb beforehand...
SH ce =z=oee XAuX 3 Wnxs [MINA
he/she will turn on the light *
and cause a blackout.
I found out some work was done on this
Ch GO Ao or Yee Clie
Beside the dead body is the reference
room where the important file was stored.
And there is no window in that room
which people can go in and out of
One more thing,
the window In Mr. Masakage's room
was left open...
Considereing all this, it is likely that
the person manipulated the switeh
so he/she can safely stew!
Masakage's notes and runway.
To runaway.
That's right...
the breaker has goes down...
Somebody has to reset the breaker on the
first floor. right?
While somebody is downstairs,
the murderer:jumps out of the window
of Mr. Masakage's room and runs away...
But it didn't go like the murdercr planned.
RX Wrin=A1%) in An 0 ews
there's usually only one woman living
along
But today. she had seven guests.
Nog} tlh) lity Do
Tenko cameo into the reference room
uel OR hoe hot
an I saw the murderer. so he/she had to
Altar that
the murderer went back. to searching-for
Masakage:s notes injpanic.
But then. Kazuh1 and the others came up
to call for Tenko.¥
Fortunately for him, this time the breaker
had gone down.
So he put Tenko's dead body in the
hallway and ran away...
fies dest)
11)-
Bec1use the people were struck with the
dead victim.
There was a plenty of time 0 run away
LANL
mafia-Ml)
Loo wbdd- bib
I see.
Well.
If you think logicnlly it seems that an
outsider committed this crime.
Nf eddie Eke) 8 Oe Haye
there 1s one possible suspect among us.
Among us
It's the person who caused the blackout.
It is. Mr nshlkawa!
What?
You were here during the blackout
It wasn't that hard for you to move Tenko
from the reference room to the hallway
then to go back to where the girls were
before the lights turned back on. right?
That's impossible! I think.
Right?
Yeah,...
Because
We were holding Mr. Hoshikawa
while the power was out.
Holding him!?
Gosh!
Why?
What do you-mean why
Because it was-dark and scary...
Are you sure
it was this guy?
Yes I am!
I was
holding Mr. Hoshikawa's arm like this...
nd I was holding.Kasuha hike this...
See? Mr. Hoshikawa couldn~t do it!
It's just like the case of Doctor Nude
isn't it. Conan!?
Isn't it. Conan!?
Isn't it. Con:an!?
Yeah...
Talk about nuts!
Mean it was just 1 mere blackout,
and god you're not a kid anymore. either!
Ell Hew. They're gels
They couldn't help it
Huh!? What's with you?!
By the way,
Wor WR YO) ehiding) 2) Talker wit
I was taking a nap in the reem
right below thé bookroom.
I went mm ms roam to wake him up
That was when the power went out.
Ok, then there's no way
you guys murdercd the vietim.
0, RUIN
that the murderer was-an outsider.
Anyway, could you tell us
more about that important file?
It's my husband, Mr. Masak1gc's notes
and it is filled ideas on his original tricks.
Oh! I rcmomber
I used to watch Mr Masakago's
Show on 'V when I was a kid!
His magic included beautifu assistants
and fantastic illusions!
God. I still remember it! Ha ha ha...
Actually. I was his assistant.
(OANN@ AAO SAO (XXX Vv
Then, where 1s he now?
Somebody told me ho disappeared...
Oh. Is that true?
cs. It was teday 10 years ago...
He used to go on outings suddenly
without notice
So I wasn't really wor red at first.
Half a year past but he nover came back.
Hoshikawa, Handa and Taonko were living
here. since they were live-in students
But they left and became independent.
So this 1s actually our reunion
for the first time ing10 years.
So you're the one who called everybody...
Actually...
It was me...
I told them to coma hero
mii he
SO that we oculd discuss
the collaborative magic show together.
Well, I used to come hereon thissd to,
every year
and stay to cat Mrs. Masakage's meal
Alnght. Wns there anybody
who hated or held a grudge on
Mr. Masakage...?
Huh?
According to Hatteri's deduction,
Ws likely that the murderer know
that Mrs. Masakage is living alone.
As well as being knowledgeable about
the layout of the room and such...
as well as being knowledgeable about
Mr. Masakage's notes would've been
worth quite a price. I would figure...
Would somebody who would've been
interested in getting 1 hold of it,
ever have come by here?
But sensei is not the kind of person
anyone would want to
hold a grudge agaist...
Actually.
There was a man...
Who visited here many times, ww
saying that he wanted to see my husband...
I just thought he was one of his fans,
sO. let him in.
But as soon as he went
Into my husband's room...
He started yelling.
Where are you? Come out
You crook! You stole my-trick!
Hey, Handa, I told you 1bout
WU DO, AAR FR
Uh. yes. I thik you did.
What did the man look like?
IR WES I \Lk=h 3 EX JO
I don't really remember how he looked.
The layout of the hwuse seems to have
changed a bit after that incident tough...
Although It could just be my imagination.
Thelayout has changed...?
Ran. what's wrong?
Uh. no. it's nothing.
I just thought that something's changed
before and after Tenko was murdered.
But I don't know what it is
Oh, you think so too?
What? You too?
Yeah. but I don't know what it is either...
Maybho I should call Shinich
and ask him what it is.
I thought his,number was unlisted?
Yeah. but he finally gave itto me!
Shoots!! I didn't turn it off!!
Where's it! Whereis it!
Ok, then call him and. ask
Kudo is a gen us!
If you tell him about this case.
He'll probably say that,
he's gonna solve it with Heiji.
>Orry. Ran
Erik
I'm going to keep this
cell phone untii*we crack the case...
VV ht!
H. Ho!
What!
H. Heiji!!
He Co
You can't do that.
Hey!Hem!
Give it back to hor!
Ok. Now, let's hear
the truth behind this murder.
Right. Mr. Genius?
What do you mean. truth
You said it a while ago.
You lair! I know you got something!
Something that's bugging you...
Uh. yeah. Just a little...
First of all, why did the murderer
choose today of all the other days...
Yeah Today is the day Mr Masakage
disappe red 10 ears ago .
If the murderer was familar with the
mside detals of this housed,
that person should've been aware that
Mrs. Masakago would not be
none today boa-muse
Mr. Hand had been
siting her every year...
Secondly why can't we,find the splattered
blood. of the victim. Tenko anywhere...
If my deduction is correct.
She must've been murdered n the
hallway or the reference room,
but there's no blood
whatsoever in these places...
You're right...
Destruction of evidence seems
too well-prepared
for a murder that happened aceidentally...
Yeah. .-
We should be able-to find blood
hoetwoeen the tiles on tho floor or
in between the spaces of the wooden pillar
And thirdly.
Ou mean there's some more?
Kasuha.
What?
I don't know what it 1s.
But something's bugging me.
Ha ha
You know, she's acting frivolous...
Lighthearted and all that
It just irritates me
I can't concentrate on my deduction...
Why is it?
Wi rd
HT...
Huh?
Why 1~t?
Look, I don't think it's about her just being
frivolous or lighthearted.
It's more than her just being frivolous and
Iighthearted WITH another guy
don't you think?
Oh yeah!
You're right! That must be it!
How did you know, Kudo!
Huh?
What?
K. Kudo!?
Hattori!
What's wrong with you!
Oops
Uh no. Dud,
I mean! It's the dude
That dude on TV was saying
the temperature went up to 39 degrees
yesterday afternoon
It was hot. wasn't it?
Oh eah,
I remember I saw something like
that on TV at the airport this morning.
Alright So. why am I feeling irritated?
Don't you know?
Kudo...?
Hattori...
You knowswhat...
Cause you're a kid...
Scre ou. man!
I fnanot letting a brat call mesa Kid you brat!
Haiji.
What're you getting all upset
over a child for!
Poor Conan.
What do you mean poor Conan!
He's the one who started talking nonsense!
Oh. come on ourre he one.
Besides your husband's pupils,
Mr. Hoshikaw: and Mr. Hand:
were there any other magician fiends
of your husganc who visited you?
Well...
10 ea s ago
until My husband disappeared,
many people had been visiting this house
so ll can't really tcll who was who.
Since my husband designed
and built this house.
He would even invite the people
he just met at work over too.
Wanting to show this house off...
I see .
So he designed and built this house
In fact,
he showed them not only this house.
LT Ta,
but also the tricks that
mu d be done only in this house.
Therefore, even more people came here
after hearing about it...
The Christmas tree magic was
a really popular one.
Especially during tho Christmas season,
\ OU Know
Hmm? ls anything wrong?
In a» 1
Sorry...
This has nothing to do
with the case. I guess...
could you tell us what kind of trick it was?
We'll
Only sense! can explain that trick...
But since he's disappeared
there's no way
we can figure out how it works
Too bad we'll never find 1 clue
whatsocver about it
The man that you mentioned
visited you 5 years ago.
Could you tell us more in detail about him?
If he really snd that your husband
Mr Masakage stole his trick?
Then it is probable that ho ronlly wanted Lo
ace the Masakaaqu notes
PX IORERU CO) WARCRT ES WANK
Mr. Masaki1ge kept his ideas
regarding the magic tricks he performed.
If we assume that the murderer sneaked
Into this house to steal Masakage's notes.
And silenced Tenko.
Since she saw that person searching for
the notes in the reference room...
It's plausible to think that this man who
visited yous years ago is the killer.
His height or
something characteristic about his face
Anything. Anything you can remember,
Mrs. Masakage.
Yeah. I'm trying but I can't...
Do you remember whether
he was Japanese or not, right?
yeah,-
He was speaking fluent Japanese
and his hair was black...
I don't know what kind of hnir style he had
since he was wearing a hat...
Also.
RO REC) CU WEED on 619)
his face was covered with a beard...
So I couldn't really tell how he looked
I really can't
tHe seemed to be taller than me though...
Ummm...
A aco with 1 beard, wearing 1 ht,
and-sunglasses,.
Maybe he/was.disguising himself.
Probably...
Anyway,
have you checked whether Masakage's
notes have actually been stolen or not?
No...
But. I heard that he kept it put away
somewhere in the reference room.
I never knew exactly
where it was though...
Maybo it wasn't thoro fromitho'boginning
hecruse sense took it with him
when he disappeared...?
then,
8 XRT he DO Wo AN
Photo albums?
Thero should bo pictures since thore
wele 0 many visitors in this house. night?
Maybe we can find the man
in those pictures!
Or at lcast someone that looks like him.
LS(.P...
Mrs. Ma-akage,
where do you keepiyour photo albums ?
In my husband's room...
What is this. Mrs. WM: sakage?
his door cannot b0 opened completely
Oh that
My husband wanted to make his reem big
so he narrowed the hallway
He must hate a small rooms...
He was a great magician,
but certainly not a great architect...
Irsee that...
Yo. Kudo...
Yeah...
What are you guys doing there
You're net coming in?
Uh ..Yeah. Ha ha...
How is it, Mrs. Masakage .
Did you find anybody-that
Iooks like the man you met 5 years ago?
INOHINTINYE
You sure have a lot of pictures,
Mrs. Masakage...
Hey.Hem
I think it's impossible 10 find the picture of
theaman from a nong these p ctures
don't you?
Don't you?
Yes we can!
Because what we are looking for is...
Ifofindflfl
moms Om Ovomm 'on mMOmom ohm me
So. this is the Christmas tree magic. huh
Look, the tree is standing
at the end of the hallway.
That's actually where
Tenko was lying on the floor, right?
There must be something behind it.
Hey! Look at! this. Kudo
This picture.
Huh? A picture of the three young pupils
Maybe this is.
She must be hiding something...
What? What is it? What's going on?
Oh, It's that...
There.
The thing on the ceiling.
Isn't that a screen for a projector?
What about it...?
People usually put that kind of screen
on the wall, right?
Cause they don't wanna watch it too close?
It's better to watch it that way
But it's not like that here.
See? It's so tar from the wall
Dont ou think it's strange?
You know what. you're right. It is strange...
It's no ordinary scroen, actually
It Is cut so that people can go through it...
MN Ay
k alan aw
You guys have probably seen it.
You know the trick.
When a real person comes
out of the screen that you're watching!
Yeah I know. I've seen it before!
We used that screen for practice
That's why it's not on the wall.
Alll /
was sucra ong 'me ago. washes I+
You used to come here
and practice together
But now. you're on your own.
This room is no longer in use...
we couldn't have become successful hike
we are right now. seriously.
ATH \ New
You know. every magic has a gimmick
Lg W Wath
thorc 1s no exception
And that's why we practice.
There. iS no exce tion...
We practice practice. practice.
Until we can do the trick so that
nobody can recognize how it works.
Man... Who would think that
there's a cut on that screen?
Never crossed my mind...
They used to come to-this room
everyday back then.
They used to check on when
they should come out of the screen and
Tried to avoid
unnecessary shadow on the screen
Shadow!
Yes. the shadow!
Oh yeah
It was the shadow of the vase
It looked different!
The shadow of the vase
The moonlight was shining
on the vase from behind.
So we couldn' see the patterns on it...
But after the blackout,
when we found Tenko's dead body
the moonlight was shining
on the vase from the side
SO we could see the patterns!
It doesn't make sense!
Here's no way the moon moves that fast)!
The shadow. of the vase...
Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
GOSHOMOYAMA
Producers.
MIHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YCSHIDRA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
SGwripts By.
I A-HIWA
> . _ ~ > Tr ju
ALAIIN/ARI NUJU/GT TI
Y I HI HIGURE
Animation Directors.
MAS TOMO SUDO
HIRGWTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
AISUSHI AONO
AKTOYKAWAMURA
TAKASHI W000
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUIANI
Directors Of Photoeraphy.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOWSY, 1
TAKAHISA OWAGA
Recording Direct
KAISUYOSHI KQBAYA NI
Editor.
1 NUIVITTIOU VIN/ALT/N
Editor:
TERUMITSU OKADA
Editon .
IERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJI KC DAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT TD
w In a3socration with
YOMIURI-TEI FGASTINC
CORPORATION
Dr JaLaliV) st
\ Capt MA 1a VRE Yd MA
The moonlight...
The vase
Then. the murderer is an outsider...
But why did she lie?...
Because she figured out who it was...
From the wny
Tenko's dead body was placed...
and from the way we found her
What!?
What is it?
There's nothing
What the!
It vanished?
Next Conan.
Conan and Heiji's, Deduction Magic
(Partulll)