Stars are for some reason attractive
They can be the culprit or the actor
Today's story 15
the finale of the magic case.
Solve the miraculous trick
With Conan and Heiji!
With Conan ghd Helji
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the 1. Q. of an adult
Nb ctwsc) us, left unsolved Wllh
Dotective Conan
Due to popular magician
Dougo Hoshikawa's show,
Dougo Hoshikawa's show
We got invited to the legendary magician,
Mr. Masakage's
It has been,
Exactly-10 years since the day
Mr. Masakage suddenly disappeared
The pupils m1agicinns
have gotten toycther there
Ianko Himomiya among thom
Tenko Himemiya among them
Was discovered ded
in the hallway on the 2nd floor!
More than 30 minutes
have passed since she died...
Did you find her yourselves?
No. Hoshikawa was also here with us...
What the.
What is it? This room is...
Our Master.
His is the storage room
for the magic Mr. Masakage gathered
from around the world...
Ifoflndfifl
So. this Is the Christmas tree magic
What's more,
the tree is where Ms. Tenko's body was
found at the end of the hallway...
Something's suspicious
Look at this Kudo.
his picturo.
What? The pictures of\the 3 pupils
when they were\young...
This might be...
hats right. the shadow!
That's right. that's right
the shadow; of the vase us wrong!
The shadow of the vase?
First the moonlight is directly from tho back
the design of the vase could not be seen...
After the b ackout.
When we found Ms. Tenko's body.
The moonlight was from the side
so we could see the design of the vase!
Huh!? The moon can't move that fast!
The shadow of the vase...
it) 1h)
Conan and Heiji's
Deduction Magic Solution(Part Ill)"
Moonlight...
the vase
What's happening?
That's not possible. that doesn't .
First the moon was covered by clouds.
So it was dark and the design
of the vase couldn't be see
the cloud disappeared during "the blackout
and so the design could:now.be seen?
If\ ou say so...
It may be so...
And then?
Didn't you hear the culprit run away or
voices during the blackout
It may have been so
but the lights suddenly turned off
and we were, screaming so...
Mr. Hoshikawa was telling us
in a soothing voice to'calm down...
Soothing voice?
It's alright!
He repeated I'm with you so it's alright.
He really seemed so reliable!
Uh huh
well... good for you .
Aw, cmon!
Whom WN
Mr. Handa 1s said to have been
toking a nap during the blackout
please lead us to your room...
INN \\
Um. sure
Kazuha. you stay with that lady there!
Whaaaaat! Why?
You annoy me when you're around...
What's that supposed to mean?
Maybe its because
Maybe he's burning with jealousy
Willa of?
Heyes not red because of the sunburn
Um. ah... I don't mean that
This as tho room Mr. Hwnda used wtmrm
you were still Mr Masakage's pupils ~
ne DOC Bn RAVE 3 Uke] (nO)
was disposed of when Mr. Handa left
d7... Where were you and Mr. Han
when there was a blackout... '2
When I opened the door, he was lying
down on the sofa.
And was.-standing still for about one minute
of the blackout
I told her it wouldn't be a good idea to
move around in the dark...
Then who reset the breaker?
I did.
Me and this kid was right by the breaker
when it was thrown.
This room definitely is right under the data
storage room...
It's impossible to climb out from that
(small window
Thought there might be some tricks to the
house since a magician built it...
Umph...
Umphe
there seems to be no elevators to carry
Ms. Tenkds body to t-he 2nd floor...
7 sow Xe] bukit, (REIN GAS Bio folks 60010
during the blackout,
it would be impossible to commit the
crime...
When Ms. Tenko's body was found,
Mr. Hoshikawa who was the closest
was being clung onto by Kazuha
couldn't have put the body thcro.
Then he creme must have been
committed by someone from outside...
Inspector Megure!
Huh? What is it?
When I investigated the shrubbery,.
hfound some broken branches and
footprints all around
that summed to have boon smoothud out
shrubbery 18 right under
1AM AS ak THIS ToS...
Hattori! Just like you said
The culprit was hiding in the storage room
threw the breaker and left the body and
went into Mr. Masakage's room
Leaped from the window and used the
shrubbery as cushion.
He seems toghave escaped from the
backdoor...
OK! Ask around the neighborhood If
INyonce has seen a suspicious figure
Yes, sir
If 1's an outsider
The rest . should be left in the hands of
the police
Our role .
Is finished...
Wham. 2
Goal
I 868. .
So that's it...
Wha. what!?
Do you 'know who did it! ?
Na SE § Hn
culprit who boat Ms. Tonko to doath,
uscd this as a trick
to cover up the crime...
rick?
1 og PE ft oh
SO let ma borrow your tall detective Wind
fat detective
NEED NS ARES (ERE AVN a th
Neel TER Co CIDA
I'll let you borrow themO¥but what arc you
planning to do?
U don't mean to use them ns
guinea pig in a dangerous trick...
No need to worry!
I understand you being worried
{ebout our men
H. hey Hatton. are you OK?
H. he's OK!
Bring everyone to where Ms. Tenko's body
was found
the hallway on the 2nd floor in ten minutes!
You will be surprised too!
Is what Brother Heiji was.saying! Right?
Uh. yeah
I'm counting on you... Hattori.
R.right!'" I'll get Takagi and Chiba to come
to this room.
Will Mr. Handa "nd Mrs. Mann, please go
(WL WY.
back to your rooms and wait
Get Mr. Hoshikawa too...
Y.yes...then I'll go to the living room...
Hey. Kudo
What?
I think I got it
I think I got It
[Fue 2 UNO WR LO (BC)
everyone up...
No'? not that!
I'm not talking about the case...
I'm talking about why there was something
about Kazuha that was annoying me!
Well... 9.0004 for you. .
[REC Elknaxox=gd 00) nalkntr Xa
Sorry to have kept you waiting...
Then, can you all step up on the
stage where I will unravel the mystery
of course, with tho:culprit
whovs among us...
Laud)?
I he killer is
AMONG Us?
But Hattori!
YOu Just ect I
the culprit who killed Ms. Tenko was In
outsider!
The intruder's target was
In the storage room on the 2nd floor
down the hall to the right.
Mr. Masakagc's magic book!
And Ms. Tenko ran into him when he
was looking for the book.
And was killed.
And afterwards, Mr. Hoshikawa, Kazuha,
Ran came in so
after the blackout, put Ms. Tenko's body
at the end of the hallway
went into Mr. Masakage's room down the
hall to the left
And escaped from the window.
There were works on the hallway switch to
make it look like a blackout...
There ware works on the hallway switch to
fnlfii U ilk In I? ilk) e1 Ukir»! um
ng) @e) [Oe oOUke bars [RE XC) EX]
1 m I111" x m) [in no nu Inn (ik xwnxfl fimao
Mr. Hoshikawa was being clung/onto by
Kazuha and Ran and couldn't move.
If it wasn't an outsider.
How would someone among the three
put Ms. Tenko's body over there?
Also Mrs. Manri, you said that,
Quelalion 3 ORION
who called Mr. Masakage,
WG NUSOONC, [NOY
visited 5 years ago.
If there's anyone to be suspicious 1bout,
wouldn't it be him?
If there's anyone to be suspicious about,
BE) fnein Ane WARE) nee / Winer yy,
didn't he have a habit or something?
Huh? H... habit...
I don't know...there might have been,
but it's been 5 years.
Hmmm. for example.
Push ng up the middle of his sunglasses
ith his left hand little finger .
Right, right! That habit...
What?
Why does Heiji know?
I don't know but I know...
that what Mrs. Manri is saying is...
the person in the very right of this picture.
The man with 1 hat, sunglasses, and 1
nmwpnilvtsfino flea m» 001Of!
Is. Isn't it...
Mr. Handa when he was young?
That's right
Mr. Handa pushed up the middle of his
sunglasses with his left hand little finger...
Then, the suspicious Man Mrs. Mann met
5 years ago was Mr. Handa ?
Stupid!
If that-rm an was Mr. Hand who was hiving
in this house as Mr. Masakage's pupil
Mrs. Manri would've recognized him!?
Oh. that's true...
Well. that's to say...
when people say things that's not true but
actually sounds like it's true.
They usually visualize someone they
know in their heads!
It would be bothersome If things don't
add up later on...
And that someone is...
Is Mr. Handa when he was young!
I see...if that man's habit
ANTI
Is just like Mr. Handa's
Mrs. Mann will-have 0 problem
recognizing it, so it will not bc suspected...
But.
Why lie like that...
She realized who the culprit was...
from where Ms. lenkaers body lay...
and from the state the body was found...
Mr Hoshikawa...
t-hut you are t-ho murdOrOr!!
Then Mrs. Mann, you covered up for
Mr Hoshikawa
N.no that can't be true!
When Mr. Hoshikawa found Ms. Tcenke.
I was clinging on to him
so he wasn't able to move.
That's why I'm going to unravel that
mystery right now!!
Look at this. this hallway...
It's the same as last time. right?
Uh...yes. justilike'this
It was poorly lit but I noticed thoro was
nothing at the end of the hallway...
WwW .well at that time...
I was holding on to Mr. Hoshikawa's arm
Iike this!
S.stupid! You're too c ose!
So you won't play any tricks on me!
So behave!
Hey...
Hey. so hurry up and unravel the mystery!
WwW. when Mr Hoshikawn pressed this
switch...
you said it blacked out
If it blacked out. the breaker...
Conan!?
Since when were'you there?
How did you...
I was here all the time
Don't lie to me!
When it got dark,
You came out of the storage room,
didn't ou?
I was here in this storage room
the whole time
but the door didn't open I
B.but I didn'ttsee Conan...
Huh? What?
What is it. Conan
Huh?
Disappeared?
We didn't disappear!
Conan?
Like this...
Brother Heiji just moved Mr. Masakage's
room
door like this...
during, the blackout...
Just like Mr. Hoshikawa did...
Rh... that can't be true!
Ah!!
Th this is...
Isn't it similar? This room...
Iooks just like the end of the hallway...
The door of the storage room is
that closet...
The right wall is this screen!
And...
And.
The small window at the
end of the hallway is...
The big window hidden by this sideboard...
Ws = Om, Om CF Bales Wks leges
room that can be scen.
If behind Mr. Masakage's room door 18
the mirror...
You can tell already. right?
Before the blackout what Kazuha saw
The roomyseen as reflected in the mirror
behind the door!
Then, the body was at the end of the
hallway from the very beginning...?
Ah. .so during the blackout
Mr Pl loshik yw shut the mirror door
and showed it!
But when we centered the room, there was
no Mirror in back of the door...
That's right, that's right! There was ne extra
door at all!
That's right, that's right! There was no extra
Conan?
This door is some door
move the mirror by the knob and put the
door together...
And I becomes one door
Some trick!
You noticed the trick because the door was
too thick
and the line down the center, right?
Uh huh...
and also
because of the uncomfortabl: feeling
Kasuha and that Indy was talking about!
Huh?
You were saying.
Before and after Ms Tank body was
found,
the shadow of the vase was different
I was convinced as I recalled that...
before and after Ms. Tenko's body was
found.
It must have been a different place where
the moon light was cast differently.
But this house is a convenient house for
tricks...
Of course...
this door, room, hallway...
Mr Masakage made everything in order to
play this trick...
What! ?
Bring the guests to this hallway...
When he turns off the light closes the door.
And shows the Christmas tree at the
end of the hall
and surprises everyone with the magic.
So that's it!
No w\ Wy
That's"why Mrs. Manri knew that
Mr. Hoshikawa
was the culprit from the beginning.
Cr Ww\ \ \\
But, wasn't it you who wanted to come here
Mr. Handa...?
\\\\
Mr. Hoshikawa didn't intend te kill. His
intent to Kill probably developed
when Ms. TenkoO said she was going to do
the trick "Witch Reborn in the next show...
No...
Actually It's
The Resurrection of the! Dev I'...
the titlovof the magic
Mr Masakage:-thought of...
Huh?
The same stage setup and performance...
I realized right away
that she looked at
Mr Masakage s trick book
and was going to copy it...
1 he Mogic that had been sealed because
It was too dangerous.
That miracle magic
But, she was just going to steal the
master's trick...
She)d id nxtiknewWAtha™
everyone, in other words. wo discussed
and decided not to do that magic...
Because it was before she became my
husband's pupil
Mrs Mann covered up for me-when she
said the book was in the storage room...
Master always carried the book around...
but one day ten, ears ago. he misplaced
the trick book
but one day ten years ago, he misplaced
and said he was going to go look for
it but never came back...
I thought if was strange for her to be able
to look at the book
so I celled her to the teacher's room
ind confronted her...
That's right. I stole it...
I am clever with my hands by profession...
I was going to return it the teacher
when he returned
but I didn't think he would be so shocked
to disappear from everyone.
But...
the teacher who was always telhng us to
surpass him
didn't realize that he was betrayed...
It was probably his time to quit...
As a magician...
Well, if I perform Mr. Masakage's not yet
performed magic all over the world...
The master will be happy from under the
sod don't you think?
Th that's why you killed her?
Uh huh. my mind went into total panic
and when I snapped back to myself,
she was all bloody lying in front of me...
I recalled the master's
Christmas tree magic...
and used that to make at look lake an
outsider had killed her...
Then you broke the branches in the
s rubbery. and erased the footprints...
Yeas...
Probably, the weapon was the vase in
Masakage's room
There was blood on the base of the vase...
and maybe a few drops of blood got on
Mr. lioshikawa's black clothes...
Uh huh. the evidence is all over the place
I failed as a magician...
You're a failure even If you're not a
magician!
Brace yourse
Unlike magic, your charge will not
disappear eas ly
Original Comic Books By.
(tOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MIC HIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITOYY SH IPRA
Backoround Music
Ghmracter Designs By.
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI HHOKA
Saripls- By.
I KASHIWALI
Animation Dircctors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUONOOCAWARA
AISU- HI. AONO
Kl + KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
TAKASHI NOMUR
HIRONOBU HORI +11
YAKAHISA OWA
Recording Direct
KAISUYOSHI KQBAYASHI
Ldiltor .
Editor N
IERUMIISU OKADA
Lrlllfor.
['RUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENT KODAMA
Produced By
TM. ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
in association with '%
YOMIURI TELEGCASTING
CORPORATION
1): JATIN 1 eel A
CONTI (OVYAATN TB "VAT Re O YI IAIN.
Wvrsud
Wow. what can you expat of Yiattori!
It was excellent deduction!
You are no less than Kudo
maybe even more!
Inspector. you think sm too
What!"
By the way, brother Heiji
weren't you saying?
Huh?
That you get annoyedwhen Sister Kazuha
Is friendly with other men!
Huh!
What does that mean?
Oh. that's right! Now I know why.
Huh? What?
I...probably...think of you.
What! ?
No. no Heiji. not in front of everyone....!
As my henchman
Huh .
what-did you just say...
Henchman. my henchman!
As the boss, I would fac) good Wf you
wag your tail at someone else.
I'll lose face. right?
Hat's why was annoyed
Why should I be your henchmanl!!
Your fathers my father's henchman!
That night...l got mail from Ran
WBS. Shinichi hope you dons think of me
as~ our henchman?
Hey. hey...
Whoa
OK. stop!
Uh hum. behave yourself!
The trinvoling acting group featuring
ramac ke Ito
has come to our town to put on a show
again
Then. it was just a week ago
that the threat note was sent
over the internet.
Hmmm. something s not right
1b'!
TA AA
(alm)
» ooo
Concurrent stagessand Kidnapping!
Part 1