Stars are for some reason/attractive
They can be the culprit or the actor
The heroine ls kidnapped
Only a few hours are loft
until the curtain opens
Let's get at it. detective!
He sees through the one and only truth
A child \n appoarance
with the I @. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Détective Conan
yf 414
Boe quiet!
Freeze!
Oops
Stop there!
Thief. give up
please forgive me!
Thank you. officer!
OK! Stop there!
Everyone's pretty good!
Really!?
Especially-Conanl.
Thank you
I'm- very happ¥!.
H.hey. wait a minute the twojiofiyou
Huh!
Hahaha...
Mr. Tamanosuke
Huh?
amateurs like us'
Of course.
This 18 a special performance
different from out show
the problem is net you but...
Huh?
AREER te) Roy NY ¥ To of dally
Everyone!
You don't need a stage to rehearse!
Sorr chairman.
Range!
When do you:think we started rehcCarsing!
I'm sorry
Don't apologize so easily!
If you're not proud of your acting
quit being an actress!
I'm sor.
No. I mean. yes!
Scary. seems like a different person.
Uh uh, Genta, that's what an actor is like
impressive.
Don't youlthink Ms. Renge
Is a bit like Ran?
Huh?
(Ra 4,
Rehearsal begins!
Tamanosuke Ito.
This young director lending
the traveling theatrical troupe,
comos to our town again and performs
- 000
th AA
(BIFR)
Th RA
(RIFE)
Concurrent stage and kidnapping Part 1
Th Rh
(AIR)
Ran, hurr hurr
Tamanosuke's rehearsal will end!
But. I have to make lunch for my father
NO nA IR, ox vO hg,
he's going to fall asleep drinking. right?
Hey. Sonoko!
Sneezes
Ah, ah
Did I catch a.cold?
Or, ah... Is it?
You think the detective maniac will mind...
Huh?
1h st
DOM 000 fnllinG,
Tamanosuke looks like someone.
to Shinlchi...
I don't think so.
Oh.by the way, the tess
Taketori Story. 'Princess Kaguya. right}
Right!
And Tei that falls in love with
Princess Kaguya is Mr. Tamanosuke.
Oh. I want to be Princess Kaguyal!
Oh Sonoko
What an expensive car...
Ho is It?
This way president.
This way president
What!
-- Ay ed ry
Hey! Watch I" Excuse youl I!
Ql I wel
Huh?
I came for you Renge.
Come home with me)
I'm not going home!
I am staying right here!
RENGE!
Ohnuki!
Let's go Miss Range
Let go!
Miss Range!
: Ha on -
Huh? What!? What's It about!?
That girl...
plays Princess Kaguya .
WAR €) [naling
AMBER DY Qala AA Ree) 1)
oul?
I am 'Hanshiro Kataoka
The father of Renge Kataoka.
Huh?
Hanshiro. 7?
Kataoka...
Isn't he.
Is the founder of the Kataoka Kozern.
And is the current president
ado dle ulin.
She's a real LADY!?
Wow!
Renge, you didn't say
a word of this to anyone...
But...
that has nothing to do with this!
This has nothing to do with me
wanting to act!
That's .
By any chance Ronge.
Did you run away?
Il haven't heard from her for 6 months.
I asked Ohnuki to look for.
What a surprise.
We're not much different from you.
WO (He == do pun TeO RY HAO
be present at a parents death .
Tree...
But it's not good to worry them, I think .
Ohnuki
Right.
Let us go Miss Renge.
I don't want to! I'm not going home .
I am NOT
going home!
Miss Range!
Ohnuki!
Sorry to have troubled you.
We would like to do what is appropriate
for everyone here
I don't want anything from you
I have no business doing so.
D.director
Go home now! Renge.
Full?
Reng!
Go home once and talk things over
and then come back.
Wait a minus. director.
There won't be time
for the rehearsal and plan
The first day 'is 3 days from today.
You're right. it won't do...
But it won't do to leave things like this. ,
You're right .
Go home now. Range
Wait...
Miss Renge...
Please wait director! I...
Oh. Ran, can you come here?
Huh? OK...
Someone bring the costume
r Princess Kaguya and the props
He. . he. , come on.
Are you kidding!?
Ran is going to substitute for Miss Renge!?
No. no way!?
You're right, we need Kaguya
for the rehearsal and planning
To make it in time for the first day.
So until then?
It can't be helped
You're right...
OK. let's do the rehearsal!
Miss,
Miss Range!
Wasn't that a little cold .
Who the director?
Ou're right...
You're right...
You're wrong.
Whe eles TYlkeOn In FE jo
that she will return...
That: Wright.
So'pretty. Miss Ran
So'pretty. Miss Ran...
She's really pretty!
She should actually act out in the play!
I agree
Hey. hey.
Hmmm
I don't think that's such a 'good idea...
See.
WwW what!?
Oooh!? A love scene!
Maybe this
Miss Ran "nd Mr. Tamanosuke...
@O...
Not good "hot good.
Not good. not good.
Not good--not good.
Glad the detective maniac isn't watching,
hahaha 1
I'm watching
Hey, besides that's, why isn't it me!?
But Miss Range did not return.
But Miss Range did not rot-urn.
And the first day
of the performance arrives...
mm 76
«8 . . *
3 more hours...
We have come too far
GCE RO om Go aunt in
Without the protagonist?
Director...
What are we going to do?
I'm going to go get her
Go and get her.
Renge?
It's going to be difficult with that father...
Maybe she changed her mind
No way
what's going to happen to this play...
We will have to cancel it.
I haven't heard of a Taketori
I'm going.
Director!
Wait Mr. Tamanosuke!
Huh?
I have something to say
to Miss Renge as a substitute
Driver, please hurry!
Conan!
Hey. Takagi .offl...
Shh!
{Hey you two!
How come you're here!?
Father... O
Takagi.
There's nO knowing
where the culprit could be watching
so I had to let them in...
culprit?
It's you...
What do you want?ta
There's only one thing!
Where is she .
Where's Renge >
was In ing
she is at your place
what?
I don't KNOW Where she is since last night.
She said she was going shopping .
What!?
Father,
what's goingon!??
You keep out of this!
Hmm?
Conan!
Hey. stop it!
Hey, stop it!
Raisom money
1500000.000 yen"
Miss Range!
Divide the money withalmai Electronics.
Pf Wit Ai
2nd Nakae Media
wy orosonling Ry
have the money ready by 2p.m
2nd let a secretary carry it to
the parking lotiat 1-chome Yoshioka
Ransom...
Is 117?
Jlfillhlfiwipnlin will?
Then...it was just an hour age
that they sent
this blackmail letter was sent.
Yes...
originator?
This ls quite some trouble.
This Is used In international crimes
and the method has become
a problem all over the world.
Uh huh.
Mr. Kataoka...
The dema™ d of this division of the ransom...
Ohnuki
All the three companics,ingdemand
has had recent transaction}With 'Us.
Uh huh
But why these three companies?
Whee Way
It's OK. explain.
Well. the. managers of these 3 companies
have all asked for a hand
in marriage with Miss:Renge.
Uh huh. wdll, that um like...
Thatis right! Snow:White!,
Ggh.
Ugh...
Father! You mean Princes» Kaguya!
Yeah, that's right, that's what I meant)!
Of course you meant that,
Hmm what is it?
Something smells here...
Excuse me. ,
» Wry
Turn him back!
I don't want to hear any excuses!
What's wrong?
As a matter of fact...
One of the suitors I mentioned.
due to situations at the company
can't get the ransom ready...
That's a lie!
They just.-don't want
any trouble and scandal!
How dare,
they... weigh my daughter, Renge's life
with that of the company's reputation...
hwon't forgive them!
Then,
what will happen to the ransom money..."?
I already have it ready.
1 have their company name on the outside.
But,
I'm net giving my daughter away to them!
Dropout from the wooing race.
This Is becoming more and more
Ahhhh .
Ahhhh...
Please forgive me...
Snow white.
Princess Kaguyal
That's it!
Meanwhile, we have received
the money from the other two.
AS soon as it's time.
I will carry It to the destination.
Hmm...we must agree with their terms.
And see what they will do afterwards...
We. the police
will go about the investigation
with the rescue of your daughter
as top priority
Thank you.
JEL]
{uh ?
This is.
The image was cut once
probably to make the halation disappear
The dnapper stopped the camera
and closed the window.
No. wait,
hat's this...
There's something there.
Is this the spider web?
No. then the
position isn't right
This place...
This place looks familiar...
What! ?
HEY How many timaos
Do. Irhave to tell you!
HEY! How many times!
Do I have to tell you!
You brat!
Father!
I'm sorry
Rats. I almost made it...
Kidnapped?
Miss Renga...!?
I'll have te be here for awhile
Ayumi, how is it down there?
Everyone doesn't know what to do.
Tere's only one hr
untilsthe curtain goes up...
What should we do. Conan?
Ughhhh!
Do something, do something!
Ms:=Sonoko?
You shouldn't go off
on your ewntherc and there
Get rid of the cobweb yourself!
I'm asking'you because I canto It myself!
I hate spiders!
My sol?
I can't do it myself...!
That's It. I got it)!
False kidnapping!?
Renge did it herself!?
What!?
Why would she want-to do*that...1?
Maybe she wanted to
ruin the talk about marriage?
What's that supposed to mean?
I don't really know
but probably-the reason for
asking for ransom
from the-people who proposed to her...
was her way of wanting to relate
how she-f@lt to-her father
In accordance to
he story of Princess Kaguya...
Right! I think so too!
But that's no excuse for her
to do:such a thing!
Little one!
Rengye:is at the warehouse, right?
Yup. probably...
It's probablythere!:
Huh! ?
Ov ca
Let's go!
Wr. ff
Walt up
Mr Tamanosuke!
This Is
the storrge warehouse
for the costumes and props
that we Yen ted
4, \ar
Renge should have the key (00.
Rengo should have the key 00...
( » - I
Range should have the key too
On {ep
This place must be it
v-9?
Don't you think we should tell father?
Ut there's no sign of anyone.
2 Quad
But there's no sign of anyone.
But ther.:s nolsign,of anyone
Rengel
Ms. Range!
I knew It...
Th.this!
Re.renge!?
And at this instant.
The false kidnap became a real one!
Oh no.
Ms. Range really got kidnapped
The culprit is probably
the other person
who helped with her false kidnapping!
I'll be going.
Uh huh.
Huh?
Where's Ran...?
Where. did they go?
Inspector
the re going.
And the caso moves on...
The curtain for the play
has also gone up
has also gong up!
Original Comic Books By.
OSHOO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIDRA
Background Music
KA Two ONO
Charter Designs By
MAS/HOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
11 (tS UV
8 Ives x
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
FIROTOSHI.TAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YOKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
[irectors Of Phototraphy!:
TAKASHI NO RA
HIRONOBU HOPIkOsH1
TAKAHISA O
Recording Direct Hr
KATSUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
ILRUMITSU (WKADA
Editor «
IERUMIISU OKADA
Filth)! .
ILRUMIISU OKADA
Chief Director.
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, [TD
inassocration with
YOMIURI-TELH@ASTINC
- DR? DNL 21
DIE Lge
V0 Ht nounkrrzey
RI hie en VU)
Once upon a time.
INT Wels olin
Old man who harvests bamboo.
Let me do it!
Ir 47
Huh!?
Darn!
Don't let him get away!
We re definitoly: going to find Ms. Rongo!
Qu an. 240
I tound: hor, Conan
Hurry back Ms Renge! Mr. Tamanosuke!
(1% FR)
@oncurrentistage and Kidnapping- Part 2