They can bo tho culprit or the actor (star)
There's not much time left
Youth Detective Squad.
Curtain call the case But makesyxit'in time
for the curtainsfiising on stage
He sees through the one 1nd only truth
A child in appearance withthe I. @. of an adult
No case 1s left unsolved
with Detective Conan
The traveling theatrical troupe
Tamanosuke troupe are herc again.
The show this time is "Taketori Story."
However. Range Katnoka who plays the main
character Princess Kac uya is kidnapped.
However, Range Kntaokq who plays the main
character Princess Kaguya Is kidnapped.
CW» ou
However. Range Kataoka who plays the main
character Princess Kaguya Is kidnapped.
The investigation of the detective start but
I realize that this 1s 2 false kidnapping
done by Renge herself
I realize that this is a false kidnapping
done by Range herself.
However,
Range wasn't where she
was supposedly held.
Believe it. or not,
She was really kidnapped.
The case started to move on, and the
curtain of the play has also gone up.
(122 hi)
Coincidental Development!!
Stage and Kidnapping!! Part 2
* $00
(1% FR)
Once upon a time... there was
an old bearded bamboo cutter...
What's going on, the curtain is up...
There is no Princess Kaguya. Is it alright?
D.Don't tell me that the director!
Youl really...you really are
going to put her on stage!
Ou really...you really are
going. to put her on stage!
We're talking about he leading role,
Princess Kaguya!
Her lines are really long. you know!
True
Don't worry
I changed the script
Everyone, hurry
And memorize tl
I changed it so that Megumi,
"If who is Kaguya as a child has more parts,
and shortened the adult part
11 who is Kaguya as a child has more parts,
and shortened the adult part 1]
Mt who is Kaguya as a child has more pars I
and shortened the adult part
as well as the stage direction. With the
positionifig of Kaguya and tho lighting.
We will try not to show her face.
Excopt for the climax where
Kaguyaircturns to the moon
we willineed to show her face
we will need to show her face .
I'm telling you it won't work...
00 BO WA- HG Beneoling
theater I's all about.
There are times when it pours
Tough times are indeed when
we should all come together
Words of wisdom by
the old man. I mean, the late. leader.
Let's have faith that Renge will
return. and do our best
But umm...
Please let me try!
Ran...
Everyone is looking forward to the show
Cancelling is out of the question...
Let me do
Pleas!
[Ran
Alright. let's. if youssay so.
If you say so
That's true...
Thank ou!
OD Qu
Thank ou.
Thanks everyone!
Mr. Tamanoesuke, how long
into the show is the climax?
Umm... yeah
The whole show is
approximately 2 hours so...
That would be just around
an hour and a ha ff...
hat would be just around an
hour and a half.! by then. right?
You must have some clue. little boy?
Flys (a, VAN) Ly
[I Soft tin
NO IR GO axl
The Youth Detective Squad. in action!
Hey. hey. I wasn't talking to you...
Then I'm coming with you.
Mr Tamanosuke
My part "Tel" is about half into
the play, an hour.
I 11 look for Renge until then teo.
EN VAY A EE TY
The case 1s in progress too.
Can you hear me detective?
I'm almost at the designated parking lot.
Huh? He received some kind of an envelope
It says to switch cars to the
one written on the memo.
HO aloe [ks
It's this car...
This as from a cell
phone. I'll answer it
MG 1M
¢ 136
Yes...
es... es...
I was told te go north of Takayama street
Will obey their instructions.
This child possesses beauty
that does not-éxig{ in this world,
and there are no dark places within the
house she resides, for it is filled with light.
It's almost time. Miss Ran.
Calm down, calm down....!
This place is...
where Miss Renge was confined, right?
Well, that was actually a false alarm...
Which is to say...whoever helped
with Renge's false kidnapping
is the real kidnapper,
Is that right? Little one?
Right, that's what I think...
No doubt about it...
The problem Is. who is that person...
But... there are only so many people,
who a girl can easily ask to do this...
What's up. Conan?
Do ou see something?
Alt a minute. \
What 3 It's Just ai"construction site?
Hey! Isn't thattwhier
Yeah, right! You're right!
Huh? What?
What's going on?
What are you talking about?
But. meanwhile...
Vt gy
I understand
Aww... he got us
I won't let them get away.
[FOV oud?
Hey. Mounir
Sto»
Make a right turn there. Inspector!
Takagi!
Yesi sir!
Mr. O@hnuki!!
Are.are you okay?
Come on!
What happened?
L1...1 was told nsthe cell
phone to shake off the police
and come in here...
And when I stopped the: car
suddenly out of nowhere...
I'm sorry...
¢ Takagi, emergencysdeployment,
on the double!
Yes, sir!
And... what about the hostage!?
We'll let her go -as soon
as her safety is confirmed.
So tell them to wait until then...
Darn
Oh. Detective Takagi?
There's something Mr Mouri
wanted ou to check out...
Sorry. there's not me for that!
Huh)
What do you mean?
And the play kept on rolling...
Kaguya tells the stone maker prince to
bring the holy stone bowl of the Buddha.
To the wealthy prince she tells
him to Bring the jeweled sprig.
Finally, she tells Prince Ohtomo-no-Miyuki
to bring her the neck of a dragon...
Oh. I'm so nervous!
Please hurry back,\Miss Range!
Mr Tamanosuke!
Look. I don't know what your talking about.
Hoy. me, don't you guys!
You're not supposed goiin there .
I'm sorry
So he's still hasn't been
caught at inspection point?
Huh?
No. although we set itiup
in less than a minute
Hey! told you not to go in there
Aren't there any. witnesses?
Huh?
Imm, you re...
Anyway. what about the witness?
When he was attacked...
What?
No one saw anything?
It was right afte \1 got out of the car.
Isnét that...
Camera!
Thank you for your cooporation's
Do you see something. little one?
There's no doubt about it!
What do you mean. onan?
Did ou find 4 clue in the video?
But with the camera there
the scene is out of range.
Uh huh.
But the kidnapper...
Heyl
COMA =I TO.
Ow! That hurt...
That's enough!
I. I'm. sorry. I thought you...
red thatgs what was going on... H
Huh? Where did he go?
Mr'. MOUTH?
Detective Takagi
Yes?
Bring everyone outside here.
Huh{?
Uh es.
There's one more thing...
There's om, more-thing...
Uh... es
What is it. Mr. Mouri?
Detective llakag!
It's already on the screen.
*"> 64
I Asked them to forward this
from the investigation headquarters.
The problem is the chimney
seen here on the screen.
[ITER e EN 5,
this' was taken down 4 days ago.
What!
This public bath was taken down to
be remodeled.
In other words, this was not
taken on the same day it was sent.
Which means...?
So long as the image was
set up to be forwarded.
The kidnapper could've been
on the receiving end too.
In other words, what you're drying
to say is...the kidnapper was among us!
Deteclve akag)
Yes. I looked into it just like you sald.
I chocked on who wis 1lwnys
on the receiving end of
the image: sent.out by the-kidnapper
as well as the instructions by phone...
Kn4knock it.out.
And: .take a look at-the
recorded image of the security camera.
Mr. Ohnuki: instructed
to do so by the kindapper,
you tried to shake off the police.
That's right
When was that?
When...
I was stopped at the traffic light. I.m.sure
I you detectives heard the oxchange too...
But. we couldn't hear the kidnapper's voice
Th. that's because it
was a telephone call.
That telephone call,
did it really come in?
MH: How absurd...
Then why did the kidnapper
take the cellphone with the ransom?
Th that's...
Huh?
What /
no but .
If understand.
This is .
As ou can see he is not using the phone.
If we look at the cell phone, we
can tell that there is no call log.
That's why he didn:t leave it behind...
It is probably somewhere
along with the ransom...
If wessearch the area,
we will soon have tho results.
But before that, we will
need toirescue'the hostage.
What's this suposed toe'mean?
The kidnapper himsélf should know.
Il don't know!
I don't. know .a.thing!
Quit fooling, Ohnuki!
Where's my daughter?
Where's Range?
Chairperson'...?
If something happens to:my daughter,
you won't get away, with this!
Just remember that!
Nino! I just helped your daughter
to do what she asked me to do .
Helped?
Uh oh!
Right. in the beginning it was just an act
So, Miss Renge candefinitely
say who helped her out
That is.:she can name
the real kidnapper!
So. the kidnapper can't just release her.
Were you planning. to Kill her
from the beginning!?
I don't know!
I don't-know-a thing!
I'm, not. going to talk anymore!
Please stay here Mr. Ohnuki
To protect the beloved Kaguya
Tel dispatched 2000 soldiers
to the Taketori house...
Don't Worry,
We will definitely find Miss Range!
Leave it to us!
NON,
+ The Youth Detective Squad to tho rescue!
Right on!
Brother, hurry back!
Just:around here.
I found It!
This. is it!
What is it? Weed?
It hasn't-even rained..why is it so muddy
Maybe it grew near water?
BRR WL
C3 ON (rl ev ¢ I
VOW VG UL WS Avinnge!
Mr. Tamanosuke!
I am not going to
return you to the moon. Kaguyal
COMO ON NO Joke 1s hie sapous
1 Ge [00 [ony SOU edkakay, tks GOMGRATY
my parents?! am ready
to give everything up!
R. Tamanosuko's eyes.
They are not looking at
Princess Kaguya:, and they
are surely not looking at me.
Have faith in me. I want you
OS ayw me. aguya, orever...
The possibility*of the kidnapper choosing
a place-far from hero
Il so. tho place of confinement should bo
somewhere nearby again.
And that place 1s probably
A place that has to dw With waten! »
O "ay!
Leave it to me!
In the light of the night,
brighter than the bright noon day.
Comes the messengemfiom the moon nding
upon a cloud descending towards earth...
comes the messenger from the moon riding
pon a cloud descending towards earth.
I founds it, wpan!
Are you» okay. Miss Range?
The play . 1°
What I appened to the.play?
Hurry -Kaguyal Come Rare,
Let's go back to the moon together!
Ends here...!?
I can't watch anymore...
Miss Range!
Range?
N. No I can't do this.
Not after all the trouble
pu ou through...no!
What are you talking about. Miss-Rengelg
That won't do...
Neither:-for you nor Mr. Tamanosuke...
I'can tell.
Ran.
Miss Range!
Woe will meet mngaimin
I believe in you. Kaguya...
INK Dy () area [300m OD
I hate to admit it...
But it's so inspiring!
Oriein1l Comic Books By.
OSH AQYAMA
Producers
MASAHITO YOSHIORA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MAS TOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 110OKA
ME jiDD
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARU NOOGAWARA
AISUSHI AONO
AK! , WAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art DiFector
YOKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography
AKASHI NOM RA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI1?
TAKAHISA OWA A
cording Dir
KAISUYOSHI KQBAYASEHT
1:11:10).
IERUMI11SU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KODAK/IA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, (TD
INarssocration with
YOMIURI-TH EEASTINC
CORPORATION
Prdiestive we)
Rights Resist
Secretary Ohnuki was arrested
and the ransom retrieved.
Like Princess Kaguya,
Miss Range returns home once.
And after persuading her father,
returns to he troupe.
Now, she travels around the
country performing with
Mr. Tamanosuke and the group.
It was also a now start for both
Tamanosuke a diss Renge.
Why didn't you tako us with your?
That's not fair!
We wanted to see the fireworks tdo!
Uh Old
Wh, whattis this!?
Look at that!
Please: help me!
Someone's been killed and
we're In trouble too!
Al ik)
Shrine TorinGale Surprising Code! "Part 1