Stars are for some roason attractive
They can be the culprit or the actor.
Today's storys stage
Is set on a village shrine.
Another meaning to the letters we've
been seeingis h'ding an unexpected secret!
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the l.Q. of an adult.
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
Rhinoceros beetle. Rhinoceros' Beetlef
60 @=fein Q Boeo Bo Ln
It Must be around here...
Why doilihave to look for insects.
Op a hot day like 'his?
Hey Mitts ihikeo.,. are yow sure
they e around ere?
WwW .wait a second!
Moreover, in a mountain where...
there's garbage everywhere
It can't help it...
The poople from the village
usually take turns cleaning up,
but'yesterday there was a festival and
a lotrof people seem to have come here.
A ff. festival?
It's called the Tento Festival.
Where peoplo walk-through town with
a float decorated with. 8 million g&ds!
See. that's the shrine Ver there
That shrine gate is the starting point!
Behind the float that is lit yp
with -colorful lights
Behind the float that 1s lit up
with colorful lights
fireworks are shot up In the air
and it is indeed a magnificent sight!
Huh? Doc. you were here last night?
Ah no..ummm...ha.ha.ha
What?!
Why didn't you bring us with you?
That's *6t fair!
We wanted to see the fireworks too!
Aaa .hahaha...
hahaha
2A RA
CAI FR)
dA RA
(AI #R)
Shrine Toril Gate Surprising Code! Part 1
dA RA
(AIF)
We had our reasons too. right Al?
Right. I'm sleepy because of it...
You're alwaysgsleopy
UT, RO SO OF yD
What were you two doing here?
I know! you came 10 catch insects?
Well. something like that...
What, but we didn't see
any unicorn beetles orrstag beetles.
You can't find any just groping
around here and there...
5 4 Pe fo.
I'm notgjust groping around!
I'm selecting trees like sawtooth oak
that the unicorn beetles favor.
Then Mitsuhiko!
Touch the ground of the root) Hard isn't it?
Uh huh.
Nd there's garbage,
but no fallen leaves.
End WO don't 800
ay withered trees either. pigh ?
Th0 hrm/of- thn us-uczoru-w hoot-lo qrowq whom
fallen leaves havé rot and the ground is so t
Iho stag beetle grows by withered trees
$0 there Aren't much afithem in groves
hike these where the ground is hard,
and routine cleaning is carried out.
Youisure know a lot.
If we were to look, it would be in the woods
n the other side of our tents.
And I think dawn
would be best tie to start...
Then let's eat dinner and hi} the sack!
But don't expect too much!
The collecting season is from after June
until around the middle of August...
These days the nights are a bit chilly
Exo) Witt) ok nod faze x=) Snouman
that t-he insects favor.
Don't be too disappointed,
ilhave-a little treasure for you instead...
WL 2 on
Yeah. something you will like!
Wh:.where Is It?
Wh where is it?
Wh. where is it?
Yéah, yeah ll
Ahem! To find it...
you must...
Maru mushi?
Tent?!
Wiv @I
What is that'!
The maru mush curls up; into a round ball
when it's poked at hike a roly poly.
E We going to set a tent up over hin
Or maybe it's the tento bug?
Ip other words. the ladybug
At times like this, 7
it's
At times like this...
Nana
That's night.
Up to Conan
Huh?! Wh:what?!
No! Don't depend on Edogawa's wits...
Why not? Ms. lfaibara.
I'm just saying it's not good
to depend on others so easily
You might be able to figure it out
if you lie down and think carefully) +
And if you still can't come up with anything.
Wash your face and start anew...
am a aw
It's easy to say but...
Doc and Al (re so monn!
What makes you say that Al...
Whatdmakes you say that Ai .
Fy Hb) Beggs xo = Alla ¥
I want to discuss with you...
Shinichi I have something
Can you go to the place of the code
and secretly checkithings out...
Huh. uh.lok
If Aiorlg , they'll probably find out
where the coded location is through us.
Mm? Well, well?
Don't tell me you can't decipher my code!
Oh, leave. me alone.
Oh. is that right?
Hmmml
Ha, ha, ha... This 1s all bechuse
Al thought it through.real 'hard!
Pont let him get you. Poe
Huh?!
He Must trying to make you 'happy
by. making you think you beatshim.
Is.is that right?
Hahn.
Flaha
It unthinkable that he can't solve a
super simple code. ..like this... Right?
R. Holmes of the age of Heisei
Huh?!
She's really making me:mad...
What. Conan you don't get it too?
Ey. the same with us!
Mere alivaaiaell
You're just an ordinary first grader after alll
Um no I almost have the answer...
Like the crab and shrimp it"has a hard shell.
Just like a person who protects himself
with hard frame work or cloth
when sleeping in a tent in the mountains,
so does the pill bug
They can both curl up into a ball!
And?
A.and so...
And so? Y%
Even if I run the common points together
Ies till cant solve. it
Hah.
Ha.ha
I've .go mail .
Let's talk about the code later...
Conan...
It's from Sonoko! It'sja picture. Huh?
Wh. what's this?!
What on earth is this.
M. next is the p ione...it's from Ran
ah, umm. voice changer. voice changer
What s he doing?
0 odo Moy
R.Ran?. Whats' up?
Sore Shinichi
Sonoko just sent you a picture, right?
Erase it right now!
Huh?
\ Don't erase it!
DAO TR Ls = El) O 1 HR
Hey Sonoko!! What are you saying!
Hee hee, hee
Special sexy shot 7?
Th then. this is...
What?!
Ran's...
Oh yeah, Ran and Sonoko were saying
they were going to the beach...
Hey... Who are you talking to? Conan...
MEXR Cot nf?
Is Conan nearby?
Uh oh?!
Ummm, ui
Ko. Kona coffee!
It's the kbna coffee I-mMm drinking right now...
Ko. Kong coffee!
It's the kona coffce I'm drinking rig NOW...
Kb. Kona coffee!
It's the kona coffee I'm drinking right now...
Don't drink too much!
Uh yeah...I'm going to hang up
Y If that's all you have to say!
Ummm the picture
I know! I'll erase it! See you!
Save, save...
Hmmm...she'll find out sooner or later...
Hmmm:...she'll find out sooner or later...
Hmmm...she'll find out sooner or later .
LIA LORE) We ser bool
Where did you find it?
I bet you just turned
overa rock or something?
over a rock or something?
No! No!! I found it!
On the other side of the woods!
Huh?! You found it?
Is it true. Genta?
E000 WOO [x 4 I)
Mere. over (here!
Loo . there!
It's Maru mushi, right?
Marumushi hot spring ?
I've heard of a Asamushi hot spring but...
It's such a lonely hot spring nn
Th& sign is comirg off...
There's probably 1 tont
inside that inn, right!
There myst bea Key
to the code In that tent!
En! lets gol
Haha
As gol
I don't.see-the:point.in
saying "yeah" so.enthusiastically...
Huh?
Strange
I thought-there wns. something
BANE nl] Ink Ks SPiN ).
Hat Inn Is closed down...no tent
Yeah...t~hore was no one there...
So hatdo olLsa ?G e up?
Mmmm,
Uh. guess so.
Uh. I guess so
Mmmm,
Uh. I ques; so...
Unfortunately...
So show us the treasure
Actually this codelis.
Wait! Dr.!
There's one person
who still hasn't given up...
He ..Conan?
Why don't you just give up!
There are time Me this! Hahaha...
But it's so odd Conan You love codes
so much and you solve them so easily
Maybe you're suffenng
HO oO SUG IOCESE
oh be quiet...
It's just that I I can't really get into it,
when it's not connected to an Incident...
ap ne call?
Ah...it's Ran again, .
What can it be this time?
Yes. hello?
Ah, Shinichi?
Please. help me!
Huh?
Someone been killed, and Sonoko and I
were also attacked and we're in trouble!
Hey?! What! Are you in the
middle of running away from the killer?
No, We're alright now..we're not hurt,
we're with the police right now...
And? 'Who was killed?
A.man called\Miyama
who was 'staying insthe same hotel as us!
Then, were you attacked
because you saw the killer?
NO, we didn't see him...
We found out:that the man was killed only
after the police informed us...
What? You mean, were attacked
despite the police being there?
No. we were attacked on
our way back from the police!
It was too dark to see who it Was though...
Issthe one who attacked you. the killer?
con. NOW.
That person ran off with Sonoko s bag so
maybe it was just a purse snatcher
He 7!
Wait! What are you doing!! Give it bac
That person ran off with Sonoko's bag so
maybe it was just a purse Snatcher .
He 7!
Wait! What are you doing!! Give it bac
Why did you go to the police at night?
Sonoko remembered there was
something written on the window
where the man, was killed so
we went to the police tell them about it...
What writing?
Yeah...some kind of a code...
A code?!
Hey! What are you:so happy about?!
Someone died you know...
Um, Sorry» .
And. what was written...
Yeah... According to. Sonoko, it was written
in red by something similar to lipstick...
There-were 4 alphabets written
in"small letters. telu...
Teiu?
Yeah. so Sonoko thinks :.
The: victim probably left a message...
It's notiprobablyly
I That is definitely a.dying message!
The; victim probably wantedOto say teiuka
He's, he's, "8...
S:sOnoko...
It Is so-called...!
The teluka homicide!
Huh?
What?! "The teluka homicide"
Huh?! Hey! Sonoko!! Quit fooling...
I'm not fooling around!
A man called Miyama:was killed
and on his window were the letters telu!
Teiu. "teiuwithithe, letters
telu thentit mustibe:teiuka"
that he wanted.to leave as a message?!
When we met Mr. Miyama on the beach.
He kept using the,word teiuka.
Uh huh! So whatever you say,
it's "The.teiukahomicide
Was the "I" in "teiu
the alphabet "I"?
Huh? 1? Yeah maybe...
So:what if it is?!
Nd the fourth letter
wasn't the length of the right side
a little shorter than the left?
Huh?
So I'm asking if it wasn't the hiragana "shi"!
Hmm...? Now that yousmentioned it...
It mightihaveibeén that...
Think of the "shi" coming right
after the alphabets "tel".
Tel...tel shim?
I get it! "please tel it means "please call
and he was trying to" call for help this way!
I knew you could do it Shinichi!
Uh huh. your hubby Is great. great!
H,he's not m hdbb. ,1
What are you saying Sonoko!
Hey, Ran, your face...it's red!
H. he's not mm hubb
What are you saying Sonoko!
Hey, Ran, your face...it's red!
Ahem! And?
In what situation was the man killed
Oh yeah...according to the police.
He was-lying onithe floor bleeding from
his head. near'the window-of.the hotel...
He was hit byfsomething hard from the back
If he was trying to write tel shite, that
guy probably wrote it with his own blood...
What?!!
It was red, right? The letters...
And, who found the body?
The 3:friends of Mr. Mlyama Who was killed!
If I'm not mistaken,
Mr Kino the classmate of Mr. Miyama.
Miss Yanuma. Mr Miyama's girlfriend
and Mr Bito a colleague
at a part-time job they both worked for
Mr. Miyama and the the
were planningto have dinner together
so they went to his room to ¢e shim
because he didn't come.
They found the door unlocked
and the window broken
Mr..Miyama was found
on the floor near:the window
This is what they testified to the police...
The window was broken?
Yeah, that's why the police say
the killer broke in from the window,...
When Sonoko went to the-police about
the letters that were written on the window
The didn't find an thing of that
sort among the broken pieces of glass...
The letters ""'teiu were not understandable
so wouldn't behave us anther...
So I toldfthe police!
I'd"bring the evidence!
Hey, hey, Sonoko?!
Do you really have it? The evidence...
Yeah, remember I sent it to you Kudo?
Huh...?
What?!
The special sexy shot of Ran that
I took with my cell phone!
Noticed the . red letters
before I took the picture
so it should be in the background
of Ran's:picture!
Hey! What do you mean by should
You raven ci1ec ec .
No I thought left
my cell phone. back at the hotel.
So-we headed back
from the police station to go get it...
But; half way back,
realize thatlit was in my bag.
So we were heading back to the
police station again when
I was unfortunately mugged
and my bag was taken!
I didn't want to be called a liar so
I told Ran to call you and
ask you to send me back-that picture!
Huh?
I told her that .you probably erased it
so it would be no:iuse...You erased it. right?
Uh, yeah...of course...
See]
Really?
Well anyway. you know the moaning
of the letters now. so go tell the police!
Okay!:I:ll:call If something comes up!
Yeah .
That sexy shot...is"he Kidding?
Ummm...picture:. picture...
Ah...the red letters...
There's: something written
on the window just like Sonoko said...
The, curtain is closed so
It's not possible to look inside the room...
Sdly the letter t" which is hidden
behind RA"$ hips iS in view...
Only the letter "{" which is hidden
behind RA's hips is in view...
Hmm? There's something written
n red besides the.
Hmm? There something written
in red besides the t"...
cold DO e GOtmlme OF & ello GF no [pom
What a weird killer
If the dying message were to be "tel shite
Some time after committing the murder,
he must've noticed the writing and
broke the window to retrieve
the pieces with writings on them.
Even if it were to be an attempt to delay
the discovery of the body,
breaking the window would risk
attracting more attention
and hastening the discovery.
What are you looking at, Conan?
What, what?
What is it?
'Wow: hey,
that's! It'sta:woman"s nude.lisn't it?!
What!
Conan! It might be against the law
if a grade schooler looks
atfa picture like that!
It's not...
Hahaha. ..it's Just spam mail
When I accessed the site to the mail
I just happened to get this picture...
By the way,
were you able to decipher Doc's code?
No...Not at all...
No way!
If even you can't, how could we
We borrowed the paper with the code
Maru mushi mi tent...
Maru mushi...
I wonder if we'll really be able to find
the site of the treasure
after deciphering this code?
If I were to choose,
I would rather have come here
for the festival Dr. Agasa went to
Festival...?Wasn't that festival
called the Tento Festival...
What?! What did you just say
Yeah! You can see the shrine gate
that lit up. right?
Doc said that it's a village festival and
the float starts from there.
Then the "tent" in the code points
to the Tento festival?
Even so, I still don't understand
the maru mushi part...
I still think it has something to do with
the Marumushi hot spring inn?
3ut-that-place was closed down
The entrance was closed
and no one answered our calls...
What is it?
Hey... look! Something's getting bright!
That's where...
Marumushi hot spring is located...
Maru mushi ni lento...
does that mean to light itaup?
T.that's«it] That must b it!
I'm getting it!
Lot's go!
Yeah!
Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO. YOSHIDRA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI I1OKA
u ,--Qs-Bv
141709 UD
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
A UNARI KOUGHI
JUNI HI MIYASHITA
HI HIGURE
TWSHIKI INOUE
Amimalion Directors
MASATOMO SUDO
HIRO TOSHI TAKATANI
FMTARUO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
AKASHI-HYODO
Art"DiFector
YOKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWA A
Recording Direct »
KAISUYOSHI KQBAYA_} 1
Filton,
TERUMIISU OKADA
Fditor.
ITFRUMiliT1§UPkOKA DA
Fditor .
IERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KODAAWA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, {TD
INarssocrtation with
YOMIURI TELFGASTIN(
CORPORATION
Ff LIVE Cnn
UAC SHOCUALM LT 70s
RIP his aeserye I)
We give up. right?
You guys give up too easily!
First this code written all in Katakana...
Secondly. the balance of each letter is off.
And thirdly...
The hint Dr and Haibara was talking about!
WnWIIL
( T.this must bel?
Ari Should've realized this earlier...
(18 "R)
(Ma)
Shrine TorinGate Surprising Code!1Part 2