Stars are for some reason attractive
They can be the culprit or the actor.
Dr. Agasa s weird code is
even tough for the Youth Detective Squad
Who's going to be the first to solve it!
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I met an adult
NO caso 1s left unsolved with
Dotective Conan.
Yf 40
Once hot summer day,
we came to collect insects.
Doc gave us 1 codo quiz
maru mush! nl ténto"
YE I 1 YO { 1 O00) us
where the treasure IS hidden
But I couldn't solve the code either.
Meanwhile, I get a call
from Ran and'Sonoko
who are at the beach :sayingithat'there was
a murder at the héitdlrsthétirfftfeyére staying at!
Sonoko says that"there were strange letters
written on the window of hotel room
where the man:was killed...
S.Strange letters?
Yep...something like a code...
Who found the body?
The three friends of
Mr. Miyama who wastkilled!,
Mr. Miyama and those three wen.
Planning to have dinner together
but when they went to his room to get him
because he didn't come,
they found the door unlocked
and tho window. brokon,
ith Mr. Miyama lying on the floor nearby.
/lJ'lhLl'U MEI M4100 {U161 Gum bunk /
Then we...
Then the "tent" in the code points
to the Tento festival?
Even if that's so, I still don't
understand the maru mushi part...
That's where...
Marumushi hot spring is located...
Maru mushi ni tento...
does that mean to light it up?
(1% #R)
(1% FR)
Shrine Toril Gate Surprising Code! Part 2
(ifi $5)
Theré're a lot of people...
There must be some kind of a gathering,
don't you think...
Stupid! Take a closer look!
Everyone is holding a basin.
How: true!
The village probably bought the closed
down inn and the people are using it
as a public bath!
4 see...
public bath...sento...
Maybe this tento
means "sento
No matter how you look at it,
Genta. this te doesn't look like se!
And it can't be "tentou because
there s no "u" after the "tento
I don't get it!
He I Genta...
Don't lie down in despair!
I'm not in despair! Remember
Doc told us to lie down and think it through
I just might get it!
Yeah. but...
Ai was saying that if we still don't get it,
we should wash our faces and start anew.
Since there's a public bath...why don't we
go and wash our faces and our bodies!
Tihat-s a great idea!
It's no use .
Huh!?
It's no use going to that inn...
there's nothing there...
W've got to do something!
Then tell us!
Where is the treasure?
Please! Tell us...
Sure...l can tell you...
If someone here gives up...
Umi?
Huh!?
I'm not giving up!
Hmm!? Mail...
It's from Sonoko...
Hmm? I thought her cell phone was
in the bag that was stolen...
I found this bag on the street
and since there was no ID,
I mailed the most recent person the
cell phone listed to have sent a mall to.
I want to send this bag to you, so-can you
please let me know your address. and-name.
It seems like the purse=snatcher just took
the purse and threw the bag away.
Wouldn't you usually ask for the address
and name of the owner of the bag...?
Why did this person send a mail?
Wouldn't it be quicker to look
at the record of calls made
and call someone from that list?
Huh!?
You give up. right?
Huh?
Oh...ah...Time out!
Take the bag to the police if you found it!
Hello, Ran? I just got mail from the person
ho found Sonoko's bag...
Oh. really?
You'll probably received mail too,
so can do something about it...
Hey. I'm sorry...
What's up?
My batteries are almost gone.
I'm at the police station right now,
I'll get back to you
WAR [HERO {RO WO hr:
when I return to the hotel...
Then did you tell them that
the letters might mean tel shite"?
Uh huh! The police and Mr=Miyama's three
LES EETR SIS AVY ) ARERR fed 8Ok:
But that doesn't help to specify the killer,
SO We're going back 10 the hotel for now.
SO we're going back to the hotel for now.
Hey, be careful. The purse-snatcher is
probably still roaming the streets.
We'll be alright!
I just asked Mr Kanouio take me and
your wife back to the hotel!
Wife!?
I just asked Mr Kanou:to take me Ind
your wife back to the hotel!
I just asked Mr Kanou'lo lake me and
your wife back to-the hotel!
I just asked Mr. Kanou to take me and
your wife back to the hotel!
W.who's Kanou...
WwW. who s Kanou.
an was just talk/Ag to yeu about him.
Mr. Miyama'sl good. looking friend
Good looking!
Sonoko
What's the big doal! It's true!
The other two friends are with him, right?
Hmm...It seems likeihe's alone...
Mr. Miyama's ginifmend, 'Miss Yanuma is
still being questioned by the police
so Mr. Kanou was planning to wait
for her In his,car until. she fifished...but...
(Rai? (AD
SO Mr. Kanou was planning to wait
for her in his car until she finished\.-but.
for her in his car until she finished\.-but...
So Mr. Kanou was planning to wait
for her in his car until she finished... but...
Mr. Bito seems to have returned
to the hotel already...
Since Miss Yanumn's
questioning 1s taking time
Mr. Kanou will be taking us back to
the hotel and returning for her!
Okay.
I'm hanging up!
I'm really running out of battery...
Come on...
I should have gone to the beach too...
Beach?
Talking about the beach. I found a jellyfish)!
+ What are you talking.about{Ayumi!
There are no jellyfish in the mountains!
Yas, there areal
See, there!
Really?
Huh!?
Se88...8 jellyfish
T.true
turn the hot spring mark upside down
and it looks like a jellyfish...
See?
Yeah .
I 88...
Turn the hot spring mark upside
1nd it looks like a jellyfish...
So that's it. that's what it is .
Lie down and wash you face. huh...
How stupid of me...
Having trouble with a code such as this...
Sometimes easy codes
are difficult to solve...
Huh?
Doc! It's about time...
Tell us the answer...
What's 'maru mushi nl tento"?
Ha. ha. ha...alright
No! I won't tell you until everyone gives up!
I'll give up so just tell me...
That's not fair Gental
Why Ran .
Conan
Huh!?
Can't you still solve it?
Uh, no... It's totally Greek to me,
I haven't got a clue...
Then hurry up and give up!
Conan! Admit defeat!
You guys give up too easily!
Ha, ha, ha, it seems like Shinichi
can't solve it yet either...
Anyway, let's think it over
from the very beginning
Let's take (these (8tters that
are written only in katakana...
It's understandstable that 'maru mush
and tento are written in katakana...
Don't you think it weird for the "ni"
in between to be in katakana too?
That's true...
Secondly, if you look closely,
the letters are not balanced.
How true!
Isn't that because
Doc's handwriting is messy
Ha, ha, ha
And thirdly.
The hint Doc and Haibara gave us!
What!? Did they give us a hint?
Yeah...
Iie down and think carefully and
If you don't get it,
wash your face and start anew"
are things Doc and Haibara
don't. usually say...
It's obviously a hint!! Maybe it means
to "lie down and look at these letters'
Okay!
Ah...
Lie down. right?
Ummm...
I don't see anything different.
Huh? What happened Gental?
Did ou get something!?
Yeah
Huh??
What?
Hey. Genta. what's going on!
Uh. no...ll thought I almost got it.
Almost?
Which Is it!
Shut up! I thought I could almost
read it when I lied down!
Phew
Close call, close call...
No...
That smile. that provoking annoying look...
He probably... already knows...
Hmmm
Mmmm, nothing comes to mind
evenuif I look at it from the side
Then let's look at the other hint
You mean the "go wash your face one?
But...to wash your face
in the middle of the woods...
Ah! Maybe...Does it mean to go
take a bath at the bath in the inn.
Huh? No...remember Halbara and Doc
said there was nothing at the inn...
Then where do you say we should wash?
Yeah. that's right!
I don't know... maybe it doesn't mean
to actually wash your face...
Maybe it has something to do with
what you do when you wash your face...
Hmmm... first of all, turn the faucet on...
Splash wator on your face...
Wipe your face with a towel...
And then after that?
After that...
Hmmm
Let's eat!
Hey! Gental We're talking about
when we are washing our faces!
You eat after you wash your face,
don't oul?
Mirror!
Huh!?
I look in the mirror!
Mirror!? You can only see your face in it}
I'm getting more mixed up!
I think the mirror is on the right track... see!
Turn it upside down
Iike that hot spring mark...
and it looks like something totally different,
Iike the jellyfish.
Ven if I hold ithupside down.
It doesn't look like a porgy or a flounder!
I can't even read what it says...
W.wait a minute!
Could it be, to wash your face
while lying down...
To look at the mirror with the letters written
downwards by turning it sideways...
Turn it sideways, reverse the paper
and look at it through the mirror!
Wow!
Mum mutsun no torn
Mura matsuri no tori
(The shiine gate of the village festival!)
It's that shrine!
Are we right?
Doc! Ail
Correct!
You're correct! Hahaha...
San!
We did it!
Hahaha .
Let's hurry and go there!
Yeah!
Treasure! /,
1...you look like you taught the ki
that they can do it if they try...
Uh huh...don't I look great?
Huh...
Shinichi, aren't\you going to go see
what the treasure is?
I bet you want to see it 100...
I don't have to see it to know what it is!
The place of the code Is the tori gate of
the shrine that's lit up even late at night .
If we put sap on the pole of the toril gate.
DW OAR 0 OR BA exCtron
I found it!
Wow!
Unicorn beetles and stag beetles!
That's right!
Anyway...
You did a great job with the code .
This can be read from the front-and back .
Thanks to Ail
First
we were going to make it an animal code...
We thought of sticking paper with
animal names on the window!
Watching that from the outside. Ai told me!
Isn't "sanNnso (oxygen)
a little bit hard for the kids ?
Isn't 'sanso (oxygen)
a little bit hard for the kids?
Like that...
I see
The letters kirin looked like sanso
from the back and
mu thought of the coda.
Shinichi...?
Glass. back?
See through...w.wait a minute...
This!?
Dar ;!
That's it!
Shinichil?
Kudo!?
So that was it!
That's why Ran's face crossed my mind...
Ran...Ran's in danger!
Oh, Shinichi?
Where am I?
I told you
Returning to the hotel in Mr. Kanou's car...
What? Get out of the car now?
I got what "teiu really means!
There was a little punctuation
before the "t" in "teiu!!
Put that vertical and reverse it!
The killer's name
H.hey, Rani?
Ran!! Ran!
The batter's dead
Your husband...what did he say?
Hey Sonoko!
Um... get out of the car,
make it vertical andfreverse it?
VVihatis)it
Your husband! Maybe he's jealous?
N.no way...
What!? Ran and Sonoko are in trouble!?
Yeah... Sonoko saw it! The letters written
by the person murdered in the hotel room...
Letters!?
It was in lower case
alphabet written horizontally!
To be more accurate,
there's a comma before the.
It's the same as "Mura matsurl no tori!
Tun the letters written horizontally.
Vertical and read it from the back.
Maru mush! nl tento"
Make "Sanso vertical and read
from the back. and?
Then what about teiu!?
That is um .
It becomes "Kanou"...
Kanou...
Why did he leave such a difficult code
as ad ing message?
It's not a code!
Th murdered guy fell on the floor and
wrote the words
othe window from the inside
And Sonoko saw
the letters from the outside.
Then we have to hurry and tell Ran...
Ranis phone ls dead...
And the thing is, Ran and Sonoko are both
In a guy anous car.
Hey...this is not the way to the hotel.
Dont worry. it's a short cut...
where's the hotel those two are staying at?
If I knew I would call the police!
They told me they were going to the beach
but I don't know where...
Darn! I should've noticed earlier...
When I received the weird mail from
Sonoko's cell phone
whieh was thought to be mugged!
The picture sent to my cell phone,
he wanted to delete the picture
with the dying message
Thatrg why he asked
form address and name...
Wait a minute...then it must mean!
Hmmm...
The guy you were talking about,
Shinichi. he's only in high school.
Yet he's a detective?
H eah sort of...
Wow...having a detective boyfriend...
Uh. no he's not my boyfriend...
They're so lovey- dovey...
That's why I sent her boyfriend
a picture of her inf her bathingssuit
Hey Sonoko!?
Haha
That's so unfortunate...
Shinichi is not here. right?
I would have liked to meet the detective...
If the killer is waiting for me to contact him
he should be carrying Sonoko's cell phone
around with it switched on.
Realize that he's the man!
He's the killer!
NOT TNE Wie,
the same as Sonoko's...
Or rather, that...
IS mine...
You're right!
Really!? But why?
TQ VY LLOLLWDY VANDA JWG
who snatched the purse from. you...
Huh!?
To erase the evidence of the killing!
What!?
When we go a little farther,
I want you to talk to me...
Andigive"me the address
of the kid Shinichi too!
Still won't answer!?
Be quiet!
Uh...yeah...
He answered!?
Hello! Hello! Hello!?
Original Comic Books By.
OSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By.
MASATWMO SUDO
Story Editor.
NICHI 11OKA
NE J JAD gL
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
Animation Dircctors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
Kl + KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
IAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSEI?
TAKAHISA OWACA
Recording Dire«tor.
KATSUYOSHI KQBAYASHI
Fditor.
11 RUMI1ISU OKADA
Chief Director
KEN] KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT-LTD
Inassociation with
YOMIURI -TELE ASTIN
CORPORATION
Di Jd alive oe)
2.401\ks J sil GAAS (17 Hd)
dag PM ers, I
What do you mean hello! pl
Where were you when Ran needed Vow?
Eek!
What do you mean hello!
Where were you when Ran needed you!?
Eek!
Hey! Are you listening?
Uh, yeah, where
Uh, yeah, where...
The car crashed into a: tree,
and it was so much trouble!
Huh? The car... why'd it ram into a tree?
Don't ask me why. it just happenod!?
Ran side kickéd the face of the killer
who was driving the car...
Is that right...
After that the police that Sonoko called
arrived and the killer was taken into custody
His motive for committing the murder was
because his friend found out about
his illegal enrollment to the university
and he was being blackmailed...
He committed a more serious crime
siren of police car driving away to
hide his first criminal act,a typical pattern
of cases like these...
Then
I"tholight™I™saved it here...
Huh!?
I thought I saved it Were...
Huh!? Oh. ..if it's the picture of the lady
mn thé bathing suit. I deleted it for you!
Huh ls?
WwW. why!
W.why. bbécause it's against the law]
Sorry. I asked Al to delete it!
Ie Hone)
[0 =x tn (KL
Damn
Something working out
by fluke is interesting
How can they think up of a trick like that?
That go
he's one of thexthree scriptwritens. Isih't he?
That guy
he's one of the three scriptwriters, isn't he?
Hose challenging aye
he cultpriti sts arsah I
He has confidence in the trick used.
=I he Mystery of the Complete Half @rime"