Stars are forssomec¢ rcason- attractive
They can be the culprit or the actor.
Stars are for somoyreason attractive
The stage forslodayss episode-is-a TV
station. he passion for creating a program
he stage for today s episode is a 1V
station The passion for creating a program
gots bent out of shape along
the way and leads to mundey,
He sees through the one and only truth A
child In appearance with the L1G! of an adult
No cases loft unsolved
with Dcotective Conan
You want me Kogoro Mouri to...
Speak before the scriptwriters
Yes, I'd relly like you to tell
them your story Detective Mourn...
Have you ever seen the
SON OER baa
Nos - hl
Well, since it's a detective story,
I've watched it several times.
I watch it every week!
AMORA [RC At WOO)
Thank you.
Three diffarcnt people are taking turns
writing the scripts of "Detective Fluke"...
However, since we've heen
doing this for HL years now...
WA ila of Gust en Hie
ind tricks to write about.
So, you want to usc. my var ous experiences
as reference for making your, scr pts.
ER VO BIR is eal ORAMRR
doesn't happen all the time but
Once in awhile there are
fantastic ones. For example...
52nd Closed Door Murder
had a surprising trick
If so. Fluke, that locked room was...
It was set up afterwards, Inspector...
The entire house was lifted up with a crane.
No one would ever think that such a
Iarge scale method would be used But
you can't fool the eyes
of Detective Rintaro Fluke here.
53E0)
It's amazing how they can
think up a trick like that.
It makes me so happy .
I think that the "52nd Closed Door Murder
is a great mystery story too.
But it was broadcast
more than 2 years ago...
How old are you now anyway, Conan?
How old are you now anyway. Conan?
Uh I saw it on a. a video the other day
COIN wi YOR3, OF GOUGH:
Yep. Ahaha whew
that was close.
CITE»
R.-*
Yep. Aha. ha. whew,
that was close...
'Understand: xl! tell the scriptwriters of all
the various experiences I've been through.
understand: Al tell the scriptwriters of all
the various experiences 've been through.
May lgbiitéio? I'd lake to meet the
people who are writing "Detective Fluke!
he Ah BA.
He Ah SN
The Mystery of the Complete Half Crime!
Sv As Xx A
Hmm maybe we came here too early
There's an hour more to
before the appointed time.
I'm sre th ré was a
coffee shop on the top floor...
I'm scriptwriter, Yagami. I'm going to
Detective Fluke s producer Inoue s place
Yes sir. one moment please.
He's one of the scrptwriteréw;
of the three. isn't he?
Hmm... he seems somewhat
unfriendly and arrogant *!
Oh. Yagami SenseiO™long time no see.
Well, I got caught in traffic
riding We cab.
I think it's been 6 months already that
we've all gotten together like this.
Uh. while we're waiting for
Mr. Mouri to arrive a while later.
I would like to conduct ameeting as to
the development of this series from now on.
I'd hike something to drink
=X DONA all off OT
I'd like something to drink
What about all of you?
No. thank you. not yet.
I'll go get it... I'll take your order.
I'll go get it... I'll take your order
Coffee! Hot...
Sarno horo
Same here.
Okay. I'll be right back
Oi, Plan) excites, = ox) kod iY
It's okay. I'm always doing this.
3 (NO) WEIROR fr Whe
a Bul ny meetin) Be ment TogeeidOmtd
TO Geil @) axetil, or wiERE
He writes great stuff
m not talking about what he writes
I'm t1lking About the way
1@ usually behaves. Sakuma...
He's still a newcomer so...
I'm sure he's trying to be
as considerate as possible!
No om Yoana) fr aOR? Gx
Iist, after all. Mr Inoue.
2 you a hold Mo mi off {ho
Iist. after all. Mr Inoue.
I think you should take him off the
Iist. after all. Mr. Inoue.
SekUmalandlifcaAnlR IODA BLY;
handlic "Detective Fluke ourselves.
Sakmma "and I can probably
handle Detective Fluke" ourselves.
Mr. Yogorw I
At Ca rN
aw - -
Sorry»to keep you all waiting.
Filmy CO Pulp you!) 6.110 xmilillrng.
hank you
Thank you
Oh WV remembcr correctly you
use milk. don't you. Mr Inoue?
Oh ..if I remembaor correct y, you
use milk, don't you, Mr. Inoue?
1144)
I forget the milk. I'll be rightsback
I forgot the milk I'll bo right.back.
I toll you. ho lacks composure
Well... he's still very young.
M.Mr Yagami!
>» 25
- - ON
os. oh! Mr Inoue
WwW. What did you just
Yes, oh! Mr. Inoue
Huh? WW What did yu just say!
Yes! That's right
Uh, he address here is...
Yos! Thates right
Uh tho address hare is
Yes! Tholes right
Uh. the address here is...
Mr. Mouri...
The smell of almond
t's poisoning by cyanic acid.
There was po son in the coffee
cup that was on the floor...
NO poison whatsoever was
detected in the other three cups.
In other words, the culprit put
poison only in Mr. Yagami's cup...
That's right. Mr. Keda, you're
the one who got the drinks?
Yes sir. I took everyone's order
Everyone usually drinks hot
coffee while I drink Japanese tea.
But, doesn't a staff of the TV station
usually serve tea and things likc that?
OO, TR
I'm still a fledgling scriptwriter, so
I try to help out whenever I can...
Is: somethin¢ strange about what I did?
No. not really...
see! One of the cups in the hot
water room was smeared with poison
and«that-cup just happened
to go to Mr. Yagami.
Oh { $6 ousre sa Ing: that someones
wanted to commit at random murder?
I can't think of anything else...
So. you said: that you d-serve the coffee
but Mr. Koda insisted on doing it himself.
Yes. he said he'd do it... himself
May I have a moment with you. Inspector .
Ms. Inouo. will you ploasc como with mo?
Judging from the circumstances
the only one who would've been able
to mix the poison in the drink is Mr. Koda.
His remark of it being a random killing is
shaky justification
and we feel that he's our man
But. what's his motive?
You brat, I told ou to stay in your room
Butyhe's writing for the same
program, isn't he?
Why would he want to
poison his colleague?
He may be a colleague but...
Is something bothering your
Please tell us about it. This is
a homicide case. you know!
The scripts of Dotective Fluke wero
ply (Ol) WIRE Ly Cot
The scripts of "Detective Fluke" were
originally being written by both
Mr. Yagami and Mr. Sakumadby turns.
Then, this man who introduced himself
as a fervent fan of the program brings
a plot that he had written to me.
J te 6) foo) IR
to be verytintcresting.
So, I decided to have him work for us
as our 3rd scriptwriter.
Although Mr. Sakuma evaluated him highly,
Mr. Yagami for some reason didn't like him
Therefore, Mr. Yagami had repctedly
told me to take him off the program...
Bid"Mr. Koda know about this?
I think he could sense it
from the atmosphere.
I'm sure it was a very trying
situation for Mr. Koda...
Which means...?
Ms. Inoue.
I want to write as many scripts of
this popular program as I can,
sell my name and succeed as a scriptwriter.
Mr Koda wee ai dn +) hie folio
on "Detective Fluke."
os um
But, Mr Yag mi wanted to get
Mr. Koda off the project no matter what! .
Nspector. theres no coubt that he
He does have a motive...
But. if he did do it...
But of he did do it
Hey. .Mr: Mouri. wait!
\ Hal
We already know who the killer is!
But we don't have any material
evidence whatsoever yet!
Besides. there are things
that are not solved yet
Quiet!! I'll make him spit it out!
I. Detective Kogoro Mouri will!
Are ou sure?
Huh?! I, I killed Mr Yagami 7?!
You:re'suspecting that I did it? N.No way...
Well, it's true that I
slightly hated him. but...
Mr. Mouri, even if I wore to have
put poison into the coffee cup.
I wouldn't make Mr. Yagami drink it./
Because out of the three cups
onl one-would be roisoned.
Moreover. I left to go get milk
so I wasn't there
In ether words,
I didn't urge him to drink it.
In other words,
But Mr. Yagami drank
it of his own initiative...
could've known that Mr. Yagami
would choose the coffce cup he chose.
Am I wrong?
WwW. Well...
W... Well...
That's it. If he's the killor
That's it. If he's the ki ler
how did he make Mr. Yagami choose
the cup he drank out of?
Hew did he make Mr. Yagami choose
the cup he drank out of
I seal
M. Mr. Mouri?
You brought the drinks and gave the cup
AOR fie) xotieson edlclo §0O uk (0000,
which loaves two cups remaining.
Two cups would be the same
as I mentioned earlier.
I'd have no idea which one
Mr. Yagami would choose.
VES Ex o» ANN YO [¥=n&
ne it up this way to begin with...
Mr. Yagami was sitting just about
here, in the room back then
He would most natdrally
Q €& Ne Cup Ya IS neares on Aim.
Moreover, Mr. Sakuma would never pick up
his cup before Mr. Yagami. his superior.
0 sea
wonder about that .
No, though he 1s my superior
and I came In after him,
we know each other quite
well, so even back then
I took the coffee cup before Mr. Yagami
and gave him the remaining cup .
If'thatss the case doesn't that make
Mme suspicious (7?
Mr. Mouri, if you want to implicate
me SO much
Just what kind of trick did I use to
make sure Mr. Yagami drank the poison?
Figure that out first
Those challening eyes, he's gotta be
the suspect
And he's confident about the trick he used.
Two drinks between two people
Iho porcontage of each choice is 50'/%
Just what kind of trick€«did ho uso to
Rel I Joo
Mr. Mouri, to be honest, I have my
doubts about suspecting Mr. Koda.
If by chance. Mr Sakuma and not
R AAJA ¢ 10s 12 O1IS0ONNnGaC CO QC
he would have to stop Mr Sakumn
no matter what But. he...
Ieft the room saying
that he forgot the milk...
If he were the killer, would he
Ieave the scene?
That's true. Didn't it cross his
mind that an accident could occur?
Hmm?! Hoy!
Are you listening to me. Mr Mouri.
I wonder what's going to happen to
Detective Fluke"... from now 0...
Is it going to end?
J don't know. But with
something like.this happening
After all'thé effort.that was
put intoxwritingithe scripts...
Oh. is that the list tor "Detective Fluke?"
May I have a look at 1t?
May I have a look at it?
Go ahead.
mung: _
ze. WE
pa TA ORS
hank you!
WAY CW
want
nty=04 v
GRAD
What lb at?
That was Mr. Koda's script, wasn tit,
the one oentitlod
22nd Closed Roomy Murder.
Oh, the ono you $11d tht
you thought was interesting too.
Actually, that was tho first plot
that Mr. Koda brought here.
I was also surprised that 1 new
scriptwriter with such talent existed
What /!
Mr Koda also wrote the
Supporting Performers Club ™ 2!
Yes. what is it?
Don't tell me.
Most of the scripts aro written by
both Mr. Yagami and Mr. Sakuma.
Ififl
Thoy're after all the main scriptwriters so...
4&52
Thoy're after all the main scriptwritors so...
They're after all the main scriptwriters so
I hey:refafiariall the main scriptwriters so.
In;otherword:. no matter how talented he
IS. 'herdoesn.t have the chance to display it.
Anduf that's the motive
every mystery is solved!
What's the matter. Conan?
Ms. Inoue!
I've finally arrived at the gE
It seems that he's figured out 1B ck!
C.Can't be.
There are two people and two drinks. I
Tha way to make the target
drink the poison for sure is...
No malt-tor how much I think.
There's only one way
That's...
To believe in luck
Mr. Maura?! 1» Is that the conclusion
you've reached
Inspector! This is no joke.
The rate of success 1S 50%
You took a s nk or swim chance.
Your desperate feeling of not
wanting to be removed
from the script writing of "Detective Fluke
made you take the dreadful
risk of sink or swim.
- That's enough.;Mr Mour
No. Inspector! I'm saying
this with conviction.
M.Mr= Mouri?!
Could this be the rumored...
Sleeping Kogoro?!
I took a sink or swim chance?
Are ou serious about What ou're sa ing?
At one point I really thought so. but...
MM. Mr. Mouri. my God...
Please hear me out. Inspector.
Mr Koda. you said, to solve the mystery of
the trick you used to make Mr. Yagami
cheese the poisoned coffee (if
we're 90mg to bUbl-NIH-fl you.
But that's impossible. Because.
You used no trick to begin with.
T.There's no trick?!
T.There*s no trick?!
No. nothing at all.
If SO. how did he make
Mr. Yagami drink the poisoned coffee?
Before I tell you that, please let me explain
how I came to such a-conclusion.
Conan. bring me the stuff.
Oh, oka...
This 1s the list of the scripts of
Detective Fluke that Conan just borrowed.
I was surprised at seeing this
One among severa scripts is an
extremely well written mystery story.
Ingenious tricks. logical mystery solving.
And most of all a story development
that sticks to unbiased standards...
For example, "52nd Closed*Door Murder
is one of them.
So is "Supporting Performers Club,
Evil Well Murder.
And When the Door of Fate Opens *
hose scripts are all
es, all those scripts that
I thought to be amazing
were those that you have written Mr. Koda
re Ofter ne 0X
that's when I changed my mind.
When I found out,
A person such as you who writes such
a perfect mystery story would never
A personlsuch as you who writes such
take a sink or swim chance
when the SUCLLbS nan us {>070
and I Hogan to GUOSLHON Your Mowe...
That's, why: did youmleave the place
back then
That is, why did younleave the place
back then.
You of course had it in mind beforehand
that you would say that you forgot the milk.
You may have wanted to
instill the impression on everyone
that you had nothing to do with
which cup of coffee
We Ye oh end) Me, Sra
were going to choose. but
that action of yours is suspiciously
strange after all
Because as Inspector Meguro
had mentioned earlier...
If byrchance, Mr. Sakuma had -chosen
the poisoned coffee instead of Mr. Yagami.
You would've 'had to stop him
from drinking it no matter what.
That's right, no matter how goed your plan
IS It can always go wrong.
You, who writes flawless mysteriesm would
not overlook that fact
Nevertheless. you left the meeting room
There 1s only one possible answer.
You did not only target Mr Yagami!
At aout
Just what are you trying to get at,
Mr. Mouri?...
It didnrtomatter whether
Mr. Yagami or Mr. Sakuma drank it.
That's why no trick needed to be used
In other words, you're saying that I V
he didn't care which of us hé killed!
You monn it was such
flimsy murder plan?!
This is no flimsy plan Inspector
No matter who.dies,
the result:he 'wantsiis achieved.
So long as one of the two main
scriptwriters disappears
the chance of the 3rd scriptwriter,
Mr. Koda getting to intreduccehis
writings would increase tremendously...
He wanted to write as many scripts of
Detective Fluke" as he possibly could.
This 1s probably the real motive
for the murdefithat was committed.
Is it not. Mr. Koda... >
Ms. Inoue.
PA) RDO GO MO 08 Gin «XO Of hls
program as I possibly can. sell my name
and make a name for myself
as a successful scriptwriter!
MIR, [Ok
At first glance it looked to be a plan
with only 50% chance of succcecedimg
Bu. Ah wom violate wing Or tic
o drank the poisoned coffe
the rate of success would be 1004.
I 888
I 888...
el 2, You
By age 30 I'll be a writer in great demand...
That's my goal as a scriptwritor
hat's my (Ba as a scriptwriter...
What's this thing about being
a writer in demand.
Eveniif you write only one in ten scripts.
Those who read your scripts can
all tell how talented you are...
Even Ms. noue evaluated
your scripts highly
I recmombaoer all your scripts too
They were all so very good...
I rOomomb or all your scripts too
I romembeor all your scripts too
[hey woerne all so very, good \
You're so stupid,
Original Comic Books By.
TOSHO AOYAMA
Producers
Mic HIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIORA
Background Music
ka Y00 ONO
hr rater Designs By.
MAS/HOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 11OKA
Saripls-By.
KANJI KA -'HIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUGHI
I MIYASHITA
! HI HIGURE
T@OSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors.
MAsATdMo sum)
HIROTDSHITAKATANI
HARUO OOGAWARA
AISUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YOKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
TAKASHI woman
HIRONOBU HORIKC > 11
TAKAHISA OWA
Recording Direalot.
KATSUYOSHI KQBAYASIHIT
Editor.
TERUMIISU OKADA
Chictf Direwtor
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, (TD
In«rssocration with
YOMIURI TEIE@ASTINC
GORPORAIIGN
DELIV ON
CAND VOY AMY sd TONAL eT TMM
ES uryed
So "Detective Fluke's
going to end:-after all...
8» EAT
Agh?!
Detective Fluke ends, and a new
series of "Detective Fluke" will begin!
YL Yd
It says that the name of the main
character's going to be changed from
Rintaro Fluke to "Kogoro Fluke".
Kogoro Fluka #
It sounds like Kogore's a fluke!
That's what you actually are. no?
Judging from how you were all acting
I figured that you may have come Up with
some unthinkable deduction
Tsuburayn Mitsuhiko. my life's
greatest mistake
Whit if we don't make it? We should've
told Conan about this
Genta!
The Youth Detective Squad
Pursues the Bluebird!