CY Xow
Stars are for some reasonrattractive W
They can be the culprit or the actor, AI
Yuka's bluebird that's
supposed to bring happiness
Turns INtY 4 Caso
urns Iintd a case.
Hurry/to the scene Youth Detective Squad!
He soes through the ono and only truth
A child In appearance
with the Ir@. of an adult
NH casa is left unsolved
with Dectoctive Conan.
The Youth Detective Squad
Pursues the Bluebird!
Breve it sure is cold again today too .
It seems that low temperature usual
for the end part of November
has been continuing for the past 3 days!
Nukes
What /!
MS, . 0 NO fn deed Co
She's always standing
I MBMIS MIKO IAN ORCAS OS WatEN ING {I= [odlrteks,
in front of the cage watching the birds WV
Yuka!
Agh?! Ayumi...
Do you like birds?
Yes. I love them!
I have a budgie at home too. a blue one.
Oh, what's its name?
Chicch He's two years od and]
Jocrehius on people's hands
;He also talks just a little bit.
You mean he speaks words 4
I want to see hi 1!
Okay. Do you want to stop over
atm house toda ?
Bl BO!
Mc too! May I?
You're Conan and Al. right?
Oh" yes...
You two are also welcome to come
But, all ef us ¢o once
Don't worry about it=mother 1s at work
,r~ v
and won't be enc till early evening
Oh, your'!parents are both working
Same with me.
In my case... it's abit different though
Huh?!
Yuka's fathagldiad of an (illness)
two years ago.
Oh, is that right!
Come let's go.together Conan.and Ar~
Come letis go together Conan and Al
Iet's all go see the ,.hand perching budgie!
Let's go!
We did it!
WIneX? CC) YO CO?
Huh!
Huh?!
Do you know how to tell the difference
betwecn an adult male and female?
Hmm... is it the size of their bodies?
Is:.it the pattern on the feathers,
You can tell by the color of the cere of
the parakect which is above the beak
Makes have blue ceres
while females have brown ones...
Exactly!
But despite Chicchi being a male.
His cere has recently been turning brownish
I"'wonder why?
Cave... Heave..we-re not there Bet?
J. Huh The door...it's unlockod.
What?!
M.Maybe it's a thief?!
Huh /!
Stand) back. everybody!
Okay! Ready.
All right! Hah
Y You two?!
Y.You two?!
G Go ahead!
I'm ready!
WwW. Who are you?!
A thief?!
OW 1H
Welcome home. Yukat
Huh?!
Po yous know him?
No I don't.
9 >. 4
She's saying she doesn't know you!
YOU re a thief after all!
No. I'm Shinya Sakaguchi
I work at the Beika University research lab
of the Engineering Department.
Na friend of Yuka's mothe
Yuka's mother manages 1
jardening shop in Hardocho
ind since she s gong to be
coming home ate from work today.
I was asked to eat out
together with Yuka tonight.
Your mother 8 that
she told you so.this morning too...
Oh... she didn't si. an thinc to me.
YY Wen
Please wait!
How did you come into the house?
Well. .Yuka's mother told me
where the house key as hidden...
Everybody!
Never mind him, and come on in.
Hello!
Aaagh...
n other words...
you're very intimate friends
with her mother.
Huh?!
Ahaha if) m sorry
Will you stop pushing me...
Wow: it's so spacious!
The gardens nice too
But. why are the windows all open?
Oh. well,
pair.
I just thought that It would be nice to
air the room out before Yuka came home.
Bd § Re wy aw
Chicchi. I'm home!
How cute!
Its color is beautiful too.
What's the matter?
Nothing but it seemsfthat
Chiechi's become slightly smaller...!
Nothing but it seems that
Chiechi's become slightly smaller.
Nothing... but It seems that
Chicchi's become slightly sma ler
What?!
Don't think so. It's just your imagination.
* qo.
Chicchi! Chicchi!
Chicchi, "Welcome back. Say,
Welcome back.
Strange. he always says
Welcome back when I come home. but.
( Ly y
I.I'm sure he's nervous because a lot of
your friends that he doesn't know is here.
Di< he talk this morning?
Yep. he said,
Good morning very energetically.
«> «<__
Whaa!
Ticklish! So ticklish!
Its were really is brown. isn't it?
Yeah...
Oh. do you have a.col 78 O
WY. Yes. just slightly y
Is that why you're standing
away from everyone else I
because you don't want us to catch. cold?
Y.Yes Cough...cough...
I wonder why he had all the glass windows
pen despite having a cold
It sure is strange.
Let's have some juice. okay?
Hey'?
"Il bet you letsthelbird-goR
Huh?
You went to the pet shop and bought a bird
that looks just like the one she had. right?
You left the windows open because
the bird that fled may come back...
I get it!
And you bought a bird
that was a bit smaller!
That's why it doesn't talk!
@ome on and spit out the truth!
Come on and spit out the truth!
N.No! Just what are)you talking about!
You spilled soy sauce. didn't you? .
_» ed
Huh?
When llopadned the refrigerator
I..smelled soy sauce!
Oh, right
The soy sauce container fell a while ago
when ll'was putting t! e cake that
I got for you inte the refrigerator.
Don't you dare open the refrigerator of
other people's houses without permission!
What's all the shouting for, Yuka
Mother?!
Hello!
,Hello.My client suddenly
canceled the appoit tment
Mr. Sakaguchi. let's go eat out together.
Oh. no. I'll leave for today
Huh... But...
Okay then, Conan, Al
see you both tomorrow!
Eah. It's already late
so go home straight oka
Y.Yes!
You guys go straight home and don't
go rendezvousing some place together!
Well maybe that's not 4 bad idea
Huh?!
Y.You gotta be kidding!
- - OF
My. what are you all worked up about,
Conan?
Conan is as donse as ever.
But. we've got to check this out.
Rea Wied
Come on. et sgol
Come on. letss go.
Yes. .a person
WC Foot) [DOR
who 10Oks like this
did come to buy a blue parakeet...
aboutt o hours. go...
R.Really"
Just as We thought!
ust as We thought
Just liké m said}.
That man let the parakeet go!
Oh! But. ho...
Oh! But he...
was holding a dead parakeet in his hand.
What?!
And, he sud to give him 1 parakeet
just hike the one he was holding
He scemad to He wa rush Lo.
It" so shocking that
Chicchi was already dead...
Um. but Yuka said that thebird greeted
her in good health this morning and
said "Good morning didn't she?
Yes... Which means
the bird didn't die of an illness
Besides, it was in a cage so
it couldn't have died accidentally either...
Could it be that the man killed it?
Butiif he rushed to go buy
another parakeet after what happened.
We 1t least know that
he didn't do it on purpose.
Then. he mistakenly killed WW?
Huh? What kind of work?
Sos.
Mr Sakaguchi mentioned that he 1s working
at the research lab at Beika University
didn't he?
I was just wondoring
what kind of research he was doing...
Well don't renllyknow, but I think
he's researching some kind of dru yy.
WOW)
But. it.it can't be!
But...I'm sure it was some kind of drug...
Agh! Conan.
Doe you have a relative
by the name of Kithdar?
Ag onan
Do you have a relative
by the name of Kitada?
Agh! Don't, Ayumi!
Do you have a relative
by the name of Kitada?
Huh?!
Well. because he always gets tho credit.
So. this time. let's solve the truth ourselves.
B.But...
Oka. . Ayumi?
O Okay...
Hi. I'm sorry to keep youwwaiting...
We're sorry ig) have called you out like this
despite your busy schedule.
We're sorry!
Is your resoarch lab in here?
Yep. it is...
May we see it?
Ou can't.
Why not?
Boecause there are many
dangerous chemicals inside.
Dangerous chemicals?
Just as we thought!
Actually
we went to the pet shop yesterday...
Actually .
We went to thejpet shop yesterday...
Huh?
The employee told us everything
Will you plbase explain the situation?
Lil-m sorry...l lied yesterday...
The facts, when I got to Yuk's house,
Chicchi'was dead in the cage...
Yuka real ytook good care of Chicchl
sO I thought she'd be sad of
she-came back and found out.
That's why I rushed over to the, pet shop
- andsbought a parakeet
tht looks just like Chicchi that
perches on'hands at the pet shop.
Then,
what did you do with Chicchi that died ?
After I left Yuk1's house at sundown,
I buried it in a park nearby.
Would you please take us there?
Huh?!
We'd like to offer our prayers
Yeah
I rom Tow? Well
You can't take us?
I'm in the midst of amexperiment right now.
[Warmth mm:
maybe some othe time I'm sonry!
M.Mr. Sakaguchi!
M.Mr Sakaguchi!
Plik Al
There's something suspicious about him.
There's no doubt that
he's the one who killed Chicchi!
But... I wonder what he: did-te Kill it?
Thank you very much.
Pals
Hmm. isn't it thisrway?
He probably mistakenly spilled the chemical
that he brought back from the research lab
VAR:
HAIRS OTB WATER IA KS HIN FEI) Ue Glivciinties)
that he brought back from the research lab
Ii) Ghat ETR7 Cake fine)
fe) 0) Wei eOEREE Off $0 Creeks,
and the parakeet drank it...
B 1. hats tee mu ; of a goincidence,
ou thin ?
Maybe it was an. aerosolized-toxin!
Huh?
What's that air something about?
Aerosolized toxin. Genta! In other words.
The parakeet inh1lod the. vapor of a
poison thathe mistakenly spilled!
If this is what happened,
everything falls into place!
If this as what happened.
Everything falls into: placer:
Huh?!
Mr Sakaguchi opened the
windows and door of Yuka's'house
because he thought that. . the vaporized
poison may still be left"in thezair...
His eyes were bloodshot and
he was coughing because
he inhaled the vaporized poison by mistake
hat's why-he stayed away from us.
That is, he'stayed away from he place
he:spilled the poison!
I see!: SO" the thing aboutd: im
havingra cold was also a lie!
Hello!
Hello?
Yuka
Oh. h. hello!
Thank you for 1ll the food yesterday!
Oh, not at all. I didn't do anything at all.
Arc you shopping?
Yesy
we're having hand-wrapped sushi tonight!
Oh. what.a-coincidence!
We revgeing, to Docs house
tonight to eat hand-wrapped sushi too!
Huh?! Doc'.
Dr Ag 191
Is Mr=Sakaguchi coming for dinner too?
Well. I asked him over
but he turned me down
s 1ying that he is busy tonight...
Please come over again. O
Yes. Goodby)!
wasit okay not telling]them about the man? **
wast okay not telling them: about the-man?=-
WAS WON Cn
at we should « 0100. but
Maybe we should tell"therm I
after things:become clearer.
Hello!
OR YA 00
Oho, ho...vinegar rice.
I smell vinegar rice
Doc. whoro's Conan 2!
Oho, ho...vinegar rice.»
I smell vinegar rice
Conan again...
Oho, ho...vinegar rice.
I smell vinegar rice
Huh?!
It's nothing
It's nothing...
He'll probably... get here soon.
Al, would you like me
to help you with something?
Oh? Well,
would you line out the plates then?
Okay! Sure.
The point is why Mr. Sakaguchi
brought the poison to Yuka's house.
Don't tell me that he wns trying te
poison Yuka orthcramother
I don't want to think that way,.
but the possibly cannot be denied either
Then maybe hoe already may have
Huh?! Yeah. cake, cake!
PUl something in the cakeithvathe bough 2!
Genta! We already ale the cake
at her house yesterday!
Wall. it's' really 'notienough.
Lo PH UTES Gnd]
NOOO HO), Wee, DOO
Come to think of it.
Yukadidn't eat the cake 1t all
Shaeprobably really doesn't like
Mr Sakaguchi.
But. then. what om earth's...
[3 next
he just took the poison to the house
ind hasn't-donc anything with it yt
Otherwiso. we wouldn't. be here
taking it easy like this.
Al, hero's tho soy sauce
wonder if this will be enough?
The soy sauce container-fell.
Shoots!
Huh? Don't tell me he put it in there 2!
That's why Mr Sakaguchi refused to
have hand wrapped sushi together
with them tonight!
What!
Oh. no!
We've got to stop them quick!
What, What is it?
I'm going with you!
GY LIT
H.Hey. wait!
Vr vere tr wv rtar BH Tad
I wonder...
Mitsuhiko Tsuburayn has made
the mistake of a life timely
We should've told Conan
about this to begin with!
There you go. Conan again!
What if we don't... make it in time?
Heave. hOdVG. aghlwhaaa!
GGenta?!
In 07
Aa!! The traffic light's red!
Uuuugh
Uwe ugh
Quick! Quick!
Turn green! Turn green!
Plcasc, lot us make it in time!
Let's go around to the yard!
Kan )
W,Wu made at!
T. They're alive.
Huh?!
I.I'm so glad.
Whaaaan!
What's the matter everybody?
D.Don't use that soy sauce! It is poisoned
Poi...son?
What-re you talking about?
It's not poisoned
We-re already usi g it and eat ng.
Huh?
Yes!
Oh...Conan!
Agh...
Mr. Sakaguchi...
Just as I thought.
I thought this is what you guys were up to!
Conan. what brings you here?
Based on your appearance. you look like
your deduction is messed up.
Then, is it true that when Mr Sakaguchi
came here, Chicohr was dead?
Yoah Very ofton hittlo birds peck on food
until just before they die.
and act healthy trying to hide
the fact that they are ill.
Why /
When living in flocks. if they display
any signs of being weak from an illness
They ma. become rey to an enemy
and: lose their life. right?
Even If the parakeet is
tame enough to perch on fingers
it has rem ning instincts of
when it used to be in the wild
I see.
That's why it was saying "Good morning
healthily hike always until yesterday morning
But,
there were signs of an upcoming illness.
Tho core of male parakeots scom to change
from blue to brown when they get sick.
Right. Chicchi's cére became brown
because he wasn't in good health.
I didn't know that.
So, Mr. Snkwgucfni (indnélqaouffitvzor
have bloodshot cyes because...
he inhaled poison
No. Mr Sakaguch really had a cold
He hadnititaken a bath for three days.
So. he thought that he "had: bod. odor...
That's why he opened
the windows and doors to keep the smell
from onvoloping tho room...
Moreover. that's the very reason why
he was standing some distance away"
from Yuka after she came home.
She's a girl So. I thought
she'd dislike me even more if I smelled...
I'm sorry. Yuka.
He came awhile ago to tell me
that I should tell you the truth.
hat it would save you from being hurt.
That's when I first realized how stupid I was.
Life is invaluable.
I think that you're regretting the fact that
you didn't realize sooner that he was ill...
But, Chicchi was taken good care of by you,
and I'm sure he was really happy
Since @higeny's cure was brown,
I mistakenly bought a female yesterday.
It's a budgie!
The sere Is blue. It's a male!
NY ve To
Wow! Fantastic!
I was thinking about
whether it's good or not
- Aw NV owe -
to buy a new budgie
right after Chicchi.died but.
Thank you
How lucky. You've got a family now...
Original Comic Books By.
GGOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MIL HIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YCSHIORA
Background Music.
KAISUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
UNICHI I1OKA
Sarapts By.
KAN]! KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHI IA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
bn Directors
MAS TOMO SUDO
HIROTWSHI TAKATANI
OOGAWARA
ATSU HI AONO
AKITOYRAWAMURA
TAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photography.
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIK >)
YAKAHISA OWA
PRCCor™ ing Director.
KAISUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
II RUMITSU OKADA *
Editor
IERUMITSU OKADA
Editor.
[+ RUMIISU OKADA
IERUMITSU OKADA
Chief Dir. ctor.
KENT KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
In «aidsSoct1ation with
YOMIURI-TELE@ASTINC
CORPORATION
PIP FOIE ARNTY
OH a AMY SHOWER NVI TMA
NOE ROVE
They sure are late
I wonder what they're doing?
Why don't you-gg .thead and eat already.
R.Right! Sandwichgice like so Supreme
Soy. here goes! Munch...
Sigh...
Whether it's sushi or 7 play on words,
the point is how fresh they are...
The five cases that happened here.
Ph EEOD
EEL K
3 (37 AB D5
The five cases that happened here
fin anmaam
3 (37 AB DBE
The five cases that happened here
HEED Dal
AHL K
HIE ANBOHR
The five cases that happened here
they say... The first occurred on Feb
4th the year before last.
The next, on July 4th..;.-Last year it also
happened on Feb. 4th and July 4th.
Tihis year was on April 4th, right?
Which means,
the day before was a Butsumetsu?
The Evil-Spirit that
Appears on Butsumetsu-The Case 4