Matective Conan will be going into
its 10th year
Daotoctive:Conan will be going into
its 10thryear
One down and more to come!
The unlucky day calendar is
a point of conc .rn
An apparition i1sicreated from a nightmare
Homicide despite tight security
Ho soos through the ono and only truth
A childpin appoarance,
with tho I.Q. of an:adult
No case Is left unsolved
with Detective Coin.
E.Evil spirit?! You're asking me
Yo get id of the curse of an vil spit!
Evil.spint?! You're asking mc
to get rid-of-the-curse---of-an-evil spirit?!
"9300
E. Evil spirit?! You're asking me
tO g8tarid of-the~curse=-of-an-evil spifit?!
On300
E. Evil spirit?! You re asking me
tovgetsridr*ofsthc curse of amevilespinité?!
Y.Yes, wel . to put it straightforwardly...
MR At Arar a nua nolvard Arlaste ans
You see... detective solves cases...
Oh. of cour=e, we've asked priests and
clairvoyants to try and perform exorcisms
but nothing seems to be working <0 far
So! We have gone for the last resont
tho Mourn Dotoctive Agency..inThopos
that you may be able to solve this
paranormal phenomena scientifically...
And?
Just what Is that paranormal phenomenon,
It all startec with a nightmare that the
master of the house had seen 2 years ago...
A.A nightmare...
He jumped up from bed screaming
inka: chilling voice that was out of this world
repeating time again that,
It's a curse...I'm going to be killed...
But. that was only a dream. right?
4 O.0Of course, that's not the only thing!
Six months after that
the brakes of th's car
that the master was riding went out of
controland he bare y escaped a big accident
Right. Mr. Watabiki!
You remember. don't you?!
Y.Yes... I didn't realize that
the brakc oil was leaking...I'm sorry.
Bocuse of that accident, the master
came down with a heart ailment...
His eye became sunken and
his hair turned completely white.
It can also be considered a mere accident.
In what way IS an evil spirit involved?
We can't help but think
Its the doings of an evil spirit!
With this kind of card being sent to us!
Hmm?
TH EEE DO SS Aull
HIE ABOR
Qlmfloouw
I HER er OS Bul
(3 HA BD
Alone your sins before I awaken.
I am the 5th soul...
HHER and al
(3 FAB DR
YALE SRS Date I awe em
I am the 5th soul...
FH BEE SD SS aul
EEL RD KR
HIE ABOR
Atone your sins before I awaken.
I am the 5th soul...
mh ERH DHE
ZBL OK
(2A AB DR
Atone your sins before I awaken.
I am the 5th soul.
Wh ERD DH
ETEURSZGDJI
(3 AHAB DBR
VOL is DEO [I Gwelen
I am the 5th soul...
HHBRBED Saul
EMBULROK
Fe 1x HA AB one
you ES nsihefenclfawaken
I am the 5th soul...
TH "BED Dall
mL KR
3 (3 HA B DR
YOURS DN SIE ere] No Re
I am the 5th soul...
HHBREHDEN
ZA 3 LN OD I~
HIE ABOR
Atone your sins before I awaken.
I am the 5th soul...
TA AN
The Evil Spirit that Appears
on Butsumetsu-The Case
And, when did you get this card...?
Around a We alter New Years Day
Iast year. It was in the mailbox...
At first. we thought it was just a prank,
hut whon I showod it to tho master
his wife was also very surprised
His wife was also surprised
Yes...
Then six months later,
the dish cabinet suddenly toppled over...
Furthermore, in April this year a queer
sound was heard from inside the house
where only the master and
his wife were supposed to be...
Uh... Was there something in common about
the days when strange things happened?
Maybe like things always happened on
Friday the w13th or something like that...
\...no.the days were at random
but the date was always on the 4th...
Then, maybe something happened
on the 4th previously?
But. no one has an idea.
U.Uh today is Oct. the 3rd,
so tomorrow is the problem date. the 4th...
Oh. that's true...
Uh. It seems that stranggathings
happened 5 times so far...
Do you remember what
year and what month it was?
Oh. no... don't...
I do!
Uh at first...
2 ears ago on Fob
4th the master had a nightmare...
Then, he got into an accident I
n the same year on July 4th #
A ear ago. on Feb. 4th
a strange card was found in the mailbox
ind on July 4th the same year
the dish cabinet fell...
On April 4th this year, a strange sound
was heard from inside the house...
You've taken notes of everything!
Yes...l have to write things down
because I'm sorforgetful
He's just like you. Conan.
Y.Yep.
Maybemthe sender of this card is
up to something.
By the way,
don't you sense anything about this card...?
Huh? Sense something?
You mean like something spiritual...?
Well, you know...
Oh, well if you don't sense anything...
Hey. hey! I heard differently!
I thought
we were going to have just one guest?
My daughter insisted on coming so.
I'm sorry...
R rr 7
I'm sorry
No. I'm not angry at you people!
I'm angry at this old man here *:
who didn't bother to contact me!
Old man... Namika...
I've got to go and shop for more stuff then...
You sure have a perky daughter
No...she's the chef...
Chef. . 71
Her father used to be the
chef for the Kunitomo family.
But. he died of an accident.
And she succeeded him!...
Oh... she's still so young...
Come to think of it,
he also took after his father.
Hat's right, Mr. Watablki!
The master will be going to the
University Hospital at 20:00 tonight...
Oh es sir...
H.Huh?
Here!
Use this
T.Thank ou...
IT. Thank you...
Huh?
O@h..I'm sorry)
Please don't be offended
I experienced food poisoning
when I was a child.
And since then
I've become a neat paranoiac...
Here you go...Thank you...
Okay...
Conan'...
We're going to eave youlbehind!
Leave him! Leave him!
Huh? The master and his wife?! saw them
a while ago.in the 3rd floor bedroom
Okay...
Huh?
What is it?
You sure look like the chef
we saw a while ago.
Ouch!
DJDadW
D.Dad!
Of course we 10Ok like!
Namnka as my daughter!
Oh. no wonder...
And, please don't point your finger at me,
okay? I have belonepthobia.
Oh. see...
Belonephobia...?
Dad!...
If you have a messagc for the master)
shall I go relay it for you?
No. .I'll go see him myself.
By the way, Shigeko...
That picture...
Huh?
Will you please fix it in place?
I think it is about 5 millimeters
tilted to the right
Huh?
5 millimeters...
Y.Yes. sir!
Thank ou.
Shall we go. then...
{mm 2
What a strange place for a door to be...
Oh. that's.
The door that a friend of Mrs. Kunitomo
installed after they received that weird card
It's quite some door.
Oh...?
U push the pass code. like so
and place your index finger here...
Who is it?
Rm Akatsuka the steward
I've brought Detective Mourl with ma.
Oh...I'll open the door right away...
Like so...
Wow. fantastic!
It's made SO that the bell
doesn't ring inside unless
s the registered] fingerprint
of 1 family member.
T's just like some science fiction movie
It's not science fiction at all.
Hmm?
Huh?
There are condos equipped with
fingerprint recognition machines nowadays
Although. it's not that all widespread'yet...
Right... This is Mrs. Yasue Kunitomo,
and the person to the left is the person
who made the door,
Mrs. Kunitomo's friend. Mr. Sekiguchi...
Um, it seems that someone who
was inside opened this door a while ago
but what If nobody Is
on the 3rd floor either 7?
No one can open the door...
Except for my husband
whose fingerprints are set
inside the fingerprint recognition machine
Anyone in this house can go out by placing
his finger on the machine though...
So...I'dulike to give it a try...
Don't touchiiit!.
Whaaall
When someone from outside places
his finger on the machine,.
the alarm within the house
will go off and the people
from the security office will rush over here!
().Oh
0.Oh
I also thought that we should put up
surveillance cameras too. but...
I told him not to do it...
IV told him not to do it...
A camera at the front entrance 1s okay but...
I have something against setting up
such exaggerated security precautions
in this fine house that my father had built...
I think it has enough exaggerated
ecurity precautions a ready...
Oh...You're Mr Mouri
the renown detective!
Y.Y.es.
I'm Kunitomo. the one who asked for you...
Ouch. ow. ow...
I'm counting on you
as far asithe investigation is concerned...
Y.Y.Yes sir!
I shall give you a quick tour #&
of the house then...
Thank ou...
Hey. kid. hurry up!
Oh. okay!
I 1111000
Are you sure
It's okay calling a detective over. .?
If he finds out about the, you know what.
He won't There's no evidence
of it anywhere anymore.
But from what was written on that card...
That's why we hired a detective.
To have him catch the one
who is blackmail ing us and find out
how far he knows. right?!
Wait! Ill go: get your medicine right away.
Kuooooh...Kugh, kugh. kugh. kugh...
Here our medicine!
Ay. hey, are you okay
At the rate you're going. you're going to
rop dead before we catch the culprit.
Hay, watch your mouth!
You're the one to blame for
what happened to begin with, you know!
That's why Ism here. aren't I...
Tomorrow's the «Day in question, right?
Yes The day that
this mansion's mouse begins to move.
Wow...
Hmm?
[I x_=>..,(. ll ,
And'.
How Is it?
Muguh.
Muguh...
Tow?...It's good of course!
Oh. no. I'm not talking about the food.
But. rather the investigation...
I can't say yet, for now...
Dram
Even If someo re were to set it up so that
the dish cabinet would fall or
queer sounds would be made
I'm sure the gadgets
would've been retrieved by now...
Hey. not again!
Y Wearing-gloves when eating!
Everything's washed clean. How rude!
LI-'m sorry
Oh. it's "bout time
I take the master-to the hospital...
LC you, why don't you at ens
drink your coffec before you:go!
Those two get along well. don't they...
Yes... they're parents were best friends
and they're childhood friends...
Oh. excuse me,
could I have some coffee too!
Oh here .
Huh
Here, give it to me!
She's acrophoebic so she can't go near a
window that's more than 2nd floors high .
By the way,
that steward 1s a meticulous perfectionist
and hates things that are crooked.
Even if it's a tablecloth,
he finds that it's crooked.
See!
What the heck... 1s with this house?!
Neat paranoiac... an acrophobe,
and a meticulous perfectionist.
I took the job only because
I thought we could spend the night
at the mansion of a tycoon in Shizuoka...
@onan. we shou d've stayed home
fins kind of 8 yook stor
was going to come up. right'!
Huh. what're you looking at?
Oh, well... About the dates of the
5 incidents that happened here...
Tho first ono was, tho yor before Inst on
Feb. 4th. next it was July 4th Last year.
It was also on Feb 4th and July 4th
And this year, it's April the 4th, right?
Wonder why it's April 4th only this ear?
Beats me If it's the 5th,
Dad was out on eb. 5th and
July 5th last year and the year before last...
Huh?
Huh
Remember. you went to a wedding,
helped people move and
went on a trip
with the community committee...
Come to think of it...l went to a wedding
on the 5th of April this year too...
Uh...A lucky day is usually chosen for
weddings. trips and moving. night?
Oh, yeah...
Right.
Which means the day before
those days are all Butsumetsu?
B.Butsum tsu?.
Wit! If I remember correctly
the supermarket on 3-c ome will be having
a grand opening en Oct 5th,
the day after tomorrow.
Doimean to say that
tomorrow Oct. the 4th issButsumetsu and
and something's going to happen?!
Lo 56 exact. it's already today.
To be exact, it's already today.
What was that?!
What was that sound .
SPP)
Huh?
A.A shoe?...
Kyaaaaaahn aaaaah!
Oh. Mr. Akatsuka? This is Yasue...
We got a flat tire so we were a bit stalled.
We're late.
But we should be arriving there soon...
Huh?
What? Mr. Sekiguchi...?!
Y.Yes
On the veranda where your bedroom is...
We called the ambulance and
the police right away.
But theronly person
who can enter the 3rd floor is Mr. Kunitomo.
SO NO one has gone in et...
P.Please hurry back!
WwW. What on earth is going on.
It.It's a curse...It's an evil spirit after all.
Kugh...
D.Dear?!
Kuooooh...
Here's your medicine!
Mr. Watabiki. please hurry!
Y.Yes... I'll try my best...
The victim is
r. Toshimichi Sekiguchi age 43.
The estimated time of death is
4 hours ago between 20:30 to 21:00
Mr. Sekiguchiwas your friend,
Mrs. Yasue Kunitomo...
Yo WO
we were classmates in high school...
He 1s the president of
2 security. company NOW...
Oh.which means that
the fingerprint recognition device
installed at the entrance of the 3rd floor
was put there by Mr. Sekiguchi...?
Would you please tell me where
you were botween 20230 and 21:00¢
I was in 1 car, on my way
10 the hospital with my husband.
My husband has a heart ailment
sO on the 3rd of every month,
wergo to doctor acquaintance of ours
to have him checked
What time did you leave the house?
1.1 think it wns just about 20°00
Lip 60) YOU 30xiO00Ring
I'm sure that Mr. and Mrs. Kunitomo
Ift here at 20-00!
Oh... I s00
I came here to the 3rd floor at 5» minutes
to 8 in order to takc the two to the car...
Besides, at that time
r. Sekiguchi was alive.
Hmm... I see
Hmm... I sec...
C.Could Mr. Sekiguchi have
committed suicide?
Well. there are some queer points
as to his death...
The position of the rope tht
he put his neck through...
The position of thejrope that
IS much too close to the ruling
of the veranda!
Wold, he could've dona soraven if
he was lose...
Noe oo Vy
cxtremely difficult time doing so
So. this may homicide made to
Iook like a Nicide...
Well, it's hard to say just yct whether
it's suicide or homicide but...
There's NO mistake that this card
MW ammo [may um <11 "113: yz q
348)
will be the key to solving this case...
all Ye [YT end]
W. Where did yougget that?!
I found it in Mr. Sckiguchi's clothes
) ENE O pelts (x
You shouldn't do stuff
Iike that on your own...
Yeah
that's why I gave him a good licking...
Huh?
Right kd.
What is this-card anyway?
Sin of 13 years 140.
Beats me, it kind of looks to be 1
dying message too...
But, I guess we can 1sk the three who went
pale when they saw this card for the details?
What seems to be the matter'?
What seems to be the matter?
Does-something 13 ears ago come to mind
t was Just aboeuti13 years from no
Miama a
The master's cruiser had a marine accident
Marine accident
Yes. back men, every year.
Just about thisgtime
It was usual practice for all of us here
to go cruising on Master's boat. but...
got strandod off shore the SurugaO?Bay
Mr. and Mrs. Kunitomo and Mg. Sekiguchi .
Who just happened to be sailing
that day somehow made it to safety...
Ab. go au on
And. what about the others?.
Tho whereabouts of everyone
else is unknown...
The ship that sunk hasn't been
found yet ether.
Could it be that
Mr Sekuguchi caused the ship to sink
SO someone had a grudge against him?
Oh, well...I'm not't home at the sea.
And never went cruising with them so...
Since you two were saved, you know
what happened. don't you?
Huh?!
The reason why the ship sank...
No. bocause I was sleeping, when Mr
Sekiguchi suddenly shouted to run for it...
Wee were despornnate to flee that
we didn't know what was going on
Is there anybody here that
is the bereaved family of a victim of
that accident and working here?
YY %.
Which means that
this case may also be connected in
some way to the 5 oth x2rs incidents
that happened here...
5 incidents?
It happened...
Mr Kunitomo had nightmares
The car brakes didn't function,
The dish cabinaot-falls.down
In theynuddle of the might.
Ind strange sounds are heard in a house
where nobody else s supposed to be...
Oh...
And to top things off, is. this card
hat was found directly in the mailbox!
HhERDHIEN
Hg UL) LO) J.
TA AB DR
And to top things off, is this cand
that was found directly in the mailbox!
And to top things off, is this card
Huh?! P.Ploaso wait a minute!
Figfiwafil
LSD &K&
EABDOR
Huh?! P.Please wait a minute... .!
Mammal:
Hfiwdi
DAE DR
It looks exactly like the e¢ard tht
was found in on [Mr Sckiguchi, moreover
It looks exnctly like tho mm tint
was found in on Mr. Sekiguchi, moreover,.
If all the incidents are happening on
Bultsumelisu I the AW
I's natural to think that'someone
in this houso Is up to somothing, isn'tt?
somconc wheels still working here
and is a bereaved family member
of the victim of the accident I
That person riay have thought that
r. Sekiguehi was respoiTsible
or the accident and killed him...
So. please call the people who
fit in to this category rere"
YXes. she'...
Huh? Mr. Sekiguch's wristwatch...
Something's engraved on it...
E" and "N"
£" and "NN" would usually mean.
Oh? Maybe not. Which means...
Original Comic Books By.
(+OSHO AOYAMA
Producers
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIORA
Background Music
KA Two ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor
wripls By.
I KASHIWAL
Animation Dircclors
MAS YOMO SUDO
SHI TAKATANI
Hr NOOGAWARA
HI AONO
A ASHIHVODO
Art'DiFector
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
TAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIK( HT
YAKAHISA OW
"Recording Director.
Editor.
TERUMITSU OKADA
Edit Igy
IERUMIISY OKADA
Editon,
IERUMIIST OKADA
Editor.
TERUMIIST OKADA
Chief Director
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT, [TD
mmassoctalion with
YOMIURI TELE@ASTIN(
CORPORATION
ILA TINE ON AN
GLOVE TT AMA iota ve IM TR
RY¥p hits Reserva
'yr.
! Thais is absurd!
The thing that bothers me is that rope...
If my deduction is correct .
M: Mrs. Kunitomo!
It. It's a curse...
Mr. Kunitomo probably alse saw the ghost
Whaaaaaa!
Hurr up 2nd open the door!
Intruder!
CHEER)
The Evil Spirit that
Appears on Butsumactsu Suspicion