Dotective Cohan will be going into its
. 10th year One Hown -and more to come
The mystery deepens with the 2ndlincident
(It ism-he existence of something»
that's not supposed to
[his gives tho ovil spirit rackot a boost!
This gives the evil spirit racket a boost!
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance with
the 1.QQ. of an Tun
No case as left unsolved
with Detective Conan
We were invited to visit the house
of a tycoon living in Shizuoka Prefacture
But. the request of the
client was a dfficult one
RH EBD Dau
3 (3 FAB DBR
BU iSthelieques Tofathe)
client was a difficult one
wHBEEH Dw
EMBL KX
wlZHEABDHR
asking to scientifically explain
the curse of an evil spirit
At the-house
For, the past-few-ycrs,
the sa on Butsumetsu the 4th, occurs.
Andlion Butsumetsu:of October 4th,
the misfortune befalls the first victim...
The victim is Mr. Toshimichi
Sekiguchi, age 43...
3% OF
- {PR -
Well, we (can't tell whether
it's suicide or homicide et but...
IF aD
The card that reads,
I atone my sins of 13 years ago.
The cared that rods,
Il atone my sins of 13 years ago
is sure to be the key {o solving the case...
ust about 13 years from now...
The master's cruiser had
a marine accident.
Ss there anybody here tht
Is the bereaved family of a victim
of that ace dent and working here?
Ya Ant
vov % no.
The Evil Spint that Appears
on Butsumetsu-Suspicion!
Then... will each of you introduce yourselves
and tell me of the person that
died in the accident 13 years ago?
Then. why don't we start with Shigcko?
XY NC
I'm Shigoko Sonczaki, tho housokoopor.
I lost my husband whe used to
work here as a chef in the accident.
He was in ¢harge of preparing the
meals during the cruise...
My daughter Namik1 and I were
also scheduled to go on the cruise.
But Wo woro both in bod with a cold...
After father died. I succeedecd
[ull nT WY =o he's =o SEE odnAf
I 1ls0 have succeeded my
father and work here as a chauffeur.
I'm Masashi Watabiki.
I lost my father and younger
broth win the-accident
You beth lest members.of the family?
Oh. es sir...
My father was in charge of
sailing the ship. so he had no choice,
But my younger brother just
happened to go along...
It's truly regrettable.
The Inst victim was my wife who
useditorwork us/athousekeeper here.
She was a'great wife who used to
help me out with my job as a steward too.
Who would've thought. . thought that
she would end up like. that...
Mr. Akatsuka.
Just what do you-think yousre doing?
Forcing us to tell you
what we don't want to recall.
Oh. well you see, I figured that
maybe the one who killed Mr. Sekiguchi
could be among you...
could be among you.
After all, it's strange...
( Even afleg seeing the card,
I am tho bth soul,
none of you met oned anything
about the marine accident 13 years ago.
740 )
none of you'me Yt oned anything
about the marine accident 13 yoars ago.
NC) OF VEO Gy MOTE 2 NA
about the marine accident 13 years ago.
Could it be that you already
know who the killer as.
But not telling us and protecting the killer?
N No way!
After all, four people died in the
accident, you know!
Wo don't ew 3 oul
One, two, three, four
Oh, that's true .
One, two, threo, four
Oh. that's true
In the first place. tho accidont
occurred on Sept 29th
on Taian (lucky day) 13 yearsingoe
It wasn't o the 4th.
Nor was it on Butsumetsu!
Oh, I see
Besides, I don't think the chef
and housekeeper could've done it...
What?
Because ..look
Mr. Sekiguchi was found
hanging on the veranda!
I see! Namika who has aerophobia
I can't go near it!
Fl? That's true. but what-about Shigeko?
The killer hung Mr. Sekiguchi to
make it look like-suicide, right?
If so, the killer would look
below belore domg so. night?
In order to make sure that
nobody is watching...
If you look below from where
Mr. Sekiguchi was hung
he pointed bars of the steel
ence comes into view...
and it's kind of scary!
"Seal
Shigeko who has be, dniphoba
would probably avoid this place
and /hang the victim more to the side!
Tue SAW) Clo) I
The chauffeur Mr. Watabiki ws
driving the car
The chauffeur Mr. Watabiki was
diving the car
together with Mr. and Mr. Kunitomo
it the time of the murder
So. he couldn't have committed
the murder... Which means...
You're the only one left. Mr. Akatsuka...
OO. Oh mo...
I don't think the steward did it either!
Look at tho two cards
that you were just checking!
The writing is slanted
and slightly (ut of place. right?
HEED oR
£7 BLAND
RR BEANBD
HERD o BY
ge Zs ID
BR BEANBD
CSCO GO ft OF IK
an) OO lol < OF IR
C.Comc to think of it...
In other words, Mr. Akatsukaswho
IS a meticulous perfectionist
would never write such a card...
Yep But
the killer could-ve pretended to have
such a habit or phobia to throw people off.
Conan
Justhas Conan has mentioned.
All of the habits and phobia
can deliberately be acted out
At any rate.
I would like you all to coma down onco
50 that I can interrogate you individually
I would like to also take your fingerfprints .
Of all things! Why do we
have toget our fingerprints taken too?
I'm sorry,
I need it to make out:which
fingerprint is the killer's...
And? What about the-alibis
of the rest of the suspects?
The alibis everyone except
Mr. Watabiki are quite ambiguous. #
So. the fingerprints of everyone
except Mr. Kunitomo were taken
just in case, but only Mr Sekiguchi's
fingerprints were found on the rope so far...
Huh? Way didn't you take the
fingerprints of Mr. Kunitomo?
Well
he said he won't see anybody
until Oct. 4th is over,
and locked himself in the room
on the 3rd floor...
Hey: dear?! Will you cut it'out!
Dear!
Well, hold your horses
If something comes up.
We can discuss It later. you and me.
Huh?
Later then...
Dear?!
I This Is absurd?!
DD. Dc ar'?!
Don't tell me that there's somebody
m there with Mr Kunitomo 2!
When
Huh?!
It can't be?! He said that
he didn't want to see anybody. didn't he?
Uh, Mrs. Kunitomo!
Where 1s this interphone connected to?
Our bedroom.
In other words, it's the. room
where Mr Sekiguchi was hanging.
The room right above ours!
Conan!
Rope.
H He Y¥Conan?!
Huh?
Tihe pill. has: beenicrushed...
Somebody was here after all.
But, there are no traces of the window
being forced opened.
He couldmt have forgotten to lock them
under these circumstances...
How in the world...
Did the killer get inside?!
We've got to call an ambulance right
although under these circumstancges,
it may already be too late...
But... what bothers me is that rope .
If my deduction is correct .
The culprit is still...
The culprit is still.
AM Xl
The boy with the glasses got into the
room on the 3rd floor!
Yep!
There was a rope ted to the veranda where
Mr Sekiguchi was found hanging
so he climbed up that rope to tm,
re oor...
Hoey! Kid!
Open up!!
H. Hey.
Hurry up and open the door
I tell you!tlil.\
Intruder!
...A bell?
What in the world is happening?!
Um. what's with this alarm?
Did ou. do something?
Oh. Conan?
Sorry.
Dad tried to force his way in and touched
the fingerprint recog iition device...
despite the fact that only the people who
Iive In this house are allowed to touch it...
At any rate. stop the alarm-andiopenithe
door! Do you know where the button 1s?
I'll open the:deer now! But
other than Pops and Officer.Yokomi-lo.
Please don't corm. Inside
But. they're already...
MM Master!
Hey. hey. everybody's inside...
His pulse is gone and he snot breathing.
Dl DOE Was A if
I'll call an ambulance!
I'll go inform the officer who as below
about this .
Wait!
I already calledathe¥ambulance.
Please don't movevrom here. everyone!!
Huh?!
Ran?
Are yoursti Iroutside the door?
Y.Yep. I'm here...
Then stay on the lookout for any
suspicious people that walk out. okay!
Inspector Yokomizo and Pops
will you both check to see If there are
traces of the windows
#.0of the other rooms on the 3rd floor having
been forced opened?
Huh? Why?
Because! Look at this!
Huh"?
This 1s a trace offa ll having been
stopped-on, right?
It means somebody was here. right?
Y.Yeah...
4 Whoever it was probably surprised
Mr. Kunitomo.
( Causing him to get an attack and kept him
from drinking the medicine
causing-him to get an attack.and kept him
And this rope...
IS probably what the killer used to
get away...
It wasn't swaying!
What!
I heard Mr. Kunitomo's loud voice from
the interphone on the 3rd floor.
so I went to tho rodm downstairs and
fou 1d the rope.
SO I went 10 the room downstairs nd
found tho rope.
It didn't even take me a minute
{.Hey?! In that case .
Correct... maybe the killer
saw me climbing the rope and.
Decided not to run away,
but came back to this room instead?
C.Could be .
If the killer surprised Mr. Kunitomo to
induce a heart attack.
Took the medicine bottleraway
stepped on the pill andicrush it
and fed after making sure that
Mr. Kunitomo was-dead.
It would take at least a minute
The rope should still be swaying.
Which means that...
it is very likely that thc killer 1sstill here
on the 3rd floor...
Huh?
T. Then why don't we split,up and look for
the killer!
G Good idea!
That's too dangerous! v
Hat if you run-into the killer...
But. if we dilly-dally the killer will get away!
Wouldn't it be faster if we all go look for
the killer together?
Okay. let's do this then.
We search one room at a time
First I'll go In an check the windows.
You all come into the room after me...
Mr. Mouri, please go out into the corridor
and stay on the look out for any
suspicious people.
O Okay. I got you!
Hmm...
Nothing abnormal!
Please come in all of you...
Nobody s hero
No one ere either...
Lets go on to the next room:then...
We"searched all the 78oms. but there
was no suspicious person anywhere.
Moreover, all the windows on the 3rd floor
were locked from the inside
and there were no traces of the windows
being forced opened either.
Hey. Ran!=Can you hear me?
Have you=seen anyone leave from that
door.
Three paramedics carrying a stretcher went
in and out though...
Nobody besides them passed...
Which means that...
This kid is making up stories.
What's with you, man?!
No. there is still another possibility...
Huh!
Whon Conan openod the door
with the fingerprint recognition device
and we went inside
the killer who was hiding on the 3rd floor
could've joined In
among us...
OO. Oh mo...
Wait a sec!
Are you saying that the killer is among us?!
Well, not really...
We all ran here after hearing the alarm,
you know!
Didn't you see us come in from behind you?
WwW Well I do remember that Mrs. Kunitomo
as with us right through but.
Mr Mouri, do you remember?
Not at all
Didet I tell you nBPto et anybody
else Inside...
We I appoint an officer to stand guard
in front of the security door.
And close off the 3rd floor.
As for all of you,
please let me question you once again
understood ?
Hom Ba other words, 4
when Mr Kunitomo was heard
shouting over the interpheno of the 3rd
floor with the fingerprint recognition device.
Aside from Mrs=Kunitomo-who was with us,
the alibis of the four of you are ambiguous.
Ambiguous /!
We were staying still in our rooms just
as the police told us to.
We all have our own rooms.
Why didn't you appoint an officer to stand
guard in front of our rooms then?!
Oh. well...
The point is,
regardless of Mrs. Kunitomo saying that he
would not see anyone until Oct. 4th is over
how did the killer enter the room...?
C.Comc to think of it. back then .
FMong with my husbandss voice
through the interphone...
Kay. I'll talk te you later then.
Think I heard what sounded like a knock...
Y hushand didn't seem te~be surprises
by that sound .
A knock
And right after that. he suddenly shouted
and started suffering?
Don't tell me that he invited someone
in on his own...?
That cant be...
Mr. Kunitomo sent the officers who were
investigating the 3rd floor
on Mr. Sekiguchi's case.
Out and confined himself to his room on the
3rd floor.
You know? Why would he invite
someone in?
Even if he were to have done so.
The distance between the interphone
beside the bed and the door of the room
Is prett far...
It-8. unthinkable that he'd have an atthck
Iust because thokiller opened the door.
Even if the killer were to have some kind
of weapon on him
if his hands were on the interphone.
Ho would probably have put his finger
In the fingerprint recognition device
ind openod the door...
What frightened Rim to the point of not
even being able to do so .
What on earth?!
Letes go over all the incidents that
happened so fa
Please start by telling me about the
ship accident.that occurred
13 years ago off shore Suruga Ba
Did anything out of the ordinary happen
before it set sail?
I went to see everyone off at the harbor...
But nothing other than Mrs. Kunitomo's
friend,
Mr Sekiguchi suddenly participating
ha)penced.
Mr! Sekiguchi suddenly participating
happened.
Why did Mr. Sekiguchi suddenly decide to
participate?
He had been wanting lo go cruising
with 1s tor some time now and .
It just sO happened that Namika and
IShigeko came down with a cold
Nd the number of people
boarding decreased...
and the number of people
If I were to mention something I thought
was strange...
If I wore to mention somothing I thought
was strange.
Mr Sekiguchi was carrying a large bag.
Oh...1d...the contents
I I'm sure. he sid it was
scubn diving equipmont
I see
I see.
And, uh. and tho people that\died back
then were
first of all, is the chef that used 'to:work
here and Shl'eko°s husband.
1s well as Namika's father...
The second as Mr. Watabakrs father who
worked here as a chauffeur...
The third, is Mr. Watabiki's younger
brother who just happened to participate
and go on board...
And the fourth, was your wife, who worked
ere as a Y0uUse eeper, rt. AQ SU a.
Yes...
Y@&sg...
You said that Mr and Mrs. Kunitomo and
Mr. Sekiguchi were the only ones
who survived but wer 2 there other boats
on board?
Who survived but were there other boats
n) Doone
T.Thore were but, we ware so desperate
to save ourselves
that I have no idea whether the others got
on or not...
that I have no iden whether the others got
I'm not even suré whether an SOS was
sent out either...
And after that,
your husband start having nightmares,
almost got into a car accident
Rag an
JR AR
this strange card was delivered, the dish
cabinet falls over in the middle of the night
and you heard strange sounds in the
house...
Did anyone here realize that these things
were all happening
on the 4th of Butsumetsu?
Well, I did realize that it was always the
4th but...
Maybe... the - aster was aware.
He used to be hooked on the 6 da
calendar. and he used to choose
Iucky days and mark them on the calendar
whenever he chose to go cruising...
And on the day\bcfore something was
bound to happen.
And on the day before. something was
he used to always invite Mr. Sekiguchi
over...
Then was Mr. Sekiguchi at the house when
Mr. and Mrs. Kunitomo heard strange
strange noises In the house
where no one e se was supposed to be?
Mrs. Kunimoto.
ALE Pudlinne, 3D
AER [AC] OF OUT wax 3 IKE
It sounded like something being hit against
the wall like thud. thud...
And slash, like leather being hit...
It's as if a ball is being hit against the: wall
and being caught with a glove...
Is there anyone who plays baseball in this
house?
U.Uh...l don't...
U Uh... Il don't...
U.uh I don't
but my younger brother who died. did...
hey,
hold on.
Don't tell me that. it's a ghost after all...
HuR~=~=~7?
Has mghtmere as about the housekeeper
that makes the bed
Ihe car accident is the chauffeur...
The dish cabinet isthe c¢ cf...
The dish cabinet is the chef...
And if the strango sound is baseball...
it all has to do with people who died
13 years ago...
T.Then, don't tell mo that,
the words that are written on the card.
T. Then, don't te I me that,
Atone your sins before I awaken
I am the 5th soul. means
the spirits of the dead are going to
resurrec one a:'er ee 0 er...
NO EOE) Y= = = te me ms me ms ma I
M:Mrs. Kunitomo?!
Are you all right, Mrs. Kunitomo?!
Uuugh .
It's a cursew=after all
Phis house is possessed by evi spirits.
Don't be ridiculous .
There are no such things as evil spirits In
this world!
B.But a spirit could easily go through the
door with the fingerprint recognition device
"» Vl
R.Right! I'm sure Mr Kunitomo also
saw that ghost...!
No darn way!
Right. Inspector Yokomizo...?
Whwaa?!
Huh?
Oh...
It's just tht my=cell phone'rang
at such good timing
Yes...Yokomizo!
Of all things!
Oh forensics?
What? Fingerprints were detected from the
rope and medicine bottle?!
Yes yes. then there's no mistake that
the prints
are those of the person who last touched
the bottle
So. it's the same as having already nabbed
the killer!
Because all your fingerprints have already
been taken...
And? Whose fingerprints did it match
WwW Well...
WwW. Well.
It.it doesn't match anyone who works
in this house: .
T's the fingerprint of an unknown entity...
Huh?
No way!
Then how did the killer gel through that I
door?.
Wonder
wonder
E. Evil spirits...
Evil spirits... after all...
Phooe
Very interesting!
Original Comic Books By.
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Background Music.
KATSUO ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
JUNICHI 110OKA
Saripls By
KANJI KASHIWABARA
Animation Directors.
MASATOMO SUDO
HIROTOSHI TAKATANI
HARUWO OOGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAMURA
IAKASHI HYODO
Art Director
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
Directors Of Photooraphy.
IAKASHI NOMURA
HIRONOBU HORIKOSHI
AKAHISA OWA A
Recording Direalor.
KAISUYOSHI KOBAYASHI
Editor.
IERUMITSU OKADA
Chicf Director.
KENJI KODAMA
Produced By.
TMS ENTERTAINMENT LTD
massosTiion with,
YOMIURI TELFGAS TIN
CQRPQ All
$2 dd (al lV.) co
\ CCD AMA SWAG TTRFRAN Vy An
@3yrsetl
Which means that the company's president
disappeared on Sept. 2613 years ago?
- F .v Can
So\now that youircidene,
I'd like to get back towork!
Was someone there or not! Which is ii?!
Yikes!
Huh?
No one was...
Yes. there was a suspicious figure .
Let me start then...
and tell you of the truth of the 2 incidents
that happened in this house...
The Evil Spirit-that Appears on
Butsumetsu - Solution