Conan is nearing its 10th ear,
achieve a mi cstone and aim! for the next!
Today'srstonmEmtho clinthx of the
Butsume su mystery
Ran"s casual remark helps clear up the
mM ster
It rings a bell to something that was
Jd MMOs oval 00 C«
Ho soos through the one and only truth
A child appearance withh the d Q of
mn adult
No case islgftunsolvidswith
Detective Conan
> invited ty 3 weallhy p-«
residgmce In Shizuokn prefecture
t that residence.
For the past few years,
0 the 4th of Butsumetsua phenomenon
was always said to occur
And. on October 4th
2 victims ina row.
What!? Fingerprints found on the rope
and medicine bottle!?
And? Whose fingerprint did it match?
It, it...
Doesn't mateh with anyone who works here
it's an unknown fingerprint.
The Evil Spirit that Appears on
Butsumetsu-Solution
Then we know it's an outsider who 'did it
Can we go back to our rooms and rest?
Yes... A policeman will be right outside each
of your rooms. but please get some rest...
Hey. «where does Mr. Sekiguchi live and
hat does he do?
His company is...Mr. Watabiki?
\ uy ¢ 7
Ah, yes...
It's Sekiguchi Secuntios
at Umeki-cho. Nishhku. Yokohama
Detailed. aren't you...
I go to pick Mr. Sekiguchi up whenever he
comes here...
He's memo crazy
Memo...crazy?
By the way...
Wasn't it in Yokohama that....?
Yes. my brother
Yes. mm brother
sagnel
hat is"it brothcTl? Atthis time,of night
Toshimicht Sokiguohy? Yoah, know him.
mot<him=1-few times when he was:still=n
newcomer
I romembaor him wall because I didn't like
So what's with him?
He was found hanging {from a rope at
Kunitomo's residence...
What? He committed suicide ?
He might have been murdered...
After that It seems like somaoone also
killed the, owner of the residence...
WA, IV mat the guy when Ah company
president's family filed
a missing person report
Missing person report?
YOR oR OHO OCR,
disappeared!
E still hasn't returned after 13 years...
Th.thirteen years?
What?
Yup. it was the end of September 13 years
ago. it was mother's birthday...
Then you mean on September 26th
the president of the company disappeared
13 years ago
If I'm not mistaken, the ship sunk 13 years
ago on September 29
off shore at Suruga Ba
3 da s ago!
And. that Sekiguchi stepped in to take his
place!
Plnspector!
Let's go for a few drinks after work.
OK but let's split tho bill}
Hey. why don't you-treat him once in
a while! You're so stingy...
Call-me an econom cal person! See yal
Sigh
Hmm. sting
people living hercasmust also have some
peculiar habits or symptoms...
You all look tired so why don't all of you get
some rest. Mr. Mouri
Yes. I think we'll do that...
Hey. -belore you go to sleep
Iet's check up onthe people in their
bedrooms
Let's check If theshabitsrand symptoms
they were talking about are real or not!
What!? You want to know why I have
be onephobia?
When I was a child I was taking the
sewingfbox to my mother,
21314148
and I fell and poked my forehead
wth a needle!
That must-have hurt...
119939113191817181020311496181713192911921394109897
wy nnn NPNMNANNN NY? I VHN WWM TANNM
Huh?»
Seng. ads eng alsa ge snes
*» oO eSamsuan bee
«tid A Vi
Is that why the calendar is stuck on the
wa wi tape.
MA pu NOP MP et od HER me mpg
Uh, yes
Mm? There are somesmnrks on.'the
ca encdr...
Mm? "hare re some .marks on the
SC 27
283» 34
Ws Aha hthdayseol mysaolt, my dragon
Namiki, Mi Akatsuka andfMr Watabiki
My husband. Mr. Watabiki's father,
«and Mr Akatsugi's wife
who died in the ship accident*wcre all
classmates from grado school
and we always celebrated our-"
birthdays together...
Before Mr. Watabiki's mother passed away,
there were 8 marks
it has become half of that now...
If you want to know about my fear for
heights
(ll \}
you'd better ask Mr. Akatsuka and
Mr. Watabiki
What? You full from a high place
because of them?
He opposite!!
Whon I was ma 4th grade,
when I fell from:-a tree,
Watabiki saved me from the fall!
Nd at that time the. ICcft hand.
Then
you must have been hurt real badly?
Ah, well actually it was Watabiki
who got hurt.
A year or two ago, I had completely
forgotten until I saw the scar on his hand...
he's obsessed with ¢leanliness and always
wea s gloves...
I always thought it was his younger brother
that saved me
Really...
The room is so clean
Of course! Chefs are suppdscd to be «7
clean!
I guess that's right.
Hey! don't come into the ladies room
without permission!
Oops. excuse me!
This is the scar from back then
So. what's the problem...?
Ou wear gloves inside your room too...
Yes. . always except during bath time and
when I had my fingerprints taken.
and I also take them off when I drive and
write...
Ah, these are the gloves your younger
brother used!
But. my brother used then Owhen he was
) kid
I don't see the older brother's gloves...
Unlike my younger brother,
I am not a sportsman...
Really .
I. - aa
Is tk=n Al
Your calendar also has a lot of marks...
Yes...
Once forgot m master s business...
Ever sings than, I write things down...
What?
SO you became a punctual perfectiomist ?
Do I need to have a reaso 7?
You're absolutely right...
It seems like your tidiness is for real...
everything in this room is straight and
tic y
I can't settle down until I do so
Hey. is there someone who is just tho
opposite?
ChMApL
Not really sloppy but...
- QO 10 of Ro
Shigeko seems to be a little sloppy...
the way she piles the plates up. is 3ml off.
Watabiki and Namika is always exact...
What's this?
Is this compass yours?
Yeah. I like to hike to the mountains...
Hey. did yougnotice the letters engraved
In MreSekiguchi'sfwatch?
What!?
Oh yeah. wasn't it E and N7?
Oh yeah. wasn't it E and N?
But isn't weird? >
Waals the same as has compass,
the position of t efilN and E was wrong,
wast it?
I wonder why?
Oh, I don't know!!
Well, we went around the 4 rooms .
We didn't find anything suspicious. did we?
Agh...this kid just took us for a ride!!
Well, let's continue with the investigation
after a little rest
Yeah, let's do that
I wonder what it is
something's not right...
I feel like I must've overlooked something...
it doesn't feel ric ht... what is it!?
Hey Conan! I bought you new pajamas,
do you want to wear it tonight?
It's 2 matching outfit with mine
What?
Matching outfit?
Yup.
I see...l must have overlooked this
POSSI) IY.
That is the truth. . the factitive method of
Sekiguchi's murder...
the way that the culprit must have made it
through
the fingerprint identification machine...
the reason why the master was surprised
enough to have a fit.
Will explain It all!!
Well done
Mr Kogoro... asked to have the 4 people
and the wife to assemble on the 3rd floor...
What!?
Does Mr Mouri know who the culprit 1st!
Yup. I think sol!
he said the culprits still on the premises
so please don't let him escape! /
T at's great!!
Hews going to start the deduction sthiow!!
NotAright now but in about 3 hours!
What!? Th.three hours later...
Up. of course...
Yup. of cou se
If Inspector Yokomizo listens and does
what ie says!
Q=,
Y. yes. certainly...
PERL SIR 0 Orly Nn 806) Geog
So now, let me explain... the truth of the 2
murders that took place on this premises...
And that the culprit is...among you...
First of all, is the murder of Mr. Sekiguchi...
The first case...
Butedidn't you say, that it was an outsiders
doing?
Yes. that's right!
That's true...
Namika who is afraid of heights couldn't
have hung any body.
On tho 3rd floor vorandn...
Shigoko who has bolonophobia
would have avoidoecdeplaces where sharp
points such as that of the iron fencing are...
The words that were written on the card
that the culprit is thought to have slipped
Wo Sekiguihn's pocket
The lettering was slanted...
a tidy and pcrfectionist Akatsuka
would not have done that...
At the time of the crime,
Watabiki and the master's wife
who went to the hospital withithe master
could not have committed the crime.
I Then who did it?
You're not really saying that
someone among us is faking it. are you?
No, Namika's room is clean/but the area
around the window was not...
Thus proves that you are afrad of heights
because you canno come
close to the window...
Shigeko who has helonephobia
uses tapestoihang hericalendar...
even when we intruded Akatsuka's room
unexpectedly.
The things in the room were tidy.
I think it is safe to say that no one isilying. #
Let's investigate the 2nd crime
A person enters this bedroom on the 3rd
floor
by opening the door of the
fingerprint identification machine
and slips through.
This person sets things up to cause the
master to have a heart attack
that results in death...
Nd disappears without leaving any
traces of having run away
The plausible explanation here is.
The getaway rope tied to the veranda
The culprit notices Conan climbing up
and returns to the premises.
Opens the fingerprint identifiention machine
door. comes inside and blends in with us
has as possible
But:wasn't that proven innocent by the
fingerprints on the medicine bottle
and rope?
That is probably the fingerprints of the
accomplice...
Ac. accomplice!
Yes... there are 2 culprits!
Does that mean.that someone amongstius
brought someone. suspicious with us?
But the master said that he wasn't planning
on meeting anyone toda...
After all, we all looked in every room on
the 3rd floor and we didn't find anyene!!
Umm...no one suspicious turned up.
And there was no trace of escape from the
veranda. nor the window
hen where's the accomplice!?
Yeah. soO...
Yeah. so...
I wanted to reenact this with everyone and
that is why" asked you all to come here...
I might have overlooked something...
OK, everyone! We are going to search the
rooms one b one...
Unlike then. I wil enter thejroom last!!!
In order to watch if anyone makes 1
SUSPICIOUS Move
So. would Watabiki play myprole
by entering first
and inspecting the window and veranda!!
OKI?
Ah sure!
So. let's start with the library next to the
bedroom!
And of course, if you see something org
notice something please let me know!!
You don't have:to shout, I can hear you!
Ah, excuse me! I shout:when I get
excited. .!
Mr. Watabiki. please go in...
Y.yes...
Umm. the window+is-locked...
no onc's onthe veranda...
May we also go in?
Yes, of course!
Do you think we'll find something out
this way?
LET 21
Umm. then next room...
OK ovoryone:ipleaso hurry.
No one suspicious came to the hallway!
Thank you, Conan!
Darn...nothing turned up!!
Darn .nothing turned up!!
So. if we're done. I'll be goingilback to work!
O. if we're done. I'll be going back to wor
Stop babbling and answer'myapquestions.
Arc you really sure there was no onc
suspicious?
Huh?
Was anyonc there or not?
YVAN [Rd
No"no one there...
No. there was someone there... in the room
that ou just searched...
I just told you. No one was there!
Yes there is ..behind Inspector Yokomizo
theres one: more person...
Twins!?
Uh...hgjs my brother who works, for the
Kanagawa Prefectural Police...
I'll be off then...
don't tell my boss that I was
In on this investigation...
Right... Thanks...
But why 1s twin the answer?
In other words. it's.like this...
when searching the room, the culprit
stayed in the back.
Making sure to do so when entering and
Ieaving the room...
He acted as though he was leaving the
room right before the one the accomplice
was in. but actually stayed there.
When Inspector Yokomizo finished
searching the window,
and was waiting for the right time
the accomplice that was hiding behind the
door joined everyone.
If the accomplice is a twin wearing the
sane clothes...
switching places like Inspector Yokomiso
no one would have noticed.
Nor would it have been suspicious that
somebody else was hiding.
Where are they!?
Tihere are no twins here....!
Right. whon Shigeko montionod
the story "bout the birthdays.
Something bothered me...
20 years ago, there were Watabiki and his
parents and a ounger brother,
Shigekoiind husband and Namika.
AkatsUka and his wife.
There were supposed to be a
total*of 9 birthdays
but she said there were only eight.
Which means someone had the same
birthday...
And when! heard 'about the time when she
fell off. a tree when she was In 4th. grade
I was convinced
She could just vaguely remember who
saved her at that age
IS because there were 2 people that were
alike...
In other words...
Watabiki, you conspired with your twin
brother and committed this crime...
Wh what are you talking about!
His brother died in that accident
13 years ago!?
What If he didn't die in that accident?
What?
What if he swam to shore and survived?
X X, WOO I 3 Xxx «xn Wo I
of his left hand.
Which he got:when he saved Namika
from: her fall...
When he drove us here
there was no scar on his left hand...
The calendar in his room,
the mark at the head of the words were
dnffuront UQpUHUiHQ on tho unto...
They probably switched places
once in awhile...
noting everything down and
by using the same organizer,
they could become one
and the same\person...
They did it in preparation for toda
In order to murder
Mr. Sekiguchi and the master!
The younger brother took the two
to the hospital to establish an alibi...
Aftor that, tho older brother
who was hiding in the mansion
enters the 3rd floor
by making Sekiguchi open the door.
Chokes Sekiguchi and
hangs him from the veranda railing...
And after a few hours,
he goes loathe 3rd floor again
andimurders the master.
But master said
he wasn't going to meet anyone...
The master will meet with him
especially If he was with him
when Sekiguchi was killed...
since he would be
the most unsuspicious person...
the master must have been surprised...
A man wearing the same clothes
with the samc face appears.
Furthermore. that
Is the s1mo parson who supposadlh
was said to have died 13 years 1go...
You deliberately left
your younger brother's fingerprints
on the medicine bottle and rope.
To make us believe
it was of an unknown person,
in order to exclude the people
inside the premises from the suspect list...
B.but where is the other one?
He didn't turn up in the search. right?
That is why hasked Mr. Watabik
to search the window
and gave you. instructions in a oud voice
so that the accomplice
who is hiding on the 3rd floor can hear...
I dropped him hints telling him
that 'hell be safe on the veranda!
Tithe police has surrounded the premises!
Please bring him in!
That won't be necessary...
Brother...
Then you will admit to the crimes?
Yes...
Wait a minute! If you're alive...
What about my father!?
What about my wife!?
They probably died
because they were abandoned
by\ ou know who...
Ah...ah .
What is it?
What happened 13 years ago!?
Something suddenly went wrong
with the ship while cruising.
SO I dived to check it out...
someone's bag was tangled
in the screw and helm.
And Inside it was somebody's hand...
A human hand.
It was most probably the hand
of the missing former president
of Sekiguchi's company
who disappeared 13 years ago.
You suddenly participated in the cruise
to dump his bod into the sea...
In other words,
the "5th soul written on the first card
referred to him...
Did you know thnt
he was going to dump the dead body?
No. no I didn't know!
When I told everyone on the ship.
Sekiguchi suddenly shoved Father away
and speed the ship up .
Speeding without
having control of the helm...
the ship turned over
and everyone was ossed I 10 the sea
only the master and his wil¢ escaped
with the only rubber raft that had air in it...
N.No!
I was going to return to call for help!
But Sekiguchi...
They won { survive anyway!
Just keep quiet about this,
you are so an accorip ice
and abandoned them!
Is what he told me...
We were all holdin onto a small float
but thought that woe would all dio hko this...
So the person with
the most physical strength. me.
Went to call for help...
But I felt consciousness shippimg away
When I woke up. I was in a hospital bed
and I lost my memory
I sneaked out of the hospital
and wandered around...
Then. in summer 2 ears ago
I coincidently met my brother
md at the some bind
my memory came back to me...
I mot my brothor on tho day aftor
I Almost had a car accidont
with the master's car...
The ncadant was my fault
but the master was the one
who kept on apologizing
so I thought it a little weird...
That night, when I'heard my brother's tale,
I understood why...
Then. the master's nightmare and
the car accident on the 4th of
That's where we got the idea
of taking revenge...
There was no evidence left
for the police anyway...
But if we can find the sunken ship.
That's impossible!
It actually sank within the Suruga Bay
but he told the police
it sank way out at sea...
34 degrees north latitude 45 minutes.
138 degrees east longitude 30 mi utes...
What?
Remember, the N and E engraved
on Mr. Sekiguchi's watch!
N is north latitude: 45 minutes,
E's east longitude 30 minutes!
If it's within Suruga Bay, then
it's approximately 34 degrees north latitude
and 138 degrees east longitude
That's probably where the ship sdnk!
Oh. so that's what it means...
But- why on the 4th , the unlucky.day?.
The ship accident:was
on September 29. a luc \ day 7
That's becausc...
13 ears aco this da
October 4th was Butsumetsu...
when the master went to the police
to ask them to stop the investigation...
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Pro d UCC fF S
MICHIHIKO SUWA
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Iore -mndmMusic.
CE 66
Chart 'r Designs By
Editor.
HI 11OKA
Scripts By.
KAN/Al KASHIWABARA
KAZUNARI KOUCHI
JUNICHI MIYASHITA
YUICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Amimalron Direwlors.
MASAI + M_+ SUDO
HIROT HI.TAKATANI
HARU . +» OCAWARA
SU HI AONQ
AKIO KAWAM R
TAKASHI HYO >
Art hire clo.
YUKdHIRO $HIBUTANI
IAKAVHIRY PM BRAY
At nl J3) it ° {0 Srl
Iv OWAGA
Regording Director.
ISUYOSHI KOB ASHI
Editor.
[HI RUMIISU'QOKADA
Chief DirCc tor.
KENJT KODAMA
Produced By.
IN. ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
mm assocration with
Y « MIU I TELECASTING
CORI. ORATION
LL o= 4
DID live CONAN
GOSTIO AMAA NHHOGARTIRAN YIN 1
WY RM Rover
After that,
although the tide drifted it a little.
The ship was somehow found...
with the bag in question
still tangled in the screw...
Talking about a problem.
Ever since that day, there's a problem
that's been on my mind...
E . Conan!
Iet's at least wear it once and take a pic ure!
It's cute!
A Junior in high school wearing
stuffed animal pajamas...
what's more. it's a panda.
I felt soOMmoona's eye on mec
Maybe it's my imagination
Grenler's skylight window...
C.camera?
Why? The Investigation Firm?
You're being photographed?
Could it bo the mon in black. 2
Oh no. ah
What the... 1?
Wow, oh no. oh no
The house of Grenier in Beikamachi