Detective Conan will be
going into its 10th year
One down and;imore to come!
A.mysterious elderly. couple
moves: into-a new*house
A presence and sense
of being watched that sprout concern
Am I the target or. is it Ai?!
Am I the target or, as at An?
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case as left unsolved
with Detective Con 1
2» 4?
NF XC
To Belkacho?
Okay...
Hey? Do you know that anew
house was\bllilt near your house- Conan?
A new house? No.
A new'house? No
What kind of house is it?
Is it big.
No, its small
and very cute! 'i
The house suits your taste,
doesn't it Yoshida...
>a oS!
Yep!
I thought that I'd like to live 3
na house like that after I get married...
What?!
Married?!
Conan! Would you like to go
see it onsOur way-home?
What...?
Nothing
Come on. Ayumi, let's:just all of us go!
Just leave that -u. alone. oka!
What?!
Why: are coming along too. Genta?
The same to you. Mitsuhiko...
Quick. Conan!
How:come you're asking Conan to come!
Right!
Yeah!
What's the matter?
No, I just thought I felt
someone watching...
What?!
Is it just'-my imagination?
Us oy
The The Grenier House on BeikachoO
I OTTO.
So. it's this house...
Here you go... Mitsuhiko,
open your mouth
Oh my, Genta, you
finished eating already?
Hey, hey...what are they
It's really a small . Ad cutechouse
Don't you think «Conan?
Do you like houses like this?
Don't you think, Conan.
Huh?! Me?
Yes. you.
Ayumi! How come you're asking Conan?
He's out of the picture
Because he ma become
Myshusband:in-the future!
So, I'd like to know what
kind of things he likes.
Hey, Ayumi!
Then, you've got to see the
inside of the house at all costs too.
Huh?!
So. will you show us inside?
You've gotta be kidding.
Just because I didn't say anything
about your ridiculous conversation...Huh?!
Her parents are lookingdfor
a house right now. you know.
If she likes the house .
Huh?!
They may just buy the house!
Let me!
There are two 6-mat western st. le rooms.
A.bathroom with a bath tub
with. a. changing room on the 1st floor.
Are the two western style
rooms for children?
Yes. It seems that the person who built this x»
house had in mind a couple in their-30's.
With two children. a total family of four.
On the 2nd floor is a 16-mat
Iiving room and a kitchen.
Wow, how spacious!
It's nice and sunny too!
There is an 8-mat western
style room towards the roadside.
There's a 3rd floor too...
Yes, the selling: point.of
this house is the Grenier.
This is interesting
There's a window here too!
Wow, you can see the sky!
You can star watch at night too.
Hmm... Detective agency?
It's in view from here.
How: did you like it?
Hmm, the Grenier and-the 2nd floor
Iiving room were nice. but...
Both rooms on the 1st floor
were kind of dark
A larger yard would be better too.
The stairs were a bit too steep too.
But, for a house built on a small lot, ~
I think it's pretty well made!
And williyou recommend,
this to your parents?
Huh?!
What?
Huh?! Aha, ha...Well, ofscourse...
Huh?!
So, now that we got to see
the inside. let's fie!
The layout was not all that great.
My house is a lot mo e comf to live 'nl
Huh?
What?! That house was sold?
Yep, when I passed by
yesterday with mother...
the for sale sign was folded, so asked...
That's too bad, since you
seemed to like it. Yoshida.
But the inside wasn't all that great.
No need to be disappointed, Ayumi.
I'll build you a better housek
Just why arefyou going
to build Ayumi a house. Genta?!
I'm the one who's going to
build her house, if anybody!
I wonder If the buyer was
a couple in their 30's with two children?
Well I guess so.
Nope.
They were an elderly couple
way into the 70's.
An elderly couple?
Strange That houseriisn't
made for elderly people:tovlivesin.
You're right, it's got three floors
and the stairs were steep too.
But to each his own. so I guess it's okay.
Hisashi Udo...?
What a plain name.
<< ID
Since there s a name plate it means...
They've already moved in.
What brings you guys here?
We figured you'd be
concerned and come look!
Even if it's a trivial thing, if
in doubt check it out thoroughly...
That's the basics of.a- detective!
Hey. hey
Huh?!
My...Hello!
Hello!
You boys
Iive in this neighborhood?
We just moved In today.
If it's okay with you, please come in and
tell me all kinds of things about this town.
Yes! Sure!
If it's about Beikacho.
You can count on us!
I even-know which shop sells the
best eels over rice and is cheap too!!
Here goes
I'll be going then.
Bye!
Oh...so you're all detectives?
Yes! The Youth Detective Squad
of Teitan Elementary
Dem, .
Is known by everyone in Beikacho!
We're just as well known
as Kojima Liquor Store!
Here 'you go
Thank you!
What? Is that so?
I'm sorry. the furniture hasn't arrived yet.
Not at all
Uh, are you going to live here together with
the elderly man who went out a while ago?
That's right.
The stairs seem sleep.
But aren't you atraidy
Not at all
I've always been wanting to...
Iive in a house like this since I was young.
I think I know how you feel!
My grandma said that she wanted to try
Iiving in a tower condo just once too!
Besides...this house is close to
the house our only son lives in.
Oh. I see. But, please do be careful.
Thank you. it's*so nice of you.
Thank you for everything.
Bye!
Our doubts have been cleared.
That couple bought that house
because their son livesinearby:
She also said she wanted to
Iive in that type oféhouse.
But, something bothers me
Huh? What does?
Well, I cant really say
What?! Day after tomorrow?
Yeah.
Whatiistit? What is it that:sibugging me...
I've alwaysibeeniwanting to...
Iive in a house'likerthisSince I was young.
Here goes.
Is, itithis? Is this what-s bothering-me?
But, any elderly man would do so...
More than that, back then .
Why was she wearing
that look on her face?
Huh?
Since dad and I have to attend a
memorial service tomorrow and will be late,
please watch the house. really! Conan...
Oh. okay. sorry.
Hey.» don't ponder when you're eating!
Shoot!
A cab...bummers
Damn!
Shinich! What're you doing
In a place like this?
Doc!
All nght!!
Talk about good timing!
Could you...
go after that cab up front!
Doc! Hurry!
Yea...
Okay
Yeah...
Okay...
Although it bothers;you...
There's nothing unnatural
about the-activity of the old man.
Old.people usually use their
hands for support when standing up.
I thought so 100. but...
The old lady probably frowned because
she's been telling him time and again...
to get up smoothly!
She probably doesn't like
her husband acting too old.
Although I'm always being told
that I act like an old fart by Genta too...
Old man!!
Im sorry:to. have bothered you on
your way shopping .Go on ahead home.
Hmm... understand you want to
check things out until you're convinced but.
Are you going to be okay alone?
Don't worry!
"Wonder what Al would
Fyre
Ur lw wll EPIIK BL: [DY
Close call, real close.
Who on earth is that Chinese man,
and that old man...?
I wonder
Huh?!
That's%in:the direction...
of the Grenier house?!
Don't tell me that!
The skylight of the Grenier house...
A camera?
Moreover...
why Is it face towards
the detective agency?
Are they taking pictures of Pops? Or...
What's the matter?
No, I just fell like someone
was watchingjme...
Huh!
Am I the target?!
If so...don't tell me
it's, the guystin black...?.!
How about it. Haibara?
Have you ever seen them
in the organization?
I see.
But, they could be in disguise...
In disguise...?
Yes .
Disguise...?
Shin-chan?!.
So, it's you after all. mom.
Long time no see. Yukiko.
Oh. Dr Agasa...
He got us. Yukiko.
Ni);
This time he got Doc to act on his side...
He's paid us back for:what
we did some time ago...
How'd you find out?
Give me an explanation
before you ask me questions...
Just what do you think you're
doing pulling something likethis off...?
We came back to Japan in the morning
before yesterday.Yusaku's job interview.
Beikacho?
Okay...
After we stopped over at the house once...
I got worried about you,
went alone;to check you
out at the elementary school.
You just:happenedito come
out with yourifriend...
Conan! Quick!
Why call Conan!
Right!
Really! You're really sharp, Shin-chan...
I thought you saw through me.
I was relieved to see that
you were doing well. but
I got to thinking that I wanted
to see what kind of life
you were livingrafter becoming Conan
before leaving*for the States
withoutletting you know!
You didn't have to start feeling that" way...
You didn't have to start feeling that way...
I was walking thinking how
cou watc 'you wit: out :eing notice...
I coincidentally;found that'house...
Though it was small: I liked the house...
although 'I didn't intend to getéit.at first...
The detective agency
was in view:from-the
window of the Grenier...!
That's when she came
upon this striking thought.
We'll just rent the house for a week,
disguised as an elderly couple...
and watch your lifestyle...
secretly from
the window of the Grenier...
Yusaku thought that my
idea was amusing too.
So, we went to the realtor to
ask if it was okay.
Then, the president happened
to be a great fan of mine...
Here you go...
Thank you.
He immediately agreed
I was really surprised when you
all came the following day, though.
Since I'm an actress I had confidence that
I could deceive you, but as for Yusaku...
Yeah, that acting of yours, dad,
was what got me thinking.
Here goes.
But that's...
Yeah. like you said Doc.
It's only natural for elderly men to use their
hands to support themselves getting up.
But, that's
only nobody's watching
In front of people I think they: try
with all their might not to show it.
I feel that's the psyche of elderly people.
Yes, even in the world of acting,
when you people act out elderly
people. they are-inclined to act that way.
That's why you frowned
when he did so right?
Oh, you saw? Right, I thought,
oh no. he did it.
It cc n't be help:.can it? After all, I'm
a suspense novel-writer. and:not an actor.
But, your acting was :pretty-good too, dad.
You knew that Doc and I
were tailing you, right?
Hmm?! S.Sort of...
The Chinese owner of the shop.
Used to be the head of a chivalrous
group of robbers that raided the great
continent during his younger days.
I interviewed him about my,
upcoming Night Baron Series,
Night Baron vs. Mysterious Chinese Man
I asked him to scare you a bit...
I was really surprised when
he threw the dagger at you.
Yusaku!
At any rate...don't you
think that's going a bit too far?
I'm sorry...
But I was really worried about
the kind of life you were living.
Since we've been living away
from you for a while
If I were to ask you: you'd say
that ever thin *s oka. , ri ht?
I wanted to know... the real genuine fact.
Besides. I wanted a
Iot of pictures of you...
As a child again
Huh?
You win, mom
Original Comic Books By
Producers
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
$v Jad
KATSUG ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMITSUDO
Story Editor
JUNICHI 11OKA
Scripts By
I KASHIWABA
UNARI KOUCHI
ICHI MIY SHITA
HI HIGORE
sum: nvdut
Animation Directors
HIROT +» I TAKATANI
HARUO DEA WA RA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAM
TAKASHI HY
Art Director
KIHIRO 'HIBUTANI
Diractors Ii Par + § /
TAKASHI NOMURA
dig nlisldc
FAGUIGA JVC)
ecording Direc
KAT§UYOSHI KOBA ASH!
Editor
TERUMITSY OKADA
Chief Director
KEN] KODAMA
tuced BY
ENT $8 RENT, LTD
neass cation with
( ()eti YA iON
Ergin GOA AN
GOSHO AOYAMOY SHOGARURAN YT)
WIRES Reverved
That elderly couple already moved,
didn't,they?
The housefwasn't suited for elderly
people after all.
But, their name was sure interesting.
Uh...
1 NJAJNIY UUULLLVNTLY UN LN
realize something so simple?
All I had to do was interchange
the characters of Udoku.to make Kudo
Oh, well...
I'm going to check out the famous
sightseeing spots and drink up.
I wonder?if something happened?
Huh?
Don't tell me that this Is!
The Sword of Yamatano Orochi! Part 1
(B11 RR)
The Sword of Yamatano Orochi!" Part 1