Detective Conan will be
going into its 10th year
Par Dd
- -- >
So I'm going to check out the!
Famous sightseeing spots drink!
Aha. ha, He's 180 degrees
unlike what he was in the plane
Tihe=place we Came to visit thisstime
isithexhome-of-mythology:..1zumo...
TA NA
(BJ FR)
The Sword of Yamatano Orochi! Part 1
TA NA
(AJR)
Izumo Shrine IS where
the God for matchmaking is enshrined...
I can understand Ran praying with passion
bM-ii
Please: please:do find meia good match...
Gee..l wonder
what kind of match his expecting...
Fie mine here
Wow... For a good match. a good match!
For a good match. a good ma
So. this 1s Japan's greatest"Ooshimenawa!
(Thick rope indicating the place of the gods)
It.It. sure is huge!
Well, this is fantastic... It weighs 5 tons
You're Mr. Kogoro Mour:...aren't you?
The famed detective.
Y.Yes
You look way better in person than on TV .
E-hem
Uh. do you work here?
Oh. I'm Eiko Esumt. I run a Japanese inn,
front of the path to this shrine.
Oh~ a Japanese inn...
Oh I'm his daughter. Ran
And... he's @onan.
Hello. excuse me. what's that money there?
Really!
There's $0 much money stuck to it...
I guess you can call it
a kind of tradition. maybe?
If the coin gets stuck on it,
they say your wish us granted.
Which means,
I'll meet the person of my dreams?!
There! Go for it!
Dam~There!! Darn you! Oh». darn it
Your wish will probably never be granted.
How luc « 10 have a hometown in a place
where the god of matchmaking is.
I have a tentative offer for marriage too
Tentative. .?
Is it with someone you don't really care for?
ge. 1 le a man is poor
I think he has money. Because he's
Involved in large-scale business.
He has a bad personality, then!
A rich-man with bad personality
IS the worst match in any category...
You should call off the marriage.
D. Dad!
But. \ ave a-reason fo (
not being able to refuse.
But when you get married-it should:be
with-someoneithat you really love, right?
What 1s the name of that man?
Mr. Koji Wanibuchi.
No matter what reasons you may have.
Reluctantly getting married with
Mr. Wanibuchi is like giving yourself up
as human sacrifice!
I'm sorry. Dad. come off it...
No. don't be, because Mr. Mouri is saying
this for me. right...Conan?
Shall we go see
an interesting miniature model?
Huh?! An interesting miniature model?
Did Izumo Shrine look like this before?
This 1s indeed
the worldiof mythology!"
Th § seems to have been
the biggest shrine in all of Japan...
I'm not sure of the details .
It I$ a shrine that was builtttowards
the end of the Heian Period
10 the first part of the Kamakura Period
Sorry...can you wait a while...
He's Ryosuke Fukama.
A childhood friend of mine...
He used to like ancient history
since he was a child...
Hess lucky because he's working doing
what he likes...
Eiko actually hikes Mr. Fukuma
I'm sure he likes her to
Yep... I'm sure he likes hér too
Ep... msure 1@ 1 es .er 00.
How exasperating,
All three pillars were creathdiby benching
three huge trees together as one.
Huh?
Eiko 1s going to be taken away
by a rich guy with bad personality because.
You don't keep a firm grip on her!
Yes?!
Cr Cr
Mr. Mourn
Dad!
I'm really very sorry
No. it's okay.
Mr.'Mouri. thank you for today .
- \ Do
Oaa... "e.agnpo yourse ,0 ay
Ch pn -—
You seem to be saying good stuff. but
Who knows what's actual} ON your ming...
The following day. murder is committed
A current price of 10-000.000 yen?!
That does it.
IvA current price of 1010002000syen!
That does it"
Stabbed right in the back
Don't let outsiders in here!
Don't tell me that you're
I'm Mouri. a private detective from Tokyo
Just as I thought!
I've heard of your activities...
I'm Officer Yamane of
the Izumo Police Department!
Likewise. I'm Officer Komura!
It's amazing how you got here
I just happened to be nearby
However. there seems to be no need for
the assistance of
a famed detective for this case.
How's that?
The victim, 1s Mr. Koji Wanibuch.
The owner of Wanibuchi Sogyo
that 1s doing extensive business centering
around the Izumo area. age 35...
Koji Wanibuchi 2!
Tihesfiancé that
Eiko was talking about yesterday?!
He was killed
So. you know him
He 1s a famous businessman that is well
known locally. as beinga wheeler-dealer...
The person who found him is
1a Coup e over were... weyre 0cCas...
Well. this is not alplace that
tourists would come...
The estimated time of death is
around 1:00 in the afternoon...
The time that Mr. Wanibuchi's watch
is thought to have broken when he fell.
It is stopped at 1:05
It's probably okay to determine
that it was time the murder was committed.
The motive of the killing was
probably due to a grudge.
Being a wheeler-dealer businessman,
he must've had a lot of enemies too.
He seems to have
had a bad personality too.
It's true that
he didn't have a good reputation.
But the purpose of the killer was to steal
his sword that is worth 10.000.000 yen.
A sword priced at 10.000.000 yen?!
This us Mr. Wambuohfs notebook
He was scheduled to
go to a local antique shop today
and get the sword as collateral
for lending money this afternoon.
I confirmed with the shop
and found that at>around 12:00 noon
they gave the sword
to Mr Wanibuchi,as promised.
After receiving the sword,
Mr. Wanibuchi came here to Inome...
And we're not sure for what,
but at around before 1:00.
He was witnessed
standing holding the sword...
However. when his body was found,
the sword was nowhere in sight...
So. the killer"who/saw;him receive
the sword:at'the.antique shop
may have tailed Mr. Wanibuchi and
So you see. this is a simple case
of robbing treasure.
So. there 1s no need for a detective
Yes. now I clearly understand...
I wonder If this case 1s really
ill that simple...?
Why come out all the way
to a place like this?
Moreoyerabringing a sword
worth 10.000.000 yen along...?
What're you thinking about?!
I'm not thinking anything!
I hate to.sa. -this.about
the late Mr. Wanibuchiibut.
Eiko won't have to get married
reluctantly anymore.
I know that I shouldn't be saying this
But, you were saying so yourself
yesterday 100...
That it's like human sacrifice
Well. you see that was
This case sounds similar to
the stor. of cettinernd of
nn, Tn, wT.
The Eight-forked serpent: doesn't it?
Getting rid of the Eight-forked serpent
the mythology of Susano-0-no-mikoto
There was an unfortunate princess that
was about to be taken awayagainst her will
when Susano-o-appears to save her.
When Susano-0 appears to.save her.
Thanks to Susano-o getting rid of
the Eight-forked serpent.
The princess Is rescued
and Susano-0 gets a hold of he
Eight-forked serpents sword!
It sure as similar
Don't,you think so
Heck, .Susano=0=no-mikoto may be a hero.
But the killer is nothing close to it!
It just sO happened-to help Eiko out.
But the guy's a robber
I Know: without you having 10 tell me.
All I'm saying is that
It seems similar to the mythology about
ent...
Right. Conan!
Yeah... .Ha, ha
This case was not just
a simple robbery after all.
Once a year when the gods
from all over Japan gather at Izumo
It 1$ said that they land here
on Inasanohama!
It 1s said that they land here
on nasanohama!
Huh?!
They're notlistening
I'm explaining: this to 'you
I wonder: if it-found.something?
Huh?
Woof! Woof! Bow-wow!
Huh?!
Don't tell me that's?!
I confirmed-it"'with the.antique shop owner
and was told that it was indeed
the sword in question
Just as I thought
I don't understand .
Why would you hide the treasure
so that gets covered with sand like this...
It was probably thrown away. not-hidden
because whoever it was'
didn't need it anymore...
Taking the sword away. from the site
of the murder-was a camouflage
to deceive people into thinking
It was acrobbery.
It's most likely that
the real motive of 'the culprit
was to take Mr: Wanibuchi's life!
' He real motive is most probably a grudge
Get a list on the double
of his business rivals
all the people in. Mr. Wanibuchi's private
\ life that he was having problems with!
Excuse me?
Oh. no .
After-the list was*made. the following; day
four people were called in by the police...
Eiko and Mr. Fukuma were also
among the people who*were summoned...
I will be questioning you all
in tun insa"while...
But. before that I would like to introduce.
DetectivelKogoro Moun Ab
who will be helping us/with this case.
Mm Moun.
T.That famed detective!
Oh. well I didn't thank Aha
a famed detective would be un Izumo .
2-6)
First of all. Mr. Kazuya Ishitobi
W-9)
Oh. yes sir.
According to our investigation.
Mr. Wanibuchi approached your
shop of long standing-asking
if you'd hike to joint-=manage
the shop with him. is that right?
Joint management my foot!
Wanibuchi Sogyo will take care of
all'the management finances...
All you have to do is
Iend me thexname Ishitobr.
And we'll open stores throughout Japan
Fantastic. don't you think
You're not thinking of
refusing. are you? Fuh!
He tried to take over 'Ishitobi that
had been in business for 2.000 years
by threat and money!
Cliseean
Next Mr. Takehiko Fujie. you run
a wedding hall-called-Ryounkaku and...
The same went for my place
as Mr Ishitobijust mentioned.
We:at Wanibuchi Sogyo are thinking of
into the wedding hall
management business.
Hh 71
But: Ildonot:want to fight for customers
with Ryounkaku that
is a place of long standing...
Son I would like to make a proposal...
We would like {0 invest
our capitalin your company.
And wouldilike-to carry out
joint-management with you.
What:do you: think?
Fujie. my.isuperior? Fuh.
Ws 44
@ wanted to take over!
Superior?
Wanibuchi was an under
classman of mine...
of Teito University economics
department. in Tokyo.
Oh. at the university
His name means crocodile.
But his character 1s like/that of a snake.
A monster that swallows up
anything he targets as prey...
he's just like the Eight:forked serpent!
I see .
Ms. Eiko Esumi. you also had business
connections with Mr. Wanibuchi?
Yes. Sir
Our inn Hinodeya is .also
an inn of long standing
but wear and tear kept getting worse
Butt-we couldn=t afford to renovate it .
At about that time. we were
contacted by a company in Tokyo
saying that they'd like-to build
a modern hotelsin™its place
so they would like us
to sell them our land...
Just when-my parents were thinking
there was no other choice
than to let go of the inn}.
It's absurd to make an inn with such long #7 >
standing: as Hinodeya:go out of business!
Let us help you with the renovation fees!
For the sake of Izumo!
It was unexpected.
Because from what I heard of him.
he was a greedy man and nothing else...
My parents accepted his offer
thankfully and renovated the inn.
Let my daughter marry you?!
What's come over: youralliof'a'suddenyg'!
It-$ notall of a sudden
I lent-yousthe:money for renovation
because this is thebirth home of the
woman who is to become my wife...
For what other reason would anybody
something like this. - Fuh, fun...
He was planning on-it to begin with...
He said 10 give the total of the
money he lent back right away.
Is I refuse to marry him.
Oh no.
Oh no
My parents told me tat jythey
havelto give me up to a guy like that
they'd rather let go of the inn...
But I know how much that inn
that haswbeen handed down
for generations mean to them...
Thatssswhy I
Mr: Fukuma.
Not being able to leave
Ms. Esumi in her plight.
Ou went time.and ac ain 10 ask
Mr. Wanibuchito ask him to let her go
didn't you?
I hated him.
Lihatedihim.
I hated that man too
Next, at the time that
Mr Wanibuchi was murdered .
please tell me where and what
each of you were doing...
First of all.
I was at Matsue Castle!
Matsue Castle?
I was alone so I have no one to prove it
I signed my*name on t
the list of the castle tower .
Uh- Mr. Fukuma...
It was my day off yesterday so.
I went'to Old Taisha Station.
I was there from a little
before noon to about 3-00...
I go there often.
Because ll can relax there. 4
But. I was alone 100.
$0 there are no witnesses to, prove it.
But, I was alone 100.
SO there are no witnesses to prove it.
Then. Mr. Ishitobi
I. I was... at the Izumo Traditional
Culture Museum...
I was... alone too...
as yr. SS: SUMliogp
I was at Hinomisaki
I was: alone {00
It was a little too early for seagulls that .
I didn't get to see them...
Komura. split up and check on the alibis'
Yes. sir!
They're all famous sightseeing spots
s0-many peoplcimust've seen them...
That is. if they're telling the truth...
Exactly
How was it?
> X LN
Yes sit... Mr. Fupe'salibis been confirmed
It was written in his*handwriting
and judging from. the names written
by the people before.and after him.
TL 2 SN «
it is thought that he was
certainly in Matsue at 1:05.
1:05...
He wrote his name on the list
at the very time the victim was killed...
The lune ll ldk $10) (gut from Ialsue Castle
Gnome. es seene o - ecrime
IS about 40.minutes to,an hour by car
fl we
So. I'm not a suspect anymore
The problem is the
remaining three of you...
oO o/,
We cannot get any eyewitnesses at all
Not even one?!
3"\e
Not even one. for all three of them...
But, we can't keep you here just
because we can't confirm your alibis...
You may'have to.come in for questioning
again. but you may?go for today...
Thank you for your cooperation
Eiko and Mr Fukuma aren't
the ones. are they?
No...
I wonder why.there are
no witnesses whatsoever...
Could it be that they're lying...
ES. SIS, amane
I see, okay!
Call. him back!
Ryosuke Fukuma!!
Y.Yes sir!
\ Yesterday at around 2:00 in the
afternoon. we found a witness
that said he saw someone
burying something at Inasanohama...
The man who was witness was
a tall. lanky man.
Sand*from Inasanohamar and .
Soil from Inome Cave were
detected from your shoes...
ou did it. didn't you .
You killed Mr. Wanibuchi. didn't your'!
I stand mute...
He's exercising his right to remain silent?!
Yes... but if he's the one who did it
that explains why there were no
witnesses at Old Taisha Station.
Iv L100
that explains why there were no
witnesses at Old Tasha Station
I witnesses at Old Taisha Station
Because he had killed
Mr Wanibuchi at Inome
and got rid of the sword at Inasanohama!
BY HL
I guess he's the one
Ryosuke Fukuma...
Oh. no!
Since the:sand and soil
were found:on his shoes.
As well as a witness having seen him...
He probably did take the
swordaway from the site
and buried it at the beach
It's not enough to conclude that
he's the one who killed the victim...
Huh?
Wl went to Hinomisaki.
That reaction
Mr Fukuma knew
where Eiko was really at that time
Which means?!
Agh...
Hey. where are you going?
Why you~ brat, going into
the interrogation room on your own!
No. Conan! 7
Onh~ because I think that
Oh~ because I think that
Mr. Fukuma isn't saying anything
because he's protecting the real killer
Just as I thought
Aha. see. I'm right
Aha. see. I'm nght .
He probably saw the real killer Kill
Mr. Wanibuchi at Inome Cave...
But. I wonder who that real killer is?
Who else wouldvhe have to protect
but just one person...
You witnessed Ms. Eiko Esumi
commit the murder...
That's why you took the sword
away to make it look like a robbery...
Is that it?
I did it!
I'm the one who killed Wanibuchi!
It's too late saying it now.
Me?...
It-$ not me!
Then, at the time Mr. Wanibuchi was
murdered where were you really at?
You said you were at Hinomisaki,
but nobody saw you there...
The hghthouse worker non the
souvenir shop employee: nobody!
Souvenir shop employee. nobody!
She's:doing the same
thing as Mr. Fukuma...
She sounds like she's
protecting somebody...
It"was my day off yesterday so.
I went 10,01d Tasha Staton.
It'could be that.
Uh, I'll.bet.you're protecting Mr. Fukuma
because you know that he's the killer?
Aha .
I was right after all
He...
Ran. come withime!!
Ran. come withme
Huh?!
C-:Conan!
Just what is going on. Mr. Mouri?
The lovers are protectingreachsother
Ha. ha... which of you is the killer!
Neither of them may be the killer?!
We're going to prove that!
And where to?
To Old Taisha Station!
Original Comic Books By
Producers
MASAHITO YOSHIOKA
Jacko und Music.
KATSUO ONO
Charact r Designs By
Sto Editor.
HI 110 A
Scripts By.
KANIIVKASHIWABARA
AZUNARI KOUCHI
NICHI MIYASHITA
UICHI HIGURE
TOSHIKI INOUE
Animation Directors
MASA OMO™SUDO
HIROT + TAKATA
HARUO + OGAWARA
ATSUSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAM
TAKASHI HY
Art Director.
UKIHIRO ..HIBUTANI
eators Of hetooraph
S MURA
HI ()1 fliUllfiRIKOfifll
A 1A OWAGA
ecorting Direct
KAISUYOSHI KOBA ASHI
ditor
ER SY OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN]! KODAMA
Produced 87
5 ENTE SAINENT, LTD
n Cl Yin with
mm "1-ELEéAS'T'IHNJ-(
DIT GIVE. CONAN
C GOSTIO AMATI SHOGARL RANDY
YR Rr
All the suspects have been cleared.
So it seems
What's the meaning of this?
Suddenly there are times of the day entered.
I think that's wrong
I'm jumping to conclusions?
This us Mouri and I'd like to meet
I'll tell you the details when we meet