Detective Conan will be
going into its 10th year
One down andgmore to come!
Thoughtfulness and kindness
for the one you love
Brings about misunderstanding.
But at long last The true killer is found
in the homeland of mythology
but at long last The true killer is found
He sees through the one and only truth
A child in "pperance
with the 1. Q. of an adult
No case as left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
We came on a sic htseeinc tri» to Izumo
the homeland of mythology.
We came on a sightseeing trip to Izumo
and we become acquainted with
a woman named Eiko Esumi there.
The-following«day. Eiko"s fiance is killed
and a robbery case of a sword worth
10:000-000:-yen occurs.
And of the four suspects
that were summoned to the police
were Biko and her childhood friend...
Please tell me
where at what each of you were doing
<r ~, APT YG
at around 1:00 in the afternoon yesterday...
First of all...
Since yesterday was my day- off 3
I went to Old Taisha Station.
Lastly. . Ms. Esumi: where were you?
I went to Hinomisaki.
Eiko and Mr. Fukuma aren't the killers.
Are they?
Nope...
Why aren't there any witnesses...?
It has to be that they're lying...
(ié $5)
WwW ,
(1% hi)
The Sword of Yamatano Oroch! Part 2
Are you sure you. didn't-see wrong?
Of course not.
I've known her since.she was born.
She was Eiko of Hinodeya!
Hoh. hoh. hon...
Hoh. hon. hon...
It was after noon yesterday?
Yep... Just about 1:00...
She always sits!on that chair over there...
EikO was here at the time that
Mr. Wanibuchi was killed?!
Since there's av witness
Eiko's Wibi's been established...
But. why did she say
she was at Hinomisaki...?
Let's go tell Pops and the others!
Sadelone
salad
It Wust as-she and Conan are saying...
I'was at Old" TaisharStation.
Huh?!
I go there a lot when I have time.
I feel relaxed when I go there
It is also the place where the
history of my mother and father started.
My mother happened to+stop by
when on a trip andiscame here to Izumo
She just happened to spend the night
at my father's inn...
They were both attracted to-each other-and
eventually got married...
Then. I was born.
Although the: railroad line has
already been discontinued:.
when I . go there. I feel like
I'can see the beginning 'of everything...
I hike that station.
I like that station.
No matter how much you 10Ok for witnesses
who've seen Eiko at Hinomisaki.
You wouldn't find them
because she didn't go there.
mie lH
If you were at Old Taisha Station.
Why didn=t you say $0 to begin with!
22 Gog 7D Ze
Why did you lie about it?
Well...
Because Mr. Fukuma said
what he did: fight?
Huh?
Yesterday was my day off so
I went to Old Taisha Station.
You were more-surprisedi than an, one else
back then-weren't you. Eiko?...
Because you were there,
but Mr. Fukuma wasn't.
Because you were there.
But Mr Fukuma wasn't...
He killed Mr. Wanibuchi...for me
that's the only thing™ could think of...
So. I couldn't tell the truth
If I mentioned Old Traisha Station.
It would contradict his...
But. I was alone too so.
There are no witnesses.
If we were-at"the same place. there's no
way that we wouldn't have seen each other
Since Mr. Fukuma lied before you.
You, couldn't help but lie...
Hinomisaki just happened to cross my; mind
since I like it there 00...
I see. so that's the story...
But. if Ms Esumi is innocent. Mr. Fukuma's
activities become questionable...
He took the sword away fromthe murder
site not to protect Ms. Esum...
Bog.) fe
ut to=hide what he did.
Don't think+so...
Huh?!
Eiko*as wellias Mr. Fukuma is obsessed
over an idea and mistaken.
Obsessed and mistaken?
If you tell Mr. Fukuma that
Eiko has been.cleared fromisuspicion,
I'm sure hell tell you everything.
b nal uma ee
Fron
I'll bring Fukuma here!
Eiko! It wasn't you?
I was at Old Taisha Station right through.
But. then...
why?
Where did you find this?
What is this?
Where glss...
It's here;because?
Couldxyou explain in
chronological order pleaser
Could. ou explain.in
chronological order'please?
Yesterday at noon.
I did go to Inome Cave
But. it wasn't to kill Mr. Wanibuchu...
The day before yesterday.
Eiko told me that...
She was called out by Wanibuchi.
He told me to come to
Inome Cave at 1:30...
Why's he asking you to
come to a-lonely place like that...
I'm sure he's up to No good... Don't go!
I'll go in place of you.
I'll have a good talk with him and
make him give you up. once and for all.
RR oo...
Noon tomorrow. at 1-307
So, yesterday. in order to
Wanibuchi...?!
You found this there...
I recognized it nght away...
because-this is what I sent you.
I. 1 will have to keep it for a while.
The key is this pendant...
I thought you went despite
my telling you not to go...
Thinking that Eiko had killed him,
you impulsively stole the: sword
to make it look like a robbery...?
Bf - AA
Oh. yes sir...
The story makes sense.
Hm sorry. Ryo... I lost that
pendant several days ago.
I couldnwmake myself tell you...
So. tha vs whatdsyou meant Conan...
So. that's what you meant Conan...
when you said they were
obsessed a mistaken...
They both thought that their partner
was the Killer.
They both lied to protect each other.
CIO. aux»
How so very cute...
It's not cute!
How dare you both confuse
the case the way you did.!
Mr. Fukuma. you stealing the
sword is nothing other thanffa crime!
KO'?
Yes. sir...I'm sorry!
S or FEE
(wy.
Yes. sir...I'm sorry!
( Og - Vv
If you didn't take the pendant away.
maybe the fingerprints
of the real killer were on them!!
I completely thought it was Eiko so I...
If sO. the more so!
Trying to cover up somebody
else's crime Is not love!
\ O...
I understand...
I understandi~
Which means that the one who
killed Mr. Wanibuchi is KazuyaglshitobLn?
That jittery attitude of Mr. Ishitobi
sure as worth suspecting...
The way Mr. Fujie acted surprised
when I introduced myself also bothers me.
The real/killer had this pendant. right?
Probably...and he dropped it
when he killed Mr. Wanibuchi...!
Rather. he deliberately
put it near the, cojpse!
You said you lost it
several days ago. didn't you?
Just before or 'after those days
did you see Mr. Ishitobi or Mr. Fujie?
Oh. come to think of it...
Come on . please Eiko! If its for
you who he loves I'm sure he'll listen...
Marry him and please tell him
not to take us over! Please!
Just what do you think you're
saying. Mr: Fujie?
Are saying you want our
daughter to sacrifice
herself for the sake. of
saving your wedding hall!
I'm pleading knowing what a selfish
request this is... Please. Eiko. please!
Please let me think it over...
Eiko! There's no need to think it over!
Please leave. Mr.*Fujie!
How cruel...
to tell you to sacrifice yourself f
or his own\convenience...! Eiko?
Come to think of it.
It was after that. that I realized
I had lost the pendant...
So. it's Mr. Fujie...
But, Mr. Fujie has the alibi
of having been at Matsue Castle...
His name was on the name
Iist of the castle tower...
Let's go take a look at
Matsue Castile. Mr. Mourn.
Right. «if the killer didn't
try to frame Eiko up as the killer
MILT
Mr, Fume Wouldn't
RENO TEX XO $0 ERO «38x ON
This distinct>way of writing
is unmistakably Mr. Fujies writing...
'kg . ,.
What 'sswritten before and after his
signature. 1:05 doesn't seem to be a lie.
What's, written before and after his
signature: 105 doesn't seem to be a lie.
I guess itswas just a waste of time...
I just thought there
may be a possibility but...
Which means . there's
only one person left!
Let's hurry back!!
Conan?!
Okay! I'll catch up with you
right away so go ahead.
Really? Rightiaway. okay!
Something, bothers me...
The time here fits in too well...
1 xk GU
What 'sggoing on.
Logging in of time suddenly
started from yesterday ..7?
Hey. will you lend me your eraser!
I can't seem to do it well.
If written in a pencil,
it could be erased. but this.
But this
you.cCan=t. --Oh. No... maybe.
you can't...Oh... No maybe
Uh. will you please lend me your eraser?
Ee *)
\ Hey. Ran'sHurrysup!
Ye. Yaep!...
Wait! Conan"s=not here-yet!
Not that brat again...
Wait. Pops!
Wait Pops!
We're leaving you behind!
Yes this is Yamane...
What?! Yeah...Okay!
Mr. Ishitobi couldn't have
committed the crime. 4
Yesterday. a little after noon time.
In the suburbs of Izumo. there was
a hit and run-accident.-:around 1:00...
At about the same time that
Mr. Wanibuchi was killed in~lnome Cave.
And? t
The driver was finally found through
eye-witness reports. and just arrested.
It us Mr lshntobu
I get it
He wasn't jittery because
he killed Mr. Wanibuchu.
But because he was afraid we
would find out about his hit and run case...
But. if so. what about this case .
It's not Mr. Fukuma or Ms. Esumi™
Mr. Fujieshas a definite alibi, \)
possibility of Mr. ishitobi is,gone'...
All the suspects are innocent.
Right
Mr. Mouri!
Are \ ou all right?
Dad.
Are you all night?
So. we're»back where we started.
Uh. Pops.
Yes. I'm Fujie.
Yes. I'm Fugue .
This is Mouri, I'd like to see you...
I'll tell you the reason when
I see you in person.
Yes. Mouri here...
This is Fujie. I have something
I want to talk to you about .
You want to talk tome ?
I'll be waiting for you at Hinomisaki.
Oh what a magnificent lighthouse it 1s
Yes ..it's 43.65 meters
and is said to be tallest in Japan.
hat a beautiful lighthouse
It was built in Meiji 36 or 1903,
SO. it's been here for over 100 years.
'Pia.
100 years...
1...And. he said
wait for him at Hinomisaki. but where...
Right... At this time the
Iighthouse is already closed.
So it must be that observatory up ahead
Let's go
Yes...
What could he want to talk to me about. .?
mma VAL QE= NIE, AVEAAVIR AY VU IRANNY AALS or
What did you want to talk to me about?
Huh? Aren't*you the one who asked me
to come...
Huh? Aren't you the one who asked me
Whe... please may I meet someone nice...
Sleeping Kogoro?!
So. this is the rumored...
Mr. Fujie. you analogized
Mr. Wanibuchi to the Eight-forked serpent
His.name may/mean crocodile,
but his character'is'that-of a snake...
A monster that. swallows up
whatever-at targets' as prey...
Yes... an.Eight-forked serpent indeed.
It's true that Mr. Wanibuchi
may have been a hated existence...
But that doesn't mean
it's okay to kill him. Mr. Fujie!
What a thing to say. Ha. ha. ha
IS It about that again. Mr Mouri
That's right Mr. Mourn.
You even confirmed his alibi
at Matsue Castle yourself!
That was a trick
A trick?
You thought of killing Mr. Wanibuchi when
you went to Eiko's house several days ago
sn that right?
You pleaded with Eiko...asking her
to marry Mr. Wanibuchi and to ask him
to quit taking over your wedding; hall...
But. of course
my selfish plea was not?heard...
And in your grief!
You happened to pick upsomething
you didn't expect to...
A thought flashedithrough-your mind...
You made two calls the day before
yesterday. didn't you?
The first one to Mr. Wanibuchu.
It went something like this...
I'll give you.a great idea on how to
make Ms- 'Eiko Esumi your very own...
It-s-bestifor 'both of us to meet
where there aren-t'many people...
I'll see you at Inome
tomorrow at 1-00 then...
Your other call was to Eiko...
You pretended to be Wanibuchi...
I want to see you tomorrow: please
come to lnome at 1:30 tomorrows...
That phone call wasn't
from Mr. Wanibuchi ?!
He used Mr. Wanibuchi's tone of voice.
Come to think of it, he said he had a cold.
His voice was not like always...
1.00 and 1:30. you designated different time
because you didn't want Eiko
to witness you killing Mr. Wanibucht...
And.
Yesterday at 1:00.
You carried
out your scheme.
Huh?!
Mr. Wanibuchi's wristwatch
stopping at
1:05, was not what you planned
you had no choice but to
carry out what you did...
So. you sped over to
Matsue Castle by:car...
to log your name in on the
name list and establish your alibi.
It would be impossible to log »
in from that time. Mr. Mourn!
No matter how fast you drive there by car,
you can get to Matsue Castle
only after 2:00!
It's not impossible...
You went to Matsue Castle
twice yesterday. didn't you?
Twice?
First, it was early in the morning...
in order to set up the trick.
You used an alias and logged
In your name and the time
and at the same time switched pens.
Switched pens?
You switched the pen to one
you could erase using an eraser
After killing Mr. Wanibuchi
you went back to
Matsue Castle aga and looked
for a fandom log in around 1:00". %
So: the very moment.that
Mr. Wanibuchi was Killed...
your-alibi thatgyyou were
atsMatsue Castle. an hour
away from the murder site was established.
It can easily be proven if you try it out.
There are ball pens that can be
erased using erasers
When you think about it.
When logging in on name lists like these,
the name. address-and date are written.
But the time is usually not written...
Tihe fact is. nobody was:'writing
in the time until the day before yesterday...
However. yesterday
since the first person wrote in the time,
everyone started logging; in the same way.
If the firstyperson, writes
somethingdin ascertain way
everyone who follows thinks
that it is to be done this way
and follows the first pattern
without hesitation...
You used this behavior of people. to
carry out your trick. How about it. Mr. Fujie?
What proof do you have that I am the
first one who logged in yesterday morning?
The name: lcihiro Yamada
sure-'sounds like an alias but
the problem is the address.
Iaw 'Ymésyfi.
Naruse-shi, Tokyo?
So. what makes, you say thatiliwrote it!
Why us Naruse-shu a problem...
Mr Fugue. you used to live in
Tokyo during your university days. right?
Wanibuchi is an underclassman of mine...
f Teito Economics University in Tokyo...
I confirmed and found out that.
The dormitory that you lived in
4 years ago was located in Naruse-shi...
That only shows that there is a
point of contact! But that's no answer...
It could be that a person by the name of
Ichiro Yamada actually came and wrote it!
That's not possible...
ecause a place called Naruse-shi
does not exist in Tokyo anymore.
What?
It merged with Haido-shi that is next to. it
and theifffwame Naruse~shi is
gone:x:since a year ago.
You didn't know until now. did you?
I see. Naruse-shi doesn't exist anymore.
Mr Mourn, the fact is. back then,
I thought I was doomed already...
This is Mourn.
+ The famed detective?!
I figured that you'd
disclosed the truth in time...
It's just as I thought after all
How beautiful
I love the sunset that is
viewed from Hinomisaki...
I won't be able to see it
for some time now...
I wanted to take a good look
at it so I wouldn't forget it.
That's why I had you all come here.
I know how selfish I am
Despite knowing this.
I didn't want Wanibuchi to
take over my precious business .
I didn't want the monster to swallow it...
I was desperate
I know .
Fukuma
Be sure you protect Eiko.
Who knows what monster
would appear again in the future
will
Wow, what a beautiful sunset!
Conan!
What are you doing?
Uh. I hope things work out for the two.
I'm sure they'll work out fine...
After all, they were born in the land
where the god of matchmaking resides!
Original Comic Books By
GOSHO AOYAMA
Producers.
MICHIHIKO SUWA
KATSUG ONO
Character Designs By
MASATOMO SUDO
Story Editor.
O yoo 0
NARI KOU(CT
Animator DI i1reGlors:
SSMASAI + +.50DO
HIROT - TAKATA I
HARU : GAWAR
TSUsSHI AONO
AKIO KAWAM
TAKASHI HYOD
Art Director.
YUKIHIRO SHIBUTANI
ire.Alors Of hotooFaphy
HIRWN@BU HORIKOSHI
TAKAHISA OWAGA
ecording Direct Ty
ISUYOSHI KOBRYASHI,
Edit).
IFRUMITSU OKADA
Chief Director.
KEN/T mm MA
Produced By.
TM ENTERTAINMENT, LTD
In association with
YOMIURI TELECASTING
CORPORATION
DIHIGLIVE CONAN
CO GYSHIO TVOYAAMED SIHHOCARURAN SY IA 1A S
Ul REM IReTrY ed
There!
I'm not going back to Tokyo
till the coin makes it in there!
" This time for sure!!!
There!!
Hmm? 1 did it!
Huh?!
O. Oh no!!
Dad.
Hey. I don't think you it's too cool
to interfere with ether people's wishes...
10 years later on this day.
We shall meet at this place where
our memory lies. before sunset...
November 24th, 4th grade
A class. Kinoshita...
This may be a code that
indicates the place!
his may be a code that
This may be a code that
indicates the place!
his may be a code that
She's not wearing aihat,
but I'm sure;it's her!
Calm)
She's not wearing a hat,
but I'm sure it's her!
(B17R)
Ginkgo Colored First Love Part 17