[Script Info]
; This is a Sub Station Alpha v4 script.
; For Sub Station Alpha info and downloads,
; go to http://www.eswat.demon.co.uk/
; or email kotus@eswat.demon.co.uk
; 
; Note: This file was saved by Subresync.
; 
ScriptType: v4.00
Collisions: Normal
PlayResX: 640
PlayResY: 480
Timer: 100.0000

[V4 Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, TertiaryColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, AlphaLevel, Encoding
Style: Default,Simhei,24,&Hffffff,&Hffffff,&H232323,&H232323,-1,0,1,1,1,2,20,20,15,0,1
Style: Default2,Simhei,20,&Hffffff,&Hffffff,&H666666,&H666666,-1,0,1,1,1,2,20,27,7,0,1
Style: Default3,Simhei,20,&Hffffff,&Hffffff,&H666666,&H666666,-1,0,1,1,1,2,20,22,30,0,1

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Actor, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text






Dialogue: 0,0:00:16.80,0:00:23.68,Default2,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在这个世界上撷取你的爱
Dialogue: 0,0:00:24.35,0:00:29.89,Default2,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看着舞动的灯光  至今无法忘怀
Dialogue: 0,0:00:30.02,0:00:35.27,Default2,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,ahh  去把谜团解开吧
Dialogue: 0,0:00:36.44,0:00:43.49,Default2,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你仍然  充满疑惑
Dialogue: 0,0:00:43.62,0:00:51.62,Default2,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和朋友一起度过每一天 直到将来
Dialogue: 0,0:00:51.87,0:00:58.80,Default2,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,流着眼泪  无法释怀
Dialogue: 0,0:00:59.63,0:01:09.47,Default2,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只想请教  如何追回失去的东西
Dialogue: 0,0:01:09.77,0:01:16.73,Default2,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在这个世界上撷取你的爱
Dialogue: 0,0:01:17.44,0:01:22.90,Default2,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看着舞动的灯光  至今无法忘怀
Dialogue: 0,0:01:23.03,0:01:28.08,Default2,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,ahh  去把谜团解开吧
Dialogue: 0,0:01:28.16,0:01:33.01,Default2,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,去把谜团解开吧…
Dialogue: 0,0:21:51.17,0:21:58.25,Default3,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为何我们两人会相遇?
Dialogue: 0,0:21:58.56,0:22:06.92,Default3,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一起共看如此凄凉的夕阳
Dialogue: 0,0:22:07.52,0:22:14.40,Default3,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,搜索枯阳找寻能吸引他的话语
Dialogue: 0,0:22:14.98,0:22:23.25,Default3,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,却找不出分离仍能相聚的安慰
Dialogue: 0,0:22:23.61,0:22:31.76,Default3,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,脸色虽然有时难看只要能以笑脸拂去
Dialogue: 0,0:22:32.00,0:22:40.32,Default3,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然争执偶而有之但是也能忍耐
Dialogue: 0,0:22:42.26,0:22:50.02,Default3,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只要唯一的愿望可以实现
Dialogue: 0,0:22:50.39,0:22:58.60,Default3,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,曾经受伤的内心也将再度痊愈…
Dialogue: 0,0:00:02.45,0:00:04.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,飞逝的秒针 闪耀的彗星
Dialogue: 0,0:00:04.05,0:00:05.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,现今社会人心疲累
Dialogue: 0,0:00:05.70,0:00:07.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南的推理是一帖良药
Dialogue: 0,0:00:07.53,0:00:09.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天叔叔竟然有约会
Dialogue: 0,0:00:09.14,0:00:10.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,单纯的事件却另有隐情
Dialogue: 0,0:00:11.15,0:00:12.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,唯一看透真相的
Dialogue: 0,0:00:12.62,0:00:13.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是一个外表看似小孩
Dialogue: 0,0:00:13.60,0:00:14.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,智慧却过于常人
Dialogue: 0,0:00:14.47,0:00:16.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他就是 名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:01:37.00,0:01:39.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小五郎约会杀人事件
Dialogue: 0,0:01:47.03,0:01:47.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好好吃哦
Dialogue: 0,0:01:47.91,0:01:50.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们叫披萨还真是对了
Dialogue: 0,0:01:50.21,0:01:51.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对啊
Dialogue: 0,0:01:51.32,0:01:54.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要是爸爸在家我们就没有办法吃到这种晚餐了
Dialogue: 0,0:01:56.22,0:01:59.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说起来爸爸这个人还真是冒失
Dialogue: 0,0:01:59.52,0:02:00.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,东西都忘记带
Dialogue: 0,0:02:01.23,0:02:02.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他一定是太高兴了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:03.22,0:02:05.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他和他那个朋友好像有十年没有见面了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:07.11,0:02:09.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他说他今天要好好地喝个痛快
Dialogue: 0,0:02:09.15,0:02:10.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大概要半夜才能回来
Dialogue: 0,0:02:12.72,0:02:13.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:02:14.13,0:02:16.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是的 我们才喝到兴头上
Dialogue: 0,0:02:17.36,0:02:19.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过既然你公司有事就没办法了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:20.26,0:02:21.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我一定会尽快找一天补偿你的
Dialogue: 0,0:02:22.46,0:02:23.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再见
Dialogue: 0,0:02:29.13,0:02:29.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,各位旅客
Dialogue: 0,0:02:29.81,0:02:33.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,第二站台即将有电车进入
Dialogue: 0,0:02:33.73,0:02:34.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了您的安全
Dialogue: 0,0:02:34.33,0:02:36.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请要乘车的旅客站到黄线后面
Dialogue: 0,0:02:38.83,0:02:41.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么 现在才七点半啊
Dialogue: 0,0:02:41.92,0:02:44.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,早知道我就换个地方喝了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:08.85,0:03:11.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要到米花车站还有六站啊
Dialogue: 0,0:03:23.61,0:03:25.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,米花
Dialogue: 0,0:03:25.43,0:03:26.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哇呀
Dialogue: 0,0:03:27.26,0:03:28.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等等
Dialogue: 0,0:03:32.95,0:03:34.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好险好险
Dialogue: 0,0:03:34.95,0:03:36.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,差点就被带到下站去了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:38.97,0:03:39.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,糖果
Dialogue: 0,0:03:40.82,0:03:42.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我刚才吃过这个玩意儿吗
Dialogue: 0,0:03:55.71,0:03:58.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个景色还真是浪漫
Dialogue: 0,0:04:17.89,0:04:19.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这不是佐知子吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:04:21.23,0:04:22.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是毛利啊
Dialogue: 0,0:04:22.57,0:04:24.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毛利小五郎
Dialogue: 0,0:04:24.31,0:04:24.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你想
Dialogue: 0,0:04:25.05,0:04:28.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在我楼下的波罗咖啡我们见过好几次
Dialogue: 0,0:04:29.45,0:04:31.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你是名侦探毛利小五郎先生
Dialogue: 0,0:04:33.30,0:04:33.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,话说回来
Dialogue: 0,0:04:34.05,0:04:37.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我记得佐知子小姐住的那栋公寓好像就在这附近
Dialogue: 0,0:04:38.77,0:04:39.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,八点了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:40.16,0:04:40.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,唉呀
Dialogue: 0,0:04:40.86,0:04:42.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我竟然忘记把表带出来了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:43.59,0:04:44.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对了 毛利先生
Dialogue: 0,0:04:45.13,0:04:46.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你想不想去兜风呢 
Dialogue: 0,0:04:47.38,0:04:49.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道有好多地方的夜景都好漂亮哦
Dialogue: 0,0:04:50.22,0:04:52.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是没有同伴去那种地方又不方便
Dialogue: 0,0:04:52.60,0:04:53.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你要跟我一起去吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:04:54.27,0:04:54.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,听起来不错
Dialogue: 0,0:04:55.32,0:04:56.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们快去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:04:56.61,0:04:57.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那我把车子开出来
Dialogue: 0,0:05:16.45,0:05:17.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,太窄了是吧 
Dialogue: 0,0:05:17.74,0:05:19.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你可以把椅子往后面调一点
Dialogue: 0,0:05:19.22,0:05:20.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,调整杆就在椅子的下面
Dialogue: 0,0:05:21.13,0:05:22.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好 谢谢
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.80,0:05:31.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天晚上我一个人留在公司里面
Dialogue: 0,0:05:32.04,0:05:33.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,本来想要赶一点工的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:33.81,0:05:36.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是又担心我那个因为感冒躺在床上的室友
Dialogue: 0,0:05:36.76,0:05:38.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以就跑回家去看了她一下
Dialogue: 0,0:05:39.35,0:05:41.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那你还要回公司去了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:41.67,0:05:42.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不用了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:42.78,0:05:45.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,能够听听你这位大侦探办案时碰到的趣事
Dialogue: 0,0:05:45.73,0:05:47.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对我的工作说不定会有帮助的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:48.94,0:05:51.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个老小子突然有事真是太好了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:51.89,0:05:53.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天晚上还长得很呢
Dialogue: 0,0:06:04.27,0:06:06.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天晚上实在是太开心了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:06.26,0:06:08.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊 我也玩得很开心
Dialogue: 0,0:06:08.68,0:06:10.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么你就早点休息吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:10.66,0:06:11.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你也早点休息
Dialogue: 0,0:06:12.66,0:06:13.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,奇怪
Dialogue: 0,0:06:13.81,0:06:14.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:06:15.53,0:06:18.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,门竟然没有上锁
Dialogue: 0,0:06:29.76,0:06:33.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被害者是这里的房客竹中和美 29岁
Dialogue: 0,0:06:34.17,0:06:38.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,发现尸体的是毛利先生跟死者的室友岛村佐知子小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:06:39.85,0:06:42.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从死者下颚跟颈部等处僵硬的情况来看
Dialogue: 0,0:06:42.93,0:06:46.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,估计死亡的时间应该是距离现在之前的两个小时
Dialogue: 0,0:06:46.84,0:06:49.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是晚上九点钟左右的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:06:49.72,0:06:51.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,话说回来了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:53.54,0:06:54.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毛利老弟
Dialogue: 0,0:06:54.59,0:06:57.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他们两个怎么会到这里来的呢 
Dialogue: 0,0:06:57.89,0:06:58.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真的不好意思
Dialogue: 0,0:06:59.17,0:07:01.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我刚才打电话通知他们的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:07:01.29,0:07:03.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他们就自己跑过来了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:03.38,0:07:06.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸怎么会跑到女人的房间里来呢 
Dialogue: 0,0:07:09.81,0:07:11.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这就是佐知子小姐的房间
Dialogue: 0,0:07:12.20,0:07:13.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,中间经过一个餐厅
Dialogue: 0,0:07:14.13,0:07:16.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就可以通到被害者的房间去了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:17.54,0:07:18.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,至于这扇落地窗
Dialogue: 0,0:07:19.25,0:07:21.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来就像这样开了一点缝隙
Dialogue: 0,0:07:21.43,0:07:23.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,佐知子小姐表示可能是她忘了锁上
Dialogue: 0,0:07:23.90,0:07:25.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过不是记得很清楚
Dialogue: 0,0:07:25.14,0:07:28.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么说凶手是从这扇窗子进来的了 
Dialogue: 0,0:07:29.11,0:07:31.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是他是怎么到三楼阳台的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:32.05,0:07:33.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,警察叔叔
Dialogue: 0,0:07:34.16,0:07:34.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,危险
Dialogue: 0,0:07:35.59,0:07:36.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你看
Dialogue: 0,0:07:36.18,0:07:39.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只要从紧急逃生楼梯那里就可以跳到这个阳台上面来了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:40.06,0:07:41.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你搞什么鬼啊 
Dialogue: 0,0:07:43.76,0:07:44.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想凶手也许是
Dialogue: 0,0:07:45.33,0:07:47.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有注意到因为感冒躺在床上的和美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:07:48.04,0:07:51.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在餐厅里面专心寻找值钱东西的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:07:51.30,0:07:53.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和美小姐听到声音就前来看情况发现了小偷
Dialogue: 0,0:07:53.84,0:07:55.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小偷就拿刀刺杀了和美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:07:57.28,0:07:59.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,之后就从大门逃走了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:59.84,0:08:00.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说
Dialogue: 0,0:08:00.60,0:08:02.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是一件强盗杀人案
Dialogue: 0,0:08:02.45,0:08:03.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,似乎是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:08:04.41,0:08:06.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我还是必须要问一下
Dialogue: 0,0:08:06.56,0:08:08.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请问九点前后你人在什么地方
Dialogue: 0,0:08:08.95,0:08:10.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天晚上九点的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:08:10.68,0:08:12.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我正和毛利先生一起开车兜风
Dialogue: 0,0:08:14.11,0:08:15.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你和毛利 
Dialogue: 0,0:08:15.98,0:08:16.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊
Dialogue: 0,0:08:17.21,0:08:18.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:08:18.38,0:08:20.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你不是说今天要跟朋友见面的吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:08:20.77,0:08:22.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们见过面了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:22.38,0:08:25.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,后来因为他突然有事 我们就提早分开了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:25.71,0:08:28.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没办法我就回到了米花车站
Dialogue: 0,0:08:28.40,0:08:31.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了早点清醒 就在二丁目那里随便走走晃晃
Dialogue: 0,0:08:31.49,0:08:34.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,走到米花中学的后门就偶然碰见了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:34.58,0:08:37.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,正准备开车的佐知子小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:08:37.45,0:08:38.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,米花中学后门…
Dialogue: 0,0:08:39.35,0:08:40.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是什么时候 
Dialogue: 0,0:08:40.50,0:08:42.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那时候正好是八点钟
Dialogue: 0,0:08:42.33,0:08:44.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后我们两个就一起开车去兜风了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:45.67,0:08:49.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为她说她知道一个可以看到东京海滩大桥的好地方
Dialogue: 0,0:08:50.40,0:08:52.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们开到那里的时候已经是八点半左右了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:53.30,0:08:58.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后我们又喝了她从自动贩卖机买的啤酒跟果汁
Dialogue: 0,0:08:58.40,0:09:00.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,边喝边谈 差不多待了一个半小时左右
Dialogue: 0,0:09:01.32,0:09:03.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在十点十分左右从那里出发
Dialogue: 0,0:09:03.77,0:09:06.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,途中我们在她的公司那里停了差不多五分钟吧
Dialogue: 0,0:09:07.22,0:09:07.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在那之后
Dialogue: 0,0:09:08.15,0:09:09.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们就直接回到这公寓了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:09.62,0:09:11.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,时间大概是十点五十分
Dialogue: 0,0:09:12.66,0:09:13.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后就发现了尸体
Dialogue: 0,0:09:14.11,0:09:16.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就马上跟警官你联络了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:16.61,0:09:17.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么说的话
Dialogue: 0,0:09:17.87,0:09:19.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你就可以为她作证了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:19.89,0:09:21.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我可以证明她不在场
Dialogue: 0,0:09:22.21,0:09:26.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是你怎么跟毛利在米花中学后门碰面的呢 
Dialogue: 0,0:09:26.78,0:09:31.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为我在朝阳镇上自己经营了一家小小的进口代理公司
Dialogue: 0,0:09:31.80,0:09:33.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天本来一个人在公司里面加班
Dialogue: 0,0:09:34.69,0:09:38.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过我有点担心因为感冒而躺在床上的和美
Dialogue: 0,0:09:38.47,0:09:39.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我就在七点五十分左右
Dialogue: 0,0:09:39.95,0:09:42.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,开车回来看看她的情况
Dialogue: 0,0:09:43.00,0:09:46.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个时候你跟和美小姐碰到面了吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:09:46.76,0:09:47.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也不能说是碰面
Dialogue: 0,0:09:48.65,0:09:50.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为她一直睡得很熟
Dialogue: 0,0:09:50.14,0:09:51.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以我就没有叫她
Dialogue: 0,0:09:51.72,0:09:53.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就直接回到车子那里了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:54.79,0:09:57.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你为什么要把车子停到米花中学的后门呢 
Dialogue: 0,0:09:58.70,0:10:01.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你为什么没有把车子停到公寓的停车场 
Dialogue: 0,0:10:02.31,0:10:05.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为这里的停车场是上下两层的设计 进出非常困难
Dialogue: 0,0:10:05.88,0:10:08.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且我马上就要回公司了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:08.38,0:10:11.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样的话直接停到公寓前面不就好了吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:10:11.58,0:10:14.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们公寓前面有公交车经过会挡路的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:20.95,0:10:23.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,岛村佐知子小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:10:23.50,0:10:24.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是给你的包裹吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:10:25.99,0:10:28.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个包裹是什么时候收到的 
Dialogue: 0,0:10:28.66,0:10:29.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个…
Dialogue: 0,0:10:29.69,0:10:32.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在你回来探望和美小姐病况的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:10:32.45,0:10:33.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,它就在了吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:10:33.53,0:10:35.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有 我不记得了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:35.86,0:10:36.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:37.30,0:10:40.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明天请你抽空到局里来进行一些例行的询问好吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:10:47.79,0:10:49.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我觉得不太对劲
Dialogue: 0,0:10:50.65,0:10:51.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你卡到鱼刺啦 
Dialogue: 0,0:10:52.23,0:10:53.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是这个啦
Dialogue: 0,0:10:53.37,0:10:56.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是说佐知子小姐她把车停在米花中学后门的理由
Dialogue: 0,0:10:56.96,0:10:57.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:10:59.39,0:11:01.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们两个到了海滩大桥那里
Dialogue: 0,0:11:01.24,0:11:03.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谈了些什么会谈一个半小时 
Dialogue: 0,0:11:05.16,0:11:08.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且你为什么要跟她一起去兜什么风
Dialogue: 0,0:11:09.03,0:11:10.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道说爸爸你…
Dialogue: 0,0:11:11.04,0:11:13.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你想说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:11:13.48,0:11:15.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我可没有动什么歪脑筋
Dialogue: 0,0:11:15.50,0:11:17.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那你就把你们谈话的内容告诉我
Dialogue: 0,0:11:17.89,0:11:20.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那些琐碎的事情我记不得了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:20.78,0:11:21.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再说路上…
Dialogue: 0,0:11:22.65,0:11:23.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再说路上怎么样
Dialogue: 0,0:11:24.31,0:11:24.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有…
Dialogue: 0,0:11:24.85,0:11:26.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:11:28.81,0:11:29.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,事实上
Dialogue: 0,0:11:30.00,0:11:32.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们真正聊天只有一开始的三十分钟
Dialogue: 0,0:11:32.88,0:11:35.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在那之后我就睡着了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:35.61,0:11:36.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,睡着了 
Dialogue: 0,0:11:38.34,0:11:40.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我在喝啤酒的时候 醉酒的感觉又回来了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:41.56,0:11:44.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等我被叫醒的时候已经是十点多了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:50.24,0:11:51.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,笑死人了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:51.53,0:11:54.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸竟然会在约会的时候睡着了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:54.13,0:11:55.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不要笑
Dialogue: 0,0:11:55.64,0:11:56.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:56.50,0:11:58.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以我才不想跟你们说的嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:11:58.87,0:12:01.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔喝酒喝到一半就睡着了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:01.59,0:12:05.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是叔叔在九点之前都很清醒还在跟她聊天
Dialogue: 0,0:12:05.64,0:12:07.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,凶案发生的时间是九点前后
Dialogue: 0,0:12:07.67,0:12:09.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她有很充分的不在场证明
Dialogue: 0,0:12:10.40,0:12:10.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等一下
Dialogue: 0,0:12:11.69,0:12:12.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔
Dialogue: 0,0:12:12.85,0:12:15.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我记得你昨天好像忘记带表了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:15.39,0:12:17.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那你是怎么知道时间的呢 
Dialogue: 0,0:12:17.89,0:12:19.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我看她车子里面的时钟啊
Dialogue: 0,0:12:19.98,0:12:21.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那坐车子之前呢 
Dialogue: 0,0:12:22.05,0:12:23.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,酒店里面也有时钟啊
Dialogue: 0,0:12:24.01,0:12:26.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在芝浜车站就看车站的钟
Dialogue: 0,0:12:26.32,0:12:27.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那时候是几点 
Dialogue: 0,0:12:28.30,0:12:29.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,七点半
Dialogue: 0,0:12:29.66,0:12:30.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,七点半
Dialogue: 0,0:12:32.83,0:12:35.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从芝浜车站坐到米花车站要十五分钟
Dialogue: 0,0:12:35.88,0:12:39.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从米花车站到米花中学这段走路大概要十分钟
Dialogue: 0,0:12:40.13,0:12:43.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么说来 叔叔和佐知子小姐碰面的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:12:43.54,0:12:46.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以是我说的在刚好八点钟的时候嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:12:46.65,0:12:49.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为我正好听到那附近的钟声响起的声音
Dialogue: 0,0:12:49.76,0:12:50.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你给我乖乖的吃饭
Dialogue: 0,0:12:51.11,0:12:52.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快去上学
Dialogue: 0,0:12:54.03,0:12:55.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔说的也对
Dialogue: 0,0:12:55.50,0:12:56.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不要再想了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:04.16,0:13:05.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要跑运动场三圈
Dialogue: 0,0:13:05.82,0:13:07.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还真是不容易
Dialogue: 0,0:13:07.26,0:13:08.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我跑不动了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:09.10,0:13:10.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只剩下一点点了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:10.26,0:13:11.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,加油 元太
Dialogue: 0,0:13:12.16,0:13:13.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,想点什么喜欢的事情
Dialogue: 0,0:13:13.84,0:13:14.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很快就会到终点了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:15.40,0:13:16.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喜欢的事情啊
Dialogue: 0,0:13:17.01,0:13:19.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好 今天晚上吃鳗鱼饭
Dialogue: 0,0:13:19.78,0:13:22.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,鳗鱼饭 鳗鱼饭 今天晚上吃鳗鱼饭
Dialogue: 0,0:13:22.05,0:13:23.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,元太 已经跑完了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:24.06,0:13:26.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,讨厌 他一心只想吃鳗鱼饭都没有注意到
Dialogue: 0,0:13:27.06,0:13:29.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,搞不好会多跑一整圈
Dialogue: 0,0:13:32.97,0:13:33.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,该不会是…
Dialogue: 0,0:13:38.66,0:13:40.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,绕环状铁路一圈
Dialogue: 0,0:13:40.83,0:13:43.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔 你从芝浜车站坐上电车以后
Dialogue: 0,0:13:43.76,0:13:45.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是不是马上就睡着了呢 
Dialogue: 0,0:13:46.80,0:13:48.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,环状铁路一圈是一个小时
Dialogue: 0,0:13:49.14,0:13:52.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果说叔叔在睡着的时候电车就绕了一圈的话
Dialogue: 0,0:13:52.75,0:13:55.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么到达米花车站的时间就不是七点四十五分
Dialogue: 0,0:13:56.06,0:13:58.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而应该是八点四十五分了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:58.96,0:14:01.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不可能 我只是睡了短短的十五分钟而已
Dialogue: 0,0:14:01.87,0:14:03.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我绝对不可能睡一整圈的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:03.55,0:14:05.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那我们就来试试好了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:06.02,0:14:06.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么 
Dialogue: 0,0:14:07.17,0:14:09.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们今天晚上就一起去坐环状铁路
Dialogue: 0,0:14:10.14,0:14:14.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是芝浜车站那班七点半发车的同一辆电车
Dialogue: 0,0:14:15.72,0:14:17.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个嘛 我倒是无所谓啦
Dialogue: 0,0:14:27.00,0:14:29.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么样 爸爸 想起什么了吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:14:29.91,0:14:30.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有
Dialogue: 0,0:14:30.99,0:14:33.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看样子昨天晚上我睡得很熟
Dialogue: 0,0:14:33.95,0:14:35.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过佐知子绝对不可能是凶手
Dialogue: 0,0:14:36.03,0:14:37.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们还是先坐一圈再说吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:46.77,0:14:49.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这里是距离芝浜车站最远的一站
Dialogue: 0,0:15:00.24,0:15:01.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们几个怎么啦 
Dialogue: 0,0:15:01.86,0:15:03.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道说你们认识那位叔叔吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:15:03.78,0:15:04.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,糖果
Dialogue: 0,0:15:05.86,0:15:08.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,昨天那个叔叔坐车睡觉的时候嘴巴张得好大
Dialogue: 0,0:15:11.07,0:15:12.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后他就把糖果丢到他嘴巴里了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:18.86,0:15:20.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个时候是几点钟 
Dialogue: 0,0:15:20.30,0:15:21.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就和今天一样
Dialogue: 0,0:15:21.37,0:15:22.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,八点左右
Dialogue: 0,0:15:24.53,0:15:25.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么说来
Dialogue: 0,0:15:25.54,0:15:28.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我坐到米花车站的时候就快要九点了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:28.43,0:15:32.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么我跟佐知子小姐见面的时候就是九点钟了吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:15:32.15,0:15:32.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错
Dialogue: 0,0:15:32.95,0:15:35.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后到达海滩大桥那里应该是九点半
Dialogue: 0,0:15:36.74,0:15:38.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,聊天聊了三十分钟就到了十点
Dialogue: 0,0:15:39.87,0:15:41.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被叫醒是十点十分
Dialogue: 0,0:15:42.72,0:15:46.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔你本来以为自己睡了一个小时十分钟
Dialogue: 0,0:15:46.44,0:15:48.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,事实上你只睡了十分钟而已
Dialogue: 0,0:15:49.69,0:15:52.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说她是把时钟往后拨了一个小时
Dialogue: 0,0:15:53.17,0:15:55.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样就能够利用我为她做不在场证明了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:57.13,0:15:58.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她昨天晚上
Dialogue: 0,0:15:58.42,0:16:01.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了避人耳目就故意把车子停在这个地方
Dialogue: 0,0:16:01.33,0:16:03.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后就去杀了她的室友
Dialogue: 0,0:16:04.24,0:16:07.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从事先就打开了的窗户进去
Dialogue: 0,0:16:08.29,0:16:09.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,进入屋子里面以后故意制造出一些声音
Dialogue: 0,0:16:10.15,0:16:11.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等被害者被吵醒以后
Dialogue: 0,0:16:11.90,0:16:14.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她就可以伪装成强盗杀人
Dialogue: 0,0:16:17.57,0:16:20.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后她又回到了这里才碰到了爸爸对吧 
Dialogue: 0,0:16:23.22,0:16:25.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对了 我记得她那个时候
Dialogue: 0,0:16:26.05,0:16:29.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那一定就是她在行凶的时候所穿的血衣
Dialogue: 0,0:16:29.68,0:16:31.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有她作案的手套了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:33.89,0:16:34.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是这样的话
Dialogue: 0,0:16:34.94,0:16:37.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她一定是趁着叔叔在大桥上睡着的时候把它处理掉了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:39.60,0:16:40.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车子上的时钟
Dialogue: 0,0:16:40.87,0:16:43.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也是她在叔叔上车之前往前拨了一个小时
Dialogue: 0,0:16:43.88,0:16:46.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后趁着叔叔睡着的这段时间她才把它调回去了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:47.19,0:16:48.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可恶
Dialogue: 0,0:16:48.43,0:16:51.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,竟敢这样戏弄我名侦探毛利小五郎
Dialogue: 0,0:16:52.07,0:16:54.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,除此之外还有什么奇怪的地方吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:16:59.24,0:17:01.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那些小孩看到过毛利先生 
Dialogue: 0,0:17:01.59,0:17:03.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你的不在场证明已经不成立了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:04.36,0:17:07.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其实你跟毛利老弟在米花中学后面碰面的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:17:07.84,0:17:10.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,正好是凶案发生后没几分钟的事情
Dialogue: 0,0:17:13.17,0:17:13.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是
Dialogue: 0,0:17:14.13,0:17:15.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那些小孩也有可能是把毛利先生看成是
Dialogue: 0,0:17:16.18,0:17:19.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他们前天晚上看到的某个人不是吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:17:19.96,0:17:22.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,的…的确 是有这个可能
Dialogue: 0,0:17:22.23,0:17:25.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再说我的不在场证明就算没有办法成立的话
Dialogue: 0,0:17:26.07,0:17:30.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们也没有办法证明是我杀了和美的
Dialogue: 0,0:17:30.51,0:17:32.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说的这些的确也有道理
Dialogue: 0,0:17:33.48,0:17:35.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是我却有证据
Dialogue: 0,0:17:37.14,0:17:39.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔 今天交给你了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:42.67,0:17:45.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请问你对这支原珠笔有没有什么印象
Dialogue: 0,0:17:47.32,0:17:49.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错 这支本来就是你的笔
Dialogue: 0,0:17:51.83,0:17:52.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:17:52.97,0:17:54.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你还好吧 毛利
Dialogue: 0,0:17:54.75,0:17:55.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是的
Dialogue: 0,0:17:55.82,0:17:58.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,搞了半天还是要我来
Dialogue: 0,0:18:00.08,0:18:00.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,事情的经过
Dialogue: 0,0:18:01.30,0:18:04.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们就先回到前天晚上的八点半的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:18:04.89,0:18:07.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个时候快递公司的人把包裹送到你的公寓
Dialogue: 0,0:18:08.14,0:18:10.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来在睡觉的和美小姐出来开门
Dialogue: 0,0:18:10.63,0:18:12.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是她却找不到印章
Dialogue: 0,0:18:13.30,0:18:14.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和美小姐情急之下
Dialogue: 0,0:18:15.16,0:18:18.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就拿了餐厅桌上的原珠笔去签名
Dialogue: 0,0:18:18.86,0:18:20.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是这支笔又写不出来
Dialogue: 0,0:18:21.10,0:18:21.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,送货的人
Dialogue: 0,0:18:22.04,0:18:23.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怀疑是不是没有墨水了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:23.84,0:18:27.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就拿起了原珠笔把笔芯拿出来确定了一下
Dialogue: 0,0:18:29.06,0:18:32.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他发现笔芯里面还有一点墨水
Dialogue: 0,0:18:32.59,0:18:34.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和美小姐再写的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:18:34.64,0:18:36.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就写出来了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:37.06,0:18:38.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,送货的人走了之后
Dialogue: 0,0:18:38.69,0:18:43.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和美小姐就把那支原珠笔放在餐厅电话账单上面
Dialogue: 0,0:18:43.49,0:18:46.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后 就又回到房里面继续休息了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:46.92,0:18:48.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接着二十分钟以后
Dialogue: 0,0:18:53.51,0:18:57.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你把掉在她尸体旁边的笔当成是自己的笔
Dialogue: 0,0:18:57.73,0:19:00.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在心虚之下反射性地捡了就出去了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:00.85,0:19:01.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接着…
Dialogue: 0,0:19:10.99,0:19:12.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你不是佐知子小姐吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:19:14.90,0:19:18.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在那之后你邀请我一起去兜风
Dialogue: 0,0:19:18.78,0:19:21.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而当时用来作案穿的血衣跟手套
Dialogue: 0,0:19:21.71,0:19:23.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就放在后座的椅子底下
Dialogue: 0,0:19:24.34,0:19:27.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个时候你包里的原珠笔就掉了出来
Dialogue: 0,0:19:32.88,0:19:34.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我在想你应该没有注意到才对
Dialogue: 0,0:19:35.59,0:19:37.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那天晚上我坐到副驾驶座
Dialogue: 0,0:19:37.83,0:19:40.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚好有支原珠笔从我的西装口袋里面掉了出来
Dialogue: 0,0:19:42.85,0:19:44.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你应该知道了吧 
Dialogue: 0,0:19:45.07,0:19:46.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其实那天我的原子笔掉了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:46.96,0:19:50.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我却阴差阳错把你的那支原珠笔给捡了起来
Dialogue: 0,0:19:54.61,0:19:57.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这支原珠笔上面的确有你的指纹
Dialogue: 0,0:19:57.46,0:20:00.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,另外还有毛利的指纹
Dialogue: 0,0:20:00.52,0:20:01.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,除此之外这个笔芯上
Dialogue: 0,0:20:02.48,0:20:06.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有那天送货的那位先生的指纹
Dialogue: 0,0:20:07.33,0:20:08.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这些指纹
Dialogue: 0,0:20:08.58,0:20:12.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就可以证明你在过了八点半以后曾经进过你租的那间公寓
Dialogue: 0,0:20:12.89,0:20:13.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有错吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:20:18.09,0:20:20.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为和美向我勒索
Dialogue: 0,0:20:22.24,0:20:23.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一年以前
Dialogue: 0,0:20:24.52,0:20:27.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我曾经将一项法律上限制的违禁品
Dialogue: 0,0:20:28.18,0:20:30.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在不知情的情况下进口代理贩卖了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:31.11,0:20:32.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和美在知道这件事情后
Dialogue: 0,0:20:32.63,0:20:35.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就要求我每个月必须支付她固定金额的款项
Dialogue: 0,0:20:36.33,0:20:37.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果我不照做
Dialogue: 0,0:20:37.52,0:20:41.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她就要公诸于世 而银行就不会再融资给我了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:41.91,0:20:44.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我在无奈之下只好接受她的要挟
Dialogue: 0,0:20:44.78,0:20:48.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是想到我这辈子都要在她的勒索下工作 我就…
Dialogue: 0,0:20:48.67,0:20:50.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把心一横 就把她给杀掉了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:52.32,0:20:55.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,老实说毛利先生出声叫我的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:20:55.56,0:20:57.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我还以为一切都已经完了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:57.93,0:21:01.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是在我知道毛利先生把时间看早了一个小时
Dialogue: 0,0:21:01.96,0:21:03.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我就决定赌赌自己的运气
Dialogue: 0,0:21:04.09,0:21:06.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是 如果你没有碰到毛利的话
Dialogue: 0,0:21:06.53,0:21:08.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你打算怎么做不在场的证明呢
Dialogue: 0,0:21:09.94,0:21:12.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我在公司的窗户上装了一个防盗的摄影机
Dialogue: 0,0:21:12.57,0:21:14.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对着对面的酒店不停拍摄
Dialogue: 0,0:21:15.65,0:21:18.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样一来凶案发生的时间那里有哪些客人出入
Dialogue: 0,0:21:18.68,0:21:21.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我看了之后就可以向警方证明自己在公司了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:21.51,0:21:24.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你跟毛利兜风回来时你到公司去了一会儿
Dialogue: 0,0:21:24.98,0:21:27.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是为了把那个防盗摄影机拆下来 对不对
Dialogue: 0,0:21:28.37,0:21:29.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有错
Dialogue: 0,0:21:29.96,0:21:32.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接下来的一切就像毛利先生所推理的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:33.21,0:21:35.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉 给你们添了太多麻烦
Dialogue: 0,0:23:12.59,0:23:14.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我可以问你一个问题吗 
Dialogue: 0,0:23:15.12,0:23:17.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔在大桥上面睡着以后
Dialogue: 0,0:23:17.53,0:23:19.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你要杀他的话也是有可能的吧 
Dialogue: 0,0:23:19.85,0:23:20.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:23:22.07,0:23:23.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是你却没有这么做
Dialogue: 0,0:23:24.75,0:23:25.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么呢 
Dialogue: 0,0:23:28.21,0:23:29.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为…
Dialogue: 0,0:23:30.34,0:23:33.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我对毛利先生又没有任何仇恨
Dialogue: 0,0:23:52.47,0:23:53.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喂
Dialogue: 0,0:23:54.06,0:23:55.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你在干什么 
Dialogue: 0,0:23:56.51,0:24:00.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而这次又是因为偶然的机会来到这里的…
Dialogue: 0,0:24:00.95,0:24:03.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么又是你啊 毛利
Dialogue: 0,0:24:03.94,0:24:06.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不要这么大声嚷嚷嘛 警官
Dialogue: 0,0:24:06.52,0:24:08.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我宿醉还没醒呢…
Dialogue: 0,0:24:09.26,0:24:10.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,NEXT CONAN
Dialogue: 0,0:24:10.81,0:24:13.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,名陶艺家杀人事件 (前篇)
Dialogue: 0,0:24:15.30,0:24:17.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,Next Conan's HINT 我是高木警官
Dialogue: 0,0:24:17.72,0:24:18.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,弹珠
Dialogue: 0,0:24:19.38,0:24:20.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下回是有关烧陶的故事
Dialogue: 0,0:24:20.81,0:24:22.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我喜欢上等牛肩肉
Dialogue: 0,0:24:22.09,0:24:24.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是烧肉喔 高木
