[Script Info]
;                 This is a Sub Station Alpha v4 script.
;                 For Sub Station Alpha info and downloads,
;                 go to http://www.eswat.demon.co.uk/
;                 or email kotus@eswat.demon.co.uk
;                 
;                 Note: This file was saved by Subresync.
;                 
; // 此字幕由PopSub生成  2009-08-23 00:27:52
; // 版本: 0.74
; // popgo_fansub@yahoo.co.jp
; // 欢迎访问漫游天下 http://bbs.popgo.net
Title:漫游字幕
Original Script:漫游字幕组
Synch Point:0
ScriptType:v4.00+
Collisions:Normal
PlayResX:640
PlayResY:480
Timer:100.0000

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,文鼎新艺体简,25,&H00FFFFFF,&H0000FFFF,&H00000000,&H00000000,0,0,0,0,100,100,0,0.00,1,1,1,2,20,20,10,1
Style: op,文鼎特圆简,19,&H00FFFFFF,&H00000000,&H00000000,&H00000000,-1,0,0,0,100,100,0,0.00,1,0,0,2,30,30,10,134
Style: ed,文鼎特圆简,19,&H00FFFFFF,&H00000000,&H00000000,&H00000000,-1,0,0,0,100,100,0,0.00,1,0,0,2,30,30,10,134

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Actor, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text



Dialogue: 0,0:00:16.18,0:00:22.69,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(320,445)\fscx125\be1}命运的转轮不停地旋转
Dialogue: 0,0:00:22.80,0:00:31.19,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(320,445)\fscx125\be1}但我永远注视着你
Dialogue: 0,0:00:34.94,0:00:40.33,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(220,445)\fscx125\be1}为何
Dialogue: 0,0:00:34.94,0:00:40.33,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(310,445)\fscx125\be1}我如此
Dialogue: 0,0:00:34.94,0:00:40.33,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(423,445)\fscx125\be1}三生有幸
Dialogue: 0,0:00:40.94,0:00:46.91,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(263,445)\fscx125\be1}每见到水平线
Dialogue: 0,0:00:40.94,0:00:46.91,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(428,445)\fscx125\be1}便有莫名哀伤
Dialogue: 0,0:00:48.03,0:00:56.50,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(280,445)\fscx125\be1}远远地回首
Dialogue: 0,0:00:48.03,0:00:56.50,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(450,445)\fscx125\be1}过去的自己
Dialogue: 0,0:00:56.63,0:00:59.92,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(318,445)\fscx125\be1}无限感伤
Dialogue: 0,0:01:00.80,0:01:06.80,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(320,445)\fscx125\be1}命运的转轮不停地旋转
Dialogue: 0,0:01:07.93,0:01:13.14,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(259,445)\fscx125\be1}能够深入思考的只有
Dialogue: 0,0:01:07.93,0:01:13.14,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(442,445)\fscx150\be1}Mystery
Dialogue: 0,0:01:13.39,0:01:19.69,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(315,445)\fscx125\be1}你看  命中的良人就在那里
Dialogue: 0,0:01:19.82,0:01:26.41,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(237,445)\fscx125\be1}我永远
Dialogue: 0,0:01:19.82,0:01:26.41,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(358,445)\fscx125\be1}一直守候你
Dialogue: 0,0:01:26.53,0:01:35.01,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(237,445)\fscx125\be1}我永远
Dialogue: 0,0:01:26.53,0:01:35.01,op,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(358,445)\fscx125\be1}一直守候你
Dialogue: 0,0:21:54.09,0:22:01.16,ed,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(320,440)\fscx125\be1}为何我们两人会相遇?
Dialogue: 0,0:22:01.47,0:22:09.78,ed,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(320,440)\fscx125\be1}一起共看如此凄凉的夕阳
Dialogue: 0,0:22:10.41,0:22:17.28,ed,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(320,440)\fscx125\be1}搜索枯阳找寻能吸引他的话语
Dialogue: 0,0:22:17.92,0:22:26.21,ed,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(315,440)\fscx125\be1}却找不出分离仍能相聚的安慰
Dialogue: 0,0:22:26.54,0:22:34.66,ed,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(320,440)\fscx125\be1}脸色虽然有时难看只要能以笑脸拂去
Dialogue: 0,0:22:34.91,0:22:43.26,ed,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(320,440)\fscx125\be1}虽然争执偶而有之但是也能忍耐
Dialogue: 0,0:22:45.17,0:22:52.92,ed,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(320,440)\fscx125\be1}只要唯一的愿望可以实现的话
Dialogue: 0,0:22:53.32,0:23:01.53,ed,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(320,440)\fscx125\be1}曾经受伤的内心也将再度痊愈…
Dialogue: 0,0:00:00.96,0:00:02.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,人与人的邂逅充满了神奇
Dialogue: 0,0:00:02.68,0:00:04.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,各种刑案更是谜题重重
Dialogue: 0,0:00:04.34,0:00:06.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,能够遇到你真的是太好了
Dialogue: 0,0:00:06.89,0:00:08.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天是陶艺解决篇
Dialogue: 0,0:00:08.53,0:00:10.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南的推理天衣无缝
Dialogue: 0,0:00:10.67,0:00:12.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看清唯一真相的是
Dialogue: 0,0:00:12.35,0:00:13.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,外表看似小孩 头脑却是大人
Dialogue: 0,0:00:14.36,0:00:16.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他的名字就是 名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:01:37.31,0:01:39.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在国宝级陶艺家菊右卫门的邀请下
Dialogue: 0,0:01:39.30,0:01:44.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我跟小兰还有叔叔到了他在西多摩的家里拜访
Dialogue: 0,0:01:46.21,0:01:47.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是没过多久就发生了大事
Dialogue: 0,0:01:48.68,0:01:50.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,土屋太太竟然在仓库里面
Dialogue: 0,0:01:50.40,0:01:54.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,将菊右卫门的新作品风水号给打破了
Dialogue: 0,0:01:55.19,0:01:58.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那天晚上在酒精的助兴下土屋太太喝得太醉了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:00.08,0:02:01.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,第二天一早
Dialogue: 0,0:02:01.76,0:02:02.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大家在仓库的里面
Dialogue: 0,0:02:05.54,0:02:07.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,却发现土屋太太吊在屋梁上死了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:09.51,0:02:12.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,名陶艺家杀人事件 (后篇)
Dialogue: 0,0:02:16.49,0:02:19.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个时侯你们这些人真的全部聚集在客厅里面吗
Dialogue: 0,0:02:20.48,0:02:24.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 唯一离开过这里的只有大谷一个人
Dialogue: 0,0:02:24.11,0:02:25.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为他要去叫土屋太太
Dialogue: 0,0:02:27.00,0:02:29.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,该不会是你假装去叫醒她
Dialogue: 0,0:02:29.11,0:02:31.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,趁机把睡着的土屋太太吊死了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:02:31.53,0:02:32.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是这样的
Dialogue: 0,0:02:32.69,0:02:34.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我只有离开这个房间一会儿
Dialogue: 0,0:02:35.06,0:02:38.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为土屋太太的房间就在客厅旁边的隔壁两间
Dialogue: 0,0:02:39.51,0:02:40.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是真的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:02:40.71,0:02:41.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:02:41.83,0:02:43.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想十分钟应该都用不上
Dialogue: 0,0:02:45.05,0:02:48.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么短的时间根本不能做什么事情
Dialogue: 0,0:02:48.75,0:02:49.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有谁离开过吗
Dialogue: 0,0:02:50.62,0:02:52.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我为了打电话也离开过一下
Dialogue: 0,0:02:53.23,0:02:55.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们以为土屋太太一大早就到外面去了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:55.97,0:02:57.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过 我虽然离开了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:57.62,0:02:59.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,却是利用客厅前面走廊上的那个电话
Dialogue: 0,0:03:00.12,0:03:02.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,联络土屋太太的手机的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:04.13,0:03:06.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是怪了 没人接
Dialogue: 0,0:03:07.06,0:03:09.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,手机 那是她的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:03:10.35,0:03:15.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错 我常常会要益子随身都要带着手机
Dialogue: 0,0:03:15.88,0:03:18.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,主要的原因是我想专心在作品创造上面
Dialogue: 0,0:03:19.04,0:03:22.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以其他的事情我全权交给益子处理了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:23.14,0:03:24.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其他的事情指的是什么
Dialogue: 0,0:03:24.91,0:03:27.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是作品的取件事宜 还有发表会的日期
Dialogue: 0,0:03:27.69,0:03:30.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以我们的老师平常几乎是不出门的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:31.21,0:03:32.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过这就怪了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:33.28,0:03:36.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,土屋太太的尸体旁边并没有发现她的手机啊
Dialogue: 0,0:03:37.54,0:03:38.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说起手机
Dialogue: 0,0:03:38.88,0:03:41.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们刚才已经在被害者的房间里面找到了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:42.73,0:03:45.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我记得应该是在折好的棉被底下发现的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:45.88,0:03:46.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,棉被底下
Dialogue: 0,0:03:49.70,0:03:53.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为土屋太太每次都会把手机当成闹钟
Dialogue: 0,0:03:53.61,0:03:54.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,放在枕头底下来叫醒她
Dialogue: 0,0:03:54.66,0:03:58.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是那手机当时里面已经没有电了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:58.65,0:03:59.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:04:00.07,0:04:01.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以就算你们从隔壁打电话给她
Dialogue: 0,0:04:01.72,0:04:04.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她也听不到
Dialogue: 0,0:04:05.95,0:04:06.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么
Dialogue: 0,0:04:06.88,0:04:08.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,除此之外还有谁离开过房间呀
Dialogue: 0,0:04:09.41,0:04:10.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其他就没有了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:10.73,0:04:11.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错 
Dialogue: 0,0:04:11.64,0:04:12.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们都在这
Dialogue: 0,0:04:13.34,0:04:15.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那会是谁呢
Dialogue: 0,0:04:15.49,0:04:18.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,会是谁把她带到仓库里面杀害的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:04:18.69,0:04:21.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果她的尸体是在吊死之后就马上发现的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:21.84,0:04:24.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们全部在客厅就有充分的不在场证明
Dialogue: 0,0:04:24.73,0:04:27.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以我就说这是自杀案件嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:04:28.60,0:04:31.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,土屋太太的脚上之所以没有穿着鞋子
Dialogue: 0,0:04:31.26,0:04:34.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是因为她忽然起了想要自杀的念头
Dialogue: 0,0:04:34.58,0:04:36.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,至于她的脚都没有弄脏
Dialogue: 0,0:04:36.77,0:04:38.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是因为她从到仓库之前
Dialogue: 0,0:04:38.41,0:04:40.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一直是踏着院子里的石头走的关系
Dialogue: 0,0:04:40.77,0:04:45.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为她就是在这个仓库里面把那个风水号给打破的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:45.83,0:04:50.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她一早起来看到仓库不自觉地就走到仓库里面来了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:50.38,0:04:51.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这也没有什么好奇怪的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:52.40,0:04:53.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说的也是
Dialogue: 0,0:04:54.23,0:04:58.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,绳子是因为仓库里经常会有东西要绑才会准备的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:58.96,0:05:00.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且听到那个水壶破掉的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:05:00.83,0:05:02.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们大家都在一起
Dialogue: 0,0:05:03.59,0:05:04.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不管怎么说
Dialogue: 0,0:05:04.55,0:05:07.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果说不将这个仓库详细的搜查一遍
Dialogue: 0,0:05:07.59,0:05:08.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是不会有结论的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:09.49,0:05:12.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,现在请大家回到客厅等我们把调查工作做完
Dialogue: 0,0:05:13.19,0:05:15.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且尽量的不要采取任何私自的行动
Dialogue: 0,0:05:18.11,0:05:19.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,自杀
Dialogue: 0,0:05:20.13,0:05:21.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这真的是自杀案吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:23.24,0:05:25.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是里面可疑的地方也太多了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:26.78,0:05:29.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一个是右腿上那个切口清楚的伤痕
Dialogue: 0,0:05:30.43,0:05:32.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再来就是死者没有穿鞋的怪异举动
Dialogue: 0,0:05:33.00,0:05:34.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有 没弄脏脚底
Dialogue: 0,0:05:35.18,0:05:35.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,另外
Dialogue: 0,0:05:38.00,0:05:39.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在案发的前一天我在仓库里
Dialogue: 0,0:05:39.73,0:05:43.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,风水号摔破的碎片旁边发现这个弹珠
Dialogue: 0,0:05:44.06,0:05:45.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是哪里不对呢
Dialogue: 0,0:05:46.18,0:05:49.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我到底忽略了哪一点 是现场我没有看到的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:05:52.44,0:05:53.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来是个弹珠啊
Dialogue: 0,0:05:54.32,0:05:57.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,孩子就是孩子 才会对这种东西有兴趣
Dialogue: 0,0:05:59.52,0:06:00.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,糟了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:02.23,0:06:04.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大叔到底在搞什么嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:06:12.80,0:06:13.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:14.34,0:06:17.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南你怎么从这里出来了 走开啦
Dialogue: 0,0:06:18.10,0:06:19.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你看那边
Dialogue: 0,0:06:21.75,0:06:25.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是口红 可是我没有涂口红啊
Dialogue: 0,0:06:28.49,0:06:30.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个地方怎么会沾上口红的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:06:32.48,0:06:33.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道说…
Dialogue: 0,0:06:33.81,0:06:34.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你等一下
Dialogue: 0,0:06:35.33,0:06:36.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喂 搞什么啊
Dialogue: 0,0:06:36.69,0:06:37.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你要去哪里啊 柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:06:38.91,0:06:40.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我一直想找却找不到的东西
Dialogue: 0,0:06:43.37,0:06:44.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道是…
Dialogue: 0,0:06:47.92,0:06:48.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么事啊
Dialogue: 0,0:06:48.53,0:06:50.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我有东西忘在这里了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:50.17,0:06:52.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,忘了什么 你不可以随便进来的啊
Dialogue: 0,0:06:52.96,0:06:54.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,奇怪 那个阿姨的尸体呢
Dialogue: 0,0:06:54.89,0:06:56.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,已经被警方送到医院去了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:00.37,0:07:02.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,找到了 就是这个
Dialogue: 0,0:07:03.33,0:07:04.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,终于被我找到了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:05.14,0:07:07.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这就是凶手想要隐藏的痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:07:08.62,0:07:10.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果这种东西出现在这里的话
Dialogue: 0,0:07:10.63,0:07:11.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么上面就是
Dialogue: 0,0:07:16.50,0:07:17.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我就知道
Dialogue: 0,0:07:18.79,0:07:20.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只要利用这个方法
Dialogue: 0,0:07:20.84,0:07:23.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就算不在这个现场也可以能够作案
Dialogue: 0,0:07:26.02,0:07:29.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过如果真有实行这件谋杀罪行
Dialogue: 0,0:07:30.05,0:07:31.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个东西应该在那附近才对
Dialogue: 0,0:07:32.89,0:07:33.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,0:07:37.85,0:07:40.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喂 你要干什么 快点下来啊
Dialogue: 0,0:07:40.77,0:07:43.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我刚才不是已经说过我来找忘记的东西吗
Dialogue: 0,0:07:43.93,0:07:45.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚才我们已经看过那里了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:45.94,0:07:47.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,根本没有什么奇怪的东西
Dialogue: 0,0:07:47.74,0:07:49.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,太危险了 快点下来
Dialogue: 0,0:07:49.96,0:07:53.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错 这里除了陶艺品的确什么都没有了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:01.70,0:08:05.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此 陶艺家果然就是不一样
Dialogue: 0,0:08:06.48,0:08:07.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快点给我下来
Dialogue: 0,0:08:07.86,0:08:08.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,0:08:09.17,0:08:13.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么一来只有他们两个人可能是凶手
Dialogue: 0,0:08:14.53,0:08:18.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过很可能是他对土屋太太设下的陷阱
Dialogue: 0,0:08:19.03,0:08:20.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让一切看起来像是自杀
Dialogue: 0,0:08:21.40,0:08:24.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是现在还将杀人的证据带在身上的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:25.79,0:08:27.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就只有他一个人了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:32.41,0:08:35.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好 已经知道凶手和作案的手法了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:35.55,0:08:38.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接下来就是如何把这答案告诉目暮警部
Dialogue: 0,0:08:39.01,0:08:43.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请问 我们到底要在客厅那里等到什么时候才可以啊
Dialogue: 0,0:08:44.50,0:08:45.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真不好意思
Dialogue: 0,0:08:45.87,0:08:48.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这边再过一会应该可以结束了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:48.32,0:08:50.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们可以去吃点东西吗
Dialogue: 0,0:08:50.15,0:08:52.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天从一早起床都还没有吃过东西
Dialogue: 0,0:08:52.48,0:08:54.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也想去换件衣服
Dialogue: 0,0:08:55.11,0:08:55.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那你们去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:08:55.94,0:08:58.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想我的属下应该不会拒绝才对的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:58.38,0:09:02.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不可以 让他们离开的话证据就没了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:02.12,0:09:02.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,证据
Dialogue: 0,0:09:03.97,0:09:06.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这里用不着你这个小鬼来多嘴
Dialogue: 0,0:09:06.34,0:09:07.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:09:07.32,0:09:09.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么鬼证据啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:09.30,0:09:12.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是自杀案件 根本就没有什么凶手
Dialogue: 0,0:09:13.05,0:09:15.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我说的没错吧 警部大人
Dialogue: 0,0:09:15.50,0:09:16.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:09:16.69,0:09:17.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好疼
Dialogue: 0,0:09:18.15,0:09:21.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看样子只有再用这个麻醉枪让叔叔睡着了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:24.02,0:09:26.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我刚才发现叔叔你说的那个东西了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:27.24,0:09:28.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么东西
Dialogue: 0,0:09:28.83,0:09:32.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不好吧 大家都在怎么能说呢
Dialogue: 0,0:09:33.60,0:09:35.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,耳朵凑过来 我是说
Dialogue: 0,0:09:36.03,0:09:38.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚才叔叔你 明明就…
Dialogue: 0,0:09:46.42,0:09:50.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,现在只要在领子上装上纽扣式扩音器就行了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:52.21,0:09:54.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你真的找到了 这真是太棒了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:56.56,0:10:00.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喂 你到底找到了些什么东西啊
Dialogue: 0,0:10:00.73,0:10:04.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那当然是凶手想要隐瞒的证据啊
Dialogue: 0,0:10:04.76,0:10:06.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,照你这么说 难道说…
Dialogue: 0,0:10:07.10,0:10:11.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 土屋太太根本不是自杀而是被人杀害的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:11.70,0:10:14.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且这个凶手现在就在我们之中
Dialogue: 0,0:10:18.00,0:10:19.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,实在太有意思了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:20.18,0:10:24.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,能够近距离欣赏沉睡小五郎的名推理真是荣幸啊
Dialogue: 0,0:10:25.04,0:10:28.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毛利老弟 如果说尸体是在死亡之后立刻被发现
Dialogue: 0,0:10:29.00,0:10:31.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那这些人根本就不可能作案啊
Dialogue: 0,0:10:31.77,0:10:34.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且一直也是你认为这是自杀案件的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:34.86,0:10:37.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那只是我为了让凶手疏于防范所说的谎话
Dialogue: 0,0:10:38.01,0:10:40.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要是他起了疑心把证据都消灭掉的话
Dialogue: 0,0:10:40.84,0:10:42.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不就伤脑筋了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:10:42.18,0:10:44.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这样啊 那你说你到底找到了什么证据了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:45.64,0:10:47.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是血啊 警部
Dialogue: 0,0:10:47.12,0:10:47.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,血
Dialogue: 0,0:10:48.96,0:10:51.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毛利叔叔因为觉得这里的血不太对劲
Dialogue: 0,0:10:51.70,0:10:53.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以才叫我到这里来帮他看看的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:54.26,0:10:55.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,血不对劲
Dialogue: 0,0:10:55.80,0:10:58.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对啊 我想应该就是这个血吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:02.46,0:11:04.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这…这是
Dialogue: 0,0:11:05.01,0:11:07.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚才把尸体搬到这里的就是你们吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:07.69,0:11:10.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 我们是想也许还能救得了她
Dialogue: 0,0:11:11.25,0:11:14.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我扶着土屋太太的手 濑户就抱着她的脚
Dialogue: 0,0:11:14.63,0:11:16.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一起把她移到屋子里面的角落的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:16.60,0:11:17.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:17.23,0:11:17.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:11:19.31,0:11:22.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是这样的话 这的确是不太对劲
Dialogue: 0,0:11:22.70,0:11:24.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个血到底哪里不对了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:24.67,0:11:26.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想血迹之所以会一滴一滴的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:26.16,0:11:29.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也许是我们在移动尸体的时候流下来的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:29.83,0:11:33.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不对 这里的血并不全都是那个时侯流下来的血
Dialogue: 0,0:11:34.91,0:11:36.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这里还混杂了别的血
Dialogue: 0,0:11:36.24,0:11:39.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然不是很好辨别 不过的确还有别的血
Dialogue: 0,0:11:39.42,0:11:40.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,别的血
Dialogue: 0,0:11:41.68,0:11:44.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,人类的血迹掉落在地板上的形状
Dialogue: 0,0:11:44.74,0:11:47.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,主要是以掉落坠地的高度而定会有不同的改变
Dialogue: 0,0:11:48.99,0:11:51.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,距离越高血迹的圆点就越大
Dialogue: 0,0:11:51.65,0:11:54.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,往圆形的周围扩散的血花也更明显
Dialogue: 0,0:11:55.04,0:11:57.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果是扶着土屋太太的手脚移动的话
Dialogue: 0,0:11:57.96,0:12:01.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,身体到地板的距离充其量不过50公分
Dialogue: 0,0:12:01.69,0:12:04.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是这个血迹却很明显的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:04.11,0:12:06.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是从超过一公尺以上的高度掉下来的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:07.47,0:12:10.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个血迹会掉落在这里那就表示
Dialogue: 0,0:12:10.43,0:12:13.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道说这就表示土屋太太曾经在柜子上面吗
Dialogue: 0,0:12:14.22,0:12:17.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会 难道说…
Dialogue: 0,0:12:17.56,0:12:22.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错 土屋太太就是被凶手在大半夜的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:12:22.38,0:12:24.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,搬到架子的上面去的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:26.11,0:12:28.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,并且在天花板的屋梁上面绑上绳子
Dialogue: 0,0:12:28.50,0:12:31.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再把绳子的一端绕成圆形套住脖子就行了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:32.10,0:12:35.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么一来土屋太太一早起来因为失去平衡
Dialogue: 0,0:12:36.26,0:12:38.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就会从架子上面掉下来
Dialogue: 0,0:12:38.30,0:12:41.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到时候就可以自动的为凶手犯下了罪行了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:41.94,0:12:44.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在她被吊住之后所发出的那个巨大声响
Dialogue: 0,0:12:45.20,0:12:48.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也是凶手在屋梁绑上绳结的位置下面
Dialogue: 0,0:12:48.46,0:12:50.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,事先放置了一个水壶的关系
Dialogue: 0,0:12:50.91,0:12:52.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被害人被吊住脖子之后
Dialogue: 0,0:12:52.66,0:12:55.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从那么高的地方掉下来绝对会立刻死亡
Dialogue: 0,0:12:56.08,0:12:58.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接下来身体的脚步又顺势将水壶给踢倒了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:59.07,0:13:03.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样就会让人看起来像是死者踢倒水壶自杀的
Dialogue: 0,0:13:04.02,0:13:06.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么一来不但能让尸体尽早被发现
Dialogue: 0,0:13:06.96,0:13:09.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也能为当时在客厅里的那个凶手
Dialogue: 0,0:13:09.92,0:13:11.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,做充分的不在场证明了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:12.65,0:13:15.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那土屋太太右腿上那个切伤的痕迹呢
Dialogue: 0,0:13:16.12,0:13:20.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大家现在看到架子的上面钉了一个钉子对吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:22.10,0:13:22.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,的确没错
Dialogue: 0,0:13:23.18,0:13:27.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想这很有可能是土屋太太在失去平衡掉下去的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:13:28.07,0:13:30.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小腿就正好被那根钉子给割到了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:31.26,0:13:33.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,架子的旁边之所以会有血滴的痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:13:33.70,0:13:36.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也许是因为她抓住架子维持了几秒钟的关系
Dialogue: 0,0:13:37.39,0:13:41.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么说来死者右脚上的伤口是碰巧伤到的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:41.73,0:13:45.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 这个伤口完全出乎凶手意料之外
Dialogue: 0,0:13:46.17,0:13:50.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想他看到土屋太太的伤口心里也一定很吃惊吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:50.87,0:13:54.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过这个凶手应该很快就注意到她受伤的原因
Dialogue: 0,0:13:55.60,0:13:57.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也注意到掉落在架子旁边的血迹了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:58.48,0:14:00.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果说是被害人是因为挣扎而向四周晃动
Dialogue: 0,0:14:00.57,0:14:02.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,血迹才喷出去的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:02.63,0:14:04.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么她和架子的距离还是太远了一点
Dialogue: 0,0:14:05.17,0:14:06.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要是被人发现这些血迹的话
Dialogue: 0,0:14:06.90,0:14:10.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,凶手担心他使用的杀人手法很有可能会被揭穿
Dialogue: 0,0:14:10.48,0:14:12.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就主动带领大家
Dialogue: 0,0:14:12.74,0:14:16.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把尸体移动到原来就沾有血迹的地方
Dialogue: 0,0:14:16.65,0:14:18.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 就是想用血来遮住血
Dialogue: 0,0:14:19.31,0:14:20.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我说的没错吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:20.79,0:14:24.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,昨天晚上喝酒喝到一半从客厅里跑出来
Dialogue: 0,0:14:24.36,0:14:28.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把土屋太太抱到这里设计了这一切的手法的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:29.96,0:14:31.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,濑户隆一先生
Dialogue: 0,0:14:33.58,0:14:36.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,濑户 难道说…
Dialogue: 0,0:14:37.30,0:14:38.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是你
Dialogue: 0,0:14:39.04,0:14:42.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你等一下 昨天晚上离开客厅的人又不只是我
Dialogue: 0,0:14:43.44,0:14:45.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且你这位名侦探当时也在现场
Dialogue: 0,0:14:45.96,0:14:48.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我怎么可能做出这么大胆的事情来
Dialogue: 0,0:14:48.68,0:14:50.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你就算是这样也掩饰不了的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:51.40,0:14:56.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其实设计让土屋太太将风水号打破的 也是你吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:57.14,0:14:59.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你在风水号的下面先夹进了一个弹珠让他倾斜
Dialogue: 0,0:15:00.20,0:15:01.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样它就很容易掉下来
Dialogue: 0,0:15:02.20,0:15:05.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么做也是为了让这件谋杀罪行
Dialogue: 0,0:15:05.45,0:15:07.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看起来像是被害人因为受不了自责才自杀的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:08.13,0:15:09.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:15:09.84,0:15:12.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果说一切作品的交易都是土屋太太负责的话
Dialogue: 0,0:15:12.97,0:15:16.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,能从仓库里面收放作品的应该也只有她才对
Dialogue: 0,0:15:16.65,0:15:19.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样风水号迟早都有掉下来的一天
Dialogue: 0,0:15:19.74,0:15:24.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且昨天晚上土屋太太又为了庆祝喝了个酩酊大醉
Dialogue: 0,0:15:24.38,0:15:26.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以说昨天晚上就是最好的机会
Dialogue: 0,0:15:26.91,0:15:29.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你不要乱说好不好 你根本没有任何证据
Dialogue: 0,0:15:29.82,0:15:31.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么能说我是凶手呢
Dialogue: 0,0:15:32.08,0:15:35.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你要的证据现在不就正好在你自己的身上吗
Dialogue: 0,0:15:36.60,0:15:41.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那警部大人 现在请你把他上衣的背后翻出来看看
Dialogue: 0,0:15:47.86,0:15:48.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是…
Dialogue: 0,0:15:49.44,0:15:50.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是口红
Dialogue: 0,0:15:51.10,0:15:53.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想这恐怕是土屋太太
Dialogue: 0,0:15:53.43,0:15:55.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在被移动到架子上面的时候被沾到的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:56.47,0:16:00.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为不背到肩上他就根本没有办法爬梯子
Dialogue: 0,0:16:00.70,0:16:03.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接着你又装着什么事都没有发生的的样子
Dialogue: 0,0:16:03.57,0:16:06.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,回到客厅继续跟大家喝酒
Dialogue: 0,0:16:06.58,0:16:08.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你那个时候之所以离开客厅
Dialogue: 0,0:16:08.80,0:16:12.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是为了在土屋太太酒醒之前把她移动到仓库里面
Dialogue: 0,0:16:14.55,0:16:17.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大家还可以仔细看看客厅里面的座椅
Dialogue: 0,0:16:17.41,0:16:21.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想昨天晚上他因为流汗应该会沾上一点口红才对
Dialogue: 0,0:16:22.92,0:16:24.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你不要开玩笑了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:24.74,0:16:27.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个也许真的是土屋太太的口红没错
Dialogue: 0,0:16:27.82,0:16:31.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是这也可能是土屋太太在我们昨天喝酒的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:16:32.00,0:16:35.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为睡着的关系不小心碰到我的背后粘上去的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:36.46,0:16:39.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,昨天我喝的很醉 事情都记不太清楚了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:39.60,0:16:42.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道你能说口红不是这样沾上去的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:16:44.00,0:16:45.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你这么说就没有办法了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:45.65,0:16:47.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我就让你看看最后一项证物
Dialogue: 0,0:16:47.69,0:16:50.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南 把你刚才找到的东西拿出来
Dialogue: 0,0:16:52.31,0:16:53.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:16:54.26,0:16:55.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这个吧 叔叔
Dialogue: 0,0:16:55.91,0:16:57.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南 很危险啦
Dialogue: 0,0:17:06.74,0:17:07.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这…这个是
Dialogue: 0,0:17:08.60,0:17:09.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,手机
Dialogue: 0,0:17:11.53,0:17:13.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,手机怎么会在这个水壶里面呢
Dialogue: 0,0:17:14.32,0:17:17.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,凶手为的就是要实行这项计划
Dialogue: 0,0:17:18.96,0:17:21.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就算土屋太太真的睡在这个狭窄的架子上
Dialogue: 0,0:17:21.95,0:17:24.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过也不能保证她醒来之后会失去平衡
Dialogue: 0,0:17:24.81,0:17:28.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是如果枕头旁边的电话铃声响了就不一样了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:29.11,0:17:32.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在这种情况之下 大部分的人都会把手伸出去
Dialogue: 0,0:17:32.49,0:17:34.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,更何况土屋太太平常用手机来代替闹钟
Dialogue: 0,0:17:34.79,0:17:37.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这就更不用说了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:38.20,0:17:42.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 就是濑户先生把手机
Dialogue: 0,0:17:42.39,0:17:44.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,放在头部下方的架子上的水壶里面的
Dialogue: 0,0:17:46.33,0:17:49.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而这个水壶下面它具有双层底部的设计
Dialogue: 0,0:17:50.00,0:17:53.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只要时间一到他打过来就行了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:55.49,0:17:57.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们只要确认那个手机的号码
Dialogue: 0,0:17:58.00,0:17:59.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一切就真相大白了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:00.71,0:18:02.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那其实是濑户先生打的电话
Dialogue: 0,0:18:11.43,0:18:12.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请你告诉我 侦探先生
Dialogue: 0,0:18:13.84,0:18:15.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你怎么会知道是我的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:18:18.30,0:18:20.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天早上的确是我打的电话没错
Dialogue: 0,0:18:21.00,0:18:23.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是那个时候大谷离开屋子应该也打过
Dialogue: 0,0:18:23.91,0:18:25.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说的没错
Dialogue: 0,0:18:25.70,0:18:28.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在我听到柯南说他发现放在水壶里面的电话之后
Dialogue: 0,0:18:28.52,0:18:29.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也是这么想的
Dialogue: 0,0:18:29.86,0:18:30.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那又是为什么呢
Dialogue: 0,0:18:30.95,0:18:35.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是你在打电话的时候好像这么说过吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:36.07,0:18:38.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是怪了 没人接
Dialogue: 0,0:18:39.08,0:18:43.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是我们发现土屋太太的那个手机
Dialogue: 0,0:18:43.17,0:18:44.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,根本就没有电了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:45.73,0:18:48.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个手机当时里面已经没有电了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:49.00,0:18:52.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这种时候手机一定会传出
Dialogue: 0,0:18:52.17,0:18:53.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,电话已经没有电了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:53.90,0:18:58.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,或者是目前这电话无法接通的声音
Dialogue: 0,0:19:00.21,0:19:03.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,想到这点的时候我才真正的确定是你
Dialogue: 0,0:19:04.19,0:19:08.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想你在那个时候一定是打电话到别的地方去了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:09.15,0:19:14.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗 我那个时候要是说没有接通的话就好了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:15.03,0:19:18.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我还是不相信你会为了杀害土屋太太
Dialogue: 0,0:19:18.50,0:19:21.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,竟然不惜毁掉老师的心血结晶风水号
Dialogue: 0,0:19:22.07,0:19:25.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那种东西就算是在我面前摔得粉碎也没有什么
Dialogue: 0,0:19:27.16,0:19:30.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为那个其实是我模仿老师的风水号
Dialogue: 0,0:19:30.41,0:19:33.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,自己作出来的一个赝品而已
Dialogue: 0,0:19:34.08,0:19:34.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是赝品
Dialogue: 0,0:19:35.43,0:19:39.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 真品早就被我放在别的地方保管了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:44.73,0:19:47.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有想到看到它在自己眼前摔坏
Dialogue: 0,0:19:47.99,0:19:50.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,竟然连土屋太太都被骗过去了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:50.82,0:19:52.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看来我的手艺也不错嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:19:54.38,0:19:55.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就因为这样
Dialogue: 0,0:19:55.48,0:19:58.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,土屋太太才能把我做的作品卖了那么高的价钱
Dialogue: 0,0:19:59.18,0:20:00.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是什么意思
Dialogue: 0,0:20:01.12,0:20:01.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道说…
Dialogue: 0,0:20:02.97,0:20:05.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错 土屋太太把我做的作品
Dialogue: 0,0:20:06.13,0:20:08.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,当成老师做的到处骗人用高价出售
Dialogue: 0,0:20:09.36,0:20:12.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,卖的对象都是那些没有眼光的愚蠢暴发户
Dialogue: 0,0:20:12.06,0:20:13.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:20:14.30,0:20:16.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我发现的时候她已经卖了好几十个了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:17.43,0:20:21.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我当时就找土屋太太问过 但是她居然连道歉都不肯
Dialogue: 0,0:20:22.33,0:20:25.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我倒认为你还应该要感谢我呢
Dialogue: 0,0:20:25.53,0:20:27.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你的东西虽然没创意
Dialogue: 0,0:20:27.62,0:20:31.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过你做的那些东西我可都帮你卖出去了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:37.40,0:20:40.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那难道濑户你最近一直都没什么作品啊
Dialogue: 0,0:20:41.35,0:20:42.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是我故意的
Dialogue: 0,0:20:43.01,0:20:47.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为我不想继续这样对老师的名声造成任何伤害
Dialogue: 0,0:20:47.68,0:20:50.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是土屋太太却对我说我不做的话她就要把我给赶出去
Dialogue: 0,0:20:51.07,0:20:53.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以我不得已只好这么做
Dialogue: 0,0:20:53.90,0:20:55.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你这个笨蛋
Dialogue: 0,0:21:09.78,0:21:12.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喂 你为什么不把这件事告诉老师呢
Dialogue: 0,0:21:13.78,0:21:14.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果你说的话
Dialogue: 0,0:21:14.52,0:21:16.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我怎么能说得出口
Dialogue: 0,0:21:16.48,0:21:18.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我怎么能说我的那些赝品
Dialogue: 0,0:21:19.05,0:21:22.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在外面卖的价钱要比老师的高了很多
Dialogue: 0,0:21:27.43,0:21:28.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们走吧
Dialogue: 0,0:23:12.64,0:23:14.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个茶杯的市价就要一千多万啊
Dialogue: 0,0:23:17.98,0:23:19.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我怎么都看不出来呢
Dialogue: 0,0:23:20.12,0:23:22.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很多东西是不能够用外表判断的
Dialogue: 0,0:23:23.16,0:23:24.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好烫
Dialogue: 0,0:23:30.47,0:23:31.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,绑了线啦
Dialogue: 0,0:23:37.56,0:23:39.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我看我这个大叔啊
Dialogue: 0,0:23:39.37,0:23:41.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,外表跟骨子里根本也没有两样
Dialogue: 0,0:23:44.31,0:23:45.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,初…初恋
Dialogue: 0,0:23:47.29,0:23:48.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,糟了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:49.37,0:23:52.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,麻美学姐是新一的初恋情人
Dialogue: 0,0:23:54.40,0:23:55.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,别墅失火了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:57.24,0:23:58.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会
Dialogue: 0,0:23:58.45,0:23:58.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是那里…
Dialogue: 0,0:23:59.48,0:24:02.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,现在那里还有…麻美学姐
Dialogue: 0,0:24:06.63,0:24:07.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,学姐
Dialogue: 0,0:24:08.68,0:24:09.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,NEXT CONAN
Dialogue: 0,0:24:10.02,0:24:13.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,初恋情人回忆事件 (前篇)
Dialogue: 0,0:24:14.73,0:24:16.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,Next Conan's HINT
Dialogue: 0,0:24:17.30,0:24:18.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柠檬批
Dialogue: 0,0:24:19.35,0:24:21.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下集的初恋是什么味道呢
Dialogue: 0,0:24:21.25,0:24:22.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,当然是鳗鱼饭的味道
