[Script Info]
Title:苍之涛
Original Script:苍之涛
Synch Point:0
ScriptType:v4.00+
Collisions:Normal
PlayResX: 640
PlayResY: 480
Timer:100.0000

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,文鼎新艺体简,24,&H00FFFFFF,&HF0000000,&H00000000,&H70000000,0,0,0,0,100,100,0,0.00,1,2,2.5,2,0,0,15,134

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Actor, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text
Dialogue: 0,0:00:01.30,0:00:02.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,《名侦探柯南》不久就要满10岁了
Dialogue: 0,0:00:03.10,0:00:04.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,百尺竿头更进一步
Dialogue: 0,0:00:05.09,0:00:06.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,难道是相遇之神的恶作剧
Dialogue: 0,0:00:06.30,0:00:08.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,仿照八岐大蛇
Dialogue: 0,0:00:08.00,0:00:09.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,柯南挑战事件之谜
Dialogue: 0,0:00:09.80,0:00:11.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看清唯一真相的是
Dialogue: 0,0:00:11.30,0:00:13.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,外表看似小孩 头脑却是大人
Dialogue: 0,0:00:13.10,0:00:15.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他的名字就是 名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:02:00.70,0:02:02.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,0:02:02.00,0:02:06.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,游览名胜古迹 再狠狠地喝个痛快
Dialogue: 0,0:02:08.90,0:02:11.19,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在飞机上还紧张得要死呢
Dialogue: 0,0:02:15.10,0:02:17.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这次我们来到的是
Dialogue: 0,0:02:17.50,0:02:19.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,神话的故乡
Dialogue: 0,0:02:19.69,0:02:20.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,出云
Dialogue: 0,0:02:22.60,0:02:28.19,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,八岐大蛇之剑（前篇）
Dialogue: 0,0:02:29.10,0:02:31.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,出云大社里供着的是掌管姻缘的神
Dialogue: 0,0:02:32.40,0:02:35.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,兰这样真诚地祈求是能理解啦
Dialogue: 0,0:02:35.30,0:02:38.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,无论如何请赐段良缘
Dialogue: 0,0:02:38.80,0:02:41.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真是的 还在期待什么缘份啊
Dialogue: 0,0:02:43.00,0:02:44.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就挂在这里吧
Dialogue: 0,0:02:44.20,0:02:46.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这里还真挂了不少啊
Dialogue: 0,0:02:46.40,0:02:48.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,良缘 良缘
Dialogue: 0,0:02:51.30,0:02:54.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是日本第一的大稻草绳呢
Dialogue: 0,0:02:51.30,0:02:54.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\fn黑体}{\fs19}{\pos(317,30)}（注：稻草绳为挂在神殿前表示禁止入内，或新年挂在门前表示吉利用的）
Dialogue: 0,0:02:54.20,0:02:56.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的是 好大啊
Dialogue: 0,0:02:56.60,0:02:59.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真是了不起啊
Dialogue: 0,0:02:59.00,0:03:00.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大叔 有5吨哦
Dialogue: 0,0:03:00.80,0:03:03.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,5吨啊
Dialogue: 0,0:03:04.40,0:03:08.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,您是毛利小五郎先生吧 那位名侦探
Dialogue: 0,0:03:10.00,0:03:13.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,您本人比电视上看起来还要英俊呢
Dialogue: 0,0:03:17.00,0:03:19.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,您是这里的工作人员吗
Dialogue: 0,0:03:19.40,0:03:21.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我叫做江角荣子
Dialogue: 0,0:03:21.40,0:03:23.45,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我家三代都是经营旅馆的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:24.30,0:03:25.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,经营旅馆啊
Dialogue: 0,0:03:26.00,0:03:27.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是他的女儿 小兰
Dialogue: 0,0:03:27.50,0:03:29.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他是柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:03:29.70,0:03:30.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,您好
Dialogue: 0,0:03:31.10,0:03:35.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大姐姐 请问那个钱是作什么用的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:35.20,0:03:38.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的呢 上面扎着好多钱啊
Dialogue: 0,0:03:38.50,0:03:40.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有这样一个传说
Dialogue: 0,0:03:40.50,0:03:42.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,能好好扎上的话愿望就会实现
Dialogue: 0,0:03:42.90,0:03:46.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这么说也能赐予良缘了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:47.70,0:03:50.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好 看我的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:53.40,0:03:54.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可恶
Dialogue: 0,0:03:55.40,0:03:56.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看我的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:56.60,0:03:58.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:03:59.30,0:04:00.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,再来
Dialogue: 0,0:04:01.40,0:04:02.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可恶
Dialogue: 0,0:04:03.60,0:04:06.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一辈子都不可能实现了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:04:06.40,0:04:08.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但真是很羡慕呢
Dialogue: 0,0:04:08.40,0:04:11.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,掌管姻缘的神就在你们这里
Dialogue: 0,0:04:11.20,0:04:15.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我姑且算有吧 有门亲事
Dialogue: 0,0:04:15.50,0:04:17.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,姑且
Dialogue: 0,0:04:19.10,0:04:21.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是不喜欢对方吗
Dialogue: 0,0:04:22.00,0:04:22.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:22.80,0:04:25.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个男的没什么钱吧
Dialogue: 0,0:04:25.30,0:04:27.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想他是有钱的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:27.10,0:04:29.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因为他生意做得很大
Dialogue: 0,0:04:29.60,0:04:31.89,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那就是脾气不好
Dialogue: 0,0:04:32.70,0:04:36.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,脾气不好却很有钱是最差劲的类型了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:36.70,0:04:39.39,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,您还是不要和他成婚为好
Dialogue: 0,0:04:40.20,0:04:41.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:04:41.80,0:04:44.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但有拒绝不了的内情
Dialogue: 0,0:04:44.70,0:04:48.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,结婚嘛 要和真正喜欢的人一起才行啊
Dialogue: 0,0:04:48.70,0:04:51.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个人叫什么名字
Dialogue: 0,0:04:51.50,0:04:53.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,鳄渊耕司
Dialogue: 0,0:04:53.89,0:04:59.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因为有内情而和不喜欢的那位鳄渊先生勉强结婚
Dialogue: 0,0:04:59.70,0:05:01.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不就成为牺牲品了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:01.70,0:05:03.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:05:03.20,0:05:05.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思 我爸爸他…
Dialogue: 0,0:05:05.10,0:05:09.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没有 毛利先生为我着想才这么说的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:10.39,0:05:11.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:05:12.20,0:05:14.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要不要去看好玩的模型
Dialogue: 0,0:05:15.00,0:05:16.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好玩的模型
Dialogue: 0,0:05:17.00,0:05:20.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,出云大社以前是这个样子的啊
Dialogue: 0,0:05:20.30,0:05:22.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这才正是
Dialogue: 0,0:05:22.00,0:05:23.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,神话的世界
Dialogue: 0,0:05:23.89,0:05:26.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像曾是日本最大的神殿呢
Dialogue: 0,0:05:27.20,0:05:28.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,详细的内容
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.20,0:05:32.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是从平安后期到镰仓时期的神殿
Dialogue: 0,0:05:32.80,0:05:33.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小良
Dialogue: 0,0:05:34.90,0:05:36.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思 稍等一下
Dialogue: 0,0:05:39.10,0:05:41.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,福间良介 是我的青梅竹马
Dialogue: 0,0:05:41.90,0:05:44.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他从小就喜欢古代历史
Dialogue: 0,0:05:45.00,0:05:48.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,很幸福吧 把这个作为工作
Dialogue: 0,0:05:50.10,0:05:53.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,荣子小姐其实是喜欢那个福间先生吧
Dialogue: 0,0:05:53.10,0:05:54.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,最重要的仪式…
Dialogue: 0,0:05:54.10,0:05:55.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,福间先生说不定也…
Dialogue: 0,0:05:55.10,0:06:00.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,…刺向胸口 而且在河边的柱子有三处…
Dialogue: 0,0:05:58.50,0:06:00.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个臭小子
Dialogue: 0,0:06:01.20,0:06:04.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,…三根柱子和三棵大树捆在一起 一根…
Dialogue: 0,0:06:05.70,0:06:08.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就是因为你没有好好地抓紧她
Dialogue: 0,0:06:08.40,0:06:09.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,才会让那个脾气不好
Dialogue: 0,0:06:09.30,0:06:12.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,却很有钱的人纠缠着荣子小姐吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:12.50,0:06:13.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:06:13.80,0:06:14.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生
Dialogue: 0,0:06:15.10,0:06:16.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:06:16.40,0:06:18.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真是对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:06:19.10,0:06:20.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没有 没关系啦
Dialogue: 0,0:06:21.30,0:06:24.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生 今天多谢了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:24.00,0:06:26.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,哪里哪里 要好好干哦
Dialogue: 0,0:06:27.10,0:06:29.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,说得倒是一本正经
Dialogue: 0,0:06:29.10,0:06:30.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,到底在想些什么啊
Dialogue: 0,0:06:31.50,0:06:33.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,然而 那之后第二天
Dialogue: 0,0:06:33.30,0:06:34.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,事件发生了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:47.90,0:06:49.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,时价1千万
Dialogue: 0,0:06:49.90,0:06:51.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一定是这么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:06:52.00,0:06:55.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从背后一刀致命啊
Dialogue: 0,0:06:55.70,0:06:57.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,闲杂人等不得进入
Dialogue: 0,0:06:59.00,0:07:00.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,莫非您是…
Dialogue: 0,0:07:00.90,0:07:02.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我姓毛利
Dialogue: 0,0:07:02.60,0:07:04.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在东京经营私人侦探事务所
Dialogue: 0,0:07:04.90,0:07:07.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然没错 久仰大名
Dialogue: 0,0:07:07.80,0:07:09.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是出云警署的山根
Dialogue: 0,0:07:09.70,0:07:11.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是同一组的小村
Dialogue: 0,0:07:11.20,0:07:13.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个 您怎么找到这儿来的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:13.30,0:07:15.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我只是碰巧来到这里
Dialogue: 0,0:07:16.10,0:07:21.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但这起案件好像无需借助名侦探的力量了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:21.90,0:07:23.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,此话怎讲
Dialogue: 0,0:07:23.70,0:07:26.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,被害者是以出云为中心
Dialogue: 0,0:07:26.40,0:07:30.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,开展大型生意的鳄渊创业的经营者
Dialogue: 0,0:07:30.60,0:07:32.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,鳄渊耕司先生 35岁
Dialogue: 0,0:07:32.90,0:07:34.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,鳄渊耕司
Dialogue: 0,0:07:35.60,0:07:38.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是昨天荣子小姐提到的那个结婚对象
Dialogue: 0,0:07:38.50,0:07:40.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个人被杀害了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:41.00,0:07:42.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你们认识啊
Dialogue: 0,0:07:42.70,0:07:46.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他是本地首屈一指的实业家
Dialogue: 0,0:07:46.60,0:07:49.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那对夫妇是第一发现者
Dialogue: 0,0:07:49.20,0:07:50.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也是本地人
Dialogue: 0,0:07:51.40,0:07:55.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看来这不是个会有观光者来的地方呢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:55.30,0:07:58.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,死亡推测时间为下午1点左右
Dialogue: 0,0:07:58.40,0:07:59.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们认为鳄渊先生的手表
Dialogue: 0,0:07:59.80,0:08:02.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是在他倒下时摔坏的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:02.10,0:08:04.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,手表停在1点05分
Dialogue: 0,0:08:04.50,0:08:07.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果把这看作遇害时间应该不会有错
Dialogue: 0,0:08:08.00,0:08:10.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,杀人动机是出于怨恨吗
Dialogue: 0,0:08:10.70,0:08:14.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,首屈一指的实业家会有很多的敌人
Dialogue: 0,0:08:14.50,0:08:17.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,加上他似乎脾气又不好
Dialogue: 0,0:08:17.60,0:08:20.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,虽说他的确是没什么好评的人
Dialogue: 0,0:08:20.70,0:08:24.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但犯人的目标是夺刀哦
Dialogue: 0,0:08:24.30,0:08:25.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,时价1千万
Dialogue: 0,0:08:26.00,0:08:28.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,时价1千万的刀
Dialogue: 0,0:08:29.90,0:08:31.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是鳄渊先生的记事本
Dialogue: 0,0:08:32.90,0:08:34.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天上午
Dialogue: 0,0:08:34.10,0:08:39.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,市内的古董店寄存了一把刀给他作为借钱的担保
Dialogue: 0,0:08:39.79,0:08:41.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,经店里的人确认
Dialogue: 0,0:08:41.20,0:08:44.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他们照约定在12点左右把刀交给了他
Dialogue: 0,0:08:44.90,0:08:50.29,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,收到刀后 鳄渊先生走到了猪目这里
Dialogue: 0,0:08:50.50,0:08:52.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,虽然不知道是什么原因
Dialogue: 0,0:08:52.40,0:08:53.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,下午1点前
Dialogue: 0,0:08:53.70,0:08:57.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有人目击到他曾拿着刀站在这里
Dialogue: 0,0:08:57.40,0:08:59.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但在发现尸体之后
Dialogue: 0,0:08:59.70,0:09:01.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就再也找不到那把刀了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:02.00,0:09:02.79,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说
Dialogue: 0,0:09:02.79,0:09:06.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,犯人看见他在古董店拿到了刀
Dialogue: 0,0:09:06.00,0:09:08.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,尾随在他的身后
Dialogue: 0,0:09:15.29,0:09:17.29,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就是这样一起
Dialogue: 0,0:09:17.29,0:09:20.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,目的为夺宝的单纯的抢劫杀人案件
Dialogue: 0,0:09:20.60,0:09:23.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以你们才说 不用名侦探出手啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:24.10,0:09:25.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我终于明白了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:28.10,0:09:31.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的是那么简单的案件吗
Dialogue: 0,0:09:31.70,0:09:33.79,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那为什么特地到这样的地方来呢
Dialogue: 0,0:09:34.10,0:09:37.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,而且还拿着1千万元的刀
Dialogue: 0,0:09:38.20,0:09:40.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你在想什么啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:40.20,0:09:42.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我什么都没想啦
Dialogue: 0,0:09:43.00,0:09:46.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,虽说鳄渊先生被害身亡不是什么好事
Dialogue: 0,0:09:46.29,0:09:47.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但这么一来
Dialogue: 0,0:09:47.50,0:09:50.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,荣子小姐也不用勉强结婚了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:50.40,0:09:51.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,兰
Dialogue: 0,0:09:51.00,0:09:52.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我知道啦
Dialogue: 0,0:09:52.40,0:09:54.29,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这样说并不好
Dialogue: 0,0:09:54.29,0:09:57.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不过你昨天也不是说过吗
Dialogue: 0,0:09:57.00,0:09:59.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这样简直就是当牺牲品嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:10:00.00,0:10:01.79,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个
Dialogue: 0,0:10:02.70,0:10:06.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这起案件有点像八岐大蛇呢
Dialogue: 0,0:10:06.29,0:10:08.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,八岐大蛇
Dialogue: 0,0:10:04.10,0:10:08.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\fn黑体}{\pos(315,30)}（八岐大蛇：神话中曾出现在出云的大蛇，八头八尾）
Dialogue: 0,0:10:08.60,0:10:11.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是神话啦 那个须佐之男
Dialogue: 0,0:10:11.29,0:10:14.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,说是有位可怜的姑娘被八岐大蛇选中
Dialogue: 0,0:10:14.10,0:10:16.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,当他的新娘
Dialogue: 0,0:10:16.40,0:10:18.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,多亏出现在那里的须佐之男
Dialogue: 0,0:10:18.90,0:10:21.29,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,消灭了八岐大蛇
Dialogue: 0,0:10:21.29,0:10:23.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这位姑娘才得救了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:23.79,0:10:27.29,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,连从大蛇那里得到了剑这一点都很相似
Dialogue: 0,0:10:28.40,0:10:29.29,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是吧
Dialogue: 0,0:10:30.50,0:10:33.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,须佐之男可能还算是位英雄
Dialogue: 0,0:10:33.40,0:10:35.29,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但这次的犯人铁定不是
Dialogue: 0,0:10:35.70,0:10:39.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他只是碰巧救了荣子小姐而已
Dialogue: 0,0:10:39.70,0:10:42.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那家伙可是抢劫杀人犯啊
Dialogue: 0,0:10:42.50,0:10:45.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这我当然知道啦
Dialogue: 0,0:10:45.00,0:10:49.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我只是说有点像八岐大蛇的神话而已嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:10:49.00,0:10:50.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是吧 柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:10:52.90,0:10:54.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但这起案件
Dialogue: 0,0:10:54.20,0:10:57.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然不是单纯的抢劫杀人案
Dialogue: 0,0:11:03.20,0:11:08.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,每年一回全日本的神灵在出云汇聚
Dialogue: 0,0:11:08.90,0:11:11.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就是在这个稻佐海滨登陆呢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:13.00,0:11:14.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没在听啊
Dialogue: 0,0:11:14.70,0:11:16.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我在解释给你们听呢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:17.20,0:11:18.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是不是出什么事了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:27.30,0:11:28.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个难道是
Dialogue: 0,0:11:30.00,0:11:31.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,向古董店确认了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:31.70,0:11:34.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就是那把刀没错
Dialogue: 0,0:11:34.50,0:11:35.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然是呢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:35.90,0:11:36.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,搞不懂呀
Dialogue: 0,0:11:36.90,0:11:41.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好不容易得手的宝物怎么会藏在沙里呢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:41.30,0:11:42.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是扔掉的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:42.60,0:11:45.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,反正也没什么用了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:45.80,0:11:48.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,之所以把它从现场拿走
Dialogue: 0,0:11:48.00,0:11:50.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是为了掩人耳目吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:50.30,0:11:53.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让人觉得是以抢劫为目的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:53.50,0:11:54.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也许吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:54.90,0:11:57.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说 犯人真正的目的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:57.30,0:11:59.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是取鳄渊先生的性命
Dialogue: 0,0:11:59.80,0:12:03.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也许真正的动机是出于怨恨
Dialogue: 0,0:12:03.30,0:12:05.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快点列表调查
Dialogue: 0,0:12:05.20,0:12:06.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不仅是生意上有关系的人
Dialogue: 0,0:12:06.90,0:12:11.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还有在私人问题上与鳄渊先生有过节的人
Dialogue: 0,0:12:11.30,0:12:11.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,0:12:13.30,0:12:14.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:15.10,0:12:15.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没什么
Dialogue: 0,0:12:19.70,0:12:21.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,列表调查后
Dialogue: 0,0:12:21.00,0:12:23.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,第二天被叫到警署的有4人
Dialogue: 0,0:12:26.00,0:12:29.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,荣子小姐和福间先生也在其中
Dialogue: 0,0:12:35.10,0:12:37.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那么就按顺序询问吧
Dialogue: 0,0:12:37.80,0:12:39.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在此之前
Dialogue: 0,0:12:39.00,0:12:42.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,先介绍一下来协助调查的这位
Dialogue: 0,0:12:43.10,0:12:45.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,毛利小五郎侦探
Dialogue: 0,0:12:45.70,0:12:47.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是毛利
Dialogue: 0,0:12:48.20,0:12:50.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那 那个名侦探
Dialogue: 0,0:12:52.20,0:12:53.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没什么
Dialogue: 0,0:12:53.00,0:12:57.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没想到那个名侦探会到出云来
Dialogue: 0,0:12:58.50,0:13:01.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那先从石飞一也先生开始
Dialogue: 0,0:13:01.30,0:13:02.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:13:02.50,0:13:04.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从我们的调查来看
Dialogue: 0,0:13:04.50,0:13:07.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,经营着出云面馆石飞店的你
Dialogue: 0,0:13:07.00,0:13:12.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,受到过鳄渊先生想要联营的邀请是吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:12.10,0:13:14.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这算什么联营啊
Dialogue: 0,0:13:14.70,0:13:19.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,运转资金全部由鳄渊创业来准备
Dialogue: 0,0:13:19.20,0:13:23.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只要改了石飞这个名字就能在全国开分店
Dialogue: 0,0:13:23.40,0:13:25.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这等美事
Dialogue: 0,0:13:26.20,0:13:27.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然
Dialogue: 0,0:13:27.50,0:13:29.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你应该不会拒绝吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:31.30,0:13:33.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那家伙就是想投资收并
Dialogue: 0,0:13:33.40,0:13:36.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,已经有200年历史的石飞
Dialogue: 0,0:13:36.60,0:13:37.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:13:38.00,0:13:39.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那下一位
Dialogue: 0,0:13:39.30,0:13:40.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,藤江竹彦先生
Dialogue: 0,0:13:40.80,0:13:44.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是在经营结婚会场吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:44.30,0:13:47.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我和石飞先生的遭遇一样
Dialogue: 0,0:13:47.90,0:13:52.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们鳄渊创业也想加入结婚会场的经营
Dialogue: 0,0:13:53.70,0:13:58.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但跟你这家老字号抢生意实在是很无聊
Dialogue: 0,0:13:58.60,0:14:00.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以给你一个建议
Dialogue: 0,0:14:00.30,0:14:02.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,由我们来投资
Dialogue: 0,0:14:02.70,0:14:06.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,然后双方合作经营 你觉得怎么样
Dialogue: 0,0:14:10.80,0:14:12.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,藤江学长
Dialogue: 0,0:14:13.70,0:14:14.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:14:15.30,0:14:17.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他叫你学长啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:17.40,0:14:19.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,鳄渊是我的学弟
Dialogue: 0,0:14:20.00,0:14:22.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们同读于东京的帝都经济大学
Dialogue: 0,0:14:23.30,0:14:24.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是校友啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:24.70,0:14:28.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那家伙名字是鳄 但性格却是蛇
Dialogue: 0,0:14:28.20,0:14:30.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想要的东西无论如何都要夺取的魔鬼
Dialogue: 0,0:14:31.20,0:14:33.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,对 就像是八岐大蛇一样
Dialogue: 0,0:14:35.70,0:14:36.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:14:37.20,0:14:38.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,江角荣子小姐最初也是
Dialogue: 0,0:14:38.40,0:14:42.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在生意上认识鳄渊先生的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:42.00,0:14:42.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:14:42.90,0:14:45.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我家经营的旅馆“日出屋”也是老字号
Dialogue: 0,0:14:45.50,0:14:48.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,旅馆的建筑老化程度日趋明显
Dialogue: 0,0:14:48.90,0:14:51.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但又没有资金进行改建
Dialogue: 0,0:14:51.40,0:14:53.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那时 东京的同行跟我们说
Dialogue: 0,0:14:53.70,0:14:55.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想在这里建造现代化的酒店
Dialogue: 0,0:14:55.90,0:14:58.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让我们把这块地卖给他
Dialogue: 0,0:14:58.60,0:15:00.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也许我们只有把旅馆转让了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:00.90,0:15:02.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就在我父母亲准备放弃它的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:15:03.60,0:15:06.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要让这家有悠久历史的日出屋倒闭简直荒唐
Dialogue: 0,0:15:06.80,0:15:09.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,改建的事就由我来办吧
Dialogue: 0,0:15:10.30,0:15:11.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为了出云
Dialogue: 0,0:15:12.40,0:15:13.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,出乎意料
Dialogue: 0,0:15:13.90,0:15:17.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因为我听说他是个脑袋里只有贪婪两个字的人
Dialogue: 0,0:15:17.50,0:15:19.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,父母非常感激地接受了他的提议
Dialogue: 0,0:15:19.90,0:15:21.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,对旅馆进行了改建
Dialogue: 0,0:15:22.30,0:15:22.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是
Dialogue: 0,0:15:23.20,0:15:25.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,把女儿嫁给你
Dialogue: 0,0:15:25.60,0:15:27.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么突然说这个
Dialogue: 0,0:15:27.50,0:15:29.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么是突然呢
Dialogue: 0,0:15:29.90,0:15:32.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,正因为是我未来妻子的娘家
Dialogue: 0,0:15:32.20,0:15:34.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我才会借给你们改建用的资金啊
Dialogue: 0,0:15:34.20,0:15:35.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是这样的话谁会借啊
Dialogue: 0,0:15:36.50,0:15:39.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从一开始他就是那个打算
Dialogue: 0,0:15:39.60,0:15:41.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果我拒绝结婚
Dialogue: 0,0:15:41.20,0:15:43.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他就要把援助的钱全要回去
Dialogue: 0,0:15:44.10,0:15:45.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会
Dialogue: 0,0:15:45.80,0:15:48.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我父母说与其让我嫁给那种人
Dialogue: 0,0:15:48.80,0:15:50.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还不如当初把旅馆转让了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:51.40,0:15:53.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但我心里明白
Dialogue: 0,0:15:53.40,0:15:55.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,世世代代经营的那个旅馆
Dialogue: 0,0:15:55.50,0:15:58.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,父母是如何用心来对待的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:58.20,0:15:59.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以
Dialogue: 0,0:15:59.50,0:16:00.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,福间先生
Dialogue: 0,0:16:00.90,0:16:03.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你在江角小姐不知情的情况下
Dialogue: 0,0:16:03.30,0:16:05.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,曾经向鳄渊先生请求过好几次
Dialogue: 0,0:16:05.60,0:16:08.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让他放过江角小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:16:08.70,0:16:09.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我恨他
Dialogue: 0,0:16:10.00,0:16:11.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我恨那个男人
Dialogue: 0,0:16:19.80,0:16:23.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,接下来 鳄渊先生遇害的时间
Dialogue: 0,0:16:23.50,0:16:25.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,昨天下午1点左右
Dialogue: 0,0:16:25.40,0:16:28.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你们各自说明一下当时在哪里干什么吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:29.00,0:16:29.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,首先
Dialogue: 0,0:16:30.40,0:16:32.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我在松江城
Dialogue: 0,0:16:32.90,0:16:34.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,松江城
Dialogue: 0,0:16:34.80,0:16:36.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是独自一人
Dialogue: 0,0:16:36.30,0:16:38.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,并没有证人
Dialogue: 0,0:16:39.40,0:16:42.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我在天守阁的名册上登记过
Dialogue: 0,0:16:44.20,0:16:45.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那福间先生
Dialogue: 0,0:16:46.20,0:16:48.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我因为昨天正好休息
Dialogue: 0,0:16:49.20,0:16:51.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,去了旧大社车站
Dialogue: 0,0:16:52.90,0:16:55.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从上午一直到下午3点左右
Dialogue: 0,0:16:55.90,0:16:58.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我经常去那里 因为能静得下心来
Dialogue: 0,0:16:58.50,0:17:00.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但我也是一个人去的
Dialogue: 0,0:17:00.80,0:17:02.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以没有证人
Dialogue: 0,0:17:02.50,0:17:04.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那石飞先生
Dialogue: 0,0:17:04.58,0:17:07.58,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我在出云民间文化展览馆里
Dialogue: 0,0:17:08.80,0:17:11.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我也是一个人
Dialogue: 0,0:17:12.08,0:17:14.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,最后 江角小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:17:14.58,0:17:17.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我去了日御崎
Dialogue: 0,0:17:18.50,0:17:20.58,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也是一个人去的
Dialogue: 0,0:17:21.30,0:17:23.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没到海猫出现的季节
Dialogue: 0,0:17:24.20,0:17:26.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以还见不到
Dialogue: 0,0:17:26.90,0:17:28.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小村 分别去确认一下
Dialogue: 0,0:17:28.90,0:17:29.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:17:33.40,0:17:35.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,全部都是观光胜地
Dialogue: 0,0:17:35.20,0:17:37.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一定会有很多人见过他们吧
Dialogue: 0,0:17:37.58,0:17:40.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果说的全是真话的话
Dialogue: 0,0:17:40.80,0:17:42.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没错
Dialogue: 0,0:17:46.00,0:17:46.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么样
Dialogue: 0,0:17:47.20,0:17:50.58,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是 藤江先生的已经确认了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:51.00,0:17:52.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是藤江先生的笔迹
Dialogue: 0,0:17:52.70,0:17:54.58,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看了前后的记录
Dialogue: 0,0:17:54.58,0:17:57.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,1点05分时他确实是在那里没错
Dialogue: 0,0:17:58.50,0:17:59.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,1点05分
Dialogue: 0,0:18:00.08,0:18:02.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就是被害人被杀的时刻
Dialogue: 0,0:18:03.00,0:18:05.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在册子上记录了他的名字啊
Dialogue: 0,0:18:05.90,0:18:09.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从松江城到案发现场猪目
Dialogue: 0,0:18:10.50,0:18:12.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,开车要40分钟到1小时
Dialogue: 0,0:18:12.70,0:18:13.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:18:14.08,0:18:16.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我的嫌疑消除了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:17.58,0:18:20.58,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,问题是剩下的3位
Dialogue: 0,0:18:20.58,0:18:23.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像都没有目击者
Dialogue: 0,0:18:23.90,0:18:25.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一个都没有
Dialogue: 0,0:18:25.30,0:18:27.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,都没有 3位都没有
Dialogue: 0,0:18:27.80,0:18:30.58,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,虽说无法确认不在场证明
Dialogue: 0,0:18:30.58,0:18:32.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但我也不能就此拘留你们
Dialogue: 0,0:18:32.90,0:18:36.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们会重新对你们进行询问
Dialogue: 0,0:18:36.40,0:18:38.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请大家暂时先回去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:38.80,0:18:40.08,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,辛苦了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:43.50,0:18:47.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,荣子小姐和福间先生不是犯人对吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:48.80,0:18:51.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但为什么一个目击者都没有呢
Dialogue: 0,0:18:52.20,0:18:54.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只能说明他们在说谎吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:58.30,0:18:59.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,喂 我是山根
Dialogue: 0,0:19:02.80,0:19:03.58,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:19:04.30,0:19:05.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是吗 明白了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:06.70,0:19:08.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快点叫他过来
Dialogue: 0,0:19:08.00,0:19:09.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,福间良介
Dialogue: 0,0:19:09.30,0:19:10.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:19:11.20,0:19:13.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们找到的一位目击者说
Dialogue: 0,0:19:13.58,0:19:18.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,昨天下午2点后看到有人在稻佐海滨埋东西
Dialogue: 0,0:19:18.40,0:19:21.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,据说是位瘦高个的男子
Dialogue: 0,0:19:25.20,0:19:26.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们从你的鞋子上查出了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:26.50,0:19:30.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,稻佐海滨的沙和猪目洞窟的土
Dialogue: 0,0:19:30.80,0:19:31.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是你干的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:19:31.80,0:19:34.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你把鳄渊先生给…
Dialogue: 0,0:19:36.30,0:19:37.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不知道
Dialogue: 0,0:19:39.08,0:19:40.80,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,保持沉默
Dialogue: 0,0:19:41.50,0:19:43.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不过说到他的行踪
Dialogue: 0,0:19:43.40,0:19:45.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因为在旧大社车站没有目击证人
Dialogue: 0,0:19:45.70,0:19:47.08,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以得出这样的结论
Dialogue: 0,0:19:47.40,0:19:50.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,事实上他是在猪目那里杀害了鳄渊先生
Dialogue: 0,0:19:50.00,0:19:52.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,再到稻佐海滨处理了那把刀
Dialogue: 0,0:19:53.58,0:19:56.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这样就确定是福间良介了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:56.90,0:19:58.08,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不可能
Dialogue: 0,0:19:58.20,0:20:01.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,的确 附着在鞋子上的沙土
Dialogue: 0,0:20:01.30,0:20:03.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,和看到他的人可以证明
Dialogue: 0,0:20:03.50,0:20:05.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从现场拿走刀
Dialogue: 0,0:20:05.40,0:20:07.58,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,并在那个海滨埋刀的是福间先生
Dialogue: 0,0:20:08.30,0:20:13.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但说杀人的就是福间先生的话
Dialogue: 0,0:20:14.20,0:20:16.58,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我去了日御崎
Dialogue: 0,0:20:17.08,0:20:18.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个反应
Dialogue: 0,0:20:18.90,0:20:20.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,福间先生他知道
Dialogue: 0,0:20:20.70,0:20:23.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那时荣子小姐到底在哪里
Dialogue: 0,0:20:23.80,0:20:24.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说
Dialogue: 0,0:20:27.70,0:20:29.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,臭小子 去哪儿啊
Dialogue: 0,0:20:34.08,0:20:35.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你这小鬼
Dialogue: 0,0:20:35.40,0:20:37.58,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要随便进审讯室
Dialogue: 0,0:20:37.58,0:20:39.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不行哦 柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:20:40.00,0:20:43.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我只是觉得福间先生什么也不说
Dialogue: 0,0:20:43.40,0:20:46.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,说不定是因为要包庇真正的犯人
Dialogue: 0,0:20:48.30,0:20:49.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然没错
Dialogue: 0,0:20:50.50,0:20:52.08,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:20:52.30,0:20:53.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他一定看到了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:53.70,0:20:57.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真正的犯人在猪目洞窟袭击了鳄渊先生
Dialogue: 0,0:20:57.50,0:21:00.58,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是这个真正的犯人是谁呢
Dialogue: 0,0:21:01.40,0:21:04.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你想包庇的犯人应该只有一个吧
Dialogue: 0,0:21:04.70,0:21:08.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你目击了江角荣子小姐的犯罪过程
Dialogue: 0,0:21:08.70,0:21:12.58,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以你拿走了刀想伪装成抢劫的样子
Dialogue: 0,0:21:12.58,0:21:13.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是这样吗
Dialogue: 0,0:21:14.30,0:21:15.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是我
Dialogue: 0,0:21:15.30,0:21:17.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是我杀了鳄渊
Dialogue: 0,0:21:17.40,0:21:19.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,太迟了 到现在才说
Dialogue: 0,0:21:20.70,0:21:21.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我
Dialogue: 0,0:21:22.08,0:21:23.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是我
Dialogue: 0,0:21:23.50,0:21:29.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那在鳄渊先生被害之时你到底在哪里
Dialogue: 0,0:21:29.50,0:21:31.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你说是在日御崎
Dialogue: 0,0:21:31.20,0:21:33.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但没有任何人看到你
Dialogue: 0,0:21:33.70,0:21:36.08,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,灯塔的食品商店与纪念品商店
Dialogue: 0,0:21:36.08,0:21:37.08,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,都没人看到你
Dialogue: 0,0:21:37.08,0:21:38.08,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是因为
Dialogue: 0,0:21:38.70,0:21:40.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只能说她和福间先生一样
Dialogue: 0,0:21:41.20,0:21:43.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在包庇着什么人
Dialogue: 0,0:21:43.58,0:21:46.08,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我因为昨天正好休息
Dialogue: 0,0:21:46.50,0:21:48.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,去了旧大社车站
Dialogue: 0,0:21:49.00,0:21:50.08,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,难道说
Dialogue: 0,0:21:52.60,0:21:54.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你也认为犯人是福间先生
Dialogue: 0,0:21:54.40,0:21:56.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以才故意包庇他的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:22:01.10,0:22:02.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然是这样啊
Dialogue: 0,0:22:06.80,0:22:08.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小兰姐姐 你跟我来
Dialogue: 0,0:22:10.00,0:22:11.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,柯南 怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:22:12.50,0:22:14.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是怎么回事 毛利先生
Dialogue: 0,0:22:15.90,0:22:18.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,相互包庇的一对恋人
Dialogue: 0,0:22:19.90,0:22:22.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,谁才是真正的犯人啊
Dialogue: 0,0:22:22.50,0:22:25.10,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你说有可能他俩都不是犯人
Dialogue: 0,0:22:25.30,0:22:26.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我就是要证明这个
Dialogue: 0,0:22:27.60,0:22:29.00,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要去哪里啊
Dialogue: 0,0:22:31.10,0:22:32.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,旧大社车站
Dialogue: 0,0:24:02.40,0:24:04.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嫌疑犯全是清白的
Dialogue: 0,0:24:05.10,0:24:06.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没错
Dialogue: 0,0:24:07.10,0:24:08.90,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:24:09.20,0:24:12.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从昨天才开始详细记录日程安排的时间
Dialogue: 0,0:24:12.70,0:24:14.20,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我觉得不是那样
Dialogue: 0,0:24:14.60,0:24:16.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,自以为是的误会
Dialogue: 0,0:24:17.00,0:24:19.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是毛利 想见你一面
Dialogue: 0,0:24:19.60,0:24:22.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,至于是什么事等见面再说
Dialogue: 0,0:24:24.30,0:24:25.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,NEXT CONAN
Dialogue: 0,0:24:25.80,0:24:28.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,八岐大蛇之剑（后篇）
Dialogue: 0,0:24:45.60,0:24:47.70,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,NEXT CONAN'S HINT
Dialogue: 0,0:24:47.80,0:24:49.40,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,虚假的证言
Dialogue: 0,0:24:50.00,0:24:51.60,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你求的是和新一哥哥的良缘吧
Dialogue: 0,0:24:51.60,0:24:52.50,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是哦
Dialogue: 0,0:24:52.50,0:24:54.30,*Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是谁 谁啦
