[Script Info]
; This is an Advanced Sub Station Alpha v4+ script.
; For Sub Station Alpha info and downloads,
; go to http://www.eswat.demon.co.uk/
; or email kotus@eswat.demon.co.uk
; 
; Advanced Sub Station Alpha script format developed by #Anime-Fansubs@EfNET
; http://www.anime-fansubs.org
; 
; For additional info and downloads go to http://vobsub.edensrising.com/
; or email gabest@freemail.hu
; 
; Note: This file was saved by Subresync.
; 
ScriptType: v4.00+
Collisions: Normal
PlayResX: 384
PlayResY: 288
Timer: 100.0000

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,文鼎新艺体简,14,&H00ffffff,&H0000ffff,&H00000000,&H80000000,0,0,0,0,100,100,0,0.00,1,1,1,2,20,20,10,1

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Actor, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text

Dialogue: 0,0:00:01.67,0:00:03.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,挡住去路的巨墙
Dialogue: 0,0:00:03.16,0:00:04.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,换个思考的角度就是一扇大门
Dialogue: 0,0:00:04.78,0:00:06.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好帅啊 飞车高手
Dialogue: 0,0:00:06.30,0:00:07.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在华丽的场面背后
Dialogue: 0,0:00:07.83,0:00:09.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,隐藏着不为人知的案件
Dialogue: 0,0:00:09.38,0:00:11.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看清唯一真相的是
Dialogue: 0,0:00:11.04,0:00:12.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,外表看似小孩 头脑却是大人
Dialogue: 0,0:00:12.79,0:00:14.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他的名字就是 名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:02:02.35,0:02:04.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,假面超人
Dialogue: 0,0:02:13.40,0:02:15.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不会让你得逞的
Dialogue: 0,0:02:28.50,0:02:29.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可恶
Dialogue: 0,0:02:44.41,0:02:45.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,TMD
Dialogue: 0,0:03:06.69,0:03:07.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你以为你逃得掉吗
Dialogue: 0,0:03:30.38,0:03:31.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,假 假面超人
Dialogue: 0,0:03:31.94,0:03:33.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,完了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:39.86,0:03:40.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:03:53.37,0:03:58.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,极限的汽车特技
Dialogue: 0,0:04:00.34,0:04:02.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,绝对 绝对不行
Dialogue: 0,0:04:02.85,0:04:05.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个计划绝对不能采用
Dialogue: 0,0:04:05.23,0:04:06.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,太危险了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:06.83,0:04:08.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我也这么认为
Dialogue: 0,0:04:09.02,0:04:10.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你以为是在和谁说话啊
Dialogue: 0,0:04:10.70,0:04:12.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,给我闭嘴
Dialogue: 0,0:04:12.76,0:04:14.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个计划确实危险
Dialogue: 0,0:04:14.97,0:04:16.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,对于其他特技人员来说
Dialogue: 0,0:04:16.55,0:04:18.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是我就没问题
Dialogue: 0,0:04:18.86,0:04:21.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这种特技已经做过好几次了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:21.90,0:04:23.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,对吧 木岛
Dialogue: 0,0:04:25.22,0:04:27.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是啊 但是
Dialogue: 0,0:04:27.70,0:04:30.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,千万别把镜头切断 木岛
Dialogue: 0,0:04:30.61,0:04:31.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你可别蒙我
Dialogue: 0,0:04:31.95,0:04:34.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从这里冲进去到坠楼为止
Dialogue: 0,0:04:34.19,0:04:35.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就用一个镜头拍下来
Dialogue: 0,0:04:35.97,0:04:37.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从下面拍的话
Dialogue: 0,0:04:37.78,0:04:42.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你从车里跳出去应该没问题 但是
Dialogue: 0,0:04:43.37,0:04:46.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,力石先生 现在的你已经…
Dialogue: 0,0:04:46.92,0:04:49.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天真是太感谢了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:47.74,0:04:50.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在这里可以看到假面超人的摩托车
Dialogue: 0,0:04:50.45,0:04:51.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真是太棒了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:51.61,0:04:52.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真不愧是博士
Dialogue: 0,0:04:52.94,0:04:54.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,面子真大啊
Dialogue: 0,0:04:54.61,0:04:56.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,应该是人脉广吧
Dialogue: 0,0:04:56.59,0:05:00.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看 我还拿到了很多假面超人的贴纸呢
Dialogue: 0,0:05:00.02,0:05:02.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不拿的人就太傻了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:02.26,0:05:03.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:03.58,0:05:04.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你想说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:05:04.70,0:05:05.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,已经什么已经
Dialogue: 0,0:05:05.87,0:05:06.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,给我说清楚
Dialogue: 0,0:05:06.82,0:05:08.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了 怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:08.37,0:05:09.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,争执不下啊
Dialogue: 0,0:05:09.22,0:05:10.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,吵架了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:10.10,0:05:11.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是说
Dialogue: 0,0:05:11.40,0:05:12.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,现在的电脑数码特效
Dialogue: 0,0:05:12.55,0:05:16.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可以制作出很多比真实的特技表演效果更好的画面
Dialogue: 0,0:05:16.06,0:05:16.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以
Dialogue: 0,0:05:16.85,0:05:19.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以已经不需要这种落后于时代的特技了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:20.10,0:05:21.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不 也不是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:05:23.02,0:05:24.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怪人的汽车来到了平台上
Dialogue: 0,0:05:25.72,0:05:27.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,换成另一辆车
Dialogue: 0,0:05:27.81,0:05:29.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,假设原来那辆车是A车
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.73,0:05:32.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,另一辆车是遥控车 为B车
Dialogue: 0,0:05:34.25,0:05:38.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,替换原来怪人开的A车 B车冲向了前面
Dialogue: 0,0:05:41.39,0:05:45.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,当然摄像机是从下面拍的 拍不到换车的画面
Dialogue: 0,0:05:45.47,0:05:49.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,然后 用电脑后期处理一下
Dialogue: 0,0:05:51.12,0:05:54.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个场景的特技就足够了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:54.32,0:05:56.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可恶
Dialogue: 0,0:06:06.60,0:06:07.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,方向盘 ok
Dialogue: 0,0:06:08.00,0:06:09.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,刹车 ok
Dialogue: 0,0:06:09.43,0:06:11.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那就这样吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:11.69,0:06:14.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快点决定吧 我准备好了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:14.51,0:06:17.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你都准备好了啊 木岛
Dialogue: 0,0:06:17.63,0:06:20.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看你一副成不了大事的样子
Dialogue: 0,0:06:20.47,0:06:21.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:06:21.67,0:06:22.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要吵了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:22.77,0:06:25.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就按这个计划执行
Dialogue: 0,0:06:25.14,0:06:27.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我已经得到了制片人的同意
Dialogue: 0,0:06:27.56,0:06:29.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,现在开始吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:32.00,0:06:33.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,拜托您了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:35.31,0:06:38.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,听好了 你会后悔的
Dialogue: 0,0:06:38.84,0:06:43.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,假面回旋踢那种唰唰的样子 好帅哦
Dialogue: 0,0:06:39.00,0:06:41.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,放开我
Dialogue: 0,0:06:43.56,0:06:45.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,唰唰的样子啊
Dialogue: 0,0:06:46.37,0:06:49.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,现在开始发放午餐
Dialogue: 0,0:06:49.09,0:06:50.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要进入下一个镜头了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:50.56,0:06:52.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请大家做好准备
Dialogue: 0,0:06:56.42,0:06:58.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,总觉得那个人有点可怕
Dialogue: 0,0:06:58.86,0:07:02.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,反正最后都会被假面超人打倒的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:02.16,0:07:03.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,说得好啊
Dialogue: 0,0:07:04.66,0:07:08.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,喂喂 这只是电视剧里的情节吧
Dialogue: 0,0:07:09.20,0:07:11.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是真无聊啊
Dialogue: 0,0:07:11.20,0:07:14.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好不容易到这里来 却没碰到拍摄
Dialogue: 0,0:07:14.45,0:07:17.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,现在是午休 也没办法啊 元太
Dialogue: 0,0:07:17.50,0:07:20.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那我们是不是也要吃午饭呢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:20.39,0:07:22.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这么说起来
Dialogue: 0,0:07:24.00,0:07:26.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有没有人没拿到便当
Dialogue: 0,0:07:29.12,0:07:30.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,肚子饿了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:30.89,0:07:32.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,元太真是的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:32.30,0:07:33.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还真是心急呢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:35.45,0:07:36.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,给
Dialogue: 0,0:07:38.21,0:07:40.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我这个签名真的可以吗
Dialogue: 0,0:07:40.80,0:07:43.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 谢谢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:45.03,0:07:48.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,元太和光彦呢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:48.54,0:07:50.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好厉害啊
Dialogue: 0,0:07:50.11,0:07:52.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,连车牌号都一样呢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:52.30,0:07:55.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这两辆应该就是在楼顶平台上要换的车
Dialogue: 0,0:07:55.51,0:07:58.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,其中一辆用遥控器控制着从楼顶坠下
Dialogue: 0,0:07:58.99,0:08:01.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,总觉得很紧张呢
Dialogue: 0,0:08:02.70,0:08:05.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好 作为纪念
Dialogue: 0,0:08:06.33,0:08:09.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不行啊 元太 你在做什么
Dialogue: 0,0:08:09.75,0:08:10.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了你们
Dialogue: 0,0:08:13.83,0:08:15.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没什么
Dialogue: 0,0:08:16.70,0:08:18.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,告辞了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:54.78,0:08:55.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就靠你了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:07.92,0:09:09.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思
Dialogue: 0,0:09:09.71,0:09:10.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你开什么玩笑
Dialogue: 0,0:09:10.99,0:09:13.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要你来插什么嘴
Dialogue: 0,0:09:13.37,0:09:14.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我并不是插嘴
Dialogue: 0,0:09:14.70,0:09:16.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,两个人又吵架了啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:16.78,0:09:19.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果拍摄能顺利开始的话就好了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:19.90,0:09:21.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,总觉得很担心
Dialogue: 0,0:09:21.64,0:09:22.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,力石先生
Dialogue: 0,0:09:34.86,0:09:36.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,已经开始了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:09:39.99,0:09:42.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,谁快去阻止他
Dialogue: 0,0:09:42.27,0:09:44.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他打算按自己的计划去做了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:24.48,0:10:26.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,力 力石先生
Dialogue: 0,0:10:26.28,0:10:28.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎 怎么会
Dialogue: 0,0:10:28.52,0:10:32.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以 所以我才说不要这么做
Dialogue: 0,0:10:32.74,0:10:35.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,到底怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:10:35.04,0:10:36.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,发生什么事了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:42.61,0:10:44.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没系安全带
Dialogue: 0,0:10:44.72,0:10:46.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说
Dialogue: 0,0:10:47.12,0:10:50.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在那个平台上要冲破栏杆的瞬间
Dialogue: 0,0:10:50.98,0:10:53.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他想从车内跳出来却失败了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:53.43,0:10:54.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可以说是事故吧
Dialogue: 0,0:10:55.46,0:10:56.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:02.77,0:11:05.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个 说不定是
Dialogue: 0,0:11:07.83,0:11:09.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,摄像师叔叔
Dialogue: 0,0:11:10.74,0:11:14.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,刚才摄像机都拍下来了吧 能不能让我看看
Dialogue: 0,0:11:25.65,0:11:27.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然
Dialogue: 0,0:11:42.00,0:11:45.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看来那边也要去确认一下
Dialogue: 0,0:11:48.36,0:11:49.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:11:49.49,0:11:50.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你去哪里
Dialogue: 0,0:11:50.91,0:11:52.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,又要去抢风头吗
Dialogue: 0,0:11:52.99,0:11:54.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们也一起去
Dialogue: 0,0:11:54.46,0:11:55.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,0:11:55.25,0:11:57.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,喂喂 你们
Dialogue: 0,0:12:12.40,0:12:13.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个是
Dialogue: 0,0:12:13.53,0:12:16.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,到底是怎么回事 柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:12:16.46,0:12:17.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这不是事故
Dialogue: 0,0:12:19.67,0:12:22.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是巧妙设计的杀人事件
Dialogue: 0,0:12:23.13,0:12:24.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:12:30.29,0:12:34.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,死者是汽车特技演员力石健吾 38岁
Dialogue: 0,0:12:34.71,0:12:37.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,死因似乎是汽车坠落后…
Dialogue: 0,0:12:37.90,0:12:39.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:39.25,0:12:42.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,车子撞击地面时造成其全身受重击
Dialogue: 0,0:12:42.86,0:12:44.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,当场死亡
Dialogue: 0,0:12:44.50,0:12:45.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,即便如此
Dialogue: 0,0:12:45.73,0:12:48.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让汽车从那么高的地方掉下来
Dialogue: 0,0:12:48.87,0:12:51.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这次的拍摄真是太危险了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:51.23,0:12:52.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:52.37,0:12:54.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那种特技我们是不会让他做的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:54.79,0:12:56.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:12:56.89,0:13:00.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是力石先生他擅自做的
Dialogue: 0,0:13:00.31,0:13:01.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是他自己想做的特技
Dialogue: 0,0:13:01.86,0:13:03.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可是失败了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:03.77,0:13:06.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,正确地说不是特技
Dialogue: 0,0:13:06.17,0:13:08.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,而是正式开始前的表演
Dialogue: 0,0:13:08.71,0:13:12.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不明白为什么力石先生要这么做
Dialogue: 0,0:13:12.50,0:13:13.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因为他太着急了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:13.80,0:13:14.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,太着急了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:14.99,0:13:15.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为了什么
Dialogue: 0,0:13:15.86,0:13:17.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你们应该能理解
Dialogue: 0,0:13:17.83,0:13:20.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,年轻的特技演员不断涌现
Dialogue: 0,0:13:20.39,0:13:24.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们也早就对拘泥于胶片的拍摄厌倦了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:24.23,0:13:26.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,并不是说不需要特技演员
Dialogue: 0,0:13:26.99,0:13:29.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,像这种电视剧还是绝对需要的
Dialogue: 0,0:13:29.65,0:13:32.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是现在电脑特效技术的提高
Dialogue: 0,0:13:32.56,0:13:35.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,原来的一些特技就不用冒着生命危险去做了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:35.26,0:13:39.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有人因此而被解雇也是事实
Dialogue: 0,0:13:39.68,0:13:41.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,跟我说也没用
Dialogue: 0,0:13:41.32,0:13:43.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,负责人事的是制片人
Dialogue: 0,0:13:43.30,0:13:48.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,听说制片人解雇力石先生后是你来接替他
Dialogue: 0,0:13:50.44,0:13:52.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,听好了 你会后悔的
Dialogue: 0,0:13:52.65,0:13:53.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请你放开我
Dialogue: 0,0:13:53.87,0:13:55.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不管怎么样
Dialogue: 0,0:13:55.51,0:13:59.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为了保住自己的饭碗所以他很着急
Dialogue: 0,0:13:59.45,0:14:01.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就是这样的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:01.15,0:14:04.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,听你这么说似乎你很了解他一样 木岛
Dialogue: 0,0:14:04.10,0:14:08.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,最担心会被制片人解雇的应该是你吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:08.83,0:14:10.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你到底使了些什么手段
Dialogue: 0,0:14:10.38,0:14:12.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,力石先生他好像是知道的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:12.94,0:14:14.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,别胡说八道了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:14.11,0:14:16.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你是说我对他做了什么吗
Dialogue: 0,0:14:16.60,0:14:21.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,丑事被揭穿而被他揍了的人不就是你吗
Dialogue: 0,0:14:22.11,0:14:23.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,住手
Dialogue: 0,0:14:23.14,0:14:25.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在这种情况下请你们不要打架
Dialogue: 0,0:14:25.28,0:14:29.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,话说回来你好像也常常被他打啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:29.64,0:14:33.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你还说过要杀了他呢 不是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:14:33.40,0:14:36.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你的意思是我对他做了什么吗
Dialogue: 0,0:14:36.61,0:14:39.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,警官 请你们尽快查清真相吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:39.39,0:14:41.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这件事是事故吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:41.18,0:14:42.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:42.38,0:14:45.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不过是不是因为汽车维护不力所造成的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:45.60,0:14:48.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还要请专门的鉴定人员来调查
Dialogue: 0,0:14:48.15,0:14:50.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,绝 绝对不会有这种事
Dialogue: 0,0:14:50.26,0:14:51.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们的维护是万无一失的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:51.83,0:14:53.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可是你有动机啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:53.37,0:14:54.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那你不是也一样吗
Dialogue: 0,0:14:55.02,0:15:00.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不过就现阶段的情况来看事故的可能性较大
Dialogue: 0,0:15:00.23,0:15:02.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是当然
Dialogue: 0,0:15:02.62,0:15:04.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,博士 我们上
Dialogue: 0,0:15:07.07,0:15:08.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请等一下
Dialogue: 0,0:15:10.99,0:15:12.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个
Dialogue: 0,0:15:14.06,0:15:17.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这件事是伪装成事故的杀人案
Dialogue: 0,0:15:17.12,0:15:18.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你 你说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:15:18.95,0:15:22.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你 你有什么证据呢
Dialogue: 0,0:15:22.38,0:15:24.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请你们冷静一下
Dialogue: 0,0:15:24.69,0:15:29.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,首先要确认一下死亡的力石先生的性格
Dialogue: 0,0:15:29.17,0:15:30.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,性格
Dialogue: 0,0:15:30.56,0:15:34.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,比如特技的难度越高他就越想试试之类的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:36.35,0:15:38.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,的确如此
Dialogue: 0,0:15:38.27,0:15:41.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他还曾经特地去找这种机会往下跳呢
Dialogue: 0,0:15:41.73,0:15:42.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,很早就有了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:42.80,0:15:44.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,职业病吧
Dialogue: 0,0:15:44.58,0:15:49.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,当然要做的话会有万全的准备和特训
Dialogue: 0,0:15:49.30,0:15:52.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只要做得好就是一流的水平
Dialogue: 0,0:15:52.21,0:15:53.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那力石先生呢
Dialogue: 0,0:15:54.35,0:15:55.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是一流的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:55.70,0:15:58.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 年轻的时候确实是
Dialogue: 0,0:15:58.54,0:16:02.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可最近他的水平下降也是不争的事实啊
Dialogue: 0,0:16:02.84,0:16:05.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果犯人正好利用了这一点呢
Dialogue: 0,0:16:06.38,0:16:08.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么意思
Dialogue: 0,0:16:08.10,0:16:09.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,深町先生
Dialogue: 0,0:16:09.88,0:16:13.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,当时力石先生和你说了些什么
Dialogue: 0,0:16:13.43,0:16:17.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以 我要让你看看真正的飞车特技
Dialogue: 0,0:16:17.44,0:16:19.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他就是这么说的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:22.14,0:16:23.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,正好相反吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:23.72,0:16:24.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,相反
Dialogue: 0,0:16:24.83,0:16:27.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就是说不是力石先生而是深町先生你
Dialogue: 0,0:16:27.75,0:16:30.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是你提出的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:30.58,0:16:32.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,比如你这样对他说
Dialogue: 0,0:16:32.15,0:16:34.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,虽然我们的立场相反
Dialogue: 0,0:16:34.11,0:16:37.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但要是你表演得好大家也许就会接受
Dialogue: 0,0:16:37.72,0:16:40.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,唆使他这么去做
Dialogue: 0,0:16:40.32,0:16:41.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一派胡言
Dialogue: 0,0:16:41.70,0:16:44.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你的意思就是我杀了他吗
Dialogue: 0,0:16:44.98,0:16:47.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 犯人就是你
Dialogue: 0,0:16:47.82,0:16:49.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,深町先生
Dialogue: 0,0:16:49.80,0:16:51.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,阿 阿笠先生
Dialogue: 0,0:16:51.44,0:16:53.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,即使是他唆使的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:53.70,0:16:58.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但实际上驾车坠落的还是力石先生本人啊
Dialogue: 0,0:16:58.45,0:16:59.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不能算是谋杀吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:59.90,0:17:03.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 正因为如此 深町先生
Dialogue: 0,0:17:03.31,0:17:07.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你就对力石先生这么说的
Dialogue: 0,0:17:07.29,0:17:11.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在A车里并没有放置使车在空中爆炸的炸药
Dialogue: 0,0:17:11.58,0:17:14.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以开A车的话这些特技是没有意义的
Dialogue: 0,0:17:14.99,0:17:16.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,绝对不要去做
Dialogue: 0,0:17:16.35,0:17:19.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这么一说力石先生反而下定了决心
Dialogue: 0,0:17:20.11,0:17:25.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一到楼顶就迅速换上放置了炸药的B车
Dialogue: 0,0:17:25.24,0:17:29.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想要做在坠落前的瞬间跳车的危险特技
Dialogue: 0,0:17:29.35,0:17:31.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让大家看看他的身手
Dialogue: 0,0:17:33.09,0:17:36.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这么说那个是停放在楼顶上的B车吗
Dialogue: 0,0:17:39.44,0:17:40.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是的
Dialogue: 0,0:17:40.75,0:17:43.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这辆车里并没有放置炸药
Dialogue: 0,0:17:43.18,0:17:43.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是A车
Dialogue: 0,0:17:43.99,0:17:46.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么啊 越搞越糊涂了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:46.83,0:17:47.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我也是
Dialogue: 0,0:17:47.78,0:17:50.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不对 等等
Dialogue: 0,0:17:50.41,0:17:51.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我记得当时
Dialogue: 0,0:17:51.90,0:17:55.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,高木 慎重起见 你去楼顶看看另一辆车
Dialogue: 0,0:17:55.34,0:17:56.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好的
Dialogue: 0,0:17:59.69,0:18:01.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,警官 找到了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:01.37,0:18:03.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这里的果然是B车
Dialogue: 0,0:18:03.45,0:18:07.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说力石先生并没有从A车换到B车
Dialogue: 0,0:18:07.68,0:18:09.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,而是直接进行了特技表演
Dialogue: 0,0:18:09.56,0:18:11.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,最终失败而坠落
Dialogue: 0,0:18:11.58,0:18:13.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然是事故
Dialogue: 0,0:18:13.46,0:18:16.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要那么着急下结论啊
Dialogue: 0,0:18:16.11,0:18:19.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,回忆一下事故发生后的力石先生吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:19.59,0:18:23.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果有鉴识人员所拍摄的照片的话
Dialogue: 0,0:18:28.29,0:18:29.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:18:29.22,0:18:30.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在
Dialogue: 0,0:18:30.35,0:18:32.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然就是这个 这个
Dialogue: 0,0:18:32.89,0:18:36.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,元太贴上去的假面超人贴纸
Dialogue: 0,0:18:36.11,0:18:39.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,贴在负责车辆的叔叔开到楼顶的车上了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:39.96,0:18:41.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,对吧 元太
Dialogue: 0,0:18:41.66,0:18:43.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个
Dialogue: 0,0:18:43.34,0:18:45.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不会错了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:45.07,0:18:48.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他果然是在楼顶上换了车
Dialogue: 0,0:18:48.04,0:18:49.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不 不好意思
Dialogue: 0,0:18:49.84,0:18:52.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,两辆车我都贴了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:52.66,0:18:54.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,都贴了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:54.20,0:18:55.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会这样
Dialogue: 0,0:18:55.77,0:18:59.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说证明不了他是否曾经换过车
Dialogue: 0,0:18:59.90,0:19:01.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那倒不是
Dialogue: 0,0:19:01.24,0:19:02.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我要你们看的是这个
Dialogue: 0,0:19:05.36,0:19:07.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请问 摄像师叔叔
Dialogue: 0,0:19:07.06,0:19:09.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你刚才拍的能不能再给我们看看
Dialogue: 0,0:19:11.58,0:19:12.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,停
Dialogue: 0,0:19:13.40,0:19:16.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看 门上并没有夹住东西
Dialogue: 0,0:19:16.11,0:19:17.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这 这是
Dialogue: 0,0:19:17.56,0:19:21.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这之后直到上了楼顶他都没有开过门
Dialogue: 0,0:19:21.54,0:19:23.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是 炸药呢
Dialogue: 0,0:19:23.75,0:19:26.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个只要在事先换好就可以了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:26.63,0:19:30.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是 只有这一点不能成为换了车的证据
Dialogue: 0,0:19:30.19,0:19:31.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:19:31.24,0:19:34.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我当时立刻就上楼顶去看过了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:34.64,0:19:36.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,车头还是热的
Dialogue: 0,0:19:37.00,0:19:39.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像引擎刚刚才关掉
Dialogue: 0,0:19:40.18,0:19:41.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这么说果然是
Dialogue: 0,0:19:41.80,0:19:42.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真荒谬
Dialogue: 0,0:19:42.92,0:19:44.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就算是这样又怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:44.61,0:19:47.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是假设 都只是假设
Dialogue: 0,0:19:47.10,0:19:51.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就算是我唆使他 让他在楼顶上换车
Dialogue: 0,0:19:51.38,0:19:53.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在车坠落之前没有成功跳出来的人
Dialogue: 0,0:19:53.95,0:19:57.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不管怎么说 还是他自己啊
Dialogue: 0,0:19:57.46,0:19:59.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你是说他的能力下降了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:19:59.73,0:20:02.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在冲破栏杆之前的瞬间踩刹车不就好了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:02.86,0:20:05.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,连这一点都做不到的话
Dialogue: 0,0:20:05.37,0:20:06.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,的确
Dialogue: 0,0:20:09.70,0:20:14.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不 不管是跳出来还是踩刹车都是不可能的
Dialogue: 0,0:20:15.59,0:20:17.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你这话是什么意思
Dialogue: 0,0:20:17.58,0:20:20.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请大家想一想
Dialogue: 0,0:20:20.16,0:20:23.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,停在楼顶的B车是什么样的车
Dialogue: 0,0:20:23.73,0:20:27.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,除了放置有在空中爆炸的炸药以外
Dialogue: 0,0:20:27.52,0:20:28.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,遥控吗
Dialogue: 0,0:20:28.76,0:20:31.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,遥控器现在在哪里
Dialogue: 0,0:20:31.43,0:20:32.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个吗
Dialogue: 0,0:20:36.53,0:20:37.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是这个吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:38.26,0:20:41.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 他说要检查一下好不好用
Dialogue: 0,0:20:41.39,0:20:42.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就借给他了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:42.58,0:20:43.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,用了它的话
Dialogue: 0,0:20:43.69,0:20:46.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就可以知道哪辆是A车哪辆是B车了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:58.61,0:20:59.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这 这辆是
Dialogue: 0,0:21:01.54,0:21:03.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像在哭泣一样
Dialogue: 0,0:21:03.93,0:21:05.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:21:05.67,0:21:07.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好可怜啊
Dialogue: 0,0:21:08.93,0:21:10.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我借了很多钱
Dialogue: 0,0:21:10.49,0:21:12.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因此就挪用了拍片的经费
Dialogue: 0,0:21:12.77,0:21:15.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他发现这件事后就威胁我
Dialogue: 0,0:21:16.46,0:21:19.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,于是你就反过来利用力石先生的心理
Dialogue: 0,0:21:19.49,0:21:21.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,设计了一个杀人计划
Dialogue: 0,0:21:21.80,0:21:25.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,力石先生开着A车到达楼顶的平台
Dialogue: 0,0:21:25.63,0:21:28.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,换上了B车之后
Dialogue: 0,0:21:28.25,0:21:31.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你用遥控器启动并控制了车
Dialogue: 0,0:21:35.06,0:21:36.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,刹车失灵了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:36.54,0:21:37.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,门也打不开
Dialogue: 0,0:21:37.98,0:21:39.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就这样使车坠落了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:46.25,0:21:49.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,等力石先生被认定为死于车技失误而引起的事故
Dialogue: 0,0:21:49.53,0:21:53.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,遭到严重破坏的车也会被认为是A车
Dialogue: 0,0:21:53.09,0:21:57.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这时再把遥控器还给管理车辆的西胁先生就行了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:57.93,0:22:00.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你就是这样打算的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:23:40.08,0:23:41.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我再也吃不下了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:41.86,0:23:43.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,假面超人太帅了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:43.27,0:23:44.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这样不行啊 元太
Dialogue: 0,0:23:44.73,0:23:46.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,贴得到处都是
Dialogue: 0,0:23:46.13,0:23:48.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我的推理也无用武之地了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:49.65,0:23:50.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,说对了
Dialogue: 0,0:24:03.68,0:24:05.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,山本先生是自杀吗
Dialogue: 0,0:24:08.21,0:24:09.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一定另有隐情
Dialogue: 0,0:24:09.89,0:24:11.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还有我没发现的东西
Dialogue: 0,0:24:18.31,0:24:20.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是什么呢
Dialogue: 0,0:24:24.42,0:24:25.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,NEXT CONAN
Dialogue: 0,0:24:25.90,0:24:27.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,临终的安
Dialogue: 0,0:24:45.86,0:24:48.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,NEXT CONAN'S HINT
Dialogue: 0,0:24:48.16,0:24:49.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,搅拌棒
Dialogue: 0,0:24:50.46,0:24:53.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就凭一根搅拌棒就能解开这个案件吗
