[Script Info]
; This is an Advanced Sub Station Alpha v4+ script.
; For Sub Station Alpha info and downloads,
; go to http://www.eswat.demon.co.uk/
; or email kotus@eswat.demon.co.uk
; 
; Advanced Sub Station Alpha script format developed by #Anime-Fansubs@EfNET
; http://www.anime-fansubs.org
; 
; For additional info and downloads go to http://vobsub.edensrising.com/
; or email gabest@freemail.hu
; 
; Note: This file was saved by Subresync.
; 
ScriptType: v4.00+
Collisions: Normal
PlayResX: 384
PlayResY: 288
Timer: 100.0000

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,文鼎新艺体简,14,&H00ffffff,&H0000ffff,&H00000000,&H80000000,0,0,0,0,100,100,0,0.00,1,1,1,2,20,20,10,1

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Actor, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text
Dialogue: 0,0:00:01.62,0:00:02.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,挡住去路的巨墙
Dialogue: 0,0:00:02.99,0:00:04.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,换个思考的角度就是一扇大门
Dialogue: 0,0:00:04.83,0:00:06.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,“啊”地把嘴张大
Dialogue: 0,0:00:06.70,0:00:08.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不由自主的动作
Dialogue: 0,0:00:08.20,0:00:09.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,与今天的案件到底有什么联系
Dialogue: 0,0:00:09.60,0:00:11.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看清唯一真相的是
Dialogue: 0,0:00:11.20,0:00:12.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,外表看似小孩 头脑却是大人
Dialogue: 0,0:00:12.90,0:00:15.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他的名字就是 名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:02:29.16,0:02:35.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,通向死亡的“啊”
Dialogue: 0,0:02:40.44,0:02:41.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生 快点
Dialogue: 0,0:02:41.98,0:02:43.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不能再跑快点吗
Dialogue: 0,0:02:43.60,0:02:45.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,已经不能再快了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:45.32,0:02:47.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,新田太太你为什么就不能再瘦一点呢
Dialogue: 0,0:02:48.81,0:02:49.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:02:49.90,0:02:52.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这该死的助听器又不好使了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:54.91,0:02:55.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,里面
Dialogue: 0,0:02:55.87,0:02:57.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,最里面的那个房间
Dialogue: 0,0:03:16.85,0:03:18.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是改装手枪啊
Dialogue: 0,0:03:18.90,0:03:21.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,赫赫有名的大侦探出马
Dialogue: 0,0:03:22.08,0:03:24.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,很快就能破案了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:25.59,0:03:26.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,感冒了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:03:26.15,0:03:28.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是 没关系的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:28.13,0:03:29.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,即使是医生也不能大意啊
Dialogue: 0,0:03:29.90,0:03:30.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还是要注意点
Dialogue: 0,0:03:31.06,0:03:31.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,哪里
Dialogue: 0,0:03:31.99,0:03:33.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不是什么医生
Dialogue: 0,0:03:33.87,0:03:36.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只是在牙科诊所工作而已
Dialogue: 0,0:03:36.93,0:03:39.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那么请继续说明一下吧
Dialogue: 0,0:03:39.50,0:03:42.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,新田太太听到类似枪响的声音是在3点前吧
Dialogue: 0,0:03:43.11,0:03:45.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,准确地说是2点45分
Dialogue: 0,0:03:45.56,0:03:48.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我在2楼睡午觉刚醒过来
Dialogue: 0,0:03:48.33,0:03:50.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这位铃木小姐就来了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:52.10,0:03:53.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,面包皮
Dialogue: 0,0:03:53.47,0:03:54.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:54.35,0:03:57.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我中午做了些三明治
Dialogue: 0,0:03:57.37,0:04:01.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想起你说过可以用这个给池里的鲤鱼喂食
Dialogue: 0,0:04:01.70,0:04:04.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,太谢谢了 我正好想去呢
Dialogue: 0,0:04:04.44,0:04:05.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真帮上大忙了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:06.12,0:04:07.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天你不去上班吗
Dialogue: 0,0:04:07.57,0:04:09.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我请了假
Dialogue: 0,0:04:09.34,0:04:11.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那我回来后一起喝杯茶吧
Dialogue: 0,0:04:12.10,0:04:13.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,3点过我就回来
Dialogue: 0,0:04:15.22,0:04:16.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,刚才是什么声音
Dialogue: 0,0:04:16.94,0:04:18.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从山本先生的房间里传出来的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:19.04,0:04:20.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,该不会是枪声吧
Dialogue: 0,0:04:20.65,0:04:21.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会
Dialogue: 0,0:04:21.97,0:04:23.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也是啊
Dialogue: 0,0:04:23.14,0:04:25.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大白天在这种地方怎么可能
Dialogue: 0,0:04:28.18,0:04:30.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,鲤鱼们空着肚子在等我呢
Dialogue: 0,0:04:30.31,0:04:30.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,回头见
Dialogue: 0,0:04:31.54,0:04:33.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,之后3点刚过我就回来了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:35.03,0:04:37.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,隔壁后来有什么动静
Dialogue: 0,0:04:37.40,0:04:38.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没有 什么也没发生
Dialogue: 0,0:04:43.05,0:04:44.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,中西先生 你好
Dialogue: 0,0:04:47.15,0:04:49.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你现在住的房间以前曾是他在住
Dialogue: 0,0:04:51.17,0:04:52.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,出去了也不知道关门
Dialogue: 0,0:05:04.02,0:05:05.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像是遗书啊
Dialogue: 0,0:05:05.76,0:05:10.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,听说中西先生和山本先生是好朋友
Dialogue: 0,0:05:10.34,0:05:12.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,即使山本先生是自杀
Dialogue: 0,0:05:13.07,0:05:17.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,作为好朋友不叫警察或救护车就走了也很奇怪吧
Dialogue: 0,0:05:17.87,0:05:19.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你是说他像是在逃跑吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:20.02,0:05:22.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 绝对没错
Dialogue: 0,0:05:22.88,0:05:25.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么看都让人有理由认为他是犯人
Dialogue: 0,0:05:26.29,0:05:29.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这么看来的确是很有嫌疑
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.70,0:05:31.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还是先联系目暮警官吧
Dialogue: 0,0:05:33.11,0:05:36.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,受小兰之托我们在买蛋糕回去的路上
Dialogue: 0,0:05:37.01,0:05:40.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,遇到要去报警的新田太太而来到了这里
Dialogue: 0,0:05:40.93,0:05:42.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,致中西
Dialogue: 0,0:05:42.47,0:05:46.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因为无法偿还债务所以我以死谢罪
Dialogue: 0,0:05:46.59,0:05:49.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是这封遗书是用打字机打的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:50.10,0:05:53.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不能确定是山本先生本人所写
Dialogue: 0,0:05:53.64,0:05:55.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,而且最让人感到不解的是
Dialogue: 0,0:05:55.80,0:05:57.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,发现从小一起长大的好友的遗体
Dialogue: 0,0:05:57.90,0:05:59.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,却一声不响地离开了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:01.43,0:06:05.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 因为是大白天 所以那时…
Dialogue: 0,0:06:05.76,0:06:08.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,根据我曾经担任刑警的经验来看
Dialogue: 0,0:06:08.44,0:06:10.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,犯人就是山本的儿时玩伴中西
Dialogue: 0,0:06:11.05,0:06:13.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,动机就是最常见的债务纠纷
Dialogue: 0,0:06:13.99,0:06:17.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生 根据现场鉴定的结果
Dialogue: 0,0:06:17.36,0:06:19.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,基本可以排除他杀的可能
Dialogue: 0,0:06:19.34,0:06:23.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因为从死者身上检查不出任何反抗的痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:06:23.56,0:06:25.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,居然没有反抗
Dialogue: 0,0:06:25.69,0:06:27.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果把枪塞入喉咙的话
Dialogue: 0,0:06:28.26,0:06:32.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,牙齿 嘴唇和口腔内都应该留下反抗的痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:06:32.93,0:06:34.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果没有的话
Dialogue: 0,0:06:34.34,0:06:37.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只能认为是死者自己张开嘴开枪自杀的
Dialogue: 0,0:06:38.27,0:06:39.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,警官 请过来看
Dialogue: 0,0:06:41.25,0:06:43.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,的确没有反抗的痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:06:44.02,0:06:46.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是 就算是这样…
Dialogue: 0,0:06:46.84,0:06:50.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这种蝴蝶被称作赤蛱蝶
Dialogue: 0,0:06:50.41,0:06:51.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,摆放在这里的植物…
Dialogue: 0,0:06:51.70,0:06:53.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,现在少跟我说这些
Dialogue: 0,0:06:53.57,0:06:53.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,别碍事
Dialogue: 0,0:06:54.05,0:06:55.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,给我滚到一边去
Dialogue: 0,0:06:59.15,0:06:59.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,警官
Dialogue: 0,0:06:59.92,0:07:01.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,调查了犯罪前科的记录
Dialogue: 0,0:07:01.40,0:07:04.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,山本先生曾因改装枪械而被逮捕过
Dialogue: 0,0:07:06.54,0:07:08.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,根据邻居铃木小姐所说
Dialogue: 0,0:07:08.95,0:07:12.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她曾提醒他控制电视的音量却遭到拒绝
Dialogue: 0,0:07:13.16,0:07:15.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个男的似乎只钟情于蝴蝶
Dialogue: 0,0:07:15.81,0:07:16.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,警官
Dialogue: 0,0:07:16.98,0:07:18.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,像这种反应迟钝的人
Dialogue: 0,0:07:18.79,0:07:21.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,实在无法想象他会因为还不出钱而自杀
Dialogue: 0,0:07:22.08,0:07:22.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生
Dialogue: 0,0:07:23.48,0:07:25.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你还没弄明白吗
Dialogue: 0,0:07:25.41,0:07:27.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,铃木小姐和新田太太听到枪声的时间
Dialogue: 0,0:07:28.26,0:07:29.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大概是2点45分左右
Dialogue: 0,0:07:30.11,0:07:33.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,而新田太太看到中西是在3点过后
Dialogue: 0,0:07:33.88,0:07:36.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就算中西是犯人的话
Dialogue: 0,0:07:36.49,0:07:37.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这之间的15分钟
Dialogue: 0,0:07:38.34,0:07:40.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他又做了些什么
Dialogue: 0,0:07:40.91,0:07:45.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,犯人一般在作案后都会尽快逃离现场
Dialogue: 0,0:07:46.25,0:07:46.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,警官
Dialogue: 0,0:07:47.26,0:07:48.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,中西先生来了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:53.58,0:07:54.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是说了嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:07:54.60,0:07:56.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我按照约定3点钟准时过来的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:57.52,0:07:58.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,进屋一看
Dialogue: 0,0:07:58.96,0:08:01.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,山本已经在沙发上死去了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:02.45,0:08:04.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你说你发现的已经是尸体了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:04.43,0:08:06.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但好歹你们是从小一起长大的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:07.22,0:08:10.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为什么不立刻报警
Dialogue: 0,0:08:10.12,0:08:12.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是我借钱给山本的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:13.12,0:08:17.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不想因为债务纠纷而被怀疑才跑掉的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:17.15,0:08:18.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是吧 说谎是没用的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:19.06,0:08:24.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你为了不留下指纹和硝烟反应而用毛巾包住手枪
Dialogue: 0,0:08:24.49,0:08:28.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,2点45分左右把枪塞进了山本先生的嘴里
Dialogue: 0,0:08:28.74,0:08:31.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,伪造出他是自杀的样子将他射杀
Dialogue: 0,0:08:34.41,0:08:37.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,听到枪声的人有两个呢
Dialogue: 0,0:08:37.63,0:08:38.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,等等
Dialogue: 0,0:08:39.00,0:08:42.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你说说看我是怎么把枪放进山本嘴里的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:43.10,0:08:46.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这家伙不会傻到张着嘴让我射死吧
Dialogue: 0,0:08:47.52,0:08:53.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可能是你等山本先生打哈欠的瞬间
Dialogue: 0,0:08:53.99,0:08:56.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这家伙可是正被我追债呢
Dialogue: 0,0:08:56.80,0:08:59.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有打哈欠的空闲吗
Dialogue: 0,0:09:00.01,0:09:02.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这么说来也是啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:02.34,0:09:04.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,的确 中西先生说得没错
Dialogue: 0,0:09:05.07,0:09:07.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要说是他杀的确实说不通
Dialogue: 0,0:09:08.05,0:09:10.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那我再问你
Dialogue: 0,0:09:10.78,0:09:14.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在山本先生的死亡推测时间2点45分左右
Dialogue: 0,0:09:14.96,0:09:17.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你在什么地方做什么
Dialogue: 0,0:09:17.76,0:09:19.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,正乘出租车赶往这里
Dialogue: 0,0:09:19.57,0:09:21.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,出租车公司的名字呢
Dialogue: 0,0:09:21.62,0:09:22.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不记得了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:23.28,0:09:25.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像是蓝色的车
Dialogue: 0,0:09:25.54,0:09:28.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,上面画了不知是鸽子还是老鼠的图案
Dialogue: 0,0:09:28.41,0:09:29.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我去查一下
Dialogue: 0,0:09:35.60,0:09:37.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他只是在拖延时间罢了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:38.41,0:09:40.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个男的碰到你真是不幸啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:41.02,0:09:44.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,谁能逃得过毛利侦探的法眼
Dialogue: 0,0:09:44.27,0:09:46.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生 我正要和新田太太一起去喝茶
Dialogue: 0,0:09:46.90,0:09:48.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果方便的话您也一起来如何
Dialogue: 0,0:09:49.12,0:09:51.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那正好一起尝尝我刚买的蛋糕
Dialogue: 0,0:09:51.40,0:09:55.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真是的 借出去的钱没要回来 反而…
Dialogue: 0,0:09:54.62,0:09:56.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果山本先生的死因是自杀的话
Dialogue: 0,0:09:57.47,0:10:01.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在他死后那些蝴蝶又打算怎么处理呢
Dialogue: 0,0:10:01.96,0:10:03.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那些精心培育的蝴蝶
Dialogue: 0,0:10:04.53,0:10:05.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一定还遗漏了什么
Dialogue: 0,0:10:06.22,0:10:07.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我没有注意到的东西
Dialogue: 0,0:10:08.66,0:10:09.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,到底是什么
Dialogue: 0,0:10:17.02,0:10:18.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让大家久等了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:19.60,0:10:21.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快来吃蛋糕吧
Dialogue: 0,0:10:24.02,0:10:24.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是草莓
Dialogue: 0,0:10:25.51,0:10:28.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,柯南 把嘴张开 “啊”
Dialogue: 0,0:10:33.72,0:10:36.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生 工作请先放一边
Dialogue: 0,0:10:36.80,0:10:39.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生也来吃草莓吧
Dialogue: 0,0:10:39.70,0:10:41.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不用了 我已经是大人了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:42.49,0:10:43.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,盛情难却啊
Dialogue: 0,0:10:44.86,0:10:47.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,柯南 不准告诉小兰
Dialogue: 0,0:10:47.40,0:10:49.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,来 “啊”
Dialogue: 0,0:10:49.09,0:10:50.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,啊
Dialogue: 0,0:10:51.58,0:10:53.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真是个不像话的大叔
Dialogue: 0,0:11:01.98,0:11:04.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,红茶里加一些白兰地怎么样
Dialogue: 0,0:11:04.43,0:11:05.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好啊
Dialogue: 0,0:11:08.02,0:11:09.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一会就来 一会就来
Dialogue: 0,0:11:09.99,0:11:11.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,到底要我等到什么时候
Dialogue: 0,0:11:11.51,0:11:14.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我的手下现在正在拼命地找
Dialogue: 0,0:11:15.97,0:11:18.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,现在就要山本先生的医疗卡吗
Dialogue: 0,0:11:19.14,0:11:20.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生有什么头绪了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:11:21.71,0:11:23.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔想了解一下吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:23.52,0:11:26.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,山本先生有没有去看过牙医
Dialogue: 0,0:11:26.41,0:11:30.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果看过的话 是到哪里的诊所看的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:30.40,0:11:31.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:31.88,0:11:34.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,对 山本信男先生 是你们的病人吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:36.54,0:11:37.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,取消预约了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:38.46,0:11:41.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我让一个叫柯南的孩子过来了解情况
Dialogue: 0,0:11:41.50,0:11:43.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请详细地告诉他
Dialogue: 0,0:12:01.12,0:12:04.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,千叶警官 找到中西乘坐的出租车了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:12:05.38,0:12:10.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还没有 或者中西根本就是在撒谎
Dialogue: 0,0:12:10.24,0:12:15.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个 毛利叔叔想让你尽快调查一件事
Dialogue: 0,0:12:15.46,0:12:17.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔 快起来 叔叔
Dialogue: 0,0:12:18.79,0:12:21.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,再来一个吗 啊
Dialogue: 0,0:12:21.65,0:12:24.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,对不起 我看他喝得很尽兴
Dialogue: 0,0:12:24.80,0:12:25.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就一直在为他倒酒
Dialogue: 0,0:12:26.36,0:12:28.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔 快起来啦
Dialogue: 0,0:12:28.62,0:12:29.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,帮帮我好吗
Dialogue: 0,0:12:30.12,0:12:32.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没了 草莓没有了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:33.49,0:12:36.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,该说警官你可怜呢还是不幸呢
Dialogue: 0,0:12:36.87,0:12:38.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你在胡说些什么
Dialogue: 0,0:12:39.20,0:12:41.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们差不多该收队了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:41.53,0:12:42.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好了 起来吧
Dialogue: 0,0:12:43.65,0:12:46.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,干什么 要带我去哪里
Dialogue: 0,0:12:46.18,0:12:48.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在找到你乘坐的出租车之前
Dialogue: 0,0:12:48.50,0:12:49.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你都是嫌疑犯
Dialogue: 0,0:12:50.00,0:12:52.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,别开玩笑了 这跟我无关
Dialogue: 0,0:12:52.43,0:12:55.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你真是死到临头都不悔改
Dialogue: 0,0:12:55.08,0:12:56.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是你做的就是你做的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:56.62,0:12:58.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是男人的话就要大方地承认
Dialogue: 0,0:13:04.39,0:13:06.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我本来想这么说的
Dialogue: 0,0:13:06.30,0:13:09.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,警官 山本先生虽然是被谋杀的
Dialogue: 0,0:13:09.56,0:13:11.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,凶手却不是这个男人
Dialogue: 0,0:13:11.53,0:13:15.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,山本先生是受害后被伪装成了自杀
Dialogue: 0,0:13:15.96,0:13:17.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,伪装 谁干的
Dialogue: 0,0:13:17.60,0:13:19.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,伪装的证据在哪里
Dialogue: 0,0:13:19.66,0:13:20.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如大家所见
Dialogue: 0,0:13:20.58,0:13:23.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,山本先生十分喜欢蝴蝶
Dialogue: 0,0:13:23.91,0:13:27.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以他一定会想到自己自杀后蝴蝶该怎么办
Dialogue: 0,0:13:28.01,0:13:31.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,应该会在自杀前托人照管吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:31.95,0:13:35.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还有山本先生所坐的位置
Dialogue: 0,0:13:35.73,0:13:40.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在那里开枪的话子弹会射穿喉咙打到玻璃箱上
Dialogue: 0,0:13:41.13,0:13:44.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,搞不好蝴蝶会因此丧命
Dialogue: 0,0:13:44.71,0:13:47.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以他不会选这个位置自杀的
Dialogue: 0,0:13:49.05,0:13:49.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有道理
Dialogue: 0,0:13:49.97,0:13:55.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,山本先生2点30分曾打电话给牙医取消了预约
Dialogue: 0,0:13:55.19,0:13:56.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说
Dialogue: 0,0:13:56.60,0:14:01.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他是在2点半与被中西先生发现的3点之间遇害的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:02.48,0:14:07.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是2点45分 有证人听到枪声应该不会错
Dialogue: 0,0:14:07.98,0:14:09.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想知道的是犯罪手法
Dialogue: 0,0:14:10.19,0:14:14.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,犯人是怎么把枪伸进了山本先生的嘴里呢
Dialogue: 0,0:14:15.13,0:14:19.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,山本先生是按照犯人的指示乖乖地张开了嘴
Dialogue: 0,0:14:19.44,0:14:21.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,按照犯人的指示张开了嘴
Dialogue: 0,0:14:21.90,0:14:25.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小孩子也就算了 受害者可是个大人啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:25.65,0:14:29.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,的确有一个人可以这么操纵山本先生
Dialogue: 0,0:14:29.71,0:14:31.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个人是谁
Dialogue: 0,0:14:32.07,0:14:34.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,警官 请把嘴张开
Dialogue: 0,0:14:35.36,0:14:37.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有谁对你这么说你会乖乖照做呢
Dialogue: 0,0:14:37.93,0:14:38.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,乖乖照做吗
Dialogue: 0,0:14:39.22,0:14:41.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,老婆 奶奶
Dialogue: 0,0:14:41.48,0:14:43.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好 把嘴张开
Dialogue: 0,0:14:43.61,0:14:45.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,张开 “啊”
Dialogue: 0,0:14:45.85,0:14:46.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,医生吗
Dialogue: 0,0:14:46.73,0:14:48.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没错 就是医生
Dialogue: 0,0:14:48.70,0:14:51.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,特别是牙医大部分都会这么说
Dialogue: 0,0:14:51.83,0:14:53.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这么说犯人是牙医
Dialogue: 0,0:14:54.09,0:14:55.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,牙医到这个房间里来过吗
Dialogue: 0,0:14:56.18,0:14:59.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是 来的是在牙科诊所里工作的人
Dialogue: 0,0:14:59.50,0:15:05.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,而且认识山本先生 知道他在借钱
Dialogue: 0,0:15:05.95,0:15:07.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个人是谁
Dialogue: 0,0:15:07.83,0:15:08.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,铃木由美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:15:09.00,0:15:12.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你就在山本先生预约的牙科诊所
Dialogue: 0,0:15:12.72,0:15:15.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,米花牙科诊所里当助手吧
Dialogue: 0,0:15:16.46,0:15:23.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你耳朵后面的痕迹就是长时间戴口罩留下的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:23.80,0:15:27.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,听说你今天突然有急事向诊所请了假
Dialogue: 0,0:15:29.60,0:15:34.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你偷听到3点钟中西先生会来讨债
Dialogue: 0,0:15:34.80,0:15:38.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以就萌发了把计划很久的谋杀付诸实施的念头
Dialogue: 0,0:15:38.85,0:15:40.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,计划很久的谋杀
Dialogue: 0,0:15:40.77,0:15:43.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你大约是两个月前搬进这栋公寓的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:44.42,0:15:49.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是在山本先生去你工作的诊所看病之后不久
Dialogue: 0,0:15:50.29,0:15:54.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,目的就是可以假装成巧合接近山本先生
Dialogue: 0,0:15:54.75,0:15:58.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,然后和预期的一样他开始与你交流
Dialogue: 0,0:15:59.49,0:16:03.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,并且你知道了山本先生正在被追债
Dialogue: 0,0:16:03.34,0:16:07.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以想利用这个来伪装成负债自杀
Dialogue: 0,0:16:08.64,0:16:09.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天是工作日
Dialogue: 0,0:16:10.49,0:16:13.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,2点30分公寓里的人很少
Dialogue: 0,0:16:14.62,0:16:20.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,新田太太这时也会摘下助听器在房里睡觉
Dialogue: 0,0:16:24.86,0:16:26.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天是去看病的日子吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:27.03,0:16:28.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我来帮你检查
Dialogue: 0,0:16:28.70,0:16:31.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,作为邻居的好意可是免费服务哦
Dialogue: 0,0:16:31.72,0:16:32.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快让我进去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:35.01,0:16:36.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是啊 我有点事
Dialogue: 0,0:16:37.05,0:16:39.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请取消今天的预约
Dialogue: 0,0:16:56.72,0:16:58.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,等会再喝吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:58.33,0:16:59.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,马上就能完
Dialogue: 0,0:17:07.10,0:17:08.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那么 我们开始吧
Dialogue: 0,0:17:14.13,0:17:15.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因为很刺眼所以请闭上眼睛
Dialogue: 0,0:17:17.78,0:17:19.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,把嘴张开 “啊”
Dialogue: 0,0:17:21.14,0:17:22.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,马上就结束了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:30.75,0:17:33.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在杀害山本先生之后
Dialogue: 0,0:17:33.17,0:17:35.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你把事先录有枪声的磁带设定好
Dialogue: 0,0:17:35.42,0:17:37.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,然后带着面包皮拜访了新田太太
Dialogue: 0,0:17:38.76,0:17:39.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这样一来
Dialogue: 0,0:17:39.76,0:17:43.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,被认为是山本先生遇害时间的2点45分
Dialogue: 0,0:17:43.29,0:17:44.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你和新田太太在一起
Dialogue: 0,0:17:44.63,0:17:47.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说为自己制造了不在场证明
Dialogue: 0,0:17:47.97,0:17:51.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,之后 新田太太为了给鲤鱼喂食就出去了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:51.56,0:17:52.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看她走后你就…
Dialogue: 0,0:18:00.63,0:18:03.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这样 山本先生的死亡时间就成了2点45分
Dialogue: 0,0:18:03.96,0:18:08.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,而且尸体也会被3点钟来的中西先生发现
Dialogue: 0,0:18:08.31,0:18:11.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说 伪装成了自杀
Dialogue: 0,0:18:11.08,0:18:13.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是的 不是我杀的
Dialogue: 0,0:18:13.93,0:18:17.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我没有杀害山本先生的动机
Dialogue: 0,0:18:17.59,0:18:18.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你有动机
Dialogue: 0,0:18:18.93,0:18:20.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我去调查过了 铃木小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:18:21.10,0:18:25.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你的丈夫10年前在故乡岐阜遭遇交通事故
Dialogue: 0,0:18:26.48,0:18:29.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,现在仍然在医院里昏迷不醒
Dialogue: 0,0:18:39.01,0:18:39.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,岐阜蝶
Dialogue: 0,0:18:58.49,0:19:00.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,肇事者是山本信男
Dialogue: 0,0:19:00.74,0:19:02.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因为追逐蝴蝶而没有注意前方
Dialogue: 0,0:19:03.00,0:19:04.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,而且还喝了很多酒
Dialogue: 0,0:19:05.37,0:19:07.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,后来你突然在诊所遇见了山本
Dialogue: 0,0:19:08.18,0:19:11.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,于是就决定要为丈夫报仇
Dialogue: 0,0:19:11.88,0:19:12.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我说对了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:19:12.96,0:19:13.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不对
Dialogue: 0,0:19:13.96,0:19:18.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我丈夫的确因为山本而无法再当牙医
Dialogue: 0,0:19:18.86,0:19:20.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一生都被毁了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:21.52,0:19:23.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是我没有杀害他
Dialogue: 0,0:19:23.72,0:19:26.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个房间我也从来没有进来过
Dialogue: 0,0:19:27.50,0:19:30.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我有些感冒 失陪了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:31.55,0:19:34.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,虽然我想说请保重身体 但是由美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:19:34.92,0:19:37.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你患的并不是感冒
Dialogue: 0,0:19:37.25,0:19:38.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,而应该是花粉症
Dialogue: 0,0:19:39.66,0:19:40.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,花粉症
Dialogue: 0,0:19:41.59,0:19:43.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,而且是艾蒿花粉症
Dialogue: 0,0:19:43.69,0:19:45.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,艾蒿花粉症
Dialogue: 0,0:19:45.66,0:19:47.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个房间里的书上写着
Dialogue: 0,0:19:48.10,0:19:51.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,艾蒿是赤蛱蝶的食物
Dialogue: 0,0:19:51.60,0:19:54.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,艾蒿对于赤蛱蝶来说是美餐
Dialogue: 0,0:19:55.25,0:19:58.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但对人类来说就可能会引发花粉症
Dialogue: 0,0:19:59.51,0:20:03.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还有一点 你的头发上有些发光呢
Dialogue: 0,0:20:03.69,0:20:05.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我估计那是蝴蝶身上的鳞粉
Dialogue: 0,0:20:06.37,0:20:09.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生 我就住在隔壁
Dialogue: 0,0:20:10.06,0:20:12.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,艾蒿的花粉可能是被吹过来的
Dialogue: 0,0:20:12.99,0:20:16.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,逃走的蝴蝶也会趁我不注意时飞到身上
Dialogue: 0,0:20:16.97,0:20:18.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,柯南 把那个拿来
Dialogue: 0,0:20:25.15,0:20:28.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,由美小姐 你应该知道这是什么吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:28.43,0:20:31.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 这是用来观察牙齿背面的口腔镜
Dialogue: 0,0:20:31.85,0:20:35.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是我好不容易才从米花牙科诊所借来的
Dialogue: 0,0:20:35.83,0:20:40.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,B.D.C是诊所名字的缩写 应该是特制品吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:41.01,0:20:42.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在来看病的患者中
Dialogue: 0,0:20:42.70,0:20:46.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,会有人想得到这个或私自把它带回家吗
Dialogue: 0,0:20:46.94,0:20:48.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不 没有
Dialogue: 0,0:20:48.83,0:20:52.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,警官 在桌子下面有一个咖啡杯
Dialogue: 0,0:20:52.93,0:20:53.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请看一下
Dialogue: 0,0:20:57.59,0:20:59.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看起来只是一般的咖啡啊
Dialogue: 0,0:21:00.13,0:21:01.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有什么问题吗
Dialogue: 0,0:21:01.21,0:21:04.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,里面有一根用来搅拌的搅拌棒吧
Dialogue: 0,0:21:05.07,0:21:06.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请轻轻地把它拿出来
Dialogue: 0,0:21:20.04,0:21:21.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为什么会在这里 为什么
Dialogue: 0,0:21:32.33,0:21:35.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,把这根口腔镜带到这个房间来的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:35.80,0:21:37.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,除了你不会有别人了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:21:37.95,0:21:39.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你要怎么解释
Dialogue: 0,0:21:43.58,0:21:45.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,山本来诊所看病
Dialogue: 0,0:21:46.27,0:21:49.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,当然是早就不记得我的长相和名字了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:49.86,0:21:54.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让我不能原谅的是他明明发过誓不再酒后驾车
Dialogue: 0,0:21:55.08,0:21:58.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但他却是醉醺醺地开着车来诊所的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:59.42,0:22:02.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个人一点都没有反省
Dialogue: 0,0:22:02.52,0:22:05.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我越想越觉得丈夫很可怜 所以就…
Dialogue: 0,0:22:06.78,0:22:08.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,非常对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:23:43.99,0:23:47.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以那个蛋糕事件是事出有因的
Dialogue: 0,0:23:47.41,0:23:49.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我没有撒谎啊 小兰
Dialogue: 0,0:23:50.01,0:23:51.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请把门打开吧
Dialogue: 0,0:23:53.24,0:23:54.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,把灯也关了啊
Dialogue: 0,0:23:54.55,0:23:56.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,彻底死路一条了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:57.57,0:23:58.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这就是“啊”的惩罚吧
Dialogue: 0,0:24:04.65,0:24:06.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,[活着太累了 真的]
Dialogue: 0,0:24:05.16,0:24:05.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,遗书
Dialogue: 0,0:24:06.57,0:24:09.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,即使撒谎也肯定会留下证据的
Dialogue: 0,0:24:09.78,0:24:11.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我找到了 证据
Dialogue: 0,0:24:12.71,0:24:16.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但问题是该如何拆穿这个阴谋呢
Dialogue: 0,0:24:16.57,0:24:17.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么办
Dialogue: 0,0:24:20.26,0:24:22.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不能让奇怪的事件发生
Dialogue: 0,0:24:24.69,0:24:25.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,NEXT CONAN
Dialogue: 0,0:24:26.09,0:24:27.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,被钢筋阻挡的男人
Dialogue: 0,0:24:46.06,0:24:47.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,NEXT CONAN'S HINT
Dialogue: 0,0:24:48.07,0:24:49.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,记忆丧失
Dialogue: 0,0:24:50.72,0:24:52.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,千叶警官 今天的犯人
Dialogue: 0,0:24:52.25,0:24:52.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天的杏仁豆腐
Dialogue: 0,0:24:52.87,0:24:53.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是犯人
Dialogue: 0,0:24:53.54,0:24:54.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,吃了
Dialogue: 0,0:24:54.20,0:24:54.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么
