[Script Info]
;  This is an Advanced Sub Station Alpha v4+ script.
;  For Sub Station Alpha info and downloads,
;  go to http://www.eswat.demon.co.uk/
;  or email kotus@eswat.demon.co.uk
;  
;  Advanced Sub Station Alpha script format developed by #Anime-Fansubs@EfNET
;  http://www.anime-fansubs.org
;  
;  For additional info and downloads go to http://vobsub.edensrising.com/
;  or email gabest@freemail.hu
;  
;  Note: This file was saved by Subresync.
;  
; // 此字幕由PopSub生成  2007-12-10 22:10:43
; // 版本: 0.75
; // popgo_fansub@yahoo.co.jp
; // 欢迎访问漫游天下 http://bbs.popgo.net
Title:漫游字幕
Original Script:漫游字幕组
Synch Point:0
ScriptType:v4.00+
Collisions:Normal
PlayResX:384
PlayResY:288
Timer:100.0000

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,文鼎新艺体简,14,&H00FFFFFF,&H0000FFFF,&H00000000,&H80000000,0,0,0,0,100,100,0,0.00,1,1,1,2,20,20,10,1

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Actor, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text



Dialogue: 0,0:00:02.10,0:00:03.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,挡住去路的巨墙
Dialogue: 0,0:00:03.60,0:00:05.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,换个思考的角度就是一扇大门
Dialogue: 0,0:00:05.20,0:00:07.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,时尚的奇幻表演中发生事件
Dialogue: 0,0:00:07.20,0:00:09.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,舞台上神秘的双重机关引发的谜
Dialogue: 0,0:00:09.70,0:00:11.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看清惟一真相的是
Dialogue: 0,0:00:11.10,0:00:12.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,外表看似小孩 头脑却是大人
Dialogue: 0,0:00:12.60,0:00:14.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他的名字就是 名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:01:43.70,0:01:46.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个看上去很华丽呢
Dialogue: 0,0:01:47.30,0:01:49.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是小兰姐姐最喜欢的
Dialogue: 0,0:01:49.20,0:01:51.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,阴森恐怖的广告牌呢
Dialogue: 0,0:01:52.80,0:01:54.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是的 柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:01:54.50,0:01:56.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说起冬城幻阳的魔术
Dialogue: 0,0:01:57.00,0:02:00.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,与真田一三的阳光型表演截然相反
Dialogue: 0,0:02:00.10,0:02:02.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,舞台上始终充满着阴森诡异的气息
Dialogue: 0,0:02:02.50,0:02:06.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这位冬城先生为什么急着要见爸爸呢
Dialogue: 0,0:02:06.10,0:02:07.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,总之先去看看吧
Dialogue: 0,0:02:15.00,0:02:20.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,诡计VS魔术（前篇）
Dialogue: 0,0:02:23.70,0:02:24.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请进
Dialogue: 0,0:02:24.40,0:02:25.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,打扰了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:27.60,0:02:29.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是毛利先生啊
Dialogue: 0,0:02:29.50,0:02:31.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要您这位名侦探特地来跑一趟
Dialogue: 0,0:02:31.70,0:02:33.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是不好意思
Dialogue: 0,0:02:33.20,0:02:34.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是冬城
Dialogue: 0,0:02:35.30,0:02:36.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是毛利
Dialogue: 0,0:02:37.00,0:02:38.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是我女儿
Dialogue: 0,0:02:38.60,0:02:41.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,您好 我叫毛利兰
Dialogue: 0,0:02:41.40,0:02:43.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是寄住在我家的柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:02:43.50,0:02:44.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,寄住
Dialogue: 0,0:02:45.50,0:02:46.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是多余
Dialogue: 0,0:02:47.20,0:02:48.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,您好
Dialogue: 0,0:02:48.60,0:02:49.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉
Dialogue: 0,0:02:49.90,0:02:55.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他们听说我接到您的电话要过来就都想见见你
Dialogue: 0,0:02:55.20,0:02:56.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没关系
Dialogue: 0,0:02:56.60,0:02:58.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们喜欢魔术吗
Dialogue: 0,0:02:59.60,0:03:00.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我很喜欢
Dialogue: 0,0:03:00.90,0:03:03.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们经常去看魔术表演
Dialogue: 0,0:03:04.80,0:03:08.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我要不这么说他怎么会带我来呢
Dialogue: 0,0:03:10.70,0:03:12.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么
Dialogue: 0,0:03:27.90,0:03:31.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么在这里表演这个
Dialogue: 0,0:03:44.30,0:03:45.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好厉害
Dialogue: 0,0:03:46.10,0:03:48.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,技术是没话说啦
Dialogue: 0,0:03:49.90,0:03:55.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,开门见山 我请毛利先生来不为别的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:55.60,0:04:00.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,事实上在团员之中 有人想取我的性命
Dialogue: 0,0:04:02.80,0:04:05.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想请毛利先生把那个人抓出来
Dialogue: 0,0:04:06.20,0:04:08.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,莫非有什么人恐吓过你
Dialogue: 0,0:04:09.10,0:04:13.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,最近在排练时曾有两次器械坠落
Dialogue: 0,0:04:13.50,0:04:14.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,差点就…
Dialogue: 0,0:04:15.60,0:04:18.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果只有一次还可能是意外
Dialogue: 0,0:04:18.70,0:04:20.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,连续两次的话就…
Dialogue: 0,0:04:20.80,0:04:22.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个时候你周围有什么人吗
Dialogue: 0,0:04:23.00,0:04:24.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有 只有我自己
Dialogue: 0,0:04:25.30,0:04:27.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,团员除了冬城先生您之外还有几个人
Dialogue: 0,0:04:28.00,0:04:30.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小孩子提什么问题
Dialogue: 0,0:04:32.40,0:04:34.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉 团员有几个人
Dialogue: 0,0:04:34.90,0:04:37.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,除我之外还有5名团员
Dialogue: 0,0:04:43.30,0:04:45.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,首先是我的助手上原美佐
Dialogue: 0,0:04:46.90,0:04:48.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她是我的前女友
Dialogue: 0,0:04:48.70,0:04:52.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,3年前我单方面取消婚约
Dialogue: 0,0:04:52.30,0:04:53.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到现在她都怀恨在心
Dialogue: 0,0:04:54.50,0:04:56.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你单方面吗
Dialogue: 0,0:04:57.60,0:05:00.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接着是同为助手的中川千明
Dialogue: 0,0:05:01.40,0:05:02.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她是我的前妻
Dialogue: 0,0:05:03.00,0:05:04.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,去年协议离婚了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:05.00,0:05:08.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她现在仍在恨我曾经多次出轨
Dialogue: 0,0:05:09.50,0:05:13.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后是负责摄像的石田一马
Dialogue: 0,0:05:13.70,0:05:15.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他是我的得意弟子
Dialogue: 0,0:05:15.30,0:05:18.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了使他更好地学习魔术我让他负责摄像
Dialogue: 0,0:05:19.20,0:05:20.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,负责摄像啊
Dialogue: 0,0:05:20.60,0:05:24.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他有当魔术师的潜质 是个老实的好孩子
Dialogue: 0,0:05:24.30,0:05:25.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只有他我不相信会做这种事
Dialogue: 0,0:05:26.50,0:05:29.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在他旁边的是舞台监督庄司真吾
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.90,0:05:32.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他曾经是我的师兄
Dialogue: 0,0:05:32.10,0:05:35.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为没有魔术的才能所以我雇他来负责舞台监督
Dialogue: 0,0:05:36.90,0:05:40.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是在演出方面他总是和我意见不合
Dialogue: 0,0:05:41.00,0:05:43.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我打算这次公演结束后就不让他做了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:43.80,0:05:45.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是解雇吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:45.40,0:05:46.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:47.00,0:05:49.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,最后一位是负责道具升降的长谷川实
Dialogue: 0,0:05:50.10,0:05:53.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他热衷赌博 向我借了很多钱
Dialogue: 0,0:05:53.20,0:05:56.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果我死了赌债就能一笔勾销
Dialogue: 0,0:05:57.30,0:06:00.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说 有杀害我的动机的人是
Dialogue: 0,0:06:00.70,0:06:04.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,除石田一马之外的4个人
Dialogue: 0,0:06:04.80,0:06:06.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:06:08.20,0:06:09.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生
Dialogue: 0,0:06:09.40,0:06:10.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:06:10.60,0:06:14.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是今晚演出的门票
Dialogue: 0,0:06:15.80,0:06:19.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然我想演出过程中还不至于发生这种事
Dialogue: 0,0:06:19.60,0:06:22.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但其中也有几个性命攸关的节目
Dialogue: 0,0:06:22.60,0:06:25.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们来决定一下发生紧急情况时的信号吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:25.70,0:06:26.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,信号
Dialogue: 0,0:06:27.10,0:06:29.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,当我做这个手势时
Dialogue: 0,0:06:30.00,0:06:34.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,即使是在演出当中也请立刻上台来救我
Dialogue: 0,0:06:34.70,0:06:38.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是 既然如此还是取消公演比较好
Dialogue: 0,0:06:38.60,0:06:40.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那不可能
Dialogue: 0,0:06:40.30,0:06:44.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我有作为一个职业魔术师的尊严
Dialogue: 0,0:06:45.40,0:06:46.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:46.80,0:06:50.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么作为一个职业侦探我也会尽我所能
Dialogue: 0,0:06:50.80,0:06:51.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,拜托了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:52.20,0:06:54.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请千万别让团员们察觉
Dialogue: 0,0:06:55.00,0:06:56.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好的
Dialogue: 0,0:06:58.20,0:07:00.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,离演出开始还有一段时间
Dialogue: 0,0:07:01.40,0:07:03.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们要不要去哪里
Dialogue: 0,0:07:04.40,0:07:05.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了 小兰
Dialogue: 0,0:07:07.60,0:07:11.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小兰姐姐 你是不是对冬城先生很失望
Dialogue: 0,0:07:14.30,0:07:17.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说什么单方面取消婚约
Dialogue: 0,0:07:17.60,0:07:20.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,多次出轨导致离婚
Dialogue: 0,0:07:20.20,0:07:22.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还一副若无其事的样子
Dialogue: 0,0:07:23.50,0:07:26.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大人的世界是很复杂的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:26.60,0:07:29.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔的世界也很复杂啊
Dialogue: 0,0:07:30.40,0:07:31.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:07:32.20,0:07:33.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好痛
Dialogue: 0,0:07:33.20,0:07:34.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你少多嘴
Dialogue: 0,0:07:35.00,0:07:36.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,总之我去工作了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:37.00,0:07:39.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们随便上哪里去消磨时间吧
Dialogue: 0,0:07:39.30,0:07:40.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明白吗
Dialogue: 0,0:07:41.60,0:07:43.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南你不要紧吧
Dialogue: 0,0:07:46.80,0:07:50.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果说在演出过程中发生案件的话
Dialogue: 0,0:07:50.50,0:07:52.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,最大的可能是对道具做手脚
Dialogue: 0,0:07:55.30,0:07:56.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么你会在这里
Dialogue: 0,0:07:57.20,0:07:58.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来是这样的啊
Dialogue: 0,0:07:59.50,0:08:01.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你把我的话当耳边风吗
Dialogue: 0,0:08:02.10,0:08:02.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有人来了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:03.70,0:08:05.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,糟了 快躲起来 柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:08:05.90,0:08:06.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这边
Dialogue: 0,0:08:07.80,0:08:08.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快躺到那上面去
Dialogue: 0,0:08:09.00,0:08:10.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我帮你盖起来
Dialogue: 0,0:08:11.10,0:08:12.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗 好吧
Dialogue: 0,0:08:14.90,0:08:19.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南 这是不是分身魔术用的啊
Dialogue: 0,0:08:19.60,0:08:22.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没关系 我会帮你再接上的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:22.90,0:08:24.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 我的意思是…
Dialogue: 0,0:08:24.70,0:08:25.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把脚缩进去
Dialogue: 0,0:08:25.60,0:08:26.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,0:08:26.70,0:08:27.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,来了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:29.30,0:08:32.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毛利小五郎 是那个侦探吗
Dialogue: 0,0:08:32.10,0:08:33.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错 好像雇了他
Dialogue: 0,0:08:34.30,0:08:36.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他打电话时我听到了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:37.60,0:08:39.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你觉得他会认为是谁做的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:39.70,0:08:40.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谁知道
Dialogue: 0,0:08:40.90,0:08:43.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过既然要做就得动动脑筋
Dialogue: 0,0:08:43.70,0:08:44.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是
Dialogue: 0,0:08:44.70,0:08:46.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果我和你联手
Dialogue: 0,0:08:46.60,0:08:48.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,保证万无一失
Dialogue: 0,0:08:50.50,0:08:52.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们在说什么傻话
Dialogue: 0,0:08:53.70,0:08:56.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,团长的确在生活方面不太检点
Dialogue: 0,0:08:57.00,0:09:00.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但我们不都是靠他才能吃饱饭
Dialogue: 0,0:09:00.60,0:09:03.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊 应该感谢老师才对
Dialogue: 0,0:09:04.20,0:09:05.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么呢
Dialogue: 0,0:09:05.60,0:09:09.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你会帮他说话还不是因为欠了他一屁股债
Dialogue: 0,0:09:09.90,0:09:11.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,鸡婆
Dialogue: 0,0:09:11.70,0:09:15.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一马也是 其实内心很恨冬城吧
Dialogue: 0,0:09:16.00,0:09:19.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不知何时他才会让你作为魔术师站在舞台上
Dialogue: 0,0:09:20.50,0:09:22.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我才没有恨他
Dialogue: 0,0:09:23.10,0:09:23.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,走吧
Dialogue: 0,0:09:25.50,0:09:28.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我说你也该刮一下胡子了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:28.90,0:09:30.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一副穷相
Dialogue: 0,0:09:35.10,0:09:36.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请等一下
Dialogue: 0,0:09:37.80,0:09:38.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你算老几啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:45.90,0:09:46.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可恶
Dialogue: 0,0:09:51.40,0:09:52.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔 不要紧吧
Dialogue: 0,0:09:54.20,0:09:56.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么可能不要紧
Dialogue: 0,0:09:58.00,0:09:59.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真倒霉
Dialogue: 0,0:10:00.10,0:10:00.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔
Dialogue: 0,0:10:01.00,0:10:04.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个魔术关键是要仰面躺着把脚曲在身前
Dialogue: 0,0:10:05.10,0:10:07.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,仰面躺着 把脚曲在身前
Dialogue: 0,0:10:09.00,0:10:12.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样一来 就算箱子被切成两半也没关系
Dialogue: 0,0:10:12.70,0:10:14.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是 是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:10:14.20,0:10:20.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过现在所有团员都有了杀害冬城先生的动机
Dialogue: 0,0:10:20.50,0:10:23.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要小心行事了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:23.40,0:10:24.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,0:10:25.20,0:10:27.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你不检查魔术用的道具了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:10:28.10,0:10:29.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那种东西再怎么看也没用
Dialogue: 0,0:10:30.00,0:10:31.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,走了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:47.20,0:11:50.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,各位 欢迎来到冬城幻阳的魔术世界
Dialogue: 0,0:11:51.00,0:11:56.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今晚请沉醉于这光怪陆离的奇幻世界里吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:57.60,0:12:00.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么嘛 还是很陶醉啊
Dialogue: 0,0:12:31.00,0:12:32.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,天哪
Dialogue: 0,0:12:34.70,0:12:35.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,惨了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:44.20,0:12:45.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会吧
Dialogue: 0,0:12:46.70,0:12:47.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,太好了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:19.30,0:13:20.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好厉害啊 爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:13:21.70,0:13:24.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不愧是投飞刀的高手啊
Dialogue: 0,0:13:24.10,0:13:27.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生只是做了投刀的动作而已
Dialogue: 0,0:13:27.60,0:13:28.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:13:28.80,0:13:30.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 刀子明明插在那里
Dialogue: 0,0:13:31.00,0:13:34.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只是看上去如此 用了特殊的手法
Dialogue: 0,0:13:35.30,0:13:38.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我刚才看到了 在后台的仓库里
Dialogue: 0,0:13:40.60,0:13:42.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是和叔叔躲起来的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:13:42.80,0:13:44.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:13:47.20,0:13:48.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下面的节目就要开始了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:01.00,0:14:02.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那些刺是真的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:02.70,0:14:06.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被那个刺到的话可就血肉模糊了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:06.90,0:14:09.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那些皮带只是用魔术胶带固定的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:10.10,0:14:11.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一旦放下幕帘
Dialogue: 0,0:14:12.00,0:14:14.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他就会从道具旁的狭小空间逃出去
Dialogue: 0,0:14:20.80,0:14:22.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚才的是信号吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:22.40,0:14:23.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:14:23.50,0:14:24.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也是这么想的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:28.00,0:14:29.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等等
Dialogue: 0,0:14:54.10,0:14:55.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚才的是信号吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:55.80,0:14:56.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:14:57.10,0:14:58.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也是这么想的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:58.40,0:14:59.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等等
Dialogue: 0,0:15:07.60,0:15:08.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生
Dialogue: 0,0:15:10.20,0:15:11.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:15:17.40,0:15:18.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生
Dialogue: 0,0:15:36.40,0:15:41.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这不是名侦探毛利小五郎先生吗
Dialogue: 0,0:15:45.00,0:15:46.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有什么案件发生了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:15:47.50,0:15:48.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有
Dialogue: 0,0:15:48.50,0:15:53.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看来毛利先生是以为我被这两位美女给杀害了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:53.10,0:15:54.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以才立刻飞奔了过来呢
Dialogue: 0,0:15:55.60,0:15:57.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过请放心
Dialogue: 0,0:15:57.30,0:15:59.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,正如您所见我活得好好的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:00.20,0:16:02.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好 好像是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:16:06.20,0:16:08.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过我们也不能掉以轻心啊
Dialogue: 0,0:16:08.50,0:16:11.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为下半场还有性命攸关的惊险演出呢
Dialogue: 0,0:16:12.20,0:16:14.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还请您多多关照
Dialogue: 0,0:16:14.50,0:16:15.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哪里 彼此彼此
Dialogue: 0,0:16:17.30,0:16:20.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请大家为毛利先生热情地鼓掌吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:20.90,0:16:22.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,多谢 多谢
Dialogue: 0,0:16:25.60,0:16:27.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是太不好意思了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:27.90,0:16:31.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生您是不是能看清我发出的信号
Dialogue: 0,0:16:32.00,0:16:34.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,当时突然想确认一下
Dialogue: 0,0:16:34.10,0:16:36.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是您搞得我神经高度紧张
Dialogue: 0,0:16:36.80,0:16:39.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且还让我出了那么大的洋相
Dialogue: 0,0:16:39.70,0:16:41.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是非常抱歉
Dialogue: 0,0:16:41.40,0:16:43.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过确实有人想在舞台上取我的性命
Dialogue: 0,0:16:44.10,0:16:46.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下半场开始后就会有危险…
Dialogue: 0,0:16:48.10,0:16:50.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城 那个魔术是怎么回事啊
Dialogue: 0,0:16:50.00,0:16:53.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,钢板下面流了那么多血
Dialogue: 0,0:16:53.70,0:16:55.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在我的演出设计里并没有啊
Dialogue: 0,0:16:55.00,0:16:58.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是我的主意
Dialogue: 0,0:16:58.70,0:17:02.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是连名侦探也被成功地骗过了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:17:03.70,0:17:05.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这根本是两回事
Dialogue: 0,0:17:06.00,0:17:10.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我所追求的是在终极的恐怖里还要具备华丽优雅
Dialogue: 0,0:17:10.30,0:17:10.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一马
Dialogue: 0,0:17:11.90,0:17:12.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:17:20.00,0:17:21.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,庄司先生
Dialogue: 0,0:17:21.30,0:17:23.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从现在开始不再需要华丽优雅了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:24.60,0:17:29.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我打算用一种更刺激更令人兴奋的方式来演出
Dialogue: 0,0:17:30.60,0:17:32.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那就随便你吧
Dialogue: 0,0:17:32.50,0:17:34.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过你那种并不是刺激
Dialogue: 0,0:17:35.00,0:17:36.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只是一种变态
Dialogue: 0,0:17:40.50,0:17:42.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思让您见笑了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:48.60,0:17:49.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你有什么事
Dialogue: 0,0:17:52.40,0:17:53.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 没什么
Dialogue: 0,0:18:08.50,0:18:10.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:10.90,0:18:12.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,上厕所到现在还没回来
Dialogue: 0,0:18:13.60,0:18:14.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,随他去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:14.90,0:18:17.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,现在更重要的是紧盯着冬城先生
Dialogue: 0,0:18:17.60,0:18:20.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我总有一种非常不好的预感
Dialogue: 0,0:18:25.30,0:18:28.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在这里 不管发生了什么都能立刻采取行动
Dialogue: 0,0:18:44.90,0:18:47.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小朋友 你不能在这里看演出
Dialogue: 0,0:18:47.80,0:18:49.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快点回到座位上去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:49.80,0:18:50.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是
Dialogue: 0,0:18:51.80,0:18:52.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,走吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:53.10,0:18:54.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,0:19:44.00,0:19:44.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:19:45.00,0:19:46.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没事 那只是表演而已
Dialogue: 0,0:19:46.80,0:19:48.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他并没有给我任何信号
Dialogue: 0,0:20:18.80,0:20:20.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,已经过去很久了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:20.50,0:20:21.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没关系的
Dialogue: 0,0:20:21.90,0:20:23.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个魔术就是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:20:23.60,0:20:24.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也许…
Dialogue: 0,0:20:25.10,0:20:27.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,幕帘再次拉上去的话
Dialogue: 0,0:20:27.00,0:20:29.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生就已经站在水箱上面了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:47.10,0:20:47.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:20:52.10,0:20:53.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,糟了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:54.40,0:20:55.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可恶
Dialogue: 0,0:21:05.60,0:21:07.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生 冬城先生
Dialogue: 0,0:21:07.70,0:21:08.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们都在干什么啊
Dialogue: 0,0:21:09.00,0:21:10.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赶快将下面的锁打开
Dialogue: 0,0:21:14.00,0:21:15.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,中川 把大幕放下来
Dialogue: 0,0:21:16.40,0:21:18.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,长谷川 把盖子升上去
Dialogue: 0,0:21:29.70,0:21:30.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,出了什么事吗
Dialogue: 0,0:21:31.70,0:21:33.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,救护车 快去叫救护车
Dialogue: 0,0:21:34.80,0:21:35.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生
Dialogue: 0,0:21:36.40,0:21:37.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生
Dialogue: 0,0:21:37.80,0:21:38.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生
Dialogue: 0,0:21:39.40,0:21:41.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生 快给他做人工呼吸
Dialogue: 0,0:21:42.10,0:21:43.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生
Dialogue: 0,0:21:46.30,0:21:48.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生 冬城先生
Dialogue: 0,0:21:55.00,0:21:56.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,团长
Dialogue: 0,0:21:56.90,0:21:57.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,团长
Dialogue: 0,0:21:58.10,0:21:59.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,团长
Dialogue: 0,0:21:59.30,0:21:59.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生
Dialogue: 0,0:21:59.80,0:22:00.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,团长
Dialogue: 0,0:22:00.70,0:22:02.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生
Dialogue: 0,0:22:02.90,0:22:03.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生
Dialogue: 0,0:22:04.10,0:22:04.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,团长
Dialogue: 0,0:22:04.20,0:22:06.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,振作一点啊 冬城
Dialogue: 0,0:22:05.30,0:22:06.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冬城先生
Dialogue: 0,0:23:47.00,0:23:48.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就算是为了案情的调查
Dialogue: 0,0:23:49.20,0:23:51.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也不能告诉你们魔术的内幕啊
Dialogue: 0,0:23:52.30,0:23:54.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这件事 怎么说呢
Dialogue: 0,0:23:55.60,0:23:58.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们是说不出口的
Dialogue: 0,0:23:58.60,0:23:59.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想起来了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:59.70,0:24:00.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个魔术
Dialogue: 0,0:24:04.90,0:24:06.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个搭扣
Dialogue: 0,0:24:06.70,0:24:07.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我明白了
Dialogue: 0,0:24:07.90,0:24:09.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接下去就是证据
Dialogue: 0,0:24:11.10,0:24:12.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,NEXT CONAN
Dialogue: 0,0:24:12.50,0:24:15.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,诡计VS魔术（后篇）
Dialogue: 0,0:24:18.00,0:24:19.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,NEXT CONAN'S HINT
Dialogue: 0,0:24:20.10,0:24:21.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,搭扣
Dialogue: 0,0:24:22.40,0:24:23.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下一集诡计就真相大白了
Dialogue: 0,0:24:23.70,0:24:25.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,案件 还是魔术
Dialogue: 0,0:24:25.50,0:24:26.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不告诉你
