[Script Info]
;  This is an Advanced Sub Station Alpha v4+ script.
;  For Sub Station Alpha info and downloads,
;  go to http://www.eswat.demon.co.uk/
;  or email kotus@eswat.demon.co.uk
;  
;  Advanced Sub Station Alpha script format developed by #Anime-Fansubs@EfNET
;  http://www.anime-fansubs.org
;  
;  For additional info and downloads go to http://vobsub.edensrising.com/
;  or email gabest@freemail.hu
;  
;  Note: This file was saved by Subresync.
;  
; // 此字幕由PopSub生成  2007-12-10 23:08:02
; // 版本: 0.75
; // popgo_fansub@yahoo.co.jp
; // 欢迎访问漫游天下 http://bbs.popgo.net
Title:漫游字幕
Original Script:漫游字幕组
Synch Point:0
ScriptType:v4.00+
Collisions:Normal
PlayResX:384
PlayResY:288
Timer:100.0000

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,文鼎新艺体简,14,&H00FFFFFF,&H0000FFFF,&H00000000,&H80000000,0,0,0,0,100,100,0,0.00,1,1,1,2,20,20,10,1

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Actor, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text



Dialogue: 0,0:00:02.10,0:00:03.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,挡住去路的巨墙
Dialogue: 0,0:00:03.55,0:00:05.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,换个思考的角度就是一扇大门
Dialogue: 0,0:00:05.36,0:00:06.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天是1小时特别节目
Dialogue: 0,0:00:06.89,0:00:08.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,久违的旅行剧团
Dialogue: 0,0:00:08.13,0:00:09.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,金毗罗舞台上的怪人骚动
Dialogue: 0,0:00:09.92,0:00:11.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看清惟一真相的是
Dialogue: 0,0:00:11.32,0:00:12.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,外表看似小孩 头脑却是大人
Dialogue: 0,0:00:12.80,0:00:14.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他的名字就是 名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:01:44.46,0:01:45.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,神清气爽啊
Dialogue: 0,0:01:46.09,0:01:48.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,能这么悠闲真不错呢
Dialogue: 0,0:01:49.72,0:01:52.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗓子好干 真想来杯啤酒啊
Dialogue: 0,0:01:53.52,0:01:56.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸真是的 难得来一趟四国
Dialogue: 0,0:01:56.80,0:01:58.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,比起喝酒来
Dialogue: 0,0:01:58.02,0:01:59.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,更应该吃赞岐乌冬面
Dialogue: 0,0:02:00.81,0:02:02.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:02.24,0:02:05.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过吃面之前就稍微润润嗓子吧
Dialogue: 0,0:02:05.61,0:02:06.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那样的话
Dialogue: 0,0:02:06.85,0:02:09.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,搞不好演出时你看着看着就睡着了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:09.38,0:02:10.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是就是
Dialogue: 0,0:02:10.24,0:02:13.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难得玉之助邀请我们
Dialogue: 0,0:02:13.71,0:02:15.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:16.14,0:02:21.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,玉之助他们演出的那个金丸座非常有名吧
Dialogue: 0,0:02:21.67,0:02:22.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错
Dialogue: 0,0:02:22.93,0:02:27.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,每年春天上演的四国金毗罗歌舞伎大戏
Dialogue: 0,0:02:27.22,0:02:30.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,都吸引了来自全国各地的大量观众
Dialogue: 0,0:02:33.56,0:02:34.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看啊看啊
Dialogue: 0,0:02:34.62,0:02:36.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真的好壮观
Dialogue: 0,0:02:36.80,0:02:38.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是好期待啊
Dialogue: 0,0:02:40.88,0:02:42.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,金毗罗剧院的怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:02:47.87,0:02:50.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这就是推荐的乌冬面馆啊
Dialogue: 0,0:02:50.20,0:02:51.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是普通的民宅吗
Dialogue: 0,0:02:52.70,0:02:54.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,欢迎光临
Dialogue: 0,0:02:55.52,0:02:56.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快看这个
Dialogue: 0,0:02:57.31,0:02:59.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是下酒的小菜吧
Dialogue: 0,0:02:59.25,0:03:01.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是面条的佐菜啦 爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:03:01.96,0:03:03.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,久等了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:04.29,0:03:05.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,来了来了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:05.17,0:03:07.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,天麸罗就摆在那边 请任意品尝
Dialogue: 0,0:03:07.76,0:03:08.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:13.23,0:03:14.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好吃
Dialogue: 0,0:03:16.46,0:03:18.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,面条筋道 口感爽滑
Dialogue: 0,0:03:18.14,0:03:19.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是地道的美味啊
Dialogue: 0,0:03:20.83,0:03:22.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看上去很不错啊
Dialogue: 0,0:03:23.01,0:03:24.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么我也要去挑战
Dialogue: 0,0:03:24.78,0:03:25.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,挑战什么
Dialogue: 0,0:03:25.92,0:03:27.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个啦 那个
Dialogue: 0,0:03:29.00,0:03:32.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赞岐乌冬面边走边吃的挑战
Dialogue: 0,0:03:33.79,0:03:35.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那边的两位小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:03:35.61,0:03:37.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请用这些竹杖吧
Dialogue: 0,0:03:38.17,0:03:40.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,回来时请记得归还哦
Dialogue: 0,0:03:40.20,0:03:40.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢
Dialogue: 0,0:03:41.02,0:03:42.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,非常感谢
Dialogue: 0,0:03:43.02,0:03:44.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,用什么竹杖啊
Dialogue: 0,0:03:44.58,0:03:46.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,又不是老年人
Dialogue: 0,0:03:52.34,0:03:55.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到底有多少级台阶啊
Dialogue: 0,0:03:55.22,0:04:00.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个 到山顶的御本宫好像一共有785级
Dialogue: 0,0:04:01.07,0:04:02.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,700…
Dialogue: 0,0:04:02.32,0:04:03.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,85
Dialogue: 0,0:04:05.55,0:04:06.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,轻松啊轻松
Dialogue: 0,0:04:06.97,0:04:08.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一早就该说啊
Dialogue: 0,0:04:08.77,0:04:10.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有这么方便的东西
Dialogue: 0,0:04:12.70,0:04:14.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸呢
Dialogue: 0,0:04:14.06,0:04:14.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在那边
Dialogue: 0,0:04:15.27,0:04:17.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真好喝
Dialogue: 0,0:04:17.64,0:04:20.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这种本地酒果然非同一般啊
Dialogue: 0,0:04:20.64,0:04:21.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:04:22.79,0:04:24.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你不准备去参拜了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:04:24.40,0:04:27.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉 我那一份也拜托你了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:28.08,0:04:30.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,反正金丸座就在前面不远嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:04:30.88,0:04:32.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我在这里等你们
Dialogue: 0,0:04:32.36,0:04:34.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,老板娘 再来一壶
Dialogue: 0,0:04:34.10,0:04:37.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是还想挑战乌冬面边走边吃吗
Dialogue: 0,0:04:49.23,0:04:50.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,终于到了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:50.97,0:04:54.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,轿子只能坐到半途 太过分了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:54.08,0:04:55.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你好慢啊 园子姐姐
Dialogue: 0,0:04:55.82,0:04:59.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在下面休息不就好了嘛 和我爸爸一起
Dialogue: 0,0:04:59.12,0:05:01.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喂喂 别把我当成他那样的人
Dialogue: 0,0:05:01.98,0:05:04.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,金毗罗神是海之守护神吧
Dialogue: 0,0:05:05.15,0:05:06.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是呢
Dialogue: 0,0:05:06.06,0:05:09.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这上面说在海上谋生的人都信奉这个神
Dialogue: 0,0:05:11.59,0:05:12.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,时间差不多要到了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:12.87,0:05:14.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快到金丸座去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:05:14.24,0:05:15.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我期待好久了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:15.76,0:05:18.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,玉之助是不是一切都还好呢
Dialogue: 0,0:05:18.55,0:05:19.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有莲华
Dialogue: 0,0:05:19.84,0:05:22.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对 问题就出在这里
Dialogue: 0,0:05:22.69,0:05:25.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那两个人是不是还那么恩爱呢
Dialogue: 0,0:05:25.91,0:05:28.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他可是我的目标啊 玉之助
Dialogue: 0,0:05:28.23,0:05:29.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,园子你真是的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:31.17,0:05:32.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,见一个爱一个啊
Dialogue: 0,0:05:38.58,0:05:39.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,欢迎各位
Dialogue: 0,0:05:40.03,0:05:42.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,远道而来辛苦了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:43.54,0:05:44.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这可不妙啊
Dialogue: 0,0:05:44.90,0:05:46.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那两个人
Dialogue: 0,0:05:46.36,0:05:48.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一看就知道还是那么要好
Dialogue: 0,0:05:49.43,0:05:50.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:05:51.09,0:05:52.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小惠
Dialogue: 0,0:05:52.91,0:05:53.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你好啊
Dialogue: 0,0:05:55.26,0:05:56.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:56.40,0:05:58.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天那群坏孩子没跟来呢
Dialogue: 0,0:05:59.34,0:06:00.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那些家伙啊
Dialogue: 0,0:06:00.57,0:06:02.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他们都恰好有事
Dialogue: 0,0:06:02.87,0:06:04.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,太好了 我太高兴了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:04.95,0:06:06.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等等 小惠…
Dialogue: 0,0:06:06.26,0:06:09.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个四眼小鬼头 挺受欢迎的嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:06:09.74,0:06:10.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你这家伙
Dialogue: 0,0:06:10.86,0:06:12.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:06:13.99,0:06:15.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请进
Dialogue: 0,0:06:15.53,0:06:16.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是躏口（注：一种矮门）
Dialogue: 0,0:06:16.78,0:06:18.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小心不要碰到头
Dialogue: 0,0:06:19.01,0:06:20.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,躏口是什么东西
Dialogue: 0,0:06:22.07,0:06:22.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好痛
Dialogue: 0,0:06:22.76,0:06:24.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:06:24.03,0:06:25.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没事吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:26.11,0:06:27.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,果然撞了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:30.21,0:06:31.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还在做开演前的准备
Dialogue: 0,0:06:31.97,0:06:33.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有点乱
Dialogue: 0,0:06:35.29,0:06:36.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真棒啊
Dialogue: 0,0:06:37.70,0:06:41.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,舞台上正好在调试升降装置
Dialogue: 0,0:06:41.87,0:06:42.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,升降装置
Dialogue: 0,0:06:43.25,0:06:46.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是由地下的人共同抬起来的哦
Dialogue: 0,0:06:46.54,0:06:49.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,演员从那里出场 摆出造型
Dialogue: 0,0:06:49.70,0:06:51.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,舞台在转动
Dialogue: 0,0:06:51.38,0:06:52.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是旋转舞台
Dialogue: 0,0:06:53.17,0:06:56.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,同样也是有人在地下推动的
Dialogue: 0,0:06:56.56,0:06:58.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,用的是和以前一样的方式
Dialogue: 0,0:06:58.42,0:07:00.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,另外 地下我们称之为奈落（地狱）
Dialogue: 0,0:07:01.19,0:07:02.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,过去地下容易积水
Dialogue: 0,0:07:03.10,0:07:04.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,工作人员很辛苦
Dialogue: 0,0:07:04.98,0:07:06.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以才起了这个名字
Dialogue: 0,0:07:07.13,0:07:09.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是花道
Dialogue: 0,0:07:09.44,0:07:14.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是演员出来后穿过观众走向舞台的通道
Dialogue: 0,0:07:15.44,0:07:17.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在花道中有一块叫鳖
Dialogue: 0,0:07:17.81,0:07:19.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,它与刚才的升降装置一样
Dialogue: 0,0:07:19.50,0:07:21.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也是从下面升起的机关
Dialogue: 0,0:07:21.47,0:07:23.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接下来是花道的正上方
Dialogue: 0,0:07:23.97,0:07:26.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,像起重机一样的是悬梁
Dialogue: 0,0:07:26.43,0:07:27.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,挂在它上面
Dialogue: 0,0:07:27.78,0:07:29.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,演员就能在空中飞舞
Dialogue: 0,0:07:29.17,0:07:30.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好厉害
Dialogue: 0,0:07:31.02,0:07:33.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,屋顶用竹子绑成了格子状
Dialogue: 0,0:07:33.80,0:07:36.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可以从那上面飘洒樱花
Dialogue: 0,0:07:38.21,0:07:40.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,仿佛坐时空机器回到了100年前
Dialogue: 0,0:07:40.47,0:07:41.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:41.76,0:07:43.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,何止100年啊
Dialogue: 0,0:07:43.92,0:07:48.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原本这个金丸座就是幕府末期的天保年间
Dialogue: 0,0:07:48.31,0:07:50.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,得到幕府的许可而建造的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:50.53,0:07:53.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是现存的日本最古老的剧院
Dialogue: 0,0:07:54.21,0:07:56.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,能在这里表演
Dialogue: 0,0:07:56.32,0:07:58.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是演员最大的荣耀呢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:58.93,0:08:01.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且两个人还是这么恩爱…
Dialogue: 0,0:08:02.05,0:08:03.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,园子
Dialogue: 0,0:08:03.67,0:08:08.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,听说今天要上演模仿《剧院魅影》情节的古装剧
Dialogue: 0,0:08:08.59,0:08:09.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错
Dialogue: 0,0:08:09.55,0:08:11.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,以华美的剧院为舞台
Dialogue: 0,0:08:11.58,0:08:16.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,用面具遮掩丑陋容貌的神秘怪人和可怜的歌姬
Dialogue: 0,0:08:17.12,0:08:22.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,围绕这对恋人展开的爱与恨的恐怖剧
Dialogue: 0,0:08:22.31,0:08:25.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有别于歌剧院的 金毗罗剧院的怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:08:40.13,0:08:42.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我所爱的女孩 歌唱吧
Dialogue: 0,0:08:42.31,0:08:44.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了深爱你的我
Dialogue: 0,0:08:44.57,0:08:46.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了音乐的天使
Dialogue: 0,0:08:46.46,0:08:48.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,放开嗓音 歌唱吧
Dialogue: 0,0:08:49.19,0:08:50.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,纯洁的天使
Dialogue: 0,0:08:50.88,0:08:52.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,光辉的天使
Dialogue: 0,0:08:52.50,0:08:55.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把我的灵魂带上蓝天
Dialogue: 0,0:08:55.74,0:08:57.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不要唱
Dialogue: 0,0:08:57.19,0:08:58.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,睁大眼睛
Dialogue: 0,0:08:58.36,0:08:59.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是恶魔
Dialogue: 0,0:08:59.60,0:09:00.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是冤魂
Dialogue: 0,0:09:02.66,0:09:03.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好帅
Dialogue: 0,0:09:05.34,0:09:06.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个人是谁
Dialogue: 0,0:09:06.71,0:09:10.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赞助本次演出的罗臼辰彦先生
Dialogue: 0,0:09:10.57,0:09:11.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赞助商啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:12.25,0:09:13.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,罗臼
Dialogue: 0,0:09:13.54,0:09:15.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,关西的罗臼集团啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:15.92,0:09:17.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,记得在报纸上看到过
Dialogue: 0,0:09:17.60,0:09:23.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,社长辞世 刚由年轻的儿子继承事业
Dialogue: 0,0:09:27.84,0:09:29.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会吧
Dialogue: 0,0:09:29.49,0:09:31.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,突然就对我…
Dialogue: 0,0:09:31.86,0:09:34.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你好 我是铃木园子
Dialogue: 0,0:09:35.38,0:09:36.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,加油 莲华
Dialogue: 0,0:09:36.48,0:09:38.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是 莲华
Dialogue: 0,0:09:39.92,0:09:42.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有我罗臼辰彦在支持你
Dialogue: 0,0:09:43.15,0:09:44.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢
Dialogue: 0,0:09:44.26,0:09:47.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过我出演的也不是什么重要角色
Dialogue: 0,0:09:47.64,0:09:49.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然如此 不过我还是觉得
Dialogue: 0,0:09:49.82,0:09:51.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,出演女主角歌姬的应该是你
Dialogue: 0,0:09:52.08,0:09:53.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要不将角色更换一下
Dialogue: 0,0:09:53.38,0:09:54.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,罗臼先生
Dialogue: 0,0:09:54.71,0:09:57.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,决定这个的是身为团长的我
Dialogue: 0,0:09:58.14,0:09:59.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,并不是你这位赞助商
Dialogue: 0,0:09:59.92,0:10:02.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,更不是那个怪人吧
Dialogue: 0,0:10:02.41,0:10:03.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错
Dialogue: 0,0:10:03.77,0:10:04.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:10:04.99,0:10:07.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是说你不会答应那个要求吧
Dialogue: 0,0:10:07.52,0:10:08.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是当然的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:09.15,0:10:13.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也只是想看青梅竹马在舞台上的华丽表演而已
Dialogue: 0,0:10:14.59,0:10:15.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要求
Dialogue: 0,0:10:16.00,0:10:17.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,更换女主角
Dialogue: 0,0:10:17.98,0:10:19.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,青梅竹马
Dialogue: 0,0:10:19.14,0:10:20.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,最后是怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:10:21.23,0:10:22.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这简直就是
Dialogue: 0,0:10:23.73,0:10:25.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,The phantom of the opera
Dialogue: 0,0:10:26.70,0:10:29.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和《剧院魅影》一模一样吗
Dialogue: 0,0:10:30.31,0:10:32.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,莲华的青梅竹马啊
Dialogue: 0,0:10:33.10,0:10:35.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是这样的话
Dialogue: 0,0:10:33.14,0:10:36.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我觉得你还是坦率一点比较好
Dialogue: 0,0:10:36.83,0:10:37.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,玉之助
Dialogue: 0,0:10:39.04,0:10:42.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是你对莲华的心意 你喜欢她吧
Dialogue: 0,0:10:42.40,0:10:44.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,罗 罗臼先生
Dialogue: 0,0:10:44.56,0:10:47.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,犹豫不决的话她会被我抢走的哦
Dialogue: 0,0:10:51.10,0:10:52.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,三角关系
Dialogue: 0,0:10:52.47,0:10:53.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,园子
Dialogue: 0,0:10:54.43,0:10:56.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是无所谓的 团长
Dialogue: 0,0:10:57.42,0:10:59.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要我跟莲华交换角色的话
Dialogue: 0,0:10:59.55,0:11:00.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你在说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:11:01.18,0:11:02.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请别开玩笑
Dialogue: 0,0:11:03.60,0:11:05.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我为什么请路美小姐你来
Dialogue: 0,0:11:06.04,0:11:07.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你应该明白呀
Dialogue: 0,0:11:07.45,0:11:08.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错
Dialogue: 0,0:11:09.01,0:11:10.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我一直都是路美小姐的忠实崇拜者
Dialogue: 0,0:11:11.10,0:11:13.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,能和你同台演出我就很幸福了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:14.98,0:11:15.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:16.84,0:11:18.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大美女
Dialogue: 0,0:11:18.36,0:11:20.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好像在哪里见过
Dialogue: 0,0:11:20.25,0:11:21.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,轻部路美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:11:21.58,0:11:23.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,著名的青年舞台剧演员
Dialogue: 0,0:11:24.20,0:11:26.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请您务必出演女主角
Dialogue: 0,0:11:26.12,0:11:27.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哥哥这样求过她
Dialogue: 0,0:11:27.60,0:11:30.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,本以为会被拒绝但她却一口答应了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:30.35,0:11:31.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让人大吃一惊呢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:32.43,0:11:34.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚才真是对不起了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:34.95,0:11:36.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请你加油吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:37.99,0:11:38.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:39.30,0:11:41.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看来我被人讨厌了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:45.49,0:11:48.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这里黑咕隆咚的还真是不习惯呢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:48.22,0:11:51.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谁来帮赞助商贴一个标识
Dialogue: 0,0:11:51.15,0:11:52.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,标识
Dialogue: 0,0:11:52.45,0:11:53.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这个吗
Dialogue: 0,0:11:54.51,0:11:56.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好脏的胶带
Dialogue: 0,0:11:56.37,0:11:57.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是荧光带
Dialogue: 0,0:11:57.88,0:11:58.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看
Dialogue: 0,0:11:58.65,0:12:00.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那里也有
Dialogue: 0,0:12:00.54,0:12:02.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真聪明啊 小朋友
Dialogue: 0,0:12:02.24,0:12:02.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错
Dialogue: 0,0:12:03.02,0:12:04.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是在安排舞台的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:12:04.56,0:12:07.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,方便演员明确自己的位置而贴的标识
Dialogue: 0,0:12:12.65,0:12:15.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么看都没有外人插一脚的余地了 园子
Dialogue: 0,0:12:15.99,0:12:17.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没关系
Dialogue: 0,0:12:17.80,0:12:19.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我已经找到另一个目标了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:19.37,0:12:20.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,另一个目标
Dialogue: 0,0:12:20.95,0:12:22.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,总算要开始排练了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:22.50,0:12:24.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这舞台还真是复杂啊
Dialogue: 0,0:12:24.18,0:12:24.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过
Dialogue: 0,0:12:25.03,0:12:27.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我只对自己的角色感兴趣
Dialogue: 0,0:12:27.83,0:12:29.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看起来酷极了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:30.07,0:12:31.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让开让开 挡着路了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:32.04,0:12:33.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:12:34.65,0:12:35.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谁让你们进来的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:35.56,0:12:37.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,演出还早着呢
Dialogue: 0,0:12:37.60,0:12:38.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个人真凶啊
Dialogue: 0,0:12:38.74,0:12:39.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,园子
Dialogue: 0,0:12:40.59,0:12:42.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉 锅岛先生 我忘了介绍
Dialogue: 0,0:12:43.32,0:12:45.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这位是侦探毛利小五郎先生
Dialogue: 0,0:12:46.41,0:12:47.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,侦探
Dialogue: 0,0:12:47.64,0:12:48.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毛利小五郎
Dialogue: 0,0:12:49.04,0:12:50.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个有名的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:52.30,0:12:55.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是 我就是那个有名的毛利小五郎
Dialogue: 0,0:12:55.33,0:12:57.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是他女儿 兰小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:12:57.66,0:12:58.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,初次见面
Dialogue: 0,0:12:58.92,0:12:59.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后是
Dialogue: 0,0:12:59.76,0:13:02.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我最喜欢的江户川柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:13:02.38,0:13:03.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们好
Dialogue: 0,0:13:03.88,0:13:04.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有
Dialogue: 0,0:13:04.82,0:13:07.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是可爱的铃木园子
Dialogue: 0,0:13:07.44,0:13:08.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请多关照
Dialogue: 0,0:13:10.70,0:13:11.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不管他们是谁
Dialogue: 0,0:13:11.66,0:13:13.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不要妨碍工作就行
Dialogue: 0,0:13:13.67,0:13:16.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,前任团长比你严格多了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:16.21,0:13:18.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,父亲是父亲 我是我
Dialogue: 0,0:13:19.47,0:13:20.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过
Dialogue: 0,0:13:20.17,0:13:23.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果没这份工作我会被追债追得团团转
Dialogue: 0,0:13:23.63,0:13:26.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以我对团长你还是很感激的
Dialogue: 0,0:13:27.23,0:13:28.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,走了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:28.06,0:13:28.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:13:29.01,0:13:30.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,别打扰人家排练
Dialogue: 0,0:13:34.63,0:13:36.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好 开始吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:36.72,0:13:37.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,莲华
Dialogue: 0,0:13:37.74,0:13:39.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,替我把漱口水拿来好吗
Dialogue: 0,0:13:39.70,0:13:40.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好的
Dialogue: 0,0:13:40.63,0:13:42.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南你们去观众席吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:42.21,0:13:43.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,0:13:55.93,0:13:56.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,危险
Dialogue: 0,0:14:03.13,0:14:03.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,路美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:14:04.78,0:14:05.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你没事吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:05.75,0:14:06.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,路美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:14:12.28,0:14:13.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,路美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:14:13.58,0:14:15.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:14:15.06,0:14:16.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快去叫救护车
Dialogue: 0,0:14:16.28,0:14:17.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叫救护车
Dialogue: 0,0:14:17.83,0:14:19.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不必了 团长
Dialogue: 0,0:14:20.10,0:14:21.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,别小题大做
Dialogue: 0,0:14:21.51,0:14:22.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我没什么大碍
Dialogue: 0,0:14:23.08,0:14:24.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,路美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:14:24.29,0:14:25.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只是轻微的擦伤
Dialogue: 0,0:14:26.13,0:14:29.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过这里的观众席离舞台很近
Dialogue: 0,0:14:29.83,0:14:31.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,布置道具时应该小心点
Dialogue: 0,0:14:32.11,0:14:32.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可恶
Dialogue: 0,0:14:32.81,0:14:33.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,开什么玩笑
Dialogue: 0,0:14:34.70,0:14:36.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是谁在这个节骨眼上干这种事
Dialogue: 0,0:14:37.00,0:14:38.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们快点让开
Dialogue: 0,0:14:38.88,0:14:41.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不抓紧把这东西修好就赶不上演出了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:42.13,0:14:43.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真过分
Dialogue: 0,0:14:43.58,0:14:44.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,犯人就是他
Dialogue: 0,0:14:45.13,0:14:46.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,园子
Dialogue: 0,0:14:46.20,0:14:47.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,总之要马上处理伤口
Dialogue: 0,0:14:47.79,0:14:49.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到后台去吧 路美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:14:50.78,0:14:54.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那根绳子有被利刃割过的痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:14:57.18,0:14:58.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是怪人干的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:59.06,0:15:00.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,胡说八道
Dialogue: 0,0:15:00.48,0:15:02.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那只是单纯的恶作剧
Dialogue: 0,0:15:02.54,0:15:04.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那这又怎么解释
Dialogue: 0,0:15:04.77,0:15:07.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,搞不好真的需要换女主角
Dialogue: 0,0:15:07.93,0:15:08.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不干
Dialogue: 0,0:15:09.61,0:15:11.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不知怎么我突然有了干劲
Dialogue: 0,0:15:12.30,0:15:15.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不能顺着怪人让他得逞
Dialogue: 0,0:15:15.03,0:15:16.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对吧 团长
Dialogue: 0,0:15:16.83,0:15:19.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉打扰你们的谈话
Dialogue: 0,0:15:19.82,0:15:21.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大家说的怪人是
Dialogue: 0,0:15:21.08,0:15:22.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是金毗罗剧院的怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:15:23.06,0:15:24.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以我说那是
Dialogue: 0,0:15:24.42,0:15:27.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那应该是本次剧目的名称吧
Dialogue: 0,0:15:27.34,0:15:28.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,金毗罗剧院的怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:15:29.01,0:15:30.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 所以说…
Dialogue: 0,0:15:30.83,0:15:31.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:31.66,0:15:33.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,吊灯 是吊灯
Dialogue: 0,0:15:33.37,0:15:34.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错
Dialogue: 0,0:15:35.28,0:15:36.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,吊灯
Dialogue: 0,0:15:36.43,0:15:40.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在这个剧本所参照的《剧院魅影》里
Dialogue: 0,0:15:42.85,0:15:46.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,第1个女主角就是被坠落的吊灯砸到的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:48.69,0:15:49.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不仅如此
Dialogue: 0,0:15:50.41,0:15:55.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大家的关系也和《剧院魅影》中的人物吻合
Dialogue: 0,0:15:55.96,0:16:00.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说起来刚才玉之助团长说过不会答应怪人的要求吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:01.48,0:16:02.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那也是一模一样的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:03.00,0:16:07.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在《剧院魅影》中怪人也要求更换女主角
Dialogue: 0,0:16:08.23,0:16:10.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到底是怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:16:10.28,0:16:14.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大家好像对我们隐瞒着什么
Dialogue: 0,0:16:15.74,0:16:17.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不愧是名侦探
Dialogue: 0,0:16:17.86,0:16:19.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,玉之助
Dialogue: 0,0:16:19.17,0:16:22.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还是跟毛利先生说一下情况比较好
Dialogue: 0,0:16:24.89,0:16:26.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:26.77,0:16:31.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,起初大家都认为这只是恶作剧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:36.01,0:16:38.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他并没有做什么
Dialogue: 0,0:16:38.45,0:16:42.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只是露出身影惊吓别人
Dialogue: 0,0:16:42.68,0:16:47.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 后来收到了10封这样的信
Dialogue: 0,0:16:50.55,0:16:53.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,全都是同样的内容啊
Dialogue: 0,0:16:53.89,0:16:56.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这到底是什么意思
Dialogue: 0,0:16:56.40,0:16:58.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,众多观众捧场
Dialogue: 0,0:16:58.45,0:16:59.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被刺 散花
Dialogue: 0,0:17:00.10,0:17:02.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赞岐金毗罗剧院的怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:17:02.88,0:17:07.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,众多观众捧场对于舞台演出来说不是很好吗
Dialogue: 0,0:17:07.13,0:17:10.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被刺 散花 也是戏剧中的场景吧
Dialogue: 0,0:17:10.96,0:17:12.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这会不会是暗号呢
Dialogue: 0,0:17:12.19,0:17:13.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赞岐语言
Dialogue: 0,0:17:14.17,0:17:15.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个你都知道啊 小弟弟
Dialogue: 0,0:17:15.75,0:17:17.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赞岐
Dialogue: 0,0:17:17.22,0:17:20.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,暗号异常简单反而让人起疑
Dialogue: 0,0:17:20.44,0:17:21.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赞岐
Dialogue: 0,0:17:22.74,0:17:24.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:17:24.19,0:17:26.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赞岐就是去掉さ啊（注：发音相同）
Dialogue: 0,0:17:26.43,0:17:29.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是把さ去掉再读
Dialogue: 0,0:17:29.53,0:17:30.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我看看
Dialogue: 0,0:17:31.00,0:17:34.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,先把汉字全部换成假名会比较容易看出来
Dialogue: 0,0:17:34.53,0:17:36.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后去掉さ是吧
Dialogue: 0,0:17:36.13,0:17:37.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么就变成
Dialogue: 0,0:17:38.01,0:17:39.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好厉害
Dialogue: 0,0:17:39.65,0:17:40.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,换女主角
Dialogue: 0,0:17:40.74,0:17:41.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让莲华来演
Dialogue: 0,0:17:41.77,0:17:45.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这 这是一封很明显的恐吓信
Dialogue: 0,0:17:45.55,0:17:49.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但如果总是介意这种东西就没法表演了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:49.38,0:17:50.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错
Dialogue: 0,0:17:50.62,0:17:53.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过 无视的话就会发生刚才的事故
Dialogue: 0,0:17:54.56,0:17:57.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说这并不是单纯的恐吓
Dialogue: 0,0:17:57.31,0:18:00.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看来 事情不会就此结束啊
Dialogue: 0,0:18:01.46,0:18:02.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,团长
Dialogue: 0,0:18:03.76,0:18:04.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我要演
Dialogue: 0,0:18:05.13,0:18:06.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只要路美小姐你愿意
Dialogue: 0,0:18:06.91,0:18:10.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果因为这点事就退缩也算不上演员了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:11.96,0:18:13.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没问题吧 毛利先生
Dialogue: 0,0:18:15.04,0:18:20.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,恐吓信和灯笼架倒下看起来没有直接的联系
Dialogue: 0,0:18:20.22,0:18:25.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,绳子的断裂究竟是不是人为造成的还需要详细调查
Dialogue: 0,0:18:25.83,0:18:26.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,的确
Dialogue: 0,0:18:27.09,0:18:29.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,现阶段即使警方有所行动
Dialogue: 0,0:18:30.22,0:18:35.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是否继续演出还是要由团长玉之助来决定
Dialogue: 0,0:18:36.14,0:18:37.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那就这么定了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:37.55,0:18:39.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,角色仍按原定的分配
Dialogue: 0,0:18:39.88,0:18:43.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,希望大家把今天的试演当成明天的公演
Dialogue: 0,0:18:43.32,0:18:44.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,全力以赴
Dialogue: 0,0:19:00.05,0:19:02.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,来吧 我所爱的女孩
Dialogue: 0,0:19:07.48,0:19:09.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为我们而歌唱吧
Dialogue: 0,0:19:09.64,0:19:12.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,顺我者昌逆我者亡
Dialogue: 0,0:19:12.51,0:19:14.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你是哪位
Dialogue: 0,0:19:14.77,0:19:15.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请等一下
Dialogue: 0,0:19:16.18,0:19:19.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你是神 还是恶魔
Dialogue: 0,0:19:19.67,0:19:21.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那家伙是恶魔
Dialogue: 0,0:19:21.13,0:19:22.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我来斩妖除魔
Dialogue: 0,0:19:22.42,0:19:25.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,除掉他这个来自于黑暗世界的人
Dialogue: 0,0:19:27.74,0:19:29.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,愚蠢无礼的年轻人
Dialogue: 0,0:19:29.79,0:19:31.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你将会受到诅咒
Dialogue: 0,0:19:31.29,0:19:34.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,若想夺取我们的爱和胜利
Dialogue: 0,0:19:34.79,0:19:38.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就来尝尝我们黑暗世界的厉害吧
Dialogue: 0,0:19:39.20,0:19:40.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好感动
Dialogue: 0,0:19:43.35,0:19:44.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是的
Dialogue: 0,0:19:44.69,0:19:47.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸果然又喝酒了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:48.69,0:19:51.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她从刚才开始一直在看什么呀
Dialogue: 0,0:19:56.88,0:19:57.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个是
Dialogue: 0,0:19:58.98,0:20:00.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是什么
Dialogue: 0,0:20:02.94,0:20:03.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在那里
Dialogue: 0,0:20:03.98,0:20:04.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:05.83,0:20:07.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是谁在捣乱
Dialogue: 0,0:20:11.40,0:20:12.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:20:12.53,0:20:14.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了 你的声音
Dialogue: 0,0:20:14.71,0:20:15.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是
Dialogue: 0,0:20:16.27,0:20:17.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好像是在说
Dialogue: 0,0:20:17.36,0:20:18.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,回 回去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:21.43,0:20:22.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:22.78,0:20:24.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这也是一模一样
Dialogue: 0,0:20:24.31,0:20:25.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和《剧院魅影》一样
Dialogue: 0,0:20:26.09,0:20:26.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:38.35,0:20:38.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可恶
Dialogue: 0,0:20:38.85,0:20:40.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到哪里去了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:40.75,0:20:42.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快把幕帘拉上
Dialogue: 0,0:20:42.47,0:20:43.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,路美小姐快回来
Dialogue: 0,0:20:49.99,0:20:51.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,出什么事了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:57.13,0:20:59.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只有这一条通道
Dialogue: 0,0:20:59.19,0:21:00.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,现场这么多观众
Dialogue: 0,0:21:00.68,0:21:03.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,居然没有人注意到经过这里的怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:21:03.93,0:21:05.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到底是为什么
Dialogue: 0,0:21:06.88,0:21:07.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是什么
Dialogue: 0,0:21:13.57,0:21:15.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小鬼 你在干什么
Dialogue: 0,0:21:15.50,0:21:18.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个 那里看起来好高好好玩
Dialogue: 0,0:21:18.95,0:21:20.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这里不是游乐场
Dialogue: 0,0:21:20.24,0:21:21.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,无关人员不能进来
Dialogue: 0,0:21:21.99,0:21:23.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:21:23.89,0:21:26.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有人把路美小姐的漱口水掉包了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:27.46,0:21:31.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她觉得和平时用的不太一样
Dialogue: 0,0:21:32.21,0:21:34.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但还是上台演出了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:34.86,0:21:35.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后就…
Dialogue: 0,0:21:35.86,0:21:36.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真过分
Dialogue: 0,0:21:36.64,0:21:37.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到底是谁
Dialogue: 0,0:21:38.75,0:21:40.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难 难道是
Dialogue: 0,0:21:40.30,0:21:41.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,现在没工夫管那个
Dialogue: 0,0:21:42.44,0:21:44.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,主要是进行了一半的演出该怎么办
Dialogue: 0,0:21:45.65,0:21:47.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你曾经帮路美小姐对过戏
Dialogue: 0,0:21:48.86,0:21:50.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,应该记得台词吧
Dialogue: 0,0:21:50.49,0:21:52.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难 难道要我来演
Dialogue: 0,0:21:52.67,0:21:54.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没时间废话了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:54.68,0:21:56.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,观众都在等着我们
Dialogue: 0,0:21:58.12,0:21:59.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但 但是
Dialogue: 0,0:21:59.73,0:22:00.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,准备一下
Dialogue: 0,0:22:01.17,0:22:02.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,15分钟后重新开演
Dialogue: 0,0:22:06.78,0:22:07.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快点
Dialogue: 0,0:22:11.85,0:22:13.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:22:13.14,0:22:14.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,肯定是演员啦
Dialogue: 0,0:22:14.98,0:22:18.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其他观众好像也这么认为
Dialogue: 0,0:22:19.43,0:22:20.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南呢
Dialogue: 0,0:22:23.48,0:22:24.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是阁楼啊
Dialogue: 0,0:22:24.97,0:22:26.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这里简直就是迷宫嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:22:33.56,0:22:36.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我所爱的女孩啊
Dialogue: 0,0:22:36.97,0:22:37.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是谁
Dialogue: 0,0:22:39.76,0:22:41.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,糟了
Dialogue: 0,0:22:41.19,0:22:42.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是哪里
Dialogue: 0,0:22:45.18,0:22:46.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我能行吗
Dialogue: 0,0:22:46.90,0:22:49.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我能代替路美小姐演出吗
Dialogue: 0,0:22:49.99,0:22:51.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不用担心
Dialogue: 0,0:22:51.97,0:22:52.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:22:52.92,0:22:56.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你有音乐天使的陪伴
Dialogue: 0,0:23:07.70,0:23:08.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有人
Dialogue: 0,0:23:09.87,0:23:10.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:23:12.00,0:23:13.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我见了他之后
Dialogue: 0,0:23:13.66,0:23:16.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,身心得到了解脱
Dialogue: 0,0:23:17.19,0:23:19.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但他是黑暗的主人
Dialogue: 0,0:23:19.51,0:23:21.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是黑暗的囚徒
Dialogue: 0,0:23:21.79,0:23:23.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不要再沉浸于黑暗之中了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:24.71,0:23:28.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我将会指引你进入光明世界
Dialogue: 0,0:23:28.57,0:23:30.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,无论何时何地都与你在一起
Dialogue: 0,0:23:30.30,0:23:32.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南 你上哪里去了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:32.24,0:23:33.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,厕所
Dialogue: 0,0:23:33.25,0:23:34.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请您发誓
Dialogue: 0,0:23:34.58,0:23:36.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今生只爱我一个人
Dialogue: 0,0:23:36.61,0:23:37.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我发誓
Dialogue: 0,0:23:37.88,0:23:39.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今生只爱你一个
Dialogue: 0,0:23:40.61,0:23:42.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,已经不能回头了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:42.91,0:23:45.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你被带到了这里
Dialogue: 0,0:23:45.21,0:23:47.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这里将被永远封锁在黑暗中
Dialogue: 0,0:23:47.61,0:23:48.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在这地狱的最深处
Dialogue: 0,0:23:49.05,0:23:51.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我并不畏惧你的容貌
Dialogue: 0,0:23:52.18,0:23:56.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我所畏惧的是你那扭曲的心
Dialogue: 0,0:23:56.32,0:23:57.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好厉害 莲华小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:23:57.84,0:23:59.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一点也不觉得是代演
Dialogue: 0,0:23:59.95,0:24:01.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,试演非常成功
Dialogue: 0,0:24:01.90,0:24:04.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个中途代演的演员非常出色
Dialogue: 0,0:24:05.08,0:24:07.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,开始期待明天的公演了
Dialogue: 0,0:24:24.14,0:24:26.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是阴森的鬼地方
Dialogue: 0,0:24:47.03,0:24:49.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这到底是
Dialogue: 0,0:24:51.66,0:24:52.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,锅 锅岛先生
Dialogue: 0,0:24:52.89,0:24:53.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不许动
Dialogue: 0,0:24:54.37,0:24:55.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不许离开那里
Dialogue: 0,0:24:55.91,0:24:57.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 不是的 不是的
Dialogue: 0,0:24:57.89,0:25:00.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是我 不是我
Dialogue: 0,0:25:08.24,0:25:09.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:25:09.45,0:25:11.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,玉之助被带到了警署
Dialogue: 0,0:25:11.88,0:25:12.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:25:14.11,0:25:15.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,帮帮我们 柯南 我哥哥…
Dialogue: 0,0:25:15.85,0:25:17.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,冷静一下 小惠
Dialogue: 0,0:25:17.22,0:25:18.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到底是怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:25:19.01,0:25:23.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,警方说他杀害了负责大型道具的锅岛先生
Dialogue: 0,0:25:27.02,0:25:30.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,玉之助怎么会做这种事
Dialogue: 0,0:25:30.24,0:25:34.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是据说他手持凶器倒在锅岛先生旁边
Dialogue: 0,0:25:34.63,0:25:36.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,晕过去了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:25:36.98,0:25:39.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且还戴着怪人的面具
Dialogue: 0,0:25:39.65,0:25:40.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,沾满血的面具
Dialogue: 0,0:25:41.61,0:25:45.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以大家都说之前的怪人骚动全是团长干的
Dialogue: 0,0:25:45.74,0:25:46.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会
Dialogue: 0,0:25:46.75,0:25:48.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸 快去警署吧
Dialogue: 0,0:25:48.93,0:25:49.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:25:55.37,0:25:57.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被这封信叫出去的
Dialogue: 0,0:25:57.53,0:25:58.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:26:00.57,0:26:01.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,退去
Dialogue: 0,0:26:02.21,0:26:05.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,零落阡陌欲缀红
Dialogue: 0,0:26:05.69,0:26:08.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,石碑早晨基地松
Dialogue: 0,0:26:08.44,0:26:09.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,罗臼
Dialogue: 0,0:26:09.81,0:26:12.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这也是赞岐暗号吧
Dialogue: 0,0:26:13.13,0:26:16.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和金毗罗剧院的怪人寄来的恐吓信一样
Dialogue: 0,0:26:16.91,0:26:17.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:26:18.19,0:26:21.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,译成普通句子的话
Dialogue: 0,0:26:22.74,0:26:25.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,想和你谈谈关于莲华的事
Dialogue: 0,0:26:25.59,0:26:29.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在石碑的空地等你
Dialogue: 0,0:26:29.07,0:26:31.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后你到了现场之后
Dialogue: 0,0:26:41.50,0:26:42.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:26:43.17,0:26:45.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是他为什么要做这种事
Dialogue: 0,0:26:46.09,0:26:49.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为他才是金毗罗剧院的怪人啊
Dialogue: 0,0:26:50.80,0:26:52.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,威胁换女主角
Dialogue: 0,0:26:52.73,0:26:54.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,寄恐吓信
Dialogue: 0,0:26:54.50,0:26:56.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让灯笼架砸到路美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:26:57.29,0:26:58.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,调换漱口水
Dialogue: 0,0:26:59.00,0:27:00.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他的行为只能让我这么想
Dialogue: 0,0:27:01.33,0:27:05.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是罗臼先生也说了同样的话
Dialogue: 0,0:27:05.64,0:27:07.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说是被你叫出去的
Dialogue: 0,0:27:08.98,0:27:09.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不不
Dialogue: 0,0:27:10.01,0:27:13.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我并没有说玉之助是怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:27:13.14,0:27:16.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只是被他叫出去这件事是真的
Dialogue: 0,0:27:16.62,0:27:17.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是这个吧
Dialogue: 0,0:27:17.86,0:27:22.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,玉之助先生也说收到了几乎同样内容的信
Dialogue: 0,0:27:22.15,0:27:24.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只不过公园变成了石碑
Dialogue: 0,0:27:24.47,0:27:27.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,寄信人变成了你
Dialogue: 0,0:27:27.66,0:27:29.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后你去了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:27:29.41,0:27:30.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:27:30.39,0:27:32.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是玉之助没有来
Dialogue: 0,0:27:32.84,0:27:34.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是当然
Dialogue: 0,0:27:34.38,0:27:37.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为那个时候他就在凶案现场
Dialogue: 0,0:27:37.55,0:27:41.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么你有没有在公园看见或遇见什么人
Dialogue: 0,0:27:42.63,0:27:44.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么说的话
Dialogue: 0,0:27:49.05,0:27:50.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,路美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:27:51.07,0:27:53.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么虽然你并没有看到罗臼先生
Dialogue: 0,0:27:53.99,0:27:56.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但确实是在公园的空地上吧
Dialogue: 0,0:27:56.40,0:27:57.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你在干什么
Dialogue: 0,0:28:01.07,0:28:03.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,[偷偷进行发声练习]
Dialogue: 0,0:28:03.92,0:28:05.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:28:05.72,0:28:07.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我 我很荣幸 毛利先生
Dialogue: 0,0:28:07.93,0:28:10.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,竟然能和您一起办案
Dialogue: 0,0:28:11.16,0:28:14.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把伊东玉之助作为嫌疑犯的证据
Dialogue: 0,0:28:14.50,0:28:17.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是他手中握着的刀吧
Dialogue: 0,0:28:17.93,0:28:18.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:28:18.78,0:28:21.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过当时玉之助先生不是晕过去了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:28:22.54,0:28:26.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也可能是别人故意嫁祸给他吧
Dialogue: 0,0:28:26.11,0:28:27.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊是啊
Dialogue: 0,0:28:27.04,0:28:28.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:28:28.38,0:28:30.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,关于这方面调查过吗
Dialogue: 0,0:28:30.44,0:28:33.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,的确我们在他的后脑勺发现了伤口
Dialogue: 0,0:28:33.39,0:28:36.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但也可以认为是与被害人扭打时
Dialogue: 0,0:28:36.22,0:28:40.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不小心撞到台座的台阶所致
Dialogue: 0,0:28:40.37,0:28:42.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,台座的台阶
Dialogue: 0,0:28:43.47,0:28:44.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请您说下去
Dialogue: 0,0:28:45.47,0:28:46.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好的
Dialogue: 0,0:28:46.35,0:28:50.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,倒下的被害人身后有座纪念碑
Dialogue: 0,0:28:50.22,0:28:52.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,它的台座是有个台阶的
Dialogue: 0,0:28:54.15,0:28:56.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,杀人动机呢
Dialogue: 0,0:28:56.41,0:28:58.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是金钱纠纷吧
Dialogue: 0,0:28:58.43,0:29:01.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,仗着自己是前任团长的老团员
Dialogue: 0,0:29:01.14,0:29:02.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被害人经常要求预付工资
Dialogue: 0,0:29:02.90,0:29:05.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还提出过很多过分的要求
Dialogue: 0,0:29:05.82,0:29:07.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以终于忍不住了
Dialogue: 0,0:29:07.94,0:29:08.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么可能
Dialogue: 0,0:29:08.83,0:29:09.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会的
Dialogue: 0,0:29:09.89,0:29:11.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有一个
Dialogue: 0,0:29:11.11,0:29:13.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想这是最主要的动机
Dialogue: 0,0:29:13.17,0:29:16.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让别人认为罗臼先生就是金毗罗剧院的怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:29:16.59,0:29:20.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嫁祸给他以博得莲华小姐的芳心
Dialogue: 0,0:29:20.95,0:29:22.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这才奇怪呢
Dialogue: 0,0:29:22.59,0:29:24.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为本来那两个人就
Dialogue: 0,0:29:24.45,0:29:25.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,亲热得很
Dialogue: 0,0:29:25.68,0:29:27.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然我很不爽
Dialogue: 0,0:29:27.55,0:29:29.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,根本没必要做那种事
Dialogue: 0,0:29:29.71,0:29:30.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是
Dialogue: 0,0:29:30.75,0:29:33.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,正因为罗臼先生出现了不是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:29:34.89,0:29:37.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,男人和女人之间的事很难说的
Dialogue: 0,0:29:37.17,0:29:38.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,特别是从旁观者的角度
Dialogue: 0,0:29:38.91,0:29:40.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会
Dialogue: 0,0:29:41.43,0:29:43.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么一来就没法公演了
Dialogue: 0,0:29:43.95,0:29:45.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,团长竟然是嫌疑犯
Dialogue: 0,0:29:45.80,0:29:46.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真可惜
Dialogue: 0,0:29:46.91,0:29:49.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,片冈莲华演得挺不错的
Dialogue: 0,0:29:54.63,0:29:57.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你相信玉之助吧
Dialogue: 0,0:29:57.31,0:29:59.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,团长也相信我
Dialogue: 0,0:29:59.79,0:30:01.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以让我代替路美小姐出演
Dialogue: 0,0:30:02.07,0:30:03.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那场演出很精彩
Dialogue: 0,0:30:04.29,0:30:06.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是当时我非常害怕
Dialogue: 0,0:30:06.69,0:30:08.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我认为自己肯定是不行的
Dialogue: 0,0:30:08.76,0:30:13.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 受了音乐天使和怪人的鼓励
Dialogue: 0,0:30:14.71,0:30:16.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会是你干的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:30:16.94,0:30:18.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你怀疑我吗
Dialogue: 0,0:30:18.80,0:30:19.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不知道
Dialogue: 0,0:30:19.82,0:30:23.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到底该相信什么该相信谁我都不知道
Dialogue: 0,0:30:24.68,0:30:27.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,既然你这么痛苦就干脆别演了
Dialogue: 0,0:30:28.11,0:30:28.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,莲华
Dialogue: 0,0:30:29.27,0:30:31.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我希望你和我一起生活下去
Dialogue: 0,0:30:33.39,0:30:34.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会吧
Dialogue: 0,0:30:35.14,0:30:36.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:30:36.12,0:30:39.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我现在很担心团长 没心情谈这个
Dialogue: 0,0:30:39.23,0:30:40.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗 好吧
Dialogue: 0,0:30:40.84,0:30:42.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么你去告诉团长
Dialogue: 0,0:30:43.71,0:30:45.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,作为赞助商的我也受到了沉重打击
Dialogue: 0,0:30:46.11,0:30:48.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很遗憾 如此下去我不得不退出了
Dialogue: 0,0:30:48.79,0:30:49.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎 怎么可以
Dialogue: 0,0:30:49.98,0:30:52.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是你的事另当别论
Dialogue: 0,0:30:52.92,0:30:54.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是绝对不会放弃你的
Dialogue: 0,0:30:58.29,0:30:59.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对 对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:30:59.59,0:31:01.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们没打算偷听的
Dialogue: 0,0:31:02.00,0:31:03.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是真的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:31:03.85,0:31:05.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说受到怪人的鼓励
Dialogue: 0,0:31:06.22,0:31:08.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以我没有觉得太高兴
Dialogue: 0,0:31:08.81,0:31:11.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然掌声响起时我感到了瞬间的陶醉
Dialogue: 0,0:31:11.78,0:31:14.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没那回事 那是你的实力
Dialogue: 0,0:31:14.29,0:31:15.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过
Dialogue: 0,0:31:15.08,0:31:18.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,新女主角受到怪人的鼓励
Dialogue: 0,0:31:18.19,0:31:21.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也和《剧院魅影》的情节一样
Dialogue: 0,0:31:21.29,0:31:22.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:31:22.24,0:31:23.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以我很害怕
Dialogue: 0,0:31:23.84,0:31:25.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到底是谁干的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:31:25.80,0:31:27.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果不是玉之助的话
Dialogue: 0,0:31:27.65,0:31:29.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道果然是罗臼先生
Dialogue: 0,0:31:29.38,0:31:31.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,或者真的是怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:31:31.44,0:31:32.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,幽灵
Dialogue: 0,0:31:33.02,0:31:34.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,鬼怪
Dialogue: 0,0:31:34.04,0:31:36.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 那不可能
Dialogue: 0,0:31:45.55,0:31:46.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是这个
Dialogue: 0,0:31:48.79,0:31:50.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了 柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:31:51.20,0:31:52.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是什么
Dialogue: 0,0:31:52.30,0:31:53.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,扬声器
Dialogue: 0,0:31:54.32,0:31:55.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错 还是无线的
Dialogue: 0,0:31:55.97,0:31:57.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,估计就是从这里
Dialogue: 0,0:31:58.29,0:32:01.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其实那天我也听到了怪人的声音
Dialogue: 0,0:32:01.89,0:32:03.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真的吗 柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:32:03.51,0:32:06.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样看来 就是说
Dialogue: 0,0:32:06.06,0:32:07.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,金毗罗剧院的怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:32:07.63,0:32:10.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是幽灵也不是鬼怪
Dialogue: 0,0:32:10.40,0:32:12.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我再去找爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:32:12.74,0:32:13.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也去
Dialogue: 0,0:32:14.61,0:32:15.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也要抓紧了
Dialogue: 0,0:32:19.64,0:32:21.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,起初我觉得有点不对劲
Dialogue: 0,0:32:22.50,0:32:24.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,需要去掉さ的恐吓信
Dialogue: 0,0:32:25.14,0:32:29.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,模仿《剧院魅影》的金毗罗剧院怪人的行为
Dialogue: 0,0:32:29.57,0:32:33.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所有这一切都好像是故意给别人看的
Dialogue: 0,0:32:33.80,0:32:35.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,感觉很做作
Dialogue: 0,0:32:35.64,0:32:37.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但杀人事件却显得很突兀
Dialogue: 0,0:32:37.97,0:32:40.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那里肯定有什么线索
Dialogue: 0,0:32:46.97,0:32:48.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,台阶就是指这个啊
Dialogue: 0,0:32:49.30,0:32:52.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对于犯人来说真是个绝好的藏身处呢
Dialogue: 0,0:33:09.43,0:33:11.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸 你想想办法啊
Dialogue: 0,0:33:12.29,0:33:14.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好不容易来一趟
Dialogue: 0,0:33:14.02,0:33:17.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样下去就看不到玉之助的表演了
Dialogue: 0,0:33:17.01,0:33:19.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们不必担心
Dialogue: 0,0:33:19.77,0:33:22.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚才大西警官通知我说
Dialogue: 0,0:33:23.09,0:33:25.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,伊东玉之助已被无罪释放
Dialogue: 0,0:33:25.42,0:33:30.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,相反罗臼先生被作为重大嫌疑犯正在接受审讯
Dialogue: 0,0:33:30.77,0:33:32.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这次肯定不会错
Dialogue: 0,0:33:33.40,0:33:36.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,掉落在案发现场的登台阶用的手杖上
Dialogue: 0,0:33:36.75,0:33:41.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,除了被害人的指纹以外还发现了罗臼辰彦的指纹
Dialogue: 0,0:33:41.37,0:33:45.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,应该是在和被害人争执时留下的
Dialogue: 0,0:33:45.65,0:33:47.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且在他的车里
Dialogue: 0,0:33:52.98,0:33:53.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,胡说八道
Dialogue: 0,0:33:54.26,0:33:55.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我根本不知道什么手杖
Dialogue: 0,0:33:56.21,0:33:59.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也没有把那种东西放在汽车后备箱里
Dialogue: 0,0:33:59.14,0:34:04.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,听说昨天试演时那个怪人的出现引起了骚动
Dialogue: 0,0:34:04.48,0:34:07.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大多数观众都以为是演出的一部分
Dialogue: 0,0:34:07.71,0:34:10.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你当时是不是用了投影仪
Dialogue: 0,0:34:17.85,0:34:20.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此 那个是这样形成的
Dialogue: 0,0:34:20.39,0:34:21.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,别开玩笑
Dialogue: 0,0:34:21.45,0:34:23.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道你们怀疑是我干的
Dialogue: 0,0:34:23.26,0:34:28.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只要使用遥控器你在观众席上也能操纵
Dialogue: 0,0:34:29.08,0:34:30.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么可能
Dialogue: 0,0:34:30.09,0:34:32.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有录音机和信号发射器
Dialogue: 0,0:34:32.89,0:34:38.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是为了把事先录好的怪人声音放给莲华小姐听吧
Dialogue: 0,0:34:38.25,0:34:41.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在后台还发现了扬声器
Dialogue: 0,0:34:41.52,0:34:44.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你这么做都是为了得到她的心
Dialogue: 0,0:34:44.48,0:34:47.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且你还为此陷害了玉之助先生
Dialogue: 0,0:34:47.04,0:34:48.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我没有说错吧
Dialogue: 0,0:34:48.72,0:34:49.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,别胡说八道
Dialogue: 0,0:34:51.71,0:34:53.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哥哥
Dialogue: 0,0:34:53.59,0:34:54.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哥哥
Dialogue: 0,0:34:55.04,0:34:56.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让你担心了
Dialogue: 0,0:34:56.21,0:34:57.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大家呢
Dialogue: 0,0:34:57.53,0:34:58.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,都在宾馆里
Dialogue: 0,0:34:58.82,0:34:59.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,走吧
Dialogue: 0,0:34:59.83,0:35:02.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,得马上决定今晚的演出该如何进行
Dialogue: 0,0:35:03.38,0:35:05.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南 谢谢你
Dialogue: 0,0:35:06.55,0:35:08.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,问题还是在于那个台阶
Dialogue: 0,0:35:09.47,0:35:13.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果说犯人是站在上面下的手
Dialogue: 0,0:35:19.29,0:35:20.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对了
Dialogue: 0,0:35:20.63,0:35:21.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不在场证明
Dialogue: 0,0:35:21.96,0:35:23.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我有不在场证明
Dialogue: 0,0:35:23.33,0:35:24.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很遗憾
Dialogue: 0,0:35:24.91,0:35:25.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那也不成立
Dialogue: 0,0:35:26.02,0:35:29.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说在空地练习发声是骗人的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:35:29.81,0:35:32.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她害怕角色从此被换掉
Dialogue: 0,0:35:32.79,0:35:36.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以就想如果对赞助商你提供有利证词
Dialogue: 0,0:35:36.62,0:35:38.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也许会有转机
Dialogue: 0,0:35:38.89,0:35:40.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她是这么说的
Dialogue: 0,0:35:40.95,0:35:41.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:35:43.56,0:35:45.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她为什么要这么做
Dialogue: 0,0:35:46.16,0:35:47.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:35:47.38,0:35:48.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:35:48.40,0:35:50.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想上个厕所
Dialogue: 0,0:35:50.66,0:35:51.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有一点
Dialogue: 0,0:35:51.77,0:35:53.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,播放出怪人的投影仪
Dialogue: 0,0:35:54.04,0:35:56.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果可以在观众席上通过遥控器操作的话
Dialogue: 0,0:35:56.77,0:35:57.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那其他地方也行
Dialogue: 0,0:35:58.02,0:35:58.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错
Dialogue: 0,0:35:58.80,0:36:00.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,即使是在台上也可以
Dialogue: 0,0:36:01.43,0:36:02.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,警察叔叔
Dialogue: 0,0:36:03.57,0:36:05.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你是毛利先生的
Dialogue: 0,0:36:05.10,0:36:08.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毛利叔叔要我过来问一下
Dialogue: 0,0:36:08.53,0:36:10.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生 问什么
Dialogue: 0,0:36:10.76,0:36:13.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,罗臼先生的指纹留在了手杖的哪个部位
Dialogue: 0,0:36:14.73,0:36:16.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是留在了胶带上
Dialogue: 0,0:36:16.31,0:36:17.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,胶带
Dialogue: 0,0:36:17.19,0:36:20.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 不同的店会有不同的包扎方法和颜色
Dialogue: 0,0:36:20.74,0:36:22.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,算是商标吧
Dialogue: 0,0:36:22.36,0:36:24.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是哪家店的手杖呢
Dialogue: 0,0:36:24.06,0:36:28.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到现在为止还没有找到这家店
Dialogue: 0,0:36:28.33,0:36:32.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,本来以为荧光带很少见应该马上就能找到的
Dialogue: 0,0:36:33.30,0:36:34.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,荧光带
Dialogue: 0,0:36:39.00,0:36:40.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这样 我明白了
Dialogue: 0,0:36:40.68,0:36:42.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道真正的犯人了
Dialogue: 0,0:36:42.93,0:36:45.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,罗臼辰彦逃跑了
Dialogue: 0,0:36:45.24,0:36:46.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:36:46.65,0:36:47.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:36:47.99,0:36:49.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我一不留神就…
Dialogue: 0,0:36:49.41,0:36:51.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,紧急通缉 赶快
Dialogue: 0,0:37:02.52,0:37:04.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你不爱我
Dialogue: 0,0:37:04.38,0:37:05.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不爱我
Dialogue: 0,0:37:05.30,0:37:06.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不爱我
Dialogue: 0,0:37:06.30,0:37:07.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,放开我
Dialogue: 0,0:37:07.30,0:37:08.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,放开我
Dialogue: 0,0:37:08.43,0:37:11.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是你命中注定永远离不开我
Dialogue: 0,0:37:12.34,0:37:14.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,离不开我
Dialogue: 0,0:37:28.58,0:37:30.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这也很做作
Dialogue: 0,0:37:30.72,0:37:33.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但为什么要故意表明自己的所在地呢
Dialogue: 0,0:37:33.58,0:37:34.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只好去一趟了
Dialogue: 0,0:37:35.24,0:37:36.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:37:36.94,0:37:38.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有没有看到莲华
Dialogue: 0,0:37:38.52,0:37:39.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,玉之助先生
Dialogue: 0,0:37:40.29,0:37:40.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是
Dialogue: 0,0:37:41.26,0:37:42.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道说被罗臼
Dialogue: 0,0:37:42.94,0:37:46.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来你在这里 我们找了你好久 柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:37:46.51,0:37:48.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们俩都怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:37:49.14,0:37:51.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,莲华 你在哪里
Dialogue: 0,0:37:51.38,0:37:53.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,莲华小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:37:53.75,0:37:55.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,莲华小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:37:55.56,0:37:56.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看那里
Dialogue: 0,0:37:58.25,0:37:59.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,罗臼
Dialogue: 0,0:37:59.11,0:38:00.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,莲华在哪里
Dialogue: 0,0:38:00.69,0:38:01.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等等 罗臼
Dialogue: 0,0:38:04.13,0:38:06.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,与我共赴黄泉的女孩啊
Dialogue: 0,0:38:06.64,0:38:08.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让我们共同坠入黑暗的深渊吧
Dialogue: 0,0:38:08.66,0:38:09.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,放开我
Dialogue: 0,0:38:09.70,0:38:11.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,放开我
Dialogue: 0,0:38:11.38,0:38:12.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等等 怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:38:16.20,0:38:17.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,放开她
Dialogue: 0,0:38:29.54,0:38:30.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,莲华
Dialogue: 0,0:38:35.81,0:38:36.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,该停手了
Dialogue: 0,0:38:36.99,0:38:38.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,园子
Dialogue: 0,0:38:38.18,0:38:39.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,金毗罗剧院的怪人
Dialogue: 0,0:38:40.07,0:38:43.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道你不是罗臼先生
Dialogue: 0,0:38:43.66,0:38:47.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且你最初并没有打算杀人
Dialogue: 0,0:38:48.45,0:38:49.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错吧
Dialogue: 0,0:38:49.72,0:38:51.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可以停手了 路美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:38:52.73,0:38:53.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:38:53.74,0:38:54.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会吧
Dialogue: 0,0:38:55.19,0:38:55.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错
Dialogue: 0,0:38:56.25,0:38:59.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从一开始你的举止就很奇怪
Dialogue: 0,0:39:06.30,0:39:09.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这一切都是你在自导自演
Dialogue: 0,0:39:09.56,0:39:11.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是在演戏吗
Dialogue: 0,0:39:11.25,0:39:12.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么要那么做
Dialogue: 0,0:39:12.68,0:39:15.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,当然是为了设圈套陷害罗臼先生
Dialogue: 0,0:39:24.42,0:39:26.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,路美小姐 为什么
Dialogue: 0,0:39:26.46,0:39:29.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,报仇 向那家伙的父亲
Dialogue: 0,0:39:29.42,0:39:32.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是已故的罗臼集团前董事长吧
Dialogue: 0,0:39:32.78,0:39:36.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我父亲的事业被他抢走
Dialogue: 0,0:39:36.14,0:39:37.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以才因为劳累而去世
Dialogue: 0,0:39:38.28,0:39:40.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没多久母亲也随着去了
Dialogue: 0,0:39:40.63,0:39:41.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:39:41.95,0:39:44.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,留下我孤零零的一个人
Dialogue: 0,0:39:44.20,0:39:45.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那时的我只能演戏了
Dialogue: 0,0:39:46.26,0:39:48.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我根本没有想到可以报仇
Dialogue: 0,0:39:48.84,0:39:50.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,后来我收到了本次演出的请求
Dialogue: 0,0:39:51.15,0:39:53.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,抓住机会 抓住机会
Dialogue: 0,0:39:53.32,0:39:55.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我听到了父母从那个世界传来的呼喊
Dialogue: 0,0:39:55.99,0:39:57.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以才接受了我的请求
Dialogue: 0,0:39:58.37,0:40:01.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是最初我并没有打算杀人
Dialogue: 0,0:40:01.62,0:40:03.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只要本次的演出失败
Dialogue: 0,0:40:03.70,0:40:07.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,使赞助方罗臼集团的名字蒙上污点我就满足了
Dialogue: 0,0:40:08.21,0:40:10.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以我给莲华施压
Dialogue: 0,0:40:11.55,0:40:13.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个女孩不可能成功
Dialogue: 0,0:40:13.82,0:40:16.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,演出一定会失败
Dialogue: 0,0:40:18.65,0:40:20.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但这是我的一大失误
Dialogue: 0,0:40:21.11,0:40:22.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我忘记了
Dialogue: 0,0:40:23.11,0:40:25.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,莲华也是一名演员
Dialogue: 0,0:40:25.41,0:40:29.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我曾经也和她一样化压力为动力
Dialogue: 0,0:40:30.02,0:40:30.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,路美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:40:32.28,0:40:34.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,之后还被那个男人发现
Dialogue: 0,0:40:38.64,0:40:40.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样我就不用愁被人追债了
Dialogue: 0,0:40:42.65,0:40:44.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说是不是啊
Dialogue: 0,0:40:44.81,0:40:48.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,父母的复仇不能半途而废
Dialogue: 0,0:40:49.03,0:40:51.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,杀了这家伙让罗臼背黑锅
Dialogue: 0,0:40:51.57,0:40:53.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我当时暗下决心
Dialogue: 0,0:40:53.90,0:40:56.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以就把锅岛先生叫到那块空地
Dialogue: 0,0:40:56.97,0:40:59.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,自己则躲在纪念碑的后面
Dialogue: 0,0:41:00.05,0:41:04.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果犯人是站在台座上刺杀了锅岛先生
Dialogue: 0,0:41:04.49,0:41:05.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那就应该是个子较矮的人
Dialogue: 0,0:41:06.15,0:41:14.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错 就算是女性也正好能把刀刺入锅岛先生的脖子
Dialogue: 0,0:41:16.22,0:41:20.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那根手杖上的荧光带是罗臼先生碰巧触摸过的
Dialogue: 0,0:41:26.02,0:41:29.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,警方就会认为把玉之助先生打晕的是
Dialogue: 0,0:41:29.34,0:41:34.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,想要夺走莲华小姐的罗臼先生
Dialogue: 0,0:41:36.02,0:41:39.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后你又故意让罗臼先生看到你
Dialogue: 0,0:41:39.82,0:41:44.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,改变证词来损害罗臼先生的信誉
Dialogue: 0,0:41:45.07,0:41:48.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,另外当他在公园等待玉之助先生时
Dialogue: 0,0:41:48.58,0:41:50.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把投影仪放到了他的汽车后备箱里
Dialogue: 0,0:41:51.58,0:41:52.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错
Dialogue: 0,0:41:52.66,0:41:54.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但终究还是被罗臼发现了
Dialogue: 0,0:42:01.76,0:42:02.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快出来
Dialogue: 0,0:42:02.97,0:42:04.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我已经知道是你做的
Dialogue: 0,0:42:09.93,0:42:12.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,既然如此我只好将计就计
Dialogue: 0,0:42:13.25,0:42:17.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让从警署逃跑的罗臼逼莲华一起自杀殉情
Dialogue: 0,0:42:18.85,0:42:22.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过竟然连你这个小姑娘也把事情全部看透了
Dialogue: 0,0:42:33.97,0:42:35.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不可以 路美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:42:42.50,0:42:44.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可怜的不幸之人啊
Dialogue: 0,0:42:56.05,0:42:57.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,糟了
Dialogue: 0,0:42:57.10,0:42:58.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,玉之助先生
Dialogue: 0,0:42:58.63,0:42:59.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:43:25.52,0:43:26.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,路美小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:43:26.76,0:43:28.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你先夺走别人的生命
Dialogue: 0,0:43:28.18,0:43:30.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,最后还要夺走自己的生命
Dialogue: 0,0:43:30.27,0:43:33.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道这也要归咎于你父母吗
Dialogue: 0,0:43:34.96,0:43:36.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不论有什么理由
Dialogue: 0,0:43:36.69,0:43:39.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你做了作为一个人所不该做的事
Dialogue: 0,0:43:39.97,0:43:42.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你就必须要为此赎罪
Dialogue: 0,0:43:42.85,0:43:44.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,绝对不允许自杀
Dialogue: 0,0:43:45.08,0:43:50.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且你故意把这里的介绍册摆放在那里
Dialogue: 0,0:43:50.41,0:43:52.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道不是希望有谁能阻止你
Dialogue: 0,0:43:52.88,0:43:55.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,阻止你自杀吗
Dialogue: 0,0:44:09.73,0:44:10.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,太好了
Dialogue: 0,0:44:10.60,0:44:11.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,多亏了园子
Dialogue: 0,0:44:12.74,0:44:14.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,又是我搞定的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:44:14.71,0:44:16.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在你睡觉的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:44:17.70,0:44:18.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:44:18.72,0:44:20.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我会继续演戏
Dialogue: 0,0:44:20.68,0:44:22.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和团长一起永远地演下去
Dialogue: 0,0:44:22.55,0:44:23.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,莲华
Dialogue: 0,0:44:24.01,0:44:24.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我明白了
Dialogue: 0,0:46:18.93,0:46:20.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好有趣
Dialogue: 0,0:46:21.13,0:46:22.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还是挺费力气的
Dialogue: 0,0:46:22.69,0:46:24.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过感觉很舒服
Dialogue: 0,0:46:26.78,0:46:29.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了乌冬面的筋道我花的劲道可不少啊
Dialogue: 0,0:46:29.45,0:46:31.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,来杯啤酒 啤酒
Dialogue: 0,0:46:33.68,0:46:35.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到哪里都一样
Dialogue: 0,0:46:39.50,0:46:43.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这可是风靡了20年的电影之完结篇嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:46:44.00,0:46:45.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,太奇怪了
Dialogue: 0,0:46:46.00,0:46:49.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看 这是两张3年前试映会的票
Dialogue: 0,0:46:50.00,0:46:52.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有用过就夹在了笔记本里
Dialogue: 0,0:46:53.50,0:46:54.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说不定他
Dialogue: 0,0:46:57.30,0:47:01.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,已经不打算回来了
Dialogue: 0,0:47:01.20,0:47:03.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,NEXT CONAN
Dialogue: 0,0:47:03.50,0:47:05.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,姻缘和友情的试映会
Dialogue: 0,0:47:08.22,0:47:10.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,NEXT CONAN'S HINT
Dialogue: 0,0:47:10.48,0:47:12.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嘉宾票
Dialogue: 0,0:47:12.38,0:47:14.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,点播率第1位的电影将在10月2日放映
Dialogue: 0,0:47:14.73,0:47:16.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那部我是主角吧 兰
Dialogue: 0,0:47:16.05,0:47:16.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是主角
