[Script Info]
; This is an Advanced Sub Station Alpha v4+ script.
; For Sub Station Alpha info and downloads,
; go to http://www.eswat.demon.co.uk/
; or email kotus@eswat.demon.co.uk
; 
; Advanced Sub Station Alpha script format developed by #Anime-Fansubs@EfNET
; http://www.anime-fansubs.org
; 
; For additional info and downloads go to http://vobsub.edensrising.com/
; or email gabest@freemail.hu
; 
; Note: This file was saved by Subresync.
; 
ScriptType: v4.00+
Collisions: Normal
PlayResX: 704
PlayResY: 396
Timer: 100.0000

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,微软雅黑,30,&H00ffffff,&Hf0000000,&H00000000,&H70000000,-1,0,0,0,100,100,0,0.00,1,1,1,2,30,30,10,1

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Actor, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text

Dialogue: 0,0:00:07.15,0:00:08.18,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们在调查水无怜奈
Dialogue: 0,0:00:08.30,0:00:11.61,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和本堂瑛祐的姐姐是否同一个人的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:00:12.05,0:00:15.62,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,发现水无怜奈的血型为AB
Dialogue: 0,0:00:16.52,0:00:18.62,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我 我是AB型的血
Dialogue: 0,0:00:19.03,0:00:21.13,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 瑛祐说自己是O型血
Dialogue: 0,0:00:21.50,0:00:24.54,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这一点在瑛祐已经去世的母亲当女佣的地方
Dialogue: 0,0:00:24.64,0:00:26.43,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所留下的母子手册中得到了确认
Dialogue: 0,0:00:27.22,0:00:29.31,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你看 这里写着呢
Dialogue: 0,0:00:29.43,0:00:31.64,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,本堂瑛祐 O型
Dialogue: 0,0:00:32.95,0:00:33.87,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:00:34.77,0:00:36.79,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这就很明白了 我肯定是O型血
Dialogue: 0,0:00:37.11,0:00:38.14,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:00:38.38,0:00:39.08,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,剩下就是要确认
Dialogue: 0,0:00:39.11,0:00:42.49,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这家伙的姐姐是不是真的给他输过血
Dialogue: 0,0:00:43.68,0:00:45.09,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一年前 在这个奥平家族中
Dialogue: 0,0:00:45.53,0:00:49.37,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,儿子锻吾被人杀害
Dialogue: 0,0:00:50.14,0:00:54.92,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是从当时所拍的录像中打印出来的照片
Dialogue: 0,0:00:55.13,0:00:58.15,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,双手双脚被缚 嘴上被贴着胶布
Dialogue: 0,0:00:58.16,0:00:59.53,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真残忍啊
Dialogue: 0,0:01:00.38,0:01:04.53,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有没有什么令郎仇人的线索
Dialogue: 0,0:01:04.65,0:01:06.35,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,线索的话
Dialogue: 0,0:01:06.87,0:01:09.25,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,外面没有 家里有
Dialogue: 0,0:01:13.18,0:01:16.45,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我一直怀疑啊 毛利侦探
Dialogue: 0,0:01:17.58,0:01:19.22,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我儿子锻吾
Dialogue: 0,0:01:19.51,0:01:22.34,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是被家里的某个奸诈之人
Dialogue: 0,0:01:25.70,0:01:28.63,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所杀害的
Dialogue: 0,0:01:52.72,0:01:54.15,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,热辣刺激的悬念
Dialogue: 0,0:01:54.41,0:01:56.72,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,急驰在黑暗中的红色尖叫与黑色子弹
Dialogue: 0,0:01:57.14,0:01:59.25,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从血型中得知的惊异真相
Dialogue: 0,0:01:59.60,0:02:01.59,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在宅邸中回响的是悲鸣和叫喊
Dialogue: 0,0:02:01.91,0:02:03.34,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看清惟一的真相
Dialogue: 0,0:02:03.43,0:02:04.98,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,外表看似小孩 头脑却是大人
Dialogue: 0,0:02:05.22,0:02:06.90,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他的名字就叫 名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:03:35.09,0:03:40.72,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,红与黑的碰撞 疾呼
Dialogue: 0,0:03:41.75,0:03:45.70,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,令郎被家里的某人杀害
Dialogue: 0,0:03:46.61,0:03:48.64,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是您不是说过
Dialogue: 0,0:03:49.19,0:03:54.61,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,令郎是全家人在起居室看录像的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:03:55.22,0:03:58.88,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被某人溺死在游泳池里的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:04.13,0:04:09.80,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好像推定的死亡时间是晚上9点到10点
Dialogue: 0,0:04:10.25,0:04:14.69,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这前后两小时 也就是晚上7点到12点
Dialogue: 0,0:04:14.87,0:04:16.99,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大家都在看录像对吧
Dialogue: 0,0:04:23.09,0:04:24.88,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,确实是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:04:25.36,0:04:28.19,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是我总觉得锻吾
Dialogue: 0,0:04:28.78,0:04:31.37,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是被这家里的某人杀害的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:33.32,0:04:36.04,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,起居室里有没有暗门什么的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:36.24,0:04:38.64,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有没有可能从那里逃出去
Dialogue: 0,0:04:38.80,0:04:40.68,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 没有这样的门
Dialogue: 0,0:04:41.05,0:04:44.48,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看录像的时候有去上厕所的人
Dialogue: 0,0:04:44.60,0:04:45.48,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样
Dialogue: 0,0:04:45.51,0:04:47.32,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那有没有趁这个时候偷偷跑去外面的人
Dialogue: 0,0:04:47.36,0:04:48.40,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也不可能
Dialogue: 0,0:04:49.00,0:04:51.06,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,厕所和起居室是连着的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:51.12,0:04:55.31,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,厕所的窗户大小也无法让一个成人进出
Dialogue: 0,0:04:56.45,0:04:59.17,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样的话 家里人不可能行凶
Dialogue: 0,0:04:59.99,0:05:03.37,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你好好看看 照片的这里
Dialogue: 0,0:05:04.55,0:05:09.34,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你看 锻吾的右手戴上了白色手套
Dialogue: 0,0:05:09.85,0:05:10.77,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,确实是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:05:11.03,0:05:14.07,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是正好两年前的今天
Dialogue: 0,0:05:14.28,0:05:17.10,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因车子从悬崖上掉落而去世的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:18.07,0:05:25.37,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,前管家开车时常带的手套
Dialogue: 0,0:05:32.33,0:05:33.97,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,正好是今天
Dialogue: 0,0:05:34.22,0:05:37.74,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好像令郎被杀害也是一年前的...
Dialogue: 0,0:05:37.77,0:05:39.58,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 就是今天
Dialogue: 0,0:05:40.29,0:05:43.06,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且儿子去世三天后
Dialogue: 0,0:05:43.13,0:05:47.84,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,左手的手套就在我书房里找到了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:48.07,0:05:49.13,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:05:49.25,0:05:52.57,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说 凶手给令郎戴上的手套
Dialogue: 0,0:05:52.61,0:05:54.93,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为什么原因 脱落了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:54.94,0:05:56.64,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:05:56.78,0:06:00.58,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是有人因为前管家的死而怀恨在心
Dialogue: 0,0:06:00.66,0:06:01.89,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说是怀恨
Dialogue: 0,0:06:02.14,0:06:05.02,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,前管家不是因事故去世的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:06:07.50,0:06:09.22,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说 有人认为这个事故是
Dialogue: 0,0:06:09.26,0:06:12.29,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,老爷爷和老爷爷的儿子造成的
Dialogue: 0,0:06:12.65,0:06:15.42,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以将前管家的手套戴在儿子手上
Dialogue: 0,0:06:15.43,0:06:16.23,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,杀害了他
Dialogue: 0,0:06:16.30,0:06:19.08,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,计划着下一个 就轮到老爷爷你
Dialogue: 0,0:06:19.28,0:06:22.17,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在房间里放下另一个手套
Dialogue: 0,0:06:23.58,0:06:25.07,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,您是想这样说吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:25.42,0:06:26.63,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,老爷爷
Dialogue: 0,0:06:28.69,0:06:30.20,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么回事 你们
Dialogue: 0,0:06:30.53,0:06:31.74,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么随便进来
Dialogue: 0,0:06:32.32,0:06:33.22,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是 柯南说
Dialogue: 0,0:06:33.24,0:06:34.32,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,事情弄完了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:34.44,0:06:37.30,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就来看看案件解决的怎么样了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:39.16,0:06:40.87,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,少给我来这套
Dialogue: 0,0:06:41.03,0:06:43.47,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,事情弄完了就赶快给我回去
Dialogue: 0,0:06:54.13,0:06:56.80,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好久不见 角藏叔叔
Dialogue: 0,0:06:58.36,0:06:59.88,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是瑛祐啊
Dialogue: 0,0:07:00.15,0:07:03.08,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我好像听说找到你母亲的遗物了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:03.15,0:07:03.93,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:04.18,0:07:06.57,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,托您的福 顺利拿到了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:07.21,0:07:11.18,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你母亲是个好女佣
Dialogue: 0,0:07:11.41,0:07:15.40,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很机灵 总是笑眯眯的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:15.41,0:07:16.88,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:17.37,0:07:20.19,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我又笨拙又冷淡
Dialogue: 0,0:07:21.42,0:07:24.06,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有没有 我不是那意思
Dialogue: 0,0:07:24.61,0:07:25.61,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么说起来
Dialogue: 0,0:07:26.21,0:07:28.56,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我听说锻吾哥哥去世了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:28.83,0:07:29.87,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,唉
Dialogue: 0,0:07:30.26,0:07:34.21,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我正在请毛利侦探帮我调查这件事情
Dialogue: 0,0:07:34.80,0:07:35.92,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么 濑川
Dialogue: 0,0:07:35.99,0:07:36.87,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:07:37.75,0:07:40.55,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请你把毛利侦探带到起居室去
Dialogue: 0,0:07:40.69,0:07:42.98,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,遵命 老爷
Dialogue: 0,0:07:43.25,0:07:44.54,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有 菊代
Dialogue: 0,0:07:44.69,0:07:46.55,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,帮我加点咖啡
Dialogue: 0,0:07:46.57,0:07:47.28,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:07:47.29,0:07:49.74,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,顺便把我夫人叫过来
Dialogue: 0,0:07:50.69,0:07:53.62,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让她过来帮忙收拾书房
Dialogue: 0,0:07:54.16,0:07:57.61,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们有空的也过来吧
Dialogue: 0,0:07:57.84,0:07:59.84,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有点事情想跟你们说
Dialogue: 0,0:08:00.29,0:08:02.57,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,遵命
Dialogue: 0,0:08:02.97,0:08:04.85,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有 濑川
Dialogue: 0,0:08:07.33,0:08:09.37,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我跟你说过多少遍了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:09.72,0:08:13.01,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,进我房间前一定要先敲门
Dialogue: 0,0:08:13.07,0:08:14.71,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么没有跟客人说
Dialogue: 0,0:08:14.72,0:08:15.83,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你这个笨蛋
Dialogue: 0,0:08:16.89,0:08:18.58,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:08:23.00,0:08:27.32,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么 叫我帮忙收拾书房里的书
Dialogue: 0,0:08:27.46,0:08:28.41,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我才不去呢
Dialogue: 0,0:08:28.88,0:08:33.22,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他总是鸡蛋里挑骨头
Dialogue: 0,0:08:33.95,0:08:35.53,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 夫人
Dialogue: 0,0:08:36.20,0:08:37.56,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是就刚刚
Dialogue: 0,0:08:37.63,0:08:39.92,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,准备整理刚到的大开本书
Dialogue: 0,0:08:39.93,0:08:42.53,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,正要打开纸箱的时候 就被狠狠的训了一顿
Dialogue: 0,0:08:42.96,0:08:45.03,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说什么 在我打开之前不许碰
Dialogue: 0,0:08:45.58,0:08:49.55,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了放置这些大开本书 还把书架改造了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:50.34,0:08:54.34,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,最后变成要把几乎所有的书都移走
Dialogue: 0,0:08:54.76,0:08:56.85,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这次又说什么帮忙
Dialogue: 0,0:08:58.27,0:08:59.97,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是
Dialogue: 0,0:09:00.47,0:09:02.17,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样吧
Dialogue: 0,0:09:02.68,0:09:05.57,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我现在带毛利侦探他们去客厅
Dialogue: 0,0:09:06.30,0:09:07.78,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你去帮忙整理书房吧
Dialogue: 0,0:09:08.78,0:09:12.91,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是 我还要去保养锻吾少爷的车
Dialogue: 0,0:09:13.09,0:09:16.63,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那辆车有两年没发动了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:17.03,0:09:18.93,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,放着不管也没什么关系吧
Dialogue: 0,0:09:19.43,0:09:20.94,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是 夫人
Dialogue: 0,0:09:21.07,0:09:23.13,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请这边走
Dialogue: 0,0:09:23.99,0:09:26.96,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车的保养以后也还可以做 麻烦你了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:27.08,0:09:27.70,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,0:09:30.32,0:09:31.45,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是这里了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:31.94,0:09:33.86,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这就是那个起居室吗
Dialogue: 0,0:09:34.12,0:09:35.01,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:09:35.56,0:09:39.46,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那天 我和丈夫 管家 还有女佣
Dialogue: 0,0:09:39.59,0:09:41.79,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,4个人一起在这里看录像
Dialogue: 0,0:09:42.18,0:09:45.18,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,去年我和丈夫去海外旅行时拍的
Dialogue: 0,0:09:45.19,0:09:46.75,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,长达5个小时
Dialogue: 0,0:09:47.33,0:09:50.50,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么令郎不一起看呢
Dialogue: 0,0:09:50.75,0:09:54.72,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一定是在回避我吧
Dialogue: 0,0:09:54.98,0:09:57.27,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不是他的生母
Dialogue: 0,0:09:58.60,0:09:59.76,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:59.80,0:10:03.48,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 锻吾是我丈夫前妻的儿子
Dialogue: 0,0:10:03.81,0:10:05.16,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他没对你说吗
Dialogue: 0,0:10:05.93,0:10:09.22,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过 我丈夫真的在怀疑我们吗
Dialogue: 0,0:10:09.47,0:10:10.36,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:10:10.75,0:10:15.25,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不管怎样抓不到犯人 怀疑我们也太...
Dialogue: 0,0:10:15.27,0:10:17.55,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我丈夫真是的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:21.40,0:10:22.60,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,起居室的厕所
Dialogue: 0,0:10:23.01,0:10:26.31,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,确实无法让一个大人进出
Dialogue: 0,0:10:27.80,0:10:31.60,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且 这里也没有能够偷偷进出的地方
Dialogue: 0,0:10:32.88,0:10:33.89,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样的话
Dialogue: 0,0:10:34.36,0:10:36.17,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在这里看录像的4个人
Dialogue: 0,0:10:36.23,0:10:37.75,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就有了完美的不在场证明
Dialogue: 0,0:10:37.96,0:10:39.68,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过我真是吃了一惊啊
Dialogue: 0,0:10:40.05,0:10:42.12,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,以前那么爱哭的瑛祐
Dialogue: 0,0:10:42.37,0:10:45.95,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,竟然带这么可爱的女朋友到我家来
Dialogue: 0,0:10:46.45,0:10:48.30,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 我们不是那种关系
Dialogue: 0,0:10:49.78,0:10:52.08,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她不是我的女朋友
Dialogue: 0,0:10:54.77,0:10:58.83,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们是为了搞清楚瑛祐哥哥的血型才来的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:59.23,0:11:03.36,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为听说瑛祐哥哥的母子手册在这里
Dialogue: 0,0:11:03.55,0:11:04.59,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:04.90,0:11:06.37,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,瑛祐哥哥
Dialogue: 0,0:11:08.50,0:11:10.74,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是 为什么要调查血型呢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:11.13,0:11:13.28,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,给毛利侦探看了我姐姐的照片后
Dialogue: 0,0:11:13.52,0:11:16.53,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他说 这不是水无怜奈主持人吗
Dialogue: 0,0:11:17.27,0:11:19.58,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了解除这个疑惑 我们才过来的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:19.91,0:11:23.85,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个水无怜奈主播是AB型 我是0型
Dialogue: 0,0:11:24.32,0:11:27.33,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,并且 我曾经接受过姐姐的输血
Dialogue: 0,0:11:27.56,0:11:30.67,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说 姐姐和那个主持人绝对不是同一个人
Dialogue: 0,0:11:30.81,0:11:31.89,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,瑛祐
Dialogue: 0,0:11:32.15,0:11:33.50,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,已经知道了啊
Dialogue: 0,0:11:34.23,0:11:36.92,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说起来 是有过这样的事情
Dialogue: 0,0:11:37.48,0:11:40.10,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,瑛祐好像是在母亲去世后
Dialogue: 0,0:11:40.57,0:11:44.21,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被父亲带到大阪生活
Dialogue: 0,0:11:44.33,0:11:46.18,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不久 他就遭遇了事故
Dialogue: 0,0:11:47.31,0:11:49.60,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我听说后赶过去
Dialogue: 0,0:11:49.87,0:11:54.48,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看见他姐姐靠在病床前精疲力尽的睡着了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:01.45,0:12:03.16,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,问护士怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:12:03.34,0:12:06.35,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好像是给弟弟输了大量的血
Dialogue: 0,0:12:07.14,0:12:12.44,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说是把我的血全给我弟弟都可以
Dialogue: 0,0:12:14.30,0:12:15.69,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这样吗
Dialogue: 0,0:12:16.75,0:12:18.15,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样就可以断定了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:19.55,0:12:20.81,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这家伙的姐姐
Dialogue: 0,0:12:20.88,0:12:24.91,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和水无怜奈不是同一个人
Dialogue: 0,0:12:31.43,0:12:33.86,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我平时不太看电视
Dialogue: 0,0:12:34.31,0:12:37.95,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他姐姐和那个人真的很像吗
Dialogue: 0,0:12:38.03,0:12:38.49,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:38.59,0:12:41.46,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,光看照片的话是一模一样
Dialogue: 0,0:12:41.67,0:12:43.63,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是您不觉得奇怪吗
Dialogue: 0,0:12:44.09,0:12:45.85,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,又不是分身
Dialogue: 0,0:12:46.82,0:12:49.50,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,世上会有那么相像的二个人吗
Dialogue: 0,0:12:49.84,0:12:52.56,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是不是和姐姐失踪有什么关系呢
Dialogue: 0,0:12:53.49,0:12:54.45,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个
Dialogue: 0,0:12:54.66,0:12:55.76,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:12:56.23,0:12:58.64,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他计划先引起叔叔对水无怜奈的怀疑
Dialogue: 0,0:12:58.74,0:13:02.21,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后叔叔去调查 挖掘真相
Dialogue: 0,0:13:02.55,0:13:05.56,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让他察觉她就是他的姐姐
Dialogue: 0,0:13:06.75,0:13:08.48,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,自己直接去找她的话
Dialogue: 0,0:13:08.50,0:13:10.46,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她可能会故意避而不见
Dialogue: 0,0:13:11.76,0:13:12.99,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那你们见个面怎么样
Dialogue: 0,0:13:13.09,0:13:13.96,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,事实上我们知道她的…
Dialogue: 0,0:13:13.97,0:13:17.13,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我说 我们去看看游泳池吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:17.52,0:13:21.07,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那样说不定可以知道一些您儿子的事情
Dialogue: 0,0:13:21.37,0:13:22.75,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那倒也是
Dialogue: 0,0:13:23.20,0:13:26.24,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是外面下着雨呢
Dialogue: 0,0:13:27.99,0:13:31.74,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,菊代 你要出去吗
Dialogue: 0,0:13:31.87,0:13:35.24,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 咖啡伴侣没有了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:35.58,0:13:37.25,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我去附近买一些
Dialogue: 0,0:13:37.60,0:13:39.01,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那不好意思
Dialogue: 0,0:13:40.26,0:13:42.94,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,帮我带大家去游泳池好吗
Dialogue: 0,0:13:43.25,0:13:45.11,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咖啡我去拿吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:45.17,0:13:46.70,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好的 没问题
Dialogue: 0,0:13:46.96,0:13:48.90,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那就拜托了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:48.98,0:13:49.82,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:13:56.31,0:13:58.65,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可真是脏啊
Dialogue: 0,0:13:59.08,0:14:04.29,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 一年前案发后就一直这样了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:05.03,0:14:06.80,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是好怀念啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:07.13,0:14:08.99,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也常在这个池子里玩
Dialogue: 0,0:14:13.01,0:14:14.39,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,瑛祐
Dialogue: 0,0:14:16.96,0:14:19.94,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是的 在这种地方也冒冒失失的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:28.27,0:14:29.26,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,正合适呢
Dialogue: 0,0:14:29.37,0:14:30.75,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思
Dialogue: 0,0:14:30.95,0:14:34.35,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只有去世的儿子的衣服尺寸合适
Dialogue: 0,0:14:34.39,0:14:35.35,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没关系
Dialogue: 0,0:14:35.38,0:14:38.55,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是说 您儿子也是小个子吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:38.75,0:14:40.62,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是有点肥
Dialogue: 0,0:14:40.73,0:14:41.51,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:42.35,0:14:44.87,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,锻吾经常健身
Dialogue: 0,0:14:44.96,0:14:48.83,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,衣服拿去洗了 请稍候
Dialogue: 0,0:14:48.91,0:14:50.09,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对了 菊代
Dialogue: 0,0:14:50.34,0:14:52.41,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,厨房里没有咖啡啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:52.54,0:14:53.84,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:14:54.06,0:14:57.42,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我把咖啡放在咖啡机里后才出去的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:58.15,0:14:59.40,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 濑川
Dialogue: 0,0:14:59.55,0:15:00.37,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:15:00.75,0:15:02.41,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你知道厨房的咖啡去哪儿了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:15:02.80,0:15:03.72,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不知道
Dialogue: 0,0:15:03.75,0:15:07.42,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,莫非是老爷等不及了 自己拿走了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:09.51,0:15:11.18,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是什么声音
Dialogue: 0,0:15:11.43,0:15:13.76,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是从老爷的书房里传出来的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:13.93,0:15:15.24,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我去看看
Dialogue: 0,0:15:15.52,0:15:16.49,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,拜托了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:16.71,0:15:19.06,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是刚才那个大花瓶吧
Dialogue: 0,0:15:19.38,0:15:20.73,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:21.03,0:15:25.24,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为那是叔叔从前就一直很珍惜的花瓶 值5000万呢
Dialogue: 0,0:15:28.52,0:15:29.65,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,停电了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:15:30.50,0:15:32.69,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,别开门
Dialogue: 0,0:15:34.76,0:15:35.93,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚才什么声音
Dialogue: 0,0:15:54.33,0:15:55.53,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,老爷
Dialogue: 0,0:15:56.18,0:15:57.26,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会
Dialogue: 0,0:15:57.51,0:15:58.83,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔他为什么
Dialogue: 0,0:15:58.95,0:15:59.80,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,老爷
Dialogue: 0,0:15:59.81,0:16:02.17,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,夫人 地板上还有花瓶的碎片
Dialogue: 0,0:16:02.78,0:16:03.97,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,您没事吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:04.56,0:16:05.98,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还好
Dialogue: 0,0:16:10.14,0:16:11.18,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,老爷
Dialogue: 0,0:16:11.66,0:16:13.53,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,总之赶快把他放下来吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:14.35,0:16:16.76,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小兰 赶快叫救护车和警察
Dialogue: 0,0:16:17.32,0:16:18.41,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:21.49,0:16:25.07,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可恶 这个绳子怎么解不开
Dialogue: 0,0:16:42.36,0:16:43.61,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,瓶口是
Dialogue: 0,0:16:44.95,0:16:46.16,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,湿的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:53.04,0:16:59.27,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很遗憾 您丈夫在送医院的途中抢救无效
Dialogue: 0,0:16:59.49,0:17:00.59,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会
Dialogue: 0,0:17:04.28,0:17:06.03,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,夫 夫人
Dialogue: 0,0:17:07.56,0:17:10.30,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,夫人 请用这个
Dialogue: 0,0:17:11.10,0:17:12.63,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢
Dialogue: 0,0:17:14.29,0:17:17.90,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可以的话我想问各位几个问题
Dialogue: 0,0:17:20.11,0:17:22.14,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,最先发现的人是谁
Dialogue: 0,0:17:23.11,0:17:29.14,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,最先发现的人是菊代和濑川 对吧
Dialogue: 0,0:17:29.23,0:17:33.92,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 我们听见这个书房里传来了什么东西打碎的声音
Dialogue: 0,0:17:33.97,0:17:36.34,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,马上赶过来敲门
Dialogue: 0,0:17:36.66,0:17:37.97,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是没有反应
Dialogue: 0,0:17:38.29,0:17:40.88,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为喊了好几声都没回应
Dialogue: 0,0:17:40.89,0:17:42.73,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,想转手柄开门的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:17:42.93,0:17:44.79,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可却听到里面大声叫着 别开门
Dialogue: 0,0:17:46.52,0:17:48.13,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那门开了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:17:48.32,0:17:49.73,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,门开了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:50.00,0:17:51.80,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们在想到底是什么声音
Dialogue: 0,0:17:51.89,0:17:56.68,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是开门后却看见老爷的身体悬在半空
Dialogue: 0,0:17:56.92,0:18:01.10,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说他正好是在开门前上吊的
Dialogue: 0,0:18:01.29,0:18:05.26,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 老爷的身体还在晃动
Dialogue: 0,0:18:06.33,0:18:10.49,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,窗户也锁的好好的只能认为是自杀啊
Dialogue: 0,0:18:10.51,0:18:13.34,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是为什么说别开门呢
Dialogue: 0,0:18:13.64,0:18:17.63,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那肯定是因为不想让别人看见自己要死的情形吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:18.19,0:18:23.62,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看来你家主人是厌倦了这个世界才选择了死亡
Dialogue: 0,0:18:24.69,0:18:26.19,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么又是你啊
Dialogue: 0,0:18:26.82,0:18:31.05,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请看地板上这花瓶的碎片 警部大人
Dialogue: 0,0:18:31.64,0:18:35.50,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那正是所打碎的东西
Dialogue: 0,0:18:35.61,0:18:40.01,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且这是这里的主人最宝贝的五千万的花瓶
Dialogue: 0,0:18:40.11,0:18:41.26,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,五千万
Dialogue: 0,0:18:41.32,0:18:42.45,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这样吗
Dialogue: 0,0:18:42.61,0:18:43.60,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:18:43.77,0:18:48.30,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,老爷还一直得意地说现在都值2亿了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:48.74,0:18:52.33,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,打碎这个花瓶再自杀的话
Dialogue: 0,0:18:52.50,0:18:55.29,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,正是再明白不过的厌世的证据了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:55.37,0:18:58.14,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是遗体解剖的结论是
Dialogue: 0,0:18:58.21,0:19:02.24,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,遗体的胃中除了咖啡外还有安眠药
Dialogue: 0,0:19:02.31,0:19:03.11,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咖啡
Dialogue: 0,0:19:04.21,0:19:05.06,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个吗
Dialogue: 0,0:19:05.76,0:19:07.53,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么有2个杯子
Dialogue: 0,0:19:07.60,0:19:09.07,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一个是我的
Dialogue: 0,0:19:09.15,0:19:10.31,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是自杀前
Dialogue: 0,0:19:10.38,0:19:13.56,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,特意喝下有安眠药的咖啡有点不合理啊
Dialogue: 0,0:19:13.57,0:19:18.37,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那一定是他一开始喝了大量的安眠药准备自杀
Dialogue: 0,0:19:18.38,0:19:19.56,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是没有成功
Dialogue: 0,0:19:19.71,0:19:22.20,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以改变了手段
Dialogue: 0,0:19:22.52,0:19:25.85,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且为了使绳子不会松开
Dialogue: 0,0:19:25.86,0:19:27.07,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,绳子的接口处还涂了粘合剂
Dialogue: 0,0:19:27.34,0:19:28.53,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,粘合剂
Dialogue: 0,0:19:28.60,0:19:29.41,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:19:29.50,0:19:33.21,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我解绳子把他放下来的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:19:33.27,0:19:36.29,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,发现绳结上有粘合剂
Dialogue: 0,0:19:36.47,0:19:39.63,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那自杀动机又是什么
Dialogue: 0,0:19:39.80,0:19:41.92,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有什么线索吗
Dialogue: 0,0:19:42.95,0:19:44.10,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有
Dialogue: 0,0:19:44.16,0:19:45.27,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么说来
Dialogue: 0,0:19:45.52,0:19:49.60,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他说过有事找我 要我之后去书房
Dialogue: 0,0:19:49.93,0:19:53.59,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,会不会是有什么烦恼的事情
Dialogue: 0,0:19:54.18,0:19:58.35,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那为什么要在和你们商量之前自杀呢
Dialogue: 0,0:19:58.38,0:20:01.08,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他是不是认为说了也没用的
Dialogue: 0,0:20:01.50,0:20:07.37,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么说来 你们的主人好像不怎么信任你们啊
Dialogue: 0,0:20:08.09,0:20:11.73,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,老爷的口中滴出了血
Dialogue: 0,0:20:11.89,0:20:14.68,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,恐怕是因为不甘心而咬了嘴唇
Dialogue: 0,0:20:15.11,0:20:19.50,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,自己死后也不愿花瓶落入他人之手
Dialogue: 0,0:20:20.22,0:20:23.71,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以干脆踩踏在上面打碎花瓶
Dialogue: 0,0:20:23.72,0:20:24.56,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这样啊
Dialogue: 0,0:20:24.57,0:20:27.79,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个叔叔果然很贪婪啊
Dialogue: 0,0:20:27.88,0:20:28.32,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:20:28.73,0:20:32.36,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是如果踩踏在上面所以发出花瓶打碎的声音的话
Dialogue: 0,0:20:32.53,0:20:35.39,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那说明那个叔叔已经被吊住脖子
Dialogue: 0,0:20:35.81,0:20:37.38,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果不是很贪婪的话
Dialogue: 0,0:20:37.40,0:20:41.53,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,之后大叫不给你的话是不可能的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:44.70,0:20:46.34,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南不对啦
Dialogue: 0,0:20:46.66,0:20:49.41,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是不给你 是别开门
Dialogue: 0,0:20:49.55,0:20:51.18,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:20:51.33,0:20:53.24,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么说来很奇怪啊
Dialogue: 0,0:20:53.59,0:20:56.46,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,脖子被吊住了怎么还能大喊
Dialogue: 0,0:20:56.82,0:21:01.66,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么说花瓶打碎时 脖子没有被吊住
Dialogue: 0,0:21:02.00,0:21:05.76,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是因为那个花瓶被打碎受了打击才自杀
Dialogue: 0,0:21:05.85,0:21:08.19,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 听到声音就赶过来的话
Dialogue: 0,0:21:08.31,0:21:10.21,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是没有时间穿绳子的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:10.50,0:21:12.86,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 会不会是因为这个
Dialogue: 0,0:21:13.99,0:21:16.73,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看这本书被血弄脏了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:16.88,0:21:20.41,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,肯定是很喜欢的书所以很失望
Dialogue: 0,0:21:20.72,0:21:22.82,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,来自黄泉的杀人者
Dialogue: 0,0:21:23.30,0:21:27.18,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个位置正好是这家主人的脚下方
Dialogue: 0,0:21:32.50,0:21:37.04,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个会不会是死亡讯息呢
Dialogue: 0,0:21:37.26,0:21:38.50,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说什么胡话啊
Dialogue: 0,0:21:39.02,0:21:42.90,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道说犯人是来自黄泉的鬼怪吗
Dialogue: 0,0:21:43.44,0:21:46.82,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 讯息是指
Dialogue: 0,0:21:47.29,0:21:49.97,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,沾了很多血的“黄泉”
Dialogue: 0,0:21:50.26,0:21:55.36,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和下面的血组成的像“ko”一样的字
Dialogue: 0,0:21:55.74,0:21:57.59,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,黄泉ko（日语发音：yomiko）
Dialogue: 0,0:21:57.82,0:21:58.78,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,日历（日语发音：yomiko 与前一句同音词）
Dialogue: 0,0:21:59.05,0:22:00.90,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是和日期有关么
Dialogue: 0,0:22:01.13,0:22:04.40,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 是不是这样还不知道
Dialogue: 0,0:22:04.49,0:22:06.40,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,像这样横过来的话
Dialogue: 0,0:22:06.50,0:22:09.25,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和平假名的i和ri也很像
Dialogue: 0,0:22:09.62,0:22:13.37,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果那是死亡讯息的话
Dialogue: 0,0:22:14.34,0:22:21.73,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们的主人就是被这个屋里的人杀害的
Dialogue: 0,0:24:06.40,0:24:09.36,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,用血留下的讯息是什么意思
Dialogue: 0,0:24:09.93,0:24:11.31,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,残忍的手法
Dialogue: 0,0:24:11.77,0:24:14.03,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那才是解开谜团的钥匙
Dialogue: 0,0:24:15.37,0:24:17.04,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下一回 名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:24:17.51,0:24:20.23,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,红与黑的碰撞 冥土
Dialogue: 0,0:24:23.74,0:24:26.38,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,写成五线谱的真相调查
Dialogue: 0,0:24:30.18,0:24:31.08,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,最新剧场版
Dialogue: 0,0:24:31.27,0:24:33.71,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,名侦探柯南 战栗的总谱
Dialogue: 0,0:24:51.57,0:24:53.23,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,Next Conan's HINT
Dialogue: 0,0:24:53.61,0:24:55.07,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,垫脚石
Dialogue: 0,0:24:55.74,0:24:57.68,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,高木警官来当垫脚石
Dialogue: 0,0:24:57.69,0:24:58.45,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那我也来
Dialogue: 0,0:24:58.46,0:24:59.41,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也来
Dialogue: 0,0:24:59.82,0:25:00.65,Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好重
