[Script Info]
Title: 504. 红与黑的碰撞 殉职
Original Script: 
Synch Point:0
ScriptType:v4.00+
Collisions:Normal
PlayResX:640
PlayResY:360
Timer:100.0000

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,simhei,26,&H00FFFFFF,&HF0000000,&H00FF8000,&H00FF8000,-1,0,0,0,100,100,0,0.00,1,1,2,2,30,30,2,1

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Actor, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text

Dialogue: 0,0:00:07.37,0:00:10.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,将我身体弄小的黑衣组织
Dialogue: 0,0:00:11.54,0:00:14.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,以及至今多次在我快要揪出组织尾巴之时
Dialogue: 0,0:00:15.38,0:00:17.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,成为我战友的FBI
Dialogue: 0,0:00:19.30,0:00:21.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,按照计划回到组织的基尔
Dialogue: 0,0:00:22.49,0:00:23.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,却遭到了琴酒的怀疑
Dialogue: 0,0:00:24.14,0:00:26.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接到了除掉赤井的命令
Dialogue: 0,0:00:28.60,0:00:30.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在新米花酒店发生的这起杀人事件
Dialogue: 0,0:00:32.03,0:00:34.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真 真的这样就能找出凶手？
Dialogue: 0,0:00:35.08,0:00:35.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:00:36.38,0:00:39.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是从新一哥哥那儿听来的咒语 绝对奏效
Dialogue: 0,0:00:40.00,0:00:40.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,试试看
Dialogue: 0,0:00:41.30,0:00:42.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,既然四个人到齐了
Dialogue: 0,0:00:43.17,0:00:43.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,首先…
Dialogue: 0,0:00:49.16,0:00:50.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“しらんぷり(SHIRANPURI)”
Dialogue: 0,0:00:59.26,0:01:01.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一句魔法咒语 事件尘埃落定
Dialogue: 0,0:01:03.09,0:01:05.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,与此同时 FBI的赤井搜查官
Dialogue: 0,0:01:06.24,0:01:08.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被回到黑衣组织的基尔
Dialogue: 0,0:01:09.12,0:01:11.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是CIA的成员水无怜奈叫了出去
Dialogue: 0,0:01:12.41,0:01:15.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,驶向了会面地点 来叶山路
Dialogue: 0,0:01:30.52,0:01:31.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,热辣刺激的悬念
Dialogue: 0,0:01:32.20,0:01:34.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,急驰在黑暗中的红色尖叫和黑色子弹
Dialogue: 0,0:01:34.83,0:01:36.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,响彻在山路的枪声
Dialogue: 0,0:01:36.57,0:01:38.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,FBI赤井秀一会是怎样的命运
Dialogue: 0,0:01:38.82,0:01:40.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看清惟一的真相
Dialogue: 0,0:01:40.12,0:01:41.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,外表看似小孩 头脑却是大人
Dialogue: 0,0:01:41.86,0:01:43.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他的名字就叫 名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:03:12.83,0:03:15.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,红与黑的碰撞 殉职
Dialogue: 0,0:04:06.22,0:04:07.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,C CIA
Dialogue: 0,0:04:09.01,0:04:10.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你在说什么啊
Dialogue: 0,0:04:10.46,0:04:12.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,姐姐你怎么会
Dialogue: 0,0:04:12.88,0:04:15.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喂 真是莫名其妙
Dialogue: 0,0:04:15.84,0:04:17.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等等 我还有话要说
Dialogue: 0,0:04:20.09,0:04:20.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小瑛
Dialogue: 0,0:04:27.62,0:04:28.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:04:28.72,0:04:30.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不能放弃啊 瑛海
Dialogue: 0,0:04:30.97,0:04:33.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等下去 一定会有战友出现的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:35.45,0:04:37.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,代替我完成任务
Dialogue: 0,0:05:23.24,0:05:27.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哎呀 怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:27.88,0:05:30.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会从反方向过来
Dialogue: 0,0:05:33.20,0:05:36.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我先转了一圈 四处查看了一番
Dialogue: 0,0:05:37.24,0:05:37.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:38.97,0:05:42.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么 你确定真的得到了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:43.74,0:05:47.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我只身前来的确凿证据
Dialogue: 0,0:05:52.44,0:05:53.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好像是的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:56.16,0:05:59.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,能不能让我听听你所说的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:59.69,0:06:01.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,以帮你远走高飞为交换条件的情报
Dialogue: 0,0:06:06.68,0:06:09.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错 能提供给你的是…
Dialogue: 0,0:07:04.48,0:07:06.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,保时捷356A
Dialogue: 0,0:07:10.44,0:07:11.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:07:22.81,0:07:23.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了 基尔
Dialogue: 0,0:07:24.54,0:07:25.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快给他最后一击
Dialogue: 0,0:07:27.78,0:07:30.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是 肺部已经被打穿了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:31.85,0:07:34.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,丢在这里 顶多坚持30分钟
Dialogue: 0,0:07:36.14,0:07:37.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,脑袋
Dialogue: 0,0:07:38.88,0:07:41.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,朝他脑袋开一枪
Dialogue: 0,0:07:41.93,0:07:45.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样才能让他 完全断气
Dialogue: 0,0:07:47.27,0:07:48.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,收到
Dialogue: 0,0:08:07.25,0:08:09.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真没想到会走到这一步
Dialogue: 0,0:08:10.33,0:08:11.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也吃了一惊
Dialogue: 0,0:08:13.06,0:08:15.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,居然进展得这么顺利
Dialogue: 0,0:08:44.36,0:08:45.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,警察
Dialogue: 0,0:08:47.21,0:08:50.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,八成是附近发生事故了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:52.19,0:08:54.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,基尔 收拾残局 撤退
Dialogue: 0,0:08:55.42,0:08:56.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,收到
Dialogue: 0,0:09:04.79,0:09:07.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可别 可别怪我啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:38.08,0:09:38.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎 怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:09:41.18,0:09:42.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快 联系署里
Dialogue: 0,0:09:43.37,0:09:43.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:09:58.64,0:10:00.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,搞什么 怎么不接电话
Dialogue: 0,0:10:00.90,0:10:03.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好不容易用向柯南借的手机打通了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:04.91,0:10:07.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,竟然不接电话 秀这家伙
Dialogue: 0,0:10:07.50,0:10:08.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可能是在打盹吧
Dialogue: 0,0:10:09.80,0:10:13.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为这回的事情赤井先生都没怎么睡觉
Dialogue: 0,0:10:13.36,0:10:13.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:15.02,0:10:16.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么样 柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:10:17.63,0:10:21.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你不是说在我们撤离医院前想再来一次吗
Dialogue: 0,0:10:24.38,0:10:26.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,现在同我们一起去吗
Dialogue: 0,0:10:26.72,0:10:28.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,开始是这么想的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:28.64,0:10:29.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还是不去了啦
Dialogue: 0,0:10:30.48,0:10:32.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我一个小孩子乱晃悠会添麻烦的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:33.71,0:10:36.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且今天是13号又是星期五
Dialogue: 0,0:10:37.74,0:10:40.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还是老老实实回去睡觉啦
Dialogue: 0,0:10:40.95,0:10:42.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再联系 朱蒂老师
Dialogue: 0,0:10:43.41,0:10:45.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,13号 星期五
Dialogue: 0,0:10:48.94,0:10:49.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小心点
Dialogue: 0,0:10:52.13,0:10:54.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天有点不祥的预感
Dialogue: 0,0:10:56.97,0:10:59.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不就因为今天是13号又是星期五吗
Dialogue: 0,0:11:01.28,0:11:04.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这种事 我从不介意
Dialogue: 0,0:11:05.97,0:11:06.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:11:20.85,0:11:24.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,秀 秀被水无怜奈叫出去见面了？
Dialogue: 0,0:11:25.99,0:11:30.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你走之后她打电话给赤井
Dialogue: 0,0:11:31.52,0:11:32.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说要两个人单独见面
Dialogue: 0,0:11:33.53,0:11:36.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,两个人？ 那肯定是陷阱啊
Dialogue: 0,0:11:37.07,0:11:39.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么 为什么没阻止他
Dialogue: 0,0:11:39.77,0:11:41.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我阻止过他
Dialogue: 0,0:11:42.11,0:11:45.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他说不去的话她会很危险 硬是去了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:46.53,0:11:50.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过是赤井的话不用担心啦
Dialogue: 0,0:11:51.25,0:11:56.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个 他们约定见面的地方是来叶山路吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:58.53,0:12:04.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚才电视里播报在来叶山路发现有车辆起火
Dialogue: 0,0:12:04.68,0:12:07.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,里面发现了一具被烧焦的尸体
Dialogue: 0,0:12:08.07,0:12:08.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:12:10.30,0:12:12.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,起火的是一辆黑色的雪佛莱
Dialogue: 0,0:12:12.59,0:12:15.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,乘坐者是20至30岁左右的男子
Dialogue: 0,0:12:15.94,0:12:18.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,发现者是 因为其它事件
Dialogue: 0,0:12:18.66,0:12:20.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,偶然经过的警车中的警官
Dialogue: 0,0:12:21.57,0:12:23.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,根据那位警官的描述
Dialogue: 0,0:12:23.64,0:12:26.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车子是突然在眼前发生爆炸的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:26.64,0:12:29.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,尸体上有被枪击过的痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:12:29.92,0:12:32.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因此警方将作为谋杀事件展开调查
Dialogue: 0,0:12:33.16,0:12:36.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从车牌号和除右手外几乎都被烧尽的尸体上看…
Dialogue: 0,0:12:36.84,0:12:38.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不对 这不是秀
Dialogue: 0,0:12:38.97,0:12:41.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,肯定是用组织的什么人伪装的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:42.08,0:12:43.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他的话肯定会这么做的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:43.82,0:12:45.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也有同感
Dialogue: 0,0:12:45.90,0:12:49.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,去警局确认的话一定就清楚了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:49.44,0:12:51.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是就算是要去确认
Dialogue: 0,0:12:51.48,0:12:53.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,尸体也已经烧毁了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:54.57,0:12:56.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果遗体留下右手的话
Dialogue: 0,0:12:56.35,0:12:59.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和赤井的指纹核对一下就知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:59.41,0:13:03.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那和登记在FBI里的赤井的指纹进行核对的话…
Dialogue: 0,0:13:03.72,0:13:06.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“为了认证身份要借用那只右手
Dialogue: 0,0:13:07.15,0:13:10.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为那具尸体很可能是FBI的搜查官”
Dialogue: 0,0:13:11.13,0:13:12.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道要这么说吗
Dialogue: 0,0:13:14.62,0:13:16.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赤井的雪佛莱也一样
Dialogue: 0,0:13:17.14,0:13:20.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,上面肯定有他的指纹
Dialogue: 0,0:13:20.30,0:13:23.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是烧毁了而且被警方回收了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:23.62,0:13:27.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果我们不说理由就要求收回也不可能吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:29.60,0:13:31.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有没有可以把他的指纹
Dialogue: 0,0:13:31.57,0:13:33.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和尸体右手的指纹相核对
Dialogue: 0,0:13:33.92,0:13:37.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而又不被怀疑的方法呢
Dialogue: 0,0:13:37.57,0:13:40.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,用沾有他指纹的手机的话
Dialogue: 0,0:13:40.99,0:13:43.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想也许可以顺利调查到
Dialogue: 0,0:13:43.93,0:13:46.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是他的手机
Dialogue: 0,0:13:49.07,0:13:51.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个是从柯南那里借来的手机
Dialogue: 0,0:13:53.30,0:13:55.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那我到外面去打电话叫他过来
Dialogue: 0,0:13:56.53,0:13:57.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他肯定会马上来的
Dialogue: 0,0:13:59.99,0:14:03.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就算是你也不行
Dialogue: 0,0:14:04.92,0:14:07.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个是我们FBI的工作
Dialogue: 0,0:14:09.70,0:14:13.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不能再把一般的市民卷进来了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:14.81,0:14:15.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是
Dialogue: 0,0:14:17.34,0:14:19.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接下来就交给我们吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:21.00,0:14:23.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么 赤井的指纹
Dialogue: 0,0:14:24.42,0:14:26.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我带着这个去警署
Dialogue: 0,0:14:27.84,0:14:30.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等一下 我开车送你去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:30.85,0:14:31.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是我啰嗦
Dialogue: 0,0:14:32.06,0:14:36.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个人是和我们FBI有联系的人的这件事…
Dialogue: 0,0:14:37.88,0:14:40.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我会用好借口 绝不会被怀疑的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:48.99,0:14:52.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可能是帮你捡过手机的人？
Dialogue: 0,0:14:52.49,0:14:55.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是刚刚被发现的烧焦的男人吗
Dialogue: 0,0:14:56.99,0:15:00.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天上午我碰巧也去来叶山路兜风
Dialogue: 0,0:15:01.44,0:15:03.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在途中的驾驶服务站用餐
Dialogue: 0,0:15:04.29,0:15:06.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那时我不小心掉了电话
Dialogue: 0,0:15:06.99,0:15:09.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个男子帮我拾了起来
Dialogue: 0,0:15:10.34,0:15:12.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个人也驾驶着黑色的雪佛莱
Dialogue: 0,0:15:12.73,0:15:13.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想可能是他
Dialogue: 0,0:15:14.81,0:15:16.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,相貌和服装我都记得
Dialogue: 0,0:15:17.58,0:15:19.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想对你们的调查可能有帮助
Dialogue: 0,0:15:19.92,0:15:20.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:15:21.29,0:15:24.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那这个手机先由我保管
Dialogue: 0,0:15:25.82,0:15:27.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个手机由于一些原因
Dialogue: 0,0:15:27.76,0:15:29.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是向柯南借的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:30.42,0:15:33.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想上面可能也有柯南的指纹
Dialogue: 0,0:15:33.88,0:15:36.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明白了 我马上去检验
Dialogue: 0,0:15:36.86,0:15:38.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请稍等一下
Dialogue: 0,0:15:48.23,0:15:49.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,调查结果出来了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:51.35,0:15:52.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎 怎么样
Dialogue: 0,0:15:53.11,0:15:56.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,果然是我多心了 对吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:01.78,0:16:03.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让您特地过来真不好意思
Dialogue: 0,0:16:04.60,0:16:08.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哪里 我才不好意思呢
Dialogue: 0,0:16:09.64,0:16:12.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个男子的特征没有记着多少
Dialogue: 0,0:16:13.32,0:16:17.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是那具尸体还有不少疑点
Dialogue: 0,0:16:17.55,0:16:20.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果想起其它什么 请和我们联系
Dialogue: 0,0:16:20.99,0:16:21.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,当然
Dialogue: 0,0:16:23.24,0:16:25.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么今天谢谢你了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:31.79,0:16:34.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,调查结果正如您所说的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:34.84,0:16:37.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你和柯南的指纹都有
Dialogue: 0,0:16:38.45,0:16:42.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚才那个被烧焦的男子指纹也有
Dialogue: 0,0:16:46.61,0:16:48.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看你的样子
Dialogue: 0,0:16:48.80,0:16:51.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,果然那具尸体是赤井吗
Dialogue: 0,0:16:54.97,0:16:58.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,即使是这样 我们也不能责怪水无怜奈
Dialogue: 0,0:16:59.56,0:17:01.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不那样做的话也许被杀的就是她了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:02.90,0:17:05.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她对赤井不也那样说过吗
Dialogue: 0,0:17:06.84,0:17:08.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果有万一的情况
Dialogue: 0,0:17:08.64,0:17:10.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我会以CIA的任务为优先
Dialogue: 0,0:17:11.72,0:17:16.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要是对FBI有什么不利请不要见怪
Dialogue: 0,0:17:16.48,0:17:17.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吧
Dialogue: 0,0:17:18.30,0:17:19.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过这样一来
Dialogue: 0,0:17:19.03,0:17:22.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们如同在组织里打入了一根楔子
Dialogue: 0,0:17:23.39,0:17:26.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一根永远也不会脱落的钢楔
Dialogue: 0,0:17:28.40,0:17:33.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,或许赤井为了把这根钢楔带入组织
Dialogue: 0,0:17:33.37,0:17:34.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而故意牺牲的
Dialogue: 0,0:17:36.38,0:17:40.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是这个代价实在是 实在是太大了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:41.09,0:17:41.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,秀
Dialogue: 0,0:17:42.44,0:17:46.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,秀
Dialogue: 0,0:17:52.49,0:17:53.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什 什么
Dialogue: 0,0:17:55.50,0:17:57.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这里是来福枪的死角
Dialogue: 0,0:18:01.18,0:18:02.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你什么时候
Dialogue: 0,0:18:02.78,0:18:03.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把枪扔了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:05.57,0:18:06.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快把枪扔了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:07.42,0:18:09.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,否则下一枪就瞄准你的头了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:14.62,0:18:17.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这声音 霰弹枪？
Dialogue: 0,0:18:17.81,0:18:21.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,OK 卡尔瓦多斯 夹击她
Dialogue: 0,0:18:24.36,0:18:26.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,糟了 从后面来了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:42.82,0:18:44.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么卡尔瓦多斯
Dialogue: 0,0:18:44.65,0:18:49.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,用你钟爱的霰弹枪把我们FBI的小猫干掉吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:52.33,0:18:55.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来那个男人叫卡尔瓦多斯啊
Dialogue: 0,0:18:59.71,0:19:02.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,来福枪 霰弹枪 还有3把手枪
Dialogue: 0,0:19:05.15,0:19:07.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我还以为是哪里来的军火贩子呢
Dialogue: 0,0:19:09.03,0:19:10.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赤井秀一
Dialogue: 0,0:19:10.96,0:19:11.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,秀
Dialogue: 0,0:19:21.48,0:19:24.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不行 秀 不能杀她
Dialogue: 0,0:19:35.14,0:19:38.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在那种情况下靠后视镜居然能够射中油箱
Dialogue: 0,0:19:40.10,0:19:40.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她可真不赖啊
Dialogue: 0,0:19:41.26,0:19:44.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,秀 你还在那里佩服什么呀
Dialogue: 0,0:19:45.12,0:19:47.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她带着人质逃走了不是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:19:49.08,0:19:51.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你应该把车钥匙拔下来啊
Dialogue: 0,0:19:54.04,0:19:56.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么接下去就拜托你了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:58.56,0:20:03.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我还不能和那个茶色头发的女孩见面
Dialogue: 0,0:20:12.59,0:20:17.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,秀 你不是还有没办完的事吗
Dialogue: 0,0:20:24.31,0:20:25.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,秀
Dialogue: 0,0:20:27.01,0:20:28.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,秀
Dialogue: 0,0:21:11.05,0:21:12.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,根本不需要两发
Dialogue: 0,0:21:15.35,0:21:19.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,银色子弹 一发就够了
Dialogue: 0,0:22:51.62,0:22:52.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个 给你
Dialogue: 0,0:22:55.33,0:22:57.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,向你借的手机
Dialogue: 0,0:22:58.06,0:22:59.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个 你不用了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:23:02.06,0:23:05.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个手机我们暂时还要保管一段时间
Dialogue: 0,0:23:06.42,0:23:10.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南的话 把这个一样的手机给他好吗
Dialogue: 0,0:23:11.46,0:23:15.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,SIM卡在你那里的话肯定可以用的
Dialogue: 0,0:23:16.61,0:23:19.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那谢谢你了 柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:23:27.20,0:23:28.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,序列号变了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:30.16,0:23:31.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,朱蒂老师
Dialogue: 0,0:23:33.66,0:23:34.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:23:35.66,0:23:38.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以 请加油
Dialogue: 0,0:23:45.45,0:23:46.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喂 柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:23:46.86,0:23:48.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你还在磨蹭什么
Dialogue: 0,0:23:48.25,0:23:49.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要迟到了哦
Dialogue: 0,0:24:09.60,0:24:10.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:24:11.24,0:24:13.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚才听到了奇怪的声音吧
Dialogue: 0,0:24:15.36,0:24:16.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,Next Conan
Dialogue: 0,0:24:16.82,0:24:19.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,律师妃英理的证词 (前篇)
Dialogue: 0,0:24:36.65,0:24:38.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,Next Conan's HINT
Dialogue: 0,0:24:38.65,0:24:40.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,头发
Dialogue: 0,0:24:41.04,0:24:41.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,开始
Dialogue: 0,0:24:41.82,0:24:42.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下回事件发生在美发店
Dialogue: 0,0:24:43.06,0:24:43.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,CUT
Dialogue: 0,0:24:43.97,0:24:44.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,剪得不错
Dialogue: 0,0:24:44.92,0:24:45.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吧
