[Script Info]
Title: 名探偵コナン 第539話「愚か者への遺産」
Original Script: APTX4869
Original Translation: 哉跟头
Original Editing: 吉法师 Global
Original Timing: LBS123456 xiaobin
Script Updated By: 無限的咖鲤棒 拾掇忧伤
Synch Point: 0
ScriptType: v4.00+
Collisions: Normal
PlayResX: 1280
PlayResY: 720
Timer: 100.0000
ScaledBorderAndShadow: Yes

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,微软雅黑,54,&H00FFFFFF,&HF0000000,&H00000000,&H70000000,-1,0,0,0,100,100,0,0,1,1,1,2,30,30,15,1
Style: note,微软雅黑,36,&H00FFFFFF,&HF0000000,&H00000000,&H70000000,-1,0,0,0,100,100,0,0,1,1,0,8,30,30,15,1
Style: Title,方正美黑_GBK,55,&H00FFFFFF,&HF0000000,&H00000000,&H70000000,0,0,0,0,110,100,0,0,1,0,0,5,30,30,15,1
Style: opcn,APTX柯黑,40,&H00FFFFFF,&HF0000000,&H10FFFFFF,&H20111111,0,0,0,0,116,95,1,0,1,0.35,2.5,5,30,30,20,1
Style: edcn,APTX柯黑,40,&H00FFFFFF,&HF0000000,&H33333333,&HF0000000,0,0,0,0,116,95,1,0,1,3,0,5,30,30,20,1

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Name, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text
Comment: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:00.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,---=== Prologue ===---
Comment: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:00.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,---=== Lead-in ===---
Comment: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:00.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,---=== Opening Theme ===---
Comment: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:00.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,---=== Title ===---
Comment: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:00.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,---=== A Part ===---
Comment: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:00.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,---=== B Part ===---
;Dialogue: 0,0:19:07.97,0:19:12.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,哭到泪干了后能形成盐的结晶的程度吗
;Dialogue: 0,0:19:18.89,0:19:21.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因为自己太过娇纵抚养
;Dialogue: 0,0:19:21.56,0:19:25.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,孩子们怎么也不能够自立
;Dialogue: 0,0:19:25.62,0:19:27.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,正因这样 自己的孩子们
;Dialogue: 0,0:19:27.48,0:19:30.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,居然搞出了假装犯罪的勾当
;Dialogue: 0,0:19:30.88,0:19:36.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还有 对儿子们的援助已经没办法继续了
;Dialogue: 0,0:19:37.67,0:19:38.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,援助已经没办法继续了？
Comment: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:00.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,---=== Ending Theme ===---
Comment: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:00.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,---=== Epilogue ===---
Comment: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:00.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,---=== Next Episode Preview ===---
Comment: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:00.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,---=== Summer Present ===---
Comment: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:00.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,---=== Next Conan's HINT ===---

Dialogue: 0,0:00:07.46,0:00:08.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爬上这个斜坡后
Dialogue: 0,0:00:09.12,0:00:11.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有一座因绣球花(hydrangea)而出名的寺庙
Dialogue: 0,0:00:11.66,0:00:14.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的很漂亮哦
Dialogue: 0,0:00:14.93,0:00:15.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,咦？
Dialogue: 0,0:00:16.33,0:00:18.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么嘛 根本没有嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:00:18.88,0:00:22.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,奇怪了 是哪里出错了
Dialogue: 0,0:00:32.33,0:00:34.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爱无止境 谜无终结
Dialogue: 0,0:00:34.34,0:00:35.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,星期六晚上是推理时间
Dialogue: 0,0:00:36.92,0:00:38.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不明白父母之心的三兄弟
Dialogue: 0,0:00:39.13,0:00:40.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,围绕遗产展开的悲哀案件
Dialogue: 0,0:00:41.28,0:00:42.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看清唯一的真相
Dialogue: 0,0:00:42.89,0:00:44.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,外表看似小孩 头脑却是大人
Dialogue: 0,0:00:44.71,0:00:46.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他的名字就叫 名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:00:46.43,0:00:51.27,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(468,670)\fscx114}眼睁睁看着近在身旁的你
Dialogue: 0,0:00:46.43,0:00:51.27,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(848,670)\fscx115}我却无法将心意传递
Dialogue: 0,0:00:51.44,0:00:54.83,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(641,670)\fad(0,50)\fscx118}时钟的指针永远不会倒退
Dialogue: 0,0:00:56.48,0:01:01.16,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(440,670)}曾经一同欣赏的风景
Dialogue: 0,0:00:56.48,0:01:01.16,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(815,670)\fscx111}为了让它能永存于我心底
Dialogue: 0,0:01:01.32,0:01:03.66,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(642.5,670)\fscx118}把记忆的碎片收集整理
Dialogue: 0,0:01:03.66,0:01:13.09,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(366,670)\fscx119}清澈的双眸中
Dialogue: 0,0:01:03.66,0:01:13.09,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(762,670)\fscx114}你看到的我已不再是从前的那个我
Dialogue: 0,0:01:14.80,0:01:20.76,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(394.5,672)\fs42\fsp1.1\bord0.25\fscx107}E{\fscx86}v{\fscx95}e{\fscx88}r{\fscx96}lasti{\fscx98}ng
Dialogue: 0,0:01:14.80,0:01:20.76,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(549,672)\fscx96\fs42\fsp1.5\bord0.25}Luv
Dialogue: 0,0:01:14.80,0:01:20.76,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(796,670)\fscx113}在如迷宫般缭乱的世界里
Dialogue: 0,0:01:20.76,0:01:24.64,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(646,670)}将这不变的思念寄予{\fsp5}你{\fsp8.5\b1}···
Dialogue: 0,0:01:24.81,0:01:29.94,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(392,672)\fs42\fsp1.1\bord0.25\fscx107}E{\fscx86}v{\fscx95}e{\fscx85}r{\fscx96}lasti{\fscx98}ng
Dialogue: 0,0:01:24.81,0:01:29.94,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(546,672)\fscx96\fs42\fsp1.5\bord0.25}Luv
Dialogue: 0,0:01:24.81,0:01:29.94,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(796,670)}虽然现在的我还开不了口
Dialogue: 0,0:01:30.27,0:01:33.98,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(468,670)\fad(50,0)\fscx115}但我永远只爱你一个
Dialogue: 0,0:01:30.27,0:01:33.98,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(758.5,672)\fad(50,0)\fscx100\fsp-1\bord0.25\fnkaiti\fs35}（{\fnAPTX柯黑\fs42\fscx107\fsp1.1}E{\fscx86}v{\fscx95}e{\fscx88}r{\fscx96}lasti{\fscx98}ng
Dialogue: 0,0:01:30.27,0:01:33.98,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(946,672)\fad(50,0)\fscx95\fs42\fsp1.5\bord0.25}Lu{\fsp1}v{\fnkaiti\fs35}）
Dialogue: 0,0:01:34.15,0:01:42.07,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(488,670)\fscx115}如果有一个愿望能被实现
Dialogue: 0,0:01:34.15,0:01:42.07,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(849,670)\fscx115}我只愿回到你身边
Dialogue: 0,0:01:42.07,0:01:43.99,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(599,672)\fscx96\fsp1.1\fs42\bord0.25\fscx107}E{\fscx86}v{\fscx95}e{\fscx88}r{\fscx96}lasti{\fscx98}ng
Dialogue: 0,0:01:42.07,0:01:43.99,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(754.5,672)\fscx96\fsp1.5\fs42\bord0.25}Luv
Dialogue: 0,0:01:43.99,0:01:52.25,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(430,670)\fscx113}等到所有的谜题都拨云见日
Dialogue: 0,0:01:43.99,0:01:52.25,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(864,670)\fscx109}那时为了能与你厮守在一起
Dialogue: 0,0:01:52.58,0:01:57.05,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(640,670)\fad(0,50)}这一次我绝不会再松开牵起的手
Dialogue: 0,0:01:57.38,0:02:06.56,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(436,670)\fscx117}在梦中对你轻声许诺
Dialogue: 0,0:01:57.38,0:02:06.56,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(815,670)\fscx114}总有一天我定会与你重逢
Dialogue: 0,0:02:06.72,0:02:10.18,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(600,672)\fad(0,900)\fscx96\fsp1.1\fs42\bord0.25\fscx107}E{\fscx86}v{\fscx95}e{\fscx88}r{\fscx96\fsp1.4}lasti{\fscx98}ng
Dialogue: 0,0:02:06.72,0:02:10.18,opcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(754,672)\fad(0,900)\fscx96\fsp1.5\fs42\bord0.25}Luv
Dialogue: 0,0:02:13.41,0:02:20.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\fs50\b0\bord2.5\shad0\fsp2}《名侦探柯南》由以下赞助商特约播映
Dialogue: 0,0:02:26.98,0:02:33.00,Title,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(640,600)\fad(380,0)\3c&H353535\bord2\be3\blur4\fsp-9\b0\fs20\t(40,290,\fs75)\t(290,330,\fs55)\t(330,370,\fs70)\t(370,400,\fs65)}给愚者的遗产
Dialogue: 0,0:02:36.85,0:02:39.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,喂 出什么事了 没事吧
Dialogue: 0,0:02:39.40,0:02:40.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这边
Dialogue: 0,0:02:46.38,0:02:48.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,喂 你在那里干什么
Dialogue: 0,0:02:50.59,0:02:51.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可恶
Dialogue: 0,0:02:54.01,0:02:55.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,刚才的枪声是怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:02:55.74,0:02:56.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,少废话
Dialogue: 0,0:02:58.66,0:02:59.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,滚开
Dialogue: 0,0:03:00.22,0:03:01.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,喂 站住
Dialogue: 0,0:03:20.75,0:03:23.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,奇怪 血是干的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:27.09,0:03:28.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还是热着的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:28.73,0:03:29.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那为什么
Dialogue: 0,0:03:32.15,0:03:32.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这些是什么
Dialogue: 0,0:03:33.83,0:03:35.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,像是什么东西的结晶
Dialogue: 0,0:03:35.69,0:03:37.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可恶 跑得倒挺快的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:38.24,0:03:39.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让他逃走了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:40.19,0:03:42.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,喂 小鬼 发现什么了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:03:44.58,0:03:45.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:48.53,0:03:51.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,被害者是矢口久卫门先生 70岁
Dialogue: 0,0:03:52.56,0:03:53.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个家的主人
Dialogue: 0,0:03:53.49,0:03:55.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像是个大财主
Dialogue: 0,0:03:55.88,0:03:58.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在离胸膛极近的距离被射杀 已死亡
Dialogue: 0,0:03:59.00,0:04:00.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,基本上是当场死亡
Dialogue: 0,0:04:01.48,0:04:03.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,凶器好像是那把猎枪
Dialogue: 0,0:04:05.11,0:04:08.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个 你们就是第一目击者吗
Dialogue: 0,0:04:09.82,0:04:12.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真是的 为什么又到镰仓来了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:12.39,0:04:14.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,观光 我们是来观光的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:14.08,0:04:16.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小兰说想看绣球花
Dialogue: 0,0:04:16.28,0:04:18.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,横沟警官 请过来一下
Dialogue: 0,0:04:22.46,0:04:23.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,让您久等了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:24.54,0:04:26.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,听说我父亲死了 这是真的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:04:27.02,0:04:29.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 冒昧问一下 您是？
Dialogue: 0,0:04:29.99,0:04:31.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(300,0)}我是长子禄郎
Dialogue: 0,0:04:31.98,0:04:33.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,您的职业是？
Dialogue: 0,0:04:33.55,0:04:35.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,电影导演
Dialogue: 0,0:04:35.70,0:04:36.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,电影导演？
Dialogue: 0,0:04:37.11,0:04:38.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,名字倒没听说过
Dialogue: 0,0:04:39.88,0:04:43.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,少说这些废话了 凶手有眉目了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:04:43.42,0:04:45.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在此之前 请问今天早上6点左右
Dialogue: 0,0:04:45.71,0:04:46.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,您在哪里
Dialogue: 0,0:04:47.09,0:04:50.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,咦？我们听到枪声是在10点左右
Dialogue: 0,0:04:51.01,0:04:53.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,遇害时间是在此之前
Dialogue: 0,0:04:53.73,0:04:54.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:04:54.82,0:04:57.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 根据检尸 死亡推测时间为…
Dialogue: 0,0:04:58.17,0:04:59.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,别多嘴了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:59.69,0:05:00.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是…是
Dialogue: 0,0:05:00.97,0:05:03.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,死亡推测时间是在6点左右啊
Dialogue: 0,0:05:04.17,0:05:06.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这样的话 我们听到的枪声
Dialogue: 0,0:05:06.52,0:05:08.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是为了伪装行凶时间吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:09.33,0:05:10.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不对 就算是这样…
Dialogue: 0,0:05:10.87,0:05:12.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在德岛
Dialogue: 0,0:05:12.91,0:05:15.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我当时在德岛为新电影取材
Dialogue: 0,0:05:16.38,0:05:19.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我记得出酒店是在6:30左右
Dialogue: 0,0:05:19.50,0:05:22.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,到达东京已经过了10:30了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:22.95,0:05:27.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,啊 对了 机票的存根还在呢
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.17,0:05:31.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(551,111)\fnsimhei\b0\fs28\frz-11\bord0.1\shad0\1c&H000000\3c&H000000\be1}登机牌
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.17,0:05:31.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(551,111)\fnsimhei\b0\fs28\frz-11\bord0.2\shad0\1c&H000000\3c&H000000\be1}登机牌
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.17,0:05:31.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(623,211)\fnsimhei\b0\fs17\fscy120\frz-11\bord0.3\shad0\1c&H000000\3c&H000000\be1}在到达目的地之前请勿丢弃本登机牌。
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.17,0:05:31.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(623,211)\fnsimhei\b0\fs17\fscy120\frz-11\bord0.3\shad0\1c&H000000\3c&H000000\be1}在到达目的地之前请勿丢弃本登机牌。
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.17,0:05:31.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(645.5,286)\fnsimhei\b0\fs19\fscy120\frz-11\bord0\shad0\1c&H000000\3c&H000000\be1}矢口  禄郎先生
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.17,0:05:31.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(478.5,270)\fnsimhei\b0\fs14\frz-11\bord0\shad0\1c&H000000\3c&H000000\be1\fsp2}目的地
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.17,0:05:31.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(784,366)\fnsimhei\b1\fs14\frz-11\bord0\shad0\1c&H000000\3c&H000000\be1\fsp1}航班号
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.17,0:05:31.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(455,380)\fnsimhei\b1\fs14\frz-11\bord0\shad0\1c&H000000\3c&H000000\be1\fsp1}登机口
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.17,0:05:31.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(452,444)\fnsimhei\b1\fs17\frz-11\bord0\shad0\1c&H000000\3c&H000000\be1\fsp1}座位号
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.17,0:05:31.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(550,510)\clip(0,0,677.5,720)\fnsimhei\b0\fs21\fscy124\frz-11\bord0\shad0\1c&H000000\3c&H000000\be1\fsp0}航班起飞{\fsp2}前{\fsp4}1{\fsp0}0分钟登机口停
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.17,0:05:31.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(565,622)\clip(0,0,680,720)\fnsimhei\b0\fs15\frz-11\bord0\shad0\1c&H000000\3c&H000000\be1}本次营运受运营公司之运营条款约束
Dialogue: 0,0:05:27.17,0:05:27.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就是这个
Dialogue: 0,0:05:31.44,0:05:33.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,原来是这样 去确认一下
Dialogue: 0,0:05:33.97,0:05:34.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:05:35.10,0:05:38.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,说起来 这个家里只有久卫门先生一个人住吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:38.57,0:05:41.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 以前还有佣人
Dialogue: 0,0:05:41.84,0:05:44.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不过半年前都被解雇了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:45.14,0:05:46.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真是的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:46.40,0:05:48.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,连佣人的钱都舍不得花的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:49.25,0:05:51.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也只有这种唯利是图的父亲了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:51.81,0:05:55.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这么大的房子居然没有雇佣人
Dialogue: 0,0:05:55.29,0:05:56.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还有别的家人吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:56.99,0:05:58.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还有两个弟弟
Dialogue: 0,0:05:58.82,0:06:03.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,对了 说不定他们知道些案件的情况呢
Dialogue: 0,0:06:03.83,0:06:07.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不过 他们会不会说实话就不知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:11.24,0:06:12.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们知道你在里面
Dialogue: 0,0:06:13.02,0:06:14.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快点滚出来
Dialogue: 0,0:06:14.46,0:06:15.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,把钱还来
Dialogue: 0,0:06:20.98,0:06:22.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你们想干什么
Dialogue: 0,0:06:22.48,0:06:24.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有什么意见吗
Dialogue: 0,0:06:26.10,0:06:28.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思 横沟老大
Dialogue: 0,0:06:29.73,0:06:31.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你这家伙还在做这些勾当啊
Dialogue: 0,0:06:34.27,0:06:34.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,收工了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:34.79,0:06:35.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,啊？
Dialogue: 0,0:06:35.56,0:06:36.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,动作快点
Dialogue: 0,0:06:40.24,0:06:42.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(1174,640)\fnsimhei\b1\fs20\frx16\frz4\fax-0.06\bord0\shad0\1c&H333333&\be1\fsp2}滞纳催缴书
Dialogue: 0,0:06:41.80,0:06:44.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,矢口先生 矢口明彦先生
Dialogue: 0,0:06:44.83,0:06:47.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是警察 有些事想问你
Dialogue: 0,0:06:51.39,0:06:53.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是警察啊 有什么事
Dialogue: 0,0:06:56.55,0:06:58.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,6点左右啊
Dialogue: 0,0:06:59.76,0:07:01.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我在这个家庭餐馆
Dialogue: 0,0:07:02.34,0:07:07.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从那里到父亲的家 开车也要一个小时呢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:08.15,0:07:12.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这家店的开店资金好像是你父亲出的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:07:13.21,0:07:16.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,之后也时常援助资金
Dialogue: 0,0:07:16.60,0:07:20.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但最近被拒绝的次数好像很多
Dialogue: 0,0:07:20.35,0:07:21.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是谁说的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:21.98,0:07:24.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是你哥哥禄郎先生说的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:24.75,0:07:26.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那家伙 开什么玩笑
Dialogue: 0,0:07:27.60,0:07:29.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我哥哥才是那个想要父亲钱的人
Dialogue: 0,0:07:29.72,0:07:31.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,拍电影还成
Dialogue: 0,0:07:31.47,0:07:32.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不过因为父亲出钱出得不爽快
Dialogue: 0,0:07:32.91,0:07:34.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,实际上已经浑身是债了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:37.42,0:07:41.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,其实 经营的公司已经倒闭了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:42.16,0:07:44.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一直援助我的父亲
Dialogue: 0,0:07:44.61,0:07:47.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这次的态度却完全变了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:47.70,0:07:50.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那 今天早上6点左右…
Dialogue: 0,0:07:51.69,0:07:55.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我…我6点左右还睡着呢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:55.93,0:07:56.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:07:57.58,0:07:59.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真…真的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:00.54,0:08:02.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,其实 就在案发前
Dialogue: 0,0:08:02.79,0:08:06.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有目击者称在现场附近看到过你
Dialogue: 0,0:08:13.94,0:08:15.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,能请你解释一下吗
Dialogue: 0,0:08:15.96,0:08:17.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不…那个是…
Dialogue: 0,0:08:17.58,0:08:18.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快说！
Dialogue: 0,0:08:18.67,0:08:19.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:08:19.44,0:08:21.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我去了…家里
Dialogue: 0,0:08:22.17,0:08:23.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,出于什么目的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:23.51,0:08:25.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个 因为钱…
Dialogue: 0,0:08:25.23,0:08:27.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这么诚心吗 一大清早地
Dialogue: 0,0:08:28.30,0:08:30.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是 那个…是想去偷
Dialogue: 0,0:08:30.91,0:08:31.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不过…
Dialogue: 0,0:08:33.14,0:08:34.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,和说过的不一样嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:08:34.92,0:08:36.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这样的保险柜怎么可能打得开
Dialogue: 0,0:08:37.01,0:08:38.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可恶
Dialogue: 0,0:08:38.47,0:08:39.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不许动
Dialogue: 0,0:08:40.20,0:08:42.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你是什么人
Dialogue: 0,0:08:46.40,0:08:47.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,公…公夫？
Dialogue: 0,0:08:50.33,0:08:51.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你这不知廉耻的家伙
Dialogue: 0,0:08:52.02,0:08:54.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,居然装扮成这种小偷摸样
Dialogue: 0,0:08:54.16,0:08:56.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这…这是明彦哥哥他…
Dialogue: 0,0:08:56.60,0:08:57.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你说明彦吗
Dialogue: 0,0:08:58.71,0:09:02.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你们这些家伙一直都是吊儿郎当的
Dialogue: 0,0:09:03.38,0:09:03.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是的
Dialogue: 0,0:09:04.19,0:09:05.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我才不是吊儿郎当的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:09:07.42,0:09:09.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是真的 请相信我
Dialogue: 0,0:09:09.98,0:09:13.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(0,400)}之后 我就去和明彦哥哥碰头了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:14.32,0:09:16.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那事怎么样了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:17.61,0:09:19.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不小心被父亲看到了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:19.53,0:09:23.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,笨蛋 我连方法都教给你了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:23.31,0:09:25.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么鬼方法 和你说的完全不是一回事
Dialogue: 0,0:09:26.30,0:09:28.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个保险柜坚固得要命
Dialogue: 0,0:09:28.48,0:09:29.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,保险柜？
Dialogue: 0,0:09:29.63,0:09:30.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不知道吗
Dialogue: 0,0:09:31.48,0:09:34.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,老头子什么时候有那样的保险柜了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:35.28,0:09:36.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,知道了 我来做好了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:37.52,0:09:38.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还要再干啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:38.56,0:09:39.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,废话
Dialogue: 0,0:09:39.87,0:09:42.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我会给你一点封口费的
Dialogue: 0,0:09:43.35,0:09:44.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:44.76,0:09:49.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那样坚固的保险柜的话 需要些工具才行
Dialogue: 0,0:09:51.95,0:09:54.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这些都发生在早上6点左右
Dialogue: 0,0:10:02.20,0:10:05.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真是的 没想到居然到了假扮强盗的地步了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:05.65,0:10:07.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是明彦哥哥干的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:07.61,0:10:08.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要怪在我的头上
Dialogue: 0,0:10:08.96,0:10:10.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但事实的确是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:10:10.38,0:10:11.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,起内讧了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:10:11.91,0:10:12.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,安静点
Dialogue: 0,0:10:13.70,0:10:14.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,明彦先生
Dialogue: 0,0:10:15.04,0:10:19.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你今天早上直到5:45为止在家庭餐馆的事
Dialogue: 0,0:10:19.38,0:10:22.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,女服务员及别的几个客人都记得的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:23.01,0:10:24.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没错吧
Dialogue: 0,0:10:24.91,0:10:28.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,之后 你在附近的折扣店里购物了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:10:30.19,0:10:32.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,铁撬 电钻
Dialogue: 0,0:10:33.28,0:10:36.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这里也有很多可以证明的人哦
Dialogue: 0,0:10:36.58,0:10:39.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我还记得 那只右手
Dialogue: 0,0:10:41.07,0:10:42.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这…这个是…
Dialogue: 0,0:10:44.05,0:10:45.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 我是来盗窃了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:46.05,0:10:47.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但并不是我下手的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:47.98,0:10:49.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我到这里时 他已经…
Dialogue: 0,0:10:51.20,0:10:52.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:10:53.32,0:10:54.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是谁干的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:55.63,0:10:56.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不管这些了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:59.90,0:11:02.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,话说回来还真是个坚固的保险柜呢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:03.13,0:11:05.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,费了不少工夫 却还是没能撬开
Dialogue: 0,0:11:05.34,0:11:06.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以
Dialogue: 0,0:11:07.58,0:11:08.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,用这个怎么样
Dialogue: 0,0:11:11.00,0:11:13.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那我们当时听到的枪声是…
Dialogue: 0,0:11:14.17,0:11:17.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是啊 连猎枪都没有用
Dialogue: 0,0:11:17.75,0:11:20.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,行凶时间是今天早上6点左右
Dialogue: 0,0:11:20.64,0:11:21.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个时间
Dialogue: 0,0:11:21.87,0:11:24.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,长子禄郎先生在德岛
Dialogue: 0,0:11:25.19,0:11:28.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,次子明彦先生和小儿子公夫先生
Dialogue: 0,0:11:28.31,0:11:31.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在离这里车程一小时的家庭餐馆
Dialogue: 0,0:11:32.06,0:11:34.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,久卫门先生在极近的距离被击中
Dialogue: 0,0:11:35.61,0:11:37.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,拿着猎枪的凶手就在眼前
Dialogue: 0,0:11:38.23,0:11:39.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为什么他不逃走呢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:40.79,0:11:44.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还有 那个白色的结晶
Dialogue: 0,0:11:46.40,0:11:48.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,到底是什么东西呢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:58.10,0:12:01.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好了 除了尸体之外
Dialogue: 0,0:12:02.18,0:12:03.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有什么地方有变动吗
Dialogue: 0,0:12:04.12,0:12:05.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,例如有什么东西不见了之类的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:07.54,0:12:08.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你这么一说
Dialogue: 0,0:12:10.57,0:12:13.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,父亲收藏的古董不见了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:15.36,0:12:17.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我看是哥哥你拿走了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:12:17.70,0:12:22.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么 我看是你来撬保险柜时偷走的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:12:22.76,0:12:26.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,被害者最近对儿子们的资金援助
Dialogue: 0,0:12:26.24,0:12:27.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,开始变得不爽快了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:28.40,0:12:31.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,半年前更是连佣人也解雇了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:31.29,0:12:33.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,然后古董的数量就变少了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:34.46,0:12:35.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,莫非…
Dialogue: 0,0:12:35.62,0:12:37.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那么 那个保险柜…
Dialogue: 0,0:12:39.61,0:12:43.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,对了 在这个房间里发现了这样的东西
Dialogue: 0,0:12:44.13,0:12:46.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像是叫作网络摄像头
Dialogue: 0,0:12:47.07,0:12:49.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这种东西是谁装的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:49.46,0:12:51.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,摄像机这类东西可是哥哥的专长
Dialogue: 0,0:12:51.47,0:12:52.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:12:52.68,0:12:54.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你的意思是我干的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:12:54.29,0:12:54.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,警官
Dialogue: 0,0:12:57.02,0:12:57.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,明白了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:58.54,0:13:01.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,各位 我们陆续得到很多情报
Dialogue: 0,0:13:01.59,0:13:03.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们再回到对面的房间去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:03.53,0:13:04.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,听我说几句啊 刑警先生
Dialogue: 0,0:13:05.28,0:13:07.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,能把那个保险柜打开吗
Dialogue: 0,0:13:12.45,0:13:13.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这是…
Dialogue: 0,0:13:14.37,0:13:15.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个位置的话…
Dialogue: 0,0:13:20.90,0:13:22.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个 刑警叔叔
Dialogue: 0,0:13:23.18,0:13:25.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,请问那个剥制标本原来是放在哪里的呀
Dialogue: 0,0:13:26.10,0:13:28.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个嘛…啊 是这里吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:29.64,0:13:31.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有灰尘的痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:13:31.66,0:13:33.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大概原来放在这里
Dialogue: 0,0:13:33.83,0:13:37.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在凶手和被害者推搡时掉落下来的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:38.90,0:13:43.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,禄郎先生 刚才德岛县警察发来报告
Dialogue: 0,0:13:43.74,0:13:47.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么样 我是住在德岛的酒店里吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:48.12,0:13:49.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的 没错
Dialogue: 0,0:13:49.62,0:13:52.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是和你一样戴着帽子与太阳镜的男子
Dialogue: 0,0:13:53.92,0:13:55.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个就是我呀
Dialogue: 0,0:13:55.59,0:13:57.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:13:57.86,0:14:02.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个客人好像在房间里也不把帽子和太阳镜取下
Dialogue: 0,0:14:03.49,0:14:05.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个是我的特征
Dialogue: 0,0:14:05.83,0:14:07.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在别人面前我都不取下来的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:07.51,0:14:09.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这样的话就没法看清脸了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:09.50,0:14:12.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个客人不能断定就是你本人
Dialogue: 0,0:14:13.50,0:14:14.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会
Dialogue: 0,0:14:14.76,0:14:15.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,而且 那个客人
Dialogue: 0,0:14:16.32,0:14:18.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,明明预定住宿到明天
Dialogue: 0,0:14:18.53,0:14:21.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天一早就急忙离开了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:22.16,0:14:26.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像已经预料到久卫门先生会死去
Dialogue: 0,0:14:26.87,0:14:28.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天一早…急忙地…
Dialogue: 0,0:14:28.41,0:14:29.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这么说来果然…
Dialogue: 0,0:14:30.68,0:14:33.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你的债务好像金额相当高啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:33.80,0:14:39.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但听说你很快就可以把钱凑齐还清了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:39.56,0:14:40.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个…
Dialogue: 0,0:14:40.36,0:14:42.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然是哥哥干的呀
Dialogue: 0,0:14:42.45,0:14:43.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是我
Dialogue: 0,0:14:43.41,0:14:46.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,去德岛的不过是个替身吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:47.75,0:14:51.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,然后你就通过网络摄像头监视着这个书斋
Dialogue: 0,0:14:52.51,0:14:55.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为了侦察到保险柜的密码
Dialogue: 0,0:14:55.67,0:14:57.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:14:57.20,0:15:01.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你用那个摄像头看到公夫来偷盗
Dialogue: 0,0:15:01.28,0:15:03.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,便杀害了久卫门先生
Dialogue: 0,0:15:03.23,0:15:06.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想把这个罪嫁祸给公夫
Dialogue: 0,0:15:07.62,0:15:09.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就算打不开保险柜
Dialogue: 0,0:15:09.89,0:15:11.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,遗产也能安稳地得手了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:11.72,0:15:12.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,哥哥
Dialogue: 0,0:15:12.63,0:15:13.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然…
Dialogue: 0,0:15:14.27,0:15:15.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这完全是无稽之谈
Dialogue: 0,0:15:16.06,0:15:18.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天早上你潜入这个家里
Dialogue: 0,0:15:19.26,0:15:21.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在书斋杀害了久卫门先生
Dialogue: 0,0:15:22.22,0:15:24.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这附近并没有人家
Dialogue: 0,0:15:24.85,0:15:28.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以那时的枪声并没有人听见
Dialogue: 0,0:15:28.39,0:15:31.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,然后再把德岛的替身叫回来
Dialogue: 0,0:15:31.68,0:15:34.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,拿到那张飞机票的存根
Dialogue: 0,0:15:34.58,0:15:37.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,再若无其事地在我们面前露脸
Dialogue: 0,0:15:37.17,0:15:38.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是不是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:15:39.03,0:15:41.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是 不是 不是这样的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:41.83,0:15:45.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,哪里说错了 老实招供吧
Dialogue: 0,0:15:50.08,0:15:51.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:15:53.40,0:15:57.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,禄郎先生 你还是说实话比较好
Dialogue: 0,0:15:58.05,0:16:00.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不然就会被当作凶手哦
Dialogue: 0,0:16:01.08,0:16:02.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:16:03.78,0:16:07.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,久卫门先生是死于不幸的意外
Dialogue: 0,0:16:07.71,0:16:08.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是这样吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:10.00,0:16:11.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个意外是怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:16:11.32,0:16:14.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我一直在想尸体倒下的位置
Dialogue: 0,0:16:15.60,0:16:18.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,若从那具尸体的位置推测
Dialogue: 0,0:16:18.53,0:16:20.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,久卫门先生被击中时
Dialogue: 0,0:16:20.59,0:16:23.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是在离墙壁架子几十厘米的位置上
Dialogue: 0,0:16:23.54,0:16:26.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,朝着墙壁站着
Dialogue: 0,0:16:27.07,0:16:32.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,从正面用猎枪向着那样站立的人射击是不可能的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:33.01,0:16:35.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,而且 尸体的脚根处
Dialogue: 0,0:16:35.54,0:16:37.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,掉落着老鹰的剥制标本
Dialogue: 0,0:16:38.00,0:16:41.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那根木枝被折断了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:42.16,0:16:44.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那到底是怎么一回事呢
Dialogue: 0,0:16:44.24,0:16:47.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,禄郎先生 你全都看到了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:48.31,0:16:51.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,通过摄像头 全部都看到了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:53.83,0:16:57.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,啊 没错 我全看见了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:58.34,0:17:00.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,百闻不如一见啊
Dialogue: 0,0:17:04.69,0:17:07.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,都来看吧 这就是真相
Dialogue: 0,0:17:11.71,0:17:13.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就在公夫逃回去后
Dialogue: 0,0:17:13.87,0:17:16.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他就这样坐了一会儿
Dialogue: 0,0:17:17.83,0:17:18.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个
Dialogue: 0,0:17:18.94,0:17:20.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像是什么发作了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:25.07,0:17:29.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,枪的板机勾在了剥制标本的枝上 走火了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:30.38,0:17:31.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就是这样了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:32.46,0:17:35.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,父亲的死不是凶杀
Dialogue: 0,0:17:35.42,0:17:36.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只是场意外
Dialogue: 0,0:17:36.91,0:17:39.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,混蛋 你既然有这样的录像
Dialogue: 0,0:17:39.14,0:17:40.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为什么还要隐瞒
Dialogue: 0,0:17:40.82,0:17:45.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是为了让明彦和公夫两人背上杀人的罪名
Dialogue: 0,0:17:45.37,0:17:47.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好独占遗产吧
Dialogue: 0,0:17:47.54,0:17:48.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:17:48.35,0:17:51.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以禄郎先生才急忙地从德岛赶了回来
Dialogue: 0,0:17:52.26,0:17:54.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为的是在尸体被发现前
Dialogue: 0,0:17:54.78,0:17:56.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,收回摄像头
Dialogue: 0,0:17:56.31,0:18:01.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,并做一些伪装工作 好把罪名嫁祸到明彦他们头上
Dialogue: 0,0:18:01.56,0:18:05.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不过在此之前 我们已经发现了尸体
Dialogue: 0,0:18:06.12,0:18:07.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你这个混蛋
Dialogue: 0,0:18:08.40,0:18:11.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,多亏有我 这才证明了你们是清白的
Dialogue: 0,0:18:11.47,0:18:13.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,还不快谢谢我
Dialogue: 0,0:18:13.29,0:18:14.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什么
Dialogue: 0,0:18:14.08,0:18:15.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,对了 遗产怎么分配啊
Dialogue: 0,0:18:15.72,0:18:18.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没错 还是先打开保险柜吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:18.40,0:18:23.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,伪装强盗的家伙哪里有资格继承遗产
Dialogue: 0,0:18:23.34,0:18:25.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么 你这个偷窥狂
Dialogue: 0,0:18:26.16,0:18:27.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,才不会让你独占家产呢
Dialogue: 0,0:18:27.56,0:18:28.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,都别吵了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:29.95,0:18:33.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你们难道还不明白久卫门先生的心情吗
Dialogue: 0,0:18:34.11,0:18:35.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,父亲的心情？
Dialogue: 0,0:18:36.05,0:18:38.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,公夫逃回去后
Dialogue: 0,0:18:38.36,0:18:43.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,坐在保险柜前面的久卫门先生哭了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:44.37,0:18:46.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,父亲他…哭了？
Dialogue: 0,0:18:47.10,0:18:49.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你是怎么知道这些的
Dialogue: 0,0:18:49.80,0:18:52.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,久卫门先生尸体的领子及胸口
Dialogue: 0,0:18:53.27,0:18:56.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沾有少量的白色结晶
Dialogue: 0,0:18:58.11,0:19:00.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那些应该是 盐
Dialogue: 0,0:19:01.12,0:19:04.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,渗入领口的泪水变干后残留的
Dialogue: 0,0:19:05.21,0:19:06.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,盐的结晶
Dialogue: 0,0:19:08.05,0:19:09.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,流了这么多眼泪
Dialogue: 0,0:19:09.29,0:19:13.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,多到能形成盐的结晶吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:19:13.47,0:19:16.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 那真是何等悲伤
Dialogue: 0,0:19:16.58,0:19:18.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,自己又是多么难堪自责啊
Dialogue: 0,0:19:18.97,0:19:25.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为自己太过娇纵儿子们 使他们难以自立而悔
Dialogue: 0,0:19:25.70,0:19:30.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为放任难以自立的儿子们走上犯罪道路而悔
Dialogue: 0,0:19:30.96,0:19:36.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,然后 为无法再为这样的儿子们施以援手而悔
Dialogue: 0,0:19:37.75,0:19:39.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,无法施以援手？
Dialogue: 0,0:19:39.85,0:19:43.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,恐怕这个家里能被称为财产的东西
Dialogue: 0,0:19:43.29,0:19:44.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,已经所剩无几了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:45.22,0:19:46.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这怎么可能
Dialogue: 0,0:19:47.04,0:19:48.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你们好好想想
Dialogue: 0,0:19:48.82,0:19:51.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在这个斜坡上建起的这么大的屋子里
Dialogue: 0,0:19:51.49,0:19:56.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,70岁的老人不雇佣人 独自生活着
Dialogue: 0,0:19:56.67,0:19:57.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是怎样的情况
Dialogue: 0,0:19:58.24,0:20:01.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,已经没有钱可以用来雇人了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:20:02.57,0:20:04.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,古董也卖掉了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:04.39,0:20:08.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个屋子及土地也作为债务抵押出去了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:09.13,0:20:12.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,胡说 那么那个保险柜作何解释
Dialogue: 0,0:20:12.97,0:20:14.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,里面一定有什么
Dialogue: 0,0:20:14.64,0:20:15.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那个 警官
Dialogue: 0,0:20:17.00,0:20:18.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,保险柜已经打开了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:18.73,0:20:19.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:20.87,0:20:22.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你们就亲眼见证一下如何
Dialogue: 0,0:20:26.33,0:20:27.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎…怎么会
Dialogue: 0,0:20:28.69,0:20:31.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,为什么里面只有借据啊
Dialogue: 0,0:20:29.73,0:20:32.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(604,261)\fn华文中宋\fs30\b1\frz9\be1\bord0\shad0\1c&H000000&}借据\N（金钱消费借贷合同）
Dialogue: 0,0:20:33.50,0:20:36.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不就是你们把家产吃光的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:20:36.49,0:20:37.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,电影制作资金
Dialogue: 0,0:20:38.03,0:20:40.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,冲浪店铺开店资金
Dialogue: 0,0:20:40.41,0:20:42.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,公司成立资金
Dialogue: 0,0:20:44.23,0:20:44.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可恶
Dialogue: 0,0:20:45.25,0:20:46.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎么办才好呀
Dialogue: 0,0:20:46.54,0:20:48.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,已经到头了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:58.24,0:21:00.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个 莫非是大家的…
Dialogue: 0,0:21:02.45,0:21:06.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(0,300)}那是母亲还在世时拍的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:06.58,0:21:09.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(300,0)}是呀 真令人怀念
Dialogue: 0,0:21:28.46,0:21:32.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这张照片是久卫门先生留下的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:32.96,0:21:34.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,最后的财产
Dialogue: 0,0:21:36.12,0:21:38.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,凝结着全家幸福时刻回忆的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:40.20,0:21:42.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,仅有的这一张照片
Dialogue: 0,0:21:43.52,0:21:48.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但你们谁都没有继承这个财产的资格
Dialogue: 0,0:21:51.37,0:21:52.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,恐怕是的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:54.10,0:21:56.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(0,300)}对不起 父亲
Dialogue: 0,0:22:05.54,0:22:13.72,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(502.5,670)\be5\fscx117}回味有你陪伴的日子
Dialogue: 0,0:22:05.54,0:22:13.72,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(814,670)\be5\fscx118}树下的光影斑斓
Dialogue: 0,0:22:15.76,0:22:24.56,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(488,670)\be5\fscx114}下定决心要舍弃的事物
Dialogue: 0,0:22:15.76,0:22:24.56,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(828,670)\be5}虽然已经不在此处
Dialogue: 0,0:22:25.90,0:22:34.87,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(416,670)\be5\fscx112}思绪巡回流转
Dialogue: 0,0:22:25.90,0:22:34.87,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(589.5,670)\be5\fscx104}刹那间
Dialogue: 0,0:22:25.90,0:22:34.87,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(813,670)\be5\fscx112}依恋在身边穿梭往返
Dialogue: 0,0:22:34.99,0:22:36.46,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(558,670)\fad(0,50)\be5\fscx96\fsp1.2\fs42}Doing
Dialogue: 0,0:22:34.99,0:22:36.46,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(646,670)\fad(0,50)\be5\fscx96\fsp1.5\fs42}all
Dialogue: 0,0:22:34.99,0:22:36.46,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(730,670)\fad(0,50)\be5\fscx96\fsp1.2\fs42}ri{\fsp1.8}gh{\fsp2}t!
Dialogue: 0,0:22:36.41,0:22:44.08,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(436,670)\fad(50,0)\be5}内心在摇摆
Dialogue: 0,0:22:36.41,0:22:44.08,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(744,670)\fad(50,0)\fscx115\be5}无法继续笔直向前地生活
Dialogue: 0,0:22:45.21,0:22:46.38,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(558,670)\be5\fscx96\fsp1.2\fs42}Doing
Dialogue: 0,0:22:45.21,0:22:46.38,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(646,670)\be5\fscx96\fsp1.5\fs42}all
Dialogue: 0,0:22:45.21,0:22:46.38,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(730,670)\be5\fscx96\fsp1.2\fs42}ri{\fsp1.8}gh{\fsp2}t!
Dialogue: 0,0:22:46.38,0:22:53.76,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(400,670)\be5\fscx110}摸索探寻着
Dialogue: 0,0:22:46.38,0:22:53.76,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(737,670)\be5\fscx115}哪怕怀抱的是稚嫩飘渺的梦想
Dialogue: 0,0:22:54.05,0:23:04.48,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(372,670)\be5\fscx118}静谧无风的午后
Dialogue: 0,0:22:54.05,0:23:04.48,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(606,670)\be5\fscx112}少许的安歇
Dialogue: 0,0:22:54.05,0:23:04.48,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(878,670)\be5}还有尚未回答的问询
Dialogue: 0,0:23:04.48,0:23:14.24,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(545,670)\fad(0,860)\be5\fscx109}感觉一切宛如轻展双翼
Dialogue: 0,0:23:04.48,0:23:14.24,edcn,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(821,670)\fad(0,860)\be5\fscx111}涟漪般四散
Dialogue: 0,0:23:25.44,0:23:26.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我们家真好
Dialogue: 0,0:23:27.20,0:23:29.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,没有争遗产的顾虑
Dialogue: 0,0:23:30.62,0:23:31.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是呀
Dialogue: 0,0:23:32.72,0:23:34.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有的有的
Dialogue: 0,0:23:34.12,0:23:35.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸？
Dialogue: 0,0:23:35.74,0:23:37.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小姐小姐
Dialogue: 0,0:23:37.50,0:23:40.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这个架子上的地酒 我全要了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:41.17,0:23:42.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好的
Dialogue: 0,0:23:42.11,0:23:43.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,等一下 爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:23:44.14,0:23:45.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你在干什么啊
Dialogue: 0,0:23:45.59,0:23:46.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,干什么…
Dialogue: 0,0:23:46.62,0:23:48.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这里的特产是地酒嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:23:48.37,0:23:50.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,土特产的话买一瓶就足够啦
Dialogue: 0,0:23:50.33,0:23:51.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一瓶
Dialogue: 0,0:23:51.33,0:23:52.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,别这么小气嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:23:54.54,0:23:57.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,这样根本不会留下什么遗产嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:24:00.54,0:24:02.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,蒲…蒲生先生?!
Dialogue: 0,0:24:03.92,0:24:05.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,明明是清白的却被怀疑
Dialogue: 0,0:24:06.04,0:24:06.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,被追查得走投无路…
Dialogue: 0,0:24:07.21,0:24:08.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是我逼死他的…
Dialogue: 0,0:24:09.68,0:24:10.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8}Next Conan
Dialogue: 0,0:24:08.92,0:24:14.84,Title,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(640,600)\fs65\fscx100\3c&H535147\bord4\be5\blur5\fsp-12}毛利小五郎侦探停业之日\N{\fs45\fsp-6\fn方正大标宋_GBK\fscx125\fscy120\frz-0.02}({\fn方正美黑_GBK\fscx140\fscy100\frz0}前篇{\fn方正大标宋_GBK\fscx125\fscy120\frz-0.02})
Dialogue: 0,0:24:15.76,0:24:17.51,Default,,0000,0000,0003,,名侦探柯南 夏日礼物
Dialogue: 0,0:24:17.70,0:24:20.70,Default,,0000,0000,0003,,从今天起连续4周送出超豪华礼物
Dialogue: 0,0:24:20.82,0:24:24.23,Default,,0000,0000,0003,,写下NEXT CONAN's HINT 到节目的主页去报名吧
Dialogue: 0,0:24:24.36,0:24:28.00,Default,,0000,0000,0003,,本周的礼物是特别编辑漫画《名侦探柯南 vs. 黑衣男子们》
Dialogue: 0,0:24:28.00,0:24:29.43,Default,,0000,0000,0003,,将有20位观众获得哦
Dialogue: 0,0:24:21.13,0:24:29.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(165,51)\fad(350,0)\fs39\bord3\shad0\1c&H2823C6&\3c&HFFFFFF}广告之后是{\fscx60\fs35\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0}NEXT CONA{\fsp-6}N{\b1\i1\fsp2}'{\b0\i0\fscx80\fsp0}s {\fscx70}HINT{\fscx80}！
Dialogue: 1,0:24:21.64,0:24:22.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(165,51)\fs39\bord3\shad0\3c&H2823C6&\1c&HFFFFFF}广告之后是{\fscx60\fs35\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0}NEXT CONA{\fsp-6}N{\b1\i1\fsp2}'{\b0\i0\fscx80\fsp0}s {\fscx70}HINT{\fscx80}！
Dialogue: 1,0:24:22.47,0:24:22.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(165,51)\fs39\bord3\shad0\3c&H2823C6&\1c&HFFFFFF}广告之后是{\fscx60\fs35\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0}NEXT CONA{\fsp-6}N{\b1\i1\fsp2}'{\b0\i0\fscx80\fsp0}s {\fscx70}HINT{\fscx80}！
Dialogue: 1,0:24:23.26,0:24:23.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(165,51)\fs39\bord3\shad0\3c&H2823C6&\1c&HFFFFFF}广告之后是{\fscx60\fs35\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0}NEXT CONA{\fsp-6}N{\b1\i1\fsp2}'{\b0\i0\fscx80\fsp0}s {\fscx70}HINT{\fscx80}！
Dialogue: 1,0:24:24.06,0:24:24.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(165,51)\fs39\bord3\shad0\3c&H2823C6&\1c&HFFFFFF}广告之后是{\fscx60\fs35\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0}NEXT CONA{\fsp-6}N{\b1\i1\fsp2}'{\b0\i0\fscx80\fsp0}s {\fscx70}HINT{\fscx80}！
Dialogue: 1,0:24:24.85,0:24:25.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(165,51)\fs39\bord3\shad0\3c&H2823C6&\1c&HFFFFFF}广告之后是{\fscx60\fs35\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0}NEXT CONA{\fsp-6}N{\b1\i1\fsp2}'{\b0\i0\fscx80\fsp0}s {\fscx70}HINT{\fscx80}！
Dialogue: 1,0:24:25.64,0:24:26.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(165,51)\fs39\bord3\shad0\3c&H2823C6&\1c&HFFFFFF}广告之后是{\fscx60\fs35\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0}NEXT CONA{\fsp-6}N{\b1\i1\fsp2}'{\b0\i0\fscx80\fsp0}s {\fscx70}HINT{\fscx80}！
Dialogue: 1,0:24:26.44,0:24:26.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(165,51)\fs39\bord3\shad0\3c&H2823C6&\1c&HFFFFFF}广告之后是{\fscx60\fs35\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0}NEXT CONA{\fsp-6}N{\b1\i1\fsp2}'{\b0\i0\fscx80\fsp0}s {\fscx70}HINT{\fscx80}！
Dialogue: 1,0:24:27.26,0:24:27.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(165,51)\fs39\bord3\shad0\3c&H2823C6&\1c&HFFFFFF}广告之后是{\fscx60\fs35\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0}NEXT CONA{\fsp-6}N{\b1\i1\fsp2}'{\b0\i0\fscx80\fsp0}s {\fscx70}HINT{\fscx80}！
Dialogue: 1,0:24:28.06,0:24:28.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(165,51)\fs39\bord3\shad0\3c&H2823C6&\1c&HFFFFFF}广告之后是{\fscx60\fs35\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0}NEXT CONA{\fsp-6}N{\b1\i1\fsp2}'{\b0\i0\fscx80\fsp0}s {\fscx70}HINT{\fscx80}！
Dialogue: 1,0:24:28.84,0:24:29.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(165,51)\fs39\bord3\shad0\3c&H2823C6&\1c&HFFFFFF}广告之后是{\fscx60\fs35\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0}NEXT CONA{\fsp-6}N{\b1\i1\fsp2}'{\b0\i0\fscx80\fsp0}s {\fscx70}HINT{\fscx80}！
Dialogue: 1,0:24:29.64,0:24:29.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(165,51)\fs39\bord3\shad0\3c&H2823C6&\1c&HFFFFFF}广告之后是{\fscx60\fs35\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0}NEXT CONA{\fsp-6}N{\b1\i1\fsp2}'{\b0\i0\fscx80\fsp0}s {\fscx70}HINT{\fscx80}！
Dialogue: 0,0:24:17.68,0:24:29.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(4,487.5)\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0\bord0\shad0\fs51\c&HF53435&}写下{\c&H2823C6&\fscx63}NEXT CONAN's
Dialogue: 0,0:24:17.68,0:24:29.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(4,536)\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0\bord0\shad0\fs51\fscx85\c&H2823C6&}HINT{\c&HF53435&\fscx100}来报名吧
Dialogue: 0,0:24:17.68,0:24:29.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an1\pos(297,536)\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\1c&HF53435&\b0\bord0\shad0\fs52\fscy110\frz-15}!
Dialogue: 0,0:24:17.68,0:24:29.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(925,596)\fn方正超粗黑_GBK\b0\bord3.5\3c&H000000\shad0\fs43}详情请参见节目主页
Dialogue: 0,0:24:30.63,0:24:38.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\fs50\b0\bord2.5\shad0\fsp2}《名侦探柯南》由以下赞助商特约播映完毕
Dialogue: 0,0:24:45.41,0:24:46.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8}Next Conan's HINT
Dialogue: 1,0:24:45.04,0:24:49.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,0)\pos(640,590)}{\fn方正大标宋_GBK\fs46\b0\bord0\shad0\fsp1.5\1c&H000000}手电筒
Dialogue: 0,0:24:45.12,0:24:49.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(400,0)\pos(642,592)}{\fn方正大标宋_GBK\fs46\b0\bord0\shad0\fsp1.5\1c&HEEEEEE}手电筒
Dialogue: 0,0:24:49.84,0:24:51.61,Default,,0000,0000,0003,,老爸可能不当侦探了
Dialogue: 0,0:24:51.61,0:24:53.74,Default,,0000,0000,0003,,此话当真？毛利先生竟…
Dialogue: 0,0:24:53.74,0:24:54.55,Default,,0000,0000,0003,,大嗓门儿
Dialogue: 0,0:24:49.84,0:24:55.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,{\an5\pos(704,552)\be3\blur1\b1\fsp3\fscx100\fs57\bord3.5\shad6\4a&H20\3c&H525252\4c&H000000}敬请期待下集
