[Script Info]
; Script generated by Aegisub v2.1.3 RELEASE PREVIEW (SVN r2429, amz)
; http://www.aegisub.net
Title:幻樱字幕
Original Script:幻樱字幕组
Synch Point:0
ScriptType: v4.00+
Collisions:Normal
PlayResX:1280
PlayResY:720
Timer:100.0000

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,黑体,50,&H00FFFFFF,&HF0000000,&H00000000,&H32000000,-1,0,0,0,100,100,0,0,1,1,2,2,30,30,10,134

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Name, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text



Dialogue: 0,0:00:11.53,0:00:13.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 出彩虹了
Dialogue: 0,0:00:14.07,0:00:15.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快看 好漂亮
Dialogue: 0,0:00:16.45,0:00:17.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,彩虹啊
Dialogue: 0,0:00:19.54,0:00:22.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是的 又通宵麻将了
Dialogue: 0,0:00:22.91,0:00:26.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那你就不知道了 那可是一期一会的决战啊
Dialogue: 0,0:00:27.21,0:00:30.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,赌的可是洋子小姐的写真照片呢
Dialogue: 0,0:00:33.92,0:00:36.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这也要去温泉吗
Dialogue: 0,0:00:42.60,0:00:43.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快看那个
Dialogue: 0,0:00:48.77,0:00:50.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爱是魔法 谜是挑战
Dialogue: 0,0:00:51.03,0:00:52.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,周六6点 点击柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:00:53.36,0:00:54.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,视野宽敞的路口却频繁发生交通事故
Dialogue: 0,0:00:55.15,0:00:57.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,恐怖的十字路口上的蛛丝马迹
Dialogue: 0,0:00:57.41,0:00:58.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,揭开唯一真相的
Dialogue: 0,0:00:59.16,0:01:00.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是一个外表看似小孩头脑却过于常人的
Dialogue: 0,0:01:00.95,0:01:02.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他的名字就是……名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:02:44.05,0:02:49.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,恐怖的十字路口
Dialogue: 0,0:02:53.56,0:02:54.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,发生事故了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:05.78,0:03:07.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小兰 你去看看那边的情况
Dialogue: 0,0:03:08.04,0:03:09.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:10.83,0:03:12.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个是…
Dialogue: 0,0:03:15.46,0:03:17.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不行啊 这样救不了人…
Dialogue: 0,0:03:17.96,0:03:19.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,兰 你那边怎样
Dialogue: 0,0:03:20.67,0:03:22.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,门打不开
Dialogue: 0,0:03:23.18,0:03:24.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,振作点
Dialogue: 0,0:03:25.47,0:03:29.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个 这两辆车刚才都在便利店门口停着的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:03:29.35,0:03:30.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那种事无所谓啦
Dialogue: 0,0:03:35.81,0:03:37.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没事吧
Dialogue: 0,0:03:37.94,0:03:39.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,算是吧
Dialogue: 0,0:03:42.03,0:03:43.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,发生什么了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:43.99,0:03:45.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看来是交通事故
Dialogue: 0,0:03:46.45,0:03:48.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对方车里的人得救了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:03:49.83,0:03:51.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然想救他
Dialogue: 0,0:03:51.66,0:03:53.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是一直在燃烧着 没法接近
Dialogue: 0,0:03:56.88,0:03:57.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没事吧
Dialogue: 0,0:03:58.38,0:04:00.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小兰 赶快叫救护车和警察来
Dialogue: 0,0:04:00.92,0:04:01.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:04:13.27,0:04:14.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会这样
Dialogue: 0,0:04:17.31,0:04:19.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我闯大祸了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:20.90,0:04:22.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我该怎么办啊
Dialogue: 0,0:04:23.57,0:04:25.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是罪人…
Dialogue: 0,0:04:27.03,0:04:28.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,先冷静下来
Dialogue: 0,0:04:29.37,0:04:30.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要来一支烟吗
Dialogue: 0,0:04:31.83,0:04:33.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不吸烟的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:35.08,0:04:35.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:04:36.54,0:04:38.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你是驾驶绿色车子的人吧
Dialogue: 0,0:04:39.59,0:04:40.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:41.51,0:04:44.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有些话想问你 请问方便吗
Dialogue: 0,0:04:45.05,0:04:45.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:45.93,0:04:47.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,首先请告诉我们你的名字和职业
Dialogue: 0,0:04:48.35,0:04:49.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车谷整司
Dialogue: 0,0:04:50.26,0:04:51.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,汽车维修技工
Dialogue: 0,0:04:52.56,0:04:54.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你就是第一发现人吧
Dialogue: 0,0:04:54.89,0:04:55.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请问名字是…
Dialogue: 0,0:04:59.86,0:05:02.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你就是那个名侦探毛利小五郎先生啊
Dialogue: 0,0:05:03.57,0:05:04.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我听说了不少有关你的事迹
Dialogue: 0,0:05:06.24,0:05:07.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也没那么厉害啦
Dialogue: 0,0:05:08.12,0:05:09.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个毛利小五郎…
Dialogue: 0,0:05:10.24,0:05:12.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,能得到名侦探的协助
Dialogue: 0,0:05:12.87,0:05:13.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是帮了大忙了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:14.33,0:05:17.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么是毛利先生最先发现事故的两辆车的吧？
Dialogue: 0,0:05:18.83,0:05:20.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,红色的已经进行了救援
Dialogue: 0,0:05:21.59,0:05:24.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,驾驶员速水准  已经确认死亡了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:26.13,0:05:27.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车谷先生
Dialogue: 0,0:05:27.80,0:05:30.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,能告诉我事故的经过吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:30.97,0:05:32.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:32.77,0:05:34.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到达十字路口的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:05:34.68,0:05:38.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不知道为什么 完全没有注意到对方的车子也正开过来
Dialogue: 0,0:05:39.86,0:05:41.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就在我这么直行开着的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:05:41.69,0:05:44.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,突然一辆红色的车子冲了出来
Dialogue: 0,0:05:46.40,0:05:48.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然马上急刹车和避让了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:49.62,0:05:51.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,却没能躲开
Dialogue: 0,0:05:52.74,0:05:56.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到达十字路口前没有突然停车什么的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:56.71,0:05:59.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉 是我的疏忽
Dialogue: 0,0:05:59.83,0:06:01.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以说才会发生事故啊
Dialogue: 0,0:06:02.96,0:06:05.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,铁柱被撞的这么弯
Dialogue: 0,0:06:07.34,0:06:10.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这辆车 保险杠做过加固
Dialogue: 0,0:06:14.01,0:06:14.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过话说回来
Dialogue: 0,0:06:15.77,0:06:20.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说突然间对方的车子冲出来 还是有点可疑
Dialogue: 0,0:06:21.11,0:06:25.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你真的没在驾驶中打瞌睡或走神吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:25.82,0:06:26.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,当然不是
Dialogue: 0,0:06:27.15,0:06:29.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我只是正常地向前开着
Dialogue: 0,0:06:29.49,0:06:32.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,完全没注意到对方的车子
Dialogue: 0,0:06:32.41,0:06:33.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么可能啊
Dialogue: 0,0:06:34.20,0:06:37.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在这田圃正中央 这个十字路口都没有视线遮挡
Dialogue: 0,0:06:40.37,0:06:41.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可能是因为那个吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:42.46,0:06:43.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个是…
Dialogue: 0,0:06:43.42,0:06:46.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这里是有名的事故高发区
Dialogue: 0,0:06:47.09,0:06:50.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被当地人称作 恐怖的十字路口
Dialogue: 0,0:06:51.01,0:06:53.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,恐怖的十字路口
Dialogue: 0,0:06:54.56,0:06:59.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也有人把这个称为「碰撞航向」现象
Dialogue: 0,0:06:54.56,0:06:59.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8}{\fs40}「collision course」=「碰撞航向」
Dialogue: 0,0:07:00.14,0:07:00.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:07:01.19,0:07:03.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个「碰撞航向」
Dialogue: 0,0:07:03.69,0:07:05.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,「碰撞航向」现象
Dialogue: 0,0:07:06.40,0:07:10.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明明是白天 视野也非常好 却经常在十字路口发生事故
Dialogue: 0,0:07:11.78,0:07:15.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,两辆车以相同的速度接近十字路口
Dialogue: 0,0:07:16.33,0:07:20.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,平面上两辆车成45度角
Dialogue: 0,0:07:21.25,0:07:26.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说 双方都处在对方的视野视角的状态
Dialogue: 0,0:07:27.25,0:07:31.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,人的视野分为中心视野和周边视野
Dialogue: 0,0:07:32.43,0:07:36.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,周边视野不能识别移动中的小物体
Dialogue: 0,0:07:37.01,0:07:39.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以不能马上发现对方移动中的车辆
Dialogue: 0,0:07:40.27,0:07:43.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后等发觉的时候已经到了路口
Dialogue: 0,0:07:44.10,0:07:45.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就那样撞上了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:48.32,0:07:50.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么 车谷先生他们的事故是因为这个…
Dialogue: 0,0:07:52.74,0:07:54.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,碰撞航…
Dialogue: 0,0:07:54.74,0:07:56.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,「碰撞航向」现象
Dialogue: 0,0:07:57.37,0:07:59.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可能就是因为那个引起的事故
Dialogue: 0,0:08:01.62,0:08:03.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为有那个现象
Dialogue: 0,0:08:04.29,0:08:07.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我要是更加注意就好了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:07.63,0:08:08.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是
Dialogue: 0,0:08:13.22,0:08:16.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这里根本没有那辆红色轿车的刹车痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:08:17.68,0:08:21.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那辆车也没注意到其他方向有车啊
Dialogue: 0,0:08:22.06,0:08:26.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看来只有「碰撞航向」现象这个解释了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:26.40,0:08:27.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是
Dialogue: 0,0:08:27.82,0:08:31.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在这么广阔的地方没注意到对方车子的事
Dialogue: 0,0:08:32.44,0:08:34.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,确实难以让人相信啊
Dialogue: 0,0:08:35.11,0:08:38.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,侦探先生真的喜欢怀疑啊
Dialogue: 0,0:08:40.66,0:08:44.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在便利店看到的两辆车都撞得破破烂烂的了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:44.96,0:08:46.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错吧 叔叔
Dialogue: 0,0:08:49.29,0:08:51.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,两辆车都曾停在便利店吗
Dialogue: 0,0:08:52.51,0:08:54.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,观光回来的路上
Dialogue: 0,0:08:55.55,0:08:59.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大概在5点的时候两辆车都离开了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:03.77,0:09:04.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等等
Dialogue: 0,0:09:05.06,0:09:07.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,仔细想想看还是有些奇怪啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:07.60,0:09:08.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:09:09.27,0:09:11.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,同时离开便利店的两辆车
Dialogue: 0,0:09:11.53,0:09:13.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,朝着不同的路走
Dialogue: 0,0:09:14.07,0:09:16.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,几分钟后就在这里撞车了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:17.49,0:09:19.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是偶然吗
Dialogue: 0,0:09:21.12,0:09:23.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然我认为是偶然
Dialogue: 0,0:09:23.95,0:09:26.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么我们去便利店确认下吧
Dialogue: 0,0:09:30.09,0:09:31.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 就是这个人
Dialogue: 0,0:09:32.46,0:09:34.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个人大概2点钟左右来的
Dialogue: 0,0:09:34.97,0:09:37.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,态度很奇怪 所以有些介意
Dialogue: 0,0:09:41.60,0:09:43.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,客人昨天也来了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:44.48,0:09:47.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我记得你开的那辆绿色的车哦
Dialogue: 0,0:09:48.44,0:09:51.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是车谷的车 别搞错了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:53.03,0:09:54.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就对我那样咆哮
Dialogue: 0,0:09:54.44,0:09:55.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会
Dialogue: 0,0:09:55.90,0:09:58.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真的提到车谷的名字嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:09:58.36,0:10:02.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哦 和车谷认识
Dialogue: 0,0:10:02.74,0:10:03.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有什么头绪了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:05.00,0:10:06.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么
Dialogue: 0,0:10:07.58,0:10:09.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个人呢
Dialogue: 0,0:10:10.21,0:10:16.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个人和刚才年轻的那个好像发生什么争执了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:17.13,0:10:17.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:10:18.47,0:10:21.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们看到那两辆车开走的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:10:21.47,0:10:23.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是他们刚吵完架之后吧
Dialogue: 0,0:10:24.10,0:10:26.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,之后立马就发生事故了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:39.86,0:10:41.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,确实那个时候
Dialogue: 0,0:10:53.59,0:10:54.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们走了 柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:10:56.05,0:10:56.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:01.47,0:11:02.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车谷先生
Dialogue: 0,0:11:03.47,0:11:08.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你跟开红色进口车的速水是朋友吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:09.14,0:11:15.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是 虽然不敢肯定 但只是见过几次而已
Dialogue: 0,0:11:15.61,0:11:19.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那你在便利店和速水争吵什么
Dialogue: 0,0:11:20.03,0:11:24.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,便利店的店长可是看到你们了哦
Dialogue: 0,0:11:24.62,0:11:30.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其实那红色的进口车是三个月前我的卖二手车的朋友卖的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:31.00,0:11:33.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,听说买车的人还不起贷款
Dialogue: 0,0:11:33.46,0:11:35.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就上前去问了几句
Dialogue: 0,0:11:35.96,0:11:38.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是让他很生气 就吵了起来
Dialogue: 0,0:11:38.84,0:11:40.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:11:41.55,0:11:44.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么说来 你怎么会把车开到这边
Dialogue: 0,0:11:45.35,0:11:47.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你的家在反方向吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:48.47,0:11:53.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没什么 就是有时间想兜兜风
Dialogue: 0,0:11:54.36,0:11:56.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊 彩虹很漂亮
Dialogue: 0,0:11:56.69,0:11:57.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,彩虹？
Dialogue: 0,0:11:58.28,0:12:00.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有彩虹么
Dialogue: 0,0:12:01.70,0:12:03.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从刚才开始怎么回事啊
Dialogue: 0,0:12:03.99,0:12:05.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,总是问与事故无关的事
Dialogue: 0,0:12:06.62,0:12:07.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:08.41,0:12:11.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车谷先生你是汽车维修技师的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:12:13.04,0:12:14.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:14.92,0:12:19.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以说 你事前就知道这里是撞车事故的多发地段
Dialogue: 0,0:12:20.71,0:12:21.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是
Dialogue: 0,0:12:21.72,0:12:23.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在便利店发生争吵的你
Dialogue: 0,0:12:23.88,0:12:26.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在速水先生买东西的几分钟里
Dialogue: 0,0:12:26.64,0:12:28.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在他的刹车上动了手脚吧
Dialogue: 0,0:12:29.31,0:12:32.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对于汽车维修技工的你来说是轻而易举吧
Dialogue: 0,0:12:32.48,0:12:35.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以那辆红色进口车才没有刹车的痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:12:36.19,0:12:40.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是那辆红色进口车的刹车没有任何异常
Dialogue: 0,0:12:41.94,0:12:42.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:12:43.40,0:12:46.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那就是在刹车连动杆里夹了什么东西吧
Dialogue: 0,0:12:47.20,0:12:50.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是伪装成交通事故的惯用手段
Dialogue: 0,0:12:52.41,0:12:55.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你本来是想吓唬一下速水的
Dialogue: 0,0:12:56.08,0:12:59.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是却意想不到发生重大车祸导致了他的死亡
Dialogue: 0,0:12:59.63,0:13:02.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,于是你就想掩饰这一切
Dialogue: 0,0:13:02.76,0:13:07.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是在红色的车内没有发现可疑的物品
Dialogue: 0,0:13:10.01,0:13:12.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,侦探先生 你可别再说那些不靠谱的事了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:17.81,0:13:20.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸 你别边走边抽烟啊
Dialogue: 0,0:13:20.65,0:13:22.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车里不是有烟灰缸吗
Dialogue: 0,0:13:25.20,0:13:26.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车里的烟灰缸
Dialogue: 0,0:13:41.71,0:13:44.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来 原来是这么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:13:51.85,0:13:53.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南你干什么去了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:53.52,0:13:54.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没…没什么
Dialogue: 0,0:13:54.93,0:13:56.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,交通监控录像准备好了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:58.40,0:14:00.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个地方也安装了监控录像啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:00.77,0:14:02.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 这里的交通事故实在是太多了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:03.69,0:14:05.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哦 原来如此
Dialogue: 0,0:14:08.24,0:14:09.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小孩别碍事
Dialogue: 0,0:14:14.66,0:14:18.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,红色进口车经过十字路口是没有刹车的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:18.29,0:14:20.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被后面开过来的绿色车撞了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:20.75,0:14:24.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,之后绿色的车撞到广告牌停下了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:24.76,0:14:27.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,红色的车就掉进水渠里了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:29.30,0:14:32.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好象没有什么可疑的地方
Dialogue: 0,0:14:32.76,0:14:34.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 好像是那样
Dialogue: 0,0:14:35.98,0:14:38.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那当成事故处理没问题吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:40.77,0:14:44.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可恶 好想看监控录像啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:46.74,0:14:49.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再乱跑的话 会被爸爸骂哦
Dialogue: 0,0:14:54.45,0:14:55.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小兰姐姐等一下
Dialogue: 0,0:14:57.12,0:14:58.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:14:59.25,0:15:00.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:02.63,0:15:03.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个是…
Dialogue: 0,0:15:09.59,0:15:10.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小兰姐姐
Dialogue: 0,0:15:14.39,0:15:15.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸他…
Dialogue: 0,0:15:24.36,0:15:26.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个 怎么样了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:27.94,0:15:29.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,跟你的证言一样
Dialogue: 0,0:15:29.61,0:15:31.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是交通事故
Dialogue: 0,0:15:32.16,0:15:35.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是 无视临时停止的你
Dialogue: 0,0:15:35.24,0:15:36.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,罪也是很重的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:36.70,0:15:38.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,实在是对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:15:41.67,0:15:43.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么这下都解决了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:44.04,0:15:45.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那拜托你了 兰
Dialogue: 0,0:15:49.59,0:15:53.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接下来请你跟我回警署里做笔录 请配合
Dialogue: 0,0:15:55.14,0:15:56.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:58.47,0:15:59.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请等一下
Dialogue: 0,0:16:01.69,0:16:04.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这不是普通的交通事故
Dialogue: 0,0:16:05.02,0:16:07.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而是有计划的杀人事件
Dialogue: 0,0:16:09.53,0:16:10.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是怎么回事
Dialogue: 0,0:16:11.53,0:16:16.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车谷先生和速水先生在便利店偶然相遇是假的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:18.29,0:16:19.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你在说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:16:20.08,0:16:24.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚才我家那小鬼看了你车里的烟灰缸
Dialogue: 0,0:16:25.21,0:16:27.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说是有很多烟头
Dialogue: 0,0:16:29.09,0:16:33.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不对劲吧 你明明不抽烟
Dialogue: 0,0:16:34.22,0:16:35.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那…那是
Dialogue: 0,0:16:35.80,0:16:42.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个烟是Paradise牌的 烟嘴有被牙咬过的痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:16:43.48,0:16:44.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是一样的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:45.27,0:16:49.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和丢在便利店的停车场 速水先生扔的烟头一样
Dialogue: 0,0:16:50.86,0:16:51.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说
Dialogue: 0,0:16:51.90,0:16:56.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在到那个便利店之前速水先生开的是绿色的车
Dialogue: 0,0:16:57.16,0:16:58.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很可能是…
Dialogue: 0,0:16:58.66,0:17:01.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,速水先生的车在工厂维修期间
Dialogue: 0,0:17:02.04,0:17:05.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是你把绿色的车临时借给速水先生开的
Dialogue: 0,0:17:05.75,0:17:06.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后
Dialogue: 0,0:17:06.75,0:17:13.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了换修好了的车 你才在便利店等的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:17:13.92,0:17:18.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再然后 你预谋撞车意外 从而杀害了速水先生
Dialogue: 0,0:17:19.39,0:17:21.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么回事啊 毛利先生
Dialogue: 0,0:17:21.68,0:17:22.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说
Dialogue: 0,0:17:22.77,0:17:28.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车谷先生本来就想用自己的车撞速水先生的车
Dialogue: 0,0:17:29.40,0:17:32.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说什么傻话 我也受伤了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:33.32,0:17:35.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只要稍有差池 我也会死的
Dialogue: 0,0:17:35.20,0:17:36.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那没什么问题吧
Dialogue: 0,0:17:37.36,0:17:42.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为你的车前面装有加强过的保险杠
Dialogue: 0,0:17:43.91,0:17:49.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,受点小伤就更能让别人看出是事故 那不正合你意
Dialogue: 0,0:17:49.25,0:17:50.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是强词夺理
Dialogue: 0,0:17:50.63,0:17:53.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是因为「碰撞航向」现象引起的事故
Dialogue: 0,0:17:53.80,0:17:56.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对方的车全然没有踩刹车
Dialogue: 0,0:17:56.93,0:17:58.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是最好的证据啊
Dialogue: 0,0:17:59.05,0:18:00.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也是啊 毛利先生
Dialogue: 0,0:18:01.01,0:18:03.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有预谋地引起这桩事故 有点困难啊
Dialogue: 0,0:18:04.73,0:18:10.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,速水先生没有踩刹车不是因为「碰撞航向」现象
Dialogue: 0,0:18:12.23,0:18:17.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是因为车谷先生做了不让速水先生踩刹车的手脚
Dialogue: 0,0:18:18.32,0:18:21.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,刚才不是说了车里没有动手脚吗…
Dialogue: 0,0:18:21.16,0:18:22.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车里是没有
Dialogue: 0,0:18:23.41,0:18:26.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,手脚动在了别的地方
Dialogue: 0,0:18:28.00,0:18:28.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小兰
Dialogue: 0,0:18:29.42,0:18:30.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在
Dialogue: 0,0:18:38.47,0:18:40.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个和道路标示一样
Dialogue: 0,0:18:40.59,0:18:43.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,本来是涂了反光材料的广告牌
Dialogue: 0,0:18:44.10,0:18:47.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,平时是面朝速水先生的车过来的方向的
Dialogue: 0,0:18:47.52,0:18:50.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车灯照射在上面会引人注目的
Dialogue: 0,0:18:50.69,0:18:53.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,确实很耀眼
Dialogue: 0,0:18:53.73,0:18:58.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大概是车谷先生事前改变了广告牌的朝向
Dialogue: 0,0:18:59.24,0:19:04.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,速水先生的车就会被太阳光反射到而一时影响视线
Dialogue: 0,0:19:05.24,0:19:10.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那看监控录像的时候怎么没有发现啊
Dialogue: 0,0:19:10.83,0:19:13.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是因为在监控录像范围之外
Dialogue: 0,0:19:14.04,0:19:15.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,才没有拍到
Dialogue: 0,0:19:16.96,0:19:19.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从便利店出来的速水先生的车
Dialogue: 0,0:19:19.80,0:19:23.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,沿着水渠的路 向十字路口开去
Dialogue: 0,0:19:24.26,0:19:27.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为在十字路口上 他走的是优先道路
Dialogue: 0,0:19:27.47,0:19:30.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,才没有减速就一直往前走
Dialogue: 0,0:19:31.77,0:19:32.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,正好就在那个时候
Dialogue: 0,0:19:33.15,0:19:35.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被广告牌折射的阳光
Dialogue: 0,0:19:35.57,0:19:38.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,正好照着十字路口前面一点的地方
Dialogue: 0,0:19:39.28,0:19:42.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不知情的速水先生就直接冲了过去
Dialogue: 0,0:19:46.79,0:19:47.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是什么
Dialogue: 0,0:20:00.55,0:20:04.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,速水先生因为受到刺眼反射光的影响才没踩刹车
Dialogue: 0,0:20:05.30,0:20:05.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有就是
Dialogue: 0,0:20:06.35,0:20:11.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为反射光的残像才没有发现车谷先生的车
Dialogue: 0,0:20:11.69,0:20:16.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,约到下午2点在便利店见面也是因为考虑到阳光的角度吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:17.65,0:20:18.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是说
Dialogue: 0,0:20:18.78,0:20:22.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,撞到广告牌是为了掩饰自己换了广告牌的方向
Dialogue: 0,0:20:22.66,0:20:26.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,恐怕你撞到速水先生的驾驶座也是如此吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:29.16,0:20:31.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其实我是想直接撞到
Dialogue: 0,0:20:31.33,0:20:32.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把那家伙给…
Dialogue: 0,0:20:33.37,0:20:37.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,速水就是一年前撞了我妹妹之后逃跑的凶手
Dialogue: 0,0:20:37.63,0:20:38.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:20:38.96,0:20:39.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,半年前
Dialogue: 0,0:20:40.13,0:20:43.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看到来维修的红色进口车才发现的
Dialogue: 0,0:20:44.05,0:20:48.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从那以后我就一直想着怎么报仇
Dialogue: 0,0:20:48.97,0:20:52.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,速水又一次来维修他的那辆车
Dialogue: 0,0:20:52.77,0:20:55.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我就计划了这次的事件
Dialogue: 0,0:20:56.36,0:20:57.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还车的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:20:57.98,0:20:59.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我让他去自首了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:00.44,0:21:02.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是他却断然否认了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:03.49,0:21:05.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我才实施了计划
Dialogue: 0,0:21:07.45,0:21:10.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,自首的话就不会把命丢了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:11.75,0:21:12.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个卑鄙的家伙
Dialogue: 0,0:21:14.37,0:21:17.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,伪装成事故杀害速水先生 还试图掩盖
Dialogue: 0,0:21:18.59,0:21:20.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你也一样卑鄙
Dialogue: 0,0:21:21.80,0:21:23.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这回该你自首了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:29.39,0:21:30.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,侦探先生
Dialogue: 0,0:21:30.68,0:21:33.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你是什么时候发现我的计划的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:34.06,0:21:38.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是 你说没有发现彩虹的时候
Dialogue: 0,0:21:39.82,0:21:43.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,「碰撞航向」现象 不正面相向是不会发生的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:44.49,0:21:46.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你没有发现彩虹
Dialogue: 0,0:21:47.07,0:21:52.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是因为你想撞速水先生 光看侧面开车的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:21:53.66,0:21:56.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,固执于仇恨和憎恨
Dialogue: 0,0:21:56.67,0:22:00.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,才没有发现眼前更美的东西
Dialogue: 0,0:23:26.88,0:23:29.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸 睡眠不足 还开那么快很危险的
Dialogue: 0,0:23:30.30,0:23:33.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没事 我的大脑现在很清醒
Dialogue: 0,0:23:33.72,0:23:36.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是的嘛 你都睡了一觉了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:36.72,0:23:37.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今晚要是不回去的话
Dialogue: 0,0:23:38.27,0:23:40.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,租车费会长的
Dialogue: 0,0:23:41.27,0:23:43.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要是发生事故 那就更贵了哦
Dialogue: 0,0:23:43.61,0:23:44.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没事没事
Dialogue: 0,0:23:44.98,0:23:50.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今晚还有以洋子小姐的DVD做赌注的麻将大会呢
Dialogue: 0,0:23:51.57,0:23:53.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等着我啊 洋子
Dialogue: 0,0:23:54.66,0:23:57.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这也是独有的「小五郎」现象啊
Dialogue: 0,0:24:00.62,0:24:02.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个眼神不善哈欠女
Dialogue: 0,0:24:03.21,0:24:04.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是不好意思啊
Dialogue: 0,0:24:06.09,0:24:08.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是眼神不善哈欠女
Dialogue: 0,0:24:10.26,0:24:13.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,沿途搭的车 是罪犯的车？
Dialogue: 0,0:24:14.14,0:24:16.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这两个到底是什么人
Dialogue: 0,0:24:17.14,0:24:19.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,万一是黑衣组织他们一伙的…
Dialogue: 0,0:24:19.98,0:24:20.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么办
Dialogue: 0,0:24:21.23,0:24:22.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,打个半死？
Dialogue: 0,0:24:22.65,0:24:23.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,杀死？
Dialogue: 0,0:24:24.40,0:24:27.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下集柯南 危险的两个人
Dialogue: 0,0:24:45.63,0:24:49.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下集柯南提示 方言
Dialogue: 0,0:24:50.01,0:24:51.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下集博士和小哀的大危机呢！
Dialogue: 0,0:24:51.80,0:24:52.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,关西腔？
Dialogue: 0,0:24:52.72,0:24:54.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下周绝对不容错过哦
