[Script Info]
; // 此字幕由PopSub生成  2010-02-28 02:26:39
; // 版本: 0.74
; // popgo_fansub@yahoo.co.jp
; // 欢迎访问漫游天下 http://bbs.popgo.net
Title:漫游字幕
Original Script:漫游字幕组
Synch Point:0
ScriptType:v4.00+
Collisions:Normal
PlayResX:1280
PlayResY:720
Timer:100.0000

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,黑体,50,&H00FFFFFF,&HF0000000,&H00000000,&H32000000,-1,0,0,0,100,100,0,0.00,1,1,2,2,30,30,20,134

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Actor, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text


Dialogue: 0,0:00:00.71,0:00:05.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,烤番薯～
Dialogue: 0,0:00:05.85,0:00:08.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,多谢惠顾 很好吃的哦
Dialogue: 0,0:00:11.06,0:00:11.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是的
Dialogue: 0,0:00:12.13,0:00:14.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,以为会是很容易的事
Dialogue: 0,0:00:14.38,0:00:16.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为很热 要呼呼的吹才能吃
Dialogue: 0,0:00:16.84,0:00:19.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样呼呼
Dialogue: 0,0:00:19.49,0:00:20.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,来 要吃吗
Dialogue: 0,0:00:24.01,0:00:26.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在哪儿 去哪里了
Dialogue: 0,0:00:27.37,0:00:28.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,三太
Dialogue: 0,0:00:29.25,0:00:29.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,年龄是两岁
Dialogue: 0,0:00:30.15,0:00:30.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,名字叫三太
Dialogue: 0,0:00:31.68,0:00:32.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,个子大概这么高
Dialogue: 0,0:00:33.12,0:00:34.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,衣服是蓝色的
Dialogue: 0,0:00:34.62,0:00:36.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,裤子是绿色的
Dialogue: 0,0:00:37.03,0:00:40.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,三太君 你在哪儿
Dialogue: 0,0:00:41.35,0:00:46.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,三太君 三太君
Dialogue: 0,0:00:51.78,0:00:53.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,三太
Dialogue: 0,0:00:55.00,0:00:55.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,危险
Dialogue: 0,0:01:00.52,0:01:03.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那里 那里 那里
Dialogue: 0,0:01:07.03,0:01:08.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不可以哦 三太
Dialogue: 0,0:01:08.77,0:01:09.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不要擅自行动
Dialogue: 0,0:01:10.08,0:01:11.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那里那里那里
Dialogue: 0,0:01:11.71,0:01:13.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么啊 想看汽车吗
Dialogue: 0,0:01:13.87,0:01:16.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不不
Dialogue: 0,0:01:22.86,0:01:24.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,花随着钢琴的旋律起舞
Dialogue: 0,0:01:25.17,0:01:26.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,相对的两人却充满谜题
Dialogue: 0,0:01:27.21,0:01:31.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有着可爱名字的柯南的小搭档
Dialogue: 0,0:01:31.45,0:01:32.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,揭开唯一真相的
Dialogue: 0,0:01:33.10,0:01:34.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是一个外表看似小孩头脑却过于常人的
Dialogue: 0,0:01:34.96,0:01:36.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他的名字就是……名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:03:18.38,0:03:23.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,搭档是圣诞老人
Dialogue: 0,0:03:25.38,0:03:27.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦 爸爸拜托你的？
Dialogue: 0,0:03:27.49,0:03:29.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 拜托我照顾他
Dialogue: 0,0:03:32.29,0:03:33.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们先走吧
Dialogue: 0,0:03:33.59,0:03:34.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:03:40.50,0:03:41.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你叫什么名字
Dialogue: 0,0:03:41.79,0:03:43.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,圣诞老人
Dialogue: 0,0:03:41.79,0:03:43.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an2}{\fs25}{\shad1}[注：三太日文发音同圣诞老人（santa）]
Dialogue: 0,0:03:43.36,0:03:47.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,三太先生？说自己的名字时带「先生」吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:03:43.36,0:03:47.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an2}{\fs25}{\shad1}[注：santaさん（san）さん表示对他人的尊敬 类似于先生小姐 一般不用于自称 此时小兰以为三太自称是三太先生]
Dialogue: 0,0:03:48.38,0:03:49.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,几岁啦
Dialogue: 0,0:03:53.62,0:03:54.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,二岁吗
Dialogue: 0,0:03:55.81,0:03:57.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好可爱
Dialogue: 0,0:03:59.76,0:04:00.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,兰
Dialogue: 0,0:04:02.14,0:04:03.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:04:03.73,0:04:04.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你也在啊
Dialogue: 0,0:04:05.20,0:04:09.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,-柯南 你有好好照顾吧
Dialogue: 0,0:04:05.20,0:04:09.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,-妈妈 妈妈
Dialogue: 0,0:04:09.54,0:04:10.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:04:11.21,0:04:13.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我来介绍一下
Dialogue: 0,0:04:13.85,0:04:15.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这位是石川茂子
Dialogue: 0,0:04:16.54,0:04:17.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,初次见面
Dialogue: 0,0:04:21.53,0:04:25.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦 在天桥上被人撞了吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:04:26.06,0:04:29.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 被一个戴着封闭式安全帽的人
Dialogue: 0,0:04:29.69,0:04:30.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,从后面撞的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:31.18,0:04:34.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我正要开始做清扫的零工时
Dialogue: 0,0:04:35.10,0:04:37.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在工作的过程中
Dialogue: 0,0:04:42.29,0:04:46.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,正好呢 我经过了那儿
Dialogue: 0,0:04:46.41,0:04:48.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然万幸没有受什么伤
Dialogue: 0,0:04:48.71,0:04:53.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但总觉得这附近的道路上有可疑的人
Dialogue: 0,0:04:53.53,0:04:58.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,总是觉得 我被人监视着
Dialogue: 0,0:05:02.97,0:05:06.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然只从远处看不会有什么伤害
Dialogue: 0,0:05:06.19,0:05:10.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但被撞倒毫无疑问有发生事件的可能
Dialogue: 0,0:05:10.41,0:05:12.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我这么认为的于是把孩子交给柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:05:13.21,0:05:15.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后去附近查看
Dialogue: 0,0:05:15.49,0:05:16.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真过分
Dialogue: 0,0:05:17.17,0:05:18.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其他的家人呢
Dialogue: 0,0:05:19.05,0:05:21.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有了 丈夫去年就去世了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:22.03,0:05:23.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就剩我和这孩子相依为命
Dialogue: 0,0:05:24.23,0:05:26.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毛利先生这么忙还…
Dialogue: 0,0:05:26.22,0:05:27.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是非常抱歉
Dialogue: 0,0:05:27.80,0:05:29.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么还这么说
Dialogue: 0,0:05:29.97,0:05:32.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也是单身父亲带着一个孩子
Dialogue: 0,0:05:32.20,0:05:34.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,过着与你一样的生活
Dialogue: 0,0:05:34.32,0:05:37.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果你卷入了什么案件
Dialogue: 0,0:05:37.79,0:05:40.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这孩子就会流浪街头
Dialogue: 0,0:05:40.62,0:05:42.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对于做出这种胡闹行为的人
Dialogue: 0,0:05:42.89,0:05:45.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我的正义感是绝对不会原谅的
Dialogue: 0,0:05:45.30,0:05:46.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,绝对不能
Dialogue: 0,0:05:46.35,0:05:47.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然能理解这种心情
Dialogue: 0,0:05:48.12,0:05:49.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但因为对方是美女
Dialogue: 0,0:05:49.27,0:05:50.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你也理解的过头了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:50.77,0:05:53.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,关于那个带封闭式安全帽的人
Dialogue: 0,0:05:53.86,0:05:55.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有什么线索吗
Dialogue: 0,0:05:55.49,0:05:57.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 完全没有
Dialogue: 0,0:05:57.64,0:05:59.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那 走吧
Dialogue: 0,0:05:59.46,0:06:03.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,来吧 看我不逮着你 狠狠教训你
Dialogue: 0,0:06:05.49,0:06:08.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一二 一二 一二
Dialogue: 0,0:06:08.50,0:06:09.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喂
Dialogue: 0,0:06:14.49,0:06:17.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只要看着路 和平常一样
Dialogue: 0,0:06:18.17,0:06:20.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不要在意我的存在
Dialogue: 0,0:06:20.99,0:06:21.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:06:28.93,0:06:31.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很好 目前万无一失
Dialogue: 0,0:06:43.76,0:06:44.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是的
Dialogue: 0,0:06:44.97,0:06:47.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一件接一件的给我找事
Dialogue: 0,0:06:47.93,0:06:50.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对我难道有什么怨恨吗
Dialogue: 0,0:07:06.87,0:07:07.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下一条新闻
Dialogue: 0,0:07:08.09,0:07:10.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,昨天在动物园里
Dialogue: 0,0:07:10.26,0:07:12.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一只可爱的熊猫宝宝出生了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:13.02,0:07:15.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,据饲养员铃木说…
Dialogue: 0,0:07:15.64,0:07:19.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你好 我是桑桑清洁
Dialogue: 0,0:07:20.12,0:07:21.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请进
Dialogue: 0,0:07:22.21,0:07:22.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,打扰了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:29.89,0:07:33.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是的 为什么我要干这个
Dialogue: 0,0:07:36.02,0:07:37.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了 三太
Dialogue: 0,0:07:41.41,0:07:42.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要上厕所吗
Dialogue: 0,0:07:43.10,0:07:44.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等一下 忍住啊
Dialogue: 0,0:07:45.02,0:07:46.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再忍忍 再忍忍
Dialogue: 0,0:08:01.27,0:08:02.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,给我？
Dialogue: 0,0:08:03.51,0:08:04.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,化了的糖吗
Dialogue: 0,0:08:04.99,0:08:06.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,上厕所 谢谢
Dialogue: 0,0:08:07.72,0:08:09.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不客气
Dialogue: 0,0:08:09.71,0:08:13.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是真让我吃惊 没想到会这样
Dialogue: 0,0:08:13.88,0:08:15.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南 孩子没事吧
Dialogue: 0,0:08:16.25,0:08:20.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,三太 柯南 三太
Dialogue: 0,0:08:21.38,0:08:22.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了 叔叔
Dialogue: 0,0:08:23.02,0:08:23.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:08:24.79,0:08:26.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你没事吧
Dialogue: 0,0:08:26.68,0:08:28.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,茂子小姐被一个男人劫走了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:29.20,0:08:30.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,劫走了？
Dialogue: 0,0:08:30.94,0:08:35.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那人事先埋伏在客户家里
Dialogue: 0,0:08:35.43,0:08:38.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对方到底对一个主妇有什么目的啊
Dialogue: 0,0:08:38.68,0:08:40.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,孩子 有叔叔陪着你
Dialogue: 0,0:08:41.03,0:08:43.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也会联络警察的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:43.22,0:08:44.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你不用担心
Dialogue: 0,0:08:50.94,0:08:53.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么样 找到石川茂子小姐了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:08:54.02,0:08:54.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有
Dialogue: 0,0:08:55.00,0:08:58.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车的后座上留下了少量血迹
Dialogue: 0,0:08:59.01,0:09:01.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可能反抗的时候受了伤
Dialogue: 0,0:09:01.81,0:09:05.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这车是前不久被盗的车子
Dialogue: 0,0:09:05.65,0:09:07.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们接到过报告
Dialogue: 0,0:09:07.72,0:09:10.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,又是戴封闭式安全帽的男人
Dialogue: 0,0:09:10.30,0:09:13.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,现金没有被抢走
Dialogue: 0,0:09:13.37,0:09:16.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看来犯人的目的不是钱
Dialogue: 0,0:09:17.38,0:09:19.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,茂子小姐是个美人
Dialogue: 0,0:09:19.87,0:09:22.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也许犯人暗中迷上了她
Dialogue: 0,0:09:22.93,0:09:25.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后无法忍耐就诉诸暴力
Dialogue: 0,0:09:25.84,0:09:28.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是心术不正的无耻行为
Dialogue: 0,0:09:28.48,0:09:29.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不可原谅
Dialogue: 0,0:09:29.80,0:09:32.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 会撞飞喜欢的人吗
Dialogue: 0,0:09:32.65,0:09:34.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南 你是不会懂的
Dialogue: 0,0:09:35.05,0:09:36.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不要说多余的话
Dialogue: 0,0:09:36.64,0:09:37.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,给我到那边去
Dialogue: 0,0:09:37.97,0:09:39.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:09:40.51,0:09:43.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,包的开口处里面的物品掉了出来
Dialogue: 0,0:09:43.66,0:09:46.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 是散落着
Dialogue: 0,0:09:46.54,0:09:48.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是在包里找什么东西吗
Dialogue: 0,0:09:57.07,0:09:58.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢你 三太
Dialogue: 0,0:10:09.57,0:10:10.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就如我想的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:12.69,0:10:14.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,犯人在找东西
Dialogue: 0,0:10:15.61,0:10:17.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,时间是一点半左右
Dialogue: 0,0:10:17.95,0:10:20.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,劫走茂子小姐后拿到的钥匙吗
Dialogue: 0,0:10:21.98,0:10:23.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,犯人到底在找什么
Dialogue: 0,0:10:28.30,0:10:29.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,鸟的羽毛
Dialogue: 0,0:10:30.26,0:10:31.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么会在这儿
Dialogue: 0,0:10:33.65,0:10:37.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,圣诞老人 你好 我给你带礼物来了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:37.74,0:10:40.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,发生了什么事 这么凌乱
Dialogue: 0,0:10:40.44,0:10:42.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们只是在玩摔跤呢
Dialogue: 0,0:10:42.54,0:10:45.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大哥哥你和这孩子很熟吗
Dialogue: 0,0:10:45.39,0:10:48.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 我是住在楼上的森胁实
Dialogue: 0,0:10:48.97,0:10:51.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是米花兽医大学的学生
Dialogue: 0,0:10:51.45,0:10:52.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请多关照
Dialogue: 0,0:10:52.50,0:10:55.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这房间里在养小鸟吗
Dialogue: 0,0:10:55.33,0:10:58.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我在屋里发现了这个
Dialogue: 0,0:10:58.32,0:11:00.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但窗户是关着的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:00.37,0:11:02.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,会是哪里来的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:02.53,0:11:05.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可能粘在谁的身上带来的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:06.06,0:11:09.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,比如粘在了你或者三太的身上
Dialogue: 0,0:11:09.49,0:11:11.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,粘在身上带来的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:11.87,0:11:14.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,犯人的身上吗
Dialogue: 0,0:11:14.47,0:11:17.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这不是绣眼鸟的羽毛吗
Dialogue: 0,0:11:18.21,0:11:20.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要看看圣诞老人的关于小鸟的书吗
Dialogue: 0,0:11:21.11,0:11:22.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,书  要看
Dialogue: 0,0:11:24.64,0:11:27.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看 眼睛周围是白色 所以叫绣眼鸟
Dialogue: 0,0:11:27.79,0:11:29.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,麻雀的同类啊
Dialogue: 0,0:11:29.72,0:11:33.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,唉 还有种叫目黑鸟的鸟类啊
Dialogue: 0,0:11:33.78,0:11:36.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 是快绝种的珍稀动物啊
Dialogue: 0,0:11:36.71,0:11:40.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 之前有送你绣眼鸟的扭蛋吧
Dialogue: 0,0:11:40.80,0:11:43.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,朋友 礼物
Dialogue: 0,0:11:43.86,0:11:45.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,送给朋友做礼物了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:11:46.07,0:11:49.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,绣眼鸟的羽毛和绣眼鸟的扭蛋玩偶
Dialogue: 0,0:11:50.14,0:11:51.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,都是绣眼鸟
Dialogue: 0,0:11:51.60,0:11:55.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这和茂子小姐被劫持有什么关系吗
Dialogue: 0,0:11:57.62,0:12:02.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,圣诞老人 你把绣眼鸟送给了哪里的朋友呢
Dialogue: 0,0:12:02.79,0:12:06.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那边 那边 还有这边
Dialogue: 0,0:12:06.94,0:12:09.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么多地方啊
Dialogue: 0,0:12:16.73,0:12:21.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,三太 等待你礼物的朋友的家是在哪边啊
Dialogue: 0,0:12:21.72,0:12:24.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,-好疼…疼
Dialogue: 0,0:12:21.72,0:12:24.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,-这边
Dialogue: 0,0:12:25.80,0:12:29.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真疼啊 耳朵肿的像兔子了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:38.70,0:12:39.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯？
Dialogue: 0,0:12:39.50,0:12:40.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你看啊
Dialogue: 0,0:12:42.39,0:12:45.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不对 那些人不像是犯人
Dialogue: 0,0:12:45.76,0:12:47.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,都叫你别拉耳朵啊
Dialogue: 0,0:12:51.42,0:12:53.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好疼...
Dialogue: 0,0:12:55.54,0:12:57.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好疼…疼 别拉了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:57.93,0:12:59.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 好可爱
Dialogue: 0,0:13:04.01,0:13:07.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,圣诞老人 接下来要去哪边啊
Dialogue: 0,0:13:08.12,0:13:11.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了 圣诞老人快起来
Dialogue: 0,0:13:12.07,0:13:14.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要办的事还没办好呢 圣诞老人
Dialogue: 0,0:13:14.88,0:13:16.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,妈妈
Dialogue: 0,0:13:16.71,0:13:20.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你累了想睡觉我也能理解请在忍耐一会儿
Dialogue: 0,0:13:20.78,0:13:25.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不要 妈妈 妈妈
Dialogue: 0,0:13:25.24,0:13:26.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我才想哭呢
Dialogue: 0,0:13:33.08,0:13:34.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,给糖吃的叔叔
Dialogue: 0,0:13:34.85,0:13:36.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,给糖吃的叔叔？
Dialogue: 0,0:13:37.71,0:13:39.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,给你这个的人？
Dialogue: 0,0:13:40.20,0:13:41.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:13:41.96,0:13:42.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这样啊
Dialogue: 0,0:13:47.45,0:13:48.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是…
Dialogue: 0,0:13:54.51,0:13:59.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天下午5点到店里？4点半
Dialogue: 0,0:14:00.46,0:14:02.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看来没多少时间了啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:07.64,0:14:09.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,圣诞老人 没事吧
Dialogue: 0,0:14:20.59,0:14:23.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,住在旁边的山内先生是不是开了一家宠物商店啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:24.22,0:14:29.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊 我听说是专卖一些鸟啊金鱼之类的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:29.20,0:14:32.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请告诉我地址和店名好吗
Dialogue: 0,0:14:32.25,0:14:33.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好吗
Dialogue: 0,0:14:33.32,0:14:36.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好像是米花町三丁目
Dialogue: 0,0:14:36.30,0:14:38.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是好像快倒闭了呢
Dialogue: 0,0:14:39.51,0:14:41.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天下午5点到快要倒闭的店里去？
Dialogue: 0,0:14:42.46,0:14:45.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,三太的母亲或许就被关在那里
Dialogue: 0,0:14:52.03,0:14:55.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哈哈 他好像很喜欢这样啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:55.76,0:14:57.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嘛 开心就行了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:07.20,0:15:08.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来是这样啊
Dialogue: 0,0:15:09.89,0:15:13.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在追赶喜欢的给糖的叔叔时被我打扰了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:13.62,0:15:15.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,生气也是情有可原的啊
Dialogue: 0,0:15:26.95,0:15:28.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喂 大叔
Dialogue: 0,0:15:29.37,0:15:31.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们有什么事啊
Dialogue: 0,0:15:31.60,0:15:33.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们是来找人的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:33.43,0:15:37.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个三太的母亲是在你这里吧
Dialogue: 0,0:15:37.81,0:15:41.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我不认识 这里除了大叔我什么人都没有
Dialogue: 0,0:15:41.73,0:15:45.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思 叔叔我现在很忙 你们能不能回家去啊
Dialogue: 0,0:15:45.91,0:15:49.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你那个鸟笼里的鸟是不是叫目黑鸟啊
Dialogue: 0,0:15:50.00,0:15:53.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,目黑鸟？哦 不是 是绣眼鸟
Dialogue: 0,0:15:53.91,0:15:57.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这样吗 可是这上面写着啊
Dialogue: 0,0:15:57.59,0:16:00.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,目黑鸟 国家的自然保护动物
Dialogue: 0,0:16:00.93,0:16:04.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是由于眼睛四周都是黑色 所以才这样叫的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:04.51,0:16:08.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,特征是从喉咙到胸这里长着黄色的羽毛
Dialogue: 0,0:16:08.50,0:16:10.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喜欢吃的食物是番木瓜
Dialogue: 0,0:16:11.20,0:16:12.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是的 不是的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:12.76,0:16:16.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这只鸟要是快要绝种的目黑鸟的话
Dialogue: 0,0:16:16.89,0:16:18.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一定可以卖个好价钱的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:19.03,0:16:20.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我都叫你快走了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:20.57,0:16:23.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大叔 你去过这孩子的家是吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:23.72,0:16:26.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这根羽毛掉在房间里了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:26.81,0:16:30.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大概是把鸟塞进口袋里时沾上的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:30.87,0:16:32.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 我不知道
Dialogue: 0,0:16:32.86,0:16:38.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大叔我认为你还是自己去警局自首会减轻点罪哦
Dialogue: 0,0:16:38.67,0:16:43.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,警局？为什么我要去警局啊
Dialogue: 0,0:16:43.29,0:16:45.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我可没空陪小孩玩
Dialogue: 0,0:16:46.17,0:16:48.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你再不走的话可会让你吃点苦头的哦
Dialogue: 0,0:16:48.41,0:16:52.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你听我把话说完 我想你一定是搞错了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:53.13,0:16:54.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么事啊
Dialogue: 0,0:16:54.53,0:16:57.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个玩偶是放在你家门前的对吧
Dialogue: 0,0:16:57.55,0:17:00.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,放这玩偶的就是这位三太
Dialogue: 0,0:17:00.67,0:17:01.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,三太
Dialogue: 0,0:17:02.25,0:17:04.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这孩子？
Dialogue: 0,0:17:04.36,0:17:08.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大叔以前给这孩子吃过糖对吧
Dialogue: 0,0:17:08.31,0:17:09.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这就是那时的回礼啊
Dialogue: 0,0:17:10.18,0:17:11.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,回礼？
Dialogue: 0,0:17:11.93,0:17:17.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这孩子自称为「山太先生」是因为很喜欢圣诞老人
Dialogue: 0,0:17:17.30,0:17:20.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,自己也想成为一个能发给大家礼物的人
Dialogue: 0,0:17:21.40,0:17:24.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,圣诞老人？礼物？
Dialogue: 0,0:17:25.76,0:17:31.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,留下这个的是这孩子？ 是想送给我的礼物？
Dialogue: 0,0:17:31.96,0:17:35.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这样啊  是这样的吗
Dialogue: 0,0:17:35.83,0:17:41.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大叔 三太很喜欢你 也很信赖你哦
Dialogue: 0,0:17:41.58,0:17:44.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让三太哭的话不是太可怜了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:17:49.27,0:17:52.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,三太 对不起啊
Dialogue: 0,0:18:01.19,0:18:03.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,妈妈
Dialogue: 0,0:18:03.58,0:18:08.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这家店运营的不好 负债累累
Dialogue: 0,0:18:09.03,0:18:14.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,于是我趁人不知跑进小笠原村的山里
Dialogue: 0,0:18:16.57,0:18:18.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在那里发现了目黑鸟
Dialogue: 0,0:18:18.82,0:18:22.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是种面临绝种的鸟
Dialogue: 0,0:18:23.06,0:18:26.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我的债主是一个叫仓田的男人
Dialogue: 0,0:18:27.04,0:18:30.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,知道动物买卖的内幕 就叫我卖掉它
Dialogue: 0,0:18:31.14,0:18:36.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然而就在当天早晨 我在门前发现了目黑鸟的玩偶
Dialogue: 0,0:18:37.20,0:18:41.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后就看到走到门口的女人意义不明的笑容
Dialogue: 0,0:18:42.45,0:18:44.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就好像看穿了一切似的
Dialogue: 0,0:18:44.95,0:18:47.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我认为那个女人一定知道了目黑鸟的事
Dialogue: 0,0:18:47.82,0:18:53.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,玩偶和笑容就是对我无形的恐吓
Dialogue: 0,0:18:53.21,0:18:56.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我只是来接孩子而已
Dialogue: 0,0:18:56.28,0:18:59.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是你不是邀请了有名的侦探吗
Dialogue: 0,0:18:59.87,0:19:02.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了不让你破坏交易
Dialogue: 0,0:19:02.61,0:19:07.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果你有什么证据的话我就抢过来 所以才到你家去搜查的
Dialogue: 0,0:19:10.56,0:19:15.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我看到三太看扭蛋机的样子很可爱
Dialogue: 0,0:19:15.66,0:19:17.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不自觉就发糖给他吃了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:17.95,0:19:22.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我误解了送我的回礼和孩子的善意
Dialogue: 0,0:19:25.84,0:19:33.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,孩子 我要成为一个配的上从圣诞老人那里接受礼物的人
Dialogue: 0,0:19:34.43,0:19:36.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,目黑鸟就拜托你们了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:38.17,0:19:40.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔 给你
Dialogue: 0,0:19:42.84,0:19:44.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,目黑鸟的玩偶啊
Dialogue: 0,0:19:44.95,0:19:47.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔 你仔细看啊 这玩偶是绣眼鸟哦
Dialogue: 0,0:19:48.15,0:19:51.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,唉？绣眼鸟？
Dialogue: 0,0:19:51.70,0:19:55.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是 眼睛四周都是黑色的 这是目黑鸟啊
Dialogue: 0,0:19:55.86,0:20:00.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不对  是眼周围涂得白色化了使得看上去是黑色的而已
Dialogue: 0,0:20:01.10,0:20:04.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,唉 是真的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:20:05.14,0:20:06.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,颜料化了而已
Dialogue: 0,0:20:08.66,0:20:13.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我没有仔细看连这都没有发现呢
Dialogue: 0,0:20:14.55,0:20:17.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,圣诞老人 我会好好珍惜的
Dialogue: 0,0:20:18.04,0:20:19.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好好珍惜
Dialogue: 0,0:20:20.51,0:20:23.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是一番愚蠢的话
Dialogue: 0,0:20:23.92,0:20:27.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你要去自首啊 那目黑鸟就由我来接收吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:27.41,0:20:30.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不行 我要把这鸟送回原来的岛上
Dialogue: 0,0:20:31.20,0:20:32.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,少碍事
Dialogue: 0,0:20:32.09,0:20:33.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快住手
Dialogue: 0,0:20:33.84,0:20:35.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小鬼给我滚一边去
Dialogue: 0,0:20:35.65,0:20:37.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我要叫警察了哦
Dialogue: 0,0:20:37.55,0:20:40.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你要是敢叫警察的话就叫叫看啊
Dialogue: 0,0:20:40.90,0:20:42.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不要...
Dialogue: 0,0:20:42.59,0:20:43.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把电话放下来
Dialogue: 0,0:20:44.63,0:20:47.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,知道了 你快把孩子放了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:48.06,0:20:51.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等到了安全的地方我才放了这小鬼
Dialogue: 0,0:20:52.90,0:20:53.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,三太
Dialogue: 0,0:20:53.94,0:20:54.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,仓田
Dialogue: 0,0:20:56.06,0:20:59.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哎？因为刚才的撞击使得手表出故障了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:20:59.65,0:21:01.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,仓田快放手啊
Dialogue: 0,0:21:01.44,0:21:04.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,都别动啊 都不许动啊
Dialogue: 0,0:21:11.88,0:21:13.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就是现在 看招
Dialogue: 0,0:22:49.13,0:22:53.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嘛 警察说会考虑对山内酌情处理的
Dialogue: 0,0:22:53.21,0:22:54.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这样吗
Dialogue: 0,0:22:54.52,0:22:57.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哦 真厉害啊 三太酱
Dialogue: 0,0:22:57.70,0:23:00.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯？怎么了 三太酱
Dialogue: 0,0:23:01.78,0:23:03.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还带上了丝带
Dialogue: 0,0:23:03.55,0:23:05.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是小兰送的
Dialogue: 0,0:23:06.12,0:23:08.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很合适哦 小遥
Dialogue: 0,0:23:08.76,0:23:12.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小…小遥？ 三太难道是女孩子？
Dialogue: 0,0:23:12.92,0:23:13.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:23:14.29,0:23:18.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是还真亏你发现了呢
Dialogue: 0,0:23:18.20,0:23:19.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,第一次抱她的时候…
Dialogue: 0,0:23:22.31,0:23:26.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,听人说女孩子会往抱她的人身上扑
Dialogue: 0,0:23:27.44,0:23:29.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南你也知道了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:23:29.99,0:23:31.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 完全不知
Dialogue: 0,0:23:32.04,0:23:35.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其实带她去厕所的时候就知道了
Dialogue: 0,0:23:35.69,0:23:38.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们一直在一起也没发现啊
Dialogue: 0,0:23:38.37,0:23:40.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗 是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:23:44.68,0:23:47.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哈哈 好玩吗
Dialogue: 0,0:23:47.26,0:23:51.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那就一起来玩吧 和你妈妈一起哦
Dialogue: 0,0:23:52.01,0:23:55.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和妈妈一起啊 就知道你会这样说
Dialogue: 0,0:23:59.93,0:24:01.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,注意脚边 五右卫门浴池
Dialogue: 0,0:24:01.98,0:24:03.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在温泉公园发生事件
Dialogue: 0,0:24:03.88,0:24:06.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,除去迷雾 揭发真相
Dialogue: 0,0:24:06.61,0:24:09.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下集柯南 露天温泉降下的杀意
Dialogue: 0,0:24:25.38,0:24:27.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下集柯南提示
Dialogue: 0,0:24:27.38,0:24:28.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,毛巾
Dialogue: 0,0:24:29.68,0:24:32.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下集的舞台是露天温泉 混…混浴？
Dialogue: 0,0:24:32.84,0:24:34.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大叔
Dialogue: 0,0:24:35.55,0:24:37.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,女士们先生们
Dialogue: 0,0:24:37.57,0:24:38.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,终于到我出场了
Dialogue: 0,0:24:39.09,0:24:40.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然对不住小侦探
Dialogue: 0,0:24:40.87,0:24:42.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,天空是我的主场
Dialogue: 0,0:24:42.52,0:24:44.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,老老实实看我的表演吧
Dialogue: 0,0:24:44.53,0:24:45.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,基德
Dialogue: 0,0:24:45.31,0:24:46.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,剧场版 名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:24:47.09,0:24:48.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,天空的破难船
