[Script Info]
; // 此字幕由PopSub生成  2010-03-28 01:19:03
; // 版本: 0.74
; // popgo_fansub@yahoo.co.jp
; // 欢迎访问漫游天下 http://bbs.popgo.net
Title:漫游字幕
Original Script:漫游字幕组
Synch Point:0
ScriptType:v4.00+
Collisions:Normal
PlayResX:1280
PlayResY:720
Timer:100.0000

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,黑体,50,&H00FFFFFF,&HF0000000,&H00000000,&H32000000,-1,0,0,0,100,100,0,0.00,1,1,2,2,30,30,20,134

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Actor, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text



Dialogue: 0,0:00:10.98,0:00:11.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦
Dialogue: 0,0:00:13.35,0:00:18.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们刚来的时候那个人就已经坐在那里了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:00:18.73,0:00:20.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哇 超级美女
Dialogue: 0,0:00:21.19,0:00:25.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,确实如此 已经过了两个小时了
Dialogue: 0,0:00:32.80,0:00:34.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喂 你好
Dialogue: 0,0:00:35.14,0:00:36.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:00:37.73,0:00:41.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦 你说什么？
Dialogue: 0,0:00:45.31,0:00:47.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你没事吧
Dialogue: 0,0:00:48.01,0:00:49.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思
Dialogue: 0,0:00:49.25,0:00:51.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,发生什么事了吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:00:51.25,0:00:53.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可以的话请告诉我们
Dialogue: 0,0:00:53.62,0:00:56.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我名叫毛利小五郎
Dialogue: 0,0:00:56.78,0:00:58.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦 就是那个名侦探
Dialogue: 0,0:00:59.18,0:00:59.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:01:00.63,0:01:04.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其实 刚才是警察来的电话
Dialogue: 0,0:01:04.49,0:01:06.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说是家里有人死了
Dialogue: 0,0:01:06.49,0:01:08.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:01:11.54,0:01:13.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,花在钢琴的旋律中漫舞
Dialogue: 0,0:01:13.31,0:01:14.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,相对的两人却充满谜题
Dialogue: 0,0:01:15.24,0:01:17.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天的案件相当棘手
Dialogue: 0,0:01:17.40,0:01:18.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所谓无法证明的犯罪究竟是什么
Dialogue: 0,0:01:19.16,0:01:20.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,唯一看透真相的
Dialogue: 0,0:01:21.11,0:01:22.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是一个外表像小孩智慧却过于常人的
Dialogue: 0,0:01:22.93,0:01:24.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他的名字就是……名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:03:06.32,0:03:11.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,证实几率为零的犯罪
Dialogue: 0,0:03:18.76,0:03:22.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,死者名为副岛逸郎 27岁
Dialogue: 0,0:03:23.09,0:03:26.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是这一家的主人高畑响子的妹妹
Dialogue: 0,0:03:26.32,0:03:27.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是高畑栞的丈夫
Dialogue: 0,0:03:31.31,0:03:35.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是落下的枝形吊灯和霰弹枪
Dialogue: 0,0:03:36.11,0:03:38.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看来是枪支走火了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:03:46.49,0:03:47.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:03:47.84,0:03:51.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 没什么
Dialogue: 0,0:03:52.79,0:03:54.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接下来让人吃惊的是
Dialogue: 0,0:03:58.15,0:03:59.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我来晚了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:59.34,0:04:01.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你干什么去了 千叶
Dialogue: 0,0:04:01.68,0:04:03.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,抱 抱歉
Dialogue: 0,0:04:03.92,0:04:07.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦 副岛 不会吧
Dialogue: 0,0:04:08.33,0:04:11.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被害者是千叶警察大学时代的朋友
Dialogue: 0,0:04:12.50,0:04:14.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,发生了什么事啊？
Dialogue: 0,0:04:14.84,0:04:18.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看来是枪支走火打到吊灯
Dialogue: 0,0:04:18.42,0:04:19.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被落下的吊灯砸到了头
Dialogue: 0,0:04:20.94,0:04:23.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,死亡推定时间呢？
Dialogue: 0,0:04:23.34,0:04:25.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,大约是一小时之前
Dialogue: 0,0:04:25.41,0:04:30.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也就是说他趁她不在的时候进入家里
Dialogue: 0,0:04:30.44,0:04:37.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喝醉以后从保存箱拿出猎枪 放入弹丸
Dialogue: 0,0:04:37.41,0:04:40.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在摆玩之中不慎走火了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:40.81,0:04:42.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会
Dialogue: 0,0:04:42.61,0:04:44.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,逸郎他果然…
Dialogue: 0,0:04:44.89,0:04:48.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,早知道会这样 所以一直很担心
Dialogue: 0,0:04:48.72,0:04:50.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦 这是怎么回事？
Dialogue: 0,0:04:51.05,0:04:54.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然我不想说的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:54.24,0:04:58.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,逸郎的新开始的事业遭到了失败
Dialogue: 0,0:04:58.29,0:05:00.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,欠了一屁股的债
Dialogue: 0,0:05:00.35,0:05:03.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,妹妹小栞为她格外操心
Dialogue: 0,0:05:03.25,0:05:08.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但他却只知道酗酒 到处惹麻烦
Dialogue: 0,0:05:09.00,0:05:12.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,半年前妹妹生病去世后
Dialogue: 0,0:05:12.57,0:05:13.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他就变本加厉
Dialogue: 0,0:05:14.09,0:05:19.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,醉醺醺的进出我介绍的健身俱乐部和射击场
Dialogue: 0,0:05:19.31,0:05:19.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请住手
Dialogue: 0,0:05:20.06,0:05:22.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,放开我 放开
Dialogue: 0,0:05:28.87,0:05:32.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,结果被俱乐部强制退会
Dialogue: 0,0:05:33.00,0:05:35.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,枪支的许可证也被没收
Dialogue: 0,0:05:35.75,0:05:38.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以想来用我的枪
Dialogue: 0,0:05:38.78,0:05:42.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,于是趁你不在的时候进来
Dialogue: 0,0:05:42.62,0:05:43.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,结果就…
Dialogue: 0,0:05:44.09,0:05:45.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会吧
Dialogue: 0,0:05:45.87,0:05:51.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他的确酗酒无度 我也找他谈过
Dialogue: 0,0:05:51.38,0:05:55.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是他说他会戒掉的 戒掉喝酒
Dialogue: 0,0:05:55.58,0:05:58.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,想戒也戒不掉的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:05:58.99,0:06:02.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会呢  我听他说过射击场的事
Dialogue: 0,0:06:02.65,0:06:04.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他向我发过誓的
Dialogue: 0,0:06:04.80,0:06:06.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说再也不会碰枪了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:07.17,0:06:10.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被酒迷昏了头 所以就忘得一干二净了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:10.31,0:06:11.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他才不会这样呢
Dialogue: 0,0:06:11.76,0:06:14.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,摆了那么多好吃的料理的话
Dialogue: 0,0:06:14.87,0:06:17.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可能不知不觉的就想喝酒了呢
Dialogue: 0,0:06:17.81,0:06:21.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,的确 哪个都是上好的下酒菜呢…
Dialogue: 0,0:06:22.12,0:06:25.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这种事不用你小鬼头来多嘴
Dialogue: 0,0:06:27.49,0:06:31.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,擅自把饭菜拿出冰箱
Dialogue: 0,0:06:32.19,0:06:34.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也有责任吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:34.48,0:06:36.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 没有的事
Dialogue: 0,0:06:36.47,0:06:37.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,兰
Dialogue: 0,0:06:38.03,0:06:40.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南 我们会碍事的该走了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:40.31,0:06:41.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是钥匙呢？
Dialogue: 0,0:06:41.70,0:06:42.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,钥匙
Dialogue: 0,0:06:43.14,0:06:45.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不在家的话 这个人是怎样进来的呢？
Dialogue: 0,0:06:46.19,0:06:49.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,门和窗看上去也都没有被撬的痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:06:49.50,0:06:51.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他拿了备份钥匙之类的
Dialogue: 0,0:06:51.70,0:06:52.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没错就是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:06:53.08,0:06:55.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 哪儿都找不到备份钥匙哦
Dialogue: 0,0:06:55.78,0:06:57.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不仅如此
Dialogue: 0,0:06:57.44,0:07:01.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个人看上去连手机 钱包都没有带
Dialogue: 0,0:07:01.55,0:07:04.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,臭小子 不要到处走动
Dialogue: 0,0:07:04.25,0:07:06.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,备份钥匙放在玄关外面
Dialogue: 0,0:07:06.95,0:07:09.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也告诉过他放的地方了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:10.14,0:07:12.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,猎枪和弹丸的保存箱呢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:12.47,0:07:14.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,保险箱应该是上锁了的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:15.39,0:07:16.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么样
Dialogue: 0,0:07:16.22,0:07:20.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 很旧的锁了 零件也已经损坏了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:20.32,0:07:23.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样的话 应该很容易就能打开
Dialogue: 0,0:07:23.71,0:07:26.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再说这样不坚固的柜子
Dialogue: 0,0:07:26.86,0:07:30.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也不符合法律规定的储藏要求啊
Dialogue: 0,0:07:31.09,0:07:32.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可能会被吊销许可证
Dialogue: 0,0:07:32.58,0:07:35.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你要做好心理准备会受到相应的处罚哦
Dialogue: 0,0:07:35.27,0:07:36.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:07:36.92,0:07:40.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个么…也是没办法的事了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:40.53,0:07:42.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是反过来说
Dialogue: 0,0:07:43.05,0:07:47.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,能不顾一个人死去的事实就这样了结了么
Dialogue: 0,0:07:47.73,0:07:50.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这次案件就作为意外交给当地警署吧
Dialogue: 0,0:07:50.85,0:07:53.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请等一下 我还是不能相信
Dialogue: 0,0:07:53.91,0:07:55.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是
Dialogue: 0,0:07:56.01,0:07:57.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请再仔细调查一下吧
Dialogue: 0,0:07:57.92,0:08:00.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,千叶 冷静一点
Dialogue: 0,0:08:00.24,0:08:01.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这怎么看都是意外
Dialogue: 0,0:08:02.08,0:08:02.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是
Dialogue: 0,0:08:03.10,0:08:04.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你给我适可而止
Dialogue: 0,0:08:04.77,0:08:06.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,给我到外面去头脑清醒一下再说
Dialogue: 0,0:08:16.64,0:08:20.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,失去朋友的心情 倒也不是不能理解
Dialogue: 0,0:08:20.76,0:08:24.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个 你在那个咖啡厅里做什么啊？
Dialogue: 0,0:08:24.61,0:08:25.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦
Dialogue: 0,0:08:25.67,0:08:29.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,坐了两个多小时 是在等待什么吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:08:30.46,0:08:33.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我没有在等谁啊
Dialogue: 0,0:08:33.70,0:08:34.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真的吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:08:35.10,0:08:36.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你也适可而止
Dialogue: 0,0:08:38.18,0:08:39.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也给我出去头脑清醒一下吧
Dialogue: 0,0:08:41.23,0:08:42.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,疼……
Dialogue: 0,0:08:54.23,0:08:56.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是什么啊
Dialogue: 0,0:08:56.38,0:09:00.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是副岛的手机吊坠
Dialogue: 0,0:09:00.96,0:09:01.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真的吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:09:02.14,0:09:06.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 与死去的小栞小姐的刚好是一对
Dialogue: 0,0:09:06.26,0:09:08.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是现场没有发现手机啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:09.11,0:09:12.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,能问你些事吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:09:12.69,0:09:13.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦
Dialogue: 0,0:09:16.34,0:09:18.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,副岛的人品啊
Dialogue: 0,0:09:19.52,0:09:22.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我在运动方面只会柔道而已
Dialogue: 0,0:09:23.19,0:09:25.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而他是个什么都会的全能
Dialogue: 0,0:09:25.95,0:09:29.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 他面对压力却显得很脆弱
Dialogue: 0,0:09:29.64,0:09:34.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,工作上的压力 只能用酒来倾诉了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:34.44,0:09:39.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说不定 事故不仅仅是在射击场和水池发生过吧
Dialogue: 0,0:09:40.72,0:09:44.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要是在这方面仔细调查一下的话
Dialogue: 0,0:09:44.13,0:09:46.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说不定会发现什么呢
Dialogue: 0,0:09:46.27,0:09:50.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对啊 也许就会有新的发现
Dialogue: 0,0:09:51.43,0:09:52.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好嘞
Dialogue: 0,0:09:56.39,0:10:00.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,根据调查 同样的事故曾多次发生
Dialogue: 0,0:10:00.51,0:10:02.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,撞击的痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:10:02.42,0:10:04.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果没有护栏
Dialogue: 0,0:10:04.30,0:10:07.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,车子就会翻落下去 人也许会死
Dialogue: 0,0:10:08.25,0:10:10.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是一个月之前
Dialogue: 0,0:10:12.66,0:10:13.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后两个月前
Dialogue: 0,0:10:14.32,0:10:18.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,隆冬时节醉倒在了路边
Dialogue: 0,0:10:19.30,0:10:21.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要是发现晚了 就这样冻死了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:23.30,0:10:25.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,加上其他可疑的事件
Dialogue: 0,0:10:26.17,0:10:28.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这半年内一共发生了九起
Dialogue: 0,0:10:29.27,0:10:33.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小栞死后 副岛确实消沉了很久
Dialogue: 0,0:10:33.60,0:10:36.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,的确那段时间喝酒的量也增加了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:36.83,0:10:39.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,以为他这次终于下定决心了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:40.01,0:10:44.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是好了没多久却又旧病复发了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:45.23,0:10:47.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这半年就这样反反复复
Dialogue: 0,0:10:48.56,0:10:50.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就像毛利先生说的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:50.87,0:10:53.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,想戒都戒不掉吧
Dialogue: 0,0:10:54.98,0:10:57.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过他也真的挺幸福的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:57.94,0:11:00.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然只是妹妹的丈夫
Dialogue: 0,0:11:00.30,0:11:02.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,无论事故的赔款还是罚金
Dialogue: 0,0:11:02.49,0:11:05.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,甚至连探望用的钱
Dialogue: 0,0:11:05.38,0:11:08.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好像都是由做姐姐的响子小姐揽下的
Dialogue: 0,0:11:08.74,0:11:13.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且无论是介绍他去俱乐部和射击场之后发生的事故
Dialogue: 0,0:11:14.10,0:11:16.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还是用备份钥匙就能进入
Dialogue: 0,0:11:16.60,0:11:20.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,锁已经没用的枪支的保管箱的主人都是她…
Dialogue: 0,0:11:22.79,0:11:25.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你知道 故意的过失吗
Dialogue: 0,0:11:25.73,0:11:27.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,故意的过失？
Dialogue: 0,0:11:29.17,0:11:31.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所谓 故意的过失 就是指
Dialogue: 0,0:11:31.24,0:11:34.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然预料到某种行为也许会成为犯罪
Dialogue: 0,0:11:35.15,0:11:37.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但认为那样也没所谓
Dialogue: 0,0:11:37.80,0:11:41.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,仍然进行这种行为的这种心情
Dialogue: 0,0:11:43.03,0:11:45.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这我当然知道
Dialogue: 0,0:11:45.78,0:11:49.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,倒是柯南你知道的还真清楚呢
Dialogue: 0,0:11:51.46,0:11:55.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也是之前听小五郎叔叔说过
Dialogue: 0,0:11:56.38,0:12:02.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然已经预料到嗜酒的副岛也许会因此丧命
Dialogue: 0,0:12:03.02,0:12:06.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,却仍然设计了可以开车的环境
Dialogue: 0,0:12:06.34,0:12:08.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怂恿他去射击和游泳
Dialogue: 0,0:12:08.73,0:12:11.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不在家里而使其喝醉并拿到枪
Dialogue: 0,0:12:12.53,0:12:15.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可能会死 也可能不死
Dialogue: 0,0:12:15.88,0:12:18.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这种几率既非百分之百 却也不为零
Dialogue: 0,0:12:18.95,0:12:21.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果在此赌上一把的话
Dialogue: 0,0:12:21.30,0:12:23.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道说是…
Dialogue: 0,0:12:32.43,0:12:34.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南 我借来钥匙了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:35.16,0:12:38.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还是向毛利先生和警部打声招呼比较好
Dialogue: 0,0:12:38.91,0:12:40.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,行了啦 快点快点
Dialogue: 0,0:12:40.66,0:12:42.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:12:45.61,0:12:46.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这间房间…
Dialogue: 0,0:12:48.15,0:12:50.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好暗啊 灯开关在哪儿啊
Dialogue: 0,0:12:51.04,0:12:51.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等等
Dialogue: 0,0:12:57.63,0:13:01.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此 是手机充电的灯光啊
Dialogue: 0,0:13:01.15,0:13:02.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,充电？
Dialogue: 0,0:13:03.23,0:13:04.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是谁的手机啊？
Dialogue: 0,0:13:05.04,0:13:07.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那是小栞的手机
Dialogue: 0,0:13:08.52,0:13:09.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,副岛那家伙
Dialogue: 0,0:13:09.96,0:13:12.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为了不让小栞手机里的数据丢失
Dialogue: 0,0:13:12.92,0:13:14.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一直在给手机充电啊
Dialogue: 0,0:13:14.93,0:13:16.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等一下
Dialogue: 0,0:13:16.24,0:13:20.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在这半天里应该没有人来过这房间才对
Dialogue: 0,0:13:20.71,0:13:25.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道说是就在刚才还有人在此使用过这部手机？
Dialogue: 0,0:13:25.47,0:13:28.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么 到底是谁…
Dialogue: 0,0:13:29.77,0:13:31.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,的确有人来过的样子呢
Dialogue: 0,0:13:32.21,0:13:34.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有些被翻动过的痕迹
Dialogue: 0,0:13:34.91,0:13:36.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道是闯空房盗贼？
Dialogue: 0,0:13:34.91,0:13:36.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an2}{\fs25}{\shad1}闯空房：指小偷趁主人不在家入宅盗窃
Dialogue: 0,0:13:36.96,0:13:40.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那样的话也不会特意把门都关好的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:13:40.32,0:13:41.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,话虽如此
Dialogue: 0,0:13:41.85,0:13:45.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可是我刚才从无线电里听到
Dialogue: 0,0:13:45.24,0:13:48.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,米花公署那里抓到了最近一直闯空房的盗贼
Dialogue: 0,0:13:48.29,0:13:50.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等等 难道说…
Dialogue: 0,0:13:51.66,0:13:52.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么呀
Dialogue: 0,0:13:53.58,0:13:55.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好像有个闪闪发亮的东西掉下来了
Dialogue: 0,0:13:56.12,0:13:57.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦 什么？
Dialogue: 0,0:13:59.19,0:14:00.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是…
Dialogue: 0,0:14:02.55,0:14:04.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此啊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:07.31,0:14:09.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到底怎么回事呀  毛利先生
Dialogue: 0,0:14:09.33,0:14:12.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道是在怀疑我吗
Dialogue: 0,0:14:12.78,0:14:16.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 不是这样的啦
Dialogue: 0,0:14:16.30,0:14:17.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,喂 千叶
Dialogue: 0,0:14:18.04,0:14:21.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到底怎么回事啊 突然把我们都叫过来
Dialogue: 0,0:14:21.87,0:14:22.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快给我说明一下
Dialogue: 0,0:14:23.20,0:14:25.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个 其实 也就是说
Dialogue: 0,0:14:25.66,0:14:30.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这件案件的犯人就是你 高畑响子
Dialogue: 0,0:14:31.53,0:14:33.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么 你说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:14:33.45,0:14:37.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南说 毛利先生会详细解释清楚的
Dialogue: 0,0:14:38.07,0:14:41.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊  这种事我可没有答应过…
Dialogue: 0,0:14:45.82,0:14:48.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么 我开始解释给你们听
Dialogue: 0,0:14:48.50,0:14:49.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,撤回前言
Dialogue: 0,0:14:50.20,0:14:55.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我的确怀疑过你是否杀害了副岛先生
Dialogue: 0,0:14:55.26,0:14:57.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我杀害了逸郎先生？
Dialogue: 0,0:14:57.81,0:15:01.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是件花了半年长的时间…
Dialogue: 0,0:15:01.65,0:15:06.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 是在成功之前无论花多久都要去实行的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:06.39,0:15:08.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,远大的杀人计划
Dialogue: 0,0:15:08.40,0:15:11.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,使用密室手法的完美犯罪
Dialogue: 0,0:15:13.29,0:15:15.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你为酒品不好的副岛先生设计了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:15.59,0:15:19.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,各种各样的一不小心就会出人命的场景
Dialogue: 0,0:15:20.19,0:15:22.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接下来你只要等待就行了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:22.56,0:15:26.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对 在咖啡厅边喝红茶边等
Dialogue: 0,0:15:26.45,0:15:29.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是有趣 说得好像电影和小说一样
Dialogue: 0,0:15:29.59,0:15:31.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你有证据吗
Dialogue: 0,0:15:31.62,0:15:33.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,证据吗
Dialogue: 0,0:15:33.44,0:15:35.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说起来差不多第一个证据
Dialogue: 0,0:15:35.85,0:15:38.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不 证人就要到了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:38.95,0:15:40.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,证人？
Dialogue: 0,0:15:40.69,0:15:44.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,千叶你看 我硬是从米花公署那里带来了哦
Dialogue: 0,0:15:45.20,0:15:46.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢你
Dialogue: 0,0:15:46.50,0:15:48.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,唉 我可什么都没听你说过啊
Dialogue: 0,0:15:48.82,0:15:50.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:15:50.25,0:15:53.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是受毛利先生所托 让我帮千叶一把
Dialogue: 0,0:15:54.20,0:15:57.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个男子名叫西谷直也
Dialogue: 0,0:15:57.29,0:16:00.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,昨天被米花公署逮捕的闯空房的常犯
Dialogue: 0,0:16:00.98,0:16:02.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,闯空房？
Dialogue: 0,0:16:02.49,0:16:06.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是的 昨天他潜入这间房间
Dialogue: 0,0:16:06.28,0:16:09.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看到了案件的一部分事实
Dialogue: 0,0:16:09.19,0:16:10.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么
Dialogue: 0,0:16:10.58,0:16:13.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好了 把刚才所说的话再说一遍
Dialogue: 0,0:16:13.82,0:16:21.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,都说了 我爬进2楼时那人突然回来了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:22.53,0:16:26.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是逸郎  大姐？
Dialogue: 0,0:16:28.18,0:16:30.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么呀 把我叫来自己却不在…
Dialogue: 0,0:16:36.01,0:16:38.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不行 不能喝
Dialogue: 0,0:16:42.20,0:16:43.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会吧…
Dialogue: 0,0:16:53.11,0:16:56.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那人不一会儿就喝的昏昏沉沉的
Dialogue: 0,0:16:56.99,0:16:59.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,突然把枪指向了我
Dialogue: 0,0:16:59.52,0:17:01.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就在我觉得不妙的瞬间
Dialogue: 0,0:17:14.45,0:17:16.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所有的一切都是被设计好的
Dialogue: 0,0:17:17.29,0:17:22.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这已经不是管理不当猎枪走火那种程度的事了
Dialogue: 0,0:17:22.60,0:17:24.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而是明显的犯罪行为
Dialogue: 0,0:17:24.55,0:17:28.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等一下 这都是他的一面之词
Dialogue: 0,0:17:28.77,0:17:31.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我和他之间你们信谁啊
Dialogue: 0,0:17:31.47,0:17:35.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你难道不在意副岛先生的手机在哪儿吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:17:37.09,0:17:40.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那时你在找什么东西
Dialogue: 0,0:17:40.92,0:17:43.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,其实就是副岛先生的手机
Dialogue: 0,0:17:44.02,0:17:46.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你其实想要消除掉的是…
Dialogue: 0,0:17:46.90,0:17:49.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么呀 把我叫来自己却不在…
Dialogue: 0,0:17:50.08,0:17:55.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你把副岛先生叫到这里来的短信数据
Dialogue: 0,0:17:57.92,0:18:03.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你昨晚去房间找副岛先生的手机了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:03.56,0:18:05.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说什么呀
Dialogue: 0,0:18:05.49,0:18:08.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真是漂亮的艺术指甲啊
Dialogue: 0,0:18:09.70,0:18:13.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是莱茵石都还齐么
Dialogue: 0,0:18:09.70,0:18:13.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an2}{\fs25}{\shad1}莱茵石：人造钻石
Dialogue: 0,0:18:15.74,0:18:16.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,千叶
Dialogue: 0,0:18:16.88,0:18:17.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:18:18.97,0:18:21.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在小栞手机附件掉下来的
Dialogue: 0,0:18:21.70,0:18:25.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和你指甲上的东西一样吧
Dialogue: 0,0:18:28.54,0:18:30.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那么手机呢
Dialogue: 0,0:18:30.79,0:18:32.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说来可惜
Dialogue: 0,0:18:32.54,0:18:35.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,把钱从钱包里拿走之后
Dialogue: 0,0:18:35.14,0:18:37.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和手机一起丢进了河里
Dialogue: 0,0:18:38.00,0:18:40.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,数据都丢失了 不可能修好了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:41.10,0:18:42.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会这样啊
Dialogue: 0,0:18:42.84,0:18:46.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哼 真可惜啊 没有证据了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:47.16,0:18:51.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说起来那种短信本来就不存在的
Dialogue: 0,0:18:51.57,0:18:56.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我所找的不是你发出的短信
Dialogue: 0,0:18:58.58,0:19:01.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你所碰到的小栞小姐的手机
Dialogue: 0,0:19:01.96,0:19:04.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然已经去世了但是还放在充电器上充电
Dialogue: 0,0:19:04.88,0:19:07.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看来副岛先生很珍惜啊
Dialogue: 0,0:19:08.63,0:19:13.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说不定对他来说小栞小姐还活在心中
Dialogue: 0,0:19:13.84,0:19:19.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,别说傻话了 那个男人使得小栞有多痛苦啊
Dialogue: 0,0:19:19.58,0:19:21.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他死了也活该
Dialogue: 0,0:19:22.34,0:19:25.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,总算听到你的真心话了啊
Dialogue: 0,0:19:25.83,0:19:29.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那又怎么样 你要逮捕我吗
Dialogue: 0,0:19:29.61,0:19:31.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是一个侦探
Dialogue: 0,0:19:31.72,0:19:34.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,既不能逮捕你 也不能处罚你
Dialogue: 0,0:19:35.25,0:19:39.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,侦探的工作只有找寻真相而已
Dialogue: 0,0:19:40.03,0:19:45.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这次我所发现的是你妹妹的真心话
Dialogue: 0,0:19:45.34,0:19:48.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小栞的真心话？
Dialogue: 0,0:19:49.93,0:19:50.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦？
Dialogue: 0,0:19:51.04,0:19:53.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是短信 不必客气请看好了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:56.01,0:19:56.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思
Dialogue: 0,0:20:02.21,0:20:03.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不…不会吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:06.80,0:20:09.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,说不定是来自天国的信息啊
Dialogue: 0,0:20:10.23,0:20:12.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你读读看啊
Dialogue: 0,0:20:14.87,0:20:16.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对不起啊 逸郎…
Dialogue: 0,0:20:17.04,0:20:21.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明明应该和你一起努力的 竟然生了病
Dialogue: 0,0:20:21.69,0:20:26.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等我病好了恢复后 一定去向姐姐道歉
Dialogue: 0,0:20:26.82,0:20:29.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没关系的 姐姐一定会理解的
Dialogue: 0,0:20:29.78,0:20:31.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为她很温柔
Dialogue: 0,0:20:31.75,0:20:34.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她就我这么一个妹妹啊
Dialogue: 0,0:20:35.29,0:20:36.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小栞…
Dialogue: 0,0:20:38.32,0:20:40.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道说是…
Dialogue: 0,0:20:40.73,0:20:44.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在生前小栞小姐寄给副岛先生的短信
Dialogue: 0,0:20:45.25,0:20:50.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在小栞小姐的手机已发信箱里留下来的
Dialogue: 0,0:20:51.30,0:20:51.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:20:52.13,0:20:53.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,来了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:53.58,0:20:55.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让你吃惊了 真是对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:20:56.41,0:20:58.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是小栞小姐的手机
Dialogue: 0,0:20:58.35,0:21:01.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,昨天你一定没仔细看过吧
Dialogue: 0,0:21:04.28,0:21:07.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 结果小栞小姐病死了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:08.46,0:21:11.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你在没理解小栞小姐真心的情况下
Dialogue: 0,0:21:12.15,0:21:16.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,开始了对副岛先生的谋杀计划
Dialogue: 0,0:21:16.19,0:21:22.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说谎 小栞应该是很恨那个男人的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:22.41,0:21:25.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,副岛真的是想重新做人的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:26.18,0:21:28.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果不是你被仇恨迷惑了双眼
Dialogue: 0,0:21:29.09,0:21:33.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,应该可以理解那家伙以及小栞小姐的心情的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:34.02,0:21:36.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这之后就看你自己了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:36.36,0:21:38.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在知道小栞小姐的真心之后
Dialogue: 0,0:21:39.29,0:21:41.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你是要继续不正视自己的罪行
Dialogue: 0,0:21:41.77,0:21:46.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,连妹妹也要欺骗的这样活下去呢
Dialogue: 0,0:21:46.59,0:21:47.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还是…
Dialogue: 0,0:21:48.21,0:21:50.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,小栞…
Dialogue: 0,0:21:55.76,0:21:58.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,高畑响子坦白了一切
Dialogue: 0,0:21:58.77,0:22:03.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是在法律上她的罪行 故意的过失
Dialogue: 0,0:22:03.80,0:22:07.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,该怎么惩罚 这还都是未知数
Dialogue: 0,0:22:09.40,0:22:10.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,名侦探柯南 特别礼物
Dialogue: 0,0:22:11.12,0:22:13.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,拨打屏幕上的电话
Dialogue: 0,0:22:13.68,0:22:14.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,收听电话讯息
Dialogue: 0,0:22:14.91,0:22:16.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就有可能抽中精美礼品哦
Dialogue: 0,0:22:17.11,0:22:18.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,快快来电吧
Dialogue: 0,0:23:39.74,0:23:42.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我说爸爸 你在干什么呀
Dialogue: 0,0:23:42.38,0:23:46.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也认为不该喝很多酒
Dialogue: 0,0:23:46.27,0:23:50.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以开始训练 眼前放很多酒也能忍住不喝
Dialogue: 0,0:23:51.91,0:23:53.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不行了啊
Dialogue: 0,0:23:53.60,0:23:55.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我开 我开…
Dialogue: 0,0:24:02.75,0:24:05.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,忍着不喝才对身体不好呢
Dialogue: 0,0:24:06.21,0:24:08.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,叔叔你也稍微吸取点教训啊
Dialogue: 0,0:24:35.19,0:24:37.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真相永远只有一个
Dialogue: 0,0:24:38.50,0:24:41.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,被恐怖主义者夺走的危险细菌
Dialogue: 0,0:24:41.40,0:24:42.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,难道说我也…
Dialogue: 0,0:24:43.87,0:24:44.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,剧场版名侦探柯南
Dialogue: 0,0:24:45.17,0:24:46.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,天空的遇难船
Dialogue: 0,0:24:46.88,0:24:49.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,4月17日特约预映
Dialogue: 0,0:24:25.69,0:24:27.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下一集柯南提示
Dialogue: 0,0:24:27.94,0:24:29.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,勾玉
Dialogue: 0,0:24:30.04,0:24:31.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好想吃大雁蛋啊
Dialogue: 0,0:24:31.55,0:24:32.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,又在想吃的啊
Dialogue: 0,0:24:32.76,0:24:33.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,或者鳗鱼蛋也行
