Mr. Mori received a
letter from a dead man
and then headed to Tsukikage Island.
The letter's author was Keiji Aso,
a pianist who murdered his family,
lit his house on fire, and died
while playing the Moonlight piano sonata.
The 1st murder happened on the night
of the memorial for Mr. Kameyama,
the previous mayor.
Hideo Kawashima was
found dead in the piano room,
while the first movement
of Moonlight played.
The second murder took place
as the second movement played.
The victim was the current mayor,
Tatsuji Kuroiwa.
The number of suspects was
narrowed down to six people.
The third murder was
that of Ken Nishimoto.
He was killed in a manner
that made it look like suicide.
"To my son, Seiji."
Ah, now I see!
The reason the killer dragged
Kawashima-san into the piano room
after drowning him!
The meaning of the music
played at the murder scenes!
And the mystery behind
the code written in blood!
There's no doubt about it!
That's the one who did it!
What's the big idea, rushing here
to the broadcast room like that?!
Is there something here?!
No, not really.
I've got no choice! I'll have to
use the old man's voice for this!
One shot of this
Anesthetic Watch Gun and...
Hirata-san and Shimizu-san will
have to come to the mainland with us
tomorrow morning.
You can't be serious!
The first incident, in which
Mr. Kawashima was drowned
and dragged into the community center's
piano room last night...
The second incident,
in which Mr. Kuroiwa was murdered
in the broadcast room
this very night...
The third incident, which also
took place this very night,
in which Mr. Nishimoto
was killed in the storeroom
in such a way to make
it look like a suicide...
The only ones without alibis for
these three incidents are you two
and Murasawa-san,
who is resting at the clinic.
I'm sorry to do this, but we'll
have to watch you tonight.
I've figured it out, Inspector!
Almost everything about the murders
on this island, that is.
Dad! You're in the broadcast room?
First, the person who beat Murasawa-san
unconscious in the piano room.
That would be you, Hirata-san!
What?!
Hirata-san suffered
the injury on his left hand
when he broke the window and escaped.
You were also the suspicious
person we saw last night.
But what was he doing?
He was making deals with
Mr. Kawashima in that room.
Drug deals.
Drugs?!
Hirata-san used a
hidden panel in the piano
to trade drugs he bought overseas
for large sums of money.
Aha! So that's why they were at the
community center every single night!
The reason Hirata-san always
claimed the piano was cursed
was to keep people
from getting in the way.
He probably assaulted
Murasawa-san and escaped
because Murasawa-san saw him taking
back the drugs he had left there!
Does that mean you killed Mr. Kawashima
because you were having a dispute
with him about the deals?!
No!
Hirata-san has nothing
to do with the three murders.
If he was the murderer, he wouldn't
have killed anyone in the piano room.
That was the room where
he left the drugs, after all.
Next is Murasawa-san.
He's the killer?!
He's not the killer either.
The reason the killer wrote a
will to make it look a suicide
but didn't place an object
to stand on in the room
was because the murderer bolted
when Ran and the others showed up.
It would have been impossible
to enter the piano room afterward.
You're right!
So far, our image of the
killer has been that of a man,
because all three murders
required someone with strength.
And someone without an alibi.
The only suspect left is Shimizu-san...
Next, we need to look
at the second murder.
We assumed Kuroiwa-san was killed
only minutes before he was found.
But if you'll remember...
...the blood code didn't
come off when Conan fell on it.
At room temperature, it takes 15
to 30 minutes for human blood to dry.
But that blood was dry,
even though he was supposedly
killed only minutes before.
That's right. It was a trick the killer
did to alter the estimated time of death.
What?!
But only the first 5 and a half minutes
of the tape were blank!
Automatic tape reverse.
The killer played the 2nd side
of the tape, which had no music on it
and gained 30 extra minutes
by using tape reverse.
Please have a look at the photographs.
There's a button lit
near Kuroiwa-san's neck.
And the light is off
just after his body is moved.
That's proof that the killer
turned it off when you weren't looking.
But if I remember correctly,
the one who approached the body was--
That's right.
The person who got near the body,
aside from the police...
The person who faked
the estimated time of death...
...was the one who inspected
the body--you, Dr. Narumi!
That's not true, is it, Dr. Narumi?!
You drowned Kawashima-san and
dragged him into the piano room
in order to send the coroners
back to the mainland,
since they wouldn't be able
to examine an unnatural death here.
And the reason you put blank space
at the start of each tape
was so that you could throw us off
by faking the time of the 2nd murder.
Doing this, you altered
Kuroiwa-san's time of death,
thereby creating an alibi for yourself.
But Mori-kun! You just
said the killer was a man!
The motive for the murders
extends 12 years back.
Come again?
Back to the incident in which pianist
Keiji Aso and his family were killed.
Killed?!
Kawashima-san, Nishimoto-san,
Kuroiwa-san,
and the previous mayor, Kameyama-san...
They used Aso-san's
international performances
as opportunities to buy and sell drugs.
But then Aso-san said he
refused to help them any longer.
Afraid their secret would get out,
they shut him and his family inside
his house and set it on fire.
This is all written in the sheet music
that survived that fire...
In the confession letter
that Aso-san wrote for his child...
A son?!
He had a son in a Tokyo hospital.
One named Seiji.
Seiji? It couldn't be...
Dr. Narumi's real name is Seiji.
She was Keiji Aso's son, Seiji Aso!
You can't be serious!
Asai is probably his
foster family's last name.
So it was all to avenge his father...
What?!
Inspector! The killer's gone!
Find him!
I know where he is!
The place where Aso Keiji's donated
piano is kept--the community center!
It's over, Father.
It's not over yet!
Here, look at this!
It's written in this sheet
music your dad left for you!
He says he wants you
to live an honest life!
I wish I had known that sooner.
How did you find out about your father
if you haven't read this?!
I always had my suspicions
about my foster father.
After graduating from medical school,
I came to this island
as a woman doctor.
It doesn't say on my license
how to pronounce my name, after all.
But I was sweating bullets
when they started questioning people.
They would've found out
I was really a man.
I see. So that's why you
stayed with us that night--
so you could have them
question you last.
When I told Kameyama, the previous mayor,
that I was Aso's son,
he suddenly grew fearful
and told me everything.
He finished it all off by falling
lifeless from a heart attack.
It was when I played my father's
favorite piece, Moonlight,
as a farewell song for him that I came up
with the idea for these murders.
Seiji! Let's get out of here!
We can still make it!
It's too late for me.
These hands are as
bloodstained as theirs are.
Conan-kun!
Dammit!
No!
Let go!
What's that sound?
This is the code.
He's playing it. Inside the fire.
Murasawa-san missed Keiji Aso,
the pianist,
so he apparently tuned
his piano on occasion...
On the night he was assaulted, too.
Why did Dr. Narumi warn us
about the murders?
My only guess is that it was actually
a letter of challenge to Dad...
I think she wanted to be
stopped from killing...
Say, what did the code
that Dr. Narumi played say?
Oh, I already forgot.
Your expression says otherwise!
Thank you, Little Detective
Don't tell me the car
Ayumi-chan got in
belonged to those kidnappers
who're killing little girls!
Hold on, Ayumi-chan!
We're coming to save you!
On the next Conan--
Ayumi-chan's Abduction.
Next Conan's Hint:
A School Festival.