Eh?! Kaitou ♪1412 disguised
himself as Daddy to get on the ship?!
I just found his disguise
and props in the bathroom!
The officers are checking it now!
But this is him. I doubt
they'll find any evidence...
Oh? Where's Ran-neechan?
Out looking for you,
since you didn't come back.
She was worried
Kaitou ♪1412 had caught you.
It's not "♪1412."
His name is Kaitou Kid!
Get it right!
Okay...
Who's he?
Inspector Nakamori. He works
full-time pursuing the Kaitou Kid.
Like you, he's a reliable knight
we hired to protect the Black Star.
Still, Madam!
All 500 people here
are wearing black pearls!
And except for the real one,
they're all imitations!
I can't guard it unless
I know which one is real...
They all look alike,
but they're still imitations.
Close scrutiny could
narrow it down a bit;
among them are dull
and dreary ones such as mine
and excessively
shiny rubbish such as yours.
But checking every
person in this crowd would be...
Then I'll give you a special hint.
The Black Star, the black pearl
with a peacock-green luster
that fascinated my
grandfather sixty years ago,
is with someone
especially worthy of it.
Worthy?!
Coincidentally, that someone
is one out of five hundred...
It must be a woman,
if the jewel suits them...
Oh, but it suits you, too, Mori-san!
Oh, so it is you!
Hatamoto Joji (41)
lt's good to see you again!
Thank you for your help a while back!
Hatamoto Joji (41)
Aren't you the Hatamoto Group's--
Yes! Thanks to this fine
woman and the president,
I've opened up more restaurants!
In fact, tonight's meal is my own--
So sorry, Joji-san.
Mifune Takuya (26)
Seems Mr. Suzuki won't be there,
thanks to the Kaitou Kid.
Mifune Takuya (26)
Your flattery food will go to waste!
You're as reprehensible as ever!
Nothing of the sort!
The guy from the
Yotsui girl's birthday party...
Oh? You're not wearing yours?
I hate childish games like this.
But you'll seem suspicious
if you don't wear it.
Fine.
Eh? Ayako-san isn't here?
Tomizawa Yuzo (28)
No, she couldn't make it...
Oh. That's too bad...
Tomizawa Yuzo (28)
This is the Suzuki
Industries party, all right.
It's teeming with rich kids
and company presidents.
Ran's taking a long time...
She's probably lost somewhere!
Ran has no sense of direction!
Who has no sense of direction?!
Oh, Ran! I didn't see you there!
I'm Police Commissioner Chaki!
You may have already heard,
but that pesky villain has
somehow boarded the ship!
As you know,
he's a master of disguise!
He possesses an immeasurable
evil talent that he uses
to learn about his target
and fully imitate them,
even down to their face,
voice, and personality!
He may even be among you already!
Normally, we would carefully
inspect each and every person,
but we'll refrain
from such incivility here.
Passwords!
Pair up with the person next
to you and decide on a password!
I get it! That way he
can't keep disguising himself,
which will allow the
police to single him out!
What should our password be?
OK, when I say "Holmes"...
...I'll say "Lupin"!
What're you doing, Power Room?!
No, this is--
Kaitou Kid!
Your passwords are pointless.
What?!
The Black Star is
already in my hands.
Impossible!
Oh, dear. It's the pesky thief.
I'll just have to punish
this scheming boy.
Mom!
What have you done?!
There's no need to worry,
Inspector. After all...
...he's still alive!
My guards caught him
in the tablecloth
after I pretended to shoot
him with this model gun.
Yes. He's a brilliant magician
I hired as entertainment...
...Sanada Kazumi-kun!
Sanada Kazumi (27) - Magician
Let's give him a round of
applause for acting out
the Kaitou Kid's
pitiable end for us!
I see. Kaitou Kid is an expert magician--
the perfect role for you.
The two of us do happen to
be artists who deceive the eyes...
Artists?!
...but I'm a magician by nature.
A thief is no match for me!
Now, then! Please come to the stage!
I'll show you some of my magic!
A kaitou is a creative artist
who skillfully steals his prey,
but a detective is
nothing more than a critic
who finds fault
in what is left behind!
This sensation!
It's him! He's somewhere in here!
I'll begin with a simple card trick!
Hold on. I've always
been the skeptical type.
May I cut that deck?
Certainly. Would any
others like to as well?
Who is it?! Who's the Kaitou Kid?!
Darn it!
They all seem suspicious!
There's what she said...
The black pearl is with
someone especially worthy of it.
If only I knew what that meant!
I apologize!
That's all right! Spilled cards
won't ruin my luck (tsuki).
Moon (tsuki)?
Say, didn't you have a
list of everyone at this party?
Yeah...
Can I see it?
This? Here.
Here you are!
Thank you, ladies!
Let me give you a card in return!
Are you sure?!
Wait! First, let me use my
X-ray eye to read your minds
and predict your card!
I'm so excited!
Yeah!
Now I see!
That's why he said that in the 2nd letter!
I've figured it out, Kaitou Kid!
The location of your prey, that is!
A pigeon (hato)? Hato? Heart?
The Ace of Hearts, then!
Please pick any card you wish!
Ran! The right! The right one!
"As Caesar was with Cleopatra,
I am already by your side.
- Kaitou Kid"
The Kid!
He's here!
Calm down, everyone!
Confirm your passwords!
Hey! Nakamori-kun! Don't tell
me it's already been stolen!
No, he doesn't have it yet,
nor has he escaped!
He's simply confusing us
to make things work his way!
Don't worry, we can catch him!
He's not a wizard!
He's a human being
who relies on tricks!
Kaitou Kid really left a message?!
Yep! It was on
the card Ran just picked!
But when and how
did he put this in there?!
The Kid is crafty!
Everything about him is a mystery!
All we know is that he's
somewhere in here!
Please calm down, everyone!
Does that mean he knows
where the real pearl is?!
Even if he did,
this is a floating prison.
Could he possibly
make off with the Black Star
with this police presence?
Inspector! We'll arrive in
Tokyo Harbor in thirty minutes!
Alright! Seal all the exits!
Let no one outside!
Time to show yourself,
Kaitou Kid!
This is your only chance to
strike while everyone's restless!
Hey, Ran! Where'd your pearl go?!
Eh?! No way!
Excuse me! Could someone
pick up that pearl?
What the...
What was that sound?!
The pearl! It exploded!
Don't tell me the Kid rigged them!
Forget this!
I'm not wearing this thing!
Calm down, everyone! Calm down!
Mom!
Are you all right?!
Yes. Thank you, Ran-chan!
Open the door this instant!
I can't do that!
Huh?! Your pearl is gone, too!
The Kid! He stole the Black Star!
What?! So you were
wearing the real one?!
Inspector! We can't hold them back!
Inspector! A large
group has gotten out!
The Kid's with them! Capture him!
Yes, sir!
Ran-neechan! Let's go catch him, too!
Wait, Conan-kun!
I know who the Kaitou Kid is!
A letter declaring the upcoming theft
of the Suzuki family's Black Star
arrived at Sonoko's house.
The sender was one Kaitou Kid.
Upon cracking his code, I waited
for him atop the Haido City Hotel.
He landed silently before me
so as not to disturb
the stillness of the night.
I only had one chance
to use my tranquilizer gun!
The instant he turned away to escape!
But instead of running, he imitated
multiple voices without a machine
to lure the police in,
and then vanished like smoke!
All that remained was another letter.
Against Inspector Nakamori's protests,
the Suzuki Industries' 60th anniversary
boat party began as scheduled.
Sonoko's mother,
Suzuki Tomoko, devised a plan
that looked to spell
failure for the Kaitou Kid,
but he blew up the pearls and stole
the Black Star during the confusion!
I've figured out who you are, Kaitou Kid!
What?! You didn't find the Kid?!
No. We checked all the passengers
who left the room earlier, but...
He has to be on board still!
Check every last person on the ship!
Yes, sir!
But how did he know she was
wearing the real Black Star?!
This is the engine room,
Conan-kun!
Is the Kaitou Kid really in here?
Say, Ran-neechan. Do you
know about the language of jewels?
The language of jewels?
A pearl means "moon" or "woman."
Of the passengers on board,
the only woman with moons in her name
is Suzuki Tomoko-san.
In other words, she had the real one!
But how does that
tell you who the Kid is?
The cards!
You know how the card
you chose had his message?
Yeah...
It's a basic trick in which the magician
used the pigeon in his right hand
to distract the audience while
he switched decks in his left hand.
So the chosen card would be
fixed regardless of who cut the deck.
So if the message
was on that card...
...does that mean
Kaitou Kid was that magician?!
No! I watched the whole time,
but he never got near the lady!
Then who is it?!
There's one other person
who could've switched cards!
Yes! That person made them fall,
pretended to pick them up,
then removed a card
and added the message!
They hid it in their palm and
pretended to pull it from the deck!
Right, Ran-neechan?
Or should I say, Kaitou Kid-san!
This is Chopper ♪1!
He hasn't fled outside!
This is Chopper ♪2!
No suspicious people on deck!
This is Surveillance!
Sonar and radar show nothing!
Alright! Keep your eyes peeled!
All onboard officers are
to split up onto each floor
and capture the Kid on sight!
Don't let a familiar face fool you!
He's a master of disguise!
Yes. You switched places with
Ran when she left to find me.
Impressive. I hadn't noticed at all.
After becoming Ran, you agitated
everyone with your message
and scattered the exploding
pearls to cause mass panic.
You then stole the real Black
Star during the confusion
by pretending to prop her up.
Huh?! Your pearl is gone, too!
The Kid! He stole the Black Star!
The fact that you prepared
those fireworks means you knew
she had a large number
of replicas made.
Quit joking around, Conan-kun!
I didn't know which one was
real, and I didn't have any hints!
You didn't need hints to
know which one was real!
Once she took her pearl
out with a glove, that is.
Pearls are made of calcium carbonate
and are highly reactive to acid.
Oil in the fingers would oxidize
the surface and make it lose its luster.
Some people realized, though...
...Realized that she'd never give
such a delicate jewel to anyone else!
But that's not enough to--
Indeed, that wouldn't be enough.
But add her dull pearl to the equation
and speculation becomes certainty!
Yes. Just as old pearls in famous
museums fade in color over time,
a pearl's luster lasts
a few decades at most.
The Black Star was
purchased sixty years ago;
it can't possibly look flawless now.
So it would have been obvious
once you saw her carefully
handle her faded pearl with gloves!
Talk about pathetic!
I was so concerned with
you that I completely forgot!
But wasn't the Black Star
in the museum all shiny?
That's why you didn't take it.
You knew it was a fake.
Then you challenged
her in your second letter
and told her to bring the real one.
You even made
sure to write "the real one."
Here! If you suspect me that much,
I'll call a policeman to--
I won't let you disappear
like you did on that roof!
You didn't call for the
police that time to spite me!
You acted like you were
about to hang-glide out,
but you quickly dressed up
as an officer during the flash,
and hid yourself among them!
Besides, it's senseless
to ask for help here...
...I set up this 1-on-1
match out of respect
for the criminal artist who snuck
on board amidst all the security.
Yes. Most great artists
become famous after they die.
I'll make you a great
master, Kaitou Kid.
Once I place you in
the cemetery known as jail.
I surrender.
I'll give up on this pearl.
Tell the lady I'm
sorry for ruining the party!
Now you're sorry...
Oh, yeah! The girl I knocked
out to get these clothes...
She'll catch cold if we don't hurry!
I'm a perfectionist, you see!
Another flash grenade!
Oh no!
Damn! I won't let you escape!
Bastard!
I'll get you for this!
Hey! There's a girl asleep in this boat!
What?!
What's she doing in here?
Anyway, let's get her out...
Stop!
No! Don't take her out! Stop!
Huh? Wha...
"This crimson dress you gave me
the other day suits you wonderfully.
- The Occasional Dry Cleaner, Kaitou Kid"
Bastard...
They later found the hang glider
Kaitou Kid planned to escape with,
but he, himself, had completely
vanished from the ship.
There you are! "Grade-schooler
Protects Black Star!"
You're a big hero, Conan-kun!
Come on, it was just luck!
But you guys actually
met the Kid! You're so lucky!
Not.
Say, what did he look like?!
Ran?
What?
The Kid's face!
Sorry! He knocked me out too fast...
I saw his face, though.
What kind of older man was he?!
He was surprisingly young.
In his twenties, or maybe...
Don't give me your cold!
Falling into the ocean while touring
the Selizabeth! Talk about stupid!
You're so annoying.
It's that brat's fault!
Swimming away was my only option!
Hey! That high-schooler...
Doesn't he look like Shinichi-kun?
You think?
Maybe the guy
you saw in Shibuya was...
Whew!
That's good to hear!
Next Conan's Hint:
Rival Detective.