A racing second hand,
a shooting comet!
Conan's logic is the tonic for
hearts tired by modern society!
Today's the Kaitou Kid special!
Detective and thief square off!
He sees the single
truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid but
has the mind of an adult!
His name?
I'm high school student
Kudo Shinichi.
I went with Mori Ran,
childhood friend and classmate,
to an amusement park,
where I witnessed a suspicious
deal involving a man in black.
I was so engrossed with watching
that I didn't see his partner hiding!
I was knocked down
and given a poison.
When I woke up,
my body had shrunk!
If they learned
Kudo Shinichi was alive,
people around me would be in danger!
After following Prof. Agasa's
advice to conceal my identity,
Ran asked me my
name and I quickly said...
... "Edogawa Conan!"
Then, to uncover
information about them,
I moved in with Ran
and her detective father.
Conan vs. Kaitou Kid
Conan vs. Kaitou Kid.
Kaitou ♪1412?
Yeah! He's an older thief that
all the young girls are crazy about!
"Older"?
Your dad's a detective
and you never heard of him?!
That doesn't mean
I love following crimes.
But hear me out!
So you want my
dad to catch this thief?
That's right!
You know Beika Museum's
exhibit of world-famous jewels?!
Daddy submitted our family gem,
the lucky Black Star pearl,
and wants it protected
Black Star
from Kaitou ♪1412's evil grasp!
But why ask my
dad and not the police?
We can't do that! The police would
haul him off if they caught him!
But if your dad catches him,
he might let us see his face!
His face?
Yeah! Don't you
wonder what he looks like?!
♪ 1412 has the entire
world going crazy!
I bet he's a fabulous guy!
Like Harrison Ford or John Lennon...
You live so happily...
The light's green, Sonoko.
Coming!
It'd be nice if he
was like Brad Pitt!
Shinichi!
Hey, now! The light's red!
But, that was Shinichi!
It was Shinichi...
You sure it wasn't just a look-alike?
You passed by
Shinichi-niichan in Shibuya?!
Yeah, right!
It's true!
But he wouldn't respond!
Isn't that horrible?!
Hey, now! I wasn't in Shibuya!
And besides, I haven't
even changed bodies!
Yeah, he's probably sick of you.
Just forget about that mystery dweeb.
Yeah... He was walking with a girl, too...
It was someone else!
Don't worry about it!
What?
Anyway, do they really want me to
catch this Kaitou something-or-other?
Kaitou ♪1412!
What's with the 1412?
No one's really
sure where it comes from.
According to Sonoko, he steals art
and jewels from all over the world,
and his top secret FBI or CIA
or Interpol number was 1412.
"International Criminal Number"
The leading theory is that people
learned the number and it just stuck!
Sounds fake to me.
Apparently he has a different
name in Japan, though.
It's probably just word play.
Like "The Crazy Thief" or something.
I don't think it was
anything that old man-like.
How dumb. Who cares about some thief?
I'm going to bed.
Oh, yeah. I have a
copy of a weird warning letter
that Kaitou ♪1412
sent to Sonoko's house.
A weird warning letter?
It doesn't make any sense!
It's like a code!
"April Fools.
When the moon splits the two,
I shall enter upon waves
in the name of the black star.
Kaitou..."
It's torn here...
Yeah, Sonoko's father tore
it up in anger when it arrived
then taped it back together.
Still, this makes no sense at all.
All I do get is that "April Fools"
means he'll show up on April 1st...
Hey! I thought you went to bed!
Lemme see...
Conan-kun?
Beika Museum, 1:42 PM, March 31st
Wow...
It's like all the police in
Tokyo have been mobilized...
I guess he really is
a big international thief!
All that work and
I still didn't break the code...
Detective Mori!
Thank you for coming!
I truly appreciate your
listening to my daughter!
Suzuki Shiro (51)
We're 100-men strong with
a detective like you here!
Suzuki Shiro (51)
We're counting on you,
Detective Mori!
Suzuki Shiro (51)
It's just one measly thief.
I'll capture him with no trouble at all!
Sure you will! You haven't
even cracked the code yet!
So this is the largest black
pearl in the world, the Black Star?
Yes. The Suzuki family has
been blessed with prosperity
ever since my
grandfather first purchased it.
It's the family's guardian angel.
Security sure is tight
for the day before the theft.
Yes. All we got from
the letter was the date.
I'm told that security will be
on full detail starting tonight--
there's no telling from when
or where Kaitou ♪1412 will strike.
What?!
I already told you! The river!
Deploy men along the river bank!
Kaitou ♪1412 plans to sneak inside
Chaki Shintaro (49)
from the nearby Teimuzu River!
You cracked the code?
Sure did!
The "enter upon waves"
bit refers to the Teimuzu River!
The Teimuzu River is the only
place in the vicinity with waves!
Weren't you Mori from Section 1?
You're sloppy, Commissioner!
What?!
Don't you get it? "Waves" means the ocean,
which means "oki" (coast).
And "star" means a pop star!
In other words, the idol star
who performs live tomorrow
at the nearby Beika Town Hall,
Okino Yoko-chan!
What's more, her last
song will be "Moon Lady"!
"When the moon splits
the two" means that...
...Kaitou ♪1412 will come from
the vicinity of Beika Town Hall
when the show ends at 9:00 pm!
Whatever you say...
Yes, that does make sense.
Well done, Detective Mori!
Hey, now...
Alright! Have Teams C through E
assemble near Beika Town Hall!
Yes, sir!
Hey!
Still, I haven't broken
the code either...
Say, where's the fellow who
was transferred to us last month?
The inspector? He took some
officers somewhere this morning...
What's he thinking?!
Anyway, it's 2:00!
Why don't we have lunch nearby?
Are you guys gonna have lunch?
We ate on the way here...
Eat?
Wait a minute! Could it be?!
Conan-kun! Where are you going?
What are you doing, Conan-kun?
Checking the direction
with my watch.
The direction?
Yeah. First, you point the
hour hand toward the sun.
Japan's in the northern hemisphere,
so halfway between it and 12
is where south is!
I was just testing something
Shinichi-niichan told me, of course!
Which means south is at
1 o'clock, and southeast at 2:30!
Aha! I've figured you out,
Kaitou ♪1412!
11:04 PM, March 31st
Fast asleep!
Agasa here.
Oh, Shinichi! Eh? What?
You want me to find
out about Kaitou ♪1412?
Please, Professor.
He should be in my dad's crime files.
But what do you need it for?
I want to know about
him before I meet him!
Meet him?! You know where he is?!
Yup! I've figured out his route inside!
Then why didn't you tell the police?!
I suddenly wanna see it, too...
...the face of a retro thief who sends
warning notices in this day and age!
The "two" in "when
the moon splits the two"
refers to a satellite and the sun!
And if the splitting refers to the moon
creating an eclipse between them...
...then he'll show up between
12:30 and 4:00 am when BS TV is off!
Yes! The Black Star's initials
are BS (Broadcast Satellite)!
If the "waves" refer to
a satellite signal...
...then he'll be coming from
the direction of the BS signal!
The BS signal is sent from
south to west at a 45 degree angle
and from 42.3 degrees above the horizon.
The only place that fits the bill
is the roof of the Haido City Hotel!
Inspector! A strange kid ran
into the hotel! What do we do?!
Nothing. There's only
one person I'm after.
And not even he
could dress up as a child.
Employees Only
Beika Museum is...
right around there.
12:28.
Now I just wait for him to show up...
Hello? Professor?
Hi, Shinichi.
I checked your dad's files
with recent newspaper articles.
Kaitou ♪1412 is enveloped
in quite a bit of mystery.
His first appearance
was in Paris eighteen years ago.
He suddenly disappeared ten
years later and was presumed dead,
but he's back after eight years
and is primarily active in Japan.
Eighteen years ago?
He must be pretty old then...
He has all kinds of names...
"The Modern Lupin,"
"The Moonlight Magician"...
But there's one alias
that people like the most...
Alias?
A young novelist interested
in the crafty Kaitou ♪1412
once jokingly read
the number like so...
"K I D."
"K I D"?
That's right.
Kaitou ♪1412 is known as...
...the Kaitou Kid!
He landed silently before me,
so as not to disturb
the stillness of the night.
Together with a fearless smile,
as if he saw through everything.
What's going on, Shinichi? Shin--
A cape and a silk hat...
An impenetrable stance...
I can't make out his face,
but he's surprisingly young.
His thirties. Twenties?
No, even younger!
Hey, little boy.
What are you doing up here?
Fireworks!
What?!
A strange flash and sound?!
Yes. Above the Haido City Hotel,
southwest of the museum.
Shall I check it out,
Commissioner?
Of course you shall!
Look! A helicopter!
I think it noticed!
Seems you're no ordinary kid.
I'm Edogawa Conan. A detective.
Shouldn't you be escaping,
Kaitou Kid-san?
The helicopter will
be here any minute.
I only have one chance to
get him with my tranquilizer gun!
The instant he
turns away to escape!
A radio?!
Chaki here! Kaitou Kid sighted
on top of the Haido City Hotel!
Attention all patrol
cars in Beika and Haido
and all helicopters
in the air above Beika!
Proceed to the scene at once
and capture the Kaitou Kid!
He's using my voice!
Wait! That's not me!
It's his trap!
All units, return at once!
This is Helicopter ♪1!
I'm above the hotel!
Sighting confirmed!
What?!
I think he sent the orders!
This is Nakamori!
Attention all officers
inside the Haido City Hotel!
The Kid's on the roof! Rush
to the scene at once! Seize him!
This guy's incredible...
He can imitate any
voice without a machine!
Damn it!
Your voice is on the radio!
lt's the Kid! He's using my
Nakamori Ginzo (41)
voice to bring us to him!
That's insane!
Why on earth would he do that?!
What's he doing?!
Satisfied, Detective?
Freeze, Kid!
Oh, my. Inspector Nakamori.
You certainly arrived quickly.
Ha! You knew I cracked your
code and had the place staked out!
I figured you might hang-glide in,
so I checked everyone in the hotel
and fortified the main entrance,
but I never expected you to go
around Toto Tower and then land here.
Forget about the pearl!
You have nowhere to run!
I'm only here to observe you tonight.
I don't plan to steal anything.
What?!
Oh? I clearly wrote
so at the start of the letter!
"April Fools." It was a lie!
Don't let him escape! Get him!
A flash grenade!
Are you aware, little boy?
A kaitou is a creative artist
who skillfully steals his prey,
but a detective is
nothing more than a critic
who finds fault in
what is left behind!
What?!
He disappeared!
He vanished!
Helicopters! Track him using radar!
It only shows our
three helicopters in the area!
Has he gotten away again?!
This is insane! No one
can just disappear like that!
What's this?!
"On March 19th, I will appear
on the Queen Selizabeth
leaving from Yokohama Port
to steal the real Black Star.
--Kaitou Kid"
March 19th
--Queen Selizabeth, Yokohama Port
Please cancel it,
Commissioner Chaki!
March 19th
--Queen Selizabeth, Yokohama Port
We're dealing with the Kaitou Kid!
We can't let him get near the jewel
with such lousy security as that!
Don't be like that,
Nakamori-kun!
Tonight's party is
full of important people!
We can't do anything rough!
Besides, we'll lose face if we
cancel the party out of fear of him!
Don't worry. It'll take three hours
for the ship to get to Tokyo.
It's a floating prison! Even if he
does get on, he's like a rat in a trap!
This year marks Suzuki
Industries' 60th anniversary.
This is entirely because
of the support from you all.
Please forget about
sneak thieves for tonight
and enjoy this elegant and grand
party to which 500 have been invited!
But, first!
I have devised a
Suzuki Tomoko (43)
special plan for tonight.
Please open the small boxes
given to you before you boarded.
Suzuki Tomoko (43)
Please open the small boxes
given to you before you boarded.
They are my letter of challenge
to any foolish thieves.
This is--
Yes! These are our family's symbol,
as well as the Kaitou Kid's
prey tonight! The Black Star!
Only one is real, of course.
And only I know to whom it was given.
The rest are imitation pearls!
Now, then.
Please put them on your chests
and tell the Kid, "Go ahead
and take it, if you dare"!
Of course, that's assuming he
manages to determine which one is real
during the three hours we're at sea!
Your mom's pretty smart!
What's wrong, Sonoko?
I can't find my sister...
Don't tell me she's still at home!
Yeah, right!
Eh?! The ship already left?!
Suzuki Residence
How come?!
That's my line!
Do you know what time it is?!
But the commissioner called to
say he was delaying it two hours...
Right, Dad?
Daddy's there?!
Bastard!
Where did the company president go?!
He went to the restroom...
Now I see! He got on
board disguised as the president!
I thank you, Kaitou Kid!
You've given me a chance to
tear off that bold mask of yours!