A racing second hand,
a shining comet!
Conan's logic is good medicine
for hearts tired by modern society!
Today is the first two-hour special!
Try your hand at the two cases!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name?
"The Great Detective is Cornered!
Two Big Murder Cases in a Row"
Agasa Residence
C'mon! Hear me out, Shin-chan!
Yeah, yeah. I'm listening, Mom.
Yusaku left early this morning
Kudo Yukiko, Shinichi's mother and actress
and came home totally drunk again!
Oh, he makes me so mad!
Kudo Yukiko, Shinichi's mother and actress
He can't help it.
Dad's a popular novelist.
He has to socialize
with all kinds of people.
Whose lipstick is on his shirt, then?!
Oh, I'm so mad! I'm gonna cheat on him, too!
Kudo Yusaku, World-renowned mystery writer
Whoa, calm down!
Oh, I'm busy right now.
Wait! Shinichi!
What's wrong? I assume
that was Yukiko-san?
She was complaining
about her marital strife.
Dad coming home drunk,
dad cheating on her...
C-Cheating?!
It's just a misunderstanding.
All he thinks about is mysteries.
He'd never be that good-for-nothing.
Besides, their fights are almost
annual events. No point in worrying.
Yes. They're so close they argue a lot.
Incidentally, how are things with you?
With me?
You know, with Ran-kun.
Are you getting along well?
She gets mad every time I call her.
"When will you finally be back?!"
Even though we almost see too
much of each other every single day.
Now, don't be like that.
Why not take a break from your
cases and go somewhere with her?
Autumn is the season for love!
The season for love indeed...
Mori Detective Agency
I'm back!
You idiot!
Mind your own business!
What's with that tone?
Kisaki Eri, Ran's mother and attorney
Here I am, trying to give you another client.
As if I need your help!
Then do whatever you want.
But don't blame me when business
isn't going well, Great Detective.
Yes, thank you for worrying
about me, Great Attorney!
These two are having
their own marital spat.
Autumn's the season of love? Yeah, right.
Autumn's the season of hunger.
Hurry home, Ran. I'm starving...
I'm home!
Yeah.
Huh?
Looking for Conan?
He's asleep on the sofa.
Oh.
Sheesh! Dozing off in a place like this!
Hungry...
Yes, yes! I'll make something right now!
Sheesh! At least take
your glasses off when you sleep!
This face... I've seen
it somewhere, long ago...
Welcome back, Ran-neechan.
Huh? G-Give back my glasses!
Come to think of it, you're
always wearing glasses, Conan-kun.
Even when sleeping
or taking a bath. Why?
I-Isn't that obvious?
I have bad eyesight.
A-And I can't relax
without them always on!
Pardon me...
Might this be the
Mori Detective Agency?
Y-Yes!
I see. So you're the one
she shamelessly sent to me.
Huh?
Who's "she"?
Your mom, Kisaki Eri-san!
Right, mister?
Eh? No way!
Mom asked for your help?!
Oh! You're both getting along!
This means you're pretty
much back together, then!
You set this up, Ran.
I thought it seemed
strange that she'd call me.
Kids shouldn't be
meddling with adults' affairs!
What's so wrong with doing this?!
I want Mom to come back soon!
You've made things even worse.
So, what brings you here?
Yes.
Tsukumo Nanae (42)
It's actually about my husband,
who died one week ago...
Tsukumo Nanae (42)
Died? You don't think
he was killed, do you?!
No. I think it was suicide...
You think?
Yes.
On that day, one week ago,
I left him alone at home.
I couldn't find him when I returned,
so I worriedly checked his
special room in the basement...
...where I found his cold
body lying on the ground!
He had swallowed poison...
What sort of poison?
A policeman called it
"aconitine," or something.
Aconitine?
As I recall, it's...
A type of poison that causes denervation.
It's found in the leaves
and roots of wolfsbane.
Just two milligrams is lethal.
It's a powerful toxin that causes
death minutes after ingestion.
B-But where would
you come across that?
Mountains are full of them!
Wolfsbane is used in Chinese medicines,
minus the poison, of course!
No! I mean you, Conan-kun!
Eh?
How do you know all that?
T-Television! A monster in Masked
Yaiba mentioned it the other day!
He said, "I'll kill you with this aconitine,
extracted from wolfsbane!"
He must've been a thoughtful
monster to explain the poison like that...
There's no such monster.
So, were you the only
one who found the body?
No. I was with my
husband's three pupils.
Pupils?
Umm, my husband
and I are both magicians.
My husband, Tsukumo Motoyasu,
was maybe even world-renowned.
Tsukumo Motoyasu?
I know him! He was on the news!
They said a great magician had died.
All you ever watch
is horseracing, mister.
Remember? We all went to
his magic show a long time ago!
Speaking of which, I think there's
a photo of us with Tsukumo-san!
It was at that show that I
met your wife, Kisaki-san.
Oh. So that's why you're here today?
Yes. Kisaki-san has been
our attorney ever since then...
Here we are! This is it!
Wait, could this be...
Did you find the photo?
No! I guess I was mistaken!
Say! You should ask
about those three pupils!
Would that be all right?
Yes.
First, is Sanada Kazumi-kun,
our magic troupe's ace.
They say he's to take over for my husband.
Next, is Miyoshi Mako-san.
She's strong-minded, but greatly skilled.
There is no better female
magician in Japan than her.
Lastly, is Momochi Yuji-kun.
He hasn't been a pupil for very
long and isn't as skilled as the others,
but he shows great promise.
They're all wonderful youngsters,
and all three live with us
and practice magic every day.
So, where were they that day?
They were with me at
a Beika Hotel dinner show,
doing magic for the audience.
My husband was
supposed to come too,
but he said he
didn't do cheap work...
But, those three were at home
before leaving for the show, right?
Wouldn't they have had
the chance to poison him?
H-Hey, now.
My husband died while the
show was happening, little boy.
But, couldn't they have secretly
given him the poison in a capsule?
If so, my husband would've called
for help after noticing the poison.
There was a phone in the basement,
and the door unlocks
easily from the inside...
What about sleeping pills?
Nothing like that was
found in his autopsy, of course.
There were no strangle marks,
everything in the house was locked,
and there were absolutely
no signs of entry or exit.
Then that means it
could only be a suicide.
Yes, that's true.
But I just can't imagine my
husband committing suicide!
By which you mean?
Tomorrow is our daughter,
Ayano's, birthday.
He even got her present a month ago.
He couldn't wait to give it to her.
Does that sound suicidal to you?
That's not the only unusual thing.
We found this on
his desk in the basement.
Oh? Cards?
The Ace of Spades
and a Jack are stuck together.
The police pulled them apart,
but there was nothing written inside.
I put them back
together to show to you.
Are you sure it
isn't just a magic prop?
But my husband never
really did card tricks,
and I've never seen
a prop like this before!
Hey! Let's just go to her house for now!
You're always saying, "Let's go!"
I'm the only one going.
You butt out, kid!
Oh, come on! Take Conan-kun!
He might be helpful!
He knows all sorts of unusual things!
Yeah, but...
Okay, Conan-kun?
Y-Yeah.
Fine! But you better behave yourselves!
We will!
With Shinichi at a magic show...
Wow!
What an impressive mansion!
Of course! The late Motoyasu-san
was a world-renowned magician!
Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
Now, where is the basement
room where your husband died?
Yes.
Hold it!
Momochi-kun.
Pardon me, miss.
M-Me?
You appear to be greatly troubled.
Momochi Yuji (25) Magician
Eh?!
There's no use hiding it. I can tell.
After all, you have
a pigeon in your hair!
Wow! That's amazing!
Now, it's your turn!
Are you a new student?
Huh? Me?
No, this is Mori
Kogoro-san, a detective.
Eh?! The famous detective?!
But what is he doing here?
Oh? You can't tell?
He's obviously here to investigate
Miyoshi Mako (20) Magician
Motoyasu-sensei's death.
Isn't that right, Mr. Detective?
Y-Yes.
Little boy...
...and buxom girl.
B-Buxom?
White...
Did you see?
See what?
You should at least
use that many pigeons!
Right.
But, what is a detective doing here?
Wasn't his death a suicide?
Probably because he
wasn't the type to commit suicide.
Then, there are those
strange cards. Or so I'd surmise.
Cards?
Yes, these.
These strange cards were on the
desk in the basement where he died.
Oh, the Ace of Spades and
the Jack that were stuck together.
But, isn't this just a prop?
Plus, the police said it was a suicide.
Yes, yes. There's nothing to find now,
even if you scoured the house.
Wait! What are you doing?!
All that's left...
...is the fact there is now
Sanada Kazumi (27) Magician
only one genius here instead of two.
Why, you! You ripped up
important evidence!
It's all right. The real one
is in your jacket pocket.
Wait a minute. Aren't you...
It's him! The genius magician
who dressed up as the Kaito Kid
on that ship during the 60th
anniversary party of the Suzuki zaibatsu!
Oh, him!
Sanada Kazumi, at your service.
It'd be wise to leave soon,
unless you want to tarnish your reputation.
Seems pretty indifferent to
the fact his magic instructor just died...
I wouldn't be so sure.
See? He used cards
with different patterns just now.
He'd never normally
do this. He's a perfectionist...
I guess Sanada-san's
taken this pretty hard...
Yes. He looked up to my
husband almost as a father.
These are the three pupils, huh...
Huh? Conan-kun?
Tsukumo Motoyasu's daughter
Aren't you in Class A?
What are you doing here? Are you here to visit?
Tsukumo Motoyasu's daughter
No, we have some business here.
What kind of business?
Oh. So this is her house.
I'm the one who has business
here. He just came along, miss.
Oh, in that case, want
to go shopping with me?
Eh?
Mommy and I are just
about to go buy an outfit
for my birthday party tomorrow!
You got my invitation too, right?
Yeah, so I did...
Come on! Let's go, Conan-kun!
W-Wait!
No!
Sorry! Conan-kun's busy right now!
Maybe some other time?
Come on.
Kids should play with kids.
Ayano. I'm sorry, but I can't
go shopping today, either.
But you promised,
Mommy! You're a liar!
Daddy is, too! My birthday
is tomorrow, but he's still overseas!
You're all a bunch of liars! I hate you!
Then, will you go with me?
I'll coordinate your outfit for you!
Okay!
I'm sorry to bother you, Mako-san.
Okay, everyone! Back to your cage!
Let's go!
You still haven't told her
her father is dead?
No. I told her he's
doing a show overseas...
Huh? This isn't my pigeon.
It's Mako-san's.
That's strange for her
to mistake her pigeons...
Her teacher's death
must be hard on her, too...
Sheesh!
And magicians are supposed to
be good at concealing themselves!
You're the only one who
doesn't seem any different!
I just recently became a pupil, so...
Well, I'm going to
get dinner ready now.
Oh, thank you.
Does he always make the meals?
Our custom is that the newest
pupil always makes the meals.
I see.
Now then, let us see the basement
room where your husband died.
So, what exactly is
this basement room?
It was my husband's special room.
He would always hole up in
here and research new magic tricks.
His pupils seemed
to use it lately, too.
What are those photographs?
My husband's students.
Everyone, even those who set
out on their own or gave up...
Say, miss. Who's that guy
with the black hat?
Oh, that's Kinoshita-kun.
He was a genius among geniuses.
Unfortunately, he died in
his youth fourteen years ago,
in a training accident...
But why do you ask?
Well, it's the only
photo without dust on it.
I wondered if someone
had been taking care of it.
Oh, you're right. Was it my husband?
He was especially fond of him.
Oh, so this is where he
swallowed the poison and collapsed?
Yes. The room is still exactly as it was.
Those cards were in the pile of
cards on this desk. As was the glue.
This is an unusually thick wall.
Yes. He enjoyed classical music,
and always listened to it in here.
He had the room soundproofed
so he could play the music loud.
In short, nobody would be able to
hear shouts coming from this room?
Yes.
But the door can be easily
unlocked from the inside
even when locked from the outside.
He would've gone outside to get
help if he realized he was poisoned.
But, the fact that he stayed in the room...
Madam. Suicide is the
only possibility I can think of.
Oh...
I dunno...
See, look at the body mark.
His hands are by his side,
in a well-mannered way.
In tv and stuff, when
someone is poisoned,
don't they put their hands to
their throat or chest like this?
Come to think of it,
a policeman did say
the body seemed a bit odd
for someone who was poisoned.
When you found his body,
you're sure he hadn't been strangled?
Yes.
When all four of us found him,
we panicked and
hurried to call an ambulance,
but they said no one
had used rope on him at all.
Say, couldn't he have
been strangled with a thin thread?
You know, like what
they use in magic tricks.
Nonsense. Even if you couldn't
see it itself, it'd still leave a mark.
If there was such a mark,
the cops would've found it long ago!
Rings?
Say. When he died,
was he wearing these rings?
Yes. His best trick involved
using invisible strings on his rings
to make things seem alive.
He had probably been
practicing it that day.
But, he only had the rings on.
There weren't any strings.
Oh, then that's a relief.
Relief?
After all, if the strings
got tangled up behind him,
he wouldn't be able to move.
See? It's hard to get up if
you can't use your hands.
And using the
doorknob would be hard, too.
T-That's it!
Your husband had rings on both
hands tied with string or something!
His thumbs, most likely!
Evidence of this would
remain on the body, though!
But, by cutting that string
before the police arrived,
it would look like he had
ordinary ring marks on his fingers!
Your husband was poisoned
before you and the pupils left!
The string was cut by
someone when the body was found,
probably during all the commotion!
Then, you're saying my husband was--
That's right!
Your husband was murdered!
By one of the three
who found his body with you!
That can't be...
Then what do those cards mean?
You know, the Ace and Jack
that were lying over there.
Quiet! I'm trying to figure that out!
Plus, there was a phone in this room.
Even without thumbs, it shouldn't
be too hard to press the buttons.
Yeah, that's true...
Umm, speaking of the phone...
...when we found the body,
I rushed upstairs to call an ambulance
so I didn't notice it right away,
but this phone was buried in cards.
Buried?!
I get it! The killer hid the phone!
To keep the victim from using it!
But, wouldn't it still be easy
to find if you tried hard enough?
That's true.
This is the phone in question.
Hey, mister.
Let me see those cards.
See this symbol here?
It's the same shape as the cards!
The redial button...
That's it! These cards are a dying
message from your husband,
telling us to press the redial button!
If my guess is right, it should connect
to someone your husband
left a message with.
This number is not in use.
Huh?
The police found that number too,
but it was nonsense,
so we assumed it was
my daughter playing around.
What the...
What are these numbers?!
Hey, kid. What are you writing?
What's this? A code?
"One two six eight seven
one three two four eight nine..."
Don't get in the way!
Whose way?
Wait a minute!
Could these numbers mean...