Now I get it!
That's how this code works!
In which case, this code means...
Oh no! It's out of lead!
Say, do you have a pen or anything?
There's a fountain pen
in the desk, if that's all right.
Oh, that's strange.
My husband always had it in here.
Even his trick color pens are gone...
How long're you
gonna look at those numbers?
The police are right.
It was the daughter playing around.
I took our daughter
to the show that day,
so they assumed she entered
those numbers before then.
Meaning your husband didn't use
the phone that day for some reason.
Yes...
Say, the killer poisoned the
victim before everyone left, right?
Yeah. Probably using a capsule
that dissolved during the show.
Then, the victim was stuck
in here the entire time, right?
If it were me, I think I'd try to
leave a clue about who did it...
Oh, but I guess he couldn't!
There were no pens in the room.
All there was was this phone...
How dumb. If the victim used the
phone, he would've called for help.
Yeah, huh? I doubt the
phone was unplugged or anything.
U-Unplugged?
That's it!
The killer locked your husband
in here after unplugging the phone!
Then, it was plugged back in
during all the commotion later on!
But that's...
All three suspects are magicians.
They could all pull
off such a stealthy trick.
The killer also hid
the phone with the cards.
When the body was found,
it would be clear the phone was
unplugged if someone tried to use it.
And your husband,
poisoned and locked inside,
wanted to leave a clue
about the person responsible.
But the pens were gone,
and the phone unplugged.
The only option left was to use
the redial button to leave a message.
Even when unplugged, as long
as there's power, numbers are saved.
Then, as a hint pointing to this,
he left the two cards on the desk.
Then my husband really
did enter those numbers?
Yes. He re-hid the phone under the cards
because if someone used the phone
later, his number would be erased.
Plus, if the phone stood out too much,
the killer might get rid of it.
All that's left is to decipher
this strange number message, but...
Oh, that's why I--
Here you go!
It's my pen! You wanted
something to write with, right?
Y-Yeah.
Oh! You realized
something interesting again!
Think you could tell us about it?
I-It's nothing much, but look
at this first group of numbers.
1-2-6-8-7-1.
On its own, it doesn't make much sense,
but if you connect 1, 2, 6,
8, 7, and 1 on the phone pad,
you get a real strange shape!
D!
It's the letter D!
Oh! So that's called a "D"?
Wait a minute! Then the
next one, 3-2-4-8-9 is C!
That's it! These number
sequences write out four characters!
Adding in the 1-3-5-4-8
and 1-3-9-7 should leave us
with the message your
husband left before he died!
DCMAKO?
MAKO? Could that mean Mako-san?
Yes, most likely.
Then she killed my husband?!
No. This isn't enough to say.
It could be a message
he left for Mako-san,
and we don't know what the
"DC" before "MAKO" means...
You're really amazing to figure
that out from some weird numbers!
You're really something!
Yes. You're really something.
You're really something, Dad!
You're so smart!
Nah, this was a cinch for me!
Ran...
But what is this "DC"?
The only DCs I know are
DC Brand and Washington DC...
Direct current...
Da capo!
You know, the D.C.
that's often in sheet music!
It's read "da capo"!
Come to think of it,
he did play the piano on occasion,
so I think he often read sheet music.
Say, what does "da capo" mean?
It means to go back
to the start and repeat.
R-Repeat?!
Didn't Mako-san leave
with your daughter?!
Yes, to buy clothes!
Can you contact her right away?!
Yes, I can. She has a pager.
Oh, it's from your mom.
She must want us to hurry home.
Eh? But I still want to stay with you!
After all, we're going
somewhere really fun next, right?
Yes, I'll take you there.
To an even more wonderful place.
Eh?! Mako-san plans to--
Yes. She probably plans
to kill your daughter.
The "DC Mako" your husband left behind
likely means that Mako-san
intends to repeat her murder!
You can't be serious!
Just call the other two pupils for now!
We'll all split up and search for them!
Ayano! Mako-san!
Where are you? Ayano!
Ayano-chan!
Ayano!
No use...
Dammit! Can't find her!
Any luck?!
No! Can't find them anywhere!
Guess we should ask
the police to search now...
But, why would Mako-san
kill my husband?!
She must have some
connection with that man.
You know, the man with the
black hat in that one photograph.
It was Kinoshita Yoshiro after all...
K-Kinoshita? The genius magician
who died fourteen years ago?
What do you mean by
"after all," Sanada-kun?!
I saw her when I went to
the basement room one night.
Mako was embracing a picture with care.
I thought something was up,
but I never imagined she'd kill.
Still, I'm pathetic.
Even though I was flustered
when we found the body,
I never saw Mako cut the string
on his rings or plug the phone back in.
Oh.
I've been found out?
M-Mako-san!
Ayano!
Don't worry. She's just asleep.
I was actually going to put her
to sleep for a very long time,
just like my brother.
Brother?
Yes. The Kinoshita Yoshiro
you were just talking about
was my brother, fourteen
years older than me.
At only 20, he had received every
accolade a magician could obtain.
And he was my only family,
after our parents died when I was young.
But then that man destroyed
my brother like a bug!
Tsukumo Motoyasu
was jealous of his talent!
You can't be serious!
My husband would never--
It's not a lie. I saw it myself.
On that day, fourteen years ago,
he fiddled with the handcuffs
that my brother used in shows.
Immediately after, my brother
drowned in the practice water tank,
because his handcuffs
wouldn't come off.
The incident was swept under
the rug as an accident, of course...
I see. So you became his
pupil to avenge your brother.
Yes. My last name was changed
when I was taken in by relatives,
so he probably never realized.
My brother was killed
right on my 7th birthday.
The birthday when I was left all alone...
That's why I killed him
just before his daughter turned 7.
I revealed my identity to him
after I administered the poison,
but he still seemed calm,
so I threatened to kill his daughter, too.
He suddenly lost his calm and...
I'm sorry! That was the
only way to protect my status!
You can have my life.
Just keep my daughter out of this!
Just as I said, I planned to kill his
daughter, but then I decided not to.
She did nothing wrong, after all.
Still, he was a foolish man.
He naively let me tie his rings
together to show me a new trick,
and he unwittingly
swallowed my poison capsule.
For Japan's greatest
magician, that's a real laugh!
That's not true, Mako.
He knew you were going to kill him.
Y-You're lying!
I told you. I saw you hugging
the photo of your brother.
Our teacher had been with me then.
And then he said, "Don't tell
this to anyone until the time comes."
But you won, Mako.
Your trick completely fooled the police.
And the dying message he left
won't stand as evidence at this point.
Don't ridicule me. I have no
intention of taking the stage now.
I'm going to go to the police
and lower my own curtain on myself.
Plus, it wasn't right for me to make
Ayano-chan share my lot in life.
Afterward, we took Mako-san to the police
and were supposed to return to
the detective agency for a late dinner.
Whoa, it's already after 12:00.
I'm hungry...
Oh no! I forgot to
buy ingredients for dinner!
It's okay! Conan-kun and I'll get
something at the convenience store!
Don't take too long. I'll be waiting.
S-Say, Ran-neechan. This isn't
the way to the convenience store.
If we're lost, we should go
back to the detective agency first.
Yes. We have to go back...
Kudo
...to your house!
W-What are you talking about?
This is Shinichi-niichan's house!
You're so silly!
I see. So, that's how
you've tricked us all this time.
Isn't that right...
Shinichi?!
You're Shinichi, aren't you?
W-What are you saying?
Of course I'm not Shinichi-niichan!
No, there's no doubt about it!
That reasoning, ability to take action,
and lack of musical knowledge!
You're exactly alike!
But, look closely! I'm a kid!
You probably took a weird drug
Dr. Agasa made or something!
Everything's really adding up!
Quit playing dumb already!
I have so, so much to say to you!
Not good...
Do you have proof?
Don't say crazy things
if you don't have proof.
There's proof right here.
There! I've never seen
such a close look-alike before!
B-But that's...
It's time to fess up, Shinichi!
Oh! Ran-chan!
Why are you in front of
our home so late at night?
S-Shinichi-kun's mother...
When did you return from L.A.?
Just now. I took the last flight.
Some things came up.
Oh no! If Mom blurts
out too much now...
Oh? Who's that?
Perfect timing.
Let's have your birth mother...
...tell us who you really are!
Oh, my!
It's you, Conan-chan!
It's good to see you again!
Y-You know him?
Yes!
He's my grandfather's brother's
daughter's cousin's uncle's grandson!
But, he says he's
a relative of Dr. Agasa.
Yes! He and I are
very distant relatives!
But doesn't he look too much
like Shinichi when he was little?
You think? Conan-kun
seems much nicer to me...
Your mom's name is
Fumiyo-san, right?
Yeah!
It sounds like a trick.
It's too odd for a grade-schooler
to be so good at figuring things out!
H-He must've picked up
some of Shinichi's qualities!
He used to visit all the time, after all!
He used to hang out with Shinichi?
Right?
I love Shinichi-niichan!
Even so...
Ran-chan. Think about it.
Would Shinichi do something like this?
You're scary, Ran-neechan.
You're scary, Ran-neechan...
Sorry, Conan-kun! I guess
I had the wrong idea, again!
Forget everything I just said!
I'll make you a yummy
Salisbury steak as an apology!
Okay!
Oh, wait!
Could I take him for two or three days?
My vacation starts tomorrow,
and we haven't talked in so long!
Yes, that should be okay.
Well, see you later, Conan-kun!
Good night!
Good night, Ran-neechan!
Be careful!
So, why are you back?
Don't tell me your fight with
Dad this afternoon is the reason why.
Oh, that's some way to talk
to the person who saved your life.
Saved my life?
I heard from Dr. Agasa
that you took baths with Ran-chan!
If I hadn't covered for you,
who knows what her
karate would've done to you!
Right?
Anyways, I hope you told
Dad you were coming here.
Of course I didn't.
Hey, now!
It's alright! I'm going
to live with you for a while!
Geez! Don't get me involved, too!
But whenever I'm with mini-you,
I feel young again, too!
Okay! Let's have
din-din with Mommy!
Let go of me!
What's going on?!
Oh, are you awake, Shin-chan?
M-Mom!
I also came back to Japan to
take care of something out here.
Take care of what?!
Hey!
Yuki-chan!
Yabuuchi Hiromi (37) Yukiko's old classmate
You came! Thank you!
I know you must be busy!
Yabuuchi Hiromi (37) Yukiko's old classmate
I'd rush here from
the other side of the world
to help my childhood friend, Hiromi!
Oh? Where are Yusaku-san
and Shinichi-kun?
Oh, those two are busy.
But don't worry! I brought him instead!
Eh? Don't tell me he's...
Yep! My second son, Conan!
I had him in Los Angeles!
Hey, now!
He's a kid, but he's quite sharp!
Oh! You and your husband
must be getting along well!
Yeah, I guess!
So, what is it you
want us to look into?
The truth is--
Oh? Guests, Hiromi-san?
Uncle Yoshifusa!
This is Yukiko-san! She used to
visit all the time when she was little!
It's good to see you again!
Hmm, I don't remember her.
Yabuuchi Yoshifusa (64) Hiromi's uncle
But I did live in Brazil for a long time.
Make yourselves at home.
Alright! Let's go, Carlos!
Carlos (26) Yabuuchi Yoshifusa's friend
C-Carlos?
Uncle Yoshifusa says he's a
friend he brought back from Brazil...
Oh?
Tell me. How does
Uncle Yoshifusa seem to you?
What do you mean?
Like his face, voice, and feel...
Hmm. We used to play with him a lot,
but he went to Brazil
before I entered grade school, so...
Was it Uncle Yoshifusa
who you wanted us to investigate?!
Yes. He returned
from Brazil three days ago,
but he seems different from before...
Why not show him to your dad?
He's your dad's little brother, right?
I can't.
My father, Yoshichika,
died last month of cancer...
C-Cancer?
Yes. My mother passed
away fifteen years ago,
and all of Uncle Yoshifusa's
friends died early on...
So, we're the only two who've
met him on numerous occasions.
But, why are you
so suspicious of him?
The inheritance.
Dear!
Hiromi's husband (married into family)
Everyone suspects
that old man might be an impostor
Hiromi's husband (married into family)
trying to take her father's inheritance.
He owned all the land in this area,
and his inheritance is worth a lot.
The lawyer says he left a will,
and that anyone who's absent when
it's read doesn't get a single yen.
When is it going to be read?
Tomorrow night at 10:00,
when his mourning ends.
Yabuuchi Yoshiyuki (32) Hiromi's brother
Which means we gotta unmask
that old man before then.
Yabuuchi Yoshiyuki (32) Hiromi's brother
Or else we'll end up with a smaller share.
Yabuuchi Keiko (28) Yoshiyuki's wife
Yabuuchi Machiko (39) Yoshichika's 2nd wife
lt might not just mean a smaller share.
Depending on the contents of
the will, we may get nothing.
Yabuuchi Machiko (39) Yoshichika's 2nd wife
Anyways, we gotta do something
before tomorrow night.
Where did all these people come from?
Geez!
Aren't there any old photos left?
It seems Uncle Yoshifusa took
them all when he went to Brazil.
Oh, could this be him?
See? You guys are in it too, Mom.
Eh?
Oh, that's him!
The one in the middle!
It's definitely Uncle Yoshifusa!
But, he's too young
in it to be of any use.
Plus, he has a hat on.
But this brings back memories!
This is from the city
baseball tournament!
Do you remember?
A runner's shoe spike injured his leg.
That's right. He had to get
lots of stitches at the hospital.
Then, shouldn't
he still have that scar?
Eh?
Hiromi! Good luck!
Yeah...
Uncle! Would you like some tea?
Oh, thank you.
Ouch!
I'm sorry! I'll clean it up...
It's not there!
The scar isn't there!
What?!
Scar?
Oh, do you mean this?
A runner spiked my
leg hard on first base
during a baseball game thirty years ago.
Huh? He does have a scar...
Meaning it's really him?
So, you did suspect me!
My brother was right!
There are no decent people here!
I was wise to bring Carlos with me!
Wise?
He's a bodyguard I hired in Brazil.
B-Bodyguard?!
Why would you need one?
You'd hire one too,
if you got a letter like this!
"There's no inheritance for you.
If you value your life,
don't come back."
L-Life?!
When did you get this letter?!
One month ago. It was
sent to my house in Brazil.
It goes without saying that
the sender's name was missing.
I didn't care about my brother's
inheritance, but I did want to see
the faces of the buffoons
who would send such a letter.
Buffoons?
Now, if you're finished here,
then get the hell out!
Hey, mister!
Teach me some kanji letters!
Mom won't help me.
Hold on, Shin--
I mean, Conan-chan!
How do you write "happy new year"?
L-Left-handed?!
Did you see that, Sis?!
Yes. But I can't remember
if our uncle was left-handed or not.
Do you remember, Yuki-chan?
Not at all.
But, he did have the scar on his leg,
so I think he is Uncle Yoshifusa.
No, he could've heard from someone
and relied on an old scar of
his own he just happened to have.
Then that geezer is a fake?!
I think he's the real deal.
Take a look at the photo of
Uncle Yoshifusa we found in the shed.
See? He has a mitt on his right hand.
Proof that he's left-handed.
That's true...
Plus, his handwriting is the same.
Handwriting?
Happy New Year
I found this postcard with the photograph!
A New Year's card that Uncle
Yoshifusa sent when he was in Brazil!
Happy New Year
See? The handwriting matches
exactly with what he wrote just now!
Happy New Year
Hold on. Don't tell me you had
him write this so you could check?
Just what I'd expect
from the son of Kudo Yusaku,
the world-renowned mystery writer!
He's my son! Mine!
Okay...
Oh?
The old well is still here?
Even after that accident...
Yeah...
Accident?
Our mother fell into it and died.
She disappeared one day fifteen
years ago, after a very heavy snowfall.
We all looked for her,
but couldn't find her.
The next morning, just when
we were about to contact the police,
we found her in the well, dead.
We were going to destroy
the well because it was dangerous,
but Father asked to keep it until he
died too, so he'd never forget her.
So, that's why there's
a fence around the well.
I went and put it there myself,
so nobody else'd fall in.
But, the real trouble was
during the funeral before then.
Funeral?
Our mom's brother
suddenly caused a scene!
Claimed one of us
knocked her down there!
What really did happen?
The cause was that
camellia plant our uncle grew
as a wedding gift for our parents.
Camellia?
The sasanqua next to the well.
Our mother stood on the edge of
the well to pick a flower, but slipped.
She wanted to show it to us.
She loved those flowers.
They hardly bloomed
during the winter of that year,
and she had been
waiting for them eagerly.
A camellia flower
was found in her hand, so...
But, in the end, her brother
didn't seem to accept it.
Hey! Where is he now?!
I don't know.
He was rather old back then,
so perhaps he's passed away?
Hey, now! If he's still alive,
won't he get the inheritance, too?!
Don't worry! Legally, he shouldn't
have any inheritance rights to it!
That's not necessarily true.
He could still receive some inheritance,
if it's in my husband's will.
Then, what, he might show
up before 10:00 tomorrow night,
when the will is read?!
Eh?!
That's right. If he's alive,
he'll be absolutely sure to come.
Plus, he seems to have a
15-year old grudge with you all.
Though, it has nothing
to do with me, of course,
as I wasn't a part
of this family when she died.
Oh, yes! I'm off to a friend's
after-wedding party now.
I leave the rest to you,
Hiromi-san!
Yes, Mother.
W-Who's there?!
What's going on?
Someone was just there!
A strange person watching
us from behind that wood gate!
I don't see anyone!
Sure you weren't
just seeing things, kid?
That's strange. I'm pretty
sure someone was here...
I don't like this. Don't tell me
this person is actually her brother?!
I'm sorry to bother you by staying here
and having you make such a nice meal!
It's no problem! Nabe dishes
are more fun with lots of people!
Whatever. You even
packed a change of clothes.
I bet you were planning
to stay from the start...
What was that? Did you
say something, Conan-chan?
No, nothing...
Who could that be at this hour?
Hello?
Oh, Hiromi-san?
Oh, Mother! What's going on?
That reminds me, we were
out of firewood for the bath.
Yes. So I thought we'd go
without using the bath tonight.
Mother?!
Machiko-chan! Let's drink!
Quit it! I'm on the phone!
Oh, yes!
I bought firewood for the bath
this morning and put it by the shed.
Right.
Well, see you later!
Mother seems to be quite drunk.
She sure is carefree in
the middle of Dad's mourning.
Oh! A nabe for dinner tonight!
Now I can rest easy!
Rest easy?
I won't have to ask Carlos
to taste-test my food for poison!
Uncle!
I'm sure that letter
was a prank or something!
Let's hope so.
How's the water, Yuki-chan?
It seems just right!
Still, a caldron bath in these times?
Oh, what's wrong
with that? It has elegance.
Say, Shin-chan. Want to bathe
together like in the old days?
Forget it.
Hey. Could you tell
Uncle the bath is ready?
Come to think of it, he did love baths!
He always took the first bath, too!
Do you think he and that Carlos
person will fit in this small bath?
You're so silly!
Uncle has taken a bath
every day since he's come here,
but Carlos always stayed in the house.
Eh? He would take a bath all alone,
leaving his bodyguard behind?
Now I see. Carlos watches
everyone while he's in the bath...
Alright. I'm counting on you, Carlos.
Hello? Mother?
Well? Did you find the firewood?
Yes! Uncle just went to take a bath!
Oh, really?
I'm still at the party. I don't think
I'll be back until after 11:00.
I'm sorry to ask, but could
you keep the bath warm until then?
Sure!
That was a great bath!
Think I'll go next.
Guess I'll go after you, then.
Oh! How was the water?
It was a little cold, I guess.
I better rebuild the fire then.
Yeah.
Thanks for the hard work!
Make yourself at home!
Honestly! You can take baths
with Ran-chan, but not with me?!
What is it, Hiromi?!
J-Just now! There was a weird man
with sunglasses behind the gate!
So, I did see that guy!
Hey! Doesn't that pail seem strange?!
Eh?!
See?! The well bucket is up!
It looks like something's stuck to it!
Let's pull it up!
It's pretty heavy!
Heave-ho!
M-Mother!
H-How did this happen?!
D-Don't tell me she jumped
into the well to commit suicide?!
No! There's a stab mark in
her chest! This is how she died!
W-What?!
Does that mean someone here did it?!
Y-You can't be serious!
Say. Machiko-san's last phone
call was at around 9:00, right?
Yes. From the banquet hall
of the hotel near the station.
I went into the bath ten minutes ago.
Did anyone leave the
room while I was in the bath?
No. No one.
Then, it couldn't
have been someone here.
It would take at least one hour by
car from the hotel to this house.
In other words, while I was in the bath,
she returned, and someone killed
her and threw her down the well.
Though, it's a different
story if you suspect me,
even though I met her
for the first time today.
Then who did kill her?!
Could it be the suspicious man
with sunglasses you just saw?!
But why would he kill Mother?!
There's something in her pocket!
What?!
T-This is...
...a camellia flower!
Then... Then the person
I just saw r-really was...
The man from fifteen years ago...