Yes.
The one who murdered Machiko-san
and hid her body in the well...
Wait! Don't tell us it was
the guy with the sunglasses!
He's probably our mom's
brother, who blames us
for her death when she fell
into the well fifteen years ago!
He has a motive, but could you
save this for until after he's caught?!
No. He's likely a
detective someone hired
to determine if Mr. Yoshifusa
really is who he claims to be.
H-Hold on. If he's not the killer, then...
Y-You can't mean...
Yes. Machiko-san's
killer is in this very room!
Hey, now! You heard that she
called from the hotel at 9:00 last night!
Even if she left right after calling,
she'd arrive here after 10:00.
We were all in the same room then,
so we couldn't have done it!
Might this be possible?
Just after 8:00, Machiko-san
made her first call from the party,
then left the party immediately after.
Just after 9:00, she parked
the car in the woods
and played back a tape recording
of the party on the car stereo
while making her second call.
To make it seem as
if she was still at the party.
She was the one who was killed.
Why would she create an alibi?
Because things wound up just the opposite.
Opposite?
What do you mean?
Machiko-san planned to use
that alibi trick and kill someone.
But she wound up being
killed by that person instead.
What now?!
Ironically, her trick wound up
helping the alibi of her killer instead.
The raincoat found in the well...
She put it on beforehand to keep
her victim's blood off her clothes.
And the camellia flower...
She had it in her pocket so she could
drop it at the murder scene later
to make it look connected
to the incident fifteen years ago.
As for the tape lying by the firewood,
she either dropped it on her way
to her target who was in the bath,
or it fell from her pocket while her
body was being carried to the well.
In either case, she likely planned
to burn the tape in the stove.
The murder probably
happened in the bathroom.
That way, if any blood went flying,
it could be cleaned away.
So, who is this person who
killed her first in the bathroom?!
Machiko-san's target was someone
fond of taking a bath every day,
and the only person here whose
turn to use it was set in stone.
It was you, Yabuuchi Yoshifusa-san!
U-Uncle?! That can't be!
As I recall, Brazilian jujutsu
has a certain technique...
in which you twist the arm
of a knife-wielding attacker
and cause the attacker to stab himself.
When Machiko-san attacked,
you used that move without thinking!
Increasing her share of the
inheritance was probably her motive.
B-But that would be self-defense.
Why would he keep quiet about it?
Because he had been
sent two threatening letters.
So, there's still another
cretin out to take my life.
That clearly indicates
someone had attacked him before.
In short, Machiko-san
had also sent a threat letter.
Just like Keiko-san,
who had set up the arrow.
I assume he tied the body to the
well rope and made it easy to spot
to serve as an example to
the other intimidator.
In any case, it was
self-defense, plain and simple.
Will you confess, Yoshifusa-san?!
You still have room for improvement.
Hey! Who're you?!
The man with the sunglasses!
What?!
The tape with the will on it.
One listen will shed light on everything.
Hurry.
R-Right...
I divide my inheritance between
the following six people:
my wife Machiko, my daughter
Hiromi, her husband Hidekazu,
my son Yoshiyuki, his wife Keiko,
and Carlos.
C-Carlos?! W-What is
his name doing on here?!
I hereby divide my inheritance
evenly among those six people.
That's strange! Why isn't
your name on the list, Uncle?!
Of course it isn't.
After all, that old man is a
bodyguard who came here from Brazil
to keep Carlos safe!
What?!
Then, who is Carlos?!
The son born of the real
Yoshifusa-san and a Brazilian woman.
S-Son?
But, Detective!
Where did you find that out?!
No, I'm not a detective.
I'm just a mere mystery writer.
Y-Yusaku-san!
Yikes! D-Dad!
Yusaku-san!
What are you doing here?
Oh, uhh, you know.
But is he really not him?!
He's left-handed,
and his handwriting matched!
The world is full of left-handed people.
It's only natural the handwriting matches.
Because Mr. Yoshifusa
had the old man write for him.
Mr. Yoshifusa and the old man
owned a farm in Brazil together.
But when a tornado hit ten years ago,
the old man hurt his right leg
and Mr. Yoshifusa lost his left arm.
Ever since, the old man wrote for him.
Carlos was given part of the inheritance
because Mr. Yoshichika felt sorry
for his brother who lost his farm
and had died of illness half a year prior.
It was all written in here,
in this pile of letters left in
a hidden panel in the storeroom.
But why did you
pretend to be our uncle?
Don't tell me it was to pilfer money!
If that was his intent,
he wouldn't have taken on the role
of someone whose life was threatened.
If people learned
Carlos was Mr. Yoshifusa's son,
he would've been
targeted by the intimidators.
That's why the old man
took on the role of Mr. Yoshifusa.
To have the intimidators'
attacks focused on him instead.
This is evidenced by the fact
that when the old man would bathe,
he would leave Carlos
in the other room.
Because making it seem like
he was keeping watch over everyone
would be the safest idea.
The old man planned to
catch the intimidator,
but wound up killing her instead.
Although it was a case of self-defense,
he would've been taken
away by the police for questioning.
But he couldn't leave Carlos alone
with one other intimidator around.
He made the body easy to find to
see if the police detective who came
was a sensible man or not.
But what came was
an unreliable rookie detective.
With no other choice,
the old man decided to remain
silent until the will was read.
I see...
Did I get anything wrong,
Hickson Tanaka-san, 2nd-generation
Japanese-Brazilian?!
You're exactly right.
You didn't get a single thing wrong.
If you'll present yourself to the police,
I can introduce you to a great,
hardhearted inspector I know.
Yes, that would be best.
I think I can trust you!
Inspector Megure arrived two hours later,
and Tanaka-san and Keiko-san were
taken to the Gunma Police Dept.
Carlos, who knew very little Japanese,
watched sadly as the car left,
but Dad told him in Portuguese
that he would be back very soon,
at which he showed child-like joy.
Apparently, in order to keep Carlos safe,
Tanaka-san hadn't told
him about the inheritance
or that this was his
father's family's home.
And then, the long night ended.
Eh?! You heard my voice?!
Yeah. Dr. Agasa gave me a microphone
that picks up sounds from your bowtie.
It helped with my deduction.
I would've known the
old man wasn't the real deal
if I'd found those letters, too.
No, I knew he was a
fake before reading the letters.
How?!
His leg scar.
A left-handed first baseman
would stretch out from the left leg.
But that old man's
scar was on his right leg.
It seemed strange, so I scoured
the storeroom and found the letters.
It seems you still lack in the
observation department, Shinichi-kun!
You think you're so great.
Look at you trying to act cool,
after chasing after me.
"I'm just a mere mystery writer."
You gotta be kidding me!
Are you trying to be
Akechi Kogoro or something?
Talk about lame! I can't believe you!
Yukiko.
We leave.
Whatever. You don't care how others feel.
"We leave"? Don't insult me!
What're you doing, Shinichi?
You'll get left behind!
O-Oh, yeah.
In any event, these incidents
and this marital spat are over now.
How did they meet
looking at such a lonely sunset?
Even as I try to find clever words,
there are none to
connect our distant hearts
Do you think if
I wave with my best smile
that I might look
even a little prettier?
If I could have one wish granted
it would be that our love
wouldn't make us both hurt
Mori Detective Agency
Bye, Shin-chan!
Give Ran-kun my regards!
Oh, yes. I'd watch out
for Ran-chan if I were you.
Something bugs me
about that last smile of hers...
Yes. Underestimate women
and you'll be in a world of hurt.
Oh! You do understand!
Later!
She can't be serious... can she?
I'm...
...home?
I heard from Dr. Agasa.
H-Heard what?
If you're going on an overnight
trip somewhere, at least tell us first!
Eh?
I was worried sick!
I kept calling Shinichi's
house but no one was there!
Honestly, now!
I-I'm sorry...
D-Don't scare me like that...