The deceased is
Yabuuchi Machiko-san, age 39.
You're sure she's the
second wife of Yoshichika-san,
the head of this house
who died last month?
Yes.
Detective Yamamura.
We haven't found
the murder weapon yet,
but it appears she died of
blood loss from the stab to the chest.
O-Oh, is that so?
Can we say the body was found just after 10:00 pm?
Detective Yamamura
Yes.
It seemed odd that the well bucket
was up, so when we pulled it up...
...we found her body in the well.
Umm, is something the matter?
No, no! I just got
chills when I imagined it...
Umm, this would mean that
the killer was one of you eight
who were here when it happened...
H-Hold on, now!
She was at a friend's after-wedding
party at the hotel by the station,
and she called from
there at around 9:00!
Even if she left by
car right after calling,
she wouldn't be
back until after 10:00.
We were all in the same room
between 10:00 and the
time the body was found,
so we couldn't have killed her!
Yep! I was the only one not with them,
because I was in the bath!
Eh?! T-Then you're the killer?!
No! I only met the
late Machiko-san today!
Right, Conan-chan?
Yeah!
It's the truth!
Yukiko's been living abroad.
I just happened
to ask her here today.
"Yukiko"? Oh, wait a minute!
Don't tell me you're...
Fujimine Yukiko-san, the actress?!
Y-Yes.
Wow, cool!
I used to watch you every week on
"Dangerous Policewoman Story!"
You actually inspired me
to join the police!
Oh!
That makes you even more suspicious.
Huh?
After all, you're skilled
at using guns and knives.
That was just a TV show!
Are we gonna be alright with this cop?
Say. Was it really
Machiko-san who called?
Yes. It was her.
She responded to the conversation,
and I could hear the party, too.
See?! Only you could've done it!
I'm telling you...
There's someone
else who's suspicious!
He was lurking around here.
A strange person covering his face
with sunglasses, a hat, and a scarf.
A s-strange person?
I bet it's the brother of our mom,
who died fifteen years ago.
She tried to pick a flower there
and accidentally fell into the well.
But he's convinced one
of us pushed her down there.
But just like me, Machiko-san wasn't
part of the family fifteen years ago!
So why would he kill her?
Good question.
It was dark back here.
Maybe he mistook her for someone else?
Umm, it's still not certain if
he was the man with sunglasses...
It could be.
See? Here's this camellia flower.
A flower from that tree?
This was in this
lady's breast pocket.
What're you freakin' out for?
You're with the homicide
department, aren't you?
A-Actually, this is my
first real investigation...
There's a cold going
around the department,
so I was the only
one they could send...
So, I'm not good
around dead bodies...
Oh. I see.
A-Anyways, to find out the
precise time the victim returned home,
I'll need to check with
the taxi she took from the hotel.
Taxi?
Mother took the family car.
C-Car?
The car's in the yard, isn't it?
No. I didn't see one anywhere.
The car isn't here.
How strange. It's always parked here.
Where could Mother have put the car?
She had been drinking at the party,
so perhaps she left the
car there and took a taxi home?
Yes...
Detective Yamamura!
Yes?
We found a car in the
woods right behind the house.
I-In the woods?
What's a car doing there?
T-This is our car!
But why is it in the woods?
Maybe the killer planned to
use it, but changed his mind?
Your mother probably just ran
out of gas or had engine trouble!
So she walked to the house,
where that man was waiting to stab her!
That's strange. The engine works
just fine, and the key was still in.
Plus, it still has gas, and
doesn't seem to have any flat tires...
And this empty cassette
case seems curious.
I don't see its contents anywhere.
There's only a cell phone
in the glove compartment.
Hey!
In any case, you'll all sleep
tonight while we keep watch.
Plus, that man
could still be out there.
Geez. We all gotta sleep in
the same room as some cops?
This sucks.
Hey, Shin-chan.
How much have you figured out?
Dunno.
C'mon, tell me!
I'll get accused of being the killer
if we leave it to that lamebrain cop!
There are still too many mysteries!
There's that man in the sunglasses,
the car left in the woods,
and the empty cassette case.
What's most curious of all is the
body that was tied to the well rope.
Even though it was hidden in the well,
it almost asked to be found.
Yeah. There are too many
mysteries scattered about.
Huh?
Was that storeroom open before?.
I don't know.
W-Wait!
Wait! Shin-chan!
Come on. Let's get back
to our room and sleep.
Hurry up, Shin-chan!
Detective Yamamura!
Y-Yeah?
We found the murder weapon in the well!
Eh?!
A kitchen knife, huh?
Please see if it matches
with the victim's stab wound.
Right!
What's that plastic thing?
Oh, it's a woman's raincoat.
The knife was wrapped
in it for some reason.
A raincoat?
No, forget it!
Authorized personnel only!
What's going on?
This person just barged in...
I told you, I'm the attorney!
Attorney?
I came to read the will of the late Yoshichika-san!
The Yabuuchi Family Attorney
O-Oh, I see...
It's finally time...
Eh?! Delay the reading of the will?!
Yes. The killer still
hasn't been caught,
and we haven't
finished checking the house.
The reading should
be moved to a later date...
Screw that!
Do you have the right to decide that?!
The greedier you are,
the more noise you make.
What was that?!
Geezer! Don't be rude with me!
You got that?!
You're just an impostor, anyway!
Is pain the only way
to get through to you?
H-Hold on, you two!
How about this? We police
will also attend the reading. Okay?
Now, let's all be friends!
T-That was...
Brazilian jujutsu.
He's quite skilled, at that.
Does that mean Carlos
is even more skilled than him?
But, if he's so good at self-defense,
why would he hire a bodyguard?
Good question. Maybe
he's just being extra cautious.
The reading of Yabuuchi Yoshichika's
last will will now take place.
I ask that you listen quietly.
What's wrong?
What is it? What is that sound?!
What's with the tape recorder?
Yoshichika-san recorded a
tape that accompanies his written will.
Huh? I don't hear anything.
Wait, isn't that the record button?
We have to stop it!
Duck!
Look out!
What was that?!
T-The cabinet! An arrow
came out of that cabinet!
What?!
W-What the...
A b-bow gun!
And this clock...
A-A timing device...
So, it was set to
fire at a specified time...
W-Who would do this?!
Who set this up?!
It must've been that person
who ran from the gate last night!
Assuming he really is the brother
of our mom who died fifteen years ago...
...and that he held a grudge
against our Yabuuchi family...
I get it.
He used the fact we would gather
in here for the reading of the will
and set up the
bow gun and arrow there.
Does that mean
anyone would've done, then?
No, it doesn't look that way.
Conan-kun!
See? Look at the room on the
other side of the wall it went through.
See all the arrow
holes in the floor mat?
It's proof that the killer had
done some test shots beforehand.
In order to hit the
person sitting in that spot.
It was decided from the start
that the will would be
read in that room, right?
Y-Yes.
That's even more evidence, then.
But, kid, there'd be no
way to tell who'd sit where.
Yes, there would.
The arrow flew at the "head seat,"
Seats of Honor
the one furthest from the exit,
Humble Seats
where the most senior person sits, of course.
Seats of Honor
Humble Seats
In other words, that means the
person who set up the arrow...
...had tried to target you,
Uncle Yoshifusa.
So, there's still another cretin out
to take my life. Heaven help me.
But, isn't this a possibility?
What if Uncle was the
one who set up the arrow?
I don't think so. He barely dodged
it after reacting to Conan's voice.
Duck!
Then, is all of this the doing of
that strange man with the sunglasses?
Yes. It's a very good possibility.
Umm... I'm sorry to interrupt...
But shouldn't we
stop that tape recorder?
Oh no! I left it on record!
Hey! Did all of our
dad's will get erased?!
Why, you...
Oh, whoops!
I accidentally put it on
Side B instead of Side A.
Which means Side B was recorded to!
The will is safe and sound on Side A!
Geez...
C'mon! Just let us hear the will already!
Please calm down. I'm rewinding it now.
In any case, I don't think
we'll be able to solve this case
until we learn
who that strange person is...
Yeah. But I have a good
idea who set up the arrow.
It's that person.
D-Don't tell me they're in this room?!
Yeah.
C'mon! Who is it?! Tell me!
No! There are still too many mysteries!
I can't say anything rashly!
Just a hint, then?
No!
Oh, I see.
Fine, then! I'll figure it out
on my own! Who needs you?!
Hey, now! Don't pout, Mom!
Detective Yamamura!
We found a suspicious
cassette tape by the bath stove!
A-A tape?!
Listen, everyone! Please stay
in this room until I return!
H-Huh? Where's
Yukiko-san and that boy?
They just went outside.
Eh?!
Hold on, hold on! Please
don't wander around on your own!
So, where was this tape?
Y-Yes. It was between the firewood.
That's weird.
Hiromi got the bath ready, but she
didn't say anything about a tape.
Oh, and we just received word
from the examiners. It's strange...
Strange?
Only the victim's fingerprints and
blood were on the murder weapon,
but oddly enough, it appears
she had held it as you would a sword.
A s-sword?
Yes.
That is strange.
If she had grabbed the
handle after being stabbed,
it would've been upside-down.
If it was placed in her hands
to make it look like a suicide,
it would've made sense
to have it upside down, too!
Oh, and I contacted the hotel
the victim had supposedly been at.
What did they say?
It seems she had indeed been there,
but they're not sure when she left.
Come to think of it, Hiromi
did say something strange.
The late Machiko-san said
she'd be home after 11:00,
so why was she back just after 10:00?
Wait a minute!
This door will take you straight
from the bath to the stove.
And this stove is right next to the well,
where the body was hidden!
Which means that tape...
Could it be?!
Let's hear what's on the tape for now.
What're you doing, Mom?
Hey.
You said that sunglasses person
was watching from this gate, right?
Yeah. Hiromi-san
saw him run from there, too.
What is it? Did you find something?
It's nothing!
Hurry! Please return to the room!
Okay! Let's go listen to
that tapey-wapey, Conan-chan!
Quit talking like that!
Machiko-chan! Let's drink!
This is from the party Mother was at!
This tape was really
right next to the stove?
Y-Yes.
Just as I thought! This makes all
of Machiko-san's strange actions fit!
And her killer was the one
who blurted out something odd!
Hey, Mom. I'm gonna need your help.
I figured out who's responsible.
I'm going to explain using
your voice, so go along with it...
Forget it.
Eh?
Don't give me that. You wouldn't
tell me anything earlier.
If you wanna do it, do it on your own.
Because I know something
you don't, Shin-chan!
L-Like what?!
Don't ask me.
Whatever. Just don't get in my way.
Well, let's hear the tape with
the will for now. What do you say?
Yes.
D-Detective?
Or so I'd like to say, but the will
can wait until after my explanation.
After I've revealed who was
responsible for the two incidents here.
W-What?!
Let's start with the second incident,
with the hidden bow gun
that was aimed at Mr. Yoshifusa.
Hey, now. Wasn't the guy
with the sunglasses behind that?
I thought so, too.
Until I heard a certain
someone say a certain something.
Certain something?
Why don't we give it a listen?
We do have it...
...on Side B of the will tape.
Mr. Attorney. Please play it.
Y-You can't be serious...
L-Let's play it and see.
Duck!
Look out!
What was that?!
T-The cabinet! An arrow
came out of that cabinet!
What?!
A b-bow gun!
So, what about this?
Doesn't it seem strange?
As you all know, the
arrow fired from the cabinet
flew across the room in an instant,
shot through the wall,
and left our field of vision.
Yet, a certain person accurately
identified it as an arrow,
before we even opened the cabinet
and found a bow gun inside.
Why would that be?
Keiko! Don't tell me you--
Yes. The answer is simple.
It was because you set
up that bow gun, Keiko-san!
Say what?!
B-But that's not enough
to prove Keiko did it...
It's true! I set it up! The day
Uncle Yoshifusa came back!
K-Keiko...
I got us in debt.
I kept it a secret from you.
It was a huge amount,
with even bigger interest.
I thought if I could get
my portion of the inheritance,
I could pay it all off
without you ever knowing.
But, when I heard your uncle
came back from Brazil, I just snapped.
I didn't intend to kill him.
I just wanted to scare
him enough to return to Brazil.
I set it up so it'd miss him;
I didn't expect it to fly so close to him!
It doesn't matter,
since you killed Mother anyway.
Eh?!
That was your doing too, right?
N-No! That wasn't me!
B-But...
It's the truth! Believe me!
She's right.
The person who murdered
Machiko-san and hid her in the well...
...was someone else!
W-What?!
Who?!
Who was it?!
Okay! Solve this right, Shinichi!
The person responsible...
We'll be watching!