Encounters are mysterious!
But Osaka is even more so!
I'm so glad I'm with you!
Today is a sixty-minute Naniwa special
filled with incidents and mystery!
He sees the single truth for what it is,
and looks like a kid
but has the mind of an adult!
His name? Detective Conan!
This is the incident in Toyonaka.
And this is last
week's incident in Harakata.
There were no witnesses to these killings,
and they're dozens of kilometers away.
We're checking into how
these two victims are connected,
but they still share nothing in common.
Chief Detective Toyama, Osaka Police Headquarters
There's only one thing: the knife.
I don't know why, but they
were both stabbed in the heart,
through their wallets in their jackets.
Have you told the media about this?
No, not the wallet part.
That means the second killing
wasn't some moron's copycat attack.
Correct, it was definitely
the same person.
Serial murders...
If the murders are
at random, it'll cause a panic.
Toyama... You'd best be extra careful.
Hattori Heizo Osaka Chief of Police
Yes, I know.
"The Naniwa Serial Murder Case."
That's the Tennoji Zoo!
That's the Osaka Dome!
And this is the Tsutenkaku Tower!
Whadya think? Osaka's nice, huh?!
Yeah! This is a great view!
I dunno, it's no
different from the Tokyo Tower...
Don't be dumb! Don't compare
this with that tasteless red thing!
The Tsutenkaku and
the new world all around it
are brimming with the Osakans' humanity!
It's almost like downtown Tokyo!
How about some food now?
Just a little longer!
I'm waiting for someone!
Fine, guess I'll have a smoke.
Hey, Hattori.
Tell me why you called me to Osaka.
Huh? You're concerned about that?
You have another real reason, right?
No, no! There's really no work this time!
I just thought I'd
show you guys around Osaka!
There's no telling when you'll die, after all.
W-What's that mean?
I had a bad dream...
Dream?
Yeah... it happens when we catch a bad guy.
But he winds up stabbing
and killing you instead!
Hey, now!
Don't kill people on your own!
There you have it. So just enjoy Osaka!
Sorry! Heiji-kun!
Oh! He's finally here!
Sakata Yusuke (26) Tojiri Police Detective, Section 1
I'm Sakata of the Osaka Police, Tojiri Station!
Sorry for being so late!
Sakata Yusuke (26) Tojiri Police Detective, Section 1
Why is a police detective here?
My old man said that if
Mori-han's coming to Osaka,
he should have a proper tour guide!
Huh? Where is my old man?
He said he was going to stop by.
The chief is busy in a
meeting about the incidents.
"The incidents"?
So, did you get the car?
Of course!
I did just like you asked and
borrowed the Tojiri station's best one!
H-Hey, now. Don't tell me this car is...
Well, let's go!
Isn't this the best?! Cop cars are great!
You can pass other
cars even in traffic jams!
So, where would you like to go, guests?
Tell me...
Are you making us tour Osaka in this thing?!
Huh? You don't like it? It's brand new!
Oh, I know! Should I turn on the siren?
We can go even faster!
No, that's not what he means...
It feels like we're being arrested,
so it's kind of embarrassing.
Oh, don't worry about that!
You haven't done anything wrong!
Hold your heads high!
Whadya think?! This is real udon!
The soup's so clear
you can see the bottom!
Yeah, you can!
It's a light flavor, but good!
Tastes like nothing.
Oh, Heiji! Who's she?
A new girlfriend?
Does it seem that way?
No! I'm just a regular Tokyo--
What is it?
I suddenly got a chill...
So, where to next?
Hmm, the next thing
Osaka is famous for is...
Yum!
This takoyaki is great!
I've never had ones with such big octopus!
What is it?
Nothing... it just feels like
someone's been watching me...
Oh, don't worry about it and eat up!
I can't take my eyes off you!
I thought you were
on a diet, Ran-neechan?
Okonomiyaki? Why didn't
you say so before the takoyaki?
We already passed a great place I know!
We're going the wrong way!
We can't get there on Midosuji!
Osaka is full of one-way roads,
so you often have to go way out of your way!
In that case, shall I show
them a nearby place I know?
It's a good thing this place was nearby!
I'm gonna call my mom real quick.
Mister! Don't forget the rice!
You eat okonomiyaki with rice?
Of course! It's a main dish!
Rice with the sauce on it is great, too!
Osaka's neat!
Yeah!
Oh! That seat is taken--
You're Kudo, aren't you?
Heiji's always talking about you.
Whoa, now!
Hattori-kun does?!
Don't play dumb.
I already know everything.
H-Hold on!
I know you're the Kudo broad
from Tokyo who's seducing him!
Umm, I think you have the wrong idea...
I have just one thing to say to you:
Heiji and I were once
bound by "chains of iron"!
If you want to mess with Heiji,
you gotta go through me--!
Hey, Kazuha.
What're you doing here?
You're hilarious!
The "Kudo" I talked about is a guy! A guy!
Toyama Kazuha (17) Heiji's childhood friend
And this girl is Kudo's squeeze.
Squeeze?
I-It isn't like that!
She says she isn't.
She's just embarrassed.
Then why didn't you
ask Kudo to come too?
Don't be stupid!
Kudo's sitting right--!
H-He couldn't make it!
Anyway, tell us more
about this "chains of iron" thing!
When we were kids, we found
my old man's handcuffs in the attic.
Then we got stuck together when
I pretended to be a policeman!
It was lame;
we found ourselves in big trouble!
It was not lame! We had to bathe
and use the bathroom together!
You moron! Don't tell them that!
Bathe and use the bathroom?
Sounds like a smelly relationship.
To commemorate it, I put a piece
of the chain in here for good luck!
Gross! Throw that thing away!
Say! Are you two going out?!
No, no! Heiji and I are just
childhood friends!
I'm like his big sister
who's always looking after him!
Sure you are.
Her dad's chief detective of the
Osaka police and my dad's friend,
so we've known each other
since we were kids, that's all.
A detective runt and the
daughter of a police detective...
What an ominous couple...
Eh? How come? What's wrong with that?
Still, why are you here?
I was acting as your
big sister and keeping watch
so the creepy Tokyo girl
won't try and seduce you!
Keeping watch? From where?
The Tsutenkaku Tower.
Now I see! She was
the one I sensed watching me!
...attitude?! I was worried about you!
Thanks for the meal!
I'm stuffed!
That was delicious!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
You should've joined us!
No, no, I'm just
here to show you around!
Where to next?
I guess only Osaka Castle is left...
What are you doing in here?
Oh, come on! Take me with you!
What a pain...
Huh?
What happened to this man?!
I don't know! He suddenly
fell onto the hood of the car!
From the roof of this building!
Someone's up there!
Sakata-han! Contact the police!
G-Got it!
H-Hey!
Heiji!
Conan-kun!
Alright!
Now you tell us why you dropped
that body on top of a police car!
N-No! I'm just a--!
What?! He was called to the roof?!
Yeah... someone called this guy
about a strange man on the roof.
I run a tea shop on
the second floor, you see...
But what sent the body falling?
The body was wrapped in rope,
attached to the roof's handrail,
and covered with a tarp,
while the other end of the rope
was tied to the door so the rope
would come undone when opened.
I put his estimated time of
death at about one full day ago.
So someone murdered him this
time yesterday and left him hanging.
But why on top of a police car?
It was probably just coincidence,
but it could be someone
trying to make an example...
Example?
The knife through the wallet and heart...
This is clearly connected
with those incidents...
Hey! Lady! Hold up!
Hey! Wait!
There she goes!
It's all right.
I got her license plate number.
But never mind that.
Tell me about "those incidents," Hattori!
Serial murders?!
Tojiri Police Station, Osaka
And that man who fell was the third one?!
Yep.
In each case, they were stabbed
in the chest, through their wallets.
After they were strangled
to death with something.
Maybe it was someone
who held a grudge about money?
No, we can't say that for sure.
Nagao Hidetoshi Convenience store owner
The first victim, Nagao Hidetoshi,
was a convenience store owner.
Nagao Hidetoshi Convenience store owner
Nishiguchi Tayo Pub mistress
The next victim, Nishiguchi Tayo,
was the mistress of a small pub.
Nishiguchi Tayo Pub mistress
Noyasu Kazuto Taxi driver
And the one who fell was Noyasu Kazuto,
a taxi driver.
Noyasu Kazuto Taxi driver
None of them had enough
money to incur someone's wrath.
In fact, none of them
are connected in any way.
There's no connection?
Nope.
They were all born, raised,
schooled, and employed in Osaka,
but all in different places.
We found it, Heiji-kun!
We found a link between the victims!
Seriously?!
Goshi-san!
Goshi-san! Any comments?!
Huh? Isn't this from Goshi Sotaro's
corruption case six years ago?
The case where his secretary
took responsibility for him and quit?
As I recall,
the secretary's name was Nagao...
Hey! Is our Nagao--?!
Yes.
Nagao Hidetoshi,
the first one who was killed!
But didn't you already
investigate this? Why now?
No, take a look at the driver.
The driver?
Th-That's Noyasu, the third victim!
It seems he was Assemblyman
Goshi's driver until four years ago.
His former secretary and
his former driver...
Assemblyman Goshi
may be involved in this.
We thought so too, so one of
my seniors is headed to his place now.
Still, he's famous for his hatred of police.
Just going to see him won't help anything.
Then what do you say
we pay a visit too, Sakata-chan?
Hold on! You should
leave that to the police!
Don't be stupid.
I can't just let the guy who screwed
up your Osaka tour get away!
Head over to my house!
Kazuha can tell you where it is!
Heiji! Do you have the good luck charm?!
Yep, sure do. Don't worry.
Well, later!
What good luck charm?
A good luck charm I gave him.
It's always protected his life.
What nonsense.
It's true!
The last time he forgot it,
he got really hurt in a kendo match!
They're very important charms!
There are only two in the world!
Two?
Yeah, remember that story
about us and the handcuffs?
I secretly put a piece of the
chain in his good luck charm!
Oh?
Though it's none of your business!
Y-Yeah.
Never mind that.
I don't see the runt anywhere...
Eh?!
Did he go to the bathroom?
I guess this means
no more police cars...
Sorry, Sakata-chan.
You gotta write a letter apologizing
for the crushed car, don't you?
It's fine. I'm used to it.
But what's with the gut?
Oh, this?
This kid'll be helpful!
But won't Mori-han be worried?!
It's okay! I'll call him later!
Oh, that reminds me,
we used the license plate number to get
the address and phone number
of that suspicious woman you saw.
Her name is Okazaki Sumie, age 39.
She divorced last year and lives
alone in the West Side Apartments.
Want to check her out first?
Yeah... it seemed
like she knew something.
Here, I'll call to
see if she's home or not.
West Side Apartments
At 1:00 pm today, a body fell near the Shinsai Bridge.
The deceased was identified
as Noyasu Kazuto-san, age 41.
Moreover...
Forgive me... Forgive me...
Yes?
Oh, is this Okazaki-san's residence?
My name is Sakata,
I'm with the Tojiri Police Department.
O-Officer! Hurry here and
protect me! I'm going to be killed!
I'll tell you everything!
Just hurry here! Hurry!
Just calm down! I'll be right there!
Lock your door and don't let anyone in!
Oh no! We passed the West Side Apartments!
What now?! It's a one-way
road and it's a heavy traffic day!
It'll take forever to turn around!
It'll be faster on foot! Stop the car!
H-Heiji-kun!
Watch it!
Sorry!
West Side Apartments
Hey! Lady! We're with that
cop who called earlier! Open up!
It's unlocked!
Hey! Lady!
Hey!
Lady! Where are you?!
This is Sakata.
Eh?! Okazaki-san isn't home?!
Nope. The place is empty.
That's crazy! I told her not to leave!
Did she contact you at all?
Of course not. I didn't give her my number.
Oh, right.
Anyway, hurry here. Something's not right.
I just got off the one-way road,
so I'll be there in a few minutes.
It's from downstairs!
The public restroom!
D-Don't tell me she--!
Too late. She's dead.
But why?! Why did she go outside?!
And there's a knife
through her wallet and chest...
Who's doing this?! And why?!