The victim is Okazaki Sumie-san, age 39.
She was strangled to
death with a rope of some sort.
She appears to have been
stabbed after being strangled.
What time did you find the body?
Three or four minutes
before you arrived.
This bathroom
cleaner guy found her.
But why does the killer
stab their wallets every time?
You told this lady not to go outside,
but it looks like she died here.
Come to the Shinsai Bridge now
if you want to see some old friends.
1:08 pm.
See that? You're the
next to wind up like that.
1:10 pm.
There's no question that's the killer!
In other words,
the lady heard the first message
and went to the Shinsai Bridge.
Then, when she came back,
she heard the second message
and trembled in fear inside.
But what does "old friends" mean?
Could it refer to the
people who've been killed so far?
Detective Sakata.
There's a call from headquarters.
Oh, thanks.
Hey, Hattori. These answering
machine messages are strange.
How so?
The times and the
contents of the messages.
There were only two minutes
between the "come" message
and the "see that" message.
Does that mean the
killer was watching her?
Something's odd
about these four murders.
I get a bad feeling that
the killer is playing with us...
Bad feeling?
Kudo!
What?!
N-Nothing! Don't sweat it!
Yikes! I just remembered that
ominous dream from the other day!
So, Heiji-kun. Where to next?
Shall we visit Goshi-san's office?
Heiji-kun?
Oh, right.
These sure are strange cases.
There are no witnesses and it's
not clear how they're all connected,
yet we can ID
the victims easily enough.
Yeah, now that you mention it.
The victims' names were on the
news right after the first two killings.
That's only natural.
All four had their driver's
licenses in their stabbed wallets.
Driver's licenses? That's it!
Kadoma Driver's License Testing Ground
So all four have
clean driving records...
Yes.
I thought there might be a car connection.
Guess I was wrong again.
They also all got their licenses
different years at different places.
Hey... it says Okazaki learned
to drive in Hyogo and not Osaka.
So it does.
Why that far away?
Oh, that place is famous
for its cheap license school.
License school?! Does that mean--?!
...If you want to see some old friends.
There's her friends!
Do you have the number
for that place, Mister?
Yes.
Okazaki Sumie and Nishiguchi
Tayo shared a room at the school?!
Seriously?!
Alright! We're starting
to connect the four victims now!
But... isn't it strange?
Okazaki-san got
her license that same year,
but Nishiguchi-san
got his three years later.
Maybe he sucked at driving
and didn't graduate that year?
That's crazy!
You're really sure about that?!
Huh?! What is it?!
The others were at that
school twenty years ago, too!
The first victim,
Nagao Hidetoshi-san,
the third victim, Noyasu Kazuto-san,
and Assemblyman Goshi-san!
They were all at the same place!
What?!
And that's not all.
There was also a man
whose name is all too familiar now.
Familiar?! Who?!
Numabuchi. Numabuchi Kiichiro.
Numabuchi Kiichiro? You don't mean--!
The robber and murderer...
...who's on the run?!
Here it comes! The school photo!
No question about it!
It's Numabuchi!
The faces and names
of the other five match, too!
But this is strange!
August 23, 1978 graduates
See? It says they all graduated then...
...but only Okazaki-san
went on to get her license.
Something happened at this
school twenty years ago. Something...
I see. Thanks.
None of the current staff know anything
that happened twenty years ago.
I figured as much.
Prefectural Nakanoshima Library
But there had to have been some sort of incident
involving that training
ground twenty years ago.
Bingo! This is it!
Driving Instructor Dies in Accident
Drunk Driving Suspected
On that day twenty years ago when those six graduated,
Driving Instructor Dies in Accident
Drunk Driving Suspected
one of the instructors died in a drunk driving accident!
Driving Instructor Dies in Accident
Drunk Driving Suspected
His name was Inaba Tetsuji.
The strictest instructor at the school...
Hey, how does this sound to you?
Numabuchi, broke and in trouble,
decided to use the old incident
to blackmail the assemblyman
out of money but was refused.
So he killed off everyone
involved in the incident
and then repeated his threat.
That, or Goshi used
Numabuchi to kill off everyone
to keep the scandal from interfering
with his Diet member campaign.
Both sound plausible enough.
When Nagao-san and
Noyasu-san quit working for him,
they received a lot of severance pay.
Mention the instructor's death
and his companions back then,
and I bet that cop-hater
will start talking!
Okay! Let's go!
Conan-kun! What are you doing here?!
You suddenly disappeared!
Oh no! I forgot to call!
Hey, Hei-chan! Long time, no see!
Otaki-han from headquarters?!
Why are you here?!
Kazuha-chan asked me to be a driver.
Inspector Otaki Osaka Prefectural Police
Sakata-han called us about the glasses boy.
Now why'd you do that?
Must be convenient, always having
the cops at your beck and call!
Who're you to talk?! You were
touring Osaka in a police car!
Now, now!
I can drive the boy to
the chief's house if you'd like.
Shall we go?
No! I wanna stay with
Heiji-niichan!
Just a minute, Otaki-han.
This is Osaka. Just leave this
to us and go on your way, Kudo!
But knowing you,
you'll just find a way to butt in again.
Fine, then. I'll let you hold onto this.
Your good luck charm?
In exchange, hold yourself
back as much as you can today.
When I come home,
I'll tell you all about what happened!
'Kay?
Conan-kun! Hurry up!
Don't worry. I won't let
them mess with Osaka anymore!
I bet my life on it!
See you later!
Who's he talking to?
I'm starving...
We'll be at the chief's house
in Neyagawa in half an hour...
Heiji's mom is making
blowfish stew tonight!
Oh?!
I can't wait!
Otaki.
What?!
You found the car of
Numabuchi, the fugitive,
in the Mino mountains?!
I'll be right there!
Sorry, Mori-han, but you'll have to
wait longer for the blowfish stew.
I'm taking a side trip!
Mino Waterfall
Sorry! I'll have a youngster
come get you in a minute.
Okay...
Isn't Numabuchi that
murderer who escaped with a gun?
Things have gotten really bad.
Right, Conan--?
Conan-kun!
How's it look?
Oh, Inspector Otaki!
We found the car covered
in plants, but Numabuchi is still...
And that shack?
It was empty
when I peeked inside.
Maybe he ditched the car
and ran off somewhere else?
He's in there.
L-Little boy!
When did you get here?!
Have a look here!
I found these burned
at the bottom of this can.
See? Convenience store receipts
from five and three days ago,
and stickers from lots of convenience
store lunches that expire today.
Not many people would
eat convenience store lunches
at a place like this every day, right?
But, boy, if a wanted man
showed up at a convenience store...
Someone else probably bought it.
Someone's sheltering him.
For some reason...
Hey! You find Numabuchi?!
Well?!
No! There are signs that someone
lived here awhile ago, but...
There's mud on the windowsill!
That pillar and those
beams are free of cobwebs...
I see! He stood
on the windowsill and...
S-Stop, little boy!
Oh?! It looks like
this leads to the attic!
Wait, boy! Leave the rest to us!
Numabuchi!
Numabuchi Kiichiro! You're under
arrest for robbery and murder!
F-Food!
Hurry, give me food!
Goshi Sotaro's residence
What?! Old man Goshi won't come out?!
No, he's kept us waiting
in here since this evening.
I'll go see him myself!
Now, now! Please simmer down
and let my senior save face!
Sir! We can't keep the police detectives waiting any longer!
Goshi Sotaro Prefectural Assemblyman
Forget 'em. They'll give
up and leave eventually.
Shall I at least tell them about
the phone call with the strange voice?
N-No! I absolutely can't...
Let's make a deal in one hour
about the incident twenty years ago.
Go out the back gate
and wait in the far storehouse.
We absolutely can't tell them!
Sheesh! I told you to stop
scampering around, Conan-kun!
All you do is worry me...
Sorry.
Come on! Get walking!
Hey!
Hey, you alright?
Hey, you!
Outta the way!
It's no use!
Conan-kun!
Conan-kun! Hang in there!
It can't be--!
What is it, Heiji-kun?
Oh, nothing!
Huh? Where's Sakata-han?
He just left to use the bathroom.
I should probably go, too.
Conan-kun! Conan-kun!
Someone rush him to the hospital!
Yes, sir!
I'm okay... It only pricked me!
That can't be! The knife went--!
A good luck charm?
It must be thanks to the good
luck charm Heiji-niichan lent me!
Heiji's?
See? The knife got caught in
the chain link, so it couldn't stab me!
Never do that again!
Up, you!
No funny business!
Why does he have two
handcuffs on his left hand?
Oh, this? I'm not sure why,
but he was handcuffed to a pillar.
We had to get him free, so we cut
the chain and put our cuffs on him.
He was handcuffed?!
Looks like you were right
about someone bringing him food, kid.
Wait a minute!
It couldn't be! It couldn't be!
It couldn't be!
Oh no!
Wait all you want,
old man Goshi won't come.
Sakata-han. You're the
serial murderer, aren't you?!
P-Please don't joke like that!
I was just admiring how
unusual this storehouse is!
First, when the
body fell onto the cop car...
You craftily took us there.
Mere moments before we exited
the restaurant, you made a call
and put the special set-up in action.
Then, while I was on the roof,
you called Okazaki-san to the scene,
left a threatening call on her
machine when you knew she was gone,
and led her to
hole up in her apartment.
After you had me witness her
and made an impression on her,
you brought up the topic and
called her after passing her apartment.
Then, after I heard her
frightened voice and leapt from the car,
you parked the car in an alley
and called her again while chasing me.
I'm the detective who just called!
You're in danger there!
Please wait in the nearby
public restroom! Got it?!
And then, while we were in her room,
you killed her in the restroom!
You were able to arrive by
car immediately after she was found
because you had rented
two cars of the exact same model!
After you killed her, you got in
the other rental car that was nearby
to make it look like you'd
just gotten there after some time.
You drove for us and got us
closer to the heart of the case
to get everyone here so you
could kill old man Goshi!
He's a prefectural assemblyman.
He'd stand out if he left his home.
And he could even
take bodyguards with him.
But if you came here with us,
you could wander around freely.
When did you realize it, Heiji-kun?
The rental cars' side-view
mirrors were the first thing.
It was at a different
angle the second time.
And then I noticed the instructor
in the picture from twenty years ago
looked a lot like you.
It was your habit in the
car that finally convinced me.
You fiddled with the rear-view mirror
the same way Noyasu-san
and Okazaki-san did!
That's proof you'd all been
involved with the same person.
I don't know what
happened twenty years ago,
but shouldn't you turn
yourself in, Sakata-han?
I'm sorry, Heiji-kun.
It's all over at this point...
You idiot!
Sakata is the killer?!
That's right! Numabuchi
told us everything!
After he committed the murders,
he planned to frame Numabuchi
and then kill him in a fake suicide!
Where's Sakata?!
H-He's been gone awhile--
There, it's empty!
Now you can't do anything stupid!
A bullet hit your leg?!
N-Never mind me,
Heiji-kun... Hurry and escape!
No can do... Looks like I got hit, too...
He was my father... The instructor
who died twenty years ago.
He was a strict driver
and was always telling my
mother to check the rear-view mirror.
That's probably where I got it from.
Do you think someone
like that would drive drunk?!
And then I became a police detective...
...to expose the
truth of my father's death!
I solved the mystery when I found
Numabuchi in a mountain shack.
I look like my father, so the instant
he saw me, he grew frightened
and blurted everything out.
F-Forgive me, Instructor Inaba!
It was just a prank!
We just wanted to see your scared face
when we forced you to drink
and drive a car without brake fluid!
And then you went after all
six people who took part in it?
The statute of limitations
for murder is fifteen years.
So I decided that if the
law can't punish them, I would!
I'm sorry I dragged you into this, Heiji-kun.
D-Don't talk like that!
You're a cop! You're the only
ones in Japan allowed to carry guns!
Why don't you feel any pride for that?!
Get up, Sakata!
You put the cherry blossom
emblem on your notebook to shame!
O-Otaki-san...
How's Heiji-kun?!
They took him away in
another ambulance just now.
He's really something. He carried
you out of that fire, on his back.
Yes...
Is this the homicidal
maniac who tried to kill me?!
Why, you--!
He is still my subordinate. Hands off.
O-Old man Toyama!
I'll pay a visit later, Goshi-san.
When I do, we can talk about
what happened twenty years ago.