Well... So many balls came out today. What a great haul!
I'm super lucky!
I'm going to surprise Ran out of her wits for despising me
for playing pachinko all the time!
I'm home! The Pachinko King is home!
Hey!
A letter for me?
What's this? "I'm going to the hospital."
"Why don't you keep your cell phone switched on?"
"Ran."
Cell phone?
Oh, no! It's switched off...
34 missed calls and 16 text mails?
What?
Mom fell ill at work and is going to have surgery from now!
I'm at Haido Central Hospital so come quick!
Ran.
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire on the line to the heart.
Coincidental encounter with Amuro at the Central Hospital.
Four ladies involved in a tea party incident.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
"An Awkward Tea Party (Part 1)"
Eri!
Eri...
"Eri Mouri"
Eri!
What's with you making so much noise?
What do you mean that you're having surgery?
It's mere appendicitis.
The surgery finished a while ago, I'm out of sedation and just got up.
What do you mean mere?
Where and what were you doing with your cell phone switched off?
I'm sure you were either at the horse races,
playing mahjong or at the pachinko parlor, right?
Idiot... I was working...
Playing pachinko, right?
Because your clothes got a strange looking wrinkle on your jacket.
That goes to show you were sitting for a long time in a chair, right?
On, no, well you see...
Besides, you had your cell phone switched off
because you were in a noisy place
where you couldn't hear the phone anyway, right?
And Pops, you don't like to have your cell phone on vibration
because it doesn't feel good.
And see! You've got a pachinko ball
stuck between your shoelace!
So, you were at the pachinko parlor after all!
That's amazing, Conan!
I just happened to be watching a detective story that went just like this.
I see.
So you were playing pachinko while I was going through a lot.
What?
Actually I just went to kill time for a while
but I happened to hit the jackpot that doesn't happen everyday you see.
So you go on and let out what you have to too and get discharged soon!
Oh, see...
they say that when you get your appendix taken out,
you're ready to be discharged once you fart, right?
I hope you don't think you created a fancy pun just now.
Well, I thought it was quite a pun.
Get out of here! You goofy detective!
I tell you...
I just came over because I was worried and she gets all worked up...
I don't blame her...
Aren't you Mr. Mouri?
What are you doing in a place like this?
Bourbon?
-Are you ill? -Well... My wife, you see...
Why?
Why is a member of the Black Organization here at Haido Central Hospital?
Don't tell me that... It can't be... Don't tell me that...
What brings you here?
I heard that an acquaintance of mine was hospitalized so I came to visit
but I guess I didn't make it in time...
The nurses mentioned that you've been here before, Conan.
Do you happen to know?
A man called Rikumichi Kusuda?
Who's that? No.
I lent that man some money and I want it back.
-Are you sure you don't know him? -Yes.
You're really something.
Excuse me...
Do you know an in patient called Rikumichi Kusuda?
"Kazuki Beppu (41)" -Mr. Rikumichi Kusuda?
I wonder... What kind of person is he? How old is he?
"Tokie Happo (42)" -Do you have his picture or something?
-Oh, no... Never mind already... -Are you sure?
How about you, Mr. Mouri?
What would you do if somebody suddenly gave you a name
and asked if you knew him?
Well... I would do the same as they did...
That's right.
Most people are not really sure whether they remember something correctly.
That's why before they say no,
they want to know other information
besides the name of the person that is being sought.
That's why you're really something, Conan!
You were confident you didn't know that person just by hearing his name.
Don't take what a kid says seriously...
There are millions of people you've met
but don't know their names.
There are also those that you only know
-by their nicknames too. -Three! Two! One!
Zero!
-Mommy, the elevator's here! -Okay.
Hurry, hurry!
-What's wrong? -Oh, no.
My nickname's also Zero, so I thought somebody called me...
Why, Zero? Your name's Tohru, right?
Tohru in Japanese means transparent, in other words, nil.
Therefore, Zero...
That's how children tend to make nicknames after all.
Rikumichi Kusuda?
What about that person?
Somebody asked me about him in the corridor a while ago.
"Juri Kosaka (42)" -I don't know that person either.
I'm staying in an individual unit
and I don't have much opportunity to talk to other patients, you see...
Congratulations! I heard you'll be discharged tomorrow!
-Yes. -I wish you'd have told me.
If so, I wouldn't have had to come see you, right?
-Thanks for waiting! -Oh, Reina!
"Reina Suto (42)" -You both are here!
Okay then, let's have a tea party!
-I just went and got some hot water too! -Why not?
Would you please take three tea cups out of that cabinet, please?
Is three enough?
I have my own cup, you see.
Oh, new teacups?
-Is it okay to use these? -Yes.
I get rid of the tea stains using baking soda, so they just look new.
You're really scrupulous, after all.
I bought lemon too!
You still liked lemons.
I wonder if the teabags that I bought when coming to visit today are okay?
As to that. There are so many here already...
Why don't we try drinking and comparing various kinds of tea?
Sounds great!
This is a real girls' tea party, isn't it?
I guess you could call it an advance discharge party.
Your wife had acute appendicitis?
Yeah... I got all worked up for nothing.
But they say it's dangerous to take appendicitis lightly.
I guess so.
Don't tell me... He's...
This picture's so nostalgic.
It was taken during the school festival.
Do you keep all your old photos in your cell phone?
Only the ones that I like.
Wasn't it during this school festival?
That when you got it Sosaki, right, Reina?
Who's Sosaki?
The most popular guy in our class.
Was there a guy like that?
You're really a lucky person, Reina.
I don't think so!
The other day I was almost about to lose a large sum of stocks!
My hubby's a mere nouveau riche!
When my son had to take an exam, I thought he had a cold,
but he ended up with influenza, you see...
If I didn't realize soon enough, it could've been a tragedy!
My life's like walking on tight rope...
One mistake and I would've been in the pits.
The scream came from this room, right?
Yes.
Is something wrong?
-Reina? -Reina!
But poisoning somebody in a hospital.
It seems to have been too late by the time the doctor got here.
And who is the victim?
A resident of Haidocho, Ms. Reina Suto, age 42.
It seems she came here today
to visit her high school classmate Ms. Juri Kosaka,
who had been hospitalized,
with her other two classmates.
It seems that Ms. Suto got here before her two other friends though.
The cause of death seems to be suffocation from cyanide poisoning.
Yes.
Why were they drinking black tea in the hospital to begin with?
It seems that Ms. Kosaka, the patient, like black tea,
so every time they got together, they used to have tea parties.
I see.
Which means that the three knew that
they would have a chance to poison the victim.
But the victim seems to have drunk several cups without anything happening.
-It seems she suddenly choked and collapsed. -What?
Maybe somebody gave her a poison laced capsule or something beforehand.
Which means that this may not be the place the murder was committed.
What? It's strange.
-What? -Because see.
There are a lot of pictures in the cell phone that was on the floor here,
but the lady that passed away is holding chopsticks with her right hand!
Hey! Don't go touching the personal effects of the deceased!
But, what's strange about it?
We usually hold chopsticks with the right hand.
But, the cup that dropped to the floor and cracked...
Take a real close look...
Lipstick is on the right side of the handle of the cup!
This shows that she was drinking tea
while holding the cup with her left hand, right?
True...
But, why was the victim holding it with her left hand?
Because her right hand was blocked with something.
For example, maybe she was looking at the pictures in her cell phone.
-The pictures... -In her cell phone?
Right. When people are absorbed in something,
they seem to get careless with other things.
That is, even if the position of their cup
or direction of the handle of the cup is changed,
they pick it up without a thought.
The perpetrator probably made the victim drink the poison
by taking advantage of this mentality
by switching her cup with the victim's.
Switched cups?
Yes, the risk is lower if the perpetrator puts poison in her own cup
and switches it with the victims,
than to try to lace the victim's cup with poison without being noticed.
Since they didn't seem to be using a saucer,
it would've been easy to move the cups around.
Don't you agree, Mr. Mouri?
Oh, yeah... Well, I guess so...
Not this detective again.
There's no way the cups could've been switched!
Only she used lemon.
Besides, take a good look at the color of everyone's tea, will you?
Color?
All three of them are of different color.
From the right, it's brown, blue and yellow.
The one that the victim was drinking was a reddish colored tea.
True, that there's no way you could make a mistake then.
At any rate, if the tea was laced with poison,
the container or package that the poison was in, should be somewhere.
If we check this hospital out thoroughly,
-don't you think we'll come up with something? -Yes.
The perpetrator could probably have it on her too.
So, after the three of you are body checked,
you will all be interrogated in separate rooms.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir...
Yes, that's right.
Yes, I served everyone's tea.
Although they came to visit me, they were my guests, after all.
Well, I served everyone all right,
but all I did was put the tea bags in the cups.
Then, are you the only one who touched the cups?
Oh, no...
I had Ms. Happo and Ms. Beppu take the cups out of the cabinet for me.
Which means that all your fingerprints
would be on the cup of the victim?
But why were so many different types of tea served?
Normally, you'd serve only one type, right?
Since everyone knew that I like herb tea,
people brought me quite a lot of tea as gifts when visiting.
Since Ms. Happo also brought some,
we decided to drink various kinds of tea and compare drinking them.
I see.
Since you were the one who suggested drinking various types of tea
and served them as well,
you would've been most likely among the three of you
to serve the poison laced tea, isn't that right?
I would never do such a thing!
I poured the tea in front of everyone as they watched,
and besides, Ms. Suto had drunk almost half of her tea
before she collapsed.
Besides, as you mentioned a while ago,
if I did switch the poison laced cup with hers,
it would've been apparent in my case.
What? Why is that?
Because the tea I was drinking back then
is called Butterfly Pea herb tea that is blue.
So, I'm sure that everyone would've noticed if I made them switched.
Ms. Suto was drinking Hibiscus tea, a red colored herb tea.
Then do you know what type of tea the other two were drinking?
Yes.
Ms. Happo was drinking brown peppermint tea,
and Ms. Beppu was drinking yellow Chamomile tea, I think it was...
I was drinking Peppermint.
I thought it was going to be a green colored tea,
but was thrown off when it was brown.
I mean, they say peppermint green too, right.
Juri who is knowledgeable about tea was chuckling though.
Brown and red sort of look similar
so you would've been able to switch the cups...
They don't look at all similar!
Mine was brown tea that you usually see around a lot,
while Reina's was a really vivid red color!
It could never be mistaken, don't you think?
-Did you each decide what tea to drink? -Yes.
The tea was lined out on the table, we selected the one we wanted.
After finished drinking, we'd wipe our cups with tissue paper
and went on to the next one.
Juri had been drinking the blue tea from way before we arrived though.
She said it was good for the body but because it tastes bitter,
she wouldn't recommend it.
-By the way, how were you all seated? -Let's see.
We sat clockwise, me, Reina, Kazuki and Juri, I think.
Because Kazuki and I were looking in at the pictures
in Reina's cell phone from both sides.
Who suggested looking at the pictures?
Kazuki! It seems that Juri had shown her the pictures before.
She also told us,
"Let's have her show us the pictures when we go to visit her."
But, Reina refused to let go of the cell phone.
That's why both Kazuki and I ended up peeking in from the side.
She's always been that way.
She was strongly dominant, selfish, and nonchalant.
Her hubby used to be my boyfriend!
She snatched him away from me you see!
But, that doesn't mean that I wanted to kill her or anything.
I see...
Well, if someone were to have a grudge against her,
it would be Kazuki, more than me, I think?
Because she was furious saying
that thanks to Reina, she incurred a great loss.
A great loss?
Of course I'd be furious!
The stocks that Reina recommended me to get took a plunge
and I ended up with a great loss,
but Reina on the other hand, sold it before it went down
and really made out!
-Our sympathies. -Our sympathies.
Thanks to that I'm soaked in debt now.
If she knew it was going to go down, she should've told me.
Is that why you killed her?
If her death would bring my money back, maybe I would have.
I don't want to talk bad about somebody who passed away
but I'm sure that Juri has a load of pent up anger inside her too.
Because thanks to Reina her son failed the entrance exam.
Failed?
Juri and Reina's son were in the same grade,
and were studying towards going to the same Junior High School.
But a day before the exam, Reina's son who came over to study
had influenza.
Juri's son caught it
and was in no condition to take the exam!
-Our sympathies once again. -Our sympathies once again.
Juri was all smiles before he took the exam saying that
she was sure going to have good news to report about soon.
In other words, it would mean that all three of you
had some kind of motive to want to kill the victim.
-Yes. -Like I already said...
We didn't do it!
We may have had grudges against her
but Reina was always the way she was,
so we all took her for what she was.
Hey.
Did anyone leave the room while you all started drinking tea?
Yes.
Tokie and I, once each.
I went to the restroom
and Tokie went to buy candy to go with the tea.
I think that Juri and Reina were both in the room right through.
It seems that Reina went to get hot water to put in the thermos.
That was before Tokie and I got here though...
-It hurts! -Since when were you here?
Is that teacup the hospital's?
That's Juri's cup.
She said she uses baking soda to polish it spic and span.
Which means the only person who could've laced poison
and make the victim drink it...
The question is how that person made the victim pick that cup up.
"Next Episode"
The rim of the teacup?
Poison was laced there?
But, the perpetrator sure has guts. Don't you think so?
How about it? Do you follow?
The person who wait scrupulously for a chance
to switch her cup with that of the victims.
The only one who could've done this is you.
Next Conan, "An Awkward Tea Party (Part 2)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Lemon"
-Lemon reminds me of Shinichi. -Is that so?
-He must be a sour guy. -I'm not.