"Beika Aquarium"
The dolphins were cute, weren't they?
They were really leaping, weren't they?
Super powerful, weren't they?
But, Dr. Agasa sure is late.
I wonder how far he went to park the car?
He probably went to Yakisobuns!
There's a hamburger shop called Yakisobuns
near the parking lot you see.
I'm sure he was lured by the smell and went to eat it.
Because somebody keeps bugging him to go on a diet.
So, Dr. Agasa doesn't get to eat lunch or dinner then.
Yakisobuns, sounds good!
I want to eat some too!
Same here!
Don't worry.
They have parfaits with bananas shaped like dolphins,
scallop pastas served on sea otter plates,
and a lot of other cute, delicious dishes here at this cafe too.
You sure know a lot about this place.
Why do you know so much?
Well, because...
I smelled it.
You suddenly ended up coming here today didn't you, Ran?
Did you come here before?
I got it!
You came here on a date with your boyfriend.
It's nothing like that.
I just came here with him.
-She's blushing. -I said, that's not it.
If you came here with her before
you should've gone to another aquarium, no?
When I came here before,
so many things went on that I didn't get to see the place like I wanted to.
Who are you texting anyway?
Who else but the fatso?
"Incoming text message. Ai Haibara"
Text mail?
Just how long are you going to keep on eating?
She knows.
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire on the line to the heart.
An underwater corridor that is like the bottom of the sea.
The shark witnesses the incident.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
"Shinichi Kudo Aquarium Incident (Part 1)"
Amazing!
There are so many kinds of fishes!
It's like we're in the ocean?
It's a shark, shark!
Awesome!
How big!
They're just like sharks,
that's what a detective is.
How nostalgic.
That Holmes freak and self-loving super snob.
Not even a year has passed since then
but it seems like such a long time ago.
I wonder if back then...
he already liked me.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Dr. Agasa!
You're more than late!
The dolphin show's finished.
You got green dried seaweed between your teeth!
You were at Yakisobuns after all.
Come to think of it, I waited here back then too.
In front of this shark.
You're late.
How rude to tell me to come and be late.
Sorry... really sorry.
A lot of things came up, you see!
Rather, why didn't you wait for me by the entrance?
I had to look all over for you.
I had this great urge to come see the shark, you see.
"Mom. About dinner." "Sonoko. I'm getting better. Thank you."
It's text mail from Sonoko.
She seems to have recovered quite a bit from her cold.
I see.
Okay then, let's get on with it, shall we?
Preliminary check of the what-you-ma-call plan?
It's not a what-you-ma-call plan!
It's the great coincidental two lovers meet again
at the aquarium project!
First, I invite Dad to come to this aquarium with me.
He meets Mom in this fantasy filled space
where the fish are swimming about!
They recall the time when they fell in love
and living apart with each other ends!
You're the one who brought this plan up to begin with, right, Shinichi?
You suggested that the aquarium would be a good place
because Dad likes fish!
Yeah, but Sonoko's the one who thought up the name of this plan.
But, if it was just to check this place out beforehand,
you could've come by yourself, right, Ran?
Well, but I never came to an aquarium
and I was too anxious to come here all by myself!
I know too, that you didn't want to come
to such a lovey-dovey date spot for lovers like this
with somebody like me.
But, I couldn't help it because Sonoko caught a cold
and I couldn't think of anybody else to ask, but you...
I'm not saying I didn't want to come.
Then come with me to the cafe here, okay!
They seem to have a lot of cute menu here.
Please help me out with my parents by making suggestions, okay!
Yes, ma'am.
My parents are just an excuse.
Maybe it's not such a great idea to meet in front of the sharks.
They don't give off good images.
The real truth is I want to come here with Shinichi.
Shinichi...
What do you think?
Think what?
My clothes, clothes!
I kind of really like this dress you see.
I guess it's nice?
Is that all?
If you want somebody to evaluate how your clothes look that badly,
why don't you ask your Mom?
You're having dinner with her tonight, aren't you?
Why do you know about it?
Fantastic. It's a spotted eagle ray!
There it is... Shinichi's bad character.
Although he suddenly says things like he's seen right through you,
he'll keep you in suspense
and not tell you the reason why he knows what he does.
Answer me.
I didn't even tell Dad or Sonoko yet
why do you know when I'm going to be seeing Mom?
Don't tell me you snuck a look at my cell phone.
After you looked at Sonoko's text mail just a while ago,
you went back one mail
and checked what came in before, right?
It's only natural to think that you have other plans today
and were confirming the time.
But, you didn't look at the cell phone display back then, did you?
It's easy to tell by looking at the movement of your fingers
and that the person you're communicating with is your Mom.
You're not answering me at all.
A fashion magazine that you normally wouldn't buy
is in your bag, right, Ran?
There's a name card stuck in between the pages
and judging from the fact that you seem to be quite confident
about what you're wearing today,
I'm sure that you were scouted by an agent as a reader's model,
and had your picture taken,
and obviously got carried away with the idea,
enough to buy that fashion magazine.
You can also go around bragging that your picture may be shown
in this corner of this magazine.
That's something to be happy about...
They wouldn't give a name card to a girl
that they just wanted to make the numbers
so it's most likely that you'll make it on the magazine.
The problem is, scouts like that would only be seen
on the main street of 3-chome around here.
And it would be the long way around to come to this aquarium
The question is, why did you take that road.
You must've wanted to drop by somewhere before coming here.
The moment I looked at your lips,
I figured out the answer.
Lips?
It's a bit glossy.
Since you don't use lip cream,
you must've eaten some oily food.
There are fast food stores along that main street
so it's thinkable that you had a hamburger
to make up for the breakfast you missed.
But, since you were all for eating at the cafe here,
so I guess that's not it.
If so, the only thing thinkable is,
you took pieces of test foods
at the supermarket try-out corner!
That supermarket has a sufficient amount of try-out food corners
and today happens to be their bargain day.
You probably went there
to check out some side dishes for dinner,
which prices may come down even more later, right?
If so,
you're planning to use those side dishes
for your Dad's dinner tonight.
Why would you who are thrifty and a good cook do something like that?
Because you have no time to be doing so.
Because you promised to have dinner with somebody tonight.
Most naturally you're going to proudly wear those clothes
that caught the eyes of the scout that called out to you.
Of course the person you're going to dinner with
isn't Sonoko who has a cold.
Which means the only one left,
and judging from the way you looked when checking your text mail
that partner's got to be your Mom!
It seems you have other reasons for not being able to cook though.
Oh, and just because you came here
despite being late since your picture was taken
don't run anymore today, okay?
Why not?
That's because well...
It'll make you sad.
Why is running going to make me sad?
Oh, well, just make sure you don't run.
My name is "Ran" you know!
So, I was born to run.
Shut up already!
Okay, if you want it that way.
Ran, go back to the entrance and get the staff for me!
Quick!
Please let me through!
Shinichi.
I'm telling you, let me through.
Hey, are you all right?
Back off!
Pull away a bit more.
No good. No pulse already.
One pierce through the heart.
The murder weapon is that knife
that's sticking out of that convenience store bag.
Shinichi!
I brought the staff!
Close off the doorway of this aquarium immediately
and call the police!
The police?
Hurry!
Okay.
Make sure nobody goes near the corpse.
Corpse?
Don't tell me he's dead?
Yeah, he was stabbed by someone in the aquarium.
But, how?
We heard no scream or anything.
And yet, how'd you know?
I smelled it.
Red blood cells contain a protein called hemoglobin that carries oxygen
and its main substance is iron.
Well, when you lick a wound,
it tastes like rusty iron, doesn't it?
So, naturally it would smell like iron too.
I didn't smell anything though.
Just like a shark.
The shark's sense of smell is able to detect
even a drop of blood that has been diluted to 1/100.
They're sense of hearing is even more superior,
and they can hear an irregular low-frequency sound
of below 40 hertz from a distance of 2 kilometers away,
approach their prey with their sense of smell
that I just mentioned,
and they determine the precise location and go for it.
After smelling blood they go to the scene
and with all the faculties they possess they determine who the perp is.
Once they bite, they use their sharp teeth called evidence
and sink it deep into the perp until he gives himself in.
That's what a detective is.
I see.
The bossy youth who took charge of the crime scene
was you after all, Shinichi Kudo.
I just happened to be at the scene with Ran, so I couldn't help myself.
I asked around to see if there were any eye-witnesses of the perp
but, no luck.
The two of you dating at an aquarium?
Does it look that way?
It's nothing like that at all!
I was only playing!
He'll really think that's what it was
if we get all worked up about it, right?
How can you be that way when a person was just found dead?
It seems that the murder weapon is the knife that is beside the corpse.
The perp seems to have stabbed him
using the knife that was inside the convenience store bag.
The perp probably did so
to prevent the blood of the victim splattering on him.
The knife was placed sideways in the bag,
so that it could pierce right through the heart
without being blocked by the bones.
In addition, to make sure that a large amount of blood wouldn't splatter
the perp covered the knife with the jacket
and pulled it out carefully finally hiding the wound with the jacket
and left.
Well, then the victim probably would've shouted,
so I'm sure there were eye-witnesses around?
No, please look in back of his neck.
There's a trace of a stun gun being pushed against his neck.
If he was unconscious before he was stabbed,
he wouldn't have uttered a word.
When I got to him, there was still a bit of blood flowing,
so I think he was stabbed only a few minutes before that.
By the way, the stun gun was inside the inner pocket of his jacket.
This is it.
The perp probably said something
like there's a weird looking fish at the bottom of the aquarium
and made the victim look to the bottom inside.
Then, when the victim leaned against the rim of the fish tank to look in,
the perp probably pushed the stun gun against the back of the victim's head
rendered him unconscious.
That way, there would be no exaggerated movements,
and the victim would just slump down in place,
which after, the perp could stab him without making a scene.
Then, the victim may have known the killer.
There were no driver's license or name card in his wallet,
so first thing, we would have to identify the victim.
As to that...
the name of the victim is Kunihito Shumoto, age 26.
He part-times at a service station in Haido-cho.
It seems that he asked for a day off
saying that he had something to do today.
Therefore, I think that the victim came here with his girlfriend.
A girl about 5'4", wearing a mini skirt, who loves dolphins.
How do you know all that?
There was a cell phone inside the victim's pocket,
so I chose a number at random from his list of contacts!
"I found a cell phone,
but would you know who the owner is?"
I left a message like so.
That's how I got the name.
So I went on and asked,
"Would you know where the owner is so I can deliver it?"
Then she told me where he was part-timing
so I called there too.
I told him not to do that on his own discretion though.
No...
No need for worry!
Because I said that they should call the police
the next time they received a similar type of call.
You're really...
Then, you found out about the girl that the victim could've been with
at the place he part-timed?
No. I looked at the receipt that was inside the wallet of the victim.
The store's a cafe inside this aquarium.
The time's about 15 minutes before I found the corpse.
The details on the receipt show
one cup each of black tea and coffee
so, there's no mistake that he was with someone.
The time was 5 minutes before the dolphin show began
so, it seems they were killing time at the cafe till the time of the show.
A dolphin key holder was shown on it too,
but the victim had no such thing on him.
So, I can only think that he gave it to his dolphin-loving girlfriend.
Then how did you come up with her being around 5'4" tall
and wearing a mini skirt?
Well, I guess you wouldn't be able to understand yet, Ran.
What's that suppose to mean? How rude!
Just what do you mean, Shinichi?
From around the victim's shoulder,
elbow and thigh,
you can smell the fragrance of a woman's perfume, can't you?
The places where a woman puts on perfume
are the back of the ear lobes,
the back side of the hair,
the wrists, the sides of the stomach,
the hem of their skirts, the ankles of their feet and et cetera
but if the smell of perfume got on the victim,
when his woman companion walked hand in hand with him,
the perfume that smells on his shoulder
would've been the perfume she placed
behind her ear lobes and behind her hair
The victim is about 6' tall,
so judging from where the smell of the perfume is,
the woman would be about 5'4" tall.
Then, taking into consideration she may have been wearing high heels
being that she was on a date, subtract about 2 to 3 inches
making her about 5'2" tall.
The smell of perfume on his elbow is the perfume that was on her wrist,
and the smell on his thigh is probably what came from the hem of her skirt,
so judging from the location and the height of the woman,
she would've been wearing a mini skirt.
Well, people usually only put perfume on one part of their bodies, though.
Then, are you saying that the woman is not used to using perfume?
Not always so...
It could be that she always wears the same perfume
so her nose is used to it
and she is under the impression that she needs to use more.
Mom said so.
So, Ran, take care not to put too much on too.
None of your business!
But, why is that woman not showing up?
After all, her boyfriend's been murdered.
I wonder maybe they've just started going out together
and she doesn't want to get involved.
Or, maybe it's because she's the one who stabbed him.
Please collect all the cell phones,
cameras and videos of everyone here in this aquarium!
Maybe the scene when the perp stabbed the victim
has coincidentally been recorded.
I guess so.
"No entry"
Shinichi.
There are more than 100 here!
Are you going to check the images in all these devices?
Moreover,
most of the pictures are of fish.
I would think so.
"Kunihiro Shumoto. Incoming call"
"Kunihiro Shumoto"
"Incoming call"
Why are the phones ringing one after the other?
Before you came, Inspector,
I text mailed out to the people on the contact list of the victim's phone.
I'm calling the people who haven't responded to the mail,
one after the other now...
If I tell them that the police would be checking the picture,
I'm sure they'd all switch on their cell phones.
Then, let's call the three hear what they have to say!
As well as ask them why they're ignoring his phone calls as well.
"Next Episode" -Nao's ex-boyfriend was murdered?
It's been a year since they split, though.
I was just picked up by him last week.
Ran, will you lend me your cell phone?
Don't break it.
Because I finally got Dad to buy it for me.
I see, that's why the perp chose it.
Next Conan, "Shinichi Kudo Aquarium Incident (Part 2)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Gloves"
A surprised re-encounter.
Lovey-dovey revitalization strategy.
It ain't gonna work anyway.