HISHIDA Hall Renovation
Commemorative Lecture
Sorry I'm late.
Mom!
Hello.
Took you long enough.
How long were you going to make us wait?
I've been holding off from drinking beer.
I didn't ask you to do
that. Drink if you want to.
I found time in my busy schedule for this.
What was that?!
What?
Jeez... Stop!
You're not here to argue today.
You're having a meeting.
Then this is none of my business.
You don't need me here.
Hey, one large beer!
Yes, sir.
I'll be leaving immediately, so water's fine.
Yes, ma'am.
Mom!
I'm sorry, but I really don't have the time.
But I'll be there tomorrow.
Yes! Isn't that great, Conan-kun?
Huh? Uh, yeah.
Like I said, this is none of my business.
No one asked you to come.
You don't have to force yourself.
Dad!
I think I'll be able to make the
panel during the second half.
The great detective Mori
Kogoro reveals
his secrets!
HISHIDA Hall Renovation
Commemorative Lecture
I'll make sure to get there on time.
The great detective Mori
Kogoro reveals
his secrets!
HISHIDA Hall Renovation
Commemorative Lecture
So you'll be going onstage together.
Yeah, that's right.
Thank you for waiting.
It's the best. Right, Dad?
Either way, I'm the star of the show.
Yes, yes. Congratulations on your lecture.
I should go.
Oh, no!
Toto Keizai Newspaper
University Professor Murdered
Huh? Someone was just looking over here.
Thanks. See you later.
They're gone?
Did I imagine that?
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
The old man's invited to give a lecture.
What will happen when
the couple goes onstage?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Mori Kogoro's Grand Lecture
(Part One)
"Mori Kogoro's Grand Lecture, Part One!"
Mori Kogoro's Grand Lecture
(Part One)
The great detective Mori
Kogoro reveals his secrets!
HISHIDA Hall Renovation Commemorative Lecture
The great detective Mori
Kogoro reveals his secrets!
1 Hour Before the Lecture
Hall A - Changing Rooms
Boy, I'm nervous.
Hey, you! Another!
Hall A - Changing Rooms
Mori Kogoro-sama
Dad, are you okay?
If you get drunk, you won't
be able to give your talk.
Don't worry.
It'll be more fun with a little drink in me.
Well, it doesn't seem
like he'll need me today.
I hope not.
Ready, and...
Congratulations to the Sleeping Kogoro
From the Detective Boys
Ready, and...
Congratulations!
Congratulations to the Sleeping Kogoro
From the Detective Boys
You kids sure are considerate.
Make sure you study all this
great detective's secrets.
Congratulations to the Sleeping Kogoro
From the Detective Boys
Okay!
Congratulations to the Sleeping Kogoro
From the Detective Boys
At least, we wish we could,
Congratulations to the Sleeping Kogoro
From the Detective Boys
but we actually have to
leave before it starts.
What?
Sorry, mister. We already had plans.
We're going to see a soccer game.
But as long as it doesn't go into overtime,
we'll be able to return during the panel.
Conan-kun and Ai-chan, are you going, too?
That's right.
Sorry.
Fine. Go on, then.
You don't have to force yourselves to return.
Don't say that.
Mom will be on the panel, too.
We'll be waiting for you to come back.
Okay!
Thank you so much for
coming today, Mori-sensei.
I'm delighted to have the world-famous
detective speak at the grand opening of our theater.
Ujimori Yusaku (45)
HISHIDA Hall Manager
Hishida Junko (50)
HISHIDA Hall Owner
I'm delighted to have the world-famous
detective speak at the grand opening of our theater.
Ujimori.
Hishida Junko (50)
HISHIDA Hall Owner
Ujimori Yusaku (45)
HISHIDA Hall Manager
Ujimori.
Yes, ma'am.
Here you are, Sensei.
No, thank you.
I'm just glad to be useful.
Tsunohazu Naoya (35)
Event Company President
Thank you for coming today, Mori-sensei.
Tsunohazu Naoya (35)
Event Company President
Thank you for coming today, Mori-sensei.
This is our staff.
If there's anything you
need, don't hesitate to ask.
Thank you for coming.
Tsukuba Mei (22)
Event Staff
Amagi Kosuke (28)
Furui Kiho (25)
Event Staff
Thank you for coming.
Furui Kiho (25)
Event Staff
Amagi Kosuke (28)
Tsukuba Mei (22)
Event Staff
M-Mei-chan.
Huh?
Say hello.
Oh, I'm sorry!
I'm a huge fan of yours,
so I'm a nervous wreck.
N-Nice to meet you!
I see, I see. The pleasure's all mine.
Mori-san, I've heard so much about you.
Tsukinogi Hideki (40)
Security Company President
Mori-san, I've heard so much about you.
Thank you for coming to speak to—
Tsukinogi Hideki (40)
Security Company President
Thank you for coming to speak to—
Shall we have a battle of the detectives?
I think I recognize that guy.
That's actor Inokoshi Kenichiro-san.
He's famous for playing police
officers and detectives.
That's right. They call him
the king of mystery shows.
For some reason he's always solving
mysteries under precipitous circumstances.
Hey, he can hear you.
I hope you'll appear in one of
my shows sometime, Mori-san.
Inokoshi Kenichiro
(48) Actor
I hope you'll appear in one of
my shows sometime, Mori-san.
We could even start a new series.
What? Me, on TV?
I'm joking.
That was a joke?
You can't be serious!
I refuse to accept this hall!
I've looked after this place
since your father was here.
Reizei Mokichi (70)
Former HISHIDA Hall Manager
I've looked after this place
since your father was here.
What's with the cheap décor?
Reizei Mokichi (70)
Former HISHIDA Hall Manager
What's with the cheap décor?
There, and there, and there!
Taking pride in an outdated
management philosophy
that kept us in the red died off with
my father—rather, my predecessor.
Reizei-san, our contract
with you has already ended.
Please leave.
What was that?!
Please, calm down.
"Keep doing that, and you won't have a
single person open their heart to you."
Who the hell are you? Move!
You're not familiar with my catchphrase?
It's even better when
there's a camera around.
Isn't this actually your job, Tsukinogi-chan?
You're as useless as ever.
I quit working security because of you.
What does that mean?
Who knows?
Sounds like there's bad
blood between those two.
Yeah.
Are you all right?
Why don't you rest over there.
Would you like something to drink?
I'll help.
Thank you.
But I'm fine. You should be helping him.
What?
What's going on?
Dad, you've had too much to drink!
Yikes.
Did something happen?
Conan-kun, help me.
Okay.
Mister, be careful.
What? What happened?
Come on, this way.
Is he okay? He's blind drunk.
I'm worried.
Me, too.
Everyone, I'm sorry for the commotion.
We'll be starting shortly.
Please relax in your
changing rooms until then.
Ujimori, show them the way.
Yes, ma'am.
20 Minutes Before the Lecture
Huh? Where's Conan-kun?
Do you suppose he's still with Ran-san?
If we don't hurry, the game will start.
Fine. I'll go get him. You go on ahead.
Dad! Wake up, Dad!
Huh?
What? Did the great Sleeping...
I mean, did I impress you with
my detective skills again?
Huh? I don't remember anything...
Dad!
I thought so.
Why don't you use your voice changer
to give the lecture yourself?
That's not funny.
What was that?
Conan-kun.
What happened?
Inokoshi Kenichiro-sama
Over there...
That's...
I-Inokoshi-san asked me to bring him coffee.
I knocked on his door, but he didn't answer.
Looks like it's stuck on something.
Judging by this pool of blood...
Yeah, definitely.
Let's see.
The window to Inokoshi-san's
changing room is...
That one.
I knew it.
The body's keeping the door
shut instead of the lock.
In other words, this is...
Yeah.
It's a locked room mystery.
What?
What should we do? The game is starting.
Why not let the police handle it?
I know, but...
Inspector.
There may be some clues still.
Please be careful.
I know.
Takagi, Chiba.
Yes, sir.
Look. Even the great detective is awake.
Yeah.
The victim is actor Inokoshi
Kenichiro-san, forty-eight years old.
He was scheduled to appear on the
panel after Mori-san's lecture,
and was waiting alone in this changing room.
We're waiting on the autopsy
for the cause of death,
but it was likely blood loss due
to being stabbed in the heart.
Also, look at this.
This was in the left breast
pocket of the victim's jacket.
A pocket watch, huh?
The blade of the weapon
matched the damaged section.
It's safe to assume it was damaged when
the victim was stabbed in the heart.
Which means the time of death was 2:50.
The problem is...
Yes.
This was a locked room.
Under the circumstances, the door
only opened about five centimeters,
making it impossible for
anyone to enter or exit.
The window we broke was locked
from the inside as well.
There were no signs that
it had been tampered with.
So how did the culprit leave the
room after killing Inokoshi-san?
At the very least, one
thing is clear, Inspector.
And what's that?
Takagi, how's the security
here at HISHIDA Hall?
We confirmed with the security staff
that aside from the front entrance
and reception desk of the hall,
all entrances including emergency
exits are locked from the inside.
According to the reception desk,
around 2:50 when the crime took place,
only three children left the building.
Children?
Those were our friends.
They left because they had someplace to be.
Don't interfere with the investigation.
Which means no one else entered or left.
This wasn't the work of
an outsider, Inspector.
I-I see. In other words...
Yes.
The culprit is among the staff, guests,
and 300 audience members inside
HISHIDA Hall right now.
Wh-What?
Well, that's for sure.
It was enough to leave a mark on the floor,
so they must have dragged the
chair with the body sitting in it.
So how did they get out afterwards?
Something was pressed against it.
I see. So that's how it is.
I see.
This is how they created the locked room.
Who is this person?
What's that? What about the locked room?
What's going on?
Start the event.
It's ten minutes past.
Is the Sleeping Kogoro not coming onstage?
Delay Mori-kun's lecture an hour?
Yes.
We were thinking about making that
announcement to the audience.
What are you talking about?
This is a murder.
The lecture should be canceled immediately.
But only the owner Hishida can make
the decision to cancel the event.
Then...
Where is this Hishida-san?
Actually, I haven't seen her.
I've been looking for her.
What?
But fortunately, the great detective
Mori Kogoro-sensei is here.
I trust he'll solve the case before long.
Well, actually...
As the president of the company running the
event, I'd hate to leave things like this.
Please solve this case, Mori-sensei.
Let me handle this.
The great detective Mori Kogoro will
solve this case within an hour.
Mori-kun, you can't go promising that.
Excuse me!
Delaying the lecture an
hour may be the right call.
What?
If the event is canceled
and the audience leaves,
it could be disastrous if
the culprit is among them.
Y-You're right.
Fine.
If you're so sure about this,
Mori-kun, you must know who did it.
Of course. I've even solved the
mystery of the locked room.
R-Really?!
That's amazing. He truly
is a great detective.
He just spoke with them briefly.
Yeah, he sure is.
Inspector, could you gather
all the concerned parties?
Got it. Takagi.
Yes, sir!
The locked room didn't use
a very complicated trick,
but I still don't know who did it.
And I'm worried that no one's seen the owner.
Yeah.
Before I explain my reasoning,
Chiba, have you checked everyone's alibi?
Yes.
I was able to confirm everyone's
alibi for 2:50, with one exception.
They were all gathered in the same place.
I see. Who's the one exception?
Reizei-san, the former
manager of HISHIDA Hall,
who was resting in his changing room alone.
Dad, d-do you think...?
Yes.
You did it, Reizei-san.
Your motive was the rage you
felt towards Inokoshi-san
after he brought you in line
like you were on a TV show.
Actually...
And you created this locked
room using your cane.
Creating a locked room with a cane?
But how?
I'll show you.
This room is constructed exactly
the same as Inokoshi-san's room.
Takagi, Chiba.
Yes, sir.
You alone left the room
and removed your cane just
before the door closed.
I see.
I'm sure it would open
more if you pushed harder,
but a body is rather heavy.
It's enough to create a
quick and dirty locked room.
Well, yeah.
But...
Excuse me!
Earlier I took Reizei-san
to his changing room.
Oh, thank you.
He was exhausted, and he's elderly.
Wouldn't it have been difficult
for him to do all that?
What?
You're right.
Sitting that large a victim in the chair,
dragging it across the room,
leaning it against the door,
and supporting it all with one cane
would've been rather difficult.
You're right. I can't imagine him doing it.
Impressive, Detective. I am astonished.
What?
I knew it.
I knew you'd spot my cane trick eventually.
But I killed someone else.
What?
Wh-What?!
Episode Preview
You verified my alibi, didn't you?
We've determined the time of the crime.
Episode Preview
Stay out of—
Wh-What is it, Mori-kun?
Episode Preview
I am the great detective...
Mori Kogoro!
Episode Preview
HISHIDA Hall Renovation Commemorative Lecture
The great detective Mori
Kogoro reveals his secrets!
Mori Kogoro!
Episode Preview
Mori Kogoro's Grand Lecture
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Mori
Kogoro's Grand Lecture, Part Two!"
Mori Kogoro's Grand Lecture
(Part Two)
Pocket Watch
Next Conan's hint.
A pocket watch.
Pocket Watch
Don't miss the next episode.
I wouldn't expect less from the
great detective Mori Kogoro.
Is that appropriate to say right now?
Don't miss the next episode.
He got involved in two
cases before he knew it.
Don't miss the next episode.