A murder occurred at a theater
holding a lecture titled "The Great
Detective Mori Kogoro Reveals His Secrets."
Panelist and actor Inokoshi Kenichiro-san
Inokoshi Kenichiro (48)
Actor
Panelist and actor Inokoshi Kenichiro-san
was found murdered inside
his locked changing room.
I knew it.
The body's keeping the door
shut instead of the lock.
In other words, this is...
Yeah.
It's a locked room mystery.
What?
The old man solved the locked room mystery,
and it seemed as though the
suspect had been identified.
But the suspect Reizei
Mokichi-san confessed to...
I knew you'd spot my cane trick eventually.
But I killed someone else.
Wha—
Wh-What?!
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
The old man's reasoning was right,
but in reality, there are two cases!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Mori Kogoro's Grand Lecture
(Part Two)
"Mori Kogoro's Grand Lecture, Part Two!"
Mori Kogoro's Grand Lecture
(Part Two)
Based on Reizei-san's confession,
Reizei Mokichi (70)
Former HISHIDA Hall Manager
Based on Reizei-san's confession,
an investigation of his crime and search
for corroborating evidence were conducted.
Reizei Mokichi (70)
Former HISHIDA Hall Manager
an investigation of his crime and search
for corroborating evidence were conducted.
Hishida Junko (50)
HISHIDA Hall Owner
Once again, we have an
announcement for our guests.
Due to certain circumstances,
With Inspector Megure's approval,
the start time of the lecture "The Great
Detective Mori Kogoro Reveals His Secrets"
With Inspector Megure's approval,
the start time of the old man's
lecture was delayed an hour.
the start time of the lecture "The Great
Detective Mori Kogoro Reveals His Secrets"
the start time of the old man's
lecture was delayed an hour.
and panel will be delayed one hour.
the start time of the old man's
lecture was delayed an hour.
Anyway, I'm terribly sorry
for the inconvenience,
but we appreciate your cooperation.
Tsukuba Mei (22)
Event Staff
I understand.
Tsukuba Mei (22)
Event Staff
I'm in a bit of a bind though.
Tsukuba Mei (22)
Event Staff
I'm in a bit of a bind though.
What do you mean?
I'm honored I was invited
to appear on the panel.
Tsukinogi Hideki (40)
Security Company President
I'm honored I was invited
to appear on the panel.
But I have plans immediately after this.
I can't accommodate a one hour delay.
I see.
And you verified my alibi, didn't you?
Of course.
In that case...
But that alibi applies only to
Inokoshi Kenichiro-san's murder.
Reizei may have confessed to
Hishida Junko-san's murder,
but we haven't even determined
the time of death—
Inspector!
We've determined the time of the crime.
I just couldn't. I just couldn't accept it!
Disregarding the achievements
of the late previous owner—
rather, her father, was her style.
Emergency Exit
I wanted her to understand, so we
continued our conversation there.
But...
You never give up. I've had enough of you.
Wh-What?!
Take a look at this and this.
Th-This is...
Wasn't Inokoshi-san's time of death 2:50?
Yes.
That's the time the victim's pocket watch
broken by the weapon was stopped at.
Which means Inokoshi-san
wasn't killed by Reizei-san.
In other words, there's another culprit.
I know it's a coincidence,
but this isn't good.
That's not all that's not good, Inspector.
What?
Have you forgotten?
The two murders took place
at practically the same time.
Aside from Reizei-san,
the people whose alibis we verified for
Inokoshi-san's murder were all innocent.
In other words...
Not a single person doesn't have an alibi.
Is it true that the owner
Hishida was killed as well?
And the culprit was...
Yeah.
That old man Reizei, the manager before me.
Did he kill Inokoshi-san, too?
Ujimori Yusaku (45)
HISHIDA Hall Manager
Tsunohazu Naoya (35)
Event Company President
No, that wasn't him.
Ujimori Yusaku (45)
HISHIDA Hall Manager
Tsunohazu Naoya (35)
Event Company President
No, that wasn't him.
Amagi Kosuke (28)
Event Staff
Furui Kiho (25)
Y-You mean there's another murderer?
Amagi Kosuke (28)
Event Staff
Furui Kiho (25)
Y-You mean there's another murderer?
No way.
A-Are you sure we shouldn't cancel the lecture?
If they don't arrest the culprit...
The great detective Mori
Kogoro reveals his secrets!
If they don't arrest the culprit...
Don't worry.
The great detective Mori
Kogoro reveals his secrets!
None other than the great detective
Sleeping Kogoro is here.
The great detective Mori
Kogoro reveals his secrets!
HISHIDA Hall
Renovation Commemorative Lecture
None other than the great detective
Sleeping Kogoro is here.
The great detective Mori
Kogoro reveals his secrets!
I'm sure he'll solve the case.
The great detective Mori
Kogoro reveals his secrets!
HISHIDA Hall
Renovation Commemorative Lecture
So focus on assisting the audience.
And don't mention the case until the
police explain the situation later.
U-Understood.
We'll be standing by.
Huh?
Come to think of it, where's Mei-chan?
Do you not care about
the game? It's starting.
I know, but we can't leave now.
We have less than thirty minutes
until the old man's lecture starts.
Maybe so, but we need to come with
an excuse to tell those kids.
You can handle that.
Jeez.
Excuse me!
Kogoro-no-ojisan asked me to do something.
So, do you have any leads?
Huh? Nope.
You're unbelievable.
What's that?
This wasn't here before, right?
Are those pages from a magazine or something?
Looks like they were torn out.
Judging by the quality of the paper and
print, they're probably from the same magazine.
There's been a guard standing in front of this
changing room since after the scene was examined.
So they reached in through the
window so they wouldn't be spotted?
The question is who left it
here, and for what purpose.
Not only that, but now, after the murder.
Could it be?
Found it.
I knew it.
Are they different pages
from the same magazine?
And the one underneath is...
Is it from a gravure article?
It's probably the first page after the cover.
I feel like there's some meaning
behind the way they're overlapped.
Either way, it could be some kind of message.
Yeah.
Hey.
If you found something, shouldn't
you let Mori-san know?
Right, little detective?
Huh? What about this?
I thought it might be some kind of message.
From who?
I don't know.
Jeez. You went off and found
something trivial again.
I'm sure it was just a prank.
I'm busy over here.
Stop bothering me.
Excuse me, Inspector. And?
We thought you solved the trick
used to create the locked room,
Cane?
but if Reizei-san's cane wasn't used to
prop up the chair with the body in it,
Cane?
then what was?
I've been thinking about that, too.
Have you figured it out?
No, I have no idea.
In any case, there isn't a
single person without an alibi.
We can't proceed with our investigation
if we can't solve that mystery.
They must've used something
in place of a cane.
In place of a cane?
That's it. They used that!
Hey, mister.
Maybe it's wrong to assume it
was a long object like a cane.
But recently they sell
telescoping canes, too.
What?
A telescoping cane?
This is why I can't stand amateurs!
Stay out of—
Wh-What is it, Mori-kun?
Th-That's it! I've figured it out, Inspector!
Really?
Tsukinogi Hideki-sama
Tsukinogi Hideki-san.
You've retired from bodyguarding,
but you still carry your gear with you.
Yes, that.
I'm talking about your
telescoping nightstick.
It's a habit I developed over the years.
I feel anxious without it.
What about it?
Don't play dumb.
You extended your nightstick,
pressed it against the back of the chair
supporting Inokoshi-san's body, tilted it,
Cane
and withdrew it while gradually closing
the door, creating the locked room.
Cane
and withdrew it while gradually closing
the door, creating the locked room.
Am I wrong?
Would you hand over your
nightstick, Tsukinogi-san?
We'd like to see if the end of your
nightstick matches the mark left on the chair.
That's fine with me.
But this was actually stolen from me.
Stolen?
I went to the bathroom
immediately after arriving.
I took it off and left it in this
changing room, and it went missing.
But when I just checked,
it had been returned.
I don't know who it was, but
I thought it was strange.
You think we'll believe that excuse?
In that case, don't I have an alibi?
I was with several others
when the murder took place.
Weren't you, the police,
the ones who verified that?
W-Well...
Forgive me, Mori-san, but
I'm disappointed in you.
Is this the best the great
Sleeping Kogoro can do?
Hey, about the time of the crime...
Wasn't that the time shown on the victim's
pocket watch that was broken by the weapon?
That's it!
They broke it beforehand and
set the hands pointing at 2:50.
Then they put it in the breast pocket
of the victim after they killed him.
That's right.
In other words, the murder actually
took place earlier than that.
Takagi, Chiba. Reconfirm
their alibis immediately.
Yes, sir.
At the originally determined time of 2:50,
Tsukinogi-san met with event
company president Tsunohazu-san
and staff member Amagi-san.
But no one saw Tsukinogi-san during
the ten minutes before that.
We spoke with the others, and
they all gave the same answer.
Can you explain that, Tsukinogi-san?
What can I say?
I simply didn't encounter anyone else.
That doesn't mean I did it.
Well, yes, but...
Then what's that shining on your lapel?
What?
Maybe it's a piece of glass from the
pocket watch broken by the weapon.
If it's a match,
there's no way a piece of
glass could've gotten on you
if the pocket watch was inside
the victim's jacket was broken,
so it must have been broken beforehand.
And the pieces could only have
gotten on the person who broke it.
Right, Mori-san?
What?
Uh... Yes, exactly.
I was just about to say
the same thing, Inspector.
Well, Tsukinogi-san?
I-I couldn't forgive him.
I couldn't forgive him!
According to Tsukinogi-san's confession,
one year ago while guarding Inokoshi-san,
he caught a woman stalking him.
Inokoshi Kenichiro (48) Domestic Violence?!
Total Denial
Domestic Violence Against Ex-girlfriend
one year ago while guarding Inokoshi-san,
he caught a woman stalking him.
Inokoshi Kenichiro (48) Domestic Violence?!
Total Denial
Domestic Violence Against Ex-girlfriend
She was actually Inokoshi-san's
ex-girlfriend who was seeking an apology
Inokoshi Kenichiro (48) Domestic Violence?!
Total Denial
Domestic Violence Against Ex-girlfriend
Inokoshi Kenichiro (48) Domestic Violence?!
Total Denial
Domestic Violence Against Ex-girlfriend
and damages for domestic violence.
Inokoshi Kenichiro (48) Domestic Violence?!
Total Denial
Domestic Violence Against Ex-girlfriend
Inokoshi Kenichiro (48) Domestic Violence?!
Total Denial
Domestic Violence Against Ex-girlfriend
After explaining the situation and
turning the woman over to the police,
not only was he fired by Inokoshi-san,
but rumors of his uselessness were spread.
Because of that, he and the
security company he manages
Tsukinogi Security  - Company Lack of Security Abilities
Because of that, he and the
security company he manages
Numerous Issues - Sloppy Personnel Dispatch
Because of that, he and the
security company he manages
Inability to Fulfill Duties - No Guarantee of Safety
Because of that, he and the
security company he manages
would be forced into bankruptcy soon.
Inability to Fulfill Duties - No Guarantee of Safety
Bankruptcy
would be forced into bankruptcy soon.
You did it, Mei-chan!
You beat the great detective!
She's kind of amazing, isn't she?
Huh? Yeah, she sure is.
Her detective skills certainly
are impressive, but...
We knew you could do it.
It's just a coincidence.
There's no need to be modest.
Something bothering you?
No, really.
In any case, the two murders were solved,
and the old man's lecture was to be held.
Hanai Rika (23)
MC
Thank you for waiting, everyone.
Hanai Rika (23)
MC
Thank you for waiting, everyone.
The HISHIDA Hall renovation
commemorative lecture,
Mori Kogoro
presented by the Sleeping
Kogoro, Mori Kogoro himself,
Mori Kogoro
"The Great Detective Mori Kogoro
Reveals His Secrets" will now begin.
HISHIDA Hall Renovation Commemorative Lecture
The great detective Mori
Kogoro reveals his secrets!
"The Great Detective Mori Kogoro
Reveals His Secrets" will now begin.
I'm Hanai Rika, Nichiuri TV announcer,
and I'll be your MC today.
Rika-pon!
Thank you.
Now let's bring the star of the day onstage.
Everyone, please put your hands together
for the great detective Mori Kogoro!
Thank you, thank you.
You can do it, Dad.
Red leather, yellow leather.
Focus, focus.
Thank you for waiting!
As I was just introduced,
I am the great detective
Mori Kogoro!
HISHIDA Hall Renovation Commemorative Lecture
The great detective Mori
Kogoro reveals his secrets!
Mori Kogoro!
HISHIDA Hall Renovation Commemorative Lecture
The great detective Mori
Kogoro reveals his secrets!
I should redeem myself here.
It's no use. I can't sleep.
The case has already been solved,
so I won't be sleeping today.
What?
Seriously? I was looking forward to this!
I'll tell you all about it eventually.
The subject of today's lecture
is a great detective's secrets,
and as such, I will be telling you
all about my abundant experience.
Good. Nice one, Dad.
Then another panelist arrived.
Anyway, that's enough from me.
Mori Kogoro
Thank you for listening.
That was the great detective Mori Kogoro-san.
Mori Kogoro
Let's give him another round of applause.
Thank you, thank you!
After a short break,
we'll move onto the panel.
The audience was informed that
due to certain circumstances,
panelists Inokoshi Kenichiro-san and
Tsukinogi Hideki-san
were no longer able to attend.
The event organizers decided
to keep quiet about the case
until the police made their
official announcement.
Thanks for waiting.
Mom!
Sounds like you had some trouble.
I just heard the news.
But thanks to Mori-sensei,
the cases were solved.
I know the circumstances are unusual,
but everyone loved the lecture.
Keep up the same energy during
the panel, Kisaki-sensei.
Sure.
But doesn't that mean it'll be
just the two of us going onstage?
Something wrong with that?
Dad!
No, as long as you don't
have a problem with it.
Mom...
Well, actually...
About that...
Part 2
What are the great
detective's secrets?!
A new heroine enquires!
Tsukuba Mei
What?!
Part 2
What are the great
detective's secrets?!
A new heroine enquires!
Tsukuba Mei
Part 2
What are the great
detective's secrets?!
A new heroine enquires!
Tsukuba Mei
I'm Tsukuba Mei.
I look forward to working with you.
Episode Preview
We're looking for pages
torn from this magazine.
Episode Preview
They should be someplace visible.
All right! I'm not sure what's
going on, but let's do this!
Episode Preview
Yeah!
It seems you have some questions
for the Sleeping Kogoro.
Episode Preview
Oh, yes.
It's actually about a murder that happened
at a certain college one year ago.
Episode Preview
What?
Mori Kogoro's Grand Lecture
(Part Three)
The next episode of Conan is "Mori
Kogoro's Grand Lecture, Part Three!"
Mori Kogoro's Grand Lecture
(Part Three)
Kisaki Eri
Next Conan's hint.
Kisaki Eri!
Kisaki Eri
Don't miss the next episode.
I knew she'd show up.
Curious?
Don't miss the next episode.
Of course.
Then we'll find out next week.
Don't miss the next episode.
I'm sure we will.