Sergeant Momosaki Toko, who went to
karaoke with Naeko Miike after work,
was found dead the next morning.
Momosaki Toko (28)
Transportation Department
(Sergeant)
was found dead the next morning.
Next to her body was a bent 100 yen coin,
and there were traces suggesting that Sergeant
Momosaki had been pointing at something.
Yagi Shiori (28)
Transportation Department
(Lieutenant)
Then, Lieutenant Yagi who was at the karaoke
box with Miike and Sergeant Momosaki...
Yagi Shiori (28)
Transportation Department
(Lieutenant)
Then, Lieutenant Yagi who was at the karaoke
box with Miike and Sergeant Momosaki...
I asked one of your colleagues from work.
They said you'd be here
if you weren't at home.
Japan's police truly are exceptional.
I knew it!
You're the one who killed Toko!
And next to her body is a 100
yen coin stuck inside her phone.
Just like the one found next
to the body of the officer
discovered in the park this
morning, it was deliberately bent.
100 yen coins are engraved
with a cherry blossom.
It goes without saying that the cherry
blossom is the emblem of the Japanese police.
Th-Then this is...
Yes, without a doubt.
This case is a serial murder
of female police officers.
Furthermore, Lieutenant Miyamoto Yumi, who
noticed something about both their bodies...
I know I took the mini patrol car,
but since I'm helping the
investigation, go easy on me.
Wh-Who's there?!
Oh, just my imagination.
Jeez. I'm jumping at shadows.
Let's see. This area is...
The rhythm on my lips is footloose!
The rhythm of my detective
skills is perfect!
A black shadow closes in on Yumi!
How far will the case's darkness spread?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Target: MPD Transportation Department
(Part Three)
"Target: MPD Transportation
Department, Part Three!"
Target: MPD Transportation Department
(Part Three)
Well, I just got home.
I couldn't have seen any suspicious figures.
Then do you know anything about
this female police officer?
I haven't seen her.
I see.
Was she pushed from that apartment building?
Yes. That's what we believe at this time.
How horrifying.
And there was that incident
just the other day, too.
"That incident?"
Did something else happen at that building?
Remember the woman who committed suicide
by jumping from a nearby building?
I heard she was a resident of that building.
Suicide?
Yes.
Don't the police know
more about it than I do?
When no foul play is suspected, the MPD
isn't called to investigate the case.
The local jurisdiction
investigates it instead.
When did that suicide occur?
I believe it was a week ago.
A week ago?
I'm sorry, but could you tell
us more about the incident?
Do you know the name of the woman who died?
No, I don't know who she was.
What was that?
It came from that apartment building.
Sh-She's dead!
There's a dead policewoman!
What?
Thank you!
That mini patrol car... Could it be?
Yu...
Yumi?
No!
You're kidding.
Yumi...
Yumi!
Huh?
Whoops. I fell asleep.
Y-Yumi?
Sorry!
Sorry, I forgot to tell you.
Yumi-san asked me for a favor.
Yumi-san?
What are you doing here?
Oh, good timing.
Uh, okay.
Apparently Yumi-san noticed something
and asked to lie on the ground
in the same position as the body.
Come on, please?
You don't mind, right? You and I are friends.
Yeah, but we're not even that close.
Oh, please. That close?
You're such a naughty boy, Takagi-kun.
I'd better report this to Miwako.
No, wait!
I forgot the specifics of our conversation,
but in any case, it seemed
like Yumi-san had an idea,
and forensics had finished examining the
scene, so I thought it'd be all right.
I didn't think she'd fall asleep.
Did we scare you?
Yeah, sort of.
I was up all night playing
mahjong, so I'm so sleepy.
Anyway, sorry I forgot to call you.
So, what did you notice?
When I saw the photo of
Yagi's body you sent me,
I realized what was in the direction
Yagi forced herself to face.
Since we drive past this
alleyway on our patrols,
anyone from the Transportation
Department would know what's there.
Yagi faced this direction before she
died because she knew that was here.
She wanted us to focus on that.
A no parking sign?
What does it mean?
That sign's the only obvious
thing in that direction.
Sergeant Momosaki, who was killed first,
was pointing at a swing set in the park.
What does that have to do with this?
Try to remember, Miwako.
What else was in the direction Momosaki
pointed besides the swing set?
What?
Besides the swing set?
What else was there?
There was something!
A no parking sign!
That's right. Momosaki wasn't
pointing at the swing set,
but the no parking sign behind it.
Since Yagi knew the same
sign happened to be here,
she forced herself to face in its direction.
Yagi realized what message Momosaki
was trying to convey with that sign,
and this happened when
she went to confirm it.
But she was trying to tell us
something until the very end.
But that would mean the no parking sign...
...is some kind of direct hint to
the identity of the suspect.
Something that led Lieutenant Yagi here.
It must be the three men Yumi-san mentioned.
The three traffic violators Sergeant Momosaki
and Lieutenant Yagi arrested one week ago.
One of them must have parked illegally.
About that...
Aono was using his phone while
driving and didn't have his license.
Aono Kengo
Aono was using his phone while
driving and didn't have his license.
Akamine was driving a motorcycle
against traffic without a helmet.
Akamine Manji
Akamine was driving a motorcycle
against traffic without a helmet.
Shiroyama was driving with an expired
inspection and wasn't wearing his seat belt.
Shiroyama Yuzo
Shiroyama was driving with an expired
inspection and wasn't wearing his seat belt.
None of them parked illegally.
Then why point at a no parking sign?
Who knows?
If anything, I guess their
names contain the characters
for the red, blue, and
white used in the sign.
But that doesn't tell
us which of them did it.
Or how Yagi arrived here.
None of them have present
addresses in this building.
Come to think of it, what about
the building's security cameras?
Apparently this building doesn't
have security cameras installed.
The opinions of the residents are divided.
Oh, my.
And I just received a call from
the forensic investigators.
They figured out the last number
Lieutenant Yagi tried to call.
Well, we may have figured it out,
but calling the number 7155
didn't connect us to anyone.
Perhaps her mind was hazy since
she was on the brink of death.
No, she wasn't trying to call that number.
She pressed the call button because she
wanted to preserve the number 7155.
That way it would be left in the phone's
records even if the suspect broke her phone.
7155... Seven thousand
one hundred fifty-five?
Seven-one-five-five...
It doesn't seem to be a play on words.
Maybe it's the request number for a song.
They went to karaoke just
before they met the suspect.
Didn't Miike go with them?
M-Miike?
Could you call her and check?
Yeah, but she seems like her memory
would be worse than a cat's.
A cat? Mike (calico)?
Oh, it's just a nickname.
Cats have bad memories?
What? Isn't that what they say?
No, no.
Why am I thinking about that now?
Oh, right. Takagi-kun.
It's still unclear how it's connected,
but a week ago, one of this building's
residents committed suicide.
Really? Sounds like we should ask
the local jurisdiction about that.
That girl in the Transportation Department
might look like my first love, but...
She's someone else.
I can't keep holding onto that forever.
Miyamoto-san
Incoming Call
Reject   Answer
Miike here.
What? 7155?
A karaoke request number?
I don't remember every song everyone sang.
You've got the brain of a cat after all.
What? What does that mean?
You know, like how people
say cats have small brains.
It's not brains, it's foreheads.
A person might say their yard is the size of
a cat's forehead to mean it's really small.
And these days, you don't enter numbers
to request songs at karaoke places.
What? Seriously?
Some of them even use phone apps.
In any case, let Miwako know if you
think of anything relating to 7155.
Got it.
But we're both officers of the
Transportation Department.
You should let the violent
crimes unit handle the case
and go home and get some sleep,
Yumi-san.
Yumi... Yumi... Yumi!
We'll stay to canvas the
area a little longer.
Yumi-san, you really should go home.
Okay. Later.
So, what will you do?
Between me and Shiratori-kun,
we can probably handle this area.
In that case, I'll go ask the local
jurisdiction about that suicide.
Please do.
Then I'll go the park where
the first murder took place.
I might find something related
to 7155 in that park.
Good idea. Thanks.
See you for mahjong this weekend.
I'm falling asleep the second I get home.
You're finally back.
We saw it on the news.
Who are you guys?
We heard two lady cops were
killed one after another.
So we were guarding your
mini patrol car for you.
You owe us a fee.
What? Are you stupid?
What's your problem? You're just
a miniskirt officer anyway!
Should a cop be speaking like
that to a law-abiding citizen?
Excuse me. They're with me.
It seems they can't hold their liquor.
Just imagine they're speaking
nonsense and ignore them.
What? Who are—
You're with me, right?
Uh, yeah. I'm starting to feel like I am.
Then perhaps it would be best if
you got some fresh air to sober up.
Y-Yes! I'll do that!
Sorry for the trouble.
No problem. Thanks, I think.
Tell your friends to take care.
And tell them not to drink so much.
I will.
Brother, protect Yumi-tan! You have to!
Wh-Who's there?!
Oh, just my imagination.
Jeez. I'm jumping at shadows.
She doesn't look like a woman
who needs protection to me.
7155... 7155...
I don't see anything.
Huh?
Detective Chiba, what are
you doing here at this hour?
C-Conan-kun! I could ask you the same thing.
I saw the body of the
policewoman here this morning.
At first I thought she was
pointing at the swing set,
but I thought she might be pointing at
the no parking sign behind it instead.
That's why I came here.
The same sign was near the second
female officer who was murdered.
So he's been to the crime
scene in Haido City, too.
Both of the victims belonged to
the Transportation Department,
so you suspect the traffic
violators they arrested, right?
So I thought there might be some
meaning behind the road signs.
Sato-san and Yumi-san said the same thing.
But we couldn't figure out anything else.
Did you come to confirm their suspicions?
There's that, and we also determined
that the second victim Lieutenant Yagi
entered the numbers 7155 into
her phone just before she died.
I thought there might be something relating
to those numbers at this park, so I came here.
7155?
Seven thousand five hundred fifty-five,
seven-one and five-five...
71... 55...
Wait a minute. What does the order
of those numbers mean again?
Conan-kun, it's already after eight.
Don't you need to go home?
I told Ran-neechan I'd be staying
at the professor's house tonight,
but my skateboard ran out of batteries.
I know. Could you drive me
to the professor's house?
What?
Come to think of it, do I
have Sato-san's phone number?
Sato-san
Miyamoto-san
Momosaki-san
Yagi-san
Search contacts
Takagi-san
Chiba-kun
Sato-san
Miyamoto-san
Momosaki-san
Yagi-san
Search contacts
Chiba-kun's phone number...
Takagi-san
Chiba-kun
Sato-san
Miyamoto-san
Momosaki-san
Yagi-san
Search contacts
Takagi-san
Chiba-kun
Sato-san
Miyamoto-san
Momosaki-san
Yagi-san
Search contacts
I haven't called him since our class reunion.
Excuse me.
I left my car parked with the
trunk open in an alleyway.
A stray cat jumped in,
and it won't stop crying.
Could you search inside my car for me?
I'm allergic to cats, so I can't touch it.
Huh? Sure.
7155... No parking signs...
Damn. I nearly have the answer, too...
By the way, Yumi-san told me.
She said you studied road signs together.
Huh? Yeah, I guess.
I had no idea Japanese road signs
were based off English ones.
I doubt most people know.
When I said that to Yumi-san,
she responded that it was only natural for
a Transportation Department officer to know,
that there was no way she wouldn't
know such common knowledge.
You think that's true?
England...
Japanese road signs are
based off English ones...
That's it! So that's how it is!
Listen, Detective Chiba...
Oh, sorry. Someone's calling.
Hello? Hello?
Hey, what are you doing?!
Damn! You had two phones?
Hello? Hello?
Ch-Chiba-kun...
Episode Preview
You know who the culprit is?
For the dignity of the
police, we must arrest him!
Episode Preview
Yes, sir!
The Sleeping Kogoro's adviser...
Episode Preview
I suppose I'm not surprised.
There are a lot of patrol
cars driving around.
Episode Preview
So I recommend you release me
immediately and turn yourself in!
Episode Preview
Target: MPD Transportation Department
(Part Four)
The next episode of Conan is "Target: MPD
Transportation Department, Part Four!"
Target: MPD Transportation Department
(Part Four)
Twinkle Twinkle Little Star.
Next Conan's hint!
Twinkle Twinkle Little Star!
Twinkle Twinkle Little Star.
Don't miss the next episode
Using your phone while driving is dangerous.
Exactly! But for now, just help me!
Don't miss the next episode
Hurry, Chiba-kun!