Welcome.
This is the only place
that can grant your wish.
Oh, yeah?
Wada Tatsumi (39)
Unemployed
My wish, huh?
Wada Tatsumi (39)
Unemployed
Surely you came here because you knew that.
You simply have to believe.
As long as you follow my instructions...
I'll commit the perfect crime, right?
Exactly. I'm like a modern
day Professor Moriarty.
Providing people like you with
the perfect crime is my job.
I see...
The rhythm on my lips is footloose!
The rhythm of my detective
skills is perfect!
A world-famous planned crime!
The old man is selected for
an undercover operation!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
An Encouragement of the Perfect Crime
"An Encouragement of the Perfect Crime!"
Yes, that's correct.
Mori Detective Agency
Several strange cases have
occurred in the city recently.
I see. What's this?
Marriage fraud, bank robbery, and burglary.
Though they seem unrelated at first,
these cases have something in common.
Take a look at these notes.
What's this?
They look like instruction
manuals for crimes.
According to the arrested culprits,
they purchased the plans from a man
calling himself a criminal adviser.
That's what's thriving in the underworld now?
Said criminal adviser is a vigilant man.
We only recently determined his location.
So we have a request for you.
What is it? Spit it out.
An undercover operation, huh?
You'd be more like an adviser.
Since it's a special case, we'd
appreciate it if you joined us.
I see.
It takes a talented adviser
to take down an adviser.
I hope he's got some decent advice to give.
What are you doing here?
Since it's an undercover case, I thought
we'd seem less like cops with me around.
What kind of criminal
brings a child with him?
Why not let him come, Mori-san?
When Conan-kun's around, the investigation
always seems to go mysteriously well.
His office is in there?
Yes, definitely.
Let's go.
Yes, ma'am. Mori-san,
we appreciate your help.
Hamanaka Planning
My name is Sato. I made an
appointment the other day.
Hamanaka Planning
Welcome.
This is the only place
that can grant your wish.
You're the one we've heard about?
Yes.
I am the modern day Professor James Moriarty.
I am Hamanaka Misao, criminal adviser.
Hamanaka Misao (57)
Criminal Adviser
I am Hamanaka Misao, criminal adviser.
What does a criminal adviser do?
You're asking that now?
Isn't that what you're looking for?
Perfect Crime Manual - Showa Criminal History - Heisei Criminal History - Criminal Chronology - Japan's Unsolved Cases
In this office are all
documents related to crime,
Perfect Crime Manual - Showa Criminal History - Heisei Criminal History - Criminal Chronology - Japan's Unsolved Cases
and all the tools you need to carry one out.
In other words, as long as
you follow my instructions,
you will be able to commit the perfect crime.
What?
Aren't you the famous detective Mori Kogoro?
Which means yours companions must be,
judging by their appearance, police officers.
Of course he figured it out.
Hamanaka-san, could we speak with you?
Very well.
I've always wanted to speak
with a detective or the police.
You can start by taking a look
at these instruction manuals.
Let me see.
I did indeed write these.
What? You admit it?
What point is there in lying about that?
I produced all of these.
They are undeniably blueprints
for crimes written by me.
Plots for novels.
Plots for novels?
Plots are like the plan for
a novel or play, right?
Yeah. They're like a summary
or framework of a story.
You mean...
A plan for a crime.
Indeed. I sell those plots.
Primarily plots for crime novels.
What's this?
My price list.
Price list?
I've ranked them according
to the nature of the crime.
My selling point is the variety I offer.
I offer plots all kinds of crimes.
Murder, robbery, fraud...
There's even one called
"thumbtack in slipper."
Online Message
Prank Call
Thumbtack in Slipper
There's even one called
"thumbtack in slipper."
I offer an exhaustive list of crimes from
murder to light offenses in complete versions,
simple versions, abridged versions,
and first half only versions.
What's a first half only version?
I'm meeting the needs of my customers.
Some of them said they wanted my
plots but couldn't afford them.
So why did this person get caught?
This is a simple version
of a bank robbery plot.
Ah, he made the mistake of
not acquiring a plasma torch.
He was arrested because he cheaped out
and failed to break into the vault.
How about this one?
This is an abridged version
of a purse snatching plot.
The culprit was simply too fat to run away.
Then what about this first half
only version of a burglary?
They were arrested easily.
I remember that case well.
I can't believe they committed a
burglary without wearing gloves.
That's it?
Sounds like everyone who follows
your plots gets arrested.
You were lying when you said
you sold perfect crimes.
Th-That's not true!
There are plenty of criminals
who haven't been arrested.
I sold a plot that's been
unsolved for several years.
Could you tell us more about that case?
Unfortunately, I cannot do that.
I can't just give away my
customers' information.
Maybe so, but we can't just let it go.
I wish I could help you, but trust
is essential in my business.
No hard feelings.
Hold it right there.
Don't forget that I'm just
a crime novel adviser.
I simply sell ideas for novels.
I'm not committing any crimes.
You understand that, don't you?
Furthermore, I don't encourage
my customers to commit crimes.
The plots laid out on the table
are all works of fiction.
The characters, organizations,
and names are products of my imagination and
bear no relation to actual persons or events.
Why, you...
In other words, the police
can't lay a finger on me.
What?
Hamanaka Misao, you're
under arrest for abetment.
No matter what you say, your
plots are causing actual crimes.
You're guilty of abetment.
B-But...
Were you working as a criminal
adviser without even knowing that?
Well, I...
Now confess.
What?
The crimes you're involved it.
Tell us about every last one.
Y-You can't be serious.
Are you sure?
If you don't cooperate now, you'll regret it.
How you're treated after incarceration,
testimony during the trial,
the impression made during bail hearings...
A lot of things that will shape your
life are about to happen to you.
Hey, Takagi. Are you sure
you needed an adviser?
Yeah...
Well? What's it going to be?
Transfer complete.
Roger that. Make a backup.
Got it.
We've obtained information on five cases.
Of those five, three are unsolved,
and two are currently in progress.
We found detailed information on
the suspects and their methods.
Takagi-kun just sent you the data.
Got it.
We've received strong information
relating to a number of unsolved cases!
This is a rare opportunity for us!
Call on all officers and
arrest all the suspects!
Have everyone head to the scene!
Yes, sir!
Don't move!
Who are you?
Suspects confirmed! Arrest them!
Suspect arrested!
Hoshio-chan's Kidnapping and Hostage Case
Solved
Suspect arrested!
Takarazuka's Treasure Murder Case
Solved
Suspect arrested!
Case of the Lop-Eared Rabbit's Walk
Solved
Suspect arrested!
Attempted Rock N' Roller Cosplay Case
Solved
All right!
Only one case remains!
Project No. 980
Ishigami Takashi's Revenge Plan
Hamanaka Planning
Ishigami Takashi's Revenge Plan.
Project No. 980
Ishigami Takashi's Revenge Plan
Hamanaka Planning
The suspect's name is Wada Tatsumi,
forty-eight years old, single.
He has three previous offenses
and is currently unemployed.
He was just recently released from prison.
The scheduled time of his
crime is today at 4 PM.
Since it's just after three now,
we don't have much time left.
The plot is a complete version of a murder.
The method is to use an odorless
gas to blow up an entire building.
A gas explosion?
There's even a blueprint
showing a remote detonator.
Does he plan to blow up the evidence, too?
Ishigami Takashi was Wada's superior at
a company he worked for ten years ago.
Apparently he believed he was
responsible for Wada's firing.
The police are already heading to the
suspect's house and the target's office.
The case should be resolved soon.
Police!
What?!
Wada's apartment is empty.
The suspect isn't here.
Damn! Keep an eye on the area.
Ishigami Industries
How are things over there?
We haven't seen the suspect.
We've secured the alleged target Ishigami-san,
but there hasn't been any unusual activity.
The suspect Wada is attempting
to cause a gas explosion.
Search every nook and cranny
for hidden gas cylinders.
Got it.
3:30 already.
According to the plot, a lot of people
will get caught up in the explosion.
We must do whatever it takes
to stop the explosion.
Got it.
Nothing was found at
Ishigami-san's workplace.
What's going on?
Maybe he's not carrying out his plan yet?
The scheduled date is today.
On top of that, we haven't
determined the suspect's location.
I don't think we should be optimistic.
Where is it? Where is the detonator?
Gas Density
We're running out of time.
We need to find clues from here quickly.
I told you, as long as my customers
follow my instructions,
they can commit the perfect crime.
Remember! What did you and Wada discuss?
What did we discuss?
Tell me every last word
that was said. Got it?
A-All right, but I did most of the talking.
Was there anything about him that seemed odd?
Odd?
Come to think of it...
Surely you came here because you knew that.
You simply have to believe.
As long as you follow my instructions...
I'll commit the perfect crime, right?
For some reason he knew my catchphrase.
He came to buy one of your plots.
It's not that odd that he knew.
I suppose not.
Oh, right. He said he wanted the detonation
to be controlled remotely instead of automatic.
Perhaps he wants to deal
the killing blow himself.
Does he hate his target that much?
I believe so.
Gas Density
Wada clearly stated that his
target was Ishigami-san, right?
Yes.
I write my plots after listening
to my customers' requests.
Then Ishigami-san is definitely his target.
Isn't guarding the target and waiting for
the suspect to arrive our best option?
Detective Takagi is right,
but something's off...
Well, I guess I've got to do it.
No forewarning again...
Th-This is...
The Sleeping Kogoro.
I have a few questions for you.
Gas Density
Explosion Ready
First, why do you believe he came to see you?
Why? Because of my excellence, obviously.
What?
Fine.
Let's assume he heard of
your reputation somewhere.
When you spoke with him, did you think
there was anything strange about him?
I'm not sure.
I find it strange.
He may have been fired,
but why did he plan such
an elaborate assassination?
You're right.
You may hate someone for firing you, but
usually you wouldn't want to kill them.
He paid a lot of money for it, too.
Yeah.
Are you certain?
What?
I've been doing this job a long time.
The actions of a criminal hardly fall
within what's considered sensible.
A long time? How long
have you been doing this?
W-Well, at the very least, I
think it's been about ten years.
Hey!
Conan-kun?
What is it?
Did you figure something out?
That's definitely it.
9/13 Fired from Ishigami Industries
8/20 Purchased plot from Hamanaka Planning
9/5 Attack on Beika Finance
If my reasoning is correct...
9/13 Fired from Ishigami Industries
8/20 Purchased plot from Hamanaka Planning
9/5 Attack on Beika Finance
Conan-kun?
9/13 Fired from Ishigami Industries
8/20 Purchased plot from Hamanaka Planning
9/5 Attack on Beika Finance
I was wondering where the bathroom is.
The bathroom's at the end of the hallway.
Thanks.
There's no time.
Mori-san.
Do you recall the cases you
plotted seven years ago?
What?
Judging by your reaction, you've forgotten
about the robbery that took place
seven years ago on this day,
for which Wada Tatsumi was arrested.
What?
Does Hamanaka have something
to do with Wada's arrest?
I remember now!
He attacked some black market
lenders in Beika City!
That's right.
It's the plot for the robbery
you wrote seven years ago.
Y-You mean...
According to police documents,
after attacking the black market
lenders that were his target,
the high performance security
cameras of the shopping mall
along his escape route
captured his escape vehicle,
his license plate number,
and even the driver Wada's face.
It was your mistake for failing to
take into account the shopping mall.
Wada probably believed it was
your fault that he was arrested.
The fault of the sloppy plot you wrote.
Explosion Ready
Gas Density
You're right. That was my mistake.
In other words, this is what happened.
Haido Prison
Wada Tatsumi recently finished his
sentence and was released from prison.
Haido Prison
Several days ago, he visited your office
for the first time in seven years.
Haido Prison
Several days ago, he visited your office
for the first time in seven years.
However, you didn't remember
the robbery or Wada himself.
What's why he chose to act.
He remembered your catchphrase.
He was that fixated on you.
In other words...
The target isn't Ishigami-san.
No.
His target is you!
What?
Th-Then the detonator is...
Yes.
The detonator is here!
H-Hello?
Hamanaka, you know who I am, don't you?
You're Wada Tatsumi-san.
Do you know why I called you?
N-No, I...
I wanted to hear your voice one last time.
What? W-Wait!
Farewell, you fraud.
Damn. Why isn't it exploding?
It won't explode, Wada-san.
Who are you?
We just shut off the gas,
and the detonator you installed
in the air purifier was removed.
You were first arrested
for a burglary, right?
When I examined the entrance
to Hamasaki-san's office,
I found signs of lock picking.
Knowing the detonator was hidden in his
office narrowed down the hiding places.
In order to make a gas
heavier than air explode,
the detonator needed to be as
close to the ground as possible.
Damn.
But how did you know I was here?
Because you asked to make the detonator
remote controlled instead of automatic.
That's how you'd take your revenge.
So I thought you'd be someplace
you could see the explosion.
I lost.
Wada Tatsumi, you're under
arrest for attempted murder!
Nice work, Mori-san.
Oh, you know...
Thanks to you, we were able
to solve five cases at once.
Ultimately, Hamasaki's perfect crimes
turned out to be armchair theories.
I know.
If it means making people hate you enough
to want to kill you, it's not worth it.
I suppose it was unfortunate for him
that you had a great adviser like me.
Who do you think you are?
Episode Preview
Bocchan Restaurant
Bocchan Restaurant?
Episode Preview
Bocchan Restaurant
Now you've done it, you dastardly red shirt!
Episode Preview
Please, Yamaarashi-san.
You suspect the president? What a fool.
Episode Preview
The sun may forgive you, but I will not!
The young master's sense of justice
is this old Kiyo's pride and joy.
Episode Preview
Young master? Kiyo?
Welcome to Bocchan Restaurant
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "Welcome
to Bocchan Restaurant, Part One!"
Welcome to Bocchan Restaurant
(Part One)
Stray Cat
Next Conan's hint!
A stray cat!
Stray Cat
Don't miss the next episode.
We're off next week, and...
The roadshow is on Friday, then we're on
two weeks back to back! Don't miss it!
Don't miss the next episode.