Anyway, their donuts are made with soy pulp,
so they're low sugar.
Not only that, but they look amazing.
But aren't they fried in oil?
Won't it make us fat?
They've got holes in the
middle. We'll be fine.
They said they're low calorie
since they're low sugar.
Eat too much of anything,
and you'll still get fat.
We've arrived.
Well? Pretty tasteful, right?
Find the question that solves the mystery!
Apply miraculous detective skills
to the secrets of the heart!
A fashionable café known for its donuts!
What shocking truth will the
high school detective reveal?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Murder at the Townhouse Café
"Murder at the Townhouse Café!"
Wow.
What a pretty yard.
Seriously.
It's beautiful.
Yeah.
A place like this is sure to look amazing!
I know, right?
Our staff member Sakai takes
great care of our yard.
Tomita Satoshi (37)
Manager
Our staff member Sakai takes
great care of our yard.
It's truly impressive. I'm proud of it.
Tomita Satoshi (37)
Manager
It's truly impressive. I'm proud of it.
Yes, it really is wonderful.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Mister, do you work here?
Ah, my apologies.
I'm Tomita, the manager.
I'll show you to your seats.
This way, please.
What should we get?
Didn't we come here to eat donuts?
Of course we'll eat donuts as well.
What can I get you?
What do you recommend?
Our soy pulp donuts are our number one item.
They're low sugar and made to order,
so you can enjoy them fresh.
But judging by the state of things, this
place's popularity suddenly spiked and waned.
Sir.
I brought the soy pulp
out of the storage room.
Sakai Chitose (19)
Part-time Employee
I brought the soy pulp
out of the storage room.
Thank you.
Sakai Chitose (19)
Part-time Employee
All right. I've decided.
I'd like a hot Darjeeling tea.
Also, one shibazuke and cream
donut, two matcha and mayo donuts,
two chocolate dream donuts, one plain
donut, and one molasses crepe parfait.
How about you, Ran?
I'll have the same thing.
What? The same thing?
Conan-kun, you'll have orange juice, right?
Uh, yeah.
Thank you for waiting.
Wow, they're beautiful!
They look delicious.
Don't you agree, Ran?
Yeah, but we may have ordered too much.
Let's dig in!
Sakai, I'm counting on you.
Yes, sir.
Thanks.
Understood.
Conan-kun?
Is something wrong?
No. I'm not sure which to eat.
Then how about this one?
I had a bite, but it's good.
Isn't that the donut you just ate?
Say, "Ah."
An indirect kiss...
Right? Good, isn't it?
Yeah.
These are lighter than
expected, don't you think?
Yeah. I could eat these forever.
There's sourness and saltiness
behind the sweetness, too.
Yeah.
The sound of frying donuts really
whets the appetite, doesn't it?
Hey.
What is it, Sonoko?
Ran, doesn't he seem kind of suspicious?
You're right.
He keeps looking around
everywhere. He seems restless.
And doesn't that customer seem odd, too?
It's more like he's observing
donuts, not eating them.
There isn't a single decent
customer in this place.
What was that beeping sound?
I heard it, too.
I'll take your empty plates.
I'm stuffed.
I can't eat anymore.
You ate too much, Sonoko.
Speaking of eating too much,
it looks like he did, too.
He's having a pretty rough time.
I wonder if he'll make it to the bathroom.
Anyway, those were pretty good.
They seemed pretty high-level
for low sugar donuts.
But they're still fried.
Should we have eaten that much?
We'll be fine. That's why
they're low sugar, right?
What was that?
Conan-kun?
What's wrong?
I-It's an emergency.
The manager...
Are you all right?
Sir?
Kid, what's going on?
The manager collapsed in the bathroom.
What?
Was he struck?
The weapon was probably that mop.
The culprit used those gloves on the ground
to avoiding leaving fingerprints behind.
Or could it be...?
In any case, let's call an
ambulance and the police.
You're right.
The victim is Tomita Satoshi-san,
the owner of this café.
He was struck on the back of the head with
a blunt object while in the café's bathroom.
At that time, these people
were inside the café.
You girls again?
Sorry.
Could you tell us your names?
Yes.
My name is Sakai Chitose. I'm a student.
As you can see, I work here part-time.
Furukawa Yoshihisa (34)
Customer
My name is Furukawa Yoshihisa.
Furukawa Yoshihisa (34)
Customer
I happened to be having tea here.
Furukawa Yoshihisa (34)
Customer
I happened to be having tea here.
There's nothing suspicious about me.
Nonaka Kenji (42)
Café Manager
My name is Nonaka Kenji.
Nonaka Kenji (42)
Café Manager
I operate a café in this neighborhood.
Nonaka Kenji (42)
Café Manager
I operate a café in this neighborhood.
That's right. Come to think of it,
you always come to scout out our café
and steal our recipes, don't you?
What are you talking about?
My recipes are the product
of my own creativity.
No one cares about that.
You gathered us here because you think
one of us is the culprit, don't you?
We haven't said that yet.
We just thought we'd ask you some questions.
For someone to attack the
manager in the bathroom,
they would've had to pass through this café
where you could have seen them, correct?
Yes.
The only person who left this room while
the manager was in the bathroom was...
Nonaka-san, I think.
H-Hold on.
I didn't do it.
But you're the only one who left his seat.
I just happened to go the bathroom then.
More importantly, Furukawa is
way more suspicious than me.
He seemed nervous and had been behaving
oddly since he entered the café.
I-I'm not nervous.
Now, now. Calm down.
Tell us one at a time.
What you did after the manager
went to the bathroom.
I was frying donuts in the kitchen.
I never visited the tables during that time.
Come to think of it, we
heard the donuts frying.
I-I was at my table the whole time.
Everyone here should've seen me.
Is that true?
Yes, we saw him.
Nonaka-san, how about you?
Me?
I certainly went to the bathroom,
but by the time I entered, the
manager was already on the ground.
In other words, you're the
only one who left his seat
to go to the bathroom when
the crime took place.
So, what? That doesn't mean I did it.
But aren't you the manager of a rival café?
No.
This place sells donuts.
I sell waffles.
They're totally different genres of food.
Are they?
I guess they are.
Excuse me.
What is it?
Got it.
I'm sorry, but we'd like
you to wait elsewhere.
We appreciate your understanding.
Based on the circumstances
and testimony so far,
Nonaka-san seems suspicious.
But should we trust that?
Inspector Megure, we finished
questioning the suspects.
First, sales have declined at the
café Nonaka-san operates recently.
At this rate, he's not sure if his café
will survive beyond a few more months.
Nonaka
Tables
At this rate, he's not sure if his café
will survive beyond a few more months.
Nonaka
Hallway
At this rate, he's not sure if his café
will survive beyond a few more months.
Nonaka
At this rate, he's not sure if his café
will survive beyond a few more months.
Nonaka
Men's
Bathroom
At this rate, he's not sure if his café
will survive beyond a few more months.
Nonaka
Entrance
Men's
Bathroom
At this rate, he's not sure if his café
will survive beyond a few more months.
Nonaka
Hallway
Women's
Bathroom
Entrance
Men's
Bathroom
At this rate, he's not sure if his café
will survive beyond a few more months.
Nonaka
Yard
Hallway
Women's
Bathroom
Entrance
Men's
Bathroom
At this rate, he's not sure if his café
will survive beyond a few more months.
Nonaka
Men's
Bathroom
Entrance
Women's
Bathroom
Hallway
Yard
Next, Furukawa-san said he had money
problems with the manager Tomita-san in the past.
Furukawa
Next, Furukawa-san said he had money
problems with the manager Tomita-san in the past.
Tables
Furukawa
Next, Furukawa-san said he had money
problems with the manager Tomita-san in the past.
Furukawa
Next, Furukawa-san said he had money
problems with the manager Tomita-san in the past.
Furukawa
Hallway
They both seem
to have motives.
Furukawa
Men's
Bathroom
They both seem
to have motives.
Furukawa
Hallway
Women's
Bathroom
Men's
They both seem
to have motives.
Furukawa
Yard
Hallway
Women's
Bathroom
Men's
They both seem
to have motives.
Furukawa
Entrance
Yard
Hallway
Women's
Bathroom
Men's
They both seem
to have motives.
Furukawa
Finally, the part-time employee Sakai-san
didn't get along with the manager very well.
According to part-time employee Sakai-san,
the gloves left at the crime
scene belong to Nonaka-san.
What?
Sakai
Kitchen
Nonaka-san is a regular here.
Sakai
Kitchen
Nonaka-san is a regular here.
He clearly recognized those gloves
because he always wears them.
Sakai
Yard
He clearly recognized those gloves
because he always wears them.
Sakai
He clearly recognized those gloves
because he always wears them.
Sakai
The gloves of the only man without
an alibi were at the crime scene.
Does that settle it?
As long as Nonaka-san doesn't come
up with an alibi, it must be him.
I see.
So that's how it is.
Nonaka-san, allow me to be direct.
These gloves are yours, aren't they?
Are they?
Th-They're certainly mine,
but I lost them a while ago.
So they're yours, then?
You don't have an alibi, you do have a
motive, and then there's this material evidence.
Do you have any explanation for this?
Detective Chiba.
Huh?
What is it?
Listen...
Nonaka-san, could you
accompany us to the station?
B-But... you have to believe me.
I really didn't do it.
You can tell us about it at the station.
Please come with us.
But I don't have anything to tell you.
Sonoko?
Are you okay?
Inspector Megure, could you
wait to escort him away?
What?
Did you figure out who did it?
At first glance,
all the evidence in this case seems to
indicate that Nonaka-san is the culprit.
In other words, if Nonaka-san
really did do it,
don't you think it was a bit too sloppy?
That's right!
If it were me, I wouldn't
have left the gloves behind.
And Furukawa-san.
Like us, you didn't go near the bathroom.
Considering that, your alibi seems perfect,
but is it really?
Isn't it a perfect alibi?
You could at least let me go early.
And finally, the part-timer Sakai-san.
You said you were in the
kitchen the whole time,
but we didn't see you.
I was frying donuts in the
kitchen the whole time.
If anything, the fact that you didn't see me
proves I was in the kitchen the whole time.
Considering their testimony,
it sounds like the culprit is...
Wh-What? You still think I did it?
Well, listen.
Tables
You headed towards the men's
bathroom and attacked Tomita-san,
Hallway
You headed towards the men's
bathroom and attacked Tomita-san,
who was already in the
bathroom, with a nearby mop.
It's a very natural and
plausible series of events.
Next, let's recreate Furukawa-san's actions.
Ran, could you show us?
Yeah.
Let's see. Furukawa-san was
in his seat the whole time.
For him to attack Tomita-san
in the bathroom...
Tables
For him to attack Tomita-san
in the bathroom...
Hallway
For him to attack Tomita-san
in the bathroom...
It wouldn't have been possible for
him to do it without us noticing.
Finally, let's recreate Sakai-san's actions.
Okay, Detective Takagi.
Could you follow Sonoko-neechan's
instructions?
Got it.
There's only one route Sakai-san,
who was in the kitchen,
could have taken to reach the
crime scene in the bathroom
without passing by the tables.
Kitchen
He exited through the kitchen window,
crossed the yard, entered
through the front entrance,
Hallway
crossed the yard, entered
through the front entrance,
and reached the bathroom through the hallway.
He followed the same route
to return to the kitchen.
That's the route you want
me to recreate, right?
Yeah. Are you ready?
Anytime.
Okay... Ready, go.
How was that?
It's been 90 seconds so far.
Hup.
Well?
Two minutes, 50 seconds.
That sound we heard...
was the timer in the kitchen.
What was that beeping sound?
That sound we heard...
was the timer in the kitchen.
Excuse me.
What does all of this mean?
It means you don't have an alibi anymore.
What?
You said you were in the kitchen frying
donuts when the crime took place,
but you could have gone anywhere
during the three minutes
after you put the donuts in the fryer.
But, why were Nonaka-san's
gloves in the bathroom?
If you assume Sakai-san set everything
up, doesn't that explain it?
Your leading statements made me
suspicious of you from the start.
Hold on.
I understand that I could've gone to
the bathroom and back in three minutes.
But isn't there a big hole in your reasoning?
A hole?
That's right. Allow me to explain.
Think about it.
What is it?
It's this.
While you were having tea in here,
how did I cross this section of the yard?
No one could pass through
here without being seen.
You're right.
That's not true.
What?
You're able to pass through
this area without being seen.
What are you talking about?
I meant exactly what I said.
You did in fact pass through this
yard and return to the kitchen
without being noticed by anyone.
You didn't even see me.
Show me the evidence, then!
Oh, the evidence has been standing
in front of us this whole time.
What?
Look closely at the yard.
Look very closely.
Apparently you took care of that yard.
Making it the same color as your uniform
must've required a lot of patience.
He blends in completely with the background.
He's perfectly camouflaged.
I borrowed the uniform in the changing room.
But even with the camouflage,
wouldn't someone notice if
he passed through the yard?
It takes only a moment to cross.
It's one thing if you're staring at the yard,
but since everyone was focused
on their tea and donuts,
it was unlikely that anyone would notice.
He probably even planned where
and how he could cross the yard
unnoticed when he set it up.
No. That's just speculation.
You need more proof?
Then what's that scratch on your thigh?
You got caught on the nail sticking out
of the wall on your way back, didn't you?
Detective Takagi.
Conan-kun?
Detective Chiba said this cloth
was stuck to a nail outside.
What's this?
It's the same color cloth
as Sakai-san's uniform.
If the police examine that cloth,
I'm sure they'll find that
it came from your uniform.
There's even more evidence.
Apparently forensics reported that they
found the laxatives you gave Nonaka-san
so he'd go to the bathroom
in the water on his table.
How did you know it was me?
My plan was perfect.
It was the donuts.
The donuts?
This café's donuts are made to order.
You began frying new ones when
no new customers had entered.
I considered what that might mean.
It's all his fault!
I came up with the menu, the
concept, and the eye-catching yard.
But he kept me working part-time.
He didn't give me anything.
So I...
Apparently the manager's all right.
I guess this case is closed.
You experienced your own share of misfortune.
I suppose.
Well, I should get going.
Hold on, Furukawa-san.
You haven't paid yet.
What? Which means...
What? Furukawa-san, you were
going to dine and dash?
That's right.
Because Furukawa-san unconsciously
touched his wallet in his back pocket
when Nonaka-san accused him,
Sonoko-neechan said it might be him.
Furukawa-san, could you
tell us more about that?
That's why he was acting
nervous the whole time.
Yeah, apparently.
Huh?
Solving that case made me hungry.
I'm hungry, too.
What?
There's always room for sweets.
And after eating sweets,
you need something salty.
You're right. There's always room for more.
What about low sugar and
low—well, whatever.
Episode Preview
What?
Stay back!
Episode Preview
I'll blow her brains out!
No!
Episode Preview
I expect you to fulfill the
three demands I'm about to list.
Episode Preview
First, I want a car.
Bring me a car so I can get out of—
Episode Preview
What?
Makoto-san!
Episode Preview
Kyogoku Makoto the Understudy (Part One)
The next episode of Conan is, "Kyogoku
Makoto the Understudy, Part One!"
Kyogoku Makoto the Understudy (Part One)
Stunt
Next Conan's hint!
Stunts!
Stunt
Don't miss the next episode.
Today's is the last episode of the year.
Thank you for another year.
Don't miss the next episode.
Happy New Year.