A journey of a thousand miles
starts with the first step!
Solve 1,000 mysteries and enter a new world!
The legendary case that took
place on a remote island!
What is the mystery behind
the cursed piano and melody?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
During the next full moon
once again on Moonshade Island
the shadows will begin to vanish
The Moonlight Sonata Murder
(Part One)
"The Moonlight Sonata Murder, Part One!"
The Moonlight Sonata Murder
(Part One)
Moonshade Island Village Office
There isn't anyone by that
name on this island.
Moonshade Island Village Office
There isn't anyone by that
name on this island.
What? Can't you search your
records more thoroughly?
I have a letter from him requesting
my services right here.
But he's not on the island's resident list.
And besides, I just arrived
on this island last month.
Hey, what's going on here?
Well, actually...
This man claims to have been hired
by a resident of the island.
Hired?
Yes, by somebody named Aso Keiji-san.
Did you say Aso Keiji?!
That's not possible.
What?
After all, he passed away
more than ten years ago.
It happened 12 years ago on
the night of a full moon.
He was a famous pianist from this island.
After performing a concert at
the village's community center,
he suddenly locked himself and
his family inside his home
and set the house on fire.
According to the rescuers
who arrived at the scene,
after brutally murdering his
wife and daughter with a knife,
he played the same piece over and over
amidst the flames like a man possessed.
It was Beethoven's "Moonlight Sonata."
Jeez. What an awful prank.
It might not be a prank.
What?
After all, you received
your retainer fee, right?
Yeah.
And the postmark on the letter
is from Moonshade Island.
You're right.
Which means someone on this island probably
wants you to investigate that Aso Keiji person.
I see.
But if the man in question is dead, then...
Let's try talking to the mayor who
was allegedly Aso-san's friend.
You're right.
I believe they said the mayor
is at the community center.
Are you listening, Kenta-kun?
I believe they said the mayor
is at the community center.
Make sure you keep yourself
warm while you sleep.
Okay.
Bye, Doctor Narumi.
Bye.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Do you know where the community center is?
Take a right at that corner, and the
community center is at the end of the street.
Did you come here from the mainland?
Yes. We're from Tokyo.
Really?! My family's from Tokyo, too.
Oh, really?
But unlike Tokyo, isn't
this island wonderful?
The air is clear, and it's so quiet here.
Residents of Moonshade Island,
in order to protect the
island's fishing grounds,
The air is clear, and it's so quiet here.
in order to protect the
island's fishing grounds,
Community Planning with Vitality
Shimuzu Masato
in order to protect the
island's fishing grounds,
vote for me, Shimizu Masato!
Community Planning with Vitality
Shimuzu Masato
Vote for Shimizu Masato!
Community Planning with Vitality
Shimuzu Masato
Vote for Shimizu Masato!
Community Planning with Vitality
Shimizu Masato
Vote for Shimizu Masato!
Community Planning with Vitality
Shimizu Masato
Normally the island is quiet, but
the mayoral election is coming up.
Mayoral election?
Yes.
Moonshade Island
Mayoral Election
Poster Bulletin Board
Kawashima Hideo
Continuing to Work with Moonshade Island
Kuroiwa Tatsuji
Community Planning with Vitality
There are three candidates.
Moonshade Island
Mayoral Election
Poster Bulletin Board
Kawashima Hideo
Continuing to Work with Moonshade Island
Kuroiwa Tatsuji
Community Planning with Vitality
Moonshade Island
Mayoral Election
Poster Bulletin Board
Kawashima Hideo
Continuing to Work with Moonshade Island
Kuroiwa Tatsuji
Community Planning with Vitality
According to my patients, it's likely
that Kawashima-san will be elected.
Actually, Miss Nurse, we're not particularly
interested in the mayoral election.
I'm Asai Narumi, a doctor.
Asai Narumi (26)
Doctor
I'm Asai Narumi, a doctor.
I have a medical license.
Asai Narumi (26)
Doctor
I have a medical license.
Excuse me. You're a doctor, huh?
If you're going to the community center,
you might get to meet the
three men I just mentioned.
After all, the previous
mayor Kameyama Isamu-san's
second anniversary memorial service
is being held there tonight.
Get out, Mayor Kuroiwa!
Don't let Mayor Kuroiwa get
away with this tyranny!
Get out, Mayor Kuroiwa!
Stop polluting our fishing grounds!
Unbelievable.
Kuroiwa Tatsuji (56)
Mayor of Moonshade Island
The previous mayor's memorial
service is tonight.
Kuroiwa Tatsuji (56)
Mayor of Moonshade Island
How rude of them.
Kuroiwa Tatsuji (56)
Mayor of Moonshade Island
How rude of them.
Indeed.
They're so noisy.
Kuroiwa Reiko (27)
Kuroiwa's Only Daughter
They're so noisy.
Kuroiwa Reiko (27)
Kuroiwa's Only Daughter
Hirata.
Kuroiwa Reiko (27)
Kuroiwa's Only Daughter
Hirata.
Yes, ma'am.
Hirata Kazuaki (31)
Secretary to the Mayor
Yes, ma'am.
What are you doing?
Hirata Kazuaki (31)
Secretary to the Mayor
Hurry up and shut up those villagers.
Hirata Kazuaki (31)
Secretary to the Mayor
Hurry up and shut up those villagers.
As you wish, miss.
Whoa, whoa. Are you guys okay?
Shuichi.
According to the villagers, the odds are
against your dad in the upcoming mayoral race.
Murasawa Shuichi (27)
Reiko's Fiancee
According to the villagers, the odds are
against your dad in the upcoming mayoral race.
That's not—
That's right.
It seems that I have the most
support from the villagers.
Kawashima Hideo (56)
Mayoral Election Candidate
It seems that I have the most
support from the villagers.
That's because you know
how to use your money.
I'm just copying your methods.
There's somebody who says he'd
like to meet with the mayor.
What? Who wants to see me now?
H-He says he's a detective from Tokyo.
Jeez.
How long are they going to make us wait?
Maybe they're busy preparing
for the memorial service.
Right, Conan-kun?
Conan-kun?
A piano.
Hey, Conan-kun.
What is it, Ran?
This is a big room.
Are they going to hold a piano concert?
The ocean is right behind the building.
This piano looks pretty old.
I wonder if it works.
Don't!
Don't touch that piano!
That's the cursed piano played here
at the concert the day Aso-san died.
Surely it's not cursed.
That incident wasn't the
only thing that happened.
Something similar happened
to the previous mayor.
You mean Kameyama Isamu-san, whose
memorial service is being held today?
Yes. It happened two years ago.
The moon was full that night, just
like the night of Aso-san's incident.
I happened to pass nearby when
I heard the sound of the piano
coming from the supposedly
empty community center.
I thought someone was there, so I called out
to them, and the sound abruptly stopped.
When I entered the room...
Kameyama-san was leaning
against the keys, dead.
The cause of death was a heart attack.
And horrifyingly, the piece that had
been playing right up until his death
was the piece Aso-san played amidst
the inferno, the "Moonlight Sonata."
Since then, people started
calling this the cursed piano.
The villagers are too afraid to touch it.
There's nothing special about this piano.
Conan-kun!
In any case, please wait outside
until the service is over.
Oh, it's you guys.
Narumi-san.
Were you able to meet with the mayor?
No, not yet.
Are you here for the service, Narumi-san?
Yes.
Kameyama-san's was the first body I
examined after coming to the island.
I thought I could at least
light some incense.
Oh, right. This is one of the mayoral
candidates I mentioned earlier.
Shimizu Masato (49)
Mayoral Election Candidate
Oh, right. This is one of the mayoral
candidates I mentioned earlier.
Shimizu Masato (49)
Mayoral Election Candidate
Nice to meet you. I'm Shimizu Masato.
Shimizu Masato (49)
Mayoral Election Candidate
A pleasure.
Nishimoto Ken (55)
Unemployed
Bastard.
You hired a detective to
investigate me, didn't you?
Don't be ridiculous.
Hey, are you running away from me?
I'm going to the bathroom.
It doesn't make sense.
Supposedly no one's used that piano
in years, but it was in tune.
Someone's probably been tuning it in secret.
During the next full moon
once again on Moonshade Island
the shadows will begin to vanish
And then there's that letter
that arrived one week ago...
During the next full moon
once again on Moonshade Island
the shadows will begin to vanish
During the next full moon
once again on Moonshade Island
the shadows will begin to vanish
Th-This song...
The "Moonlight Sonata!"
Crap!
Conan-kun?
Damn it! We were too late!
It's no use. He's dead.
Kawashima-san is dead?
What's going on?
Ran, call the police substation.
Got it.
Everyone else, stay where you are.
Doctor Narumi.
Yes?
Could you examine the body?
Very well.
I see. So that's how it is.
This is what that letter
was warning us about.
Damn it! If only I'd realized
what it meant sooner.
I-It's the curse.
It's the piano's curse!
This isn't a curse.
Look closely.
It's not a curse or a ghost
that's playing the piano.
It's this tape recorder.
In other words, this is a murder case made
to look like the previous two incidents.
Oh, come on. Don't go making up stories.
Who are you, anyway?
Me? I came here from Tokyo.
I'm the great detective Mori Kogoro.
Ever heard of him?
No...
Seawater?
Judging by the body's condition,
the estimated time of death is
30 minutes to one hour ago.
The cause of death is suffocation.
I believe he was drowned.
He was drowned?
I can't say for certain without
performing an autopsy.
I think Doctor Narumi is right.
Look outside the window.
Isn't that Kawashima-san's jacket?
It looks like something was dragged from the
door leading out to the sea to the piano,
and there's mud and sand
on Kawashima-san's back.
Also, the room's doors
and windows are locked,
and the first few minutes of this
"Moonlight Sonata" tape are blank.
During the service, the culprit probably brought
Kawashima-san to the ocean and drowned him,
moved the body into this room,
locked the doors and windows,
turned on the tape recorder,
and then left the room.
After several minutes of silence, the "Moonlight
Sonata" started playing on the tape recorder.
Right, Mister?
Y-Yeah, that's right.
But since we were in the entryway of
the community center the whole time...
W-Wait a minute. Does that mean
the culprit is still...
in this room?
Yeah, as long as they didn't
use the confusion to escape.
Hey, Mister Detective.
I wouldn't call it a motive, but the
man happiest about Kawashima's death
is probably the other mayoral
candidate, Shimizu-kun.
W-What did you say?
I could say the same thing
about you, Mayor Kuroiwa.
What was that?
Now, now. Try to calm down.
By the way, how long as
that piano been here?
It was given to the community center
as a gift from Aso-san 15 years ago.
It's been here ever since.
From Aso-san?
Yes. Aso-san's name is even on the lid.
What's this?
Sheet music?
That's odd. This wasn't here when
we looked at it this afternoon.
Who was that?
Nishimoto Ken-san.
Nishimoto?
He was quite prosperous a long time ago,
but after the previous mayor
passed away two years ago,
he began shutting himself inside his home.
Since the incident two years ago, huh?
Oh, right. I believe that Mayor Kuroiwa
and he are childhood friends, right?
Yeah, I think so.
Dad.
I brought a police officer.
Took you long enough, Ran.
Yeah, but...
Uh, who called for me?
This man. His name is Mori Kogoro-san.
Who are you?
In any case, it's already late.
We'll interview the witnesses tomorrow.
Damn it. This case is full of unknowns.
Why did the culprit bother to
move the body to the piano?
Does this sheet music that was found
with the body mean anything?
the shadows will begin to vanish
And what about the letter
warning us about this case?
the shadows will begin to vanish
Wait a minute.
I think that letter said "begin to vanish."
Could it be that this case is...?
What?!
This letter warned us about this case?
Yeah. "The shadows will vanish" means
they'll be enveloped in light.
That light is the moon's light.
It's referring to the "Moonlight Sonata."
That's it. Both 12 years
ago and two years ago,
the "Moonlight Sonata" was playing right
up until Aso-san and Kameyama-san died.
In other words, if the
shadows will vanish again,
that means the "Moonlight Sonata" will be
played again, and somebody else will die.
Wait a minute.
This letter says that the shadows
will "begin to vanish."
Does that mean there's more to this case?
Sheesh.
If you ask me, spending the night
here with the body is insanity.
Well, you know...
More importantly, who moved the body?
That was me.
I felt bad about leaving
him in that position.
You shouldn't have done that.
The crime scene hasn't been
properly examined yet.
Huh?
That sheet music is missing.
What?
Oh, I thought I'd hold
onto it for safekeeping.
Here.
Huh? This is the sheet music
for the "Moonlight Sonata."
Th-The "Moonlight Sonata"?
But the fourth line is sort of weird.
The fourth line?
Weird how?
Ready?
When you play the fourth line...
See?
Could the fourth line of this sheet music
be a dying message from Kawashima-san?
Which means it's possible that the
culprit will return to retrieve this.
Doctor Narumi?
I called your inn, and
they said you'd be here.
I brought you dinner.
N-Now that you mention it...
Really?
So you're not originally from
this island, Doctor Narumi?
No. I go back to Tokyo every weekend.
It's been two years since
I started coming here.
Speaking of two years,
I have a question about Mayor
Kameyama who died two years ago.
He'd previously had heart problems, and
the cause of death was a heart attack.
But his face was rather tense,
as though he'd seen something terrifying.
He looked like he'd seen
something terrifying, huh?
In any case, I'll keep watch tonight.
You guys should go to sleep.
Okay.
Hey, Mori-kun. Mori-kun.
It's almost noon. Wake up.
I-Inspector Megure, what are you doing here?
Are you sure you're not still asleep?
I heard you were involved,
so I came all the way here.
Th-That's right.
Inspector, I have something for you.
Conan-kun already gave me the sheet music.
What?
The three of them outlined
the case for me, too.
All three of them were awake
by the time we arrived.
What?
In any case, we're interviewing
people at the village office.
Come lend us a hand.
Yes, sir.
Well? Did you figured out who did it?
Don't be stupid.
We've got 38 witnesses to question.
When will I be questioned?
I'm sure you're exhausted.
I asked them to question you last.
In that case, I'll go wash my face first.
Hey.
How many more people do
you have to question?
Six total. There's Doctor
Narumi, those four over there,
and Nishimoto, who's being
questioned right now.
You fool!
Cursed piano, my ass.
This happened because that
thing is still here.
B-But sir...
Get rid of it immediately. Got it?
V-Very well.
Enough already!
I obviously don't have a motive
to kill Kawashima-san!
I told you, we're just questioning everyone.
Wow. Reiko-san has been
yelling for ten minutes.
I told you, we're just questioning everyone.
You can't be serious!
That's odd.
Now, now. Please calm down.
They've been interviewed already,
so why aren't they leaving?
Now, now. Please calm down.
They've been interviewed already,
so why aren't they leaving?
I'm going to the bathroom!
He's not here!
Hey, did Nishimoto-san go in there?
No. Only Shimizu is inside.
Damn it. He must be upstairs.
Crap!
This song...
It's the second movement
of the "Moonlight Sonata."
Where's the source of the sound?!
The broadcast room?
Nishimoto-san!
Mayor Kuroiwa.
Call forensics and the coroner immediately.
But Inspector, the coroner left for
Tokyo to perform Kawashima's autopsy.
Damn it. Why did this have to happen now?
Excuse me.
If you don't mind, I could do it.
Doctor Narumi.
Thank you.
In that case, until the forensics team
arrives, could you examine him right away?
Yes.
Again. I knew it was coming,
but I let another person die.
It's unforgivable.
Threatening to commit murder and then
calmly carrying out that threat...
They won't get away with this!
Th-The hellfire's grudge? Could it be?
Episode Preview
It's him.
Aso Keiji is alive!
Episode Preview
Murasawa-san?
N-Nishimoto-san...
Episode Preview
What is this? Could it be?
The Moonlight Sonata Murder
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Moonlight Sonata Murder, Part Two!"
The Moonlight Sonata Murder
(Part Two)
Piano
Next Conan's hint!
A piano!
Piano
Don't miss the next episode.
Cock-a-doodle-doo!
After that moonlit night...
Don't miss the next episode.
...we'll probably see blue skies.
Nice!
Don't miss the next episode.