Allow me to propose a toast to the
continued growth of Sasano Finance.
Sasano Shuji (36)
Sasano Finance 2nd President
Cheers!
Toki Shintaro (65)
Toki Credit Union Chief Director
That's good. Truly marvelous.
Hanaoka Terumi (51)
Terumi Beauty Salon Chain Delegate
Truly delicious. It's an excellent wine.
Enoshima Akira (48)
Enoshima Hospital Director
I'm impressed that he was able to
acquire a wine of this caliber.
Enoshima Akira (48)
Enoshima Hospital Director
President Sasano is truly exceptional.
Indeed.
There's no one quite like President Sasano.
Tachikawa Kimiyuki (30)
Chef
Oizumi Nanase (23)
Housekeeper
Tachikawa Kimiyuki (30)
Chef
Oizumi Nanase (23)
Housekeeper
Good grief. I'll be working until dawn again.
You did have a busy week, Kimiyuki-san.
It looks like tonight won't be any easier.
Yeah.
A journey of a thousand miles
starts with the first step!
Solve 1,000 mysteries and enter a new world!
Everyone's a suspect at
this problematic party!
Eliminate the impossible
and close in on the truth!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Who Poisoned the Victim?
"Who Poisoned the Victim?"
With all this wine available,
I'm on cloud wine!
You must be bored.
Huh?
Would you like some more juice?
Thanks.
Ugh, Dad's drinking enough wine
for three people all by himself.
He's completely forgotten why he came here.
Unbelievable.
Mori Detective Agency
I'm Kobayakawa, the secretary
for Sasano Finance.
Kobayakawa Rokuro (44)
Sasano Finance Secretary
The reason I came to hire your services
is because this was sent to our office.
Let me see. Allow me to take a look.
Is this a death threat?
I'll kill Sasano
Prepare yourself
Yes.
Do you have any idea who
might have sent this?
Yes.
That's what I wanted
to talk to you about.
I'm asking you to identify the culprit.
I have three potential suspects in mind,
and I want you to determine
who sent this death threat.
Apparently all three of the guests invited to
this party have a grudge against the president.
I don't know the specifics,
but I've heard there were a
lot of problems between them
since the first president ran the company.
That guy with the mustache must
be the second president, then.
Yeah.
The first President Sasano
is that man in the photo.
That mustache looks just like
the current president's.
You're right.
Anyway, I'm terribly sorry about the car
accident that killed the first president.
Thank you.
The first president truly was—whoops.
Hey, Oizumi-kun. Bring us
something to clean this up.
Yes, sir.
Don't worry about it.
I've got a handkerchief.
You all right?
Yeah, it's fine.
They say it was his own maintenance error.
Truly unfortunate.
My father's hobby was his car.
I can't believe he ended up falling
off a cliff due to a defective brake.
It grieves me most deeply.
I appreciate everything he did
for me while he was alive.
I wish he could've seen Enoshima
Hospital prosper even more.
It doesn't look like anyone's
attempting anything for now.
Yeah.
I'm going to get more juice.
Okay.
Hello? This is Enoshima.
More juice, please.
You're quite the drinker.
What?
You didn't send me a
message? What do you mean?
Did something happen?
I don't know.
I see. I understand.
Thanks for handling the rest.
Thanks for waiting, Teshigawara-kun.
Tachikawa-san, it's Oizumi now.
Sorry, sorry.
Unbelievable. Be careful.
That's absolutely marvelous.
Would you like one?
Thank you.
Go ahead.
Delicious!
What's wrong, Sasano-san?
Sasano-san! Sir!
Hang in there.
Sir...
Excuse me.
It's too late.
He's already dead.
N-No...
Everyone, stay where you are.
This is a murder.
Damn it.
After the first president
died in an accident,
I never thought the second
would be poisoned today.
If the first had lived longer, the second
would've been disowned a long time ago.
Though their relationship was terrible, they
conducted their business exactly the same way.
Their methods were greedy and callous.
That's right.
Like father, like son. People resented them.
Tachikawa-san, I'm scared.
I understand how you feel, but it's better
if you feign indifference for now.
Until the police arrive,
I, Mori Kogoro, shall manage the situation.
The truth is that the victim,
Sasano Shuji, had received a death threat.
What?
I apologize that we're requesting
your approval after the fact,
but we fully utilized this
structure's security cameras.
What do you mean, Mori-san?
Everyone, take a look at
these images we recorded.
What's this?
Mister, you're picking up something
that looks like medicine.
That's medicine for my blood pressure.
Here's the next image.
Hey, what is this?
You don't have poison hidden inside
that ring of yours, do you?
Hey, don't go falsely accusing me!
I had nothing to do with this!
Next image.
That's...!
It's a syringe.
S-So what? What's wrong with
a doctor carrying a syringe?
Besides, when the president collapsed, I
was standing on the other side of the room.
Well, I was just adjusting my ring.
There's no way I could've
killed the president.
I was just picking up the medicine I dropped.
It has nothing to do with the case.
More importantly, how can you treat
our personal information like this?
That's right! I'm going
to sue for defamation!
In any case, I'm leaving!
Quiet, please. This isn't a
matter of personal information.
A man has been murdered.
I suppose you're right.
I'm sorry.
What is it, Kobayakawa-san?
That's not me.
My name isn't Kobayakawa,
nor am I a secretary.
What?
I'm actually the president Sasano Shuji.
Sasano Shuji (36)
Sasano Finance 2nd President
Kobayakawa Rokuro (44)
Sasano Finance Secretary
Sasano Shuji (36)
Sasano Finance 2nd President
Kobayakawa Rokuro (44)
Sasano Finance Secretary
A-A fake mustache? But...
Sasano Shuji (36)
Sasano Finance 2nd President
Kobayakawa Rokuro (44)
Sasano Finance Secretary
I shaved my own mustache off.
At Kobayakawa's suggestion, I lived in
disguise and traded places with him for a while.
I'm sorry for the confusion.
In other words, this is what happened.
The two of you planned to swap
places and see what would happen.
Yes.
Kobayakawa said that if the
death threat were real,
I would be safe this way.
I'd also be able to observe the reactions of
the other three from an impartial perspective.
I agreed to the plan because I believed
that, but I never thought this would happen.
What do you mean by that, sir?
Observe our reactions from
an impartial perspective?
You mean you treated us like
suspects from the very start?
That's why you used security
cameras to film us?
Was this party a farce to begin with?
How incredibly rude!
So what?
President Sasano received a death threat,
and Kobayakawa-san was murdered
while acting as his stand-in.
The police will arrive eventually.
They'll asking you to turn over the
possessions you have on you, so keep that in mind.
It's true that there wasn't a single
image of anyone poisoning the glass.
But a murder did occur.
How did the culprit poison him?
Excuse me.
I brought coffee.
Thank you, Teshigawara-san.
You're welcome.
I knew it was you, Teshigawara Nanase.
Teshigawara? You mean that Teshigawara?
I've heard that name before.
I know. It's the name of that distinguished
man who committed suicide.
Is there something the matter with that girl?
This woman was using a fake name.
Wait a minute!
My name changed because I was
adopted by the Oizumi family.
But your name before that was Teshigawara.
Am I wrong?
No, that's correct.
So you are the daughter of that family.
The family that was Sasano
Finance's first victim.
I heard the head of the family killed himself
over Sasano Finance's
aggressive collection methods.
It's true that my father killed
himself several years ago.
Does that mean the glass was poisoned by...?
It must've been this girl.
I don't know anything about that!
I was just handing out glasses!
That's right. She's the one
who handed out the glasses.
But from among several glasses,
Kobayakawa-san himself
selected the poisoned glass.
Isn't that right, Mori-sensei?
Huh? Uh, yeah.
For the time being, let's review
the security camera images again.
I hear magicians can make it look like
audience members have selected a card
while making them draw a
card of their choosing.
Hold on. Nanase isn't a magician!
I see.
You're her boyfriend, huh?
In other words, you were working together.
I just happened to invite Nanase here today!
This is the first time I've heard
about her history with Sasano Finance!
If you two were accomplices,
then it makes things simple.
First, you poison the glass.
Then your beloved Teshigawara-chan
simply hands it to him.
Hey!
Tachikawa-san, don't.
Now, now. Let's not lose our tempers.
You said at the start that
you'd let me handle this.
The police are already on their way, too.
Excuse me.
In any case, let's review the moment
the wine was handed off again.
Hey.
I'd like to see what happened
after he was handed the wine, too.
I'm always telling you not to
butt into my conversations.
But if that lady is the culprit, then I want
to see what kind of magic trick she used.
Sasano-san, could I ask
you to replay the video?
Yes, very well.
Take a look.
Haven't we seen enough?
Didn't Kobayakawa-san take a different glass
from the one he initially reached for?
You're right. It's like he changed his mind.
They're right.
Regardless of any attempt to influence him,
it was the victim himself
who selected the glass.
That's right.
What does that mean?
The culprit couldn't have predicted that the
victim would select a different glass on a whim.
You're right.
She didn't do it.
Wait a minute.
There were several glasses left on the tray.
What if the chef or that woman
had poisoned all of them?
Am I wrong, Detective Mori?
Huh?
I drank it.
This means all of the
glasses weren't poisoned.
That would mean the victim chose
the poisoned glass himself.
You mean an invisible culprit poisoned
the glass just before he drank from it?
Don't be ridiculous.
Hey, mister.
A little while before the murder, I
heard a message notification sound.
That would've been this.
Wow, that's a cool phone.
Can I see?
Sure.
Hooray. Wow, so cool.
You think so?
Don't play with it too much.
Okay.
I don't really understand how to use it.
I guess it was a little difficult for you.
Yeah, thanks.
In any case, you two are suspicious!
I'm turning you over to the police!
Dad?
When did I poison the glass?
We couldn't have done it.
You must've plotted something where
the security cameras couldn't see you.
Hold on, please.
Once again, I believe you
asked me to handle this case.
It's the Sleeping Kogoro.
It's the real thing.
Medically speaking, it's rather mysterious,
but he does appear to be speaking.
This is quite the puzzling case, but at the very
least, Tachikawa-san and Oizumi-san did not do it.
I was wondering what you were going to say.
Are you saying someone else could've done it?
Indeed, yes.
It was someone else who poisoned the glass.
Naturally, they're here right now.
I swear it wasn't me.
It wasn't me either.
Now, now. Please calm down.
I know that Sasano Finance's practically
fraudulent practices put each of you in crisis.
Therefore, all three of you
have a motive for murder.
However, as was made clear
by the security cameras,
you never had the opportunity
to poison the glass.
The same goes for Tachikawa-san
and Oizumi-san.
But wouldn't that mean
the culprit isn't here?
Not so.
There's just one more person remaining.
Which means...
Could it be?
Surely you're not referring to me.
Enough of this!
An attempt was made on my life!
Why would I be the culprit?
Once you eliminate the impossible,
whatever remains, no matter how
improbable, must be the truth.
In other words, this murder is possible
if and only if you are the culprit.
But Kobayakawa-san chose
which glass to take himself.
That's right.
He deliberately chose the poisoned glass.
It was impossible for the
culprit to poison that glass.
Wasn't that the conclusion we reached?
But didn't he collapse because
the glass was poisoned?
Are you sure about that?
We're assuming there was poison in the glass
the victim drank from just before he collapsed.
But what if it was all an act?
An act?
Precisely.
The culprit's plan began
with the death threat.
If you assume that, then
you can figure it out.
Suppose that the secretary believed
the death threat was real
and that it was the president himself
who suggested that they swap places.
The similarities in their
appearance make it possible.
They conspired to disguise themselves
as each other and swapped places.
Someone who'd never met them
directly wouldn't notice.
Kobayakawa-san, while
disguised as the president,
would pretend to be poisoned in order
to unsettle three people who had motive.
Then Sasano-san, while
disguised as Kobayakawa-san,
would intervene and uncover
who sent the death threat.
What if the idea were proposed
to the victim in this manner?
But Kobayakawa-san's death wasn't an act.
That's right. He died, right before our eyes.
Indeed. It's true that a line had been
drawn between acting and reality.
Try to recall what happened after
Kobayakawa-san pretended to be poisoned.
Sir, hang in there.
Could it be?
It was the water?
The poison was in the water.
Immediately after I confirmed
the victim's death,
Sasano-san dropped the cup directly on
top of the glass dropped by the victim.
The poisoned water scattered and mixed
with the wine that had fallen earlier.
It was an attempt to make it appear as
though the poison had been in the wine
when forensics examined it later.
This case was actually a
plot to murder the secretary
disguised as a death threat
against the president.
Wait a minute!
What motive do I have?
The conversation between the
other three gave me some idea.
If the previous president
hadn't died in an accident,
you wouldn't have taken over the company.
And maintaining his car just
happened to be his hobby.
You probably worked with
Kobayakawa-san the secretary
to make the previous president's accident
look like it was caused by a maintenance error.
Which means your accomplice Kobayakawa-san
was a thorn in your side.
What evidence is there that I did it?
If you have any, show me!
I thought you might say that.
The greatest weakness of this plan is
that one of your guests is a doctor.
It would be fatal if he saw through
the act of pretending to be poisoned.
So you sent Enoshima-san
a fake urgent message
so he'd move away from the scene.
If you wrote the message beforehand,
From: Enoshima Hospital
Subject: Emergency
Please contact us immediately.
From: Enoshima Hospital
Subject: Emergency
Please contact us immediately.
you could wait for the opportunity
to send it in an instant.
But you needed to erase the sent message
history that would be left on your phone.
Amidst the confusion, you didn't
appear to have the time to do that.
Which means I'd like to take
a look at your phone history.
I don't have my phone.
I don't bring my phone with me to parties.
I thought it would ruin the mood
if I suddenly received a call.
When I asked to see
Enoshima-san's phone earlier,
I memorized your number from his contacts.
Sounds like you do have your phone on you.
Let us see it.
It would seem that the police have arrived.
Mister, lunch is ready.
Tada! What do you think, kid?
Looks pretty good on me, doesn't it?
Uh, yeah...
If you don't hurry up,
your food will get cold.
Coming!
I'm gonna go, Mister.
Hey! Hey, kid!
Say something before you go. Hey!
Huh? What? My mustache. My mustache!
That might've actually
been a good look for him.