This way. It's over here.
I found this bracelet beneath these shrubs.
I see.
I'm impressed that you spotted
something down here, though.
I took a peek because I heard a kitty meow.
That's when I found this on the ground.
I see.
But this looks pretty expensive.
It's got a jewel or something on it.
Yes, it's a garnet.
Like I said...
Conan.
Hey, Conan.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Why don't we return this
bracelet to whoever lost it?
Good idea. That sounds like
a job for the Detective Boys.
But how are we going to find them?
If we can find the store
that sells that bracelet,
we should be able to find whoever lost it.
A journey of a thousand miles
starts with the first step!
Solve 1,000 mysteries and enter a new world!
The Detective Boys are in big trouble!
Their search for the owner of a
missing item takes a surprising turn!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Lost Article That Smells Like a Case
"The Lost Article That Smells Like a Case!"
Kaneko Jewelry
I feel like I've seen this before.
Really?
Yeah.
It might be one of our products.
Might be?
Or it might not be.
Well, we used to sell a similar design.
The initials S.Y. are on the back.
Sorry. Since we didn't sell it, I don't know.
We haven't been able to find them.
Is turning it into the
police our only option?
I'm hungry.
Hey, kids!
It's the guy from the accessory shop.
When I asked the other staff about it,
one of them said they remembered the
person who bought that bracelet.
Really?
Yeah. Their name is Yamaki Shinobu.
Since you've already got their bracelet,
could you return it to them?
Yeah!
You can count on us!
This is the place.
All right. Let's ask if
that bracelet is theirs.
Coming.
Yes?
Um, can I help you?
Miss, are you Yamaki Shinobu-san?
Shinobu is my older brother.
What? Your brother?
Yamaki Risa (25)
Yes, and? Do you have
business with my brother?
We found a bracelet that we believe
belongs to your brother at the park.
This is it.
See? It's got the initials S.Y. on it.
That's definitely my brother's.
All right.
We finally found him.
Thank you for coming all
this way to return it.
My name is Yamaki Risa.
Hey, where's your brother?
What? Oh, he's out of the house right now.
I'll return this bracelet to my brother.
Please do.
We're counting on you.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Give me a second.
It could be important.
There.
Miss.
You smell wonderful.
Must be your perfume.
Thank you. It's my favorite perfume.
I see.
I'm glad we were able to return
the bracelet to its owner.
Yes. His sister was delighted, too.
That settles that.
Yeah!
Sorry.
I forgot that Ran-neechan asked
me to run an errand for her.
Oh, no.
Shall we go with you?
Nah, I'll be fine.
Careful on your way home, guys.
Sorry for visiting out of the blue, Oi-san.
Oi Yutaka (28)
Oh, it's fine. You're Yamaki-san's...
I'm his sister Risa.
I actually lost touch with
my brother this week.
What?
I visited his home, but he
hasn't been back in a while.
I see. That's concerning.
Anyway, these are the last messages
I exchanged with my brother.
When do you want to meet up?
Yeah, we went out to eat that day.
What was my brother like that day?
I'm not sure how to answer that question.
Anything helps.
Come to think of it,
he didn't have anything to drink
because he was meeting a friend later.
Do you know who that friend was?
No, I didn't ask.
I see.
But if Yamaki-san was meeting a friend,
then it was probably Yagi or Kogure-san.
Do you know them?
No.
Then maybe you should meet with them.
I'll give you their addresses. Wait here.
Thank you.
I'm pretty sure both of them live nearby.
Well, well.
This is the errand Ran-san asked you to run?
Guys...
Uh, I...
Why are you following Risa-oneesan?
I was worried if she'd actually
return the bracelet to her brother.
Risa-san's probably looking for him.
What?
What does that mean?
Did she and her brother get into an argument?
Is it a case?
That must be it.
Yeah. After all, Conan-kun
thinks it's suspicious.
Crap, Risa-san's gone!
Damn it. I lost her.
She's missing?
Where'd she go?
Do you have any ideas?
Risa-san went to meet either her brother's
friend Kogure-san or Yagi-san.
Let's split up and look for her.
Got it.
Yagi
I'm sorry to disappoint you
after you came all the way here,
but I didn't see Yamaki-san that day.
I see.
But I don't think you need
to be so worried about him.
Yagi Keita (25)
Actually, this was found at a park.
My brother always wore this.
Since this was found,
I'm worried my brother may have
gotten caught up in something.
Have you contacted the police?
No, not yet.
I'm going to talk to Kogure-san next.
I was thinking after that.
I see. Very well. I'll go with you.
You must feel forlorn on your own.
Really? Thank you.
I'll get ready to go right
away. Give me a few minutes.
Okay.
Thank you so much.
I'm also worried about Yamaki-san.
We can't find her anywhere.
You can do it, Genta-kun.
According to Conan-kun, Yagi-san's
house should be around here.
Excuse me.
What is it, children?
We're looking for the residence of Yagi-san.
Do you know where they live, ma'am?
Kanno Shizu (65)
Yagi-san? Oh, Yagi-san.
You know them?
Yes. He lives in this apartment building.
Yagi
This is it.
Yes?
Hello!
Sorry for dropping in suddenly.
Are you Yamaki Shinobu-san's friend Yagi-san?
What? Yes.
Hey, wait.
Who are you kids?
We're the Detective Boys.
We're looking for a lady
named Yamaki Risa-san.
Did she come here?
What?
Risa-san is Yamaki Shinobu-san's
younger sister.
She seems to be looking for her brother.
I was at home all day today,
but nobody visited me.
I see.
Then she must be at Kogure's
place where Conan went.
Now that you know, get out of here.
Okay.
Ayumi-chan, let's go.
Okay...
Sorry I couldn't help.
It's fine. Sorry for interrupting
your busy schedule.
Later.
Jeez.
I can't believe those kids are involved, too.
Aw, man. This place was a dead end.
Yeah.
Risa-san must be where Conan-kun—
Hey, guys. Can you hear me?
Conan-kun, how did things go over there?
Risa-san isn't here.
According to the neighbors, Kogure-san
hasn't been home since this morning.
Risa-san probably headed to Yagi-san's place.
About that...
She didn't come here either.
I see.
Hey, Conan-kun.
I think Yagi-san is lying.
What?
I smelled Risa-oneesan at his apartment.
Is that true, Ayumi-chan?
Yeah, I'm sure I did.
It was the smell of her perfume.
Does that mean she was at his place?
Um, Conan-kun?
What is it, Mitsuhiko?
There was something about Yagi-san's
apartment that I found odd, too.
The shoes were tidily put away in
the shoe cabinet at the entrance,
except for a pair of boots that seemed
to have been sloppily stuffed in there.
What do you suppose that means?
Where are you guys right now?
What?
In front of Yagi-san's apartment building.
Got it.
Stay where you are, got it?
I'll be right there.
But what about Risa-oneesan?
It's the boots Mitsuhiko
said were sloppily put away.
What? What about them?
Since you guys suddenly showed up,
he probably hastily hid Risa-san's
shoes inside those boots.
Which means...
Yeah.
Risa-san is still inside
Yagi-san's apartment!
What?
But why would Yagi-san do that?
Probably because Risa-san brought
Yamaki-san's bracelet to him.
I found it odd when we
visited Yamaki-san's house.
Risa-san didn't live there.
Her brother lived there alone.
What? Really?
There was only a men's umbrella
in the stand in the entryway.
There was also a wilting houseplant
with yellowing leaves.
In other words, her brother
hasn't been home in a while.
Then why was Risa-oneesan there?
She probably went there because she
couldn't get in touch with her brother
and was worried about him.
But because we returned the bracelet to her,
she believed her brother may have
gotten swept up in something.
The string on the bracelet
was broken, remember?
It must've been torn off during
an argument with the culprit.
There were tire tracks in the road in front of
the park and what looked like bloodstains, too.
It was Yagi-san who got into an
argument with Risa-san's brother!
No way.
Whatever you do, guys, stay where you are!
Don't do anything until I arrive!
This wouldn't have happened to
you if this hadn't turned up.
It's your brother's fault.
I had Yamaki-san fork over some money
because I had an opportunity to get rich.
But there were some problems,
and I lost it all.
Yamaki-san was furious when he stormed in.
But that's how investments work, you know?
Sometimes you win, and sometimes you lose.
That's how investments work.
But your brother insisted
that I return his money.
I explained repeatedly that
I couldn't right away,
but he was impatient and said
he'd report me to the police.
On top of that, he threatened
to tell my fiancée.
So I...
Don't worry.
I'll take you to see your brother tonight.
Good idea.
Indeed.
We can't wait for Conan-kun.
Yeah.
We should rescue Risa-oneesan ourselves.
Besides, if I hadn't found that
bracelet, this wouldn't have happened.
That's not true.
It's Yagi-san who's the
bad guy in this situation.
That's right, Ayumi.
Besides, if you hadn't found that bracelet,
we wouldn't have identified the culprit.
You're right.
Ready?
I'll ring the doorbell, and
while Yagi-san is distracted...
I'll jump out from behind
the door and tackle him.
Yes.
Then I'll go inside and rescue Risa-oneesan.
The perfect plan, if I say so myself.
We'll settle this case before Conan arrives.
I can already see Conan-kun's
disappointed expression.
Yeah.
What is it, Ayumi?
Is there a problem with my plan?
Behind you. Mitsuhiko-kun, behind you.
What? Behind me?
I thought I told you kids to leave!
Damn it!
Let go of Mitsuhiko!
Shut up!
This is what you kids get
for playing detective!
Mitsuhiko-kun, close your eyes!
Run, Ayumi!
Damn it. I'll teach those
kids to screw with me.
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
It skipped our floor.
What are we going to do, Mitsuhiko?
You're asking me?
There's another elevator over there.
Hurry!
Hurry, hurry!
Hurry up!
The elevator is still on the first floor.
Hurry, hurry.
If you don't hurry, you'll get caught.
Hurry!
Too bad.
That won't work.
The doors won't close while
I'm holding them open.
Now then, what should I
do with you impudent kids?
Get down, guys!
I made it in time.
Later, an investigation
revealed that the tire marks
in front of the park matched
the tires of Yagi Keita's car.
The blood left there was also
found to be Yamaki Shinobu-san's.
Thank you so much.
You saved my life.
Oh, right.
Here.
What is it?
Brother...
If not for this, my brother's
case wouldn't have been solved.
No, he probably wanted it to be
solved by you, the Detective Boys.
Um, that gemstone is a garnet, isn't it?
Yes, that's right. It's my birth stone.
My brother always...
Jeez.
I kept telling you guys not to go anywhere.
Sorry.
But, but, but...
The Detective Boys did good this time.
You guys...
Hey, wait.
I just found this over there.
Doesn't this belong to you?
I-Is this...?
A lost item?
Which means...
This is a job for the Detective Boys!
They haven't learned their lesson at all.
Episode Preview
What? Solve the dine and dashes?
Dad, listen to this.
Episode Preview
Just now, at Beika Park...
Shoes?
Episode Preview
Due to that string of incidents, the
smile finally disappeared from her face.
Episode Preview
Please solve this case.
I shall.
Episode Preview
The Idol Whose Smile Disappeared
The next episode of Conan is "The
Idol Whose Smile Disappeared!"
The Idol Whose Smile Disappeared
Red Shoes
Next Conan's hint!
Red shoes!
Red Shoes
Wow!
Don't miss the next episode.
That's amazing!
Conan-kun, you're so good
at kicking your shoes off.
Don't miss the next episode.
Just like a scarlet bullet.