Hey!
What happened? Are you all right?
It hurts... It hurts...
Am I going to die?
You'll be fine, as long as
we can stop the bleeding.
What's this?
Excuse me, could I borrow your scarf?
Sure.
Mister, should we press
the emergency stop button?
Yeah.
What's the matter? Did something happen?
Someone's injured.
A passenger has been wounded.
Call the police and an ambulance.
Hurry it up! Now!
Yes, sir.
A journey of a thousand miles
starts with the first step!
Solve 1,000 mysteries and enter a new world!
Bullets fly into a moving train!
Track down the sniper who disappeared!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Monorail Sniper Case
(Part One)
"The Monorail Sniper Case, Part One!"
The Monorail Sniper Case
(Part One)
Is everyone all right?
Where's the injured person?
We're fine. We stopped the
bleeding. He's sitting inside.
Mister, let's find the culprit quickly.
You don't have to tell me twice.
Whoops. Preserving the crime
scene is our top priority.
Don't touch anything until
the police arrive. Got it?
Yes, sir.
Where did the shot come from?
Which way is the wind blowing?
This way!
Hey, wait!
Hello? There's been a shooting
near the end of the monorail line.
If you close the roads immediately, we can
trap the culprit on the artificial island.
Yes, do it. I'll track down the culprit.
Inspector Megure, you heard him.
What should we do?
Instruct the monorail
company to stop service.
Contact the Wangan Police Station
and have them set up checkpoints
at all Wangan-Toto Station exits.
Toto Artificial Island
We'll also set up checkpoints on all nine
bridges surrounding the artificial island.
Toto Artificial Island
We'll seal off the entire
island and trap the culprit.
Toto Artificial Island
Yes, sir.
The moment the shot was fired, the monorail
was around that spot on the rail.
The bullet entered through the
second window from the front
and struck the victim's arm.
If we can determine the angle
of the hole in the window,
Direction of Travel
Shooting Victim
the location of the shooting victim,
Shooter's Location
and the monorail's location at that time,
then we can calculate where
the shot was fired from.
The shooter's location was probably...
It's that building.
But...
How do you know that?
What? Uh, my daily horoscope said
my guesses would be right today.
I see. Your horoscope, huh?
Yeah, right!
Who would believe that nonsense?
Hey, look! I saw someone who
might be the culprit over there!
What? Really?
All right, kid! Follow me!
Wait, Mister!
Excuse me, it's an emergency.
Could you open the door?
Judging by the height of the monorail
car, the shot was probably fired from...
Mister, the fifth floor. The second
window from the end was open.
What? Really?
Yeah, I was watching from
inside the monorail.
It's unlocked.
There's no one here.
They fled.
This place is empty.
There's no sign of the shooter.
Maybe you made a mistake when
you thought you saw the culprit.
That wasn't a mistake, it was a lie.
There's no mistaking it.
The shot was definitely fired from here.
Looks like a man lives alone here.
Mister, could you thoroughly
search this apartment?
I'm going to look around outside.
H-Hey, wait.
We're already unlawfully entering.
Hey!
Hello, this is Takagi.
What is it?
We've arrived at the monorail.
Forensics is currently
examining the crime scene.
Also, as you suggested, we've
blocked off all the roads.
Checkpoint
Have you figured out anything else?
Yes, it's about the victim.
His name is Maruta Daisuke-san, 28 years old.
Maruta Daisuke (28)
He works for a construction company.
He was shot in the upper left arm,
and he's in no danger of dying.
The bullet has been extracted,
and he's currently resting.
He apparently doesn't know
anyone who owns a gun,
nor has he done anything to
incur someone's ill will.
But that's all according to him.
We'll continue with our investigation.
Got it.
I'll contact you right away
if I find the culprit.
They're faint,
but there are scuff marks left by something
heavy that was dragged down the hallway.
Huh? Conan-kun? What—
It's me. Takagi.
Mori-san, why are you calling
from Conan-kun's phone?
Did you find the culprit?
No, not yet.
Then is there something
you forgot to mention?
I suppose, yes.
Seriously? He must've been talking
to the old man until a moment ago.
Anyway, there's a location I'd like
forensics to examine immediately.
I'm counting on you.
What are you doing here?
Nothing.
Let's go. Standing around here
is just a waste of our time.
Let's see...
Mister.
What is it?
What do you think this is?
Bloodstains.
They lead that way.
That's it.
In other words, the culprit
is over there. Let's go.
Okay.
Hey, wait!
What's the problem?
Hey, Conan. We're pursuing a shooter, right?
Yeah, that's right.
Do the bloodstains have anything
to do with the shooter?
Oh, right...
Checkpoint
Please Stop!
It's Takagi.
Hello?
Mori-san, you were right.
Impressive as always, Detective.
I was right? About what?
Oh, please.
I'm talking about room 505.
As you suspected, we found gunshot residue.
What?
Then the shot was fired from that room?
Yes, but that's not all.
We also observed a luminol
reaction on the floor.
What?
The bloodstains were apparently wiped
away after splattering on the floor.
Judging by the volume,
the victim was probably...
The scuff marks in the hallway.
The scrap of plastic sheet.
The bullet that was fired, and
the bloodstains in the room.
Does that mean your shot
in the dark was right?
It's just a coincidence.
Coincidence?
Yeah, a coincidence.
But I wonder if it was a coincidence that
there were bloodstains in that room.
Coincidence?
Shot in the dark?
The bullet!
Takagi, have you figured out anything
from the bullet that was fired?
Yes, forensics examined the bullet extracted
from the victim's upper left arm.
It's a 30-caliber 7.62 millimeter full
metal jacket Mauser military bullet,
also known as a Tokarev bullet.
You can snipe someone with a
Tokarev from that distance?
I'm not sure,
but it's hard to imagine the culprit
used a handgun to snipe the victim.
Which means the victim was coincidentally
struck by a stray bullet?
Yes, it does seem that way.
Based on current evidence, the
culprit shot someone in room 505,
and the bullet passed through them.
That bullet flew outside the room,
pierced the monorail window,
and struck the victim's arm.
Is that even possible?
There's a hundred meters between
the window and the monorail line.
It passed through a person's body, pierced
a monorail window, and struck someone's arm.
It's possible.
Tokarevs are designed to
have excellent penetration.
It was a handgun and not a rifle?
Handguns and rifles have
different trajectories,
but striking the first victim must have
applied an angle to the bullet's path.
But that would mean...
It's impossible to do intentionally, but
with the right series of coincidences...
It's not impossible.
In other words, that's the truth.
Hey, Mister.
We found the connection between
the culprit and the bloodstains.
Found it.
Over here, Mister.
We can follow these bloodstains all we want,
but won't the culprit escape
while we're wasting time here?
What's this smell?
Mister, there's a woman tied up in there.
This smell...
Mister, it's gasoline!
Damn it. The door is locked.
We'll have to break the window.
Hurry!
Run, mister!
Mori-san!
Detective Takagi.
Are you hurt?
We're fine.
Did that woman say anything?
Yeah.
Tamura Kiyomi (32)
She was rather frightened and distraught,
but she said while walking around this area,
something was suddenly
placed against her mouth,
and she lost consciousness.
When she woke up after the attack,
she'd been abandoned inside the car.
Does she know who may have
wanted to kidnap her?
She has no idea who it could've been.
Detective Takagi, we've confirmed the
victim's background and questioned her.
We didn't find anything in her background or
testimony that would lead us to the culprit.
I see. Thank you.
Yes, sir. Excuse me.
No clues, huh?
Anyway, the culprit must have rather
violent tendencies to set fire to a car.
They've probably been watching
us tracking them down.
They did this to disrupt the investigation.
So, have there been any
developments with the apartment?
As you suspected, they seem to
have wrapped the victim in a sheet
and are transporting them somewhere.
Detective Takagi, why is the culprit
taking the victim away from the apartment?
Well...
They're obviously trying
to hide the evidence.
Don't you think carrying the victim
around with them is too risky?
I suppose.
Perhaps there's a reason
they have to take that risk.
If you were the culprit, what would you do?
What?
Well, normally you'd want to get rid
of the victim as soon as possible.
But you're still carrying them with you.
Where would you take them?
I don't know.
If you carried something as large
as a body through a normal place,
you'd draw attention to yourself.
Where would it seem natural to
carry something large around here?
That's it. That place would work.
That's right.
There's only one place
on this artificial island
where it wouldn't seem unnatural
to carry something large.
It matches the direction indicated
by the trail of blood, too.
Toto Market, Tokyo.
You certainly wouldn't
stand out at Toto Market
by carrying something large and heavy,
like a tuna or amberjack.
But what is the culprit trying
to accomplish by doing that?
Isn't determining that and
catching the culprit our job?
Toto Market
The culprit should be somewhere in here.
Episode Preview
What did the culprit come here to do?
This place is pretty big.
Episode Preview
It's big and deserted.
It's the perfect place to hide a body.
Episode Preview
We're playing hide-and-seek.
Are they hiding somewhere, or...?
Episode Preview
Why don't you stop playing dumb?
The Monorail Sniper Case
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Monorail Sniper Case, Part Two!"
The Monorail Sniper Case
(Part Two)
Turret Truck
Next Conan's hint! My first in a while.
A turret truck!
Turret Truck
Don't miss the next episode.
Hey, that's a tuna! Stop that turret truck!
Here we go!
Don't miss the next episode.
Just ignore them.