Iori.
Could we listen to that again
to confirm what he said?
Of course, Momiji-ojosama.
Do you really mean that, Heiji-kun?
Don't make me say it again!
If anything like that ever happens,
I'll do whatever you want!
Finally arriving after
swaying back and forth,
draw close to mysteries and
begin deducing the truth!
Momiji issues a mystery solving battle!
The treasure's location is written in code!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Ooka Momiji's Challenge
(Part One)
"Ooka Momiji's Challenge, Part One!"
Ooka Momiji's Challenge
(Part One)
Mori Detective Agency
I'm home.
What should I make for dinner?
I already spent a lot this
month, so I need to save money.
Jingisukan Beika
Coupon
A coupon for jingisukan.
Summer vacation starts tomorrow.
We can build up our strength
to fight the summer heat.
A text?
Messages
Ooka Momiji
Dad
Conan-kun
Sonoko
Dad
Conan-kun
Nozomi
Messages
Ooka Momiji
Dad
Conan-kun
Sonoko
Dad
Conan-kun
Nozomi
From M-Momiji-san?
From Ooka Momiji
Subj: No subject
Dear Mori Ran-sama, This is Ooka Momiji.
I apologize for the sudden message,
but I'd like Kudo Shinichi-kun,
whom I met in Kyoto, to decipher
a code for me. I've sent you a picture of the code.
From Ooka Momiji
Subj: No subject
Dear Mori Ran-sama, This is Ooka Momiji.
I apologize for the sudden message,
but I'd like Kudo Shinichi-kun,
whom I met in Kyoto, to decipher
a code for me. I've sent you a picture of the code.
From Ooka Momiji
Subj: No subject
Dear Mori Ran-sama, This is Ooka Momiji.
I apologize for the sudden message,
but I'd like Kudo Shinichi-kun,
whom I met in Kyoto, to decipher
a code for me. I've sent you a picture of the code.
"Dear Mori Ran-sama."
"This is Ooka Momiji."
I apologize for the sudden message,
but I'd like Kudo Shinichi-kun,
whom I met in Kyoto, to
decipher a code for me.
I've sent you pictures of the code.
A code?
Attachments
The treasure is here!
From your football-loving mother
"A housekeeper who worked for a wealthy man
for many years passed away at
his mansion the other day."
"Just before she died, she sent
this code to her four sons."
Apparently she wanted to
leave the incredible treasure
her employer gave her to her sons.
She loved mysteries and sent each
of her sons a different code,
so they'd have to work together
to find the treasure.
However, after the brothers shared
their codes with each other,
correspondence from the
eldest son suddenly stopped.
Believing the eldest brother may
have already solved the code,
and encountered some kind of trouble
at the treasure's location,
the three brothers reached out
to the wealthy man's family.
As the Ooka family has a
relationship with them,
the family reached out to us
to ask us to decipher the code.
I heard Kudo Shinichi-kun is a
famous high school detective.
I wanted to message him directly, but
I don't have his contact information,
so I messaged you instead
since we exchanged numbers.
I happen to have plans to go to Tokyo today.
I'll fill you
in on the details today at 4PM
on the Haido Chuo Building roof.
Best regards, Ooka Momiji
I happen to have plans to go to Tokyo today.
I'll fill you
in on the details today at 4PM
on the Haido Chuo Building roof.
Best regards, Ooka Momiji
"I happen to have plans
to go to Tokyo today."
I happen to have plans to go to Tokyo today.
I'll fill you
in on the details today at 4PM
on the Haido Chuo Building roof.
Best regards, Ooka Momiji
"I'll fill you in on the details today at
4PM on the Haido Chuo Building roof."
I happen to have plans to go to Tokyo today.
I'll fill you
in on the details today at 4PM
on the Haido Chuo Building roof.
Best regards, Ooka Momiji
That's only three hours from now!
I need to call Shinichi right away.
But I'm still too embarrassed
to speak to him directly...
Mori Detective Agency
I guess I can text him.
I have to send him the code anyway.
Summer vacation starts tomorrow!
Let's play tons of games
at the professor's house!
Yeah!
Let's enjoy our vacation!
The treasure is here!
From your football-loving mother
Conan-kun.
Huh?
Quit scowling and play games with us.
Yeah, sure.
It's all right.
He's currently engrossed in another game.
The game of deciphering a code.
Yeah, I guess.
Where'd you get that code?
Ran sent it to me.
Sounds like there's a story behind it.
Have you solved it yet?
No, I still have no idea.
What's wrong, Genta-kun?
Are you itchy?
I suddenly started feeling itchy
after eating these crackers.
They're ordinary shrimp-flavored crackers.
Kojima-kun, do you ever feel itchy
after touching shrimp or crab?
Huh? Everyone gets itchy from peeling shrimp.
Right?
No, not at all.
I don't get itchy.
Kojima-kun, you might be
allergic to shellfish.
You shouldn't eat any more of those crackers.
What? But I love these!
No eating them!
How many did you eat?
First I had three, then I had two more.
Since one was taken from me
just now, I've only eaten four.
Sounds like your addition and subtraction
abilities need fixing, too.
Addition and subtraction...
What?
Uh, nothing.
Mori Detective Agency
Shinichi still hasn't responded yet.
I have to start heading to the Haido Chuo
Building soon or I won't make it in time.
Maybe I'll call him after all.
I'm home.
Welcome back.
Shinichi-niichan called me.
What?
He said he's too busy to go to the Haido Chuo
Building, so he asked me to go with you instead.
I'll go put my backpack away.
Okay...
Why did he call Conan-kun instead of me?
Maybe Shinichi's too embarrassed
to call me directly, too.
That tall building is the
Haido Chuo Building, right?
Yeah.
Excuse me. You're Kudo Shinichi-sama's
companion Ran Mori-sama, aren't you?
Come in.
Thank you.
Hattori-kun and Kazuha-chan?
What are you two doing here?
I could ask you the same thing.
Did Momiji invite you here, too?
Yeah, she did.
Does that mean Momiji asked
Kudo-kun to solve a code?
Yeah, she did.
I knew it!
Which means this is a contest
between me and Kudo.
What's going on?
This afternoon, at our school gate...
3 Hours Earlier...
It's finally over.
Heiji-kun.
3 Hours Earlier...
Congratulations on finishing
your first semester.
It's you, Momiji.
What's up?
I'd like you to do something
for me, Heiji-kun.
The treasure is here!
From your football-loving mother
I see.
I bet you're worried something might've
happened to the eldest brother who solved the code,
so you want me to solve it
and go check things out.
But the eldest brother probably
ran off with the treasure
so he could keep it to himself,
so there's no point in solving this.
I see.
So you can't solve it either.
I didn't say that!
I could solve this thing faster than anyone!
Anyone?
If there's a high school student
who can solve this code before you,
will you do me a favor?
Sure, fine.
Heiji!
Do you really mean that, Heiji-kun?
Don't make me say it again!
If anything like that ever happens,
I'll do whatever you want!
Iori.
Yes, miss. I recorded the audio.
I'll do whatever you want!
I'll fill you in on the details today
at 4PM on the Haido Chuo Building roof.
4PM? That's just three hours from now!
Hey, Momiji!
It's all right.
We've already acquired
tickets to Haneda for you.
That's not the problem here.
It's up to you whether
or not you want to come.
But understand that if you don't,
it will mean Momiji-ojosama wins.
After he said that, we flew here in a hurry.
Isn't that a bad thing?
Doesn't Momiji-san have
feelings for Hattori-kun?
Exactly. She'll obviously
ask Heiji to marry her.
Heiji said she probably wants to play karuta
with him again like when they were kids, but...
I see. I was wondering why she asked
Shinichi instead of Hattori-kun.
Anyway, Ran-chan, I hate to
ask you to do this, but...
Could you ask Kudo-kun to
let Heiji win this time?
Little Miss Leaf, don't you think
that would be against the rules?
Th-That's Momiji's voice.
Where are you?
Kazuha-chan.
There's something on your
collar. It looks like a brooch.
A mic and speaker?
He must've stuck it on me then!
Hey, Momiji!
It's all right.
Momiji's butler must've secretly
attached it to me then!
Momiji, you're listening, aren't you?!
Quit sneaking around and show yourself!
In that case, perhaps I shall.
Come on, Momiji!
H-Hey, Kazuha-chan.
Isn't this circle drawn on the floor...?
Thank you for waiting, everyone.
I am Ooka Momiji.
Skip the formal greeting.
Fill us in on those details you promised us.
Those details are only
a few additional words.
The message "From your football-loving
mother" was written on the code,
but she apparently never
watched a football,
or in other words, a soccer
game once in her life.
Sh-She'd never seen...
...a soccer game?
Which means we should
focus our attention on...
...the word "football" at the end of the code.
In the first three codes, the characters
spelling "foot" are a little thicker.
Football
But in the final code, the "ba"
are a little thicker.
Football
Why?
Huh? I don't see Kudo Shinichi-kun.
What happened to him?
I sent him the pictures of the code,
but he said he was too busy to come,
so Conan-kun and I came in his place.
But doesn't Kudo-kun's absence give
Heiji-kun a significant advantage?
It'll be fine. I'm on a call
with Shinichi-niichan right now.
Seriously, why Conan-kun?
Fine, then.
Now that you have all the information
you need to solve the code,
ready, go!
Please let me know once
you've solved the code.
Whoever tells me the answer
first will be the winner.
I'd like to remind you that a man's
safety depends on you solving this code.
We'd like you to solve it
as quickly as possible.
Additionally, in the event that
Hattori-sama loses to Kudo-sama,
don't forget that Hattori-sama has agreed
to fulfill a request from Momiji-ojosama.
Yeah, I know.
Hattori, what's this about a request?
I'm sure it's no big deal.
Don't worry about it.
Oh, really?
In that case, everyone, shall
we get something to eat?
After all, they say you can't
fight on an empty stomach.
But, Momiji-san, why are we starting in Tokyo?
Because before her death, the
housekeeper who made the code
was working at a wealthy man's mansion
located in Tokyo's Haido City.
I thought the treasure she received from
her master must be in Tokyo as well.
Wouldn't it be hidden at the mansion, then?
Since it would inconvenience her master
to have her sons search his mansion,
the housekeeper's letter said
the treasure wasn't there.
Then maybe it's at the home of
that housekeeper and her sons.
They sold their home when the
housekeeper's husband passed away,
and it's no longer there.
After that, she put her sons up for adoption
and began working as a live-in
housekeeper at the mansion.
After the four sons were
separated as children,
they apparently haven't met once in 30 years.
Huh.
I heard only their mother the housekeeper
and the eldest son exchanged messages
with the three younger brothers.
Then maybe some bad guy who
heard about the treasure
pretended to be one of the
brothers so he could swipe it?
I wouldn't worry about that.
Apparently the four brothers
have a rather obvious mark
on the palms of their hands.
An obvious...
...mark?
It's a burn scar from when the
four brothers were children.
A burn?
All four brothers?
Supposedly they were protecting
their mother from a serious burn.
Huh.
Sounds like an honorable injury, then.
Excuse me, Ran-sama.
Yes?
Forgive me, but we've been walking
for ten minutes and 30 seconds.
Have we still not arrived at our destination?
We should be there soon.
When I went with some friends the
other day, it was really good.
That's it right there.
That pancake shop.
That store's pancakes are really good.
But there's a huge line.
Tokyoites are so patient.
We sure are.
It's normal to wait an hour
in line at a popular shop.
No, Ran-chan. That's an insult
coming from a Kyoto woman.
Huh?
What she actually means is, "look at
these idle people wasting their time."
What?
It's not an insult.
I'm dropping a hint so she can figure
it out herself before she gets hurt.
That's even more hurtful.
If only they'd add the time spent in
line plus the fatigue from standing
and subtract that from the food's price.
Add...
And subtract...
Haido Harbor Warehouse 4!
What?
That's where the treasure
is, Shinichi-niichan?
How did you arrive at that conclusion?
The key to solving the code was
in the word football after all.
In the first three codes, the
characters spelling foot were bolded.
Football
The character for foot can also mean add.
"Foot (Ashi)"
"Add (Tase)"
The character for foot can also mean add.
When you lay the three codes over each other,
they form a series of odd characters.
But I can't read what it says.
That's why you need the
arrows from the fourth code.
In the fourth code, the characters
spelling ball are bolded.
Football
In the fourth code, the characters
spelling ball are bolded.
Ball
Ba sounds like bow here, so
you're meant to subtract.
Bow
Ba sounds like bow here, so
you're meant to subtract.
Subtract
Which means we have to erase the
arrows from the odd characters
The treasure is here!
From your football-loving mother
made from overlaying the first three codes,
The treasure is here!
From your football-loving mother
which turns them into characters we can read.
The treasure is here!
From your football-loving mother
which turns them into characters we can read.
Haido kou no dai 4 souko (Haido Harbor Warehouse 4)
That's what Shinichi-niichan said.
Huh.
You're right.
It says, "Haido Harbor Warehouse 4."
In other words, we'll find the treasure
if we go to Warehouse 4 at Haido Harbor.
Since both of them solved
it at the same time,
doesn't that mean there's
no winner of this contest?
Are you sure?
If Kudo-sama told Conan-sama the
answer after solving the code,
and Conan-sama then explained it to us,
then doesn't that mean Kudo-sama solved
it slightly sooner than Hattori-sama
who explained the solution
after solving it himself?
You're right! Excellent observation, Iori!
No way. As soon as he
solved the code, Kudo—
Yeah. I think Shinichi-niichan
solved it a little quicker than—
Watch it, Kudo! I'll expose
your true identity for real!
I'm kidding.
I unintentionally spoke at the same time as
Hattori-niichan because his shouting surprised me,
but they solved it at
basically the same time.
That's a problem.
Then how about this?
We'll head to Warehouse 4 at Haido Harbor.
Whoever determines why correspondence from
the eldest brother suddenly
stopped will be the winner.
What's with you guys, anyway?
You didn't have these cars ready because
you expected this to happen, did you?
The car behind us the girls are
riding in is yours, too, right?
That will be revealed in due time.
Hey, Momiji.
It's a good thing the boys solved
the code so quickly this time,
but what were you going to do if they couldn't
solve it after you came all the way to Tokyo?
I don't know. What would I have done?
You hadn't thought about that?
Haido Harbor
Ah, you solved the code, did you?
Allow me to show you to Warehouse 4.
I see.
So you were told to escort
people to the warehouse
if they made it here
and showed you the code.
Yes.
Did someone besides us show up?
A man with a beard showed
up early this morning.
After him, another man showed up.
And just now, two men showed
up one after another.
Four people came here?
Maybe it was the four brothers.
Yeah. They must've all solved the code.
We're here.
That's Warehouse 4.
Hello. Anyone here?
Seriously? If you're here,
you should've said...
What's going on here?! Explain!
I-I don't know.
I came here at my brother's instructions
and found him like this.
I also came here because I received
a message from my brother.
M-Me, too.
Then you guys must be three of four brothers
who received a code from their mother.
Which means the dead guy
is the eldest brother.
Who are you people?
We were hired to solve the code in order
to confirm the well-being of your brother.
Oh, right.
Mom worked as a housekeeper.
You're connected to the mansion somehow.
Do you have any idea why your
brother ended up like this?
He probably lost his footing up there.
And then fell to his death.
We don't know if it was an
accident or suicide, though.
Has anyone touched the body?
No, we haven't.
Then this wasn't an accident or a suicide.
It was a murder.
What?
And it seems like one of you
three brothers is the culprit.
This is hardly the time for a contest.
Yeah.
No.
Wouldn't whoever arrives at the truth
behind this case be the winner?
Episode Preview
So he fell to his death.
We don't know yet if it was
an accident or suicide.
Episode Preview
It was murder.
What?
Episode Preview
All three of them claim they came here
because their murdered eldest brother texted them.
Episode Preview
Normally you'd assume whoever arrived first
pushed the eldest brother and killed him.
Episode Preview
Who arrived first?
Well...
Episode Preview
It was...
Ooka Momiji's Challenge
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Ooka
Momiji's Challenge, Part Two!"
Ooka Momiji's Challenge
(Part Two)
Jingisukan
Heiji-niichan, ready, and...
Next Conan's hint!
Jingisukan
Jingisukan!
Don't miss the next episode.
This is a ridiculous contest
I've gotten caught up in!
Don't miss the next episode.
I'm the one who should be saying that.