I'm absolutely certain. It's this building.
Just the thought of this mansion becoming
a factory that makes tasty cakes...
Private Property
Do Not Enter
Is kind of exciting.
I want shortcake and mont blanc.
In that case, I'd like
cheesecake and apple pie.
Then I want chocolate cake,
roll cake, pancakes, and flapjacks.
You're being too greedy, Genta-kun.
Huh?
Hey, isn't that...?
Is that real?
Yeah, right.
Private Property
Do Not Enter
This must be the place.
Finally arriving after
swaying back and forth,
draw close to mysteries and
begin deducing the truth!
The shadow of a woman moves
through a ruined building!
In the air is the smell of
something sweet and a case!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Ballad of the Woman Who Loved Cake
"Ballad of the Woman Who Loved Cake!"
Pull yourselves together, guys.
What happened?
What? A corpse came back to life?
It's true, Conan!
A-A-A hand reached out from beneath the debris!
It started moving, and a
woman wearing red emerged!
Looks like that zombie is injured.
If we follow this trail of blood...
Then we'll learn the true
identity of that lady zombie.
How far does this trail go, though?
Western Confections
Huh? Isn't this place...
Western Confections Paradise.
Huh? Isn't that woman...
Apparently there's a desolate
building outside Haido City
where they're planning to establish
a new factory for this bakery.
A desolate building? What's that?
An old building no longer in use by anyone.
Sounds interesting. Let's check it out.
We don't have school next
Thursday, so let's go then.
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
Jeez.
The same woman is in the same seat
eating the same cake as last week.
She's pretty.
Yeah, but she's wearing really dirty clothes.
Those stains...
Aren't they a similar color to that debris?
Then maybe...
She's the lady zombie?
Thank you.
Her ankle is injured.
It's gotta be her.
The lady zombie is angry.
After her!
Wait, Conan-kun!
She entered a building.
This is Western Confections
Paradise's main factory.
Western Confections
President's Office
Authorized Personnel Only
Do Not Enter
The doorman will never let us in.
What should we do?
We came this far.
Hey, guys.
Over here.
Service Entrance
What's the matter, Yayoi-san?
Th-The president!
Brother!
C-Call the police.
And let everyone in the
office know about this.
Understood.
I'll tell my wife.
Yes, sir.
This is my wife's handkerchief.
Could she have done this?
Hello? What's wrong?
What? The president's been murdered?
He drowned in red bean paste?
Yes. Anyway, where are you now?
I see. In that case...
What? Let's have lunch at the apartment?
Last night's leftover sukiyaki over rice?
Yeah, that'll do.
See you later.
Call Back
Call Ended
Ogawa Hiroshi
Block
Call Back
Call Ended
Ogawa Hiroshi
Block
He's creating an alibi.
Could he have done this?
This has turned into a serious situation.
Do you think the lady zombie
is connected to the case?
I don't know yet.
The Detective Boys are on the case.
What? Hey.
Let's split up and gather information.
Hey.
Conan, you watch the crime scene.
Wait.
Detective Boys, roll out!
Yeah!
Western Confections
The deceased is Western Confections Paradise
company president Ogawa Akira-san, 35 years old.
He apparently suffocated
to death when his face
was pushed into a sink
filled with red bean paste.
What an eccentric murder.
Was the victim making a huge amount
of red bean soup or something?
Despite being the president of
a Western confections factory,
he apparently had become absorbed
in Japanese sweet-making recently.
Imagine being killed by the red
bean paste you made yourself.
Wh-What are you doing here?
I thought I'd assist with the investigation
since I'm already here to pick
up the kids as their guardian.
So, where's the boy?
He was around here until a moment ago.
Inspector, I've brought the
people who discovered the body.
I'm sorry to trouble you when you're already
tired, but we have a few questions for you.
Ogawa Hiroshi (29)
Western Confections Paradise VP
You're the victim Ogawa Akira-san's younger
brother and Vice President Ogawa Hiroshi-san
and the president's secretary
Ito Yayoi-san, correct?
Ito Yayoi (31)
President's Secretary
The estimated time of death is 12PM.
It's not that you're suspects,
but where were you at that time?
Around that time, I was crushed
beneath some concrete.
What? C-Crushed beneath concrete?
At the ruined building where we're
planning to build our new factory.
Ruined building?
I was suppose to meet the president there.
We were going to elope.
What?!
We were in love.
But... no matter how long I waited,
the president never showed up.
I became overwhelmed by sadness
and went on a violent rampage.
Then the concrete fell,
crushing me beneath it.
Apparently I was unconscious for
some time until I was awoken
by the dreadful voices of the Detective Boys.
Those children can attest
to what happened after that.
I should thank them.
So she knew we were following her.
Hiroshi-san, what were you
doing around that time?
I returned to my apartment
to have lunch with my wife.
We had last night's leftover
sukiyaki over rice.
Conan-kun.
How'd it go?
A lot of facts have come to light.
The president was trying to develop Japanese
sweets to sell at Western Confections Paradise,
but the VP was strongly opposed,
which caused friction between them.
Hiroshi-san!
Ah, Hanako. Over here.
So, that's the VP's wife?
Ogawa Hanako (28)
Hiroshi's Wife
Yes.
His wife sided with the VP and
also opposed the president.
Ma'am, where were you around 12PM today?
I was at home with Hiroshi-san.
We were eating beef bowls for lunch.
She's matching her husband's
lie and fabricating an alibi.
The VP and his wife both think the other
did it and are protecting each other.
The VP's wife is a rude lady.
She bumped into me when she got out of
her red car at the bottom of the steps.
But she smelled nice, like she'd just gotten
out of the shower after shampooing her hair.
A red car, shampoo...
I got a bunch of information, too.
Apparently the murdered president
planned to convince the VP
and his wife who opposed him and build a
Japanese sweets factory in that ruined building.
The ruined building, debris...
Anyway, Ito-san, you seem to know a lot
about the situation at your company
and the condition of your employees.
Yes.
Though my title is the president's secretary, I'm
responsible for taking care of the entire company.
She always assists us with the details.
You know, that lady...
Isn't a zombie at all.
Yeah, she's an ordinary pretty lady.
Come to think of it, she said she was
grateful your terrified voices woke her up.
What?
The thing is...
It was actually...
The other way around.
The other way around?
She's not wrong.
We did scream in terror.
But it was because she came back to life.
Guys, tell me more about that.
Everyone, if you could
please wait down below.
Confirm their alibis.
Yes, sir.
Anyway, where did those kids go?
We need to discuss what
we're going to do next.
You're right.
Let's hold an emergency
meeting in your office.
Right now?
The sooner, the better.
I'm sure we'll come up with a good
solution while eating something sweet.
Wh-What's wrong with that kid?
How did you get in here?
Hiroshi-san, wait!
What's your problem?
Your wife didn't do it.
Vice President's Office
Hiroshi-san, what was that about?
Apparently some kids had entered the woods,
but I couldn't find them.
It was probably the Detective Boys.
I need to contact someone
regarding something.
You two go ahead and eat without me.
I'll be right back.
Where did that kid go?
Hey, you kids.
Hello.
It's just you kids?
Where's four-eyes?
He went that way.
That way? All right.
Don't wander around too much, kids.
Okay.
Hey, Detective Takagi.
Conan-kun?! Mori-san's been looking for you.
Yeah, sure.
Anyway, he said he wanted forensics
to look into something for him.
What?
Excuse me.
Oh, do the Detective Boys like cake as well?
Yeah.
I see.
I enjoy cake, too.
Or rather, I love it dearly.
I haven't thanked you yet.
Thanked us?
For testifying that you found me crushed
beneath concrete in the ruined building.
Thank you, Detective Boys.
I sensed you fearfully entering
the ruined building then.
We were laughing then.
Then a woman came back to life.
Oh, is that right?
You used the Detective Boys
to fabricate an alibi.
Isn't that right?
What are you talking about?
Hey!
I finally found you.
How dare you wandering around the crime
scene like some little wandering...
Hey! He's so heavy...
This case is the sad ballad
of a woman who loves cake.
The sad ballad of a woman who loves cake?
What is this old dude talking about?
Wait, where is his voice coming from?
Listen to what I have to say
as we dance a waltz together.
What?!
They're...
...dancing a waltz.
This ballad began one week ago at the Western
Confections Paradise cake shop in Haido City,
when the woman who loves cake learned of the
Detective Boys' plan to explore a ruined building.
This morning, the woman who loves
cake went to said ruined building.
Using a long thread and plywood boards,
she rigged some debris to fall automatically.
Conan found signs of this contrivance
in the ruined structure.
On the path between the ruined building
and Western Confections Paradise,
she left a trail of blood beforehand
so the Detective Boys would follow it.
She returned to the office and waited for
the right moment to speak to the VP's wife.
I'm sorry.
The president forgot some documents
at the new factory site.
No problem.
The VP's wife headed to the
ruined building in a red car,
where she triggered the tripwire
and was crushed beneath the debris.
And then...
Awoken by the laughter of the
Detective Boys who had arrived,
she failed to notice their presence
and hastily left out of fear.
At that time, Conan saw a red
car driving down the hill.
Since the VP's wife didn't return to
the office until after the murder,
she must've returned home and taken a shower.
Meanwhile, the woman who loves cake
headed to the president's office
as though nothing had happened.
She waited for an opportunity
to kill the president,
left behind the VP's wife's handkerchief
she'd stolen beforehand, and left.
The VP and his wife suspected each other.
The lies they told ultimately fabricated
an alibi for the woman who loves cake.
For the woman who loves cake,
predicting the VP and his wife's actions
and manipulating them was a simple task.
After all, she's the secretary.
Then the woman who loves cake waited.
She wore clothes similar to the VP's
wife, stained her ankle with blood,
and ate cake while she waited,
as though waiting for a lover,
for the Detective Boys to follow the trail.
And that's how the Detective Boys
were used to fabricate an alibi
for the sad woman who loves cake.
Why are you looking at me like that?
What proof is there that
I killed the president?
This is all just the nonsensical reasoning
of an old dude who reeks of cigarettes!
You're right. There's no evidence.
See? Told you so.
But what about the VP and
his wife's testimony?
There's no such testimony.
What makes the woman who loves cake say that?
What?
On what basis do you make that claim?
What basis? None, it's just what I think.
No, there is something.
This old dude who reeks of cigarettes knows.
He admitted it?!
What are you claiming to know?
I know the woman who loves cake poisoned
the VP and his wife and tried to kill them.
I've had enough of you!
Now you've said it! How dare you!
Stay away from me!
Get off of me!
A murderer has no right
to speak to me that way.
But don't worry.
What?
What do you see on the
other side of that glass?
The glass? What?
B-But how?
I told them.
The culprit is the secretary.
I had them pretend to be poisoned
without eating the matcha cake.
The police told me earlier that
they found poison in the cake.
And so, the ballad of
the woman who loves cake
ended with her betrayal
by the cake she loves.
I couldn't forgive the president.
How could my beloved Western Confections
Paradise make Japanese sweets of all things?
At first, they opposed the idea,
but the VP and his wife were just as guilty
for accepting the president's suggestion.
Western Confections Paradise was my dream.
And my precious Western Confections Paradise
needed to be a paradise of Western
confections, true to its name.
Shortcake, mont blanc, cheesecake.
My beloved Western sweets.
Apple pie, chocolate cake, éclairs.
A paradise of Western sweets.
We heard everything.
Ito Yayoi-san.
Could you tell us more about that elsewhere?
Ito-san?
Cream puff and maritozzo.
Shortcake.
Cheesecake, apple pie, chocolate cake.
Mont blanc, too.
Ito-san.
Ito Yayoi-san, is that all right?
We'd like to speak with you.
Yes.
I understand.
I wanted to create a true
paradise of Western sweets.
So they're making a Japanese sweets
factory instead of a cake factory.
Daifuku.
Dorayaki.
Kintsuba.
Amanatto.
Potato yokan.
Soft yokan.
Steamed yokan.
Goodbye, building. Now you're gone.
Episode Preview
I'm the foundation.
My friends are on their way to assist me.
Episode Preview
You've been spacing out a lot recently.
I told him to eat shit.
Episode Preview
Bingo!
This is the story of a group of new police
recruits who joined the academy in the spring.
Episode Preview
Police Academy Arc Wild Police Story
CASE. Matsuda Jinpei
The next episode of Conan is "Police Academy
Arc Wild Police Story CASE. Matsuda Jinpei!"
Police Academy Arc Wild Police Story
CASE. Matsuda Jinpei
Onizuka Classroom
Instructor Onizuka Hachizo
Assistant Instructor Matsumoto Naota
Outrageous Behavior
Onizuka Classroom
Instructor Onizuka Hachizo
Assistant Instructor Matsumoto Naota
Outrageous Behavior
Next Conan's hint!
Onizuka Classroom
Instructor Onizuka Hachizo
Assistant Instructor Matsumoto Naota
Outrageous Behavior
Outrageous Behavior!
Onizuka Classroom
Instructor Onizuka Hachizo
Assistant Instructor Matsumoto Naota
Outrageous Behavior
Is everyone ready for classes to start?
Don't miss the next episode.
It's finally time for the police academy arc!