Yes. I'm sorry,
but I have no idea where I am right now.
I was chasing after a man
who was suspected of
stealing a large amount of explosives,
but I was taken by surprise
and when I woke up...
Are you able to use the GPS?
It seems that he has taken my smartphone.
I had to borrow a flip phone
belonging to a body
that was left in the basement
so that I could call you.
A body?
Yes.
But its battery is running out.
Was the deceased killed by the target?
It's likely.
But it's all right.
I could escape from
this basement by myself...
No, Kazami.
If you make a mistake while moving around
and calling for backup,
the culprit will make a move
and we may not be able to
avoid the worst-case scenario.
I'll go there.
Before you end up dead, that is.
Mysterious clouds obstruct the field of vision.
A sparkle that clears them up with deduction!
Suspicious people are gathering at a farm.
Things take a sudden turn
when Amuro makes his move.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
"The Live Coals on the Farm (Part 1)"
I can't wait to see the new chickens!
I hope they're happy and healthy.
Right? The last two that died were always sick,
and we didn't get to take care of them much.
They were just old rather than sick.
They were the ones I took care of
when I was in my first year of
elementary school.
You say that, Conan...
But aren't you still a first-year
in elementary school?
I mean...
Are you stupid or something?
Everyone, listen up.
Don't forget to learn how to
take proper care of the chickens
we're getting from the people at the farm.
Yes, Ms. Kobayashi!
Is it really going to be all right?
Why are you bringing the kids along?
If you wanted them to learn
how to raise chickens,
I think we could teach them ourselves.
Ms. Wakasa...
I wanted to carry this information
with me to the grave.
It's a secret.
Sorry?
I'm terrible at handling chickens!
Is that so?
Ever since I was a kid
and I saw a flock of
vultures devouring a dead zebra on television,
I've been so scared of those bulging eyes
and pointed beaks.
That's why even if I can't do it myself,
I thought I could explain it more easily
if I could record videos of the children
taking care of the chickens.
But the officer you're dating...
Isn't his name Shiratori?
It's just a name, isn't it?
Would you think of someone named Karasudaas
a crow?
No, I wouldn't.
But crows have the image of
being dark and cunning.
They also move in groups
and are always up to something.
They're not that approachable, either.
Then again, people like that
might even be cheerful and fun to be with.
That's totally possible!
Crows.
Renya Karasuma.
The head of the organisation
that produced the medicine
that shrunk my body.
And Ms. Wakasa is a candidate for Rum,
the number two of the organisation.
Speaking of which,
the owner of the farm
we're headed to is called Hatoyama.
I hope he's peaceful like a dove.
Are you also going to Hatoyama Farm?
( Junya Hitsuka (34) )
What a coincidence.
I'm heading to that area myself.
Why are you going there?
I have some interviews to do there.
Well, it's like a tour of spiritual hot spots
where the same people often gather.
Judging by the way you look,
you must be the same. Am I right?
( Nanbu Takashi (56) )
I'm heading there for my research.
Unlike you, I'm not here for the money.
But I thought all that research
would turn into money in the end.
Interview? Research? Money?
He's watching something!
Is it a sci-fi movie?
( Shogo Kano (43) )
Kids shouldn't look at other people's phones!
Get off!
- I'm sorry.
It's okay because
I took a video of his phone screen!
I'm looking it up right now.
What do you think you're doing?
Delete that video right now!
- What?
- I said delete that video!
- Please stop...
- Excuse me.
Let go of me!
The candidate for Rum is unable to move.
I guess I have to use my tranquiliser dart...
Mr. Amuro!
Who are you?
How about we end this fight here?
And Mitsuhiko, you should delete
other people's private videos,
especially when they're
uncomfortable with it.
- Yes, sir.
- Will that be all?
Yeah.
You must be Amuro.
Yes, that's me.
I'm Kobayashi, the kids' class teacher.
I've heard so many things about you.
This is Amuro.
He works at a cafe,
but he's also a detective.
I'm Wakasa, the assistant class teacher.
Nice to meet you.
You too.
Mr. Amuro, why are you on this bus?
Like you, I'm also heading to
Hatoyama Farm for some business.
I see.
Well, a lot of things happened,
so I'll tell you more when we get there.
(Hatoyama Farm)
Nobody seems to be inside.
But the gate was wide open.
I don't see any cows, either.
Yeah.
I heard that the farm will be demolished
to make way for a golf course.
The employees aren't even around anymore.
That's why they're giving the chickens
to our school for free.
Yes, they said they might as well do so.
How about we take a look at the chickens
until the owner of the farm arrives?
Do you know where they might be?
They're probably going to be
where the arrow leads.
(Chicken Coop)
They're probably going to be where the arrow leads.
Seriously?
There's not a single chicken inside!
Why?
Could it be that they set aside
the two chickens they're giving away
and sold off the rest already?
Everyone, have a look outside!
Look! There's a huge hole in the wall!
Maybe they could've escaped from here.
You may be right.
Let's take a look somewhere else.
Yes.
What's with the pile of dirt
that's covering up the hole?
There's a toilet!
Nice! I've been holding my urge all this time.
Me too, actually.
Then let's take a toilet break
before going to find the owner of the farm.
You're right.
It's a chicken!
Hey, Conan.
You'd better tell us
the reason you came here.
Did I say that I would?
If I make a sound,
the chicken will run away from me.
I have to be quiet...
What? Yoshida has gone missing?
She seemed to have gone off somewhere
while we were on our toilet break.
Anyway, let's split up and look for her.
I'll go with Mr. Amuro,
Edogawa, and Tsuburaya.
Then I'll take Kojima and Haibara with me.
(Bishop)
What's this?
A shogi piece...
Hold on. I've seen this bishop piece somewhere.
What are you doing, Kojima?
We're leaving.
Okay.
I've got you!
What?
Where am I?
A lot of burnt twigs are scattered around.
There are also weird tracks on the ground.
And I wonder what this is.
What are these long and skinny things?
What?
Ayumi!
Yoshida!
If you can hear us, please answer!
Are you looking for someone?
What? Yes...
I'm the younger brother of Gisuke Hatoyama,
who owns Hatoyama Farm, Umisuke.
( Hatoyama Umisuke (37) )
I haven't been able to
contact my brother in the last two days,
so I came here to check on him.
We're looking for a girl
who came here with us.
She's a first-year in elementary school.
Have you seen her?
Yes.
I've seen her.
Really?
Perhaps...
This is the girl you're looking for?
- Oh, no...
- Ayumi!
Don't move.
First, put your phones on the ground,
and follow my instructions as we walk.
If you make any weird moves,
I will stab her.
(Hatoyama Farm)
Go down those stairs.
Goodbye.
Furuya?
Furuya, it's you!
You came to save me, didn't you?
- Kazami!
- Thank goodness! Now I'll be saved!
I've been caught too,
so things haven't changed.
I'm pretty sure this man
is Mr. Amuro's subordinate.
Excuse me...
Who's this "Furuya" you're referring to?
It's my alias.
I use it for my detective work.
And this is my assistant.
I'm Danroku Hida!
More importantly...
There's a body lying on the bed.
What?
And his face...
It's the same as the man
who trapped us here!
He's slightly older than
the person we met,
but they do look alike.
This is Gisuke Hatoyama!
He's the person who's giving the chickens
to Teitan Elementary School
and the owner of Hatoyama Farm!
Have you met him before?
No, we had only talked on the phone.
But I found pictures of him
when I looked him up online.
Then when that man said he was
the farm owner's younger brother,
he wasn't lying.
How about you tell us the real reason
you came to the farm?
That's because I received a call from Hida.
Yes. That was 30 hours ago.
I received information
that a large amount of explosives
were stolen from a construction site.
We were concerned
that a terrorist attack could occur,
so we tracked Umisuke Hatoyama,
who was one of the suspected workers.
That's how I came to the farm.
I was caught unaware and knocked out.
And when I came to,
I was already in this basement.
I was somehow able to contact Furuya...
I mean, Amuro using the deceased's phone.
I came here to help him escape
but was caught instead.
I see...
So detectives even do the same kind of work
as the secret police!
Well, they are public safety officials.
But what is Umisuke Hatoyama doing?
He killed his own brother
and stole explosives, too...
No, I believe that
Mr. Gisuke had killed himself.
Killed himself?
How could you tell?
There are marks left from
something around his neck,
but no signs of a struggle.
Is that so?
If someone else put a rope around his neck,
his nails would leave marks on it
from trying to take it off, right?
Things would be different
if both of his hands were tied,
but there aren't any marks on his wrists.
But if he were given a sleeping drug
before his neck was tied
and he was dropped from a high place...
I don't think that's what happened.
He probably hung himself
next to the desk in this room.
He's not wearing shoes either,
so he must have worn those boots.
I don't know if someone
laid him down on the bed...
But if someone did when he wore them,
wouldn't they have taken off the boots
and put them by the bed?
That can only mean
that he took off the boots himself
when he was getting onto that chair.
But when I came to,
the chair was upright.
I could see footprints on the seat as well,
even though they were wiped away
when I sat on it.
Were they footprints from a leather boot?
Come to think of it...
they were from a pair of leather shoes.
They must be the shoes of the man
who locked us in here.
It's likely that he discovered
his brother having hung himself
and got on the chair to
get him off of the rope.
The problem is why he tried to kill himself.
Perhaps he was researching something.
Look, there are highlighter stains
on the thumb and forefinger of his left hand.
You're right.
You use highlighters a lot while researching.
The colour gets on your left hand
if you can't cap the highlighter properly.
What's strange is that
there are pink, blue,
and yellow stains on his hand,
but only the yellow highlighter is missing
from his breast pocket.
I don't find it in the room,
so perhaps he misplaced
or dropped the yellow highlighter somewhere.
I'm more concerned about Ms. Wakasa
and the others who are outside.
If your phones were taken away,
there's no way to contact her.
There's no need to worry about that.
We have transceivers
on our detective badges.
What?
You're locked in the office basement
by the owner's brother?
Yes. We also found the owner's body
lying down in the basement, too.
Body?
So, did you find Ayumi?
Yes. He drugged her,
so she's still asleep.
We'll go and save you right away...
Wait! Don't rush in unprepared!
He's here with a large amount of explosives
that are stolen from the construction site!
Explosives?
There's no knowing what he'll do to you
if you're careless.
Anyway, the person who locked us up here
is Umisuke Hatoyama,
the farm owner's brother!
He's a man in his 30s with narrow eyes
and wearing a white safari hat.
Contact the police without him noticing...
Excuse me...
Are you looking for somebody?
Actually...
We were looking for the tourists
with children our age
who were on the bus with us earlier.
We wanted to get to know them better.
I see. You were talking about that family.
I told them that my brother,
the owner of the farm, isn't here,
so they left disappointed.
Is that so?
So he's away after all.
That's why there was no one at the office.
Well, it's my first time here
and I came alone,
so I ended up going around with this guy.
I'm not familiar with the area either,
so I thought I'd ask Mr. Hatoyama
about a few things
since I had met him once.
Something shocking
has happened to him recently,
so he's been admitted to a hospital.
He's in a hospital?
How's your brother doing?
He seems to be recovering,
but I received some instructions from him.
Instructions?
"Go to that place in the mountains."
"If you find it,"
"take it home without anyone else knowing"
"and hold on to it until I'm discharged."
What is the thing in the instructions?
I don't know.
It should be obvious if we go there.
How about we go there?
If you say you'll know when you go there.
Was it only you and the family
who came here on the bus?
There was someone else!
It was a huge and scary man!
Then let's find him,
and the four of us can go.
I wonder if we'll find him.
He went into the mountains
on his own, after all.
Okay, Haibara.
Call the police as soon as those men are gone.
I'm sorry but the battery
on my phone ran out.
And I left mine at home.
How about you use mine instead?
What?
Ms. Wakasa, there's a hole
in your back pocket.
What?
I don't have it. Is it gone?
Did you drop something?
Well, it's not that important...
Come to think of it, I saw Mr. Amuro
pick something up earlier.
It looked like a piece of wood.
The detective?
- Yes.
- We should contact the police right now!
You're right.
Ms. Wakasa!
I'm sorry, but we're unable to call the police.
Seriously?
In any case, the three of us
are heading to the office,
so let's continue when we get there.
Gosh. Where is it?
Just where am I?
A beam of light at night?
He was watching a movie about that?
Yes.
I heard someone saying,
"Who fired those skyrockets
in the middle of the mountains?"
in a low voice,
so I thought it was a sci-fi comedy.
Sci-fi comedy?
Furuya.
What have you been doing?
It's this shogi piece.
This bishop piece is damaged
on the lower left side.
I feel like I've seen this before somewhere.
When it comes to shogi,
you have to know about
Shukichi Haneda!
He's a master who has defended
his title six times.
How amazing!
Haneda...
Koji Haneda, the genius shogi player
who died mysteriously
in America 17 years ago!
(Bishop)
The only item missing from his belongings
in that incident was a bishop piece
(Bishop)
that he kept as a good luck charm
and never let go of.
The materials of unsolved and difficult cases
presented to me
during my police training mentioned that
it was the final piece
that was played in the first match
that he won against his master.
When Koji Haneda died,
his family said
there was no way he'd ever
let go of that shogi piece.
Only his murderer could have had it.
(Bishop)
The damage and the characters on the piece
are strikingly similar to the ones I saw
(Bishop)
in the pictures back then.
It seems hard to believe,
but could Koji Haneda's murderer
be on this farm?
(Hatoyama Farm)
As I expected, it's impossible.
Even the back door is locked.
We can't enter the office like this!
Ms. Wakasa, are you all right?
Are you hurt?
No...
But it looks like we can get in now
that the windowpane is broken.
You're right.
Ayumi!
You're awake.
No! Get away from me!
Ayumi!
It's okay, Ayumi.
The guy who kidnapped you isn't here.
Do you remember what happened
when you were kidnapped?
Did you see anything out of the ordinary?
I was chasing a chicken
and ended up somewhere strange
in the forest.
Somewhere strange?
Yes. There were lots of
burnt twigs lying around!
Burnt twigs?
And there was also something
like a drain dug into the ground.
A drain?
The hole in the wall of the chicken coop.
The pile of dirt covering up a hole
in the ground.
The video of a beam lighting up the night
that angered the guy
when Mitsuhiko and Ayumi were looking at it.
And the countless burnt tree twigs
and the drain dug into the ground.
I've finally figured it out.
I've figured out the reason
why those three came here on the bus!
(Next Episode)
If I recall,
those three were wearing hiking boots.
I see! So that's why they all had magnets!
Did you see them with the magnets?
Yes.
But what do you want us to do?
I want you to make them for me.
If there is a possibility that
they're coming here wearing those boots,
things will be just as we expect.
Next Conan,
"The Live Coals on the Farm (Part 2)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Highlighter"
Kazami, what are your summer holiday plans?
Are we even allowed to take a break?
Taking a break is part of work, too.