Oh, no. What have I done?
This is beyond just being careless.
Usually, I would've shouted for Ran to get it,
and things will be fine.
But right now,
Yoko Okino is at my detective agency.
Even if my mouth is forced open,
there's no way I can say it.
Mysterious clouds
obstruct the field of vision.
A sparkle that clears them up with deduction!
An SOS signal from a locked room.
The truth of the incident is shown
by the playing cards.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
"Yoko Okino And The Locked Room In The Attic
(Part 1)"
There's no way I can say it.
I can't say that we've run out of toilet paper!
That's it! I should use the phone.
If I can talk to Ran over the phone,
I shouldn't have to shout for it.
Hold on.
But if I'm not careful...
What?
There's no toilet paper,
so I should get you some?
Can't you shout more loudly?
Should I text her instead?
Huh? It's a text from Dad.
Mr. Kogoro's in the toilet, isn't he?
He said there was no toilet paper.
I can't. I have a bad feeling about this.
Now that it's come to this,
I can only ask
the clever but cheeky kid in glasses.
At this time,
Uncle Kogoro had no way of knowing
that this decision would guide him
to solve a difficult case.
(Two hours ago)
Hey, Dad.
Have you seen the buttercream sandwiches?
I put them in the fridge...
Buttercream sandwiches?
This is the last one.
What? You ate them?
Well, I was getting a bit hungry.
Was I not supposed to?
You weren't!
They were two days past the expiration date.
I should've thrown them out sooner.
I'm sorry, Dad.
Don't worry about it!
Two days aren't going to make a difference.
Huh?
Dad would've nagged me about it by now.
Besides...
His desk is all nice and tidy.
And he's dressing up a little.
Could it be that he's cheating?
I think it's because of a client.
A client?
Uncle Kogoro is a huge fan of
the person who's coming.
Excuse me.
Thanks for your patience,
Yoko Okino!
It's okay.
Come on in.
Are you here by yourself?
Yes.
My manager suggested that
I don't get involved any more than I have,
but I couldn't help worrying about it.
That's why I came without him knowing.
I'm not used to going places by myself,
so I got lost and panicked.
Well, at least things worked out.
- Sorry?
- I mean, I'm glad you've made it.
Is black tea fine with you?
Sure.
Ran, go and make some.
Okay.
So, it was at a vacation home in Karuizawa
while location scouting for a TV drama.
Were you there
because you're the main actress?
Yes. I was with the producer.
I said we were location scouting,
but really, we had to
choose between a few places.
We were just having a look in advance.
It was my first time in a dark role,
so I was excited.
What kind of role is it?
I'm playing a ghost
that lives at the vacation home.
But you said in an interview
that your next role is as a detective.
The ghost is the detective.
Long ago,
the owner of the holiday home was killed,
and she now appears as a ghost every night.
In exchange for solving mysteries
that people who come to
the holiday home have,
she asks them to find
each of her scattered bones.
I'm not going to be able to watch that.
But there aren't any holiday homes
that fit the story.
That's when the producer, Wanya Heijima,
suggested to me...
( Wanya Heijima (39) )
There's an eerie holiday home...
where a woman went missing in real life.
Want to check it out?
That's what he said.
"In real life..."
That hurts.
The holiday home
actually belongs to the family
that Heijima's sister married into.
The missing woman is his sister.
When I went there with Heijima,
I saw right away that the house
had a sinister aura around it.
I meant to go home on that day,
but I ended up staying for a night
because I wanted to have a look around.
Were you alone with the producer?
No.
It just so happened that
Heijima's brother-in-law, Nukiyasu Baba,
( Nukiyasu Baba (46) )
his brother Fugo,
( Fugo Baba (44) )
and Fugo's wife Himi came to escape the summer heat.
( Himi Baba (43) )
Then, we all had dinner.
The incident happened around midnight
when I was about to fall asleep in bed.
That really hurts.
I thought I heard someone moaning,
but then I heard footsteps from the hallway.
I was concerned about it, so I went out.
And I found drops of blood in the hallway.
I followed the trail of blood
and turned a corner...
And I saw...
What's wrong, Ran?
Don't scare me like that.
But it came out!
The ghost of the woman who disappeared!
That wasn't it. The trail of blood stopped.
Nobody was there, either.
Was there a door or a window
anyone could have escaped to?
Yes. There was only the bathroom door.
Of course, I turned on the lights
and looked into the bathtub.
But nobody was there.
While I was looking around,
everyone gathered to where I was.
Apparently, they couldn't find Nukiyasu,
the older brother.
So we decided to split up and look for him.
I said "split up",
but I was the only one
who could walk normally.
So, we split into two groups.
Was everyone else injured, then?
I see. I forgot to mention it.
Fugo, the younger brother,
dislocated his left wrist,
so it was bandaged up.
Himi is in a wheelchair due to a hernia.
Heijima sprained his right leg
and was on crutches.
I thought it would be dangerous
for anyone to be left alone
if a bad guy was lurking around.
I see.
So you split into groups of two to
look for Nukiyasu. Is that right?
But just as we were about to look for him,
this strange picture was sent to
Fugo's phone by Nukiyasu.
But just as we were about to look for him,
this strange picture was sent to
Fugo's phone by Nukiyasu.
Playing cards?
Are they hands in poker or blackjack?
But some of the hands
have the same cards in them.
So, I don't think that's it.
You're right.
Was the younger brother unable to figure it out?
He wasn't.
So we all thought it over
while looking for Nukiyasu.
I asked to have a copy of the picture,
but no one figured it out in the end.
Did you try calling or texting Nukiyasu?
Yes. Fugo tried calling him a few times.
But there was always a message saying
the phone was turned off.
Did you try looking outside the holiday home?
We did. Fugo and I went around
since we were able to walk.
We also searched the forest next to it,
but we couldn't find him at all.
Heijima and I couldn't leave the family alone,
so we cancelled our work commitments
and stayed at the holiday home
to continue the search.
The fourth morning
after we started looking for Nukiyasu,
Fugo remembered that
he used to play cards
with his brother in the attic.
Why in the attic?
Apparently, their parents were so strict
that they wouldn't buy any toys
for the brothers growing up.
Whenever they were at the holiday home,
they would sneak into the attic
and play without their parents knowing.
Fugo thought that Nukiyasu
could be in the attic.
But the stairs leading up to the attic
were locked from the inside,
so we were unable to get up there.
When we called the police,
we asked them to break into
the attic through the window,
and when they went inside...
They found Nukiyasu dead
with an arrow stuck to his back!
Hold on a second.
When you said the police
broke in through the window,
is it because the window was locked?
Yes.
So that means this is...
It's a locked-room murder.
Isn't that right, Uncle Kogoro?
That's right.
I was just about to say it myself!
A crossbow was found on
the ground near the holiday home.
But things like how the culprit
locked Nukiyasu in the attic,
or what the strange deck of cards
sent to his brother meant.
Why didn't Fugo alert the police
when he received the picture?
There were so many puzzling things.
So, please, Detective Mouri!
Please solve this mystery!
I've been so worried that I can't sleep.
Just leave it to me.
I, Kogoro Mouri, swear on my reputation
as a great detective...
Is something the matter?
Nothing.
I need to go to the toilet.
Was it because of
the buttercream sandwiches?
I'm sorry, but I heard
your conversation earlier.
A locked-room murder.
Doesn't that sound interesting?
I see.
The pop idol Yoko Okino
went to the holiday home of
her producer's acquaintances
while location hunting for a TV drama.
She heard a moan around midnight
while she was in bed.
There was also the sound of
footsteps in the hallway,
so she went out to find a trail of blood.
She followed the trail of blood
and turned a corner,
but the trail of blood stopped
and no one was there.
There was only the bathroom door.
Of course, no one was in the bathroom.
According to the others,
Nukiyasu, the older brother,
was nowhere to be found.
So everyone split up to look for him.
The fourth morning after the search began,
the younger brother remembered that
he used to play with his brother in the attic
and thought he might be there.
But the stairs to the attic
were locked from the inside,
so nobody could get in.
When they called the police
to break into the attic through the window,
they found the older brother's body,
stabbed in the back with a crossbow arrow.
This established that someone
committed a locked-room murder.
Well, that's what I heard. Was that right?
Yes.
Even though it's described
as a locked-room murder,
if you consider the trail of blood
and the sound of footsteps in the hallway,
it's clear that the older brother
was shot by the culprit with a crossbow
and ran up to the attic.
It means that you have to figure out
why he didn't call out for help
and locked himself up in the attic.
And right after the older brother disappeared,
when everyone was just about to look for him...
Why didn't he call the police
or ask someone for help,
but sent his brother a very strange picture?
So, excuse me, but who are you?
I forgot to introduce myself.
I work at Iroha Sushi next door.
The name's Wakita.
I got a call from Master Kogoro
last night at the restaurant.
He asked if I could prepare
an extra special bento box for two
full of the freshest ingredients
for this afternoon.
I see.
He was looking to have sushi with Yoko
if she happened to be hungry.
But he didn't call back this morning,
so I got tired of waiting
and brought it in myself.
But...
I won't take anything!
I'll pay for it out of my salary.
By the way, where's Master Kogoro?
He went to the toilet just now.
Let's all have sushi, then.
Right.
I love sushi!
It looks delicious!
I added an extra portion for free.
I'll make us some green tea, then.
I'm certain those buttercream sandwiches
are the reason.
They did taste weird.
Is it my imagination,
or is the office getting a bit lively?
It's yummy!
It really is. Right, Conan?
Yeah.
That's an extra special set for you!
The medium-fatty tuna has just enough fat
that makes it exquisite!
That's from bigeye tuna!
It's in season right now.
But Master Kogoro is sure taking his time.
We don't want to keep you waiting,
so let's hear the details.
In that case,
do you have pictures of the people
who stayed with you at the holiday home?
It's hard for me to imagine
from your description alone.
That's what I thought, too.
Wait a second.
I think I have a picture of everyone.
There it is!
This picture was taken when we arrived there.
I'm not in it since I was the one who took it.
Who's who?
Let's see...
The one on the left with the crutches
is Nichiuri TV producer Wanya Heijima.
The one in the middle
is Heijima's brother-in-law
and the murder victim Nukiyasu Baba.
The tall one on the right with his arm in a sling
is Nukiyasu's younger brother, Fugo Baba.
And the woman in the wheelchair
is Himi Baba, Fugo's wife.
Everyone aside from the older brother
seems to be injured in some way.
That's right. I think it's just a coincidence, though.
The playing cards shown in the picture
had a few of the same number.
Was it mentioned why?
Yes.
They often went to the holiday home as a family
to escape the summer heat
since they were children.
They used to hide decks of cards in the attic
instead of carrying them in their luggage
so that they could play
without their parents finding out.
Every time they went,
they would buy another deck just in case.
There seemed to be five or six decks in the attic.
I wonder what he was trying to tell
with the various decks of cards.
I bet it must've hurt
with a crossbow arrow stuck to his back.
Speaking of playing cards, the late Nukiyasu
had a strange nickname for his brother.
What was it?
"Ace".
What's the matter with that left arm, Ace?
I hurt it while playing baseball
over the weekend.
Was he a pitcher or something?
I thought the same, so I asked him about it.
But he laughed.
I've been a tall guy ever since I was a kid,
so I've always been a catcher.
But I've never been a pitcher in my life.
That's what he said.
There seems to be a key to
deciphering the deck of cards,
but I don't have a clue.
Then, what was Mr. Nukiyasu's late wife like?
Heijima's older sister, you mean?
I've never met her,
but when I told him
that I'm consulting Detective Mouri
about the incident, he sent me this picture.
The woman in sunglasses
is Heijima's older sister, Hoka Baba.
(Hoka Baba)
She disappeared two summers ago.
Nukiyasu wanted to go with her to the holiday home,
but something urgent came up.
She was supposed to
come there alone before him.
When he came with Fugo and Himi,
she wasn't there.
They called the police to
search for her,
but nobody could find her.
Did she often wear sunglasses?
Yes. Heijima said
she was obsessed with them
and often wore them
before she disappeared.
But Fugo and his wife said
they never saw her wearing sunglasses
while in university.
When you said, "while in university..."
That's right. The three of them
were in university together.
In fact, they were together
all throughout their school years as well.
Hoka was Fugo's first love,
and she and Himi were best friends.
I see. In that case...
If Nukiyasu was the cause of
his wife Hoka's disappearance,
then all three of them
have a motive for killing him.
Was there anything else
you were concerned about?
I can't. I have a bad feeling about this.
I can't believe it was all an act.
No. I think he understood it
but pretended not to.
There's no way I don't know!
Well, when something
that's supposed to be there isn't,
of course, you'd be concerned.
Next Conan,
"Yoko Okino And The Locked Room In The Attic
(Part 2)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Mahjong"
- Sushi is the best!
- I can't bite into the squid.
And I still don't have toilet paper!