(Kusano Chicken Eggs)
We received a request
( Hitoshi Nanba (45) )
from national champion chick appraiser,
Hitoshi Nanba,
and arrived here
at Kusano Chicken Eggs' factory.
You're moving at incredible speed.
I observe the tiny details
in a chick's bottom
and determine whether it's male or female.
So, what business does
a chick appraiser like you have with me?
To tell the truth,
it seems that my life is in danger.
Mysterious clouds
obstruct the field of vision.
A sparkle that clears them up with deduction!
Every second counts for
the appraiser's skilled hands.
Every moment matters
when a life is in danger.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
"The Chick Appraiser In Danger"
In the last few weeks,
strange things keep happening around me.
A rubber shot flew towards me
when I was walking outdoors.
My hand was burned with
a magnifying glass or something
while I was asleep.
And I left my phone somewhere,
only to find it exploding all of a sudden.
A rubber shot...
A magnifying glass...
And an exploding phone?
Detective Mouri, I would like for you
to be my bodyguard
while investigating
the cause of these incidents.
Do you have an idea
why your life is in danger?
No, I don't.
But that's why I wanted you
to investigate first.
(President's Office)
A grudge?
( Saburo Kusano (61) )
Nanba is the star of our industry.
He has an excellent reputation
and a great personality,
so I can't imagine his life being in danger.
Could someone have
an unjustified grudge against him?
No. I've never heard of such a thing.
Someone has a grudge against Nanba?
I don't know about that.
( Takashi Nakamura (29) )
But I can't exactly comment
if he's someone to be respected.
He seems to be a good guy on the outside.
You're also an appraiser, right?
Yes. But to be honest,
I'm looking to take his place.
Nanba? He's a great guy.
( Mamiko Hirasawa (22)
At the very least, he's always nice to me.
But I only started working here recently.
So, you're a new employee.
What made you decide to work here?
I wanted to become
a chick appraiser myself.
The way he handles the chicks so skillfully
is just so cool.
Did you start working for this company
because you admired Mr. Nanba,
Miss Hirasawa?
That's right.
Uncle Kogoro.
Shouldn't we ask
people outside the company, too?
What?
Well, you may be right.
In that case, someone else is here to
interview the company.
So, you're that famous detective.
I work for a magazine called
Monthly Chick Appraiser World.
I do the reporting, camera work,
and all sorts of errands.
( Kazumasa Kitazawa (29) )
My name's Kazumasa Kitazawa.
Pleased to meet you.
Thank you. Let's get right to it.
Do you have an idea of who
would have a grudge against Nanba?
I'm not sure.
It's not like he and I are close friends.
I heard that Mr. Nanba is a champion.
Is he such an amazing person?
Well, it's not like he's bad at it,
but he doesn't compare to Master Okabe
in his heyday.
Master Okabe?
You don't know Master Yuji Okabe?
( Yuji Okabe (52) )
He won the national competition seven years running.
He didn't make any mistakes four years in a row
and had broken records in no time.
Those were some intense years.
I see.
Detective Mouri!
So this is where you are.
Let's go. I've been asked to
lecture this afternoon.
Lecture?
(Lecture: On the Future of Chick Appraisers
by Hitoshi Nanba)
There are a few ways to tell chicks apart,
(Lecture: On the Future of Chick Appraisers
by Hitoshi Nanba)
There are a few ways to tell chicks apart,
but the method of
observing the anus originated in Japan.
Because it demands delicate handling,
it can be said that
it suits the Japanese
since we have smaller hands.
It's quite a profound field, isn't it?
Yes.
I have added
an original method to the technique,
which improves the speed
while preserving accuracy.
The technique is...
Look out!
What was in that liquid?
According to forensic analysis,
it was a chlorine-based cleaning agent.
It could cause blindness
if it enters the eyes,
and there's a danger of serious chemical burns
if it gets on the skin.
Getting doused in cleaning agents
isn't exactly deadly,
but this proves that you're being harassed.
It seems to be the case.
Anyway, I hope you will investigate the matter.
I'll be returning to my workstation, so this is goodbye for now.
Okay.
I told him that I'd listen, so I did.
Detective Mouri!
This may seem sudden,
but I just found out something new.
(Kusano Chicken Eggs)
I'll provide the information for free,
but I'd like to ask for an exclusive interview
(Kusano Chicken Eggs)
after the case is solved.
Sure thing.
The information is about none other than
Mr. Nanba and Mr. Kusano's
financial troubles.
Mr. Nanba helped improve
the company's performance
by appearing on billboards,
so he's been pressing Mr. Kusano
for half of the profits.
Wouldn't he be fired
if he asked for that?
But he hasn't been fired because...
It's probably because
what Mr. Nanba is saying
isn't entirely wrong.
Well then, let's find out for ourselves.
Well, of course, I don't agree.
We're currently negotiating terms
that both of us will find agreeable.
So it's true, then,
that he asked for half of the profits.
Well...
Financial trouble would make a good motive
for targeting Mr. Nanba.
How rude! I would never...
Then, why didn't you fire Nanba
even though he made
such a threatening demand?
That's because...
Could it be because he has something on you...
Leave me alone!
We have our own way of doing things here!
Just leave already!
Miss Hirasawa!
You're an accountant here, right?
Yes, I am.
Is this company a good one to work for?
Of course!
I see.
By the way, do you think
Master Okabe is number one too?
Sorry?
You see, I don't know much about
what happened back then.
Kusano Chicken Eggs
was established 24 years ago.
Six years ago, Hitoshi Nanba appeared
on the company's billboards,
and the company gradually
saw increased performance.
Saburo Kusano, the company's president and CEO.
He has been involved in
the chicken egg industry
since graduating from university.
He founded Kusano Chicken Eggs
after resigning from Miura Foods.
He's on the judging committee for
the national competition?
Isn't this...
What are you doing here?
Detective Mouri has been looking for you
because he hasn't seen you around.
Mr. Nakamura.
In all the competitions
that Mr. Nanba has been in,
was there any that you thought was unusual?
A competition I thought was unusual?
Yes.
Come to think of it...
I didn't think anything was unusual
with Mr. Nanba himself,
but there was one.
It was at the national competition
seven years ago.
That was the one he won
and became champion.
The battle was decided
when the previous champion self-destructed.
I thought it would be
more of a close contest,
but a new champion was quickly crowned.
By the way, what was
the name of the previous champion?
You don't know?
It was Master Yuji Okabe.
He's a legend in the world of chicken eggs.
Is something the matter?
Is it possible for me to watch the battle?
(Kusano Chicken Eggs)
I see.
(Yuji Okabe, Hitoshi Nanba)
This was certainly a strange battle.
(Chick Appraiser World, Special Issue)
Hello, is this Officer Takagi?
There's something I need you to investigate.
Is that so?
I see.
All right. Thanks.
So that's how it is.
I'm starting to see the whole picture.
This is the recording of
the National Chick Sorting Competition
that was held seven years ago.
The finals put Master Okabe,
the defending champion,
against up-and-coming Hitoshi Nanba.
Let's have a fair match.
I heard you're rather talented.
Well, then...
The two gentlemen will now battle to see
who can sort 100 chicks faster
and more precisely than the other.
That's Mr. Kusano!
What's going on?
The adjudicator and the contestant
are now working in the same company.
Don't you think it's too good to be true?
We shall now begin
the final of
the National Chick Sorting Competition.
Ready... Go!
Everyone expected
Master Okabe to
have an overwhelming advantage.
I will now announce the results.
Mr. Nanba measured 4 minutes and 50 seconds
with an accuracy of 100%.
Mr. Okabe measured 4 minutes and 36 seconds
with an accuracy of 83%.
The result was
an overwhelming victory for Mr. Nanba.
The winner is Mr. Nanba!
Give a round of applause for the new champion!
Hold on a second!
There must be something wrong!
He...
If the referee was on his side,
he wouldn't lose no matter who he was up against.
Assuming that is the case,
Master Okabe would have a motive.
But why would he wait seven years?
No, that wouldn't have been possible.
Master Okabe made a fuss
about the unfair judging
after the competition,
but instead, it made him unpopular
among the public
and he was forced to
exit from centre stage.
He committed suicide six months later.
No way.
In that case, that leaves us back at square one.
I don't think that's true.
Don't we have someone
who's been lying to us all this time?
Lying?
Do you mean Mr. Kusano?
That's not it.
What are you talking about?
When people lie,
they're usually under intense stress.
(Cross their arms)
They tend to make unconscious gestures or defensive poses
(Look away)
(Cross their legs again)
that can signal the fact they're lying.
Defensive poses?
That's what Shinichi told me not long ago.
He did?
That's why I checked.
There's someone here
who tends to hide her weak point,
which is her throat, when she lies.
That's right. The culprit is...
Mamiko Hirasawa.
The number you are trying to call
is out of range...
Darn it.
I can't reach his phone.
He should still be around here.
Let's search the area.
Conan!
You will pay for what you've done.
Dad, isn't this Mr. Nanba's phone?
This is bad.
I found it
in an inconspicuous patch of grass over there.
I think we can assume
that Miss Hirasawa took him away somewhere.
But where could they be?
We won't find him
if we look for him randomly.
Let's call the police
and have them search for the car.
But wouldn't that take a lot of time?
What do you say we do instead?
I wonder
what Miss Hirasawa wants to do to Mr. Nanba.
Since she went all the way to kidnap him,
she would've taken him somewhere
people won't see them.
She did say she started working
at the company recently.
If she's unfamiliar with the area,
she should've taken him somewhere
he has a connection with.
And that means...
I think I've got it after listening to
your deduction, Uncle Kogoro!
What is it?
Maybe it's this place.
This must be it.
This was where it all started.
This was where the final of
the National Chick Sorting Competition
took place seven years ago.
Stop!
Stop it, Hirasawa!
You shouldn't waste your life on revenge!
I wouldn't take a step closer if I were you.
As expected of a famous detective.
How did you figure out I would be here?
Why? Well...
If you had to ask me why...
- Dad?
- Why?
It's because this was where it all began,
and where your father chose to die.
Your life was ruined by that man.
Your father fell into his trap
and killed himself out of despair.
It seems that you were put
in an orphanage after that.
That's right. Your family name
was originally Okabe.
You were Master Yuji Okabe's beloved daughter.
How did you figure it out?
I suspected it
from the way you talked about
a chick appraiser's hands.
From your expression,
I thought you must've been involved with
a chick appraiser in some way.
I also observed that
one of your hands was injured.
I saw a tub of hand cream
and a steroidal ointment on your desk.
There was also that attack
with the chlorine-based cleaning agent
not long afterwards.
My hand?
That's right.
There was also the lie you told us.
You clearly held Nanba in disgust.
Not only that, you lied about
not knowing about your father.
The gesture you made while lying
was exactly the same as his.
That was why I had someone look into it.
After being taken in by an orphanage,
you were adopted by the Hirasawa family.
But why did you have to work for
the same company as Mr. Nanba?
It's because you wanted to confirm the fact
that Nanba won the competition
in a fixed match.
Am I wrong?
That's right. We went out for a meal together.
And the moment he was given a chance to drink,
I didn't even have to ask for him
to blab on and on about it.
Is that why...
Were you going to say
that I wanted to kill him?
No, you aren't planning to kill him.
Everything you did from the rubber shot
and the magnifying glass
to tampering with his phone
and attempting to douse him
in cleaning agents...
It was all so that you could harm his hands.
But why would you do that?
For a chick appraiser,
hands are one's lifeblood.
The job demands a delicate touch
and subtle movement of the fingers.
If one were to hurt his arms
in a way that leaves any lingering effects,
life as a chick appraiser might as well be over.
No way.
That's right!
I want to steal everything he has,
just as he stole everything my father had!
Just stop!
I'm sure your father wouldn't be happy
with what you're doing!
If you analyse the recording of
the final competition,
it's obvious
that Nanba and Mr. Kusano are guilty.
I can guarantee it.
Still, it's too late now.
It's not too late!
Leave me alone!
He should be punished for what he did!
Stop it!
Didn't you want to be
a chick appraiser as well?
An excellent chick appraiser,
just like your father.
Up you go!
Daddy, your hands are so nice.
Your hands are nice too, Mamiko.
So, I'm sure you'll be a chick appraiser
when you grow up.
Yes! I want to be a chick appraiser, too.
The best one in Japan?
No, I want to be the best in the world.
Then, I want to be the best
in the whole universe!
Dad...
Police soon came and took Hirasawa away.
Nanba and Kusano's wrongdoings
were brought to light
with help from Nakamura and Kitazawa.
Nanba was stripped of his title
and his appraisal permit
while Kusano was removed from
his position as company president.
And as a result of
the two exposing each other's wrongdoings,
they were both arrested on suspicion of
corporate embezzlement and tax evasion.
Are we meeting
a guinea pig appraiser this time?
I've never heard of one before.
Are you sure
it's not a request from a caretaker?
It's a request to find a guinea pig
that has snuck in among all these guinea pigs.
Its name is Mofuo.
We have to find it...
Among all these guinea pigs?
Hold on!
Hey, let's all become
excellent guinea pig appraisers!
Hey!
We can do it if we all work together.
Don't leave me alone here!
Hey!
(Next Episode)
This is Joji Kazama.
We met at a date party,
and he's my boyfriend now.
Just give it up already.
Sorry?
He's definitely dating you for the money.
I'm Yuki, his daughter.
I'm sure you found my father a scary man.
Next Conan,
"The Dreaming Lady And The Last Love"
Next Conan's Hint:
"A limousine"
Did you find Mofuo?
If I sleep, then maybe...
You know you can't find it
if you fall asleep.