Kid the Phantom Thief,
it's my turn next.
Saturday night,
under the waning moon,
I shall seize the jewel upon the
head of the untarnished nail,
and thus repay the debt I owe you
from 18 years ago.
Long time no see,
Kid the Phantom Thief.
Unlike then, your partner here
isn't worth a damn.
Partner?
"The Female with 20 Faces" who dropped
out of sight in Paris 18 years ago.
The gentlewoman thief...
...the Phantom Lady!
I see! It's not deja vu!
He's the guy from 18 years ago...
Mom told me this story the other day!
It all started 18 years ago...
A Saturday night when the
full moon was bright...
See? What'd I tell you?
W-What's with the handcuffs?!
And no sense having two of you,
so you'll disappear for good...
I don't know about that.
I see!
This situation...
It's just like what Mom was gushing
about, how she and Dad first met!
Phantom Lady and the Ryoma Treasure
So, what are you going to do,
Kid the Phantom Thief?
You can try to escape in
that car like 18 years ago,
except it was a
slim motorcycle then.
That car is compact, but not enough to fit
through the windows of this observation deck.
Although, being a replica,
you can't drive it in the first place.
I see.
Then this entire prized collection is a hoax.
And as for the big-ass ruby coming
in next week, it's actually a fake
that you'll say was stolen by Kid,
and then sell replicas on the black market.
It's all been arranged.
All I have to do now is take your life
and send out our fake Kid.
Who do you think I am?
You really think you can take the life...
...of a phantom thief so easily?
Don't panic!
He has nowhere to escape!
As long as we block the elevator!
K-Kid...
...vanished with the car!
I-It can't be!
That car makes engine noises,
but it's a fake!
Actually...
You said it should be a
do-over of 18 years ago,
so I went ahead and arranged
things like they were then...
You're an idiot!
H-He looped around behind us!
Fire!
Don't let him get away!
Let's see...
Shiba Park is... over there!
Maybe head-on won't work...
...but I can get through sideways!
D-Damn you!
Let's get out of here
before the cops come!
P-President!
What are those strange threads?
The height of Toto Tower's special
observation deck is 250 meters.
250 = gt squared over 2...
Subtract air resistance and that gives us
about 7.1 seconds 'til impact.
Enough time to spring
this cheap handcuff...
One of their shots must've
ripped a hole in my pocket!
My lock-picking wire is gone!
Crap! What do I do?! What do I do?!
Wire! Wire! Wire!
Calm down!
Never forget your poker face, no matter what!
The hairpin!
Ah, well, at least thanks to the commotion,
those guys will probably
end up getting arrested.
They should be held as snug as bugs
for a while with the thread I set up
while circling the car around.
Now, what do I do with this happy-go-lucky
girl who slept through all the excitement?
My dad stole a kiss from my mom when
they were in the same situation...
A-Although it's my fault
she got mixed up in this...
I-I'll let her have a rain check tonight.
Sheesh, come on, Mom!
You should've told me the bad guy from
18 years ago was never sent to prison!
The prosecutor's office is charging
President Gouzu with suspicion of...
That guy put me through the wringer because
he thought he was getting revenge!
But you caught him, right?
Great job...
...Kid the Phantom Thief II.
By the way, Chikage-san,
when are you coming back to Japan?
My friend here has really taken a
liking to me and won't let me go back.
Hey, hey!
Oh, that's right.
President Gouzu has apprentices,
and apparently, they're using the
same methods to line their pockets.
A long time ago, I did my best
to gather up the evidence,
but I still never found the place where
they stored all the fake merchandise.
So please teach them a lesson too,
Magician Under the Moonlight.
I already mailed you a list of merchandise,
so I'm counting on you!
H-Hey! W-Wait a second!
Ryoma Sakamoto three-piece memento set?
From: Chikage Kuroba
Sub: Ryoma Mementos
Ryoma Sakamoto three-piece memento set
Gun Belt
Hanging Scroll
Sake Cup
What a pain in the ass!
So this is it, huh?
Why are there so many?!
I think Chikage-sama has already told
you what happened, Young Master,
but Phantom Lady,
that is, Chikage-sama, didn't steal
all these items because she wanted to.
Gouzu sent out a fake notice using her name,
claiming she would steal the Ryoma treasure.
Yeah. That's pretty much what Mom said.
They were using her, right?
They knew if they sent out a fake advance notice,
Phantom Lady would definitely show up.
They tricked her into stealing the treasure,
then mass-produced replicas themselves,
and swindled collectors into buying the fakes
by claiming they were the stolen originals.
But Mom could tell the treasures she stole
were fake and kept returning them to the cops.
Then, 18 years ago...
...they plotted to wipe out Chikage-sama.
Except, standing in their way was...
...my old man.
Toichi Kuroba, right?
That's right.
Toichi-sama saved Chikage-sama, then became
Kid the Phantom Thief to protect her.
But it's nearly 20 years later, and their
disciples are using the same means to get rich.
That's why Mom asked me to
capture them too, right?
Yes.
To that effect, Chikage-sama has gathered
all of these mass-produced replicas of
Ryoma's treasures from various collectors.
I see.
Well, they're all here.
Now the question is, how do I
catch these guys in the act?
Tell me, Dad,
what should I do?
Listen, Kaito, and listen well.
When the magic's got you stumped,
you can often find a hint
by thinking in reverse.
Thinking in reverse?
Magicians always have to
outwit their audience.
If a certain idea is tripping you up,
you should think about an
exactly opposite method.
Now that idea is sure to surprise them.
Do you understand, Kaito?
Thinking in reverse...
Got it.
Thank you, Dad.
This is my one-time chance
to expose their misdeeds.
I'll show 'em!
That Kid the Phantom Thief
does more than just steal!
There's no need to be hasty.
I just have to wait for the right day.
He's gonna return items that he stole?!
Is that what Kid's advance
notice really said?!
Yeah.
"One day soon, I'm going to show up at
the currently-running Ryoma exhibition
to return three items.
Kid the Phantom Thief."
Th-Three items?
Apparently, Shishihiko Tarumi-san,
the sponsor of the Ryoma exhibition,
did the same thing 20 years ago.
The three items were stolen then.
The letter Ryoma Sakamoto's wife
wrote him on a scroll
the night before he was assassinated,
the soy sauce sake cup that became stained
with his blood when he was assassinated,
and the concealed pistol that
Ryoma had on him at the time.
It was a Smith and Wesson type 1.
Look, that's what it says on
the back of the advance notice.
Y-Yes,
e-except Kid isn't the one
who stole them, but...
Yeah, the "Female with 20 Faces."
The gentlewoman thief...
The Phantom Lady!
I don't know what the connection was
between Kid and Lady,
but after she stole those three items,
Lady gave up a life of crime.
If you consider that Kid came on
the scene two years later,
it may have been a master
and disciple relationship.
So when is he coming?
I don't know. It just says "one day soon"
on the advance notice.
Then let's cancel the Ryoma exhibition
immediately and get the people out of there.
He withheld the date and time
to put us at a disadvantage!
Because he knows that it's easier
just to return something!
But, Nakamori-kun...
He's offering to return stolen goods.
Why should we reject that?
I know, but Superintendent...
Besides, to catch Kid, we first
need to invite him in, don't we?
Jirokichi Suzuki, the owner of the Suzuki
Museum, received the advance notice,
and he agrees with me.
He said, "Leave the entrance
wide open and the exit narrow.
Those are the basics of
catching a mouse."
I said I'd return 'em,
but how can I bring in
all these faux treasures?
W-What the hell are you doing?
I'm on a diet!
My stomach's starting to get flabby,
which is like a nightmare.
So I go like this and
tense my tummy muscles...
Jeez. I was wondering
what you were up to.
Too bad your tummy's starting to
stick out and not your chest, right?
What do you mean by that?!
I don't believe it! You always dodge it!
Thanks, Aoko.
Nothing unusual at either
the front or back entrances!
Good job.
Thank you, sir!
Good job to you too, Inspector!
Ryoma Exhibition
This is the gun belt Ryoma got
from Takasugi Shinsaku...
Cool!
Although I'm sure it's a fake...
But nobody's looking at the treasures.
Well, I guess that makes sense.
All of them are focused on...
Space reserved for Kid the Phantom Thief
to return treasures
That Suzuki guy sure knows
how to stir up a crowd.
I get it.
Only that space has sensors.
I-I'm sorry!
It was just meant to be a little prank...
And undercover cops are
mixed in with the crowd,
so they can quickly nab anyone
who seems suspicious.
Sorry, kid.
That's okay.
Are you all right, Conan-kun?
Yeah, I'm fine.
We went to the trouble of coming here, but
it looks like Kid-sama may not even show up...
Hey, why don't we go home?
Forget it! I'm not leaving until
I meet my beloved Kid-sama!
That twerp came here to be
the fly in my ointment again.
Their security is meticulous
this time, Young Master.
And I bumped into a real troublemaker.
Well, well...
It seems this isn't going to be an easy job.
Don't worry. The wheels are
turning in my head, too.
Young Master, do you have a plan?
Well, wait and see.
Hey, Jii-chan...
Yes, Young Master?
I think it's about time to hit
'em with my next advance notice.
Understood.
And what's it going to say?
I've got something in mind.
A brilliant note befitting this job.
S-Senior Adviser!
S-Somebody just dropped this
in the post box!
Th-This is one of
Kid's announcements?
What?!
"Tomorrow at 8:00 pm,
right before closing, I shall bring
over the pistol and other items,
and by the name of Ryoma Sakamoto,
patriot of the Bakumatsu period,
I'll give them a good washing.
Kid the Phantom Thief."
Kid the Phantom Thief is here!
But there's still something
fishy about all this.
Kid obviously didn't name the date
and time of his appearance this time,
so why would he
suddenly choose tomorrow?
Just maybe...
...Kid was waiting for something until today.
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
Conan-kun!
Go ahead and rack your brains,
you modern-day Sherlock Holmes!
Young Master, as requested,
I've prepared the props
for your next magic show.
Thank you.
Young Master, please be careful.
This time, the police aren't
your only adversaries.
I know!
I bet we're gonna have another
fun showdown this time.
You don't wanna miss this one.
The battle between me and my destined
rival, the pint-sized brilliant detective.
The illusion must go on!
I should've figured this job wouldn't be easy,
since even Mom left it for me to do.
And it's made even worse with the involvement
of the brilliant munchkin detective.
On the other hand, all of these
challenges get me fired up!
In the end, I'll pull off a magnificent
victory with the aid of astounding magic!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Kid, Conan, and the Ryoma Treasure Illusion!
Kid, Conan, and the Ryoma Treasure Illusion
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
There's always only one truth!
No!
Don't miss the illusion!