Ladies and gentlemen,
I bring you marvelous illusions that
make this town sparkle at night!
For the first time this year,
please enjoy that little guy's miracle.
Hey, Kaito, class is starting!
Shut up! What do you care?
A Notice to Kid the Phantom Thief!
I possess a Big Jewel.
Blue Wonder (The Miracle of the Ocean)
W-Wha...
What?!
Preparing
Young Master!
Shouldn't you be in school?
I left early.
A Notice to Kid the Phantom Thief!
I possess a Big Jewel.
Blue Wonder (The Miracle of the Ocean)
You must have seen this advertisement.
But it's a trap, Young Master.
I know that!
You won't escape from me!
Ultra-high-definition Blu-ray Disc
Th-This old man...
He's the Suzuki conglomerate's
senior adviser,
meaning he has unlimited funds
to prepare for you.
On top of that, he's already
made the first move.
If you're going to steal it, at least
don't send an advance notice this time...
You've got it backwards, Jii-chan!
That guy is openly picking a fight with
the unrivaled Kid the Phantom Thief.
So I won't be satisfied unless I slap
him back with an advance notice!
Oh, boy...
Toichi-sama, too. Once he made up his mind,
he would see it through without fear,
no matter how dangerous the circumstances.
Anyway, I'm gonna do it.
And I'm counting on you to
lay the groundwork, Jii-chan.
I suppose any further
arguing would be pointless.
In that case, Jii will look into all
the details for you, Young Master!
Kid vs Conan: Miraculous Airwalking
I put up a good front for Jii-chan,
but I don't think my usual bag
of tricks will work this time.
Listen to me, Kaito.
Challenging hecklers who interfere with
your magic are always a pain to deal with.
Thinking you'll floor them right away
is the height of foolishness.
Magic is not a battle.
It's something that entertains many people.
Then what should I do?
You can divide challenging
audience members into two groups.
The first type wants to stand out
more than the magician.
All you can do to deal with that
sort of person is silence them.
Silence them...
And then there's the type that is so curious,
they can't stand not knowing the trick,
even if it means interfering with the magic.
For them, don't be bound
by theory, but intox...
What was that?
Don't be bound
by theory, but intox...
Right at the important part!
Kid will be fine!
But it's on the roof of the museum.
He can just run up the side of the building!
I bet Kid can do something like that!
I can picture it!
Not me.
Has Kid accepted this challenge?
The risk is too high.
I believe he has a 50% chance of success.
Don't be a dumbass! This is exactly
the kind of challenge Kid lives for!
But I wonder how he's gonna steal it?
I can't wait to find out!
Everyone is dying to find out
how I'm going to steal it?
Dad was right.
I can't just win against old man Jirokichi.
Kid the Phantom Thief is
all about entertaining the audience!
So this is Blue Wonder...
I can fly in on a hang glider,
grab it, and go, right?
That won't work.
Suzuki Jirokichi has hired
a crackerjack security team.
That includes a helicopter squad.
There are 20 choppers,
and even now,
they're bringing in more people.
That many choppers flying around will make
the wind currents too choppy for a glider.
Suzuki Jirokichi
Guess I'll think of another
means of transport.
I think that will be difficult, too.
Now what?!
Information I received from a contractor.
Hey, is that even possible?!
It is possible.
Jii-chan, what about the inside?
100 surveillance cameras operating
at all times, catching everything.
There are no blind spots.
Although cameras mean nothing
if I go in disguise!
A look at the security plan shows
they mean to have no one inside.
So I won't have anyone to impersonate...
On top of that, the helicopters
are equipped with cameras,
and all of the footage that they capture
is sent to this truck parked here.
Footage, huh?
Even though it's a special museum
exhibition, a helicopter shot?
I don't understand how rich people think.
Young Master!
Yeah. If he's mixed up in it this time,
I just have to show him some brilliant magic.
But how...?
I found an opening.
That just leaves Blue Wonder.
The Miracle of the Sea...
Walking on water is a famous miracle, right?
Yes.
Then Kid the Phantom Thief
will have to top that miracle!
Th-That's...
Interesting, right?
"Reappearance" is one of the basics of magic.
This is the same kind of thing.
I see.
Jii-chan, how long will it take you
to prepare the tools and set this up?
If I can have until Saturday...
Then it's settled.
I accept your kind invitation.
The event will take place this Sunday at 8:00 pm.
Please pardon my rudeness for performing
a preliminary inspection the night before...
Kid the Phantom Thief
p.s. Like the name Blue Wonder,
I'm going to just walk right over...
According to Kid's advance notice, he's
going to do a preliminary inspection tonight.
Will Kid actually appear as promised?
Good job.
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Young Master, we're almost there.
Then it's time to start the show.
I'm counting on you, Jii-chan!
Again, be careful!
All-righty...
He's floating?
Seriously?!
Don't be fooled!
He's just hanging by a wire from
a black ad balloon or something!
Nab him and get back to me!
Number 7 helicopter, roger!
This is helicopter number 7!
Kid isn't hanging from anything...
What?!
If he's not hanging from above...
Inspector Nakamori, there's nothing
sticking out of this building either!
Like I figured, they would suspect that.
But my magic isn't simple.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Well, on the eve of the main event,
feast your eyes on the
miracle I have wrought.
Senior Adviser, shouldn't
we activate that trap now?
It can't be helped.
Jii-chan's intel was good.
Well, that's enough for tonight.
Well, that's enough of a preview.
Let's meet back here again
tomorrow night at 8:00.
H-He disappeared!
In mid-air!
Jii-chan, it's me.
The crowd's three times
as large tonight.
Understood.
Excuse me! You're the owner of Blue Wonder
and senior adviser of the Suzuki conglomerate,
Jirokichi Suzuki-san, right?
Indeed.
It's almost that time...
Are your Kid countermeasures foolproof?
Last night he put on a cut-rate magic show,
but I've got something
to show everyone tonight.
I'll get it.
Sorry!
Five! Four!
Three! Two!
One!
H-How?! Where did he come from?!
Hey! What happened, number 7 chopper? Hey!
What the...?!
The feed from chopper
number 7 suddenly cut out.
This is helicopter number 7. I'm not
experiencing any difficulties here...
Maybe the rain temporarily
scrambled the feed?
No. My wager is that Kid
had an assistant cut the power
as part of his plan.
Kid has assistants?
Y-Yeah...
An old man, a young woman...
There are various reports.
But he definitely has at least one.
Get Blue Wonder inside the building!
This is a contest of wits!
Roger!
It's in the building!
All right! And now I'll take the initiative.
Extinguish all the lights
in the building immediately!
Turn them off?
It's possible he's intercepting the
video footage inside the building, too.
B-But why put the jewel in the museum?
The main thing is to not let him steal it.
Hello?
What's going on over there?
No problems, Inspector Nakamori. We're
definitely outthinking Kid with this plan.
Shhh!
He may be listening in,
so let's cut the chatter.
There's nothing to worry about.
Everything is going smoothly.
Another dud...
Ah, well, at least I got back
at old man Jirokichi
by showing everyone a miracle,
so not a bad night.
What's so funny...
...Kid the Phantom Thief?
W-What are you talking about?
I'm laughing because I kept Kid
from stealing the jewel, and...
Dumbass.
I saw right through you the moment you
arrived at the museum on this bike.
Then, like now, you're
not wearing your goggles.
I hear it's really painful for people who
wear contacts not to wear goggles when riding.
This kid doesn't miss a trick!
And an old man riding around in a
showy bike without bodyguards...
I'm sure you had any number of chances
to put him to sleep and take his place.
I "silenced" the old man.
Since he's the type who wants to stand out
so much that he interferes with the magic.
I can't be Kid!
For example, when Kid appeared
earlier, I was right next to you!
That was the moment he performed
that airwalking miracle.
That was no miracle!
It was a simple trick that only
required an assistant and preparation.
It must not have been that hard
for your assistant
to temporarily slip into the crowd
of hired helicopter pilots.
Yeah, Jii-chan has all kinds of licenses,
so it was a cinch for him to be hired.
First, you and your assistant flew
the chopper over those two buildings,
then attached a wire to one of the roofs.
Toss away the camouflaging
black cape into the stage smoke,
and Kid the Phantom Thief appears.
Next, your assistant in the helicopter
hovered directly overhead,
so Kid was "wired" from above and the side,
seemingly floating in mid-air.
Then you just had to pretend to walk
to match the chopper's slow advance.
A music player you had in your pocket
played the sound of footsteps,
and your exceptional body performance
ensured no one would notice you were hanging.
And then...
...for the finishing touch, your assistant
pulled you up into the chopper,
making it look like you
vanished into thin air.
Correct.
Although tonight's Kid was just a marionette
to draw the police's attention.
It was obvious to me that
it was just hanging there.
But you climbed that building, son.
If there was anything hanging from a helicopter,
you would've seen it, even a thin wire.
Preconceptions and wind.
Pathetic on my part.
When the helicopter was over you,
I didn't think you were hanging from it,
I was startled there were
no wires on the roof,
and the wind from the chopper
also made it difficult to see,
and so I didn't spot your wires.
But your hooks left scratches on the roofs
of both buildings where they were attached.
Preconceptions...
In magic, we call that the "reappearance."
If you show that there's nothing there once,
it's hard for people to get suspicious.
After they've checked something once,
they don't feel the need to check again.
But I'm sure you watched the footage
of Kid last night over and over.
The footage shows a bird's-eye
view of Kid, wires and all,
but it was shot by your confederate
in helicopter number 7.
If you'd used faked footage based
on the museum's special exhibition,
there's no way the wires would be showing.
But when it started to rain, your assistant
nixed the idea of sending out the fake footage.
Because it didn't show people at the
exhibition opening their umbrellas, right?
I bet last night's demonstration, where you
seemed to appear from the air, was to loosen
ground security so you could come in
disguised as Jirokichi Suzuki without a challenge.
But you were careless.
You were shown on TV on the bike
but without the goggles on.
Actually, I didn't forget
to put the goggles on...
I couldn't put them on.
Because that would ruin
my disguise! You know?
You sure about this? Your
assistant in chopper number 7...
He may be surrounded by police
helicopters right now.
No worries there. I'm sure
the cops are in panic mode.
And confused by all the stickers
we put on number 7.
All the stickers?
I see.
You lightly glued on stickers over the
original number so they'd peel off in the wind.
That's right.
That way, he could slip in with the
other pilots without them noticing.
And nobody could chase after his chopper,
because "number 7" was gone!
My friend took advantage
of the chaos and escaped.
There's your Blue Wonder!
A miraculous aerial escape!
Aerial?
The "blue" in  Blue Wonder refers to the sea.
Same difference, right?
The blue of the sky is reflected
in the blue of the sea, right?
It's like detective and phantom thief.
They appear to be as different
as heaven and earth,
but look closely, and you'll see
they're both insolent fellows who use
the key of curiosity to pry open something
that someone else wants to keep shut.
Dumbass. The blue of the sky and sea
are from the color's
diffusion and reflection.
It's because they're completely
different substances.
They're not the same thing at all.
You can see the proof in a puddle,
which isn't blue, right?
You have no dreams, do you?
If I talked about dreams all the time,
I wouldn't be able to see through to the truth.
That aside, do you really think you'll
capture me with that tranquilizer gun?
If I get knocked out at this speed,
we'll get into a major wreck.
Don't worry.
I won't shoot you until the bike stops.
I've already contacted Inspector Nakamori,
so he'll be the one to arrest you.
Like I'm gonna stop.
This is something old man
Jirokichi is proud about, I bet.
The bike has a trick you can do
to get rid of excess weight.
See you around, great detective.
In the end, I wasn't really after the jewel.
This time was just about
taking up the gauntlet.
Bastard!
I won't shoot you until the bike stops.
That little turd hit the gas tank!
For them, don't be bound by theory,
but intoxicate them with a display
of brilliant magic that verges
on the impossible...
If you can do that, your troublesome
heckler will turn into an ardent fan.
This is how a true magician ought to be.
What kind of magic should I use
to boggle his mind next time?
Tonight's performance was
a miraculous mid-air walk.
I'm sure even the pint-sized
detective was impressed.
Well, see you next illusion.
Sheesh! That brat's gonna get it!
I was almost burnt toast back there!
But my next prey is...
He's after the world's biggest emerald,
which is being used as a prop in a play!
Who gave you permission to do the preview?
What's the difference?
It makes a difference!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Green Dream!
Green Dream
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
You're the culprit!
Yeah, that's right! It's me! Of course!
Ahem...
Don't miss the illusion!