Ladies and gentlemen,
I bring you miraculous illusions that
make this town sparkle at night!
What is the final destination
of this jewel with a past?
Now, how should I serve up
those three crows?
What an amateur.
A flying figure?!
Th-That's right, Inspector!
There's a black silhouette holding on
to a paraglider next to Kid!
Hey, look!
On the back of the paraglider...
A... a cat?!
My name is Chat Noir.
Sunday at 9:00 pm.
I'm looking forward to our showdown
at Hotel Ocean at that time.
That's right. You capture Chat Noir,
and you can take back the
six cat's-eyes he stole.
That's the point of this whole exhibit.
If you don't take Chat Noir seriously,
you're in for serious trouble.
Sorry, Aoko.
I can't afford to lose this contest.
You will be wearing the Golden Eye
on your finger
and waiting with it on top of this case.
W-What is this weird line of sight?
So, how are you going to attack,
Kid the Phantom Thief?
I'm already set.
Golden Eye (Part Two):
Kid Versus Chat Noir: Endgame
Well, it's 8:55p.m.. Five minutes before
the theft is scheduled to be committed.
Central security room.
What's the situation?
Right! Everything is going
according to plan!
Elevators 1, 2, 3, and 4
are stopped at the top, the 30th, floor.
The elevator controls are locked.
All stairways from the top floor to
the roof and from the top floor down
have been sealed off.
Okay.
Maintain that status until
I order you otherwise.
It's perfect, Cartier-kun!
Now just protect that ring,
the Mitsuishi family treasure,
from Chat Noir and
Kid the Phantom Thief.
That ring that
Inspector Nakamori is wearing.
That memento from Marie Antoinette...
...the Golden Eye!
But are you sure about this?
I don't see any helicopters outside...
I told you, Investigating Agent Ruby.
As long as we have this glass with
embedded titanium alloy wires,
no one can use it to get into
or escape out of.
Helicopters would just be a nuisance.
Now, given the two thieves in question,
they're likely already impersonating someone,
boldly coming up to this floor,
even lurking among us now.
What's that?
Floodlights.
This exhibit is dimly-lit, so we were told
to put a spotlight on Inspector Nakamori.
Oh, and who gave that order?
Th-The inspector! Inspector Nakamori
radioed it in a couple minutes ago...
Hey, I didn't order that...
Th-There's no time!
Light him up! Turn 'em all on!
Roger! Lighting up banks 1 to 5!
Was it really the inspector?
Yes! It was definitely his voice!
Lighting up banks 6 to 10!
Lighting up banks 11 to 20!
I-Idiots! If you put them
on me all at once...
Crap!
Dammit!
Nothing to worry about.
A breaker just tripped.
With this electrical system, the lights
will be back on in ten seconds.
More importantly,
I would like to welcome our guests.
The poor thieves who willingly
entered this inescapable cage.
So, Monsieur Nakamori.
Please put on the gas mask
and prepare for their attack.
Right...
Make sure you keep that fist
with the ring on it closed.
B-But...
...how am I supposed to prepare
when I can barely see?
Thanks.
K-Kid the Phantom Thief!
It's Kid! Kid's here!
P-Protect the inspector!
Idiots! Let go of me!
He's got some cheek, showing up like this!
You're not getting away!
That's my face!
I've got Kid's leg!
That's my leg!
I've been waiting, Kid the Phantom Thief.
Waiting for this opportunity!
Power's coming back on-line!
Restoring lights to the room!
D-Do you still have the ring?
Is the Golden Eye safe?
It's fine. I kept my fist tight.
There, see?
I-Inspector!
That ring...
The jewel is gone!
I-I don't believe it!
The jewel was removed without
damaging the ring...
Look! It's him!
That white hang glider belongs to Kid, right?
I-It can't be!
C-Cartier-kun!
What's the meaning of this?!
I thought nobody could escape
from this floor!
It seems you've underestimated him.
I don't know about your French cat burglar,
but Kid is a master thief who
makes the impossible possible!
That's right!
Anyway, I'm going after Kid.
All right, we're on it, too.
Wait.
Let's let that dumb investigator
chase after a dummy.
That was a dummy?
Take a good look.
There's a black balloon attached
to the hang glider from above.
You're right. That does seem like a dummy.
But then he's...
We haven't lost yet.
You see, the ring is...
Inspector Nakamori!
I found an unconscious man in
the bathroom supply closet!
What?! What man?!
A-Actually...
...it looks like him!
H-He's Cartier?!
Bastard...
I thought you seemed overly casual...
But you're Kid in disguise!
No...
Get him!
Hey, what's the ruckus?
The inspector is scuffling with Kid
in the exhibit room!
What?!
He needs our help!
All right! Got it!
See you later!
Glass with titanium alloy wires inside...
But...
But all those wires ruined the view.
Don't worry!
I can replace that elevator
once this is over,
and you'll be able to see
the magnificent view again.
Then...
...these wires are on the inside
of this observation elevator.
In other words, they're part of the car
that takes passengers up and down.
And outside of the car...
...is just regular heavy plate glass, right?
K-Knock it off!
I'm the real thing!
Inspector!
The sleeping Cartier-san's face...
H-He's...
...the riot cop who hauled
in the floodlights!
Yeah, everything's going
according to plan, Jii-chan.
Now I just have to wait for
the inspector and company.
Still, they fell for it
hook, line, and sinker.
I attached a dummy ornament to
the underside of the ring...
...and just turned it around!
I'm a genius!
A phone?
Whose?
H-Hello?
Bonsoir, Kid the Phantom Thief.
If you're still there, then I imagine
you're gloating over the stolen ring?
C-Chat Noir!
F-Fake?!
I would never put the
real one on your finger.
Then where is the real one?
Look, the real one is on the tie pin
attached to Monsieur Nakamori's tie...
Th-The end's been chopped off?!
Yes. I expected that you
would turn off the lights,
so I took advantage of the darkness and
cut off the end of the inspector's tie.
Excuse me...
And that's how I got the real ring,
attached to the tie with the pin.
I realized the other one
was a fake right away.
Because I knew Cartier would never put
Marie Antoinette's ring on the inspector's finger.
I went to the trouble of calling
you like this to thank you.
I just had to get this ring.
It's the last precious
piece of the collection.
So that's why you provoked me and
tempted me to come here, huh?
After your theft, you sent the hidden,
remote-controlled hang glider on the roof flying.
You made it look like
Kid the Phantom Thief was escaping,
so you would have an excuse
to leave that floor.
With no other tall buildings in the area
and a dim night view, it would've been
tough to spot Chat Noir's black paraglider
coming out of that penthouse window.
Right?
"Investigating insurance agent"...
...Ruby Jones-san?
Oh, dear. How long have you known?
Since I overheard you
talking to that girl, Aoko.
Like me, Ruby said her name was
chosen from her birthstone.
And she said our birthdays are close,
so we should be friends.
But when we were talking about it,
Cartier-san butted in.
And he said, "Then was your
friend born in December?"
After hearing her birthday,
you said yours was close.
Certainly, in France, ruby is the birthstone
for March and sapphire is April,
but in America and Japan, ruby is the July
birthstone, while sapphire is September.
With a two-month difference,
you wouldn't say they were "close," right?
And only in France is malachite
the birthstone for December.
The countries are slightly different.
And that's how I figured it out.
You were French pretending to be American.
Huh. I see.
And I know that you're a sad thief who's
collecting your parent's personal effects.
Chat Noir boldly left a replica
of the accessory at the site
that looked exactly like the
Marie accessory he stole.
The only thing different was that
it didn't contain the cat's-eye,
but looked like the jewel had
been taken out of the replica.
We don't know yet if they
were really Marie's mementos,
but either way, those embedded
cat's-eyes are valuable jewels,
and the designs are close
to items from that period,
so even historians tend to
think that they're genuine.
So you left a perfect replica
at the scene of each crime,
which means you had
the replica beforehand.
But considering the original accessories
were sealed away for 30 years,
someone much older than you
must have made the replicas.
On top of that, if I imagine Chat Noir's
black costume as mourning garb,
it easily leads to this answer.
My, my. For a thief, you certainly
sound like a detective.
But you're right.
Ken Mitsuishi, a Marie Antoinette fan and
father of Dan, had my jewelry designer father
create the seven accessories.
He said he wanted to give his wife
accessories that Marie herself could have worn.
But they turned out to be such fine works
of art that Ken claimed they were real.
My father committed suicide
rather than sully Marie's name.
And Ken Mitsuishi reluctantly
sealed the accessories away.
Then I found my father's last words.
To honor his will, I took the accessories
back before they appeared on the market.
This is a keepsake from my father, this...
W-Wait...
This is...
That's right. Unfortunately,
what you have there
is a fake I prepared myself.
When the inspector flipped
his tie over his shoulder,
I made the switch.
Then you knew it was a fake, but still
stole the ring from his finger...
Yes. If I didn't live up to your expectations
by turning off the lights and appearing,
you might have gone with
a more reckless gamble.
I lose.
Too bad, but it looks like I'll
just have to give up on that ring.
If you have it, I can at least take comfort
that it probably won't hit the market.
No. This is a memento
from your beloved father.
I'm going to return it to you
in five seconds.
Silly...
Where do you think I am right now?
Even the legendary Houdini
couldn't manage a feat like that.
Three... two...
One.
I don't believe it. How...?
You're on Air France flight 273,
departing from Narita at 11:55.
An educated guess based on the schedule time
of the crime and this hotel's location.
Then you've got a confederate
on this flight...
B-But why?!
Why would you return it?
It's because...
...the reason for your crimes
resembles my own.
Perhaps...
Th-There he is! Kid!
All right!
A hole?!
Don't let him get away! Lower the elevator!
Yes, sir!
I-Idiot! That's just black paper
made to look like a hole!
You bastard!
We stopped.
Is it okay to stop?
What the hell?! Hey!
We're gonna crash after all?!
All rightie...
You're going to fly away again, aren't you?
In that garish white suit...
Yeah. I'm Kid the Phantom Thief.
Completely different from a cat burglar who
dresses in black to avoid being noticed.
A phantom thief is audacious
and magnificent to behold.
Goodbye, Kid the Phantom Thief.
And merci, Kaito Kuroba.
I'll never forget you, Kaito Kuroba.
Paris Collection,
Paris Collection! C'est bon!
A phantom thief calling
herself a black cat...
Now that she's achieved her objective,
I doubt she'll appear again.
Me?
As a phantom thief, I'm an
extraordinary illusionist.
Whether I achieve my objective or not,
as long as people desire it, the show will go on.
Well, see you next illusion.
Well, while Jii-chan is
enjoying the Paris Collection,
I think I'll start getting
ready for my next heist.
The prey is a black opal.
But then a shady mastermind called
Nightmare proposes teaming up with me.
On top of that, Interpol and a
high school detective show up!
Wait, that jerk's gonna be here?!
That leaves me without any room for error!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Dark Knight!
Dark Knight
Step right this way. Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion.