Ladies and gentlemen!
I bring you marvelous illusions that
will make tonight sparkle, too!
I hope you enjoy my somewhat troublesome
rival and a black miracle!
Two steel crows in the night sky...
Three more on their other side...
Whoa! They've even prepared armored cars!
Kudos to the Metro Police!
They're fired up!
Please reconsider, Young Master Kaito.
I have a bad feeling about tonight's job.
If you got backed into a corner like
last time and something happened to you,
no apology of mine would suffice for the
ghost of Toichi-sama, the previous Kid.
Sheesh. You're always like this
before a big job.
Gimme a break.
And anyway, tonight I'm not the son of
illusionist Toichi Kuroba, your former boss,
nor am I high school student
Young Master Kaito...
Right now, I'm the guy
who's got everyone talking.
I'm the I'm the flashy scoundrel.....
Young Master...
But now that you mention it,
that was a close call, wasn't it?
Black Star
That was too easy! Like
taking candy from a baby!
Kid the Phantom Thief Appears Yet Again
and Steals the Treasure with Style!
Kid the Phantom Thief Dazzles Police Again
with His Daring Crime
This is such a cinch, I could pull off the
next job with both hands tied behind my back!
"Number of Kid's female fans skyrocketing"?
That's awesome!
"Female fans skyrocketing," my foot!
This girl is no fan of that thief!
In fact, when it comes to the scummiest
of scumbags, he's at the head of the pack!
Come on, don't let it get to you like that.
You can't blame Kid if he gives that
third-rate inspector father of yours
a spanking every time.
After all, he's... One! Two! Three!
"The Great Thief Who Can't Be Caught!"
The Great Thief Who Can't Be Caught!
In-depth analysis of the mysterious
Kid the Phantom Thief
Yeah, right!
He always either throws away what he
steals or secretly returns it later.
He's a criminal thrill-seeker
pretending to be a good guy!
Oh, that's what I like about him.
He's cute, like a mischievous boy.
Don't let him put one over on you!
No matter how you slice it,
he's a criminal! A bad guy!
Anyway, you saw Kid's next target
on the news, didn't you?
Oh. You mean the old clock tower
in front of the station?
That's right! That belongs
to everyone in this town!
Kid the Phantom Thief's Next Target,
the Clock Tower, Slated for Relocation
Metro Police Enact Strict Security Measures,
Seal Off Entrance
"I Hope They Protect the Clock Tower,"
Says Owner
So don't you think it's terrible
that he means to steal it?
Y-Yes. You're right.
And besides...
...that clock tower is...
But I heard they're gonna
move the clock tower.
Make it the symbol of
some amusement park...
Keiko...
Everyone's saying that as long as it's
going away, Kid might as well steal it.
What's wrong is wrong!
Hey, I don't know what you're up to,
but I would call off this job if I were you.
I told you before, I'm not Kid!
"When the bells of the old clock tower
ring out for the 20,000th time,
the magus of light will
come flying from the east
to destroy the sinner in white."
Is that crap supposed to be my fortune?
Not a fortune. It's a prophecy
Lucifer the Devil shared with me.
L-Luci...
That clock will strike for the 20,000th time
on the night you announced for the theft.
Whether or not you believe it is up to you.
This goes for the choppers in the air
and all the squad cars
around the clock tower!
Report to me the moment you
see any suspicious characters!
For the guards in each block of the tower,
nobody gets past you without my say-so!
But do you really think Kid will
show up, Inspector Nakamori?
"On Saturday, night of the full moon,
I shall appear at the stroke of midnight
On Saturday, night of the full moon,
to steal the towering clock
right from under your nose.
- Kid the Phantom Thief
to steal the towering clock
right from under your nose.
Kid the Phantom Thief."
You'd need a crane or something
to swipe that huge clock.
Moron!
If he says he's gonna steal somethin',
he's gonna steal it!
It's the hand of the clock.
50 years ago, my father, the mayor,
spent a fortune to have the hands crafted
by a famous clockmaker overseas.
Several large diamonds are
inlaid in the hour hand,
which makes it a valuable piece of art.
I imagine he's after those jewels...
What's the owner doing in here?
He insisted on checking out
the security measures himself.
Anyway, please protect it.
Protect it from the clutches of the thief
who sent me his prankster advance notice,
saying he would take my beloved clock tower,
which I inherited when my father passed.
Right. You can count on us.
28 minutes and 30 seconds 'til it's time.
Well, Officer Sensui Yoichi
from Ekoda, 27 and single,
I'm going to borrow your name and face.
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
What a mob.
Sir! How is it inside?
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
Perfect. An ant couldn't get to it.
But will it be okay?
The amusement park side is saying if
dismantling it doesn't start tomorrow,
it won't be ready by their opening day,
so they'll cancel the purchase.
And if Kid steals the gems from the
hour hand and realizes the truth...
Shh! Right now, only you and I know
that I sold off the diamonds
and replaced them with fakes.
With Kid targeting the clock, its value has
shot up, making now the best time to sell.
If they find out the gems aren't real after
the tower's moved, it's not my concern.
But the replicas are safe.
Even a great, elusive thief
couldn't steal that huge clock
right in front of all these people.
Stay home, Kid!
You can do it, Dad!
Anti-Kid
Hey, Aoko, you're the only one
cheering against him.
Well, after all...
By the way, Keiko, have you seen Kaito?
Nope.
He said he was going to watch
a magic show on TV tonight.
I guess I am the only one who remembers...
What?! You were out on patrol when you saw
a suspicious guy who looked like Kid?!
Yes! He dropped this weird hat and ran off!
Th-That's Kid's silk hat and cape!
This is the front entrance!
One of our own has found
Kid the Phantom Thief's hat!
He's here, my lady.
Yes. That helicopter's definitely the one.
He gives off strong, clear energy,
just like Kuroba-kun.
He also has the cunning of a demon and keen
eyes that can penetrate a person's heart.
But who is he?
Hey! What's goin' on here?!
I see an extra helicopter!
Apparently reinforcements from headquarters.
I didn't ask for additional help!
Oh, you're the one who found Kid's silk hat?
I heard the message.
Just to be safe, please show me
your badge and license.
Certainly.
Now, tell me your name, age, and birthday.
I'm Sensui Yoichi, 27 years old.
My birthday's on June 2nd.
All right, good man.
Inspector Nakamori is eagerly
awaiting you on the top floor.
Yes, sir!
Oh, that's right. Just in case,
tell me your license number.
Oh, sure.
It's 6286-0552-4810.
I-It's...
It's Kid the Phantom Thief! Get him!
S-Seriously?!
What?! You found Kid in the building?!
Yes, sir! Currently, teams
C and D are in pursuit!
Hey, are you sure it's the real thing?
Positive!
After asking his name, age, and birthday,
I requested his license number as
advised, and got him red-handed!
License number?
Right. That thief is a master of disguise,
so the idea is, it's likely he can remember
details the average person can't.
That's what the boy sent
from HQ as backup said.
"Boy," you say?
I repeat! Please seal off all entrances
and exits to the clock tower immediately.
And keep them sealed until I give the order.
This way, he's like a rat in a trap.
This is Nakamura and Kawata from team D!
We lost sight of the target
near the third-floor restroom!
Calm down.
He's probably still very close to you.
The ventilation opening in the restroom...
Has the cover been unscrewed?
It has!
Then he's inside!
Please continue your pursuit!
There he is!
It's him!
Oh, come on! The inspector's
really sharp tonight!
Unless someone's giving the inspector advice?
But who could it be?
Megure! I figured it was you!
What's the idea of bringing a kid here?!
This is my operation!
Besides, you're in different divisions!
Sorry about that. I promised him
a ride in the helicopter,
and since we were airborne anyway,
we flew over to the scene...
Inspector! Pardon me,
but we don't have time to argue.
If you want to catch that thief,
follow my instructions.
Excuse me?!
His identity has been exposed before
committing the crime, so he's agitated.
His plan is starting to go off track.
This is the best chance to arrest him!
W-Who is this?!
Who the hell are you?!
Shinichi Kudo.
I'm a detective.
S-Shinichi Kudo , you say?!
Oh, I've heard of him.
He's a high school detective who's solved
one mysterious murder case after another.
Then you're in a different division, too!
We're dealing with a phantom thief here!
Inspector, a high school student
isn't in any division...
The point is, this is the job of the police!
As a civilian, you'd better just
sit quietly in that chopper!
Inspector Nakamori!
Kid's been spotted in a ventilation
shaft, disguised as a cop!
We're in pursuit!
What?!
This is Nakamura! It seems the target means
to exit from another ventilation opening.
Stay calm.
The prey is as good as in your claws.
Please tell me your current location.
A-Actually, I'm not sure, since I've
been crawling around in the dark.
We went up one floor, so I can tell you
we're on the 4th floor, but...
No worries. All 28 ventilation openings
in the building are now secured.
Continue support. He's out of places to run.
Officers guarding the ventilation openings
on the 4th floor, prepare to make an arrest.
There you go again, giving orders!
Th-This is Nakamura!
I lost sight of the target
at a ventilation shaft exit!
What's your current location?!
Um, this is...
The east hallway on the 4th floor!
The target shed his police officer disguise
and is currently escaping down the stairs!
Requesting immediate backup!
K-K-Kid the Phantom...
All right! He panicked and
ditched his police disguise!
All officers on the third and fourth
floors, proceed to the stairs!
Don't let him get away!
But how does that boy know so much about
the structure of this clock tower?
That's no mystery.
A little while ago, I sent the data
we have here over to his computer.
You dumbass!
Ow!
It's strange, isn't it?
The place is crawling with police officers,
so taking off his cop disguise
is like a crab that discards its shell,
roaming around the ocean floor.
I can't understand it.
I-It's the time he noted.
Yeah...
Inspector! Smoke is coming
out of the scaffolding!
What?!
H-Hey, look at that!
Th-The clock's hands...
...are gone!
It can't be!
I-I don't believe it...
Wow! You're amazing, Kid!
Kid... Kid, you idiot!
It's wobbling?
Dammit!
What in God's green earth is goin' on here?!
Sorry, but can you get us a
little closer to the clock?
W-What the...?!
Hey! What happened?!
An officer suddenly came out
of the ventilation shaft.
After nailing us with some weird spray,
h-he went outside from there!
Th-That's crazy...
Then he should be clearly
visible from outside!
K-Kid the Phantom Thief!
It's me! Nakamori! I found Kid!
Right now, he's—
Sorry, Inspector Nakamori, but I don't have time
to play games with you guys right now.
It seems you've got a sharp joker
in your hand this time.
But if you're going to call someone
here, please do so only after
cracking the code in the center
of the clock face here.
C-Code?!
No way...
The clock face is quivering...
What does this mean, Kudo-kun?
He cut the light that was shining on
the clock face during the smokescreen,
then covered the face with a giant
screen he'd prepared beforehand.
Next, he projected the image
of a clock face without hands
from a projector on the
construction scaffolding.
But wouldn't a trick like that
be figured out quickly?
That trick is a fake.
I bet he's behind the screen right now,
removing the gems from the hour hand.
I'm going to borrow this for a second.
Hey! Who's shootin'?!
Crap! There's a helicopter this close?!
I won't be able to fly away
in my hang glider!
What should I do? What should I do?!
Listen to me, unlucky spirits
wandering through Hell.
Obey the Crimson Covenant. Turn your
remains into flames and come to me.
You mustn't, Akako-sama!
Displaying your power
in front of all these people...
But at this rate...
At this rate, Kuroba-kun will...
H-Hey, Kudo-kun!
Don't worry. I won't hit anyone.
Th-That's not the issue...
And now, the magic show finale!
Let's have a look at the man
behind the curtain!
W-Who is this guy?!
He fell right into the middle
of the crowd with that screen!
Finding him in the crowd will be impossible.
Hey, Megure!
Were you shootin' at me?!
No, it wasn't me...
By the way, Inspector,
did he say something to you?
Y-Yeah, he did.
Something about a code.
A code?
It doesn't make sense to me.
You're sure he etched those characters
into the center of the clock face?
Yeah, I'm sure.
In any case, it's important evidence.
We'll just have to cancel the clock tower's
scheduled move until the code is solved.
That's what I was gonna do anyway!
Well, it worked out, right?
The clock tower is safe
and his crime was foiled.
No, not quite, Inspector Megure.
He left a code on the face and entrusted
the clock tower to the police,
taking it out of the hands of the owner,
who intended to relocate it.
His encoded message is clear.
Change the katakana to roman characters,
move the vowels over one space clockwise, and:
"The sound of this bell
cannot be given to you."
Come to think of it,
I haven't heard his name yet.
What's the thief's name?
Oh, well...
Are you waiting for someone?
Yeah. I just moved here today
and I'm supposed to meet my dad here,
but he's so busy with work that he's late...
I'm Kaito Kuroba!
Nice to meet you.
I'm Kaito Kuroba. Nice to meet you.
Kaito!
Like I could forget, dummy!
Is something wrong, Young Master?
Your negativity brought it
all back, Jii-chan!
The clock tower job
when I almost got nabbed!
Now that you mention it,
whatever happened to that clock tower?
Oh, that's right.
You moved, so you don't know.
So they did relocate it, after all?
Shhh...
Three...Two...One!
Th-That ringing...
Afterwards, the cops investigated,
found out the diamonds were fake,
and the city bought the clock
for a cheap price.
Okay, time to get a move on!
I'm after a Big Jewel, the Suzuki
conglomerate's crown jewel, the Black Star!
Young Master, I won't try to stop you again,
but like Toichi-sama always said,
"When you face the audience, it's a duel.
Never be overconfident
or underestimate them,
but see into their hearts,
focus on every nerve in your hands,
exert your talent to the utmost, always
maintaining a smile and elegance..."
"And at all times,
remember your poker face."
Right?
Well, let's meet again under the
beautiful ringing of the bells.
See you next illusion!
I know, "Never be overconfident
or underestimate them,"
but even though it was just for an instant,
old man Nakamori saw my face!
I obviously need more training!
Thanks to this, even Aoko suspects me!
To get through this pinch, I'll have
to sew together a time interval,
and perform a subtle yet bold magic trick!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Kaito Kuroba's Busy Day Off!
Kaito Kuroba's Busy Day Off
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion!