Ladies and gentlemen,
I bring you marvelous illusions that
make this town sparkle at night!
Tonight, I hope you enjoy the miracle
of a ruby that guides someone's life.
Kid the Phantom Thief has issued
another declaration of war!
This time, his target is the world's largest ruby,
owned by the Hopper Magic Troupe.
Sheesh. That sneak thief will never learn,
no matter how many times he's foiled.
Dummy. I return 'em on purpose!
'Cause they're not the jewel I'm after.
You shouldn't do it.
A-Akako?!
Shouldn't do what?
I'm talking to Kid the Phantom Thief.
That ruby is called a demon stone because
misfortune comes to anyone who tries to get it.
Red Tear...
But if Kid insists, then it can't be helped.
Red Tear?
Wait, that jewel is the one...
A long time ago, Dad...
Red Tear
Inspector Nakamori! Kid the Phantom Thief
sent out another advance notice!
Idiot!
We already got his advance notice yesterday!
He said he's going to steal the world's
largest ruby from the Hopper Magic Troupe
during their dinner show at
the Minato Hotel tomorrow.
But this came today...
What?!
To My Dear Inspector Nakamori,
Disregard what I said in yesterday's notice...
Please excuse my absence.
- Kid the Phantom Thief
He's calling it off?!
Hey, did you see the news this morning?
Nope.
Here, this.
"Kid the Phantom Thief
Concedes an Early Defeat!
Is He on the Verge of Retiring?!"
Sheesh. I oughta sue for libel...
"Jody Hopper, leader of the
Hopper Magic Troupe, comments:
"It's a shame I won't get
to see his magic." Huh...
He must be scared of my Dad.
He's a coward when it comes down to it!
Jackass! Who could be afraid
of that third-rate inspector?
I have a good reason for
not stealing that jewel!
He just picked Aoko's pocket!
Wait!
Bastard!
Hey, what's wrong? Kaito?
Here.
This is yours, right?
Huh?
Th-Thank you!
In that instant,
she got Aoko's wallet back!
And so fast, it made the first pickpocket
look as subtle as a freight train!
W-Who is she?!
Honestly. I heard the Japanese let pacifism
lull them into a sense of false security,
but I didn't think it was this bad.
Are you the leader of
the Hopper Magic Troupe,
Jody Hopper-san?!
Yes.
Oh, she's a magician...
No wonder she's got fast hands.
Remember, Kaito, she's in
the news site's article...
I know.
Her grandfather is James Hopper,
once the greatest magician in England!
Did you know?
His father is Toichi Kuroba,
once the greatest magician in Japan!
Idiot. It's the world...
Yes. I know of him.
The world's foremost illusionist,
known as the Magician of East Asia.
But in the end, he and my grandfather
were both like that pickpocket.
Just cunning swindlers who deceived people
and rolled them for their money.
B-But you do magic, too...
After my grandfather died two years ago,
I had no choice but to inherit the troupe.
But even so, this is it.
That's right.
Tonight is the
Hopper Magic Troupe's last show.
Both of you, come and see it if you'd like.
If you care to be tricked
by swindlers like us.
It's them!
The mysterious organization that
murdered Dad eight years ago!
So they're after it, too...
The Red Tear that Jody-san owns!
Their objective is to obtain Pandora, too.
No way are they gonna pass up
the world's largest ruby.
And after I canceled the
advance notice for Dad's sake...
Hey, what are you muttering
to yourself about?
The movie's gonna start!
Two people at the hotel entrance,
one in the revolving restaurant on the roof,
and...
...three here at the dinner show.
I've got detectives in the audience too,
but... is he really not gonna show?
Jeez...
Why do you look so serious, Dad?
Kid's not coming tonight, right?
So you should enjoy this!
Y-Yeah, you're right.
Amazing! Amazing!
Oh, boy. Kaito was supposed
to come with me...
No way am I gonna see a show put on
by people who disrespect magicians!
And so here I am...
How does the venue look?
There are three or four
plainclothes cops in the audience.
But we don't see anybody who could be Kid.
All right, just as planned.
Execute the plan in ten minutes.
And don't screw up.
Yes, sir!
Well, Paul...
Nice job.
When did you get this good?
Probably because it's his last chance.
It's not just Paul.
The others are also going all out
to improve their skills.
They want you to keep
this magic troupe going.
I already told you, Robert.
When I took over, I gave you all two years
to find real jobs, and that's it.
If you want to keep the troupe going,
you can do it yourselves.
B-But...
...you're the only one who
can keep us together...
I'm sick of being in this world
of lies and deceit.
Besides... I want this to be the last time.
The last time I wear this accursed jewel...
M-My lady...
Look!
That's the leader, Jody-san!
Then that's the world's biggest ruby, huh?
Just a moment!
Are you with the troupe?
Y-Yes...
Does she always wear that jewel?
Yes.
That's basically the trademark
of our magic troupe.
Um, I didn't see Jody-san listed
as a performer in the program...
Is she not very good at magic?
Heavens, no!
Ever since my lady was a little girl,
her parents and grandfather,
James-san, taught her,
so even now, she's the most talented
magician in the whole troupe.
So her parents perform magic, too...
Yes.
They were a brilliant pair
in the world of magic.
Until they died ten years ago,
in an accident in the middle of a show.
That was the day James-sama was going to
retire and pass the jewel on to those two.
Ever since then...
...my lady has felt disdain for magic.
And since then, that ruby has been called
a demon stone, bringer of misfortune.
Come to think of it, Akako-chan
was saying something like that...
Jody-san...
And now, for our finale, the Human Cannon!
How about letting me...
...take care of the show's finale?
K-Kid the Phantom Thief!
Don't let him get away! After him!
Right!
What? He sent a note saying he wasn't coming!
You just can't trust a thief!
Kid the Phantom Thief...
Paul, take our lady to the dressing room!
R-Right!
Relax.
We haven't killed anyone yet.
I'm going to count to three.
If you don't want to get hurt,
give me that jewel.
Don't do it, my lady!
One!
Robert!
Two.
Three!
P-Paul!
Moron.
Now, give it here.
Unless you want to join him...
Halt, Kid!
K-Kid shot at me?!
It can't be...
Now, give it to me!
Y-You can have...
...this jewel!
You mustn't, my lady.
Don't give them the jewel.
P-Paul!
Are you all right?!
Yes. I'm wearing a bulletproof vest.
B-Bulletproof vest?!
Why would you have that?
That's because...
...I'm really Kid the Phantom Thief!
Y-You!
But Kid was out there...
That was probably one of their accomplices.
A decoy to lure Inspector Nakamori and
the other officers out of the venue.
Then what about Paul?
He's been on the toilet
since before the show.
No wonder! I didn't think Paul
was up to that level of magic.
This Red Tear is your target, too.
But I didn't think you were coming
after you canceled the advance notice.
I didn't come here to steal that.
I came here to protect...
...both you and the jewel.
Dammit!
They escaped upstairs?
I'll go after him!
You guys get lost!
Yes, sir!
All right! Just a little more!
Damn you, Kid!
That fraudulent bastard...
You're not going anywhere!
Dammit! All right, try this on...
That's what you get!
She's not James Hopper's
granddaughter for nothing...
Bitch!
Say, tell me...
Why do you want to protect me and the jewel?
Answer me, Kid!
Minato Hotel
Revolving Restaurant
You've got nowhere left to run.
Now, give me that jewel.
Her jewel isn't Pandora.
Besides, you're the one
who has nowhere to run.
What?!
I-It's spinning!
I did a little tinkering
with this restaurant's revolving mechanism.
B-Bastard!
And right as our guest is arriving!
What?!
S-Snake-sama!
Thank you, Kid. You saved me.
But "Demon Stone" fits.
Because of this jewel,
members of the troupe were injured
and the show was ruined...
This really was the last performance
of the Hopper Magic Troupe.
With apologies to my grandfather,
it looks like I can finally be free.
Free from the world of magic that
robbed my parents of their lives...
And free from this cursed ruby, too.
I know how you feel.
But magic doesn't kill people.
The jewel will tell you that.
Don't you think it's strange?
Normally, rubies are red,
but that jewel is blue.
And its name is "Red Tear."
N-Now that you mention it...
Red, a key word used to describe fire.
Observe.
Your grandfather, James Hopper,
left this to your world, his final...
...magic trick.
G-Grandfather...
Papa... Mama...
And me, when I was little...
A letter?
"My darling Jody..."
You may despise magic
for killing your parents.
I just want you to recall once more
the rush of excitement
you felt when performing
on stage the first time...
And the enthusiastic applause.
When this jewel glows red,
I pray that Jody Hopper, magic's gift
to the world, shall rise again.
James Hopper.
G-Grandfather...
Dad...
He uses the jewel's refractive index
to make the glow of flames appear.
It's projection magic.
Huh! Wow, he's great!
To make a device like that...
Yes. He calls it "Red Tear."
My magic mentor inserted it
into the jewel for his granddaughter.
It's very special magic.
I protected it,
Dad...
Both of my parents
were so proud of my magic...
I'd completely forgotten.
So you used to look like that
when performing magic, huh?
I'm going to give it one more shot.
Magic...
...and the magic troupe, too.
Kaito!
What's this? You were curious
and came after all, didn't you?
Pfft! I can do whatever they can!
Then do it right now!
Dummy. I'm done with tricks for the night.
After the Red Tear, anything
I did would pale in comparison.
Hey, Kaito!
Sheesh! You're so stubborn!
A miracle called the Red Tear.
Making that magic work requires the device,
knowing the trick, and one more thing...
Love embedded in the jewel.
Well, see you next illusion.
Kaito! Let's do the preview together!
What do you want?!
I'm here to help you! The last
preview I did was popular!
What do I care about popularity?!
In the next episode, a mysterious
phantom thief in black appears.
It sounds like he has a duel with Kid.
I'm gonna win... No, I mean,
Kid's gonna win!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Midnight Crow (Part One):
The Name is Corbeau the Phantom Thief!
"Midnight Crow (Part One):
The Name is Corbeau the Phantom Thief!"
Step right this way. Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion.