Ladies and gentlemen,
I bring you marvelous illusions that
make this town sparkle at night!
Please enjoy the miracle that happens
around a stage heroine tonight.
Marth and Rosa
Everyone! This theater
finally opens tomorrow!
It's also opening day for Marth and Rosa.
That's the day our mortal enemy, Kid the
Phantom Thief, says he's going to appear!
Our duty this time is to protect
the world's largest emerald,
Green Dream, as it's being used
for tomorrow's performance only!
Yeah!
Don't let your guard down,
even among fellow officers.
He's a master of disguise!
He may already be here right now,
posing as one of us!
Hey, part-timer! A little help over here!
Okay!
All right! I'm going to deploy you.
Teams 1 and 2 take the first floor
front lobby and the lobby gallery.
How many officers did you bring here,
Inspector Nakamori?
But that suits
Kid the Phantom Thief just fine.
Team 3, the 4th-floor lounge.
Teams 4 and 5, the fountain plaza.
Hey, give me a break!
You can't even get through these short lines?
I-I'm sorry.
Are you trying to disgrace my
performance with your lousy acting?
N-No, I would never...
Hey, Reiko. Megumi-chan isn't
used to being on stage yet.
You don't need to get that mad.
You're just as bad.
Even though you're playing the prince,
you fumble your lines.
That's only when you throw in
too many ad libs!
Anyway!
I'm the heroine.
All of you should just focus on
making me look good.
Or rather, the tour de force
of Reiko Imaizumi!
It seems further rehearsing
wouldn't do any good.
I'm going home.
I'll leave the rest to you, fearless leader.
H-Hey, Reiko-kun!
P-Please.
I won't mess up anymore.
I promise I'll do my best,
so please, let's practice once more!
You're Megumi Furuhata-san, I believe?
Y-Yes!
You have no talent.
You can't be an actress.
It'd be better if you gave it up now.
Reiko!
Sheesh. What a disgusting woman.
Who is she?
The only daughter of this theater's owner.
Even though she used her parent's pull to
land that part, she lords it over everyone.
When I think that she's the heroine,
it makes me want to take up a different trade.
I hope Kid the Phantom Thief
wrecks the whole show.
Green Dream
Marth and Roza
0 days until the show opens
Good job, everyone!
Good job!
Hey, kid! You wanna go out drinking with us?
No, I've still got a few...
...tricks to prepare for tomorrow!
Electric Room
That being said, with all the cops around,
I can't do what I need to!
This is a pretty pickle!
Marth-sama, Marth-sama!
Main Hall Stage Entrance
Whither are you, Marth-sama?
Please, throw that name away right now...
Who's here this late?
Okay. If that is your wish,
I'll be happy to dispose of it.
Oh! Marth-sama! What are you doing here?
Why did you come?
If you're found here,
you're as good as dead...
That's the girl who got chewed out
before during rehearsal...
Oh, no! My father's here!
W-Wow!
Who are you?! Get him!
She's doing all the parts!
Go! Run away, quick!
Even if the wings of my love are torn off,
I shall return to see you...
I'm not a weirdo!
I'm a part-timer! Just a part-timer!
I was making props, see?
U-Um, look...
I don't know anything about plays,
but that was pretty great just now.
R-Really?
With your skill, they should
give you a better part.
I'm no good at it.
When I'm in front of people,
I feel weak at the knees.
I get scared. Everyone's looking at me...
I feel like they see right through me
and are ridiculing me.
Thanks to that, I keep flubbing lines...
Even though this is the first time
I've gotten a role with lines,
I'm a nuisance to everyone.
I guess I'm really not
cut out to be an actress.
A radish could out-act me.
Try a pumpkin.
P-Pump...
Everyone's like that in the beginning.
But after you get used to it, you don't
even notice the eyes of the audience.
It's like they say...
Think of the audience as
rows of pumpkins in a field.
I'll try!
The Next Day
Marth and Roza
What a beautiful theater!
And it's got a retractable roof, right?
That's Tamura-san, the actor!
Look! Anan's here, too!
Wow! Celebrities everywhere!
If that girl had this one's personality,
she wouldn't have any hassles.
I can't wait, you know, Kaito?
What kind of expression is that?
You said you wanted to see the play,
so I had my dad get us complimentary tickets!
Let's see a little more
gratitude on your face!
Yeah, yeah...
Electric room, sound off! Any abnormalities?
The power and wiring are fine.
Be careful!
Taking advantage of a blackout to
steal is a common tactic of his.
Stay alert!
Yes, sir!
All right. At least we won't
lose power in the theater.
And even if we do,
the 20 battery-powered lights we
set up will keep him in our sights!
Kid, this is your last appearance.
You'll never get the chance
to escape from me again!
Let's see...
Megumi Furuhata, Megumi Furuhata...
There!
Furuhata Megumi... "Servant A."
What are you laughin' at?
After all, it's unusual.
That you wanted to see a play like this...
The setting is Europe in the Middle Ages.
A prince and princess from two
countries that are enemies
overcome various obstacles
to be together in the end.
It's a totally romantic story.
Seriously?!
And now you're embarrassed! How cute!
I shouldn't have come here with her...
Thank you for your patience.
We now present Marth and Rosa.
It's no use.
I've searched all over the country, but no
woman here would make me a suitable wife.
Isn't she out there somewhere?
Beautiful, sweet,
and dazzling like this Green Dream,
the royal family treasure!
Kid didn't show up.
No, but there's one more scene where the
jewel's shown, so it'll be out of our hands.
He'll probably make a play for it then!
A ball to choose the queen?!
Oh... Hosted by Prince Marth of Gaia...
D-Don't do it, Princess!
Gaia is our country's enemy!
If you're discovered,
who knows what would happen?
Megumi-chan's on!
Please think better of it.
Then are you saying that I,
the most beautiful woman in the world,
should be shut away in this
country for the rest of my life?
U-Um, I-I wasn't saying...
Reiko's suddenly ad-libbing again!
Never mind. You can be excused.
I don't have a good feeling
about that heroine...
Yeah, right?
What were you thinking?
Did you want to ruin the show?
N-No, I...
You're an eyesore.
Get out of my sight.
Reiko-san! You're on!
You don't have anything to worry about!
It's not your fault, Megumi!
Come on, cheer up!
It's almost the last scene.
Let's go backstage.
Right!
Oh, beautiful one!
I hope you will become my wife.
It cannot be, Prince.
A relationship between us is forbidden.
If you would have it, I would give you...
...the Gaia royal family's treasure,
Green Dream!
All right, where are you?
Where are you gonna come from, Kid?
You won't be able to hide
in the dark tonight!
You're naive, Inspector.
Darkness isn't the only thing
that can hide a person.
L-Lights?!
Crap!
Th-The jewel!
The emerald is mine!
- Kid the Phantom Thief
Y-You... I didn't think you'd use
bright lights to disappear...
Hurry up and lock down
all entrances and exits!
He's still in the theater!
Inspector! What about the electric room?!
Leave it! All hands gather!
Electric Room
W-What the...?
What's happening?
After the curtain of night closed in
and the moon began to tilt,
there was still one girl in the palace
after everyone had left the ball,
and she was in love with the prince.
Her name...
...was Servant A!
She had been bullied every day
by the mean princess...
...and couldn't tell anyone
how she felt.
This lovely girl just
endured the pain
in her small chest,
like that of a baby bird.
Th-These cheesy lines...
But then a strange magician...
...appeared from above...
...and alighted before her.
K-Kid the Phantom Thief!
K-Kid?!
No, I'm not Kid.
I'm just a magician who'll make...
...your dream come true!
I stole this jewel, just as I
stole the light...
...but it seems it's not
what I was looking for.
Let's keep this...
...on your beautiful finger.
Well, it's time, my lady.
Go to your prince.
B-But...
But I...
I can't...
I can't do this!
Director! Should I lower the curtain?
No, leave it!
Pumpkins.
You mustn't escape the audience's gaze.
Muster courage and accept it.
No one can see through to your heart.
You...
Well...
S-She's singing?!
Megumi!
Oh! What a beautiful singing voice!
It feels as if my mind is clear
for the first time.
M-Marth-sama...
Come, let me see your face more clearly.
What a pretty young woman.
Don't move...
...so this moment won't escape me.
Well, let's continue with the play!
Yes! For Megumi...
I didn't know the story
would be this beautiful!
I wonder if that was the real
Kid the Phantom Thief before?
You know, Kaito?
There's no way!
That had to be an actor, too.
But what a great play!
Yeah. I'm glad I got to see it.
Thanks, Kaito.
Inspector, I wonder why Kid
didn't make off with the jewel.
How would I know?!
Megumi-san's in another magazine!
She been famous ever since that play.
Yeah. I hear she's gonna be
in a TV drama next.
But there's something
I don't like about her.
Huh? What is it?
Well, after all, her ideal man
is Kid the Phantom Thief...
Megumi Yoshida
Exclusive Interview
My ideal man is Kid the Phantom Thief
That sucks!
Tonight, a nameless servant
became a dazzling star
in the space of a moment.
Everyone is the main character
of their own life.
Of course, that goes for you, too.
Well, see you next illusion.
Boy, Megumi-chan had a
beautiful singing voice!
I wish I could have listened to her
forever, but who's got the time?
The next treasure's waiting for me!
Who's calling me an amateur?
It seems you've got confidence
in your own thieving ability,
but it wouldn't be wise
to underestimate me.
I accept your challenge!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Golden Eye (Part One): Chat Noir's Challenge!
Golden Eye (Part One):
Chat Noir's Challenge
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion!