Ladies and gentlemen!
I bring you marvelous illusions
that will make the night sparkle!
I hope you enjoy tonight's miracle,
in which red and white intersect.
What?! A ghost?!
Seriously?!
Yes, I'm being serious! Keiko saw it!
She was studying in the library yesterday...
It's already this late?!
What's that?
No one should still be upstairs.
Were you scared?
B-By your face...
Come on!
So what happened to Keiko after that?
She was so shocked that she stayed in bed,
and she's absent today.
So the only thing to do is avenge her!
Good luck.
You too!
Adult's Charm
Why do I have to go with you?!
Because it's dangerous for
a cute girl to be alone!
Cute, huh?
What?!
School at night gives me the creeps.
Y-Yeah...
That reminds me.
I asked around,
and apparently Keiko isn't the
only person who's seen a ghost.
11 people have seen one this month.
All of them were students
who stayed here late.
Th-Then...
...we'll be 12 and 13.
"13" is an unlucky number to begin with!
D-Don't talk like an idiot!
A-After all...
Leave here...
Leave...
A speaker... The broadcasting room?!
Dammit!
Kaito, wait for me!
Somebody's yankin' my chain!
Ow...
You're such a klutz!
That's what happens
when you run in the dark!
What's that?!
Blood?
K-Kaito, you're gonna die!
Anyway, it definitely wasn't my blood.
Somebody's trying to scare us.
Is it just a prank? Or maybe...
K-Kaito...
W-Wait here a minute.
What? I'll leave you here.
I can't go you with in there!
Number two?
Number one.
Sheesh. Women!
Sorry for the wait.
Where's Kaito?
Oh, a cat!
Come here!
Shhh! Scream, and they'll
know where we are.
W-Where were you?!
I was scared!
What else could I do?!
Quit whimpering!
You're such a little kid!
You only treat me like a little kid!
It's your fault for leaving me in the lurch!
Okay, I'm gonna take a look around.
You stay put.
Please. Don't leave me alone again.
I'll go with you.
Forget it!
From this point on, it's a man's area!
I won't let a girl be exposed to danger!
Kaito...
How cliched...
Shut up.
Here. If they come in, give me a shout.
I'll come charging over.
Okay.
See you in a bit.
I have faith in you, Kaito.
Kaito?
Wait! Why are you running away?
H-Help me, Kaito!
Kaito! Hurry up... Get in here!
Science Room
Don't tell me...
I-It's okay now, right?
I'm alone, right?
It's me. Me...
Nakamori-san?
So it is you!
Y-You've got the wrong idea.
Magic experiments?
Shhh.
Sometimes I do them here in the science
room after everyone else has gone home.
There's plenty of space in here,
and a lot of chemicals.
Don't do stuff that can be
taken the wrong way!
Listen, don't you dare breathe
a word about this to anyone.
If you tell people, then they'll also find out
that you're Kid the Phantom Thief...
I told you before, I'm not
Kid the Phantom Thief!
Huh?
Crap!
Oh, you're awake, Nakamori-san.
Akako-chan?
There aren't any ghosts. It was just Akako.
Oh, really?
Th-That's right.
Sometimes I do magic experiments here.
Magic?
No, I mean...
Yeah, magic! Akako wants to
learn how to do magic tricks!
But don't sneak around here to
do it! Next time, I'll teach you.
Really?! That would be great!
I have no interest in learning
your tricks whatsoever!
Magicians are a witch's mortal enemy!
Oh, so that's what it was!
That's right. That's why I said, "It's me."
But you still got scared and ran away.
You're such a little kid!
Guilty as charged! Sorry, Akako-chan.
Come on. Let's go home.
Let's get a move on!
I'm too tired to take care
of you if you faint again!
Thanks for that, Kaito.
Jeez, you really are a little kid, Aoko.
Quit calling me that!
Honestly, what does he see
in that childish girl?
It gets my blood boiling.
Morning, Kaito.
H-Hi.
Huh? What's that thing?
This? It's a charm.
A-A charm?!
That's right. Akako-chan
was just telling me...
Akako-chan, sorry about yesterday.
I really am a little kid!
Then shall I teach you a charm
that'll make you more like an adult?
Adult
All you have to do is write "adult" on your
palm and wrap a handkerchief around it.
But listen. You have to
leave it on for four days.
Even in the bathtub, you can't wash it.
Huh...
Cool, right?
What nonsense!
You don't even know how to be a girl!
What?! I am a girl!
You should do this charm yourself, Kaito!
Say what?!
Of course that "charm" is nonsense!
I just want her to look like a fool.
Besides, Kaito Kuroba...
Men everywhere are captive to my trick.
Their gaze falls on me alone.
So how? How can you ignore me?
You should... You should
just vanish permanently!
Vanish?
That's it. I should rid this world of him.
Then the rest of the men
will all be my slaves.
I can't believe I didn't
think of this before!
I must be too good-natured!
Kaito Kuroba!
What's wrong?
I just suddenly got a chill.
Akako-sama, where are you going?
Akako-sama!
I'm leaving early today.
Enjoy the rest of your short life!
Most wicked god of this world, Lucifer!
Reveal your misshapen form
and answer my question!
Come forth, Lucifer! Come before me!
Who are you?
What fool would dare summon me?
Now, answer me, Lucifer!
How can I bring an end
to Kid the Phantom Thief?
On the night of a full moon, the
criminal will make a path in the sky
and hide in a tall, crimson tower.
Who are you, that gives me orders?
That was it. Go home.
Have you made what I requested?
As you can see...
Better safe than sorry.
Kaito, in order to continue being a magician,
there is something you must never forget.
That is a child's heart.
By the time you realize that,
you'll be an adult.
Do you understand, Kaito?
A child's heart?
Gimme a break, Dad.
I'll be 17 this year.
I've been an adult for some time now.
Inspector! Everyone's in place!
Last Emperor's Golden Seal
Listen! Don't shoot him!
I want him captured alive!
Yes, sir!
Damn you, Kid! This'll be the
night I finally catch you!
A full moon tonight...
W-Who's there?!
Shall I let you in on a
little secret, Inspector?
This will be the night
Kid the Phantom Thief dies.
Strange...
I have a bad feeling about tonight...
But whatever!
Inspector! Where were you
at a time like this?!
Shut up! Where I go is my business!
I-Inspector?
All right...
Let's see...
Ah, is this it?
Kid the Phantom Thief!
This is bad...
See ya around!
Outta my way!
What are you doing?!
Fill that little turd full of lead!
B-But, Inspector...
Move!
I'm gonna push Kid off this mortal coil!
Weird! What's wrong with
the inspector tonight?!
Bye, Inspector!
Damn you...
On the night of a full moon, the criminal
will make a path in the sky and
hide in a tall, crimson tower.
Akako!
I've been waiting for you, Kaito Kuroba.
Or should I say Kid the Phantom Thief?
But the end result will be the same.
When you're dead, you'll be nobody!
So you're trying to steal my life, huh?
But I'm the ever-elusive Kid the
Phantom Thief. I can even fly!
You sound like a child.
You believe you can do anything!
But I'm an adult.
And adults are much stronger than children!
I can even wipe you off the
face of this Earth right now.
Do it! Kill him! Kill him!
What's wrong? Do it.
I-I don't need you to tell me...
Adults are strong, right?
Go ahead!
Morning, Akako!
I can see the beautiful gem lying
deep within your frozen heart...
Kid...
You can't do it.
You can't wipe anyone off
the face of the Earth.
After all, you're still a child!
W-What are you talking about?!
I'm no child!
There, see? You are a child.
Y-You're wrong!
No, I'm not.
Ouch. I got a scrape.
It's like you're on tiptoes, trying to
become an adult, only looking at the sky.
Y-You're talking about yourself!
Yeah, you're right!
I'm Kid.
So maybe there's nothing wrong
with staying a child.
Wait!
Jeez...
On tiptoes, trying to become an adult...
What a cheesy line.
Another dud.
Ah, well. Guess I'll secretly return it.
You consider yourself an adult?!
Far from it!
After all, you wet the bed and
cry for "Mommy" when you fall.
Not in recent memory...
Listen, if you're an adult,
you should be more composed
and less talkative.
That reminds me.
I recently had to laugh...
I went to a new pancake
house with a friend...
What is an adult?
Wipe him out! Wipe him off
the face of the Earth!
Last Emperor's Golden Seal Stolen
Wipe this out! Wipe that out!
Dad?
I'm gonna wipe everything out!
That's enough of that!
Right.
The charm that'll make you an adult!
Idiot! Like I'd do that!
Getting embarrassed about it is
more proof that you're a kid!
Shut up!
If I'm a kid, you're a baby!
Excuse me?!
Both of you are still children.
Huh? That was...
The charm to become an adult?!
Well, until next time...
May you never forget the
heart of a child, either.
See you next illusion!
Someone sends Aoko an invitation.
It's for a private dinner at the
Bell Tree Tower, which sounds great,
but apparently, there's a catch to it.
As expected, we get mixed up
in trouble, but...
Huh? Could it be...?
When the past and present converge, the
first Kid the Phantom Thief appears!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Enter: The Phantom Lady!
Enter: The Phantom Lady
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion!