Ladies and gentlemen,
I bring you marvelous illusions that
make this town sparkle at night!
What miracle is going to happen
under the moonlight tonight?
Don't let him get away! After him!
Catch Kid the Phantom Thief!
You're not going anywhere!
I'll get you, Kid!
Sheesh.
They fall for my dummies every time.
He never learns.
That makes five heists this month.
And tomorrow will be the biggest haul of all.
All right! I'll be on top of my game.
Um...
For me?
Hello?
It's been a long time, Kid the Phantom Thief.
Um, who am I speaking to?
Have you forgotten my voice?
I've warned you before.
Keep your hands off precious gems.
Precious gems?
What you stole tonight isn't the one
we're looking for, so we'll let it go.
But if you dare to do it again,
you're a dead man.
Who was that guy?
Blue Birthday
Blue Parrot
"Keep your hands off precious gems"?
That's what he said?
Yeah. "What you stole tonight isn't the one
we're looking for, so we'll let it go.
But if you dare to do it again,
you're a dead man," he said.
Maybe he's got something
to do with Dad's murder?
I don't know, but I think you'd
better be extra-careful from now on,
Young Master.
I told you stop it with that,
Jii-chan. Just "Kaito" is fine.
No, I can't do that.
After all, you're the son of
my magic mentor, Toichi-sama.
Well, if you insist on calling me that,
I guess it's fine...
Young Master, as requested,
I've already prepared the props
for your next magic show.
Thank you.
What's this?
I get it!
And this is...
Color me impressed!
You made all of these, Jii-chan?
No, it wasn't me.
All of these items were created
by a doctor acquaintance of mine.
I didn't know you had any
doctor friends, Jii-chan.
Introduce me next time!
I'm sure you'll meet eventually.
"Kid the Phantom Thief will
strike again tonight!"
Kid the Phantom Thief Will
Strike Again Tonight!
"His target is the giant
sapphire, Blue Birthday.
The sleep-deprived Inspector Nakamori rubbed
his bloodshot eyes and promised victory."
Sounds like tonight's job will
be another piece of cake!
H-Hey!
The heck with Kid!
The heck with phantom thieves!
I'm fed up with him!
A-Aoko!
This is the sixth time this month.
My dad hasn't had a decent
night's sleep in a week!
Then that third-rate cop
should call it a day...
Who are you calling a third-rate cop?!
I swear, even though it's my own birthday,
Dad's only devoted to Kid!
B-Birthday?
Don't tell me you're turning 17?!
What? We're second-year
students, so of course!
But your chest, your hips, your butt...
Aoko, don't tell me...
W-What?
Are you really a boy?
Y-You're a jerk!
That's fine. You're not
invited to my birthday party!
You're gonna have a party?
Why didn't you say so?
I've got a job tonight...
I mean, an errand to run,
so I may be late, but I'll drop by.
If you're busy, you don't have to come.
Don't worry.
I'll liven the party up with a magic show
that no one'll ever forget.
Three, two, one!
Kaito...
Okay?
Thanks. That's a promise.
Of course. So as for a b-day present,
what do you want?
Let's see...
Kid the Phantom Thief!
How about capturing Kid for me?
That's not gonna happen.
Still...
I wonder why Kid the Phantom Thief
is pulling off all these thefts.
I mean, he either dumps everything he steals
or secretly returns it to the owner later...
I don't know if he's the greatest
phantom thief in the world,
but it seems like he's
just doing it for laughs.
That's it. He's doing it to make
my desperate dad look like a fool.
Come on, don't take it so seriously.
The guy is just a sneak thief.
He's a first-rate crumb!
Anyone who would laugh at someone who's
going all out is at the top of my list!
Uh-oh, having another
lovers' quarrel, I see...
Thanks for the drama!
Wait a second! Keiko!
Aoko...
You're wrong, Aoko.
I'm neither mocking your father
nor getting my kicks by stealing.
I wanna track down the bastards who
murdered my dad eight years ago.
He was a world-renowned
magician, as well as...
...Kid the Phantom Thief.
I just wanna find the guys who killed him.
Listen, Kaito. Listen well.
What is it today, Dad?
Before you do a trick, you must never
explain what's going to happen.
That's one of the three principles of magic,
as laid out by the great Thurston.
Don't explain what's going to happen?
That goes without saying, right?
All righty...
Another night on the town.
Aoko, try to understand.
If I act as Kid the Phantom Thief, I'm sure
the guys who murdered Dad will show up.
Until then, Kid the Phantom Thief...
...can't afford to quit!
Are you sure about this, Inspector Nakamori?
The Great Treasures of India Exhibition
Is this enough security to protect the
Blue Birthday, India's biggest sapphire?
You can count on me, Curator.
Nakamori Ginzo will guard the
Blue Birthday with his life!
Yes, but still...
...that doesn't look very secure to me.
Look again with these on.
W-What are those?!
Laser beams.
And not just any old lasers.
Anything that so much as touches them...
...is blown away in an instant.
On top of that, the cage is made of a
special absolutely unbreakable alloy,
and the floor is electrified
with a high-voltage current.
Even Kid the Phantom Thief
is a flesh and blood human.
I'm sure even he's smart enough
to stay away from all this!
I see. Lasers, a special alloy,
and an electric current...
You've really outdone yourself
this evening, Inspector Nakamori.
And yet...
His notice will just be
empty words this time...
I-Inspector! I-Isn't that...
K-Kid the Phantom Thief!
H-How did he get in there?!
Y-You little...
Turn off the power and open the cage!
Okay, now!
Charge!
Look at 'em go!
Then I'll join 'em!
Th-This is a rubber dummy!
I-Inspector!
K-Kid!
I did indeed purloin the Blue Birthday.
Let's meet again, Inspector Nakamori.
Halt!
Kid!
Okay. Part one of the plan was a success!
Curator, turn off the power.
R-Right.
You mean that was a fake?
Silly. He's not dumb enough
to make off with a fake.
Then how was it a success?
Mission: Capture Kid the
Phantom Thief, part two!
Locate his hideout!
There's a miniature super-sensitive
tracking device in the jewel's chain.
Even Kid the Phantom Thief can't remove it.
Y-You put that in without asking?!
All in the name of protecting the Blue
Birthday. So don't worry, Curator.
As long as he's got that gem,
he could run to the ends of the Earth,
but there's no escaping us!
Inspector!
We're picking up Kid's signal on the roof!
Good. Keep tracking him.
Call in the helicopters and a ground team!
Yes, sir!
Kid...
Say your prayers! I'm gonna
bust your hideout tonight.
This late already?!
If I don't get back soon,
I'll totally miss Aoko's birthday party!
That's a promise.
Yeah, yeah. I know.
All right. A direct flight to Aoko's house!
I'm warning you again.
Keep your hands off of precious gems.
That voice... The guy on the phone yesterday?
Long time no see, Kid the Phantom Thief.
Or...
...maybe I should say Toichi Kuroba.
How does he know my dad's name?!
I was surprised to hear that the fool
who went after the jewels we wanted
and died eight years ago
was actually still alive.
I see. It was them...
They killed my dad!
Now, hand over the gem.
Be a good boy and I'll let you live.
Just tell me one thing.
Why are you guys after jewels like this?
It seems that these jewels are the key.
The key to what?!
Eternal time.
Eternal time?
I'll give you a present.
Eternal time in the afterlife!
Happy birthday, Aoko-chan!
Thanks, everyone.
So where's your darling?
D-Darling?!
I mean Kaito-kun, of course!
D-Don't say things like that!
Why would that jerk be my "darling"?
That's what you say,
but you invited him here.
But knowing Kaito-kun, he'll probably
appear like magic to give you a good scare.
Yeah.
You are still coming, right, Kaito?
You promised.
So this is the Blue Birthday...
Well done, Snake.
I'd better tell the boss right away.
But why is the boss so interested in gems?
Surely the boss has enough money and
jewels already to last several lifetimes.
The Blue Birthday is one of the Big Jewels
that are scattered around the globe.
It may possess incredible power.
I-Incredible power?
If this is the gem that
the boss is looking for,
there's a legend about it that's been
passed down since ancient times.
"Hold up the stone of life under a
full moon and its tears will flow."
Th-The gem's tears?
Yes. And whoever drinks the tears
will be able to realize
humankind's final dream...
They will attain eternal life!
E-Eternal life?!
However, only one of the
Big Jewels holds that power,
and unfortunately, we don't
know which one it is yet.
That's why we have to
obtain them one by one.
But how can you tell whether the gem
possesses that wondrous power?
It's simple.
Just hold it up to the moon like this.
If it's the gem that has the power,
then a second gem within will
glow red under the moonlight.
The stone of life... Pandora!
Sorry, try again!
W-What's this?!
I-It's the wrong one?
I see...
So you hold it up to the moon...
K-Kid the Phantom Thief!
H-How did you live through that?!
Well, I was nervous for a second there.
But that bullet should've hit your heart!
It did hit me.
Or rather, what was in my breast pocket,
the Blue Birthday here.
Then this one is...
...a fake!
Making up a realistic replica
in case you need it
is one of the fundamentals
of being a thief.
D-Damn you!
Shoot him!
If you want it that badly,
I'll give it to you!
B-Blue Birthday...
Unfortunately, the Pandora gem
you guys are lookin' for isn't in there!
W-What?!
But it does come with an annoying bonus.
W-What's this noise?
Sorry, but I don't have any
more time for you guys tonight.
Boss! There's an army of
cops in front of the house!
W-What?!
Kid the Phantom Thief!
We've got your hideout surrounded!
Come out with your hands up!
A-A transmitter?!
Eternal life, my ass!
Don't make me laugh!
Pass this on to your puppetmaster!
Kid the Phantom Thief is gonna find
the Pandora gem before you do...
...and crush it into bits and pieces!
D-Damn that Kid...
Abandon this hideout! Use the secret
underground tunnel to escape!
Give it up, Kid the Phantom Thief!
I-It's deserted, Inspector.
Crap.
What's this?!
The Blue Birthday!
You did it! You got it back!
Blue Birthday...
Come to think of it, I have the feeling
it was somebody's birthday today...
Great job, Inspector!
Yeah! Our plan worked like a charm!
Let's celebrate out on the town!
Thanks for everything. I had a great time.
Although it would've been livelier
if Kaito-kun had shown up.
Forget about that guy!
He said he had an errand to run, anyway.
I see. Goodnight, Aoko.
See you tomorrow.
Goodnight!
Kaito, you idiot...
Shoot! It's almost midnight!
Aoko's birthday is gonna be over!
Young Master! Let's hurry!
It's too late. I won't make it in time.
I just had a good idea.
Kaito Kuroba
Hello?
Sorry, Aoko! I don't think I
can make it there by midnight!
Why?!
Why didn't you come?!
I was waiting for you the whole night!
But you... you...
You're scum!
I hate you, Kaito!
A-Are you really that mad...
Of course I'm mad!
You said you were gonna be the
life of the party with your magic!
You're a liar, Kaito!
I didn't lie!
Hey, Aoko, look out the window.
Look out the window?
What are you scheming, Kaito?
You wanna know?
I wanted to surprise you, so earlier, I...
Before you do a trick, you must never
explain what's going to happen.
Well, I can't tell you.
I mustn't explain what's going
to happen before I do the trick.
It's one of the three rules that the great Thirsty...
no, Thurs-Thurs-Thurs came up with.
What are you talking about, Kaito?
Never mind.
Uh-oh! Here we go, Aoko!
Three...
Two...
One!
Kaito...
Don't be surprised just yet.
Beautiful!
This night view is my present to you.
Happy Birthday, Aoko.
Thanks, Kaito.
Inspector Nakamori is Japan's finest!
Let's tie one on!
Well, until we meet again.
Let's meet again under a beautiful night sky.
See you next illusion!
Jii-chan is my reliable assistant.
His bar, the Blue Parrot,
is the target of harassment?
Then I'll have to give him a hand.
It's a billiard showdown
against a real hustler!
Who's gonna win in the end,
me or the hustler?
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Hustler vs. Magician
Hustler vs. Magician!
Step right this way!
Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion!