Black...
Me...
If you can't understand how I did it,
you'll have to be a good sport and
retire as a professional thief.
How did he take the jewel
without opening the case?
Midnight Crow (Part Two):
Clash! White or Black?!
M-Mom?!
Welcome home.
You're home?!
Yes. It was all over the news.
How this was one of Kid the
Phantom Thief's appointed nights.
So how did it go? What was the outcome?
W-Well, it was all right...
Oh. really?
Net news says "Another Thief
Steals Kid's Thunder."
There must be some mistake.
If you know, then don't ask!
Lying is the first step to becoming a thief.
I don't wanna be lectured
by the former Phantom Lady!
Hey, Mom, do you know about a guy
called Corbeau the Phantom Thief?
Apparently, Las Vegas is his stomping ground.
I know about him. Even over there,
people are wild about him.
It's like the second coming of Arsene Lupin.
For a moment, it felt like
he'd almost captured my heart.
It sounds like he learned his tricks
from the same teacher as Dad.
I don't know. When I first met your father,
he was already on his own.
Then what about some old guy Harry? He's called a "magic trick buster."
Oh, I hate that guy.
He always sends e-mails to magicians
who have big shows coming up.
Huh. What kind?
He exposes all of a magician's tricks for the
show in great detail and with illustrations.
Then he brags online,
"I saw through all of his tricks!
If you doubt me, ask the man himself!"
If he goes that far, the magician's
got no choice but to admit it.
Although, thanks to that,
those shows have been a great success,
with many people going to
"see through the tricks themselves."
What? If you're interested,
why don't you go to Las Vegas?
With your talent, I'm sure you'd
find yourself on a stage in no time.
It wouldn't be a bad idea to quit being a thief
and become a Vegas magician instead.
Quit being a thief and go to Las Vegas...
I became a phantom thief to capture
Dad's murderers and uncover the truth.
That was my original intent.
And that's how I still feel.
But is that all there is...
...for me?
It's gotta be the case...
Had to be a trick case...
It was a normal case.
No hidden trap doors, the kind that
are often used in magic tricks.
W-What are you talking about?
This morning, another advance notice
came in from Corbeau.
It said, "Tonight, I shall appear
to take the real Midnight Crow."
I'm Hakuba, a "white horse," so I don't want
a creepy blackbird to beat the man in white.
Oh. Since ancient times, crows have
been a sign of good omens in Japan.
The chest emblem of Samurai Blue is
Yatagarasu, the mythical raven.
And in Greek mythology, a crow
served the sun god, Apollo.
I want to see it, too.
The cheeky white pigeon who dares to
challenge a servant of the gods.
Kaito's no pigeon!
After all, his last name is Kuroba, right?
(P.S.: Kuroba literally means Black wings/feathers.)
So he'd be more like...
...a cockroach!
Hey, knock it off!
Crows remind me of my dad, who always takes
just a quick dip in the bath, like a crow.
Last night, he got out of the tub
with a weird mark on his rear-end.
A weird mark?
Yeah, a dark red mark that kind of
looked like one handcuff.
Handcuff?
Come to think of it, the inspector sat on...
What's that black stuff under your nose?
Are you imitating my dad?
Black paint on my fingers?
Wait a second.
I see! So that's it!
At tonight's magic show,
I'll settle it once and for all...
...Corbeau the Phantom Thief!
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Listen to the booming of the Kid calls
in the background.
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
Hours earlier, the Metro Police announced
they'd received an advance notice from Kid.
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid fans and Corbeau fans from
overseas are closing in en masse!
Corbeau! Corbeau!
Kid! Kid! Kid!
The showdown of the century
is at midnight tonight!
Kids today, rooting for criminals...
Well, it's winner-takes-all.
If we can trounce both phantom thieves,
the riffraff outside will quiet down, too.
But is this floor getting even colder?
Yeah. That's because I had a contractor
cover the walls and ceiling with refrigerants.
All right, I'll give the jewel a final check.
Don't switch out the real one this time.
I wouldn't use the same trick twice.
All right. Bring in the fan.
Fan?
We were foiled last time because many
crow feathers obstructed our vision.
If we can prevent that, we win.
So, where's the key?
Of course, just like last time.
I had a feeling...
Then the champagne, as I requested.
C-Champagne?!
To celebrate.
Even for a phantom thief, getting
through all this will be next to impossible.
Heaven be my witness to this victory.
Pretty cocky...
Inspector, one minute and
14 seconds to midnight.
Please focus.
I know!
Still, between this cold
and the strong wind...
...I feel like I'm gonna
freeze to death!
No, I'll pull through somehow. Although...
...it's not cold?
The cooling system has shut down?
You didn't check it before?!
I confirmed that the ventilation ducts
were free of crow feathers,
but I didn't examine the cooling system.
Don't panic.
If he can't use the crow feathers,
he can't touch us.
F-Feathers?!
I-It can't be...
Where are they coming from?
It's cold...
I see!
He painted one side of the crow feathers
the same color as the ceiling
and then used cold spray to stick them there.
As the room heated up, the ice melted and
the wind blew them off the ceiling.
When could he have set up that trick?
The contractor you hired last night to put up
the refrigerants was likely his assistant!
Then he must have also guessed
I would use a fan...
Anyway, turn the damn thing off!
Stop blowing the feathers around!
W-What about the jewel?!
Is it safe?
No!
He's traded it for a coin again!
This time, it was a total defeat.
Oh, I wouldn't call it a total defeat.
Because he didn't take the real thing.
Don't tell me you did it again...
You didn't think I'd use the
same trick twice, right?
That was your blind spot.
The real jewel is right here.
What?!
What the hell?! That's just a piece
of junk in the shape of the diamond!
I-Inspector!
Corbeau the Phantom Thief
is right outside the window!
What?!
That bastard!
After him! Don't let him get away!
A sucker trick.
You make it look like you fail at first,
but succeed in the end.
Or after disclosing the fake secret,
you show the audience that method actually
can't be used to explain the phenomenon.
It's one kind of a magician's performance.
While the inspector and the others
were looking at the feathers,
you colored the diamond with black
marker to blot out the shine.
With a fake diamond, the ink from
a marker wouldn't stick to it,
but with a real diamond, it would.
In other words, you took the real
diamond out of the case and replaced it
with simple ice, dyed with black ink
and carved into the diamond shape.
If you planted a gold coin
inside that black ice,
the IH heater hidden inside the pedestal
would melt the ice in an instant.
The proof of that is the
black ink left on the coin.
There was a black cloth in the case so no
one would notice the melted black liquid stain.
Black gloves were so no one would see ink
on your fingers from touching the black ice.
And this floor was kept at minus 10 degrees
so the black ice you put in the case
would retain its diamond shape.
That's right. All of it...
...was magic that could only be performed
if you and Corbeau were working together!
You're a magician, right?
If not, you wouldn't have been able to
deftly switch the real diamond with the fake.
Magicians who went on with their shows
even after you saw through their tricks
means you didn't make their secrets public.
It was like a demonstration to boost
interest in a colleague's show.
Well, I solved all of your tricks.
So as promised, you two
will have to fade away...
...but first, I want to ask you a question.
Just before, Corbeau the Phantom Thief flew
outside the window with a fake diamond.
What's his connection with Toichi Kuroba,
who was murdered during a show eight years ago?
He called himself a "fellow apprentice"...
...but does he really intend to
find the guys who killed Kuroba
and avenge him?
That question...
I would ask you the same thing.
I'm...
...not just about vengeance.
I wanna round up the guys who set
that trap for him and then move on!
The guys who murdered Toichi Kuroba,
the magician I respect the most!
I think he would be moved to tears
if he heard those words,
but we'll have to table this discussion.
It seems some rude patrons
have rushed the stage.
I haven't forgotten about last time,
Kid the Phantom Thief.
And I believe this is our first meeting,
Corbeau the Phantom Thief.
You just had to muddy things up by
wearing a similar costume.
What are you talking about?
Corbeau flew past the window
a little while ago.
C-Corbeau the Phantom Thief?!
That's right. I'm the original...
...Kid the Phantom Thief-kun.
Then the Corbeau who flew past
the window before...
You've met him once before.
For a magician, an assistant
is absolutely essential.
That voice... That tone...
That mouth...
D-Don't tell me...
Just like you, I can impersonate anyone.
Even the person who would
shock you most of all.
Y-You son of a...
What are you blabbering about?!
Just hand it over!
That jewel, inside of which may
be Pandora, the stone of life!
You'll have to drag me off the stage first.
Kill 'em!
What are you doing?!
I-I'm numb from the cold!
I can't aim!
The cooling system was turned back on?!
What?!
How can they move so easily?!
I see! The steel tray the champagne was on
is on top of this IH heater,
so it's only warm right here!
My card gun...
Rude patrons, I'm afraid
I must ask you to leave.
D-Dammit!
Hey, what's going on?!
Why is the fire alarm going off?!
Huh? There's no fire...
Shoes?
This isn't the jewel I'm looking for,
so you can have it back.
- Kid the Phantom Thief
Corbeau stole it.
so you can have it back.
- Kid the Phantom Thief
And Kid returned it.
It seems this match was a draw.
The point in common between a
phantom thief and a magician.
Do you know what it is?
Magicians make the impossible possible.
And phantom thieves carry off
thefts deemed impossible.
Both of them perform miracles.
Listen well.
"When a performer continues
to have strong conviction,
true showmanship lies within."
Hey! You still haven't...
Shoot.
In the end, who were those guys?
I'm back!
Dear Kaito
A letter? From Mom?
The truth is, I came back
because I wasn't sure about
letting you continue the dangerous life
of Kid the Phantom Thief,
but it seems you have conviction,
so for now, I'm giving up
and going back to Vegas.
P.S. You'll burn yourself if you stick
heating pads all over your body.
How does Mom know that?
Wait a second. The only one
who knew about that was...
I-It can't be...!
Yeah. It can't be, right?
Kid the Phantom Thief vs. Corbeau
Clash of Phantom Thieves Ends in a Draw
It says the showdown between phantom thieves
Kid and Corbeau was a draw!
Whose side were you on?
I'm on neither side!
I'm relieved he didn't lose.
H-Hakuba?!
What are you doing here?!
I invited him!
Oh. Considering Nakamori-san invited me
here, this isn't a bad establishment.
Right?!
Why'd she have to do that?
I invited them here
because I had a good idea!
What, pray tell?
The four of us can form a detective team
to catch Kid the Phantom Thief!
Hakuba-kun is a great detective, right?
Indeed.
And Akako-chan is beautiful,
so I think she can seduce Kid!
It would be child's play.
And I could get information
about Kid from my dad.
Inspector, has your cold come back?
Yeah...
'Cause I stuck it out in that damn cold,
but in the end, Kid got away.
Mark me well, Kid!
I'll arrest you next time for sure!
Are you an idiot?
You really think you can catch
Kid the Phantom Thief like that?!
No, I think it's a great idea.
Especially the part about you
being a member, Kuroba, you know?
Hakuba, you little...
So your job is to analyze
Kid's magic tricks, Kaito.
Forget it! Why would I join your club...
Kaito, why are you always on your high horse?
Just because you're pretty good
with magic tricks!
"Pretty good"?!
How dare you address
Kaito Kuroba-sama like that?!
After all, you haven't caught
Kid the Phantom Thief, have you?
What?!
If I got serious about it, that punk...
If you got serious about it, what?
If I got serious about it...
Yeah...
One day, I'll become a Kid the Phantom Thief
who goes beyond Kid the Phantom Thief!
What? I don't understand.
Dope! You don't need to understand.
Hey, Kaito, what did you mean by that?
Hey, Kaito!
Kaito.
At the very end, I want to
leave you with these words.
"If you can imagine it, you can create it."
The words of a great magician describing his
attitude when he comes up with a new trick.
This also applies to an entertainer
who aims to reach even higher heights.
And with your conviction,
if you aim for something,
I have faith that you'll reach it.
Yeah. I'll surpass you, Dad.
One day, for sure!
I presented you with a number of miraculous
illusions that embellished the town at night.
What did you think?
For now, the curtain comes down
on Kid the Phantom Thief's show.
But let's meet again, somewhere
under the pale moonlight.