Ladies and gentlemen!
I bring you marvelous illusions that
make this town sparkle at night!
Please enjoy the miracle that is going
to happen under the moonlight tonight!
Dammit! This isn't it, either.
Another one I gotta return.
I'm home, Dad.
Listen, Kaito.
Listen well.
Okay, okay, I'm all ears.
Magic tricks and magic spells(Mahō)
can both be considered "magic" in English,
but they're completely different.
Magic spells?
Do you know the difference?
Dad...
I'm sure you know there's
no such thing as real magic.
Mirror, mirror, on the wall,
who's the fairest of them all?
That would be you, Akako-sama.
Men all over the world are enamored of you.
Except for one person.
Oh? And who might that be?
It's...
K-Kid the Phantom Thief?!
Scarlet Seduction
Hey, Kaito, don't you want something sweet?
Something sweet?
Yeah. For instance...
Chocolate...
Aoko, have you forgotten?
Forgotten what?
Back when I had that cavity...
Look at that bulging cheek!
What a weird face!
That hurts!
You laughed! So you think I'm
gonna fall for it now, idiot?!
What are you talking about?
It's February 14th.
All girls bring chocolate to school today.
It's the day when we give it to boys.
And I'm sure nobody else
would give you any,
so here.
I'm only giving it to you
because I feel sorry for you.
Besides, there's a romantic
full moon out tonight.
And if it snows, we'll have
a white Valentine's day.
Uh, Kaito?
Huh? Keiko...
Kaito-kun ran off thataway with
a big grin plastered on his face.
You're gonna give that
chocolate to him, right?
You vixen!
W-Who would give that guy chocolate?!
You're lucky to have someone
to give it to, Aoko.
I told you I don't!
That girl is monopolizing all the other guys.
That girl?
Koizumi Akako, who just
started here a few days ago.
W-What is that?!
Akako-sama, give me chocolate, too!
Me too! Me too!
Don't push, boys.
I'll give you what you want.
She acts like she's a queen!
But Akako-chan really is beautiful.
Every single man in the world
is wrapped around my little finger.
Look at all the loot I got!
This one's from Misaki-chan.
This one's from Sakura-chan.
And this is from Ayano-chan.
Kaito!
Hey, Aoko, why is everyone
giving me chocolate today?
As I was saying, today is...
Come to think of it, I never
come to school on February 14th.
Last year, I had a terrible cold...
The year before, I was hospitalized with
a broken ankle after a skating accident...
Now I remember.
I always thought it was an unlucky day,
never knowing what I was missin' out on!
Akako-chan! Give me chocolate, too!
K-Kaito?!
Another one of Kaito's tricks!
Don't scare me!
It's no trick...
Who is this girl?!
If you want my chocolate, you'll
have to dump all the others.
That's right! You're
being rude to Akako-sama!
I see. Okay, then...
I don't need it!
He doesn't need my chocolate?
That can't be...
Wow! It's like snow!
Okay, everyone, take your seats.
Hey, you brought chocolate too, right?
Not for you, Kaito!
Of course you didn't!
Why...?
Kid the Phantom Thief is the
only one who can resist me...
Unless he's...
Hey, Aoko, have you seen my hankie?
No, I haven't seen your stupid hankie!
Then let me borrow you a sec!
What do you think you're doing?!
Sorry about that!
You're rotten to the core!
You'll see...
I'll expose your other identity.
Welcome home.
Is everything ready for the ceremony?
It is all set, Akako-sama.
I'll never get over how ugly you are.
Yes. And you are always
beautiful, Akako-sama.
You are the rightful heir to red magic. You
should become the empress of this world...
Silence! I'm tired of hearing you say that.
Now, I shall begin.
As you wish...
Dragon's whisker, mermaid's tear,
eyeball of a kappa...
...and also...
...I give you this handkerchief,
symbolizing Kaito Kuroba.
It won't be long now.
You shall soon be mine.
Blue Parrot
Young Master...
Do you have a cold?
I am cold.
I guess February 14th is an
unlucky day for me, after all.
Is that right?
Thanks to you,
it's been a sweet day for me!
For some reason, I've got
a feeling of foreboding.
I just hope I don't get injured.
Hey, Jii-chan.
Yes?
Do you believe in real magic?
"Real" magic does exist.
S-Seriously?!
Another term for it would be "sorcery."
Different kinds of sorcery
have color designations.
There are black magic, white magic,
blue magic, red magic...
Red magic?
Sorcerers are the mortal
enemies of us magicians.
We have been at odds with each other
since ancient times.
Some of them despise us, and
consider what we do "fake magic."
D-Despise us?!
That's scary!
Come to think of it, there's
a full moon tonight.
It's long been said that the full moon
is an omen of bad luck.
Young Master, please watch yourself.
Huh? That's strange.
Even though I sent out advance notice...
What the...?!
You fell for one of the
oldest tricks in the book!
K-Knockout gas?
Crap!
Find him! He can't have gone far!
You're the ones who fall for old tricks!
But this is no good... I'm sleepy...
Fool. Did you really
think you could get away?
C-Can't move...
Come to me, Kid the Phantom Thief.
Or rather, Kaito Kuroba!
W-Who are you?!
Now! Grab him!
Yes, sir!
I'll release you from your suffering.
So come to me...
Kid!
Jii-chan!
I had a bad feeling about tonight...
But don't worry. I'll take care of the rest.
It's not that, Jii-chan.
They're not our enemies tonight!
Come to me, Kid.
J-Jii-chan!
Y-Young Master!
Quickly... You're almost here...
I don't know who the hell you are,
but at least your night flight woke me up!
I'll save you from your torments.
I've been waiting for you,
my ostentatious rascal.
This time, you're going to be the victim.
You see, I'm going to steal your heart.
You'll catch cold in that outfit, young lady.
Are you supposed to be a gentleman now?
I know who you really are.
Don't tease an adult.
So, hand over that doll.
Now!
A-A magic circle!
This is... red magic?!
I thought this would finally be
the year I could give it to him...
God's mean to me.
Your body already belongs to me!
Now, become my servant!
Jeez, you sure are a spoiled young lady!
Laugh while you can.
Again, become my servant...
Hot! It's hot!
Kid. You want to escape
that agony, don't you?
Then eat this chocolate.
I'm sure it'll save you.
Chocolate?
This time you'll accept my red feelings.
Wait, she's...
Although after receiving it,
your heart will be...
...mine for eternity!
What's wrong, Kid?!
Eat it, quickly!
Kid!
Young lady, your magic
doesn't work on me anymore.
S-Snow?
Snow put out my magic circle!
White Valentine's Day!
It's the magic of nature.
You mean the trick up your sleeve, don't you?
You always use magic tricks to
escape when you're in a pinch.
But in the end, they're all a fraud.
They just fool people.
My magic is real! The effects really happen!
Yes. I agree with you.
You mean to escape?!
Certainly, the magic I perform fools people.
But everyone who sees it...
Silence!
They enjoy being fooled.
That's the difference between
your magic and mine.
Stealing people's hearts
through sorcery is just sad.
B-But that's how we witches operate.
What's so funny?!
You're the one who's telling lies here.
I'm not lying!
Oh, yes, you are. You're lying to yourself.
Young lady, you can't fool
Kid the Phantom Thief.
I can see the beautiful gem lying
deep within your frozen heart...
...Akako-san.
Kid...
Farewell, cute sorceress.
M-My lady...
I know. If a witch sheds a tear,
she'll lose her magic power forever.
Aoko!
Gotcha!
Jerk!
Hey, Aoko!
You still have that chocolate
from yesterday, right?
Give it here!
That only means something if
I give it out on Valentine's Day!
I ate it all!
Huh? This is the chocolate from...
Th-That's not the same one!
I'll take it!
Get back here!
No way!
Kaito Kuroba...
As a sorceress and magician, we share the
bond of knowing each other's secrets.
Next time, I will make you mine...
Sorry about that!
You're terrible!
Are you okay, Akako-chan?!
Help!
Well, let's meet again
under the falling snow.
See you next illusion.
I'm usually at the top of my game
when it comes to thieving and magic,
but once in a while,
things don't go as planned.
This town has had a clock tower
for many years now,
and my target is the
diamond-encrusted hand,
but somebody's seeing through
my every move?
It's definitely not old man Nakamori!
Who the hell are you?!
Black Star
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Black Star!
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion!