Ladies and gentlemen,
I bring you marvelous illusions that
make this town sparkle at night!
Please enjoy the miracle that happens
to a strong French black cat tonight.
Th-There he is! Him!
We spotted Kid the Phantom Thief!
All right! Choppers one, two, and three!
After him! Don't let him get away!
Now, how should I serve up those three crows?
What an amateur.
I heard you were Japan's
number one phantom thief...
...but looks are so deceiving.
I'm disappointed.
What?!
Why do you wear that illogical, garish,
old-fashioned outfit that
screams, "Find me!"?
Are you trying to imitate my country's
proud gentleman thief, Arsene Lupin?
H-He's French?!
Certainly, I'm impressed by how
you stole that jeweled dagger
from a heavily-fortified
art museum,
but I could have done it
easily in half the time.
Then this guy's a thief, too!
Chopper one, here! Chopper one, here!
We have visual confirmation of another
flying figure at one o'clock!
A flying figure?!
Th-That's right, Inspector!
There's a black silhouette holding on
to a paraglider next to Kid!
Hey, look! On the back of the paraglider...
A... a cat?!
My name is Chat Noir.
Sunday at 9:00 pm.
I'm looking forward to our showdown
at Hotel Ocean at that time.
À bientôt!
Hey! Wait!
Blue Parrot
Golden Eye (Part One):
Chat Noir's Challenge
Sheesh. What was that guy about?
Young Master, you said he identified
himself as Chat Noir, correct?
Search
Did you find anything?
Yes. Sorry for the wait.
"Chat Noir" is French for "black cat,"
and it's a famous phantom thief over there.
Black cat?
It seems he only targets cat's-eye stones
and ignores all other treasures.
Dressed all in black and
specializing in cat's-eyes...
Hence, the Black Cat.
Then what about this
Hotel Ocean he mentioned?
Just a moment. I'll look into it now.
W-What's this?!
French Black Cat Challenges
Kid the Phantom Thief!
At Hotel Ocean This Weekend...
The target is the "Golden Eye"
at the Marie Antoinette Exhibition
The bastard...
He's got some brass nads.
Showdown Between Japanese
and French Phantom Thieves!
Kid the Phantom Thief versus Black Cat!
Who will win?
"France's Phantom Thief, Chat Noir
declares war on Kid the Phantom Thief
with an advance notice."
"The target is the Golden Eye, which once
decorated Marie Antoinette's index finger.
Will Kid take this challenge and show up?"
Hey, gimme my tablet back, Aoko!
Look, my dad's mentioned in the article, too!
"The other night, Inspector Takamori brilliantly
recaptured the jewel-encrusted dagger,
while Kid the Phantom Thief
got away as fast as possible!"
It says his approval ratings have fallen!
That's fine. It wasn't the
jewel I was after, anyway.
But I wonder if that cowardly Kid will show?
It isn't the Big Jewel that I'm looking for,
but when someone throws down the
gauntlet, I gotta pick it up.
Well, even if he does appear,
I'm sure he'll get his butt kicked.
Hey, if you're Japanese,
you should be in Kid's corner.
Idiot! The police and my dad
are gonna be the winners!
So that's what you meant.
Maybe I should've scheduled my
vacation at a different time.
No.
Everything depends on how you look at it.
Since I'm here, I'll use
my home-court advantage.
Marie Antoinette Exhibition
Oh, so this is it?
A glowing white line within the amber color.
Just like a golden cat's eye.
Golden Eye is a perfect name for this ring.
Dan Mitsuishi-san!
Yes.
Antoinette had seven talismanic
accessories to ward off evil,
and this is the last one.
The last one?
That Chat Noir has stolen the
other six cat's-eyes.
And it's always right after a buyer is found.
Then you should keep it locked up in
the vault of your English mansion.
You didn't have to come all the way
to Japan and put it on display.
Actually...
And at a hotel you built yourself
in a remote area
between Tokyo and Chiba!
It's all a trap to lure Chat Noir.
That's right. You capture Chat Noir,
and you can take back the
six cat's-eyes he stole.
That's the point of this whole exhibit.
We had a hand in this hotel
when it was constructed.
Who the hell are you?
That's Alain Cartier-kun, the head of a
security company I summoned from France.
Especially since Japan's own thief
is also after the ring.
So what do you think about
conditions inside the hotel?
The security measures display an
amateurish streak in many respects,
but at least there are plenty of guards,
so I don't think there will be a problem.
So it was you, was it?
The foreigner who found fault with
the placement of my riot squad.
Yes. I don't trust anything
but our own security system.
Besides, Kid the Phantom Thief has made
fools out of you people for a long time now.
There is no way I could trust you.
Son of a bitch! Don't make
light of the Japanese police!
My people haven't let one
person inside this hotel...
Dad!
I brought your dinner.
Who are these young people?
My daughter, Aoko, and her classmate,
Kaito Kuroba-kun...
Well, that's fine.
Sloppy security on your part
falls within my calculations.
What?!
After all, think about it.
Unless the entrance to a rat cage is open,
the trap will catch nothing.
Observe...
...this thick, mounted window glass.
And the titanium alloy wires can
withstand ten tons of impact.
Of course, it isn't just in this room.
Except guest rooms, all windows from the
20th floor to the top floor here are that way.
And the designated time, tonight at 9:00...
Five minutes before that, all elevators
will stop and shut down at the top floor.
All stairs leading to the room
will be blocked off.
Do you understand what this means,
Monsieur Nakamori?
Escape after 9:00 pm is impossible.
The paraglider and hang glider
that Chat Noir and Kid
are fond of making their escapes with
will be utterly useless.
I see.
That's why even the glass in the observation
elevator we rode up in had wires in it.
So it's easy to get in, but scary to get out.
But all those wires ruined the view.
Don't worry!
I can replace that elevator
once this is over,
and you'll be able to see
the magnificent view again.
However...
...if you keep that all-important ring
in this cheap glass case...
Of course, they won't be
able to steal it so easily.
I think you believe the
ring should be protected by
the most reliable security
alarm device in the world.
I don't see that here!
Monsieur Nakamori, it's you.
You will be wearing Golden Eye on your finger
and waiting with it on top of this case.
If you keep a tight first until the
deadline is over, it will not be stolen.
Of course, I'll have you wear this gas mask
and a necktie pin fitted with a transmitter.
Hey, are you serious?
They could try to steal it
after putting you to sleep,
or even take you into their custody...
I-I see...
That's a brilliant plan!
Kid will be shocked!
He'd have to cut my finger off
to steal the ring!
What if he does cut it off?
D-Don't be stupid!
Kid would never be that barbaric...
But...
...it's not beyond him.
I mean Chat Noir, the phantom thief.
W-Who the hell are you?!
She's an investigator for an
American insurance company.
Ruby Jones-san.
Insurance company?
Yes. Mitsuishi-san made arrangements to
put out theft insurance on his jewel,
so when she found out that Kid
is a master of disguise...
She checked all of your faces too, huh?
R-Right...
Painstakingly...
That's the way we do things
in Texas, where I was raised.
Don't take it personally.
The reason I'm here
is that the cat's-eyes have been
cleverly stolen every time,
so the company is suspicious.
Suspicious that Mitsuishi-san
and Chat Noir are in cahoots.
Th-That's ridiculous...
If Golden Eye is stolen too, the
company will take a devastating hit.
So I was dispatched to
protect it with my life.
That's the job of the police...
If you don't take Chat Noir seriously,
you're in for serious trouble.
He's a villain who has no qualms
about hurting people's feelings.
Do you know...
...what became of Mrs. Mitsuishi when she
wore a hair ornament with a cat's-eye inside?
Chat Noir cut Mrs. Mitsuishi's hair
and absconded with the hair ornament.
He didn't hold back,
but hacked off hanks of hair.
My wife cried for one month
straight after that.
Th-Then he would hack off my finger...?
Then why don't we have you
put on a glove as well?
It will make you feel better, anyway.
Dammit...
Bastard. It's not his finger
on the chopping block...
Is this strategy even gonna work?
You're the one who called it
a brilliant plan, remember?
Annoying tie!
Suddenly springing this role on me...
Inspector...
This loop isn't attached to a shirt button,
so your tie is flopping around.
Oh, thanks, Kaito-kun.
Still, Mitsuishi, Cartier, and Ruby...
All of them with frivolous,
jewel-like names...
Hey!
You took my name, Aoko, from the
"blue" of a sapphire, right?
O-Oh, yeah, that's right...
Like me, Ruby said her name was
chosen from her birthstone.
And she said our birthdays are close,
so we should be friends.
But when we were talking about it,
Cartier-san butted in.
And he said, "Then was your
friend born in December?"
But you were born in June, Kaito.
When I asked Mitsuishi-san about it,
he looked doubtful.
He said, "Is the jewel 'chite'
any month's birthstone?"
I feel a little guilty for doing this,
but a duel is a duel and a win's a win.
All right! Perfect!
Now I just have to set it up.
Phone?
From another country?
Who is it?
Hello?
Hi. Long time no see. Are you still alive?
That sickly sweet and sarcastic tone...
Hakuba?!
You've made the papers in Paris.
It says France's Chat Noir is
going up against you in Japan.
Dumbass!
I ain't goin' up against anybody! It's Kid!
If you say so. I'll give you
the info that I got from here.
Chat Noir is a phantom thief who travels
the world, only aiming for cat's-eyes.
Until three years ago, he threw away or
returned the jewels that he stole, like you.
I'm tellin' you, it's not me!
But ever since he started targeting
Dan Mitsuishi's cat's-eyes,
they've disappeared for good.
There were seven accessories,
each with an embedded cat's-eye.
Dan Mitsuishi's father was a Marie Antoinette
fan, and they were part of his collection.
The accessories were sealed inside of a
vault for 30 years, but after the father died,
Dan dug them up.
We don't know yet if they
were really Marie's mementos,
but either way, those embedded
cat's-eyes are valuable jewels,
and the designs are close
to items from that period,
so even historians tend to
think that they're genuine.
And speaking of design, I read
a very interesting article.
Design?
The same thing seems to be happening here.
I obtained past issues of this newspaper.
Several copies were sold the day
after Chat Noir stole it.
You're really diligent.
Gathering information is one of the
fundamentals of being a detective.
So about this article,
it says Chat Noir boldly left a
replica of the accessory at the site
that looked exactly like the
Marie accessory he stole.
The only thing different was that
it didn't contain the cat's-eye,
but looked like the jewel had
been taken out of the replica.
Well, that's about as far as I've gotten.
Right now in Paris, it's 12:48:22.85.
In Japan, it's almost 9 pm.
Do your level best.
I don't want you to lose to anyone
until I catch you.
I told you, I'm not Kid!
Uh-oh. It's almost time
for the Paris Collection.
Talk to you later.
H-Hey!
Jeez. I gotta envy any high school student
who goes to Paris on vacation.
Jii-chan?
You said you wanted to see the
Paris Collection once, right?
Excuse me...
Have you seen Kaito?
Yeah. He told me to tell you he took off.
He left?!
He said to give this coin purse
to somebody named "Jii."
Jeez. What's with him?!
Kaito's the one who suggested
we bring Dad dinner!
Sorry, Aoko.
I can't afford to lose this contest.
All right, Monsieur Nakamori,
thank you in advance for your cooperation.
Again, don't let them know
you're wearing a transmitter.
R-Right...
Calm down.
It'll be okay. They won't take it.
I shouldn't have agreed to this...
W-What is this weird line of sight?
So, how are you going to attack,
Kid the Phantom Thief?
I'm already set.
A showdown between phantom
thieves of Japan and France.
In the end, who will claim victory?
Don't miss the climax.
The illusion must go on.
Young Master is busy with
his showdown with Chat Noir,
so I'm handling the preview this week.
The strategy over the jewel heats up,
but which of them will laugh last?
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Golden Eye (Part Two):
Kid Versus Chat Noir: Endgame!
Kid Versus Chat Noir: Endgame
Step right this way. Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion.
I have a little confidence
in my English. Yes, I do.