Ladies and gentlemen,
I hope you enjoy my battle of wits
with the pint-sized detective
and beautiful teleportation in Kinza!
Kaito!
Good morn-ing!
What does she want this
early in the morning?
Sheesh. You have to wake me up
early on a Sunday morning?
It's only 8:00!
After all, Chikage-san asked me to make
sure you get up early, even on days off,
and have a good breakfast.
Here, coffee.
Everyone's buzzing about
this topic this morning.
Mr.Jirokichi Suzuki of the Suzuki Group
has challenged Kid yet again.
A Message for Kid the Phantom Thief!
That old man still hasn't given up on Kid?
He's persistent, I'll give him that much.
What are you doing, Kaito?
Thanks for breakfast!
I just remembered something I gotta do!
What the heck?!
Even though I haven't finished eating yet...
A Message for Kid the Phantom Thief!
The Suzuki Group again...
Kid Versus Conan:
Teleportation Under the Moonlight!
And he demands to see you tonight...
Yeah, isn't that guy pushy?
Kinza, 4-chome. That's a pedestrian mall.
The treasure is the Purple Step.
There are 100-carat amethysts
on the vamps of mules.
Young Master, we don't have
enough time to prepare.
I think you should wait for
the next opportunity...
No, I'm gonna steal it tonight.
But I don't think you have to play along
with Suzuki-shi's unreasonable demand.
When it comes to just stealing it, whatever.
But since he sent out an official challenge,
Kid the Phantom Thief is all about making it
into an entertaining show, right?
Besides, if it involves stealing old man
Suzuki's jewels, then he'll definitely show up.
"He"?
You're a jerk, Kaito.
First, you run out on me this morning,
then you suddenly tell me to come to Kinza.
It's not like you have anything better to do.
And you said you wanted to go
on a sweets-eating tour, anyway.
Huh. You remembered.
Well, I guess I did!
Clear day, partly cloudy
Temperature: 18 degrees
Ouch!
What the heck?!
A trap set...
...in the street?
This is bliss!
Which one should I eat next?
The same setup in all four
areas of the crossing...
That was delicious!
Then shall we go to the next place?
Yeah!
Let's go to an anmitsu shop next.
Hey, Kaito, are you listening to me?
What's wrong?
I see...
Nothing.
Anmitsu is next, right?
Yeah. And after that, pancakes!
Man, this girl eats...
It's fun to go on an eating tour like this,
but it's kind of a pain to get around.
And she's as demanding as old man Suzuki.
It's be so much more convenient
if we could get there in an instant.
Message: Looking for Women Who Love Dogs
Getting there in an instant... That's great!
I know, right?
Hey, what are you trying to do?
Displaying that treasure in the street
with only four guards to protect it?
Then what would you do,
Inspector Nakamori?
W-Well, I'd put it in a high building,
where it'd be harder to steal...
That's it!
That was foolish!
He made us dance to his tune
and we didn't even know it!
Who knew that when having a duel against
that phantom thief with his white wing,
a high-rise venue was
actually to his advantage!
Time after time, he's gotten away
scot-free using the wing!
But surely you're not telling me that's
why you're displaying it on the ground...
That's exactly why! To pluck
that wing out of his grasp!
He's not a bird!
If he lands on the ground once, he won't
be able to fly off with the hang glider!
Kid the Phantom Thief doesn't
only soar through the air.
He creates miracles, too.
It looks like my audience has gathered.
There he is!
It's Kid! Kid the Phantom Thief has appeared!
I don't believe it! W-Where's Kid-sama?!
K-Kid the Phantom Thief!
Could you say a few words?
Sure, pass this on to
Senior Adviser Jirokichi Suzuki.
"This time was like a bolt from the blue.
I didn't have much time to prepare, so
please forgive my rudeness for not RSVPing."
Okay, now! Net him!
Hey!
What is this?!
Like I thought.
A-A net!
A gigantic net is closing off
the crossing at Kinza 4-chome!
Even if he tries to use a balloon, forget
about it with the helicopters overhead.
Of course, if he intends to escape
into the crowd, I won't stop him.
Whenever someone leaves the net,
they'll be checked thoroughly by my staff.
However this shakes out, I'm the winner!
U-Um, you're completely surrounded.
What are you going to do?
Well, my job is done,
so I thought I'd go home.
H-How?!
Via teleportation.
Te...
Teleportation?!
Well, let's meet again in less
than a minute from now...
...after I travel through time and space.
H-He really disappeared!
Ow!
H-Him...
Kid the Phantom Thief's mark!
W-Where'd it come from?
Kid's card fell to the ground!
It says something on the back.
"Two"?
"One."
N-No way...
It can't be!
I-It's Kid!
Kid the Phantom Thief
has suddenly appeared on the roof,
where our Nichiuri TV cameras are rolling!
U-Um...
Please pass this on to
Senior Adviser Jirokichi Suzuki.
"I did indeed accept the precious items
you offered to me,
but unfortunately,
one of them is a replica.
I'll return this one to you,
so if possible,
I'd be grateful if you could prepare
the real one for me here tomorrow night.
If I gave just the one to a dear lady friend,
I'm afraid it would displease her."
Well...
Tonight's Weather:
Clear sky, beautiful full moon
Come and see me tomorrow too, Detective.
So did you figure out how he did the trick?
Not yet.
In less than 20 seconds, he moved to
the roof of the adjacent building.
It's like a miracle, huh?
Putting it the other way around, he couldn't
have done it without those 20 or so seconds.
I'll solve the riddle of those 20 seconds
and expose his trick for sure this time.
You seem to be in high spirits.
You're like a kid who's about to unwrap
a present and knows there's a toy inside.
But be careful.
Your opponent is Kid the Phantom Thief,
the Magician Under the Moonlight.
When he appears at night
wearing that conspicuous white costume,
he's always cool, calm, and collected.
Yeah. I know.
He's got the net up already,
not letting anyone in...
He doesn't care what they think, huh?
Young Master, the roofs are sealed off, too.
It's okay. Keep standing by.
Good evening, everyone.
I'm Kid the Phantom Thief.
I regret to inform you that
tonight's magic show is canceled.
Under these lonely circumstances,
without an audience or TV cameras,
there's just no excitement.
W-What?!
Take care, everyone.
Oh, come on! Kid isn't coming?
I took off work early for this...
Let us in!
Let us in! Let us in!
It helps to have an upbeat crowd.
Let us in!
Let us in! Let us in!
Hey! Kid says he wants an audience!
Let us in!
Let's all go in there!
Now there'll have to be
TV cameras in there, too.
That old man's true objective
isn't protecting the treasure.
It's capturing me.
So I can't turn this down.
That guy...
Should I confirm it?
See just how sharp the great detective's
detecting skills are...
Hi, great detective.
Do you know Thurston's three principles?
Yeah.
Howard Thurston, a magician active
at the beginning of the 20th century.
Those three principles bear his name
and characterize him.
They're three taboos that you
mustn't do with magic, right?
That's right.
The first is, never reveal your tricks.
Although that goes without saying.
The second is, never explain what's
going to happen before the trick.
Without the element of surprise,
the audience won't be as amazed.
And the third one.
Never repeat the same trick twice.
If you do the trick just once,
it'll make a strong impression
and be remembered as a
miracle of the first order,
but if you do it again, instead
of enjoying the phenomenon,
the audience will concentrate on trying to
spot the trick, which increases the danger
of it being exposed.
I see.
Conversely, even if you break the taboos,
if nobody figures out the trick,
it's amazing magic?
You've got it.
There you are! Conan-kun!
Well, it seems the gallery has
filled in with a lively audience,
so the show will go on,
after all, in just a moment!
It's too dangerous with all those people
inside, so let's watch Kid-sama on TV.
Let's take one more look at Kid's
performance from last night.
Message: Looking for Women Who Love Dogs
H-Huh?
Message: Looking for Beloved Women
He disappeared in a puff of smoke, then
reappeared on the roof. It's a miracle!
But I wonder where Kid is
going to teleport tonight.
I know that one!
I know where Kid the Phantom Thief
is gonna teleport tonight!
Into one of those helicopters
flying up there!
Remember when Kid did that skywalking?
Actually, Kid had a partner that piloted...
Too bad.
Well, I'll show it to you one more time.
If you can see through it, do it.
Damn you, Kid!
This is the night...
Look closely. He's got
a propeller on his butt!
It's just a dummy.
Then...
...he's somewhere in this crowd.
K-Kid the Phantom Thief!
Sorry I kept you waiting.
And now, like last night,
watch closely as I travel
through time and space.
last night's
All right! Get started!
Roger!
Then...
...my first shot!
Beloved Women
Three. Two. One!
Come out!
Unfortunately, you're not getting any
reward for tonight's magic show...
Message
...Magician Under the Moonlight.
Drop the weight! Now!
Your teleportation trick is extremely simple.
It's based on the pulley principle,
which is used for wells.
First, your partner played
the part of TV station staff.
After that, if you quickly
retrieve the pulley,
it looks like you've
pulled off teleportation.
Well, the real TV staff members had their
hands full covering the scene on the street.
If one of them slipped away,
I'm sure nobody would have noticed.
The problem was
Tokyo
Tonight's weather: Clear
moving two people up and down
without the crowd noticing.
Even if your friend going down
was hidden by a banner,
you had to shoot off cards
to distract the crowd,
so you couldn't go up from behind the banner.
And that's why we had the
news on the LED sign.
If you ascended with the moving characters,
you could deceive the crowd.
I see.
So your deduction that I heard
from the bugging device
was a fake so I'd lower my guard.
You caught on to my contrivance, huh?
Yeah. It was the contents of
the news that clued me in.
The news being displayed just before you
appeared on the building's roof last night,
was "looking for beloved women."
Beloved
Beloved by whom? It doesn't
make sense, you know?
That's how I caught on to your trick.
That wasn't "beloved women" before,
Who Love Dogs
but "women who love dogs."
Temperature 22 degrees, Humidity 58%
A refreshing day in store
And one more thing.
I finally figured out why you appear
wearing that conspicuous white outfit.
It's not to appear fearless or anything.
It's because it's easy to hide.
If something white disappears before your eyes,
the eyes will follow something white.
It was an easy choice for someone who can
change from white to black garb as fast as you.
Yeah. And if something white suddenly
appears from the dark at the same time...
...it's mysterious, right?
H-Hey! Isn't that Kid?
Tomorrow's Weather  Fine
Temperature: 22 degrees
Wow! He's standing on the side of a building!
Fair
Temperature: 22 degrees, Humidity 58%
A refreshing day in store
Well, give it up.
If you keep going to the top,
you may be saved,
but then your friend who descends to the
street will be caught by the police.
If you don't, you're out.
Then I'll stay in the middle.
M-Middle?
Reach out!
Dammit!
Awesome!
Take me, too!
Son of a...
Tomorrow's Weather
These aren't the jewels I'm looking for,
so you can have the shoes back.
- Kid the Phantom Thief
Sorry I put you through all that, Jii-chan!
What are you talking about?!
I would put my life on the line
to help you, Young Master!
Although I'd rather you
not do a loop-the-loop.
Did I go too far in challenging
Thurston's three principles?
But his face...
Well, let's call tonight's show a success.
Detectives are destined to be
the rivals of phantom thieves.
At the same time,
they're thrilling audience members.
Well, see you next illusion.
In the next episode, a magician
from England appears.
There you go again,
hijacking my preview!
Do you have that much free time?
Of course not!
You've got plans, anyway.
I'm just trying to help out,
so don't complain!
I didn't ask you to.
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412: Red Tear!
Red Tear
Step right this way. Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion.
If you've got complaints,
you should come over here!
All right, I will!
But a bigger stage suits me more,
like the silver screen!