Ladies and gentlemen,
when I have a miraculous battle over a crow
with Black Phantom Thief,
an unexpected rival, what will happen?
Kaito...
Finally, I'll just say this to you once more.
Remember it well.
When you come in contact with the audience,
it's the scene of a duel.
Never be arrogant. Never underestimate them.
See into their minds.
Give undivided concentration
to your fingertips.
This is your last advice, huh?
Use every trick you know.
That's just like Dad.
On top of that, never lose
your smile or dignity.
And at all times...
...remember your poker face.
Midnight Crow (Part One):
The Name is Corbeau the Phantom Thief!
Disappointing...
I came prepared with two
more back-up plans...
How anticlimactic.
Oh, well, Hakuba took a leave
of absence to travel abroad.
And with Inspector Nakamori
in bed with a bad cold,
this is a piece of cake.
Well, I guess I'll take it.
The world's biggest black diamond,
the Midnight Crow.
I should be able to pick this lock
in less than a minute...
H-Huh?
My hands aren't moving the way I want.
And it's really cold in here.
The old man was right.
Yes.
Kid the Phantom Thief...
...has a weakness to cold!
Hakuba and Inspector?! How?!
Get him, everyone!
Wait!
You let down your guard because you
thought I was home sick in bed!
Never underestimate me!
My cop nature kicked that cold
to the curb after a day!
Your plan worked.
But I only told Aoko I had a cold...
How did Kid know?
We caught Kid!
All right! Good work!
Wrong! I'm not Kid!
You don't know when to give up...
...Kid the Phantom Thief!
Th-That face...
Me?
Y-You're Oshima from Squad C!
K-Kid put a mask of you on my face...
...a-and escaped out the ceiling...
Son of...
After him, everyone!
U-Um, what should I do about these handcuffs?
Who cares?! Figure something out yourself!
O-Okay...
I will.
My double disguise worked like a charm!
Putting one of the investigators to sleep
just in case was the right move.
But it looks like I'll have to reschedule
to get another shot at that jewel.
Hakuba's watching it like a hawk.
And what the inspector said bothers me.
The old man was right.
What old man?
Did the plan go smoothly for the
inspector tonight because of him?
You there!
Are you...
...an idiot?
Excuse me?
Staying in Kid's outfit in these circumstances
could be easily misconstrued.
R-Right...
Please change into something else right now!
G-Got it!
Kaito, did you see the news on the net?!
It says "Complete Defeat
for Kid the Phantom Thief"!
That's hilarious!
Cheers and jeers!
Who toasts with ginger ale?
Huh? Why do you have band-aids
all over your face?
It's nothing!
The price I paid for using strong adhesive
on that second mask so it wouldn't come off!
That aside, Jii-chan, did you hear?
Apparently, there's an old man
giving advice to the police.
Huh...
I've heard that Senior Adviser Suzuki
doesn't have anything to do with this jewel.
No, not that rich old man...
Are you talking about Harry Nezu-san?
He's a famous magic trick buster.
It says the police drove Kid off this time
thanks to Nezu-san's advice.
Magic trick buster?!
Yeah. His nickname's "the Hedgehog."
He made his name debunking
fraudulent spirit mediums.
It seems magicians all over the world regularly
challenge him, but are soon "busted."
This says he's coming to Japan today.
Then maybe the old man's going
to meet Inspector Nakamori?
Yeah.
Then this is a gift for the inspector.
For what?
To celebrate driving Kid away.
He's gonna meet somebody famous, so you
want him to have a little style, right?
Mr. Hari!
Are you in Japan to help
arrest Kid the Phantom Thief?
Kid the Phantom Thief...
The brat in the white suit?
Silly.
Brat? I've been on his trail for 18 years...
He looks like a youngster to me.
Even his name is "Kid."
That's a fancy necktie pin.
It was...
...a present from my daughter's friend, to
celebrate us driving away Kid the other night.
It seems your daughter has a good friend.
Although I'd say he has bad taste.
So the advance notice was for tonight?
I was afraid he'd realized there's a
camera and mic planted in the tie pin.
Yes, he sent it to the police
department two days ago,
saying he was going to try again
tonight at midnight.
And does he know you're going to change
the exhibition room of the jewel?
Yes. I went out of my way to
announce it on TV last week.
I don't think he knows
the exact room, though...
That's good.
Now we just have to wait for him
to show up, as brazen as usual.
Inside the mousetrap I've prepared...
M-Minus 10 degrees Celsius!
Is this floor that cold?
Yes. That was my instruction.
Will we really be able
to catch him like this?
I'm sure it'll work for the brat in white.
He got away last time
because it wasn't cold enough.
Deceiving the eyes with skilled fingers
is what a magician does.
A phantom thief who uses magic becomes a
babe in the woods if he can't use those fingers.
Figures they would go with that.
B-But it's also hard for us cops
to catch Kid in this cold...
That's right. Your bodies will be too
sluggish from the cold to catch me.
But as for me,
I'll stay toasty-warm!
And then...
...I'll just sneak into the building before
midnight, impersonate that old man...
Kid? What are you saying?
I couldn't care less
about that brat in white.
But didn't we make it this cold
in order to catch Kid...?
My prey isn't the one in white...
...but the one in black.
The one in black?!
This morning, my father, the commissioner,
received another advance notice.
"Tonight at midnight, please forgive
my rudeness when I take my black jewel.
Corbeau the Phantom Thief"
P-Phantom Thief?!
Corbeau?!
"Corbeau" means crow in French.
That's why he refers to the
Midnight Crow as "his."
And crows do like shiny objects.
I received the same missive last week,
which is why I've come
to my father's homeland.
B-But who is this Corbeau?
A phantom thief who's been
active in Las Vegas lately.
Scattering countless crow feathers
at the scene of the crime is his M.O.
But the surprising thing
is that he looks just like...
Just like...?!
Like what?!
A black feather?
Black...
Me...
Who are you supposed to be?
Considering the outfit, my guess is...
...you're a fan of mine?
Th-That's my...
That's my line...
...Corbeau the Phantom Thief.
He's changing his voice, but it feels like
I've heard it before somewhere...
Oh, I remember.
Come to think of it, I have a feeling
I've seen you once before.
Once before?
Was it then?
You've devoted yourself to thieving in Japan
while cosplaying in an outfit like my own.
I believe your name is...
...Child the Robber.
It's Kid the Phantom Thief!
And you've only just started being active!
You're the one who's copying me!
I suffered from an illness
for quite some time.
After healing up, I was just
waiting for the right moment.
Waiting to take revenge for my
fellow apprentice, Toichi Kuroba,
who was murdered eight years ago
at a magic show.
What?!
I repurposed this stage outfit
he left behind.
It's different from your aping the style.
Aside from that, it seems you've got
portable heating pads stuck all over your body,
so the fact that you're about to dive
into a trap prepared by that hedgehog
tells me you're a thoughtless lightweight.
Shall we make a wager?
Tonight I intend to melt into the darkness,
hiding all traces of myself,
and then make that black jewel, the Midnight
Crow, my own, without even touching it.
Then, if you can't understand how I did it,
you'll have to be a good sport and
retire as a professional thief.
There is no need for two ghosts
of Toichi Kuroba.
S-Sounds like fun!
I accept your challenge!
On the other hand, if I see through
your trick, then you retire!
Of course.
Two phantom thieves...
No problem, no matter how many there are.
We just have to take the jewel
from the one who steals it.
The Stone of Life... Pandora!
Understood...
What?! Kid's not coming?!
You're sure you got that mail?
Yes. It just came to the department.
It said, "Tonight, I'll just be watching."
It was rerouted through an overseas server,
so we couldn't pinpoint the original sender,
but the mail had Kid's usual trademark,
so we believe it really came from him.
It seems he's curious about
Corbeau the Phantom Thief, too.
Corbeau, Corvette, whatever, he's
thrown cold water on the festivities.
Thanks to him, we've lost
the chance to catch Kid...
Huh?
It isn't hot?
Hey! There's no need to touch that pedestal.
P-Pedestal?
I made it in my country and
had it brought here to Japan.
It's my secret weapon against Corbeau.
At a glance, it looks like
an ordinary pedestal.
But when I release the safety like this,
if there are any objects nearby,
sharp blades spring out...
...and it rotates at a high speed
that can rip anything to pieces.
Of course, the case is
made of ultra-dense glass.
And the black fabric
the jewel lies upon is engineered
to be stab-proof.
Let's see.
Beautiful!
It certainly is the genuine black
diamond, the Midnight Crow.
That case has a weird contraption,
but it's not locked...?
Inspector Nakamori, the key...
...is you.
Me?
You're going to wear a gas mask
and sit atop this case,
holding on to the handles.
There. That's good.
As long as you hold on to those handles,
the case can't be opened.
Inspector Nakamori! It's almost time!
R-Right!
All right, Corbeau the Phantom Thief,
you night bird!
Appear from anywhere you see fit.
You should be the one sitting on the case!
A feather?
F-From the ceiling vent!
Crow feathers...
Corbeau is here!
Inspector! Hang on tight!
I'll die before I let go!
I-It stopped!
W-What about the jewel?!
It's fine. I held on the whole time...
It's gone?!
A coin in its place...
A word etched into it... Corbeau!
I-It can't be!
How could he do it without opening the case?!
That really is magic...
Is this the time to be impressed?!
There are words on the bottom, too.
"Next time I'll be back
to take the real thing."
Th-The real thing?!
Oh, it's a trick I often pull
in my confrontations with him.
I had a strange foreboding, you see.
So I switched it out with a fake
right before the appointed time.
Although it seems he saw through
my bait-and-switch.
Still, even if it was a fake,
he really did steal the jewel.
And if we don't know how he did it,
maybe next time, too...
The main point is that our field of vision
was obscured by those crow feathers.
Being distracted by that was our downfall.
Next time, we can't afford to neglect
the ventilation shafts.
R-Right...
Hey! Get this coin over to the crime lab!
Yes, sir!
Although I'm sure he won't have
left his fingerprints on it.
I see.
He melted into the darkness,
erasing all traces of himself,
and stole the jewel without touching it.
Not bad, Corbeau the Phantom Thief.
Although this is no time to be impressed.
How did he take the jewel
without opening the case?
If it was magic, there would've been some
device in the case, covered by the black cloth.
But I'm also curious about his identity,
since he called Dad his "fellow apprentice".
And Jii-chan said he can't recall
anyone referring to Dad by that.
Well, guess I'll head home
and search the internet.
Huh? The lights are on?
D-Don't tell me...
Oh, Kaito! Welcome home!
M-Mom?!
An unexpected person showed up,
but this is no time to be shocked.
I'm gonna settle my showdown
with Corbeau the Phantom Thief.
The illusion must go on.
All right, I think I'll relax
and do this final preview alone.
Still, Corbeau the Phantom Thief...
How the heck did he do that trick?
The fact that he picked a fight with me
shows just how strong he is.
But I can't be defeated here
and have a good reason for it!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Midnight Crow (Part Two):
Clash! White or Black?!
The last episode! "Midnight Crow (Part Two):
Clash! White or Black?!"
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
Don't miss the last illusion!