Ladies and gentlemen!
I bring you marvelous illusions that
make this town sparkle at night!
Please enjoy the miracle that is going
to happen under the moonlight tonight!
The culprit...
...is you!
I-I have an alibi!
You claim that when the crime occurred,
three days ago at 1:00 pm,
you were on Mt. Takao.
You have a souvenir photograph with a
clock in the background to back it up.
However, this photo was
taken at 3:44:58.22 pm.
The clock had been messed with.
The length of the shadows
indicates the correct time.
Everything has come to light.
The famous detective is just back from London,
but has already solved a case!
There it is! His famous line:
"Everything has come to light."
Should Kid the Phantom Thief watch his back?!
"Everything has come to light," my ass!
He won't stop with that arrogant catchphrase!
I bet you're looking forward to it.
The showdown between him and Kid!
Idiot!
I'm the one who's gonna
have a showdown with Kid!
I-Inspector! There's a new
advance notice from Kid!
What?!
A Great Detective Comes to Light
The Great Pecasso Exhibition
So that's Adam's Smile...
They sure are handling it with care.
Little do they know that
I'm gonna steal it tonight.
Anyway, Inspector Nakamori must be
responsible for this tight security.
But not even Buddha realizes
that I'm observing them
from way over here!
The culprit is you!
Everything has come to light.
A-Aoko...
What, you don't know that famous tagline?
I'm talking about the famous detective
who just got back from London.
What the hell do I care about that crap?
Paris, London, or wherever,
I'm not gonna humor you playing detective.
Excuse me? You're the one
who invited me here, Kaito!
Only because the expression on your face
was practically begging me to invite you!
I didn't make that kind of face!
What's your problem, Kai-troll?
Wait a sec!
So is this why you said the rink's condition
was bad today and clung to the wall?
N-No...
Say "Aoko-sama, please,"
and I'll give you a hand.
I-I'm never gonna beg you like that!
Aoko-sama...
You should've said it sooner.
Dammit...
Jii-chan's info better be on the money!
While searching for information on
the Big Jewels, as you requested,
I came across something interesting.
This is a painting.
Young Master, look at this.
Adam's Smile is definitely a
masterpiece of abstract art.
But it's valued at 400 million,
which doesn't quite add up.
What's that?
The prevailing view is that Pecasso used
a special kind of paint for this part,
but there's actually more to it than that.
Listen up!
Kid the Phantom Thief said he'd be here
at 10:00 pm on the dot!
All right, synchronize your watches.
Let's see, right now, it is...
2015 CE.
February 3rd, Tuesday,
8:50:16.05 pm.
My watch is never off more
than 0.001 seconds in a year.
For your information.
Y-You're the guy that just
got back from London...
I'm Hakuba Saguru.
Nice to meet you.
Get lost! This is no place for amateurs.
Shoo! Shoo!
Come now, Nakamori-kun.
Don't be such a hard-ass.
C-Commissioner Hakuba!
That's my son. Unfortunately, all this
media adulation has gone to his head.
I'm hoping you'll show him up here so he
learns just how tough a crime scene can be.
In that case, leave it to me, Nakamori Ginzo!
There's my great inspector!
If you've got any questions,
feel free to ask me.
Then I will.
What is Kid the Phantom Thief's gender?
M-Male, I think...
How old is he?
When was he born?
What's his blood type?
What type of women does he like?
What kind of cologne does he wear?
Favorite cologne?
Height?
How tall is he?
Weight?
How much does he weigh?
Body type?
What's his body type?
Hairstyle?
What's his hairstyle? His hobbies?
His favorite baseball team?!
Hobbies?
Favorite baseball team?
I-I dunno...
Excuse me.
The snow's really comin' down.
I hate workin' when it's freezing like this.
Then why not take a nap?
Sweet dreams!
The place is swarming with cops...
You!
I-Inspector!
Get where you're supposed to be!
Y-Yes, sir!
Slacker!
Th-That was close...
A police badge?
Th-That's...
I see.
What the hell?! What is this?!
I took the painting.
- Kid the Phantom Thief
Crap!
He must still be in the vicinity!
Find him!
I took the painting.
- Kid the Phantom Thief
See you.
Well, should I really take Adam's Smile now?
Still, I'm surprised they fell
for such a simple trick.
I know.
It was an extremely elementary trick.
When something isn't where
it's supposed to be,
people assume that it's disappeared.
It's a sensory trick.
Not even magic shows use them these days.
You're one minute, 13.02 seconds late,
Kid the Phantom Thief.
Well, I got held up by the snow.
It seems you weren't so quick on
the uptake with this trick, huh?
Oh, that's right. I cut your rope.
W-What?!
After the magic show, did you
intend to perform a circus act?
Also,
I set free the ad balloon
that was on the roof.
Is that right?
You've got no escape route now.
Kid the Phantom Thief,
true identity unknown,
it's time for everything
about you to come to light.
Secrets are everything to a magician.
And I won't let mine come
to light that easily.
A hang glider...
Just like Batman...
Batman is a comic book hero.
He doesn't really exist.
Excuse me.
Fool...
It's a north by northwest wind tonight,
seven on the wind scale.
Not conducive to night flights...
Damn that Kid!
K-Kid?!
Halt!
Yikes!
The skating rink!
Hold it right there!
Son of a...
H-He split into two!
W-Which is...?
On the right!
There's no way Kid would
be terrible at skating!
Get him!
This saves me, but I'm not
really happy about it.
You're under arrest!
Huh? A balloon?!
"Kid the Phantom Thief
is bad at ice skating."
What happened to your
great detective fresh from London?!
In the end, Kid got away!
Kid the Phantom Thief Steals Adam's Smile!
Put that away already!
February 4th, 2015.
At 9:32.41,
I transfered here from
a high school in London.
Th-That way of speaking...
Hakuba Saguru
I'm Hakuba Saguru.
Everything will come to light.
Hakuba Saguru
He's so cool!
Seriously?
Blue Parrot
Wow! Hidden treasure!
Not a winner.
That's unfortunate, but don't look
so disappointed, Young Master.
I shouldn't forget my poker face, right?
So is everything ready for
the next one, Jii-chan?
Yes, right here.
Kid will be on TV tonight!
Hey, did you hear? Kid the Phantom Thief
will be live on TV tonight.
That's awesome! I've gotta record it!
Kid the Phantom Thief's
scene of the crime on live TV
Broadcasting live, huh?
I get more good luck as
a robber than I deserve.
Morning, Kaito!
Hey, listen to this!
Recently, I entered a contest to try to win
Around the World concert tickets!
And what do you think happened?
Y-You won, I guess?
That's right!
A pair of tickets!
Your face totally gives it away, dingbat!
Excuse me?! Talk to me like that,
and I won't invite you!
It seems you're in a spot
of trouble, my lady.
H-Hakuba-kun...
I'm 180 centimeters tall.
I weigh 65 kilograms.
I was born on August 29th, 1997.
I'm a Virgo. And if you don't
mind that I'm blood type A,
I would like to go with you.
A man who thoughtlessly refuses an
offer from a lady isn't worthy of you.
B-But...
You couldn't even catch Kid!
A mediocre detective and a
mediocre inspector's daughter!
You deserve each other!
What's that supposed to mean?!
Apparently, he's partial to Kid.
Then let's do this. If I capture Kid tonight,
you invite me.
That's a good idea.
If you catch Kid, let's go
to the concert together.
Somebody like you is gonna catch the
unbeatable Kid the Phantom Thief?
Unlike you, Kid is a genius.
It won't be an easy job.
And if I do happen to lose,
I'll leave escorting Aoko-kun to you.
Sounds like fun!
I don't wanna go to the concert,
but you've got a deal!
Look at all the guards here!
Inspector, this is it, right?
The goddess statue that Kid
announced he's going to steal.
Steal it?
There's no way he can!
Not even a rat could sneak
in here, let alone Kid!
Huh? A rat...
Idiots! Catch that vermin!
Your dad is in fine form, as usual.
Y-Yeah...
And now, let's interview the detective who's
been in the spotlight lately, Hakuba-kun.
Um, he's...
What are you doing, Hakuba-kun?
Just being conscientious.
I've kind of got a personal stake
in tonight's showdown.
Why, you... What an arrogant jackass.
Watch me, you third-rate detective.
No way am I letting you go
on a date with Aoko!
I'll have the last laugh!
Nothing in the air!
Nothing on the roof!
Nothing underground!
I guess even Kid can get scared off!
Inspector.
How many guards are posted underground?
Nobody's posted there.
The basement's protected
by a myriad of sensors.
Not even Kid is stupid enough
to try and get in that way.
Kid the Phantom Thief is here!
This is impressive.
But I've got this.
Right there!
Bet they never figured I'd come up
through the basement.
Four minutes left!
Will Kid really show up?
Hey, Aoko...
Who are you rooting for?
Hakuba-kun? Or Kid?
H-Hakuba-kun, of course!
Are you sure? If he wins, you can't
go to the concert with Kaito-kun.
I-I don't need to go with him!
A mediocre detective and a mediocre
inspector's daughter! You deserve each other!
Why did he have to say that?
That idiot...
I made it!
The rest is just putting on
the finishing touch.
This is as far as you get,
Kid the Phantom Thief.
W-What?!
And now,
why don't we lower the
curtain on this circus?
S-Sleeping gas?!
I see. The circus finale is a smoke screen.
In 17.58 seconds, this whole
room will be filled with gas.
Give it up.
You lose.
I don't know about that!
Oh, no!
Just ten seconds away!
I-Inspector!
There's an interloper in the basement!
Nine!
Eight!
Seven!
He's 25 centimeters away from the mask,
I'm 20 centimeters away,
and we're moving at the same speed!
It's mine!
Six!
Five!
Four!
Three!
What's wrong, Kid? Aren't you coming?
Two!
Kid!
One!
Zero!
Inspector, I caught Kid the Phantom Thief.
I don't believe it!
Well done, Hakuba-kun!
Hakuba-kun, how did it feel to capture Kid?
Actually, it was a cinch.
What's that balloon?
Oh, it's just... time for me
to make my getaway.
I-Inspector! Kid isn't in the basement!
It's Detective Hakuba!
According to my calculations, I definitely
should've reached it before him.
But he...
Mine!
Then you're...
...Kid the Phantom Thief!
K-Kid the Phantom Thief is impressive...
I-It's Kid!
Kid the Phantom Thief has appeared at last!
Damn you, Kid!
Whoa!
I wouldn't move if I were you, Inspector.
That's unusually menacing, coming from you.
Tonight's job is a little personal...
Personal? How?
Well, I'll be seeing you!
Just being conscientious.
That son of a...
If this isn't what I'm looking for,
then there's no point.
Now!
Inspector Nakamori Protects
the Goddess Statue!
You need to keep it stabilized.
I know!
Would you like more painkillers?
No, thank you.
All traces of the gas will be out of my body
in three hours, 31 minutes, and 49 seconds.
Oh.
I'll get you for this.
How boring...
Tonight's performance featured a thief
and a detective crossing swords.
Did you enjoy it?
Well, see you next illusion!
The word "magician" has two meanings.
The first is an illusionist,
that is, an entertainer who performs tricks.
And the second is a wizard.
Our class has a new student, Akako Koizumi.
She's totally beautiful,
but a little weird.
This isn't Medieval Europe,
but is she really a witch?!
Scarlet Seduction
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Scarlet Seduction!
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion!