Ladies and gentlemen!
I bring you marvelous illusions
that will make the night sparkle!
Tonight's performance features the secret
of the Phantom Lady, unknown even to me!
Hey, Mom, gimme a break already!
How many hours have you been
yammering away now?!
Huh? I haven't even gotten through half
the subjects I want to talk about.
Are you serious?!
But, Kaito...
Have you been listening to me?
O-Of course!
Are you sure?
Because it's something that's very important.
The story of how your
father and I fell in love.
It's just a sappy story...
Did you say something?
No, nothing!
Then I'll take it from the top once more.
Once was enough!
It all started 18 years ago...
A Saturday night when the
full moon was bright...
I'll never forget that kiss.
It was so thrilling and romantic...
Crap!
That time already?!
Mom, I gotta go!
Where are you going at this hour?
I told you!
This is one of my
Kid the Phantom Thief nights!
Oh, Darling...
Long time no see.
Enter: The Phantom Lady
Look!
Kid the Phantom Thief!
This is Nakamori!
Kid the Phantom Thief has stolen the
jewel and escaped into the crowd!
But, Inspector, Kid is using a hang glider...
That's his usual decoy!
Don't let anybody out of the museum
until they've had a full body check!
Why can't I leave?!
If you don't hurry, Kid's gonna get away!
W-Wait a second!
I'm Aoko Nakamori!
I just came to drop off my
dad's brown bag! Can't I go home?!
B-Brown bag?
That's Inspector Nakamori's daughter.
Didn't you know that?
P-Pardon me!
That's okay. Keep up the good work!
Good luck!
Sorry, Aoko! I borrowed your face again!
Well, looks like it's not the
jewel I'm really after...
Guess I'll send this one back
to Inspector Nakamori, too.
Still, this is curious...
A sticker with a message was
on the bottom of the jewel...
Kid the Phantom Thief, it's my turn next.
Saturday night, under the full moon,
I shall seize the jewel upon the
head of the untarnished nail
and thus repay the debt I owe you
from 18 years ago.
What the hell does it mean?
"The head of the untarnished nail"...
I wasn't even born 18 years ago.
Well, I don't know, but they
probably have the wrong guy.
All right. This'll do it.
Nakamori Ginzo-dono
Metro Police Dept., Second Investigation Division
He makes his way through tight security
as if performing a magic trick.
The Magician Under the Moonlight...
Kid the Phantom Thief.
How does he do it?
There is a person who can walk right through
that tight net without being checked.
I'm talking about...
...Aoko Nakamori.
The world's greatest thief and this girl seem
to have a close relationship, don't you think?
But, President Gouzu,
she's the daughter of Inspector Nakamori
from the Second Investigation Division.
Kid probably just disguised himself
as her because it was convenient...
This would make the fifth such occasion.
Th-Then Kid and the daughter of the inspector
in charge of catching him are...
No way...
Yes, that is the way.
Magicians use the psychology of disbelief
to pull pigeons out of impossible places,
much to our bafflement.
Don't you think it's strange?
Why do you suppose Kid returns most of the
jewels he steals to Inspector Nakamori?
True. He could just as well return them to
other detectives or who he stole them from.
But some of those people might not be honest
about getting the jewels back from Kid.
In other words, Kid trusts
Inspector Nakamori.
It's not trust.
Ginzo Nakamori controls Kid the
Phantom Thief from behind the scenes!
He made his daughter inherit the role
of Kid, prepares her escape routes,
and has her return
the stolen gems to him.
This also explains why he
fails to catch Kid every time.
B-But that girl's been seen many times
while Kid's been pulling a robbery!
That's a stand-in.
Given her skills, it would be a simple feat
to employ another girl to dress up as her.
But then what are they after?
All I know is that I've suffered
for 18 long years thanks to Kid.
But there's no need to worry.
The bait has been put out,
and soon I'll reveal that Kid is working
for her father, Inspector Nakamori,
and that under that cape and tux is
an average high school student!
Kaito!
What do you think?
What do I think of what?
As always, your chest hasn't developed...
The hairpin, you dope, the hairpin!
It's cute, isn't it?
Yeah, sure. Really cute!
Don't make any unnecessary changes, dammit!
You're making it harder for me
to disguise myself as you!
That's hairpin's got an interesting shape.
It's shaped like Toto Tower!
It came with the invitation.
Invitation?
I won two tickets to a reserved dinner in
the special observation platform of Toto Tower!
Special observation platform...
Isn't that at the very top?
Yeah! Having a delicious meal with a
beautiful night view... I can't wait for Saturday!
But that special observation platform...
Aren't they using it to exhibit some
dead rich guy's private collection?
I saw on the news that,
just before he died,
he bought a big-ass ruby that they're gonna
put on display from next week, I think...
That's right!
I'm sure Kid is targeting that ruby, so
I invited my dad so he can check it out,
but he said, "I'll be there on a stakeout
next week anyway, so go with a friend!"
Say no more.
I guess I can make it...
Sorry.
I beat you to it.
A-Akako?!
That red tower was depressed after
Bell Tree Tower surpassed its height,
so given the "red" in my name, Akako,
I'd feel bad if I didn't show up.
What, you wanted to go, Kaito?
N-Not especially!
Too bad you don't get to case the place.
There's something fishy about the invitation.
Nakamori-san said she doesn't
remember entering any contest.
Maybe someone who knows about your other
identity has set a trap, using her to lure you.
Well, try not to stand out.
Like they say, the nail that
sticks out gets hammered.
Nail that sticks out...
D-Don't tell me...
Blue Parrot
That does indeed sound suspicious.
Maybe Akako was right, that
somebody's laying a trap for me.
"Saturday night, under the full moon,
I shall seize the jewel upon
the head of the untarnished nail,
and thus repay the debt I owe you
from 18 years ago."
18 years ago...
What's wrong, Jii-chan?
18 years ago. That sticks in my mind...
Now that you mention it...
Where did I hear that recently?
That aside, did you get that
stuff together like I asked?
I prepared it...
...right away.
Then the outfit I need is all set!
Yes. This time, the preparations were cheap.
It seems that's his one good suit.
I figured.
I never see him wear anything else.
But I was surprised!
When you suddenly said
you could make it, Dad...
Given the occasion, Superintendent
Chaki insisted that I come.
Sorry, Akako-kun. I'm sure you
were looking forward to it...
That's okay.
I was looking out for you, jerk!
You're killing my foot!
Have fun,
inspector with the crooked mustache.
Mustache?
Don't get pissed at me!
I don't know why, but the invitation
Aoko got may be a lure to get me here!
Wow!
So many things in the collection!
It's like a museum in the sky!
Sheesh, all of that fine art pales in
comparison to this beautiful night view.
They say the owner of this
collection loved Toto Tower
and wanted to have an exhibition here.
And yet, nobody else is here.
If we're having dinner here, you'd
think there'd be a waitress at least...
It looks like you can get in this car!
It says if you turn the key,
the engine will roar!
More like, the prerecorded
sound of an engine will play...
This is awesome!
Exhaust is coming out!
Can this car move?!
A-Aoko!
Handcuffs and knockout gas!
Then this is...
Long time no see,
Kid the Phantom Thief.
18 years, right?
Who the hell is he?
Though you hung up your cape
and became a police inspector.
Still, you had your snoozing daughter
over there inherit the role.
Hey, wait one second.
This guy's barking up the wrong tree!
But this situation feels familiar...
Deja vu?
What's this? Don't tell me you came here
not realizing it was my trap.
The message on the jewel
pointed to this place,
while the invitation was an obvious trap.
It was all a contrivance so I could see what
you would do before this, the final act.
But it looks like I overestimated you two.
On a whim, I enclosed that hairpin
with a bugging device inside of it,
but instead of destroying it,
your daughter just put it in her hair.
I knew it was a trap.
The "head of the untarnished nail" refers to
the head of a nail before a hammer hits it.
In other words, the top of Toto Tower,
which escaped getting hammered
by the taller Bell Tree Tower.
So you did catch the "nail that
sticks out gets hammered" reference.
But what are you going to do? The
situation is just like in the old days,
but unlike then, your partner
here isn't worth a damn.
Partner?
"The Female with 20 Faces" who dropped
out of sight in Paris 18 years ago.
The gentlewoman thief...
...the Phantom Lady!
Phantom Lady?
I see! It's not deja vu!
He's the guy from 18 years ago...
Mom told me this story the other day!
18 years ago...
Hey! Hello? Hello? Hello?! What's going on?!
One...
Two...
Three!
As I figured...
It's a fake.
Bravo!
That was a brilliant performance.
Although using fake gore to scare a cop
to the point of fainting isn't my style.
I would have gone with
a more elegant method
to send them off to dreamland.
W-Who are you?!
Toichi Kuroba.
I'm a simple magician.
Toichi Kuroba. I know of you.
You traveled the world performing
magic shows as a teenager,
and won first prize at the FISM tournament,
the Magician Olympics, at the age of 20.
You were a prodigy when it came to magic.
But what's a celebrity like you
doing in a place like this?
And wearing such a flashy outfit?
I had this suit custom-made for
my magic show in Paris next month.
It's an homage to Arsene Lupin,
France's great gentleman thief.
H-He's casually walking over
without any night-vision goggles!
Don't tell me he remembers the
positions of all the lasers?!
You're after...
...the motorcycle of the recently-departed
famous French motorcycle racer,
embedded with a diamond to
commemorate his victories.
The showpiece of the bike exhibition here
on the top floor of La Grande Dame de Fer.
Unfortunately, that's a fake.
Word gets out it's been stolen, and soon you
can buy "the real one" on the black market.
Phantom Lady reappears after a two-year
absence, but stealing this isn't worth your time.
What else can I do?! Somebody sent out a
notice saying I was going to steal it tonight!
You can give me the details later.
Let me drop you off downstairs.
Idiot. I'm riding this out of here.
Replica or not, I'm delivering
it to the police.
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
See? What'd I tell you?
W-What's with the handcuffs?!
It means I have no more use for you.
You should've stayed home,
gloating over all the stolen jewels.
But instead, you kept returning
the loot to the police,
putting a major dent in my business as I got
all these replicas in stock but no buyers.
What's this?
I didn't know you worked with assistants.
He's no assistant of mine.
Anyway, if the Phantom Lady is
captured stealing the treasure,
doesn't that put a crimp
in your plans?
No worries there.
I've already got a trained Phantom Lady
impersonator on standby.
And no sense having two of you,
so you'll disappear for good...
Bastard!
Cool it.
This is the only exit.
As long as we block the elevator,
they've got no way out...
I don't know about that.
What?!
Hey! What are you doing?!
I told you.
I'm dropping you off at the bottom.
D-Dropping me off?!
We're just falling!
First, I'll silence that...
...annoying sound.
As I suspected, there was a jewel...
...behind that mask.
Why are you talking like an idiot?!
You, me, and the motorcycle
are going to hit the ground!
Who do you think I am?
I don't believe it!
Toichi-sama!
As you requested, I staged an
accident to seal off the street.
But many bystanders have cameras,
so I don't think you can use
that costume for the show.
That can't be helped.
I'll use this costume
as a phantom thief instead.
A thief so great that the world will
forget all about the Phantom Lady.
So I'd like you to retire
from being a phantom thief
and stay nice and safe
in my jewelry box.
That doesn't sound bad,
but that jewelry box...
There aren't any other
jewels in it, are there?
Of course not.
I see! This situation...
It's just like what Mom was gushing
about, how she and Dad first met!
Then this old fart is the guy
whose crooked business was ruined
by Mom and Dad 18 years ago!
So, what are you going to do,
Kid the Phantom Thief?
You can try to escape in
that car like 18 years ago,
except it was a
slim motorcycle then.
That car is compact, but not enough to fit
through the windows of this observation deck.
Although, being a replica,
you can't drive it in the first place.
I see. Then this entire
prized collection is a hoax.
And as for the big-ass ruby coming
in next week, it's actually a fake
that you'll say was stolen by Kid,
and then sell replicas on the black market.
It's all been arranged.
Well, things look a little
dicey for me there.
The illusion must go on!
Just when I recall Mom's nostalgic tale,
I find myself in a big pinch in the present!
Still, if I can't slip out of this one,
I don't have the right to succeed Dad as Kid!
I've gotta clean up the mess from
Mom's reckless behavior, too!
Uh-oh! He showed up?!
Then things definitely
won't go according to plan!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Phantom Lady and the Ryoma Treasure!
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion!