(Detective Conan  Strategy Above The Depths)
On a luxury liner that was set to sail the Pacific Ocean,
the devil's hand creeps in unsuspectingly.
The culprit must be somewhere on this ship.
There are only 600 suspects here, right?
Who is the culprit related to the case 15 years ago?
And...
(Music: Katsuo Ohno)
How is it related to the explosion case on land?
What must be challenged is the culprit's time trick!
Looks like this is beyond you this time.
I'll definite get to the bottom of this.
However...
The case developed beyond my expectation.
The culprit's evil hands is reaching for the passengers...
Let's make a run for it!
Moreover,
my friends have gotten tangled in this!
Somebody!
Shinichi...
What is the truth behind this complicated case?
What is the culprit's true objective?
And...
What happens to the lives of the 600 passengers?
You remember, right?
Shinichi?
I won't ever forget it!
Especially you!
(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
On the sea and on land, two crime scenes.
In the past and now, two different cases.
(Theme Song: Like a Sail That Waits for Summer by ZARD)
That was the start of a huge plot.
(First in the series! Double suspense!)
First in the series! Double suspense!
A new theatrical movie!
(Detective Conan  Strategy Above The Depths)
Detective Conan: Strategy Above The Depths!
Ran!