(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
Wakasa Headquarters! This is an emergency!
(Screenplay: Takeharu Sakurai (AIBOU Series, ATARU))
I've located a suspicious boat
filled with explosives!
(Detective Conan  Private Eye In The Distant Sea)
Incredible!
Cool!
(Aegis Destroyer - To ensure the nation's safety,
an advanced combat system is equipped onto the latest warship)
During a public demonstration with civilian passengers,
the Aegis Destroyer was suddenly attacked.
There's a response!
(With full cooperation from Ministry of Defense
and Japan Maritime Self-Defense Force)
That is...
What?!
(A wrecked ship)
(A corpse without his left arm  A time trick)
It is the beginning of a huge plot
(A list of numbers  A Mysterious Female JSDF Member)
that will shake the entire Japan.
(Stolen Data)
There's spy on Aegis?!
A game of hide and seek with the culprit.
If this goes on, Japan will be in trouble!
You don't think X is among the passengers?!
(Who is Spy X?)
I've been making a terrible assumption!
(Detective VS Spy)
(Special Guest: Ko Shibasaki)
(Theme Song: One More Time by Kazuyoshi Saito)
Where are you, Kazuha?
Did you get your hands on what you're after,
Mr. Spy from a certain country?
The devil has finally
lay his hands on my friends!
(Danger approaches my friends)
If I'm not with you,
will you feel worried?
How strong!
Now, the curtain rises
(The ultimate spy mystery)
on the ultimate spy mystery in Conan's history!
Die.
Who are you?
Conan Edogawa.
A detective.
(Detective Conan  Private Eye In The Distant Sea)
Detective Conan The Movie: Private Eye In The Distant Sea!
Since you're a great detective,
you'll always be able to find me, right?