Eternity doesn't last forever.
Am I right?
What?
Kudo-kun.
(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
At an auction in New York...
Hammer price!
was the winning bid for the famous sunflowers painting.
We, the Suzuki Group,
seek to gather all seven of van Gogh's sunflowers paintings
(An impregnable art museum)
and have a sunflower-themed exhibition at Lake Rock Art Museum!
Now then...
It can't be!
(The target is...)
(Special Guest: Nana Eikura)
(a globally famous painting)
(The famed van Gogh's "Sunflowers")
Kaitou Kid suddenly makes his appearance.
However...
This is strange.
This isn't his usual trickery!
(Why, Kid...)
(Theme Song: Oh! Rival by Porno Graffitti)
Our opponent is Kid?
(Great Detective VS)
Please allow me to help!
(Kaitou)
(Suspect)
Interesting.
Shinichi...
(Will this art mystery)
(find its conclusion)
(in a labyrinth?)
(Or in a prison?)
Just looking at it
will someday
lead to regret.
Kid!
What did you do?
Be prepared,
great detective.
Detective Conan The Movie!
(Detective Conan  Sunflowers of Inferno)
Sunflowers of Inferno.
It's coming!
What?!
Hold on tight!