At midnight tonight,
I'll come for the Memories Egg.
Now...
the show begins!
Kid!
(The third theatrical movie!)
(Detective Conan  The Last Wizard of The Century)
A challenge from Kaitou Kid.
(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
His target is
the Russian dynasty's treasure, Memories Egg.
However!
Watch out!
The robbers are there.
Their name is...
Their name is...?
A mysterious organization targets people
close to me one after another.
Finally, my identity is about to be...
Conan-kun, you can't be...
(Music: Katsuo Ohno  Theme Song: B'z)
An ultimate trick set down a hundred years ago.
Now, the secret veil is about to be removed.
Ran!
Watch out!
What is his true objective?
Who is the culprit that is after the Egg?
(The series's biggest mysterious adventure!)
With Tokyo, Osaka,
and Russia as the stages
for Conan's biggest mysterious adventure ever!
If you want to be saved, then follow me!
Yes, ma'am!
Who will solve this century's biggest mystery?
A new theatrical movie!
(Detective Conan  The Last Wizard of The Century)
Detective Conan: The Last Wizard of The Century!
Shinichi.