Like water rushing down,
(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
the river rapids, we may be parted by a rock,
but in the end,
we will be one again.
(Osaka X Kyoto  Two mysteries)
The two cases are related!
Set up using the Hyakunin Isshu
was a complicated mystery.
(The key is
Hyakunin Isshu)
This is just
another beginning.
I finally meet you.
(A childhood promise)
My...
future husband.
Husband?!
(Theme Song: Togetsu Bridge -Thinking About You)
What is the objective this mysterious woman
(By Mai Kuraki)
who appeared before Hattori?
(Special Guests: Daisuke Miyagawa  Riho Yoshioka)
This will be the end of your childhood game of pretend love.
Heiji-kun is my fiance.
I'm sorry, Kudo.
I have to go, no matter what!
It can't be... Hattori!
(Fate is set into motion...)
So it begins
the fate of those two.
You have to protect
that girl, right?
Kazuha is in danger!
(A sad truth will be revealed)
(The fated day approaches)
The truth that hides behind an ancient song,
traversed over 1,000 years
and will now be revealed!
We only have one chance.
(There are feelings)
Yeah.
(I have yet to convey)
Hold on, Kazuha!
I will
protect you with my life!
(Detective Conan  The Crimson Love Letter)
Detective Conan The Movie: The Crimson Love Letter.
I won't
let you die in a place like this!