(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
Now...
Shall we guide them to heaven?
(Detective Conan  Countdown to Heaven)
(Trailer)
The Black Organization has finally shown itself!
And now...
The mission is completed.
What is about her suspicious activity
and the past that she keeps hidden?
With a skyscraper that reaches 300 meters
into the sky as the stage,
a murder game without an exit in sight has begun!
(Music: Katsuo Ohno)
In the end...
Is Ai Haibara an enemy or a friend?
Escape is impossible!
The most dangerous case in the series' history awaits us!
Give me that!
They...
What do they intend to do?
This might be the end...
It'll be okay.
I'm right here with you, Ran.
Shinichi...
With nowhere to escape,
what will happen to Ran and I?
(Detective Conan  Countdown to Heaven)
A new theatrical movie! Detective Conan: Countdown To Heaven!
Stop the time on this dangerous trap!