The one who used the drug to poison
the high school detective was you, right?
(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
I meant Shinichi Kudo.
Remember?
(Detective Conan  The Raven Chaser)
(Director: Yasuichiro Yamamoto)
Inexplicable incidents happen one after another.
And…
Tanabata...Kyo...
A mysterious message left behind by the victim.
This series of murders share a common factor
and that's the mahjong tiles
that were left behind at the crime scene.
The Black Organization that lies behind these incidents.
This case seems to be planned by someone.
Are you saying the culprit is among us?
That was Gin's car.
Why is he at the operations meeting?
(What is the organization's objective?)
(Theme Song: PUZZLE by Mai Kuraki)
Bingo.
(Conan Edogawa)
They'll find out who I am next!
What did you say?
Kudo, you can't mean...
The organization intends to erase everyone related to you!
Bye-bye!
(A death game with 0% chance of survival)
Run... It's him.
Drive them out.
Roger!
Shinichi...
Save me.
A mysterious battle never seen before
will now begin!
It's the finale.
Detective Conan The Movie: The Raven Chaser!
(Detective Conan  The Raven Chaser)
Who are you?
Conan Edogawa.
A detective.