♪Maru take ebisu ni oshi oike♪
♪Ane san Rokkaku tako nishiki♪
Watch out!
(Detective Conan  Crossroad In The Ancient Capital)
(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
With a series of murders happening in Kyoto,
the culprit takes with him a book and a mysterious drawing.
(Director: Kenji Kodama)
The victims were members of a robbery gang,
Genjibotaru.
(Chronicles of Yoshitsune)
We've determined that each of them have this book.
(Music: Katsuo Ohno)
Now, a Buddha statue has vanished
and there's a letter of challenge from the culprit!
Solve this riddle and you will find
the whereabouts of the Buddha statue.
What is his objective?
And on the second murder,
Hattori and I went to meet the murderer!
But this clever devil
has captured Kazuha!
The girl's with me.
Heiji, don't come!
Kazuha! Kazuha!
Bring it on.
(Theme Song: Time after time by Mai Kuraki)
Who is the culprit who practices suspicious kendo?
(Chronicles of Yoshitsune)
What is the secret hidden by the dark history?
All right!
I've got it!
Facing an atrocious culprit,
we're caught in a desperate pinch!
At times like this, if only Shinichi is here.
You let him take the medicine?
He might be able to return to his original body.
Can we uncover the culprit's identity?
Can we overcome this danger?
The seventh movie!
The ultimate climax awaits!
Who are you?
Shinichi Kudo.
A detective.
A new theatrical movie!
(Detective Conan  Crossroad In The Ancient Capital)
Detective Conan: Crossroad In The Ancient Capital!
Shinichi!
I finally met you!