(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
(Director: Yasuichiro Yamamoto)
(Detective Conan  Full Score of Fear)
(Theme Song: Spread My Wings by ZARD)
A huge case lurks within the dazzling world of classical music.
Why?
Why are the musicians being targeted one after another?
The culprit's devilish hands
have somehow reached us too.
To erase the beautiful melodies,
the case took a dramatic change.
Ran and a thousand in the audience are taken hostage.
The concert continues despite the explosion.
(Music: Katsuo Ohno)
There are still many people in the concert hall!
Conan-kun, wait!
Everything is for that silent night.
Ran!
This sound... it can't be...
That's right.
It's our...
Kudo-kun, I trust you.
I won't let it be eliminated.
Not this singing voice.
The curtain rises on this magnificent opera full of suspense!
A new theatrical movie!
(Detective Conan  Full Score of Fear)
Detective Conan: Full Score of Fear!