The double face
ends here.
(The 20th Epic)
(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
The secret information stolen from the Japanese police.
(NOC List
Secret Information)
The spies that are being eliminated
one by one all over the world.
The only thing common between them...
Who is that?!
Akai!
is that they have all infiltrated that organization.
If we don't catch that woman,
this world will fall into chaos.
A mysterious woman who has amnesia.
(Special Guest: Yuki Amami)
But she is...
It can't be...
one that must not be opened.
The organization's right hand!
The Pandora's Box!
I found her,
Gin.
When her memories return...
(Shinichi Kudo
Conan Edogawa)
(Sherry  Ai Haibara   FBI  Shuichi Akai)
the double face will be exposed!
(Public Security Bureau  Toru Amuro  CIA  Rena Mizunashi)
When in doubt, punish.
That is my style.
(The Top Battle)
(Theme Song:
The Color This World Will Take Depends on You by B'z)
Ready?
Okay!
Don't go!
I don't want to escape
from my own destiny.
Shinichi, where are you?
(The struggle for the secret)
Even if I am to die,
the Public Security Bureau will take her!
Found it!
The key to bringing down the organization!
Game over.
I'll destroy all of you!
Detective Conan The Movie
(Detective Conan  The Darkest Nightmare)
The Darkest Nightmare!
(It's up to you to decide what color to feel
after watching this (LOL) - Gosho Aoyama)