I really need your help this time,
great detective!
Huh?
(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
A murder took place in Singapore.
At the crime scene was a bloody notice from Kid.
(The legendary blue sapphire)
His target is the legendary treasure.
However...
The strongest karate practitioner
with 400 consecutive victories,
Makoto Kyogoku, stands in his way!
Why are you here?
No more talking!
Kid, why did you bring me here?
Tell me what's in the fist, great detective.
What is in that mysterious fist called "murder"?
(Magic  Truth  Kick)
Kid, too...
(A gigantic "darkness" begins unravelling)
will soon be done for.
I don't want to be protected
(Theme song: Blue Sapphire by Hiroomi Tosaka)
by a man who is full of lies!
Hey, Shinichi.
We're...
dating, right?
I know you're the mastermind behind all this.
(Special Guests:
Ikusaburo Yamazaki  Mayuko Kawakita)
A legendary treasure that was buried
at the bottom of the ocean
has travelled across time
and awakened the darkness within Singapore!
He can't be!
(An era...)
This time, you must not leave my side!
(comes to an end.)
Stealing a treasure
is my job!
Don't die, Kid!
Detective Conan The Movie!
(Detective Conan: The Fist Of Blue Sapphire)
The Fist of Blue Sapphire!