(Detective Conan  Captured In Her Eyes)
(Trailer)
(The Fourth Theatrical Movie!)
The police are getting murdered one after another.
What lies behind this case?
What in the world is going on?
Sorry, I cannot tell you anything.
It means need not to know.
(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
The police refuses to share a single information.
With Tropical Land as the stage,
a brutal crime is taking place.
And...
Officer Sato!
The only person who saw the culprit was Ran.
However!
Could Ran's memories be...
Ran, do you know who I am?
You must recall the culprit who targeted you!
In order to erase the only evidence,
the culprit is targeting Ran's life!
Why are you trying so hard to protect me, boy?
That's because, Ran...
You are...
precious to me.
Is this a perfect crime?
(Theme Song: Miho Komatsu  Music: Katsuo Ohno)
Who is the culprit that lurks in the darkness?
And...
Can I protect Ran's life?
We need to find the sniper
that is hidden in Ran's eyes!
A new theatrical movie!
(Detective Conan  Captured In Her Eyes)
Detective Conan: Captured In Her Eyes!
Ran!