Currently at depth of 60 meters, over.
(300 years ago, a palace was sunk into the ocean)
What is that?
(In there, are buried treasures)
That's the Seabed Palace.
(Detective Conan Jolly Roger In The Deep Azure)
(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
There were female pirates recorded in history.
(Director: Yasuichiro Yamamoto)
They're Anne Bonny and Mary Read's treasures.
Looks like the legend was true.
Amazing!
(Music: Katsuo Ohno)
With the peaceful Seabed Palace as the stage,
countless treasures were found
and troubles began to happen.
What?!
The two items that got stolen
will become the key to solving this mystery.
Damn it. So they've been eyeing that after all.
Don't move!
Do not interfere with our business anymore.
They are no mere treasure hunters.
We'll head out too!
Get the boats ready immediately!
Legendary treasures and mysterious hunters...
Interesting!
(Theme Song: Like the Wind that Blows Across the Seven Seas)
A code that prevailed for over 300 years.
Jolly Roger...
Just as the truth is within grasp,
what is going to happen?
Are you telling me to leave them?
Kudo-kun...
Drawn on wind scale
is an adventure full of mystery!
A new theatrical movie!
(Detective Conan  Jolly Roger In The Deep Azure)
Detective Conan: Jolly Roger In The Deep Azure!
I believe in you, Ran!
Leave it to me, Sonoko!