Thank you very much for coming.
I have a case waiting for you to solve.
What kind of case is that?
If you fail to solve it, this will happen.
What is this thing?
It won't come off!
What?!
(10th Anniversary Epic!)
I've made your friends
put on a bomb of the same kind.
If you want to save them,
then solve this case as soon as possible.
(12 Hours Time Limit)
The light is blinking.
(Who is this mysterious man?)
(And what is his objective?)
Do you know what it feels to lose someone you love, Kudo-kun?
(The chosen detectives)
Kudo, if he knows your real identity, that means...
(The fight to the death begins)
What was that?!
It's them!
It's here.
(Detective Conan  The Private Eyes' Requiem)
Detective Conan The Movie: The Private Eyes' Requiem.