Flight 865 departing at 18:15
is now commencing with boarding procedures.
What are you about to start,
Mr. Thief?
Let's see...
How about you take a guess, Detective-kun?
(Detective Conan  Magician of The Silver Sky)
My fated rival sent me a challenge.
(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
Hidden in there
was the mystery behind the star sapphire
and Kid's true motive.
(Theme Song: Dream x Dream by Rina Aiuchi)
And then...
A locked-room murder suddenly took place
in the flight we're on!
Kid might have blended in
among all these passengers.
The culprit is you!
(Music: Katsuo Ohno)
And this murder case turned deadly!
It's going to crash!
This is an emergency!
Do you copy?
Is this also Kid's doing?
Or is it...
We need to solve
this suspenseful locked-room murder
10,000 feet up in the air!
Absolute despair!
Is this our fate?
A new theatrical movie!
(Detective Conan  Magician of The Silver Sky)
Detective Conan: Magician of The Silver Sky!
I love you, Shinichi.