(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
Ladies and gentlemen.
(Screenplay: Hisashi Nozawa (Edogawa Rampo Prize winner))
Created using the world's top technology
is a virtual reality game system. Welcome to Cocoons!
(Director: Kenji Kodama)
Game start!
(Detective Conan  The Phantom of Baker Street)
Fifty children fell into the control
of an unknown artificial intelligence, Noah's Ark.
This is a survival game set in London a hundred years ago.
Conan! What is going on?
If we don't catch Jack the Ripper that existed in history,
everyone will be doomed!
Genta!
Does that boy know about the secret?
It has enough power to destroy the brains of 50 people.
Come here!
Their underlings that kept getting in our way
were also behind the murder happening in the real world!
It can't be!
And then one after another, my friends are being erased.
I only on count on Sherlock Holmes.
Now it's a fight between the two brains!
Shinichi...
(Music: Katsuo Ohno  Theme Song: B'z)
The most complicated mystery and trap of the series!
Can we clear this death game with Dad?
We're counting on you.
You are our Sherlock Holmes.
What is the culprit's true identity?
Ran!
Can we return to the real world?
(Detective Conan  The Phantom of Baker Street)
Detective Conan: The Phantom of Baker Street!
The culprit is...
you!