(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
Inspector Megure!
(Detective Conan  The Fourteenth Target)
(The long-awaited second movie!)
That Conan has returned to the big screen!
My companions got targeted one after another.
What are these mysterious playing cards
left at the crime scene?
What is the culprit's objective?
And Mister's hidden past is now revealed!
(Kogoro Mouri  Beika City)
The victims are all your acquaintances.
Hm?!
Dad...
(A completely original story)
The helicopter is crashing! Get out now!
(The ultimate locked room serial murder!)
Locked in a restaurant in the middle of the sea
a serial murder has begun to happen!
Watch out!
(Theme Song: ZARD  Music: Katsuo Ohno)
The culprit's evil hands have finally reached out to Ran!
Ah!
Of all Conan's cases, the hardest one has appeared!
Shinichi!
Ran!
Who is the culprit?
And who is the next target?
Detective Conan a new theatrical movie!
(Detective Conan  The Fourteenth Target)
The Fourteenth Target!
The next target is
you!