Tell Kudo...
I will show him something interesting soon.
What?
(Detective Conan  The Time-Bombed Skyscraper)
(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
(A series of dreadful bombing incidents!)
A notice of series of bombings from a mysterious man.
Who is he?
What is his objective?
(Theme Song: Happy Birthday by Kyoko
Main Theme: Katsuo Ohno/Katsuo Ohno Band)
I shall catch the culprit.
Hurry, run!
There's a bomb on that train!
What?!
The time limit fast approaches!
What terrible mystery lie hidden in this metropolis?
Shinichi!
Ran!
(Finally, a movie based on a completely original story!)
That's the bomb, Ran.
What should I do?
I don't think we'll ever meet again.
We'll die together.
(Detective Conan  The Time-Bombed Skyscraper)
Detective Conan: The Time-Bombed Skyscraper!
Only one truth
will prevail!