(Detective Conan  Quarter of Silence)
(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
(Governor)
The governor was suddenly sent
(A mysterious blackmail)
a mysterious blackmail.
And then...
A bomb?
What?
(Special Guest: Yoichi Watanabe (war photographer))
(Underground Subway X Colossal Dam)
What ties the explosion at the underground subway
with the tragedy in the snow?
The one holding the key
is the young man who lies comatose for eight years.
(The devil's hands approach the young man)
What?
What is it about...
(Diamond dust flying in the snow field)
this light before me...
No! I can't remember!
(Theme Song: Don't Wanna Lie by B'z)
We only have the last 15 minutes remaining.
Ayumi-chan!
Miracles don't often happen.
(A heroic survival mystery)
Unfolding at a colossal dam covered in snow
is a survival mystery.
What is he planning to do?
Watch out!
If I make it out alive,
we'll see each other again.
(15th Anniversary Production
Detective Conan  Quarter of Silence)
A 15th anniversary production.
Detective Conan The Movie: Quarter of Silence.
(I will definitely survive this...)