(Author: Gosho Aoyama)
Many people
will inevitably
experience fear.
Huh? What are you talking about?
Now...
Let the game begin.
What?!
(Detective Conan  The Eleventh Striker)
The great detective who suddenly got targeted.
(Fearsome puzzles)
Solve the puzzle?!
I've sworn to take revenge
on all of you.
(The Boy In Blue And The Blue Zebra)
Furthermore, the culprit has sent out a new challenge.
Be warned.
(Continuous Stadium Explosions)
What is the culprit's objective?
(With full cooperation from J-League)
(J-League 20th Anniversary
Featuring active J-League players)
With the soccer world getting involved,
(Special Appearance: Yasuhito Endo (Gamba Osaka))
the deduction game with the culprit begins!
(Theme Song: Spring Song by Ikimono-gakari)
If you're the ace striker...
Shinichi, we don't have much time!
Then stop this bomb!
(Guest Voice Actress: Mirei Kiritani)
This sportsmanship that should not be corrupted...
(Special Appearance: Kazuyoshi Miura)
Boy, do you like soccer?
has now turned deadly.
This is the last chance.
No way! It was back then!
(Solve the puzzle with teamwork!)
I'm counting on you, Kudo-kun!
Time's up.
Run!!!
(Detective Conan  The Eleventh Striker)
Detective Conan The Movie: The Eleventh Striker!