I feel like I've been told how mysteries
should be written again!
- Author Gosho Aoyama
I hope my love for Conan will reach everyone.
- Screenplay Writer Kenji Uchida
Conan Edogawa,
I will steal everything of yours.
Oh no!
(Detective Conan)
(The Disappearance of Conan Edogawa:
The Worst Two Days In History)
Conan-kun, let's go for a bath!
At the bath house we went to, we encountered
(Legendary hit man)
a legendary hit man.
Hey, what are you hiding?
(Hidden plot)
An unbelievable plot is hidden in the dark.
(Author Gosho Aoyama)
The birth of a powerful tag team
(Screenplay Writer Kenji Uchida)
from two different dimensions.
Detective Conan
(A miraculous collaboration with)
and Key of Life,
("Key of Life" directed by Kenji Uchida)
a miraculous collaboration!
A line of incredible cast will make their appearances!
Conan-kun is...
missing?
(Conan is missing)
Where has he gone?
(The worst day in Conan's life)
The worst day in Conan's life is about to begin.
Finally, it's my turn!
This is horrible!
Conan-kun!
(Conan has amnesia?!)
Detective Conan's
special anime in commemoration of its 20th anniversary!
The Disappearance of Conan Edogawa!
The Worst Two Days In History!
Who am I?