Detective Conan Episode 754 "The
Tragedy of the Red Woman (Steam)"
This feels great!
Nothing beats walking through the forest!
I know. The air is delicious, too.
It's so soothing.
I wish I could've brought my dad.
Thanks for inviting us, Sera-san.
I'm glad I got to come with you.
I'm surprised, though.
I didn't think you'd enjoy walks in the woods.
Actually, I came here at someone's request.
A-A request? You don't mean...
Is it detective work?
Yeah.
The request actually came for my brother,
but one of his high school friends
asked me to solve the mystery
of the rental villa we're headed to.
It seems my brother is busy right now.
Anyway, since I'm a high school
detective, he asked me to go instead.
Is your brother a detective, too?
No, but apparently my
brother quickly took care
of any incidents or mysteries
that came up during high school.
Huh?
But I thought your brother passed away...
Oh, yeah. That was my oldest brother.
The one who received the
request was my middle brother.
Two older brothers and one younger sister.
We all have different surnames, though.
Why do you have different surnames?
Things would happen,
like our fathers dying...
I use my mother's maiden name Sera,
and middle brother was Sera, too,
until he graduated from high school.
Then before he became Sera,
was his name...?
Red.
What?
A red person.
Wasn't there a red person
behind that tree a second ago?
Y-Yeah.
A long-haired woman wearing a
red raincoat and red boots.
It looked like she around
there until a second ago...
The Red Woman...
What?
Conan-kun!
A-A swamp?
Watch your step.
Apparently there's quicksand in this forest.
Seriously?
A refreshing autumn breeze blows through
the gaiety of summer for a stylish
and dashing display of deduction.
A villa with a bright red
door and the shadow
of the Red Woman back from the dead.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Tragedy of the Red Woman
(Steam)
Tragedy of the Red Woman (Steam)!
What a wonderful villa.
But why is only the front door bright red?
You're right.
It's a little creepy...
Are you Sera-kun's little
sister and her friends?
Yes, we are.
Thanks for coming all the way out here.
Tamami Minegishi (28)
Rental Villa Guest
I'm Tamami Minegishi. It's nice to meet you.
Um, which of you is Sera-kun's sister?
I'm his sister Masumi.
These are my classmates Sonoko
Suzuki-kun and Ran Mori-kun.
Hello!
Nice to meet you.
And this is the kid under
Ran-kun's family's care,
Conan Edogawa-kun.
He's an even sharper detective than me.
Really?
Conan-kun, you're pretty
amazing for a little kid.
Oh, um...
I'm not that impressive.
Anyway, about the request...
We took some photographs
to document the strange
occurrence at this rental villa.
Sumika said she'd have them
printed and bring them here.
Oh, there she is.
Sumika, did you bring the photos?
Huh?
Sumika Kawana (28)
Rental Villa Guest
These are the printed photos.
Do your best.
Thanks...
Bye.
Sorry. Don't let it bother you.
Sumika's shy. She's always
like that around new people.
Sera's high school detective
sister really came?
Huh? Ninda-kun and Hakuya-kun,
you came together?
N-No...
Masaie Hakuya (28)
Rental Villa Guest
W-We ran into each other in the woods,
so we walked the rest of the way together...
He said he got stuck in a swamp.
He was changing in the middle of the forest.
Jinsuke Ninda (29)
Rental Villa Guest
Man, you're as clumsy as ever.
Hey, don't tell them!
It's too bad, though.
I was looking forward to having
a high school girl visit,
but she brought her boyfriend with her.
What?
We heard Sera's younger sister
was coming with her friends.
I'm his younger sister Masumi Sera!
What?!
You're a girl?!
I thought you were a boy.
Hey.
What's inside that bag you're carrying?
Oh, this?
It's a bat.
I bring it every year to drive them off.
That's a pretty thin bat, though...
Can you hit a ball with that?
I told you, I use it to drive them off.
D-Drive them off?
Are there bears?
No, there aren't any bears...
Right?
Yeah...
This is delicious!
You're right! These are really good.
Tamami-san, these hamburgers are delicious!
Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah!
Thank you.
Tamami's hamburgers could
be sold in a restaurant.
You think so?
You're right.
You could make good
money off these burgers.
Don't be ridiculous.
Sera-no-neechan, you're
good with a fork and knife.
I was terrible when I was a kid,
but I got used to it after
living abroad for three years.
You can tell you used to live in America.
Children learn so quickly.
You have food on your face, Conan-kun.
By the way, why did you come here together?
Our high school outdoor club.
We used to go mountain climbing
and camping together.
Since we were in high school,
most of what we did was
during summer break.
Thanks.
But we had fun.
We only had five members, though.
Really?
If there were five of you,
does that mean the woman in red we
saw in the forest earlier is your fifth?
Wh-Where did you see her?!
In the forest, with Sonoko...
Was she really wearing red clothes?!
Y-Yes...
She was wearing a red
raincoat and red boots.
She was a long-haired woman
dressed in red from head to toe...
H-Hey, could it be?
No way!
I-It can't be!
There's no way Satoko is alive!
Actually,
I thought it might be the murderer
from fifteen years ago...
Hey.
Could you tell me more about that?
Don't you want to know, too, Conan-kun?
Huh? Uh, yeah.
It happened fifteen years ago.
There was a homicide at another
rental villa near this one.
The victim was an office worker.
He secretly went to the rental
villa with his mistress,
and his wife barged in with a knife.
By the time the police heard
the noise and got there,
the entire room was a sea of blood.
The wife stabbed her husband over and over,
until her white raincoat
had turned bright red.
They called her...
...the Red Woman.
Th-The Red Woman?!
D-Did they catch the Red Woman?
No...
After stabbing the policeman with her knife,
she disappeared into the forest.
She's still on the run.
Three years after that,
we came to this rental villa during
our high school summer vacation.
Our other club member Satoko
said she saw the Red Woman,
so we decided to go looking
for her in the forest.
While we were searching, we lost Satoko.
Since it was getting dark, we called
the police and had them look for her.
They found her one week later.
They discovered Satoko's body covered
in mud and sunk into the quicksand.
They found her body because Satoko's
shoes...were beside the swamp.
The knife used in the other
murder was found there, too.
Everyone thought...
...that perhaps Satoko...
...had been chased by the Red
Woman hiding in the forest,
and fell into the swamp.
D-Do you want Sera-san
to catch this Red Woman?
What? Oh, no...
That's the police's job.
Even after we graduated,
we came here every year
on the day Satoko's body was found.
But about two years ago,
strange things started happening.
A window was broken,
and tons of apples were rolling
around inside a room.
When we couldn't get any hot water,
we found red rose petals stuffed
inside the hot water heater.
Once we even had red paint
splashed over the front door.
And this time, the Red Woman...
Apparently, the owner of the villa
painted the rest of the door red.
I see. That's why the front door is red.
Those strange incidents
and the red woman
you saw in the forest were probably
just someone playing pranks on us.
But, well,
we decided to ask the sharp Sera
to determine the culprit for us.
I see.
I've got the big picture now.
We need to solve the mystery
surrounding the Red Woman.
No, you should leave the
Red Woman to the police...
Okay!
I'm going to search the forest.
Me, too!
Wait, Conan-kun!
You can't just go!
Sheesh...
I'm going to go shopping at
the store a kilometer away.
We're short on beverages, right?
Yes, please do.
I'll clean up after our meal.
Would you like any help shopping?
Oh, it's fine.
Shopping and carrying
things around is my job.
Huh? Hakuya-kun, what's wrong?
You don't look well...
Oh, it's nothing. It's nothing.
W-Well, I'm going to go clean the bathrooms.
Thanks, Hakuya-kun.
I'm going to clean the rooms.
Will you help me?
Yes.
You know,
now that I get a closer look,
this room is covered in dust.
We should have cleaned
up a little before lunch.
Yeah, but don't you think it's too filthy?
Well, considering that
incident happened nearby,
I'm sure not many people
want to rent this place.
The vacuum is so loud.
I bet it's one of those really
loud ones that work really well.
Oh, it's one of those mail order
vacuums you see all the time.
Yeah.
Hey, what do you girls want for dinner?
I'm going to start prepping.
Something yummy!
Okay, got it.
Do you need any help prepping?
No, I'm fine. I can do it myself.
Did you finish cleaning the living room?
Yes.
In that case, could you help
me clean the other rooms?
Yes, of course.
Hakuya-kun filled the bath.
He's so considerate.
If Hakuya-san's not here, could
he be cleaning the toilet?
How's the water?
It feels perfect.
The water's bright green.
They're green bath salts.
Hakuya-kun's really into them.
My mother uses them, too.
They're supposed to make you sweat.
I heard they're good for your skin, too.
In that case, why don't we finish
cleaning and take the first bath?
The bathtub here's pretty big.
Great idea.
Let's do it!
I'm back!
Welcome back!
Huh? You came together?
Yeah.
We ran into each other on the way back.
I had them carry some stuff.
We looked all around the forest,
but we didn't find any clues.
Really?
Well, that's enough of that for today.
I'm making my specialty for dinner tonight.
I'm looking forward to that.
Where are Ran-neechan and the others?
They said they'd take a bath
since they finished cleaning.
She should be in the bathroom
with Sumika and Sonoko-chan.
Wh-What is this?
Ew, gross!
Is this a prank?
What's wrong?
Hey, what happened?!
Are you okay?
Red...
Red?
The Red Woman...
A ton of tomatoes in the bathtub...
Red tomatoes...
It's just like the other pranks.
Hey, where's Hakuya-san?
What? Come to think of it, I haven't
seen him since after lunch.
Ninda-kun? Is Hakuya-kun here?
No, he isn't here.
Where did he go?
He was cleaning the bathrooms, right?
Y-Yeah, he should be...
Could it be?
That's Hakuya-san, isn't it?
Yeah.
Damn it.
That's right. This is the bathroom.
I-Is Hakuya-san dead?
Y-Yeah, it seems that way.
Episode Preview
Who did this, then?
It's obvious...
Hakuya could only have been
killed by the Red Woman.
It must have been her.
Th-The Red Woman...
They don't exist.
Evil spirits, demons,
witches, and sorcerers
only live in the world of fantasy.
Tragedy of the Red Woman
(Evil Spirit)
The next episode of Conan is “Tragedy
of the Red Woman (Evil Spirit)!”
Nagano Prefectural Police
Next episode's hint!
The Nagano Prefectural Police!
Are you okay, Conan-kun?
Don't miss the next episode.
Of course I'm not okay.
Ran-kun, pick up your towel.