At Sera's invitation,
Ran, Sonoko, and I came to a rental
villa deep in the mountains.
Fifteen years ago,
a tragic incident occurred near
the cottage at the hands...
...of the murderer known
as the "Red Woman."
Sera came in place of her brother,
to solve the mysterious "red"
occurrences happening at the rental villa.
And then...
Wh-What is this?!
Could it be?!
A refreshing autumn breeze
blows through the gaiety
of summer for a stylish and
dashing display of deduction.
Is it fantasy or reality?
Even Sonoko witnesses the
shadow of the Red Woman!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Tragedy of the Red Woman
(Evil Spirit)
Tragedy of the Red Woman (Evil Spirit)!
Good work, ma'am.
How does it look?
Yes, ma'am.
The victim is Masaie Hakuya-san,
twenty-eight years old.
He came to stay at this rental villa
with a few friends on vacation.
Hakuya-san arrived at this
rental villa this afternoon.
He was killed after eating lunch,
when he and his friends
split up to clean the villa.
Later his friends discovered
him in the water
when they tried to take a bath.
I see.
Is that blood in the bathroom the victim's?
No, it belongs to the boy
visiting the rental villa.
What boy?
He's right over there.
You...
Conan-kun, what's wrong?
Is your nose bleeding?
Y-Yeah.
I was tho thocked when I thaw the 'orpse.
Are you sure you didn't get
excited when you saw Ran naked?
Yeah, right.
Frankly, she's right.
I-Is Hakuya-san dead?
The victim was most likely...
...drowned in the bathwater after
being knocked unconscious...
...by a blow from a blunt object
to the back of his head.
Jinsuke Ninda (29)
Rental Villa Guest
Damn it!
Why'd someone have to kill him?!
Sumika Kawana (28)
Rental Villa Guest
Tamami Minegishi (28)
Apparently, the victim was cleaning.
Yes.
He was cleaning this bathtub and toilet.
We each had specific roles
every year we came here.
Sumika cleaned the rooms and hallways.
Ninda-kun did most of the shopping.
It's almost a kilometer to the nearest store.
My job was cooking for everyone.
Once we finished our own jobs,
we would help the others.
If I had helped Hakuya
instead of going shopping,
this wouldn't have happened...
When did you last see the victim?
I didn't see him after he left the living
room to clean the bathrooms after lunch.
He wasn't here when I
looked in the bathroom.
You looked in the bathroom?
Yes.
There was steam coming from the bathroom.
I thought Hakuya-kun had
drawn a bath for us.
I looked in the bathroom with those girls.
Did you look inside the tub then?
Yes.
We uncovered the bath to check
the temperature of the water.
But there weren't any tomatoes
floating in the bathwater then.
After that, we finished cleaning the rooms
and decided to take the first bath together.
And Sumika-san found all these
tomatoes in the bathtub.
Conan-kun and I ran here
when we heard the commotion.
We discovered Hakuya-san's body when
we pulled him out of the water.
Does that mean
you couldn't see his body
until after you pulled it out?
Yeah.
The surface was covered in tomatoes.
The water was green with bath salts,
and dumbbells had been placed on his
body to prevent it from floating.
In other words, after sinking
the body in the bath,
the culprit covered the water's
surface with tomatoes to hide it.
What or'er 'id you 'ome in?
What?
In what or'er 'id you enter the 'athroom?
He's probably asking in what
order you entered the bathroom.
If the first person to enter
had a bag of tomatoes,
she could have put them in the tub.
Don't tell me this kid suspects us.
Sumika-san was first, right?
She entered wearing just a
towel to uncover the tub.
Yeah.
Besides, someone would've noticed a
bag containing that many tomatoes.
You got that, you little nose bleeder?
In any case,
it seems the crime was committed between
the time Ran-chan and the others
checked the water and when they entered
the bathroom once they finished cleaning.
Can you tell us what you two
were doing during that time?
S-Sure.
Like Tamami said, I was out shopping.
It's about a fifteen minute walk
to the store a kilometer away.
We hadn't bought any beer or anything.
I ran into those two on my way back.
Is that true?
Yeah.
He gave us cold canned beverages
to drink while we walked back.
I gave the drinks to them
right after I bought them.
We ran into each other in
the forest near the store.
What were you two doing in the forest then?
There was some investigating we wanted to do.
Conan-kun and I were walking
around in the forest.
What about you, Tamami-san?
What?
I-I was cleaning up after lunch
and prepping for dinner.
By yourself?
Yes.
I was in the kitchen alone.
That's not an alibi, then.
But I was talking to those
two through the kitchen door.
Really?
Yes.
We were cleaning the living room
in front of the kitchen then.
Tamami-san asked us what
we wanted for dinner.
When we asked if she needed help,
she said she was fine.
I'm pretty sure she was in the kitchen.
I see.
Sumika-san was with you then, wasn't she?
No. Sumika-san was cleaning
the second floor by herself.
I thought it'd go faster with three people,
and went to the living room to ask them.
After that, the three of
us were cleaning together.
And it's true Sumika-san was cleaning the
second floor the whole time until then.
We heard the sound of the vacuum running,
and we could hear it bumping
against walls, too.
That means...
the only person who could have
committed the crime is Tamami-san,
who was hiding in the kitchen
while Sumika-san, Ran-chan,
and Sonoko-san were cleaning.
W-Wait!
I really was in the kitchen until
Ninda-kun came back from shopping!
I don't think Tamami could have done it.
What?
Together we only cleaned the first
floor where the bathroom is.
Tamami knows I clean the hallways, too.
She couldn't have secretly committed
the murder on the first floor.
Besides, Tamami could never
do something like that.
Who did this, then?
It's obvious.
What?
Hakuya could only have been killed...
...by the Red Woman.
It must have been her.
The Red Woman?
You mean from fifteen years ago?
Yeah.
That red demon who
committed that murder
fifteen years ago in
the rental villa near here.
She must have been hiding
in the woods somewhere.
She's the one who broke a window and
threw a bunch of apples in here, too,
and filled the hot water
heater with red rose petals,
and threw red paint on the door.
It was all the Red Woman.
B-But why did the Red
Woman kill Hakuya-kun?
She's a murderer!
Who knows how crazy people think?!
The front door wasn't locked then.
The Red Woman doesn't know
about Sumika's cleaning habits,
so she broke in and happened to kill
Hakuya without anyone seeing her,
leaving red tomatoes in the
bathwater to remind us of her!
That's not possible.
The murderer known as the Red Woman,
Komayo Takeno, is dead.
What?
But the news said she was still
on the run the other day.
Did you know a woman's body was found in
a swamp three years after the incident?
Y-Yes.
That's Satoko.
Our classmate.
Yes.
The truth is, a skeleton thought to be
three years old was also
discovered in the swamp.
Because the murder weapon
was found next to the body,
we thought it was Takeno's body.
Takeno set fire to her
house before the murder.
Her personal belongings were lost,
and we couldn't perform a
DNA test for a long time.
However,
when Takeno's mother passed away last week,
we learned she had been
hiding her umbilical cord.
When we compared it to the DNA
from the skeleton's bone marrow,
it was a perfect match.
The Red Woman died long ago.
We were planning on announcing
it to the media tomorrow.
Because it was a major case,
the Nagano prefectural police are
in chaos trying to handle it.
Th-Then who killed him?
Don't tell me it was the
ghost of the Red Woman!
If we're dealing with a
ghost, my bat is useless.
You'll protect us, won't you?
In any case, you need to calm down.
Could the three of you wait in your rooms
until we're finished with the investigation?
I see.
This is your bat for driving
off the Red Woman.
Yeah.
I also meant to use it to drive off whoever
was pulling pranks on this rental villa.
How does it look?
There aren't any obvious marks,
and it didn't react to the luminol.
It's not the weapon that was
used to strike the victim.
But...
But?
There seems to have been
something stuck on it.
It's a little sticky.
Do you know what this is?
No, not really.
Hey.
Why is there a fan in this room
when it has air conditioning?
Who knows?
Maybe a guest who doesn't
like air conditioning
pulled it out of storage and left it there.
Uehara-san.
Did you find something?
Well...
What?
The weapon was that dumbbell?
The thing weighing down
the body in the bathwater?
Yes.
Judging from the wound and
the way the skull caved in,
it's probably the weapon.
Have you heard from Inspector Yamato?
Hey, Conan-kun.
No, not yet.
What?
What do you think of this?
That's...
But how...
Also, I stole this tomato
from the crime scene.
Oh, right.
You want to test it, don't you?
Yeah, of course.
I knew it.
Yeah. There's no mistake.
Which means the culprit is...
Yeah.
It must be...
Oh, no. It's raining.
It really seems like the Red Woman's
going to make an appearance.
Don't say that.
Sheesh.
Huh?
Huh? Wh-What?
I thought I saw a woman with long
hair standing outside the window...
Oh, come on! That's enough!
Th-The power's out?
Wh-What's wrong?
S-Someone just ran by...
What?
Huh?
What? Who's there?
Tamami? Ninda-kun?
Why is the power out?
Who's there?
We weren't supposed to leave our rooms—
Where's Sumika-san's room?
This way!
Are you all right?
Who did this to you?
Th-The Red Woman...
The Red Woman?
That's not possible.
Her death has been confirmed.
B-But...
After the power went out,
someone was tapping on the window.
When I opened it,
a-a long-haired woman was standing there.
She stabbed at me with a knife.
When I tried to run, she got me in the back.
Was that person really the Red Woman?
Did you get a good look at her face?
I didn't see it.
It was dark, so I only saw her silhouette.
But she had long hair and a knife.
Wasn't it the Red Woman?
S-Sumika!
Did something happen?
We'll treat her.
Help me bring her to the living room.
Also, let's gather in the living room
until the power comes back on.
It's dangerous to be alone in the dark.
It's a clean cut, but it doesn't look deep.
Ran-chan, get me the antiseptic.
Okay.
Hey, is the power really
out in the whole area?
Yes.
A transformer was struck by lightning.
It'll take some time to
get the power back up.
Does that mean the culprit took advantage
of the coincidental power
outage to attack her?
It'll sting a little.
Okay.
Was it really the Red Woman who attacked you?
Yeah!
She gave me this!
But the Red Woman's dead, right?
Could the umbilical cord
used to test her DNA
have belonged to someone else?
That's not possible.
Family members attested
the Red Woman's mother
refused to hand over the
umbilical cord to the police,
because she refused to admit
her daughter was dead.
There is something strange
about the case, though.
What do you mean?
The villa burglaries.
For more than ten years,
we've been receiving crime
reports from the rental villas
in this area around this time of year.
They're not like the pranks
you just mentioned,
like breaking windows and
throwing something inside.
There are signs someone picked the lock
and had been living there for a while.
Some people have witnessed
uncanny figures in the forest.
That's why the Nagano police
couldn't be certain the skeleton in
the swamp belonged to the Red Woman.
Th-Then the person I saw
from my window just now...
Sonoko...
You saw someone? When?
Where did you see them?
J-Just before the power went out.
Sh-She was standing outside that window.
Sh-She was behind that tree,
and looking this way with her head tilted.
A long-haired woman.
It's her.
She's the one who attacked me.
D-Does the ghost of the
Red Woman really exist?
If we don't get out of
here, we... We'll all be...
That's right!
W-We'll end up like Hakuya-kun!
They don't exist.
Evil spirits, demons, witches,
and sorcerers only live
in the world of fantasy.
Not a single one of them
exists in this world.
Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
So don't worry.
Even if she is around, she's
a flesh and blood person.
We can neutralize her with my
jeet kune do or Ran-kun's karate.
O-Okay.
I've been wondering for a while,
but who are you?
You seem like more than just
one of Ran-chan's classmates.
Oh, I forgot to introduce myself.
I'm Masumi Sera.
I guess I'm a high school detective.
She's the younger sister
of our classmate Sera-kun.
We asked her and her
friends to come to solve
the mysterious incidents that
occurred at this rental villa.
Sera's busy, but he said
his little detective sister
had just come back from America
and didn't have anything to do.
Really?
You came back from America?
Yeah.
I'd been living there for about three years,
but I started to miss Japan, so I came back.
To be reunited with a magician...
Episode Preview
There really is something...
...hiding out in the forest.
Like Satoko and Hakuya-kun...
We'll be killed by the Red Woman's ghost.
What?
No one's going to be killed.
The ghost of the Red Woman...
...you keep mentioning doesn't exist.
Tragedy of the Red Woman
(Revenge)
The next episode of Conan is "Tragedy of the Red Woman (Revenge)!"
Long-haired Woman
Next episode's hint.
The long-haired woman!
Don't miss the next episode.
The long-haired...
...woman?
You mean me?
That's scary.