Kogoro and I ran into
comedian DoDonPa Rokusuke
turning himself in at the
police station near Beika Station.
DoDonPa Rokusuke (30)
Comedian
He claimed to have killed Hideki Tendo,
the president of his talent agency.
However, the police investigation
turned up inconsistencies
with the murder weapon, time of death,
and contradictions in his testimony.
When a witness to his alibi named
Izumi Suda-san was discovered,
Izumi Suda (68)
Artist
it became clear he turned himself in
under false pretenses to become the culprit.
DoDonPa Rokusuke-san was released.
I'm sorry, everyone!
In order to protect the
reputation of Hideki Tendo,
I, DoDonPa Rokusuke,
wanted to be called his murderer.
What that intent, I falsely turned myself in.
I'm terribly sorry!
Hey, how did you guys know
DoDonPa-san turned himself in?
Huh? Oh.
Every station received an
anonymous tip by phone.
Who had that information?
The people who knew were...
What?!
I can't imagine that policeman
leaked the information,
and it wasn't me or the old guy.
Maybe his goal wasn't to become the
culprit of a murder he didn't commit,
but to make us think that...
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
A world renowned comedian.
An unexpected remark brings
an alibi crashing down.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Comedian Who Turned Himself In
(Part Two)
"The Comedian Who Turned Himself In, Part 2!"
Hey, mister! It's time for breakfast!
Mouri Detective Agency
Huh? Where's Ran?
She left early this morning
for a karate match.
Shouldn't you be at school?
I have the day off today.
Oh, right.
I'm sorry, everyone!
In order to protect the
reputation of Hideki Tendo,
The Truth Behind DoDonPa Turning Himself In
"I wanted to be called his murderer."
Press Conference Held Yesterday
I, DoDonPa Rokusuke,
wanted to be called his murderer.
What that intent, I falsely turned myself in.
I'm terribly sorry!
Things really worked out well for him.
He was thrust into the spotlight,
and he's the man of the hour.
But why did he turn himself in?
Watching him on TV, I thought he was
an unpleasant man with a strong personality,
but he's actually a really nice guy.
With his sudden spike in popularity,
he must be getting a lot of
offers and raking in the cash!
It's true, everyone!
DoDonPa never lies!
Detective Takagi!
Hey, Conan-kun.
Kogoro asked me to check
out the crime scene.
He seems to be really stuck on this case.
Did the suspect use this emergency
staircase to enter and exit the building?
Yeah.
The landlord hasn't seen anyone suspicious.
He was also wondering about the metal
pipe that was the murder weapon.
There was a construction site
on the way from Beika Station.
Apparently, it was brought from there.
Takagi-san!
Everyone spoke highly of the victim Tendo.
They said he's not the
type to extort someone.
But then...
That's totally different from
what DoDonPa-san said.
Yes, this is Takagi.
What?
You received a call from the suspect?
Yeah.
The police department just
received a call from the suspect,
saying Tendo had been extorting her.
Tendo wouldn't stop extorting me!
I couldn't take it anymore, so...
I understand how you feel,
but could you tell me your name?
Hello? Hello?
She called from a public phone,
and I already sent some investigators there.
Based on her language, though...
It's a woman.
Got it.
The culprit's a woman, huh?
It's a woman?
DoDonPa-san.
I thought I might be able to
help you find the murderer.
At this rate, Tendo-san won't
be able to rest in peace.
I think it'll be okay.
Nah. Kogoro said he already
knows who the true culprit is.
He said all he needed now was evidence.
Is that true, Conan-kun?
C-Can I believe you?
He is a great detective.
Y-You're right.
The Sleeping Kogoro is famous.
DoDonPa-san, you dropped
your pachinko parlor tissues.
Oh, thank you.
I can understand the suspect being a woman.
She must've been easy to extort.
What?
You mean the Kogoro Mouri-san?
He asked me to confirm with you.
He truly is a great detective.
He's right. It was the same every morning.
I even asked him why once.
You always come around this time,
a little before 8:00.
I have a habit of eating while watching
morning programs that start at 8:00.
The female announcer is so cute.
Oh, I see.
So you eat while watching
the female announcer.
I can see why he liked her so much.
Thanks, mister.
I knew it.
He always ate breakfast at the same time.
Huh? What?
Kogoro Mouri-san sent you here?
Studio
So, who's Kogoro Mouri-san?
He's a famous detective.
Really? Never heard of him.
In any case, if he's got questions,
tell him to come here himself
instead of sending a kid!
I see. She certainly is
detached from the world...
That's probably why he used
her to create his alibi.
Hey, Mouri-kun.
This is Megure.
Why'd you ask me to do this, Inspector?
What point is there in talking to her now?
Studio
What are you doing here?
Suda-san, you don't pay too much
attention to the time, do you?
I'm completely indifferent.
Once I enter my studio,
I don't stop painting.
When I get tired, I lie down over there.
That's my life.
So, about yesterday...
If you don't have a TV, radio, or cell phone,
that wall clock is your only way to tell time.
That's right.
That alone is enough for me.
Also...
Shut up.
I wanted to ask you about yesterday.
I already told the police.
Two nights ago, DoDonPa-kun called to say
he would stop by at 9:00 the next day,
and he came yesterday at exactly that time.
Did you confirm the time using that clock?
That's right. It was exactly
9:00, just like he said.
All right.
Now that we've confirmed that, let's leave!
Wait.
Yesterday, when the police came...
Who are you?
Were you sleeping?
...it seemed like you were sleeping.
Do you always take naps?
Yesterday was special.
I must've been really tired.
While chatting with DoDonPa-kun
and eating the cake he brought,
I started to feel tired.
I see.
Also...
I said we're leaving, you brat!
One more question.
Do you lock the door to the studio
when you sleep here at night?
Nope.
There's nothing here anyone
would want to steal.
Studio
Her story didn't leave any room for doubt.
What were you doing there?
What?
Um, I...
Something smells fishy.
What are you up to?
Thank you.
Paradise Hall?
Do the machines pay out well?
If they could talk,
they'd be begging you to stop.
This place is up ahead, right?
I'm on my way there now!
Thank you!
Hey, mister.
What is it, kid?
Were you handing out those tissues yesterday?
Yeah.
I started handing them out just
before 10:00 AM yesterday.
Did you give any to someone
you recognized from TV?
What?
Hey!
I heard he determined the
identity of the suspect.
You were called, too?
Yeah.
I received a call from
Mouri-san on my way to work.
Damn it. I didn't get anything.
Tendo Talent
Agency
That damn pachinko parlor.
Please stop? Yeah, right.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Mouri-kun.
Inspector, I heard you determined
the identity of the suspect.
What? You're the one who called me.
Th-This is the Sleeping
Kogoro I've heard about.
Now, then...
Let's discuss the truth behind
the murder of the talent
agency president Hideki Tendo.
We know a woman was being extorted.
Oh, you mean that phone call?
That was a trick the suspect pulled
to draw attention away from himself.
What?
The story about Tendo
extorting someone is a lie.
Isn't that right, DoDonPa-san?
After all, you're the one who killed Tendo.
Who, me?
You did turn yourself in for his murder.
We already determined his
confession was false.
I'm so sad.
You don't understand my desire
to protect Tendo-san's reputation
even if it meant bearing the guilt
of a murder I didn't commit.
It's not that I don't understand.
You didn't feel even a shred of that desire.
Then why would I turn myself in?
I have an alibi for yesterday at 9:00
when the president was murdered.
Right?
What? Uh, yeah.
That's why I was released.
He's right.
You're a vicious man...
...to manipulate a police investigation.
Yesterday morning,
you secretly came to Beika City
around 8:30.
You stole a metal pipe from
a deserted construction site,
hid it inside a club case,
and took the emergency staircase to
arrive at this office around 9:00.
Good morning! It's DoDonPa!
Good morning. You're early today.
Huh? Where's your guitar?
You ate breakfast this morning around
8:00 like you always do, didn't you?
Yeah.
What about it?
It's very important
for when they determine the time
of your death during the autopsy.
Wh-What are you doing with that?
After committing the crime, you hid
the weapon behind the apartment,
hurried back to Akebono City,
and visited Suda-san's studio...
...at 10:00 AM.
10:00 AM?
I visited her at 9:00!
Yeah.
Even Suda-san said it was 9:00.
She was sure of the time
because she checked her clock.
What if that clock were
running one hour slow?
Was it?
That's not possible.
We checked for ourselves
when we went to talk to her.
Yeah.
DoDonPa-san came right at 9:00.
He returned the clock to the correct time
before the police came to check on it.
But...
Two nights ago, you must have waited
for Suda-san to fall asleep
before breaking into her studio.
Suda-san, who is indifferent to time,
wouldn't notice if her clock
were running one hour behind.
Huh? Did I come at the wrong time?
What?
No, you're right on time.
Come on in.
You made Suda-san believe
you visited her at 9:00.
Additionally, you put sleeping pills
in the cake you brought for her.
What's wrong, Suda-sensei?
I'm sorry.
I suddenly feel so tired.
You must be exhausted.
You should rest.
I'll just let myself out.
Then you returned the
clock to the correct time.
That's why the clock was showing the
correct time when I went to check.
This will be the inspiration for
my next comic monologue, Mouri-san.
The detective's show of lies!
I'm sure everyone will love it!
Yesterday morning,
you got into an argument with
someone near Suda-san's studio.
I'm from Paradise Hall.
Thank you.
Hey, you're DoDonPa
Rokusuke-san, aren't you?
No!
Can I get your autograph?
You've got the wrong person!
It happened just before 10:00.
You had art books then,
so you must have returned them later.
I'm not the one who got into a fight.
There are plenty of other
people who have art books.
Are you sure?
We'll know the truth once we check
the prints on the art books.
I borrowed them from her!
Of course my prints are on them!
Not yours.
The fingerprints of the
man handing out tissues!
You've got the wrong person!
I'm sorry.
It's fine.
He looked just like him.
Uh, oh. It's almost 10:00.
His prints could only have gotten
on the books when he picked them up
after getting into an argument
with you, DoDonPa-san.
He visited Suda-san after their argument.
Not at 9:00, but at 10:00.
It's also unnatural for Suda-san to
suddenly feel tired after eating cake.
After creating your false alibi,
you headed back to Beika City.
You left Beika Station at 11:00.
You made the metal bat appear
to be the murder weapon,
and turned yourself in at
the police station at 11:30.
After turning yourself in for the murder,
you waited for the real murder weapon
and your alibi witness to be found,
so the police investigation
would remove suspicion from you.
You made us believe you were the suspect,
and then used us to clear you of suspicion.
Why would you do that, though?
He was trying to kill two
birds with one stone.
The press said
they learned you turned yourself
in for President Tendo's murder
from an anonymous tip.
However, at that time, the only person
who could've release that information...
is you, DoDonPa-san!
You're the only one who could've done it!
On your way to turn yourself in...
Apparently the comedian DoDonPa
Rokusuke-san turned himself in!
You told the reporters who
gathered your touching tale.
In order to protect the
reputation of Hideki Tendo,
I, DoDonPa Rokusuke,
wanted to be called his murderer.
You used your unexpected confession
to make the world believe
you were a good person and
become the center of attention.
Ding, ding, ding!
That's right!
The president was old fashioned.
He thought comedians should
only put on comedy shows.
Entertainers want to rake in the cash
doing anything they can, you know?
That's why I had him get out
of my way by disappearing
while killing for two birds with
one stone, just like you said!
I got exactly what I wanted!
The jobs came pouring in!
After all, my popularity's skyrocketing,
and I'm the man of the hour!
It's true, everyone.
DoDonPa never lies.
Don't be ridiculous!
What do you think a human life is worth?!
Yes, sir.
I told you I was really the killer.
I'm sorry.
DoDonPa doesn't lie? Yeah, right.
I'm not lying.
Our machines pay out so much,
they're begging our customers to stop.
You're full of lies, too!
Give 'em to me! Give me my balls!
A detective shouldn't fall
for such obvious lies.
Episode Preview
Keigo Himura.
What?
I'm what they call a romance novel author.
Ma'am, are you all right?! Ma'am!
The clear resounding sound of this voice...
Minazuki-sama!
The Romance Novel with the
Unexpected Conclusion
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is
“The Romance Novel with the
Unexpected Conclusion, Part One!"
Room Service
Next Conan's hint!
Room service!
I don't read romance novels!
Don't miss the next episode.
In the next episode,
romance turns into mystery!