The Red Woman was seriously scary!
Though, I guess it wasn't the actual
Red Woman who attacked us.
I know.
Who knows what would have happened
if Inspector Yamato and Inspector
Morofushi hadn't arrived?
I think we could've easily
subdued her without them.
You are super strong.
Do you do anything besides martial arts?
When I was little, I was
all about jeet kune do.
I'd watch and copy the videos my oldest
brother sent me until they wore out.
There was a dojo in my neighborhood, too.
I only dabbled in other sports
during PE classes at school.
But after I moved to
America in middle school,
I sometimes played other
sports with my friends.
There wasn't a dojo where I ended up, either.
Really?
I used to watch a lot of
sports with my mom on TV.
That's how I know Conan-kun's
pretty good at football.
Th-Thanks.
Is your mother still in America?
Yeah.
Because of that, I've been living alone
in a hotel since I returned to Japan.
I tried moving in with my middle brother
who's been living in Japan this whole time,
but he turned me down.
You're living in a hotel?
Are you sure you're not the
daughter of some rich family?
My dad's friend who's always
looked after me is rich.
He's not as rich as your family, though.
I don't have any other
relatives to depend on.
Once I get older, I know
I should pay him back.
If she has two brothers and doesn't
know any of her relatives,
then who is that young girl I saw on
her phone who looks just like her?
Hey, is that hotel around here?
Y-Yeah.
Do you mind if we stop by?
I'd like to see where you live, too.
Sure, I guess.
I should e-mail my brother, then.
I had actually promised to meet my brother.
Never mind, then.
It's okay.
I made my brother agree to meet me to
discuss the Red Woman case in person.
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
A popular author is confined
to his room in a hotel.
The romance novel becomes a mystery.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Romance Novel with the
Unexpected Conclusion
(Part One)
The Romance Novel with the
Unexpected Conclusion, Part One!
Wow.
This hotel has fifty floors.
It's still shorter than my family's
Bell Tree Tower, though.
Of course it is.
That's the tallest building in Japan.
I'm planning on moving soon anyway.
You are?
Who was that group of weird old men?
Apparently they're waiting for manuscripts
from a popular author living in this hotel.
I think his name was...
Hiura Keigo.
I'm what they call a romance novel author.
Hiura Keigo (48)
Author
What?
Um, I read your books.
Right now I'm really into "The
Phone, the Ocean, and I."
Thank you.
Not at all.
You can put those anywhere.
Yes, sir.
Excuse us.
Sure.
How about you guys?
Why don't you join me in my room for lunch?
Aren't you hungry?
But...
We came for the manuscripts.
The deadline is coming up.
Don't be so rigid.
I ordered too much food.
I can't eat all of this myself.
Maybe I'll get his autograph later.
You really did order a lot of food.
No wonder so many people were
coming in and out of your room.
I hadn't eaten lunch yet, so this is perfect.
Eat as much as you'd like.
Room service.
I brought your wine.
Oh, it's here.
Thank you for waiting.
This is it.
I've been waiting for this.
S-Sir!
Surely you don't intend to drink...
Could you pour it into a decanter over there?
Yes, of course, sir.
S-Sir!
I'd like to thank you for
everything you do for me.
Don't hold back. Eat up.
Okay...
O-Okay...
I'm thinking of finishing the manuscript
of whoever eats the most food first.
B-But...
How much we eat?
How will you measure that?
We'll measure your weight
before and after you eat.
I have a scale.
I'm from Beika Sushi!
Oh, it's here.
Th-There's more?
Yeah.
I have pizza, Chinese,
and donuts coming later.
I'm counting on you boys.
What?
While you're eating,
I'll take a bath and come up with ideas.
Keep a close eye on me...
so I can't sneak out of this
room to commit any mischief.
What a wonderful view.
I think I can see the curvature of the Earth.
This is the 30th floor...
Conan-kun.
That's the bedroom.
It's kind of a mess, so don't go in there.
Really?
If you want to see my dirty underwear,
you're welcome to go in there.
I think I'll pass...
Hey, why don't we order something
from room service like that author?
Great idea.
I was just starting to get hungry.
As promised, I'll finish the manuscripts
of whoever ate the most first.
You just wait.
Yes, sir.
I heard he was unusual...
But I didn't know it was that bad.
He had been down on his luck for a while,
but recently he's been as
popular as he used to be.
Isn't that thanks to the female
assistant he hired last year?
Yeah.
Minazuki Chiaki.
She got a room just below
Hiura-sensei's today, too.
I haven't seen her, though.
It's probably tough for her to
come up while we're all here.
A weekly magazine just wrote an
article saying they might be lovers.
Come to think of it, my department
received a threatening fax.
It said to get his new
assistant away from him.
We got that, too.
He used to be a handsome author.
I guess his female fans
are still in good health.
Kyogoku-san is so cute.
Isn't he?
I can't imagine a karate master saying that.
If he likes ramen so much...
Talking about relationships at
an all girls afternoon tea party.
I'm not sure I should be here.
Don't you have any stories, Conan-kun?
What?
Maybe one about a girl you
once met who you can't forget?
N-Not really...
I bet this kid is totally into Ayumi-chan.
What?!
No way.
I thought he liked Ai-chan.
What?!
Her?
What?
Which girl do you like?
Wh-Which girl?
We won't tell anyone, so tell us.
I'm curious.
It's you.
It's already 6 o'clock.
Oh, no.
I need to get home and start making dinner.
You got off lucky this time, kid.
See you later.
Thanks for today.
Sure.
H-Hey! Ma'am?!
Ma'am, are you all right?! Ma'am!
The clear resounding sound of this voice...
He's downstairs!
Hey, wait!
Wait, Ran!
Ma'am! Ma'am!
Are you all right, Minazuki-sama?!
Minazuki-sama!
The funicular marks on her neck suggest
she was strangled by some kind of rope.
She has scratches on her neck from
struggling while being strangled.
She was strangled to death.
Wh-Who are you two?
Her jaw is starting to stiffen.
It's been two or three hours since she died.
Minazuki-kun!
What's wrong?
What happened?
Sir!
There you are.
You said you were just going
out to get some cigarettes.
Minazuki-kun was collapsed
in the doorway of her room...
What?
You mean your assistant?
She was killed.
Someone strangled her to death.
What?
B-But why?
M-Maybe it has something
to do with that fax.
What?
This morning, my department received a fax.
If you don't fire the
assistant, you'll regret it.
It said we'd regret it if we
didn't fire his assistant.
Why didn't you tell me about that?!
You had plenty of opportunities to tell me!
A-Are you saying I was working on a romance
novel while this was happening to her?
Hmm?
I see.
The culprit...
...is this guy.
Champagne, huh?
When you came to deliver the
champagne that was ordered,
you discovered the body?
Y-Yes.
I was told to bring it at exactly 6 PM.
The key card was stuck in the
door and it was slightly ajar.
I wondered what had happened,
so I opened the door.
I found her on the floor.
Do we know who the victim is?
Yes.
Her name is...
Minazuki Chiaki.
She was my talented assistant.
I think she was turning thirty this year.
Um, who are you?
I'm the author Hiura Keigo.
I'm the one who ordered the champagne.
Really? You ordered the champagne?
Yes.
I'm occupying the room
directly above this one.
I was writing, but I thought I
would be finished around 6 o'clock.
I thought we could share a celebratory drink.
I never imagined this would happen
to her while I was writing.
Did you come here because
you finished writing?
No, I was having trouble
finishing the last pages.
About thirty minutes ago,
I went out to buy cigarettes for a change
of pace and wander around while thinking.
I bought cigarettes from the vending
machines in the elevator hall two floors down.
While climbing the stairs, I heard this
bellboy scream and came running.
You were just wandering around, right?
How did you know she was killed
while you were working on your book?
Huh?
She may have been killed just now.
Her jaw was beginning to stiffen
when her body was discovered.
I think it's been about two or
three hours since her death.
If you knew that without
even touching her body,
maybe you should switch to
being a mystery author instead?
Well?
Sh-She didn't come to my room.
She was supposed to bring documents
to my room a couple hours ago,
but she never came.
When I saw her body, I assumed she
couldn't come because she'd been killed.
So was she actually killed
two or three hours ago?
Yes.
According to the coroner,
her estimated time of death is two and a
half hours before her body was discovered.
She was strangled around 3:30 PM.
Isn't that around the time you
boys were eating in my room?
Yes.
We started just after 3 o'clock.
Who are you?
I'm Hiura-sensei's editor
at Nichiuri Publishing.
He ordered too much food,
so we were eating in his
room with two other editors.
Y-You were working on three manuscripts?
Yes.
Their deadlines conflicted.
I decided to finish the manuscripts of
the editors who ate the most food first.
Did Hiura-san eat with you?
No.
While we were eating, he went to
take a bath so he could think.
That's right.
Couldn't you have snuck
out of the room then?
That's not possible.
Several food deliveries arrived afterwards,
but we could clearly see the entryway from
the living room where we were eating.
We paid for the food,
so I don't think Hiura-sensei even
approached the doorway while we were eating.
How long were you eating?
Until around 4:30.
When we finished eating and left his room,
we could see the door to his room
while waiting for the elevators.
He only left the room to give his
finished manuscript to an editor.
He returned to his room
immediately afterwards.
I don't think he had a chance to sneak out.
Does that mean you finished three
manuscripts in a short amount of time?
Yes.
I had nearly finished all three of them.
But as I said earlier,
I was stuck on the last scene of "The Phone,
the Ocean, and I" which he works on.
After 5:30, I printed out everything
except the final pages to give to him,
and went to buy cigarettes.
I thought he could read it while he waited.
Right?
Yes.
He headed towards the stairs
with his wallet in his hand.
Not the elevators?
The stairs do more to inspire me.
It's good exercise, too.
While I was reading the manuscript,
I heard the bellboy shouting.
Hiura-sensei called to tell me
something had happened downstairs.
When I got here, you were all
standing in front of the room.
I see.
Can you think of anyone who may have
born a grudge against Minazuki-san?
It's the threatening fax!
The culprit must be whoever sent that!
The threatening fax?
It arrived this morning at
my editorial department.
It said, "If you don't fire the
assistant, you'll regret it."
We did check the sender, but
it was a convenience store.
Why was she being threatened, though?
It's because a weekly magazine printed
pictures of us walking around town together,
with the caption that we might be lovers!
Because of it, my wife went
back to her parents' house.
Nearly all his works are
about pure and genuine love.
He has many female fans
who despise adultery.
What was your relationship with
Minazuki-san actually like?
There was nothing between us!
She was a great assistant
with plenty of ideas.
She worked so hard on "The
Phone, the Ocean, and I."
You could practically call it her work.
I was thinking of letting her become
an independent writer next year.
But why?
Why her?
Let the police handle this.
Conan-kun and Sera-san, you can leave now.
We might question some witnesses later.
Okay.
What happened?
There was a murder?
A murder?
What?
Whoa. Look at this crowd.
When did they get here?
Excuse me. Let me through, please.
Where is she?
Where did she go?
Why are you scowling like that, Conan-kun?
Did you see a girl?
What? A girl?
Sonoko, did you see one?
I don't know.
She was here in this crowd.
A middle school aged girl
who looks just like Sera!
A middle school student
who looks like Sera-san?
But she said she doesn't have a sister.
Maybe you were mistaken.
It wasn't a mistake. She was there.
There was a picture of a girl who
looks like Sera on her phone, too.
Who is she?
What? No way!
The author Hiura-san is the suspect?
I-Is it true?
Yeah, probably.
But I thought he had an alibi.
He was in his room with his
editors watching over him.
Yeah.
In order to break his alibi down,
I need to come up with a way to get
into the victim's room one floor below.
We're thirty floors up.
Using a rope to climb down from
the balcony would be pretty scary.
If the editors could see the entryway from
where they were eating in the living room,
then they must have been able
to see the balcony, too.
Right, Conan-kun?
H-Huh?
Don't you agree?
Y-Yeah.
Oh, no!
I forgot to make dinner!
I'd better call my dad!
Uh, oh. Mouri-san must be fuming.
He's pretty scary when he's upset over food.
Hey, Dad?
Sorry.
I was visiting Sera-san's place,
and something happened...
I'm not lying.
The caps for the shampoo and
conditioner are missing?
Episode Preview
We came in through the main entrance.
Did you knock over the table, too?
There were lots of people
bringing delivery food, right?
Y-Yeah.
How did I move the body from
this room to the one below?
That's right. That was his goal.
The Romance Novel with the
Unexpected Conclusion
(Part Two)
The next episode is "The Romance Novel
with the Unexpected Conclusion, Part Two!"
An Old Letter
Next Conan's hint!
An old letter!
Don't miss the next episode.
Does Sera-san really bother you that much?
There you go again, you precocious brat.
It's not like that.