Detective Conan Episode 760 "The Romance
Novel with the Unexpected Conclusion (Part 2)"
Ran, Sonoko, and I went to hang out
with Sera at the hotel she lives in.
On our way home, a homicide
occurred on a lower floor.
Hiura Keigo (48)
Author
M-Maybe it has something
to do with that fax.
This morning, my department received a fax.
If you don't fire the
assistant, you'll regret it.
It said we'd regret it if we
didn't fire his assistant.
Why didn't you tell me about that?!
You had plenty of opportunities to tell me!
I see.
The culprit...
...is this guy.
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
The contents of the novel
bring us closer to the case.
Who is the girl who looks like Sera?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Romance Novel with the
Unexpected Conclusion
(Part Two)
The Romance Novel with the
Unexpected Conclusion, Part Two!
It's Takagi.
There's something I wanted
to confirm with you.
What?
The caps for the shampoo and
conditioner are missing?
The ones from the victim's room?
Yeah.
They're amenities that
come with the bathroom.
We couldn't find them in the drain, either.
We only entered the main entrance.
Then you weren't the ones
who knocked over the table?
The table?
Most of the room was undisturbed, but
somehow just the table was knocked over.
A can of beer that we believe
was sitting on top of it
had fallen on top of the victim's suitcase.
The victim's clothes inside the
suitcase are covered in beer.
What kind of suitcase is it?
It was pretty big.
There wasn't much inside it, though.
What was inside the suitcase?
In addition to clothes, we found
makeup, a tablet, and a backpack.
Oh, right.
There was an old postcard in one of
the backpack's inside pockets, too.
An old...
...postcard?
What a cute story.
When I write
a story like this,
maybe I'll name the
heroine after you.
Hiura Keigo
Yeah.
It was postmarked twenty years ago.
The sender was Hiura-sensei.
It says, "What a cute story.
When I write a story like this, maybe
I'll name the heroine after you."
But it's addressed to Ota
Jun, not Mizunashi Chiaki.
Ota Jun-sama
O-Ota Jun?
That's the heroine's name from Hiura-sensei's
"The Phone, the Ocean, and I."
The Phone, The Ocean, and I
Hiura Keigo
Really?
Yeah.
What is it about?
One day, the heroine finds an old
scratched up cell phone on the beach.
Strangely enough,
the phone is a new, unreleased model she
was planning to buy the following week.
While she's looking at the phone, she
receives an e-mail asking how old she is.
How old are you?
Sounds dangerous.
Thinking the same thing,
the heroine responds, "I won't tell
you my personal information, idiot!"
She receives the response "You started
talking like that in high school.
That brings back memories."
The sender correctly guesses
a bunch of other things, too,
like the results of that day's
soccer or baseball games.
I-I-Is it...?
That's right.
Someone is sending her messages with a time
transference device using her future phone.
A time transference device?
Yeah.
It's basically a time machine.
When the heroine learns the world becomes
a mess a few years in the future,
she begins changing the future
little by little to prevent it.
Really? That sounds kind of interesting.
Doesn't it?
Anyway, the heroine asks the person,
"Who are you? What is your
relationship with me?"
But they always answer
"The phone, the ocean, and I."
Huh? What the heck?
What does that mean?
The heroine thought it was gibberish at
first, but she finally figured it out recently.
She responds to the sender with
"The phone, the ocean, and I."
The phone, the ocean, and I.
What?
The answer is finally going to be
revealed in next week's final chapter.
I can't wait.
He's a bold writer, though.
He doesn't have any time left,
but he invited the editors watching him
into his room for lunch to win them over.
If I were in his situation,
I would probably shave my head in
desperation and ask for more time.
Of course, he already has a shaved head.
Did the writer already go back to his room?
No.
Since he's a suspect,
we're having him wait in front of his
room until forensics is finished.
Then they should still be in his hand.
Huh? What is?
The alibi trick and misprint error...
...that failed to revise this crime novel.
Give me a break!
How long are you going to
keep searching my room?
You won't find anything!
The body was found in her
room directly below this one,
and she was killed around 3:30 PM, right?
I was in this room at that time, and
I even have people vouching for me!
Tell them!
Y-Yes, sir.
From 3:00 until around 4:30,
I was eating in Hiura-sensei's room.
He was taking a bath at the
time and didn't eat with us,
but there's no way he could
have gotten out of this room.
We were eating at the
table facing the entrance.
But if he had a rope, he could climb
down from the balcony to the room below.
Don't be ridiculous.
This is the 30th floor.
I'm not 007.
A simple author like myself
could never pull that off.
Besides, you can see the
balcony from the table, too.
Y-You're right.
If you want to take any
more of my personal time,
you'll have to tell me how I got out of here
when the crime was committed
and how I got back up.
There was no need for
you to leave or return.
You invited the victim to this
room and killed her here.
Th-The victim was in this room?
Wh-What are you talking about?
The editors would have noticed
Minazuki-kun coming to this room!
They recognize her face!
She didn't come here, did she?!
N-No.
Yeah, but...
Huh?
There were lots of people
bringing delivery food, right?
Y-Yeah.
I think anyone would be
fooled if Minazuki-san
disguised herself as a delivery person
and changed her hairstyle.
M-Maybe, but everyone
left once we paid them.
Really?
Then what about the wine
on top of that desk?
If you ordered a decanter,
it wouldn't be strange for the delivery
person to enter the room, right?
N-Now that you mention it,
Hiura-sensei asked the person who delivered
the wine to pour it into a decanter.
It was a bellhop wearing glasses
with her hair tied back.
A bellhop?
Did you see that bellhop leave the room?
N-No...
We were too busy eating.
Yes.
That's what he wanted.
What?
If you had been waiting outside,
you would've checked how many people
entered and how many left, right?
Hiura-sensei may have tried to escape
disguised as a delivery person.
But once he invited you into the room,
you stopped checking as diligently.
No matter who entered, you just had
to make sure Hiura-sensei didn't leave.
That's why it didn't bother you that
the bellhop who brought the wine
entered the room and never came back.
Was the bellhop Minazuki-san, then?
Yeah.
While the editors were
eating in the living room,
he told the victim to go to the
bathroom and killed her there.
He probably chose the bathroom since she
would take off her bellhop clothes herself.
The body was wearing a bathrobe which
would be easy to put on someone.
B-But why did the victim
disguise herself as a bellhop?
She's his assistant. She could have
stopped by without hesitation.
Because they were suspected of being lovers.
If the editors saw her enter, who knows
what the magazines would write next?
He asked her to do it.
What an interesting trick.
I'd like to use it if I ever
write a mystery novel.
Tell me one thing, though.
How did I move the body from
this room to the one below?
I left this room around 5:30 PM,
thirty minutes before the bellboy
discovered the body downstairs.
Was I carrying a body then?
N-No.
You were only holding your wallet.
What were you doing between the time I
left and the bellboy started shouting?
I-I was reading the manuscript you
had written in front of your room.
Unfortunately, I can't write your mystery.
It's full of holes.
Yeah, sure.
We're ready now. Do it, Detective Takagi.
T-Takagi?
Inspector Megure!
Something just fell on the
balcony from the floor above.
What?
The balcony?
Th-This is...
A suitcase!
Why did this fall from upstairs?
Inspector!
Open the suitcase!
What is he doing?
T-Two bags of rice?
Each bag is thirty kilograms.
All together, that's sixty kilograms.
That's roughly the weight of one person.
D-Did he put the body in a suitcase?
Yeah.
Climbing down on a rope would be scary,
but passing a rope through the handle
of a suitcase containing the
body and lowering it is easy.
You can swing the suitcase
onto the balcony below.
If you don't tie the rope to the handle,
you can pull it back up by one of the ends.
Which means the suitcase
in the victim's room...
He brought it to move the body.
The backpack inside the suitcase
was probably her actual luggage.
He removed the contents and
stuffed her inside the suitcase.
I see.
In other words,
Hiura-sensei strangled the victim in the
bathroom after inviting her to his room,
stuffed her inside the suitcase naked,
waited for the editors to finish and leave,
and lowered the suitcase containing her
body to the room below from the balcony.
Then he handed out the finished
manuscripts to the waiting editors,
and said he would think about how to finish
his book while buying cigarettes around 5:30.
He entered the victim's room using
the room key he stole from her,
dressed her in a bathrobe, and
placed her body near the entrance.
The bellboy instructed
to deliver champagne
to her room at exactly 6:00
discovered her body for him.
He spilled beer inside the suitcase
to cover the wetness and smell.
He hastily stuffed the body inside the
suitcase before her hair had dried.
It was probably wet and
smelled like shampoo.
Why didn't he dry her hair before
putting her inside the suitcase?
Surely he had the time.
Of course he wouldn't dry it.
The editors would've thought it strange
if they heard the sound of the hair dryer.
I see.
He has a shaved head.
Hiura-sensei took the caps off the bottles
in the victim's room for the same reason.
You had to replace the caps the victim
washed down the drain after she used yours.
After all, there's no reason
for you to use shampoo.
So you may still have them.
The shampoo and conditioner caps.
Assuming you didn't throw
them away on your way here.
Even if you did,
a bellhop uniform was
found inside a paper bag
in the garbage can in the elevator
hall on the floor below.
What? How did it get there?
His hands were empty when he left his room.
He was wearing them underneath
the clothes he's wearing now.
He took them off on the
landing, put them in a bag,
and threw them away before
the body was discovered.
You should find sweat, skin,
and fingerprints from the victim and
Hiura-san on the bellhop uniform.
I just couldn't throw them away.
I was worried someone might be watching.
You admit you did it, then?
Yes.
I tried to get away with it by
sending the threatening fax,
but I'm not a mystery writer after all.
B-But why?
She was a talented assistant.
You said she had revived your career!
Yes, that's right.
Without her, I can't write another line.
Th-Then why?
Was she actually your lover and
demanding you get divorced?
No. It was the opposite.
What?
No matter how many times I approached her,
she would always say it would upset my wife.
She took a bath because
I told her she smelled.
The Phone, the Ocean, and I
She came to my room to discuss my novel,
Hiura Keigo
the final scene of "The
Phone, the Ocean, and I."
Then... Then that novel...
Yes.
That's right.
She came up with most of the story.
It was based on an old fan letter.
You can't even call it my work.
A fan letter?
Yes.
While cleaning, I discovered an old fan
letter from a grade school student.
I decided to write a novel
based on the included story,
using Ota Jun, the name of the
sender, as the name of my heroine.
It began when I told her about the letter.
She asked me to let her choose the title.
She would meticulously revise my writing.
She made the novel
spectacular, but I didn't
understand why she worked so hard on it.
Every time I asked, she would smile
and say I would understand eventually.
Then a weekly magazine
accused us of being lovers.
That was when I became certain!
This woman intended to steal my family,
my status, my honor, and my money from me
and destroy me completely!
B-But why would she do that?
Who knows?
I used to be quite the
playboy when I was younger.
I must have done something
to make her hate me.
Honestly, I'm relieved you caught me.
Though I meant to reveal the meaning
of "The Phone, the Ocean,
and I" in the final scene,
I killed her before I could
ask her what it meant.
It means "I love you."
What?
Phone                     Ocean                        I
If you translate the words
"telephone," "sea,"
and "I" into English
and read them backwards,
you get "I sea tel."
Maybe the heroine's boyfriend or
husband was sending her messages
from the future on the phone.
Th-There's no way a child's
explanation could be...
It can't be helped.
After all, it was a child who
originally came up with the code.
Similarly, if you look at Minazuki Chiaki,
Minazuki > June
Chiaki > Autumn
"minazuki" is another word for
the sixth month, or "June".
The "aki" from Chiaki is "Autumn".
If you read them backwards, you
get Autumn Jun, or Ota Jun.
Ota Jun
Th-Then... was she...?
I see. Ota Jun was her pen name.
Once you learned the meaning of
"The Phone, the Ocean, and I,"
you would realize that, too.
B-But...
No...
Maybe she just wanted you to make
her childhood dream come true
in the best way possible.
"I love you," huh?
I see.
Her boyfriend was sending her
messages from the future.
Yeah.
That's what Sera-no-neechan said.
But couldn't it have been a stalker?
No way!
Don't ruin it by saying something weird.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Uh, nothing.
It's nothing.
A listening device?
It's from the end of his glasses.
That was close.
I've never seen one like this.
Based on the size of its battery,
it probably doesn't last long.
But this form and performance...
How fascinating.
Well? Do you like him?
I'm still a long way from trusting him,
but if he tires of waiting and
asks you about me, tell him this.
That I'm his sister from another domain.
Episode Preview
We're in Kanazawa.
You wish to challenge the
great detective Mouri Kogoro?
I accept.
Thief!
Did you notice anything?
Kaga Hyakumangoku Mystery
Tour (Kanazawa Arc)
The next episode of Conan is "Kaga
Hyakumangoku Mystery Tour, Kanazawa Arc!"
Shoulder Bag
Next Conan's hint!
A shoulder bag!
Next week we're all going to Kanazawa!
Don't miss the next episode.
I'm excited for the Kagawa hot springs!
Don't cause any trouble.
Okay.