Detective Conan 761 "Kaga Hyakumangoku
Mystery Tour (Kanazawa Part)"
We traveled to Kanazawa.
Look, Conan-kun.
Tsuzumi Gate
Isn't that the Tsuzumi Gate?
It's shaped just like a drum.
Yeah. It's bigger than I thought.
Mori-san!
Someone asked Kogoro for help with
the "Kaga Hyakumangoku Mystery Tour"
city revitalization event.
Welcome to Kanazawa
Kanazawa is Nice
This is Kanazawa
Nice to meet you.
I'm Tanimoto Yuzo from the tourism agency.
I look forward to working with you today.
Tanimoto Yuzo (57)
Tourism Agency Employee
Miyazawa Moeko (27)
I'm Miyazawa Moeko,
another employee of the tourism agency.
I'm Tadokoro Yuya. I run an event company.
Tadokoro Yuya (48)
Event Company President
Kuranishi Osamu (33)
Event Company Employee
I'm Kuranishi Osamu. I work for the company.
I'm Akiyama Harumi.
I also work for the company.
Akiyama Harumi (29)
Event Company Employee
I am the great detective Mori Kogoro.
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
A mystery event in Kanazawa.
The mysteries are as big as Hyakumangoku.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kaga Hyakumangoku Mystery
Tour (Kanazawa Arc)
Tour, Kanazawa Arc!
The event takes place in Kanazawa and Kaga.
Participants travel to various
checkpoints while collecting clues
to discover the truth behind a
certain case and expose the culprit.
Checkpoints, huh?
Yes.
We've chosen several tourist spots in
Kanazawa and Kaga for checkpoints.
I see.
Participants can go sightseeing
while solving the mystery.
Yes.
Participants solve the mystery by cracking
the code they receive at each checkpoint.
That sounds kind of fun.
Doesn't it?
Akiyama's already come up with the codes.
We'd like you to come up with a story
to serve as the backdrop for the codes.
What?
We're calling it:
"A Challenge from the Great
Detective Mori Kogoro!"
I see.
I understand.
Leave it to me.
I, Mori Kogoro,
have solved countless cases before now.
I'll prepare an exceptional case for you!
We do have one suggestion.
We were thinking of having
you solve the codes
as we visit each checkpoint so you could
get a grasp of the event's atmosphere.
How does that sound?
I see...
You wish to challenge the
great detective Mori Kogoro?
Very well.
I accept.
All the famous tourist spots we've chosen
for checkpoints are in this guidebook.
Thank you.
This is the code for the first checkpoint.
We're starting already?
Let me see.
Kagami no yu no mae de
(NOMITORI) taiken
"Kagami no yu no mae de nomitori taiken?"
What is this?
Except "nomitori" is written
with different characters.
Nomitori, nomitori, nomi...
I know!
"Nomitori" means we should remove the
letters "no" and "mi" from the sentence!
Let's see. If you remove
"no" and "mi," you get...
"Kaga yu mae de taiken."
"An experience in front of Kaga-yu!"
"Kaga-yu" must refer to the Kaga hot springs.
We're going to experience something in
front of those hot springs, aren't we?
Wait a second, Dad.
Kaga has four major hot springs.
There's Yamanaka Hot Springs,
Yamanaka Hot Springs
Katayamazu Hot Springs
Katayamazu Hot Springs,
Awazu Hot Springs
Awazu Hot Springs,
and Yamashiro Hot Springs.
Yamashiro Hot Springs
They're all pretty far apart from each other.
And only "mae" is written in kanji, right?
Maybe it's a trick of some kind.
Our preconceptions make us read it as "mae,"
but it can be read as "zen," too.
"Zen?"
Which means it's "Kaga yu zentaiken."
It's "Kaga Yuzen experience!"
The Kaga Yuzen experience is available at...
Here it is!
The Kaga Yuzen Traditional Industry Center.
You can experience Kaga Yuzen here.
That's correct.
You're quite the detective.
Even your assistants are excellent.
They certainly are.
You're slacking, old man.
Kaga Yuzen Traditional Industry Center
The clothes make the woman.
You look wonderful.
That looks great on you.
I don't look that nice.
Akiyama-san, your watch.
How fashionable of you to
wear a larger men's watch.
Oh, this?
I'm not wearing it to be fashionable.
I got it from my older brother.
I'd actually prefer a more feminine one,
but I can't afford it.
Thank you.
This is the next checkpoint's code.
Normally the participants would
receive their first hint now.
I see.
I understand.
What's the next code?
OOOO taiken
"Something something taiken?"
I guess four characters
go in the four circles.
Free experience, bungee experience...
Is it "supernatural experience"?
Give me a break, Dad!
I figured it out.
The four circles stand for "wagashi."
Maybe it says "Japanese sweets experience."
I see.
Where can we experience Japanese sweets?
Here's one.
The Ishikawa Prefectural Museum
for Traditional Products.
That's correct.
Well done, kid.
We didn't need a great
detective to solve this one.
You're absolutely right.
Can't you be more considerate?
You're making me lose face.
But...
Thief!
There!
Damn it!
You'll pay for this!
Whoa.
Idiot.
Are you hurt, miss?
No. Thank you.
I appreciate your help.
Thank you so much.
Are you all right, Mori-san?
Yes, of course.
What an insolent guy, though.
Next time we run into him, let's catch him.
Kanazawa should be a safe place.
Look this way.
I'll take the next one.
Is it just my imagination?
I thought I felt someone watching me.
Ishikawa Prefectural Museum
of Traditional Products
of Traditional Arts and Crafts
Handmade Japanese
Sweets Experience
Ishikawa Prefectural Museum of Traditional Arts and Crafts
Ishikawa Prefectural Art Museum
Okay, smile.
Yeah!
It's that couple again.
We keep running into them.
Could it be?
We're going to get lunch
at Oumicho Market now.
Oumicho Market
I'm currently at the Komatsu Hikiyama
Exchange Hall Miyossa in Komatsu City.
Komatsu Hikiyama Exchange Hall Miyossa
What? Kuranishi-san and
Akiyama-san, you're engaged?
Yes.
We plan on getting married next spring.
The Hokuriku Shinkansen's
opening at the same time.
That's great news.
You did well while I wasn't watching.
Our company doesn't prohibit
workplace relationships.
Hey, Miyazawa-san.
What is it?
Why have you been carrying
that heavy looking bag?
You could've left it on the bus.
What? Um, this is...
Is there something important inside it?
Conan-kun, it's rude to ask a
woman what she has in her bag.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
It's fine.
And now our next story.
After four years,
the man suspected of assaulting
an elderly person living alone,
and stealing five million yen on May 6, 2010, in Kanazawa was arrested yesterday.
The man denies he committed the crime,
but the Ishikawa Police have charged the man
with robbery and are investigating the crime.
According to the police investigation...
He doesn't look like a bad
person from his mugshot.
Don't be fooled.
Those who don't are most
likely to be the culprit.
But it would be a disaster
if the charges are false.
It would ruin the life of the accused.
What's wrong, Akiyama-san?
What? Um...
Are you all right?
Yes. It's nothing.
This is good!
These would be great with liquor!
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Huh? Oh.
I was just thinking there's
so much delicious food.
You're right.
That couple doesn't seem to be here.
Did you really look for it?
Yes, but I couldn't find it.
I probably dropped it somewhere.
Is something wrong?
Yeah.
Akiyama-san lost the cards with the codes.
Now that you mention it,
we still haven't received the
code for the next checkpoint.
I remember the code, though.
I'll make new ones right away. It'll be fine.
Sheesh.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Mori-san, I'm sorry you have to
use these handwritten cards.
This is the next checkpoint's code.
Let me see.
I'm not letting you see these anymore.
One, zero...
One thousand fifty... sword...
Sword, five, six...
Hey, Ran. Let me see that guidebook.
This is it!
1056 stands for "Togoro!"
The "G" stands for "gold!"
The sword stands for the
"ken" in "Kenroku-en!"
In other words, it's the Kinjo
Reitaku at the Kenroku-en Garden!
That's correct.
That was amazing, Dad.
Well done.
Wow. The old man's starting
to get the hang of this.
That's how I do it!
But who's "Togoro"?
Kanazawa Shrine
Long ago,
a man known as Togoro the
Potato Digger discovered gold
while washing potatoes
in a mountain stream.
Kinjo Reitaku
This place was called Kanazawa because
he discovered gold in the stream.
That's why the code
featured Togoro and gold.
I'm impressed you knew that, Dad.
Every adult knows about it.
Let's head towards the Kenroku-en Garden.
Akiyama and I have something to discuss.
We'll catch up later.
I'll go with you.
Kuranishi, do you want to be
with your girlfriend that badly?
No. I don't mix business and romance.
Kenroku-en Garden
This is the next code.
Huh? What's this?
It's a bunch of pictures this time.
Looks like he's stumped this time.
This one's a diamond, and this
one looks like an arrowhead.
A diamond, an arrowhead, and a saddle.
Hishi, ya, kura...
Isn't the Hishi Yagura
turret at Kanazawa Castle?
You're right!
There's a place called the Hishi
Yagura at Kanazawa Castle!
That's correct.
Really?
Kanazawa Castle is right in the area.
Kanazawa Castle
This is the next card.
This is the final one.
I see.
You're wrong, Akiyama-san.
That's not the last one.
I'm sorry. My mistake.
It's fine.
Do you notice anything?
This one's quite simple.
24 minus 3 is 21.
21...
The Kanazawa 21st Century Museum!
That's correct.
There wasn't anything to notice.
It's just simple subtraction.
He's right.
Don't you think this one's too easy?
I'm sorry.
I couldn't come up with anything else.
We're a little behind schedule.
Let's head to the 21st Century Museum.
You'll pay for what you did!
How dare you get in my way?!
You're the purse snatcher!
Wait!
Are you all right, Mori-san?
Move!
Stop!
Wait!
Hey, wait!
Please wait!
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Ouch.
You didn't tell me he was
that strong, Miyazawa-san.
Stop!
What?
What's going on here?
There's one more person hiding over there.
That's the woman whose bag was stolen.
But what does Miyazawa-san have
to do with the victim and thief?
It was all staged.
The couple was taking pictures of
us and Miyazawa-san was filming,
using a camera inside her bag, right?
I'm sorry.
It was actually a prank to promote the event.
A prank?
Yes.
This couple is our cameraman and assistant.
The thief and woman are actors
we hired to act out an incident.
Akiyama-san and I were secretly filming you.
Akiyama-san, too?
Mori-san, we've been looking for...
I'm sorry. They found out.
What is the meaning of this?
I'm sorry.
We'll explain the situation.
Let's head back to the castle.
Akiyama-san?
Harumi?
Harumi!
Quickly! Call an ambulance!
Got it!
H-Hey! Don't film this!
This isn't staged! It's for real!
What?
It's not a prank? Then why is Akiyama-san...
It doesn't look like a robbery.
If she was attacked
randomly by a passerby,
there should be other victims.
Which means the murderer specifically
wanted to kill Akiyama-san.
What's going on?
Episode Preview
Ran, tell them.
What? But...
Being so shaken makes you
seem more suspicious.
Hey, hey.
This fell out of Akiyama-san's bag.
I see. That's how it is.
To prevent anyone from escaping, Ran...
Kaga Hyakumangoku Mystery
Tour (Kaga Hot Springs Arc)
The next episode is "Kaga Hyakumangoku
Mystery Tour, Kaga Hot Springs Arc!"
Code Card
Next Conan's hint!
The code cards!
Don't miss the next episode.
It's finally time for hot springs!
You have to do your job first.
Maybe the hot springs will be a prank, too.