We came to Kanazawa to help with
a city revitalization event
called the "Kaga
Hyakumangoku Mystery Tour."
We were solving riddles
and visiting checkpoints like participants
would during the actual event when...
Thief!
Damn it!
You'll pay for this!
However, the thief reappeared later
and attacked Kogoro-no-occhan,
but it was all actually
part of an event PR prank.
Immediately afterward...
Akiyama-san.
Harumi?
Harumi!
Quickly! Call an ambulance!
Got it!
H-Hey! Don't film this!
This isn't staged!
It's for real!
What?
It's not a prank?
Then why is Akiyama-san...
It doesn't look like a robbery.
If she was attacked
randomly by a passerby,
there should be other victims.
Which means the murderer specifically
wanted to kill Akiyama-san.
What's going on?
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
The filming of a prank turns into a case.
Kogoro solves the case
while taking a footbath.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kaga Hyakumangoku Mystery Tour
(Kaga Hot Springs Arc)
Kaga Hyakumangoku Mystery
Tour, Kaga Hot Springs Arc!
Akiyama Harumi (29)
Event Company Employee
Wait! Akiyama-san's bag!
This is...
We'd like someone to come with us.
Ran, go with her.
What?
But shouldn't her fiancée
Kuranishi-san stay with her instead?
They still have work to do.
She'll be fine.
Kuranishi Osamu (33)
Event Company Employee
We should keep visiting the checkpoints.
Miyazawa Moeko (27)
Tourism Agency Employee
Is that all right?
Very well.
Tanimoto Yuzo (57)
Tourism Agency Employee
He's right. Kuranishi-kun may
be worried about her, but...
Tadokoro Yuya (48)
Event Company President
Take care of Akiyama, Ran-san.
I will.
See you later.
Does the old man suspect
one of these guys, too?
He sent Ran to prevent anyone from escaping.
Kanazawa 21st Century Museum
How did this happen?
Don't worry.
I'm sure Akiyama will be fine.
Um, shouldn't we inform the police?
We can wait to call the police until
after we see how Akiyama-san's doing.
G-Give me a break!
I didn't do it!
I just don't want to involve the police
in a way that will affect the event...
We know, Tanimoto-san.
No one said you did it.
Being so shaken makes you
seem more suspicious.
Hey, now.
Hey, mister...
What?
Could I see the handwritten
card Akiyama-san gave you?
You mean this?
Thanks.
I'm going to the bathroom.
These things that fell
out of Akiyama-san's bag
were probably the cards
she prepared beforehand.
Why did Akiyama-san lie about losing
the cards and write new ones?
This is our next story.
The assault of an elderly person and
theft of five million yen in cash
that occurred on May 6, 2010...
I see. That's how it is!
That person probably attacked Akiyama-san.
But I don't have the evidence to prove it.
The next location is the final checkpoint.
We don't have the code because
of what happened to Akiyama-san,
so I'll just tell you.
Yamashiro Hot Spring Old Public Bath
The next checkpoint is Yamashiro
hot spring's Iroha Soan.
Rosan Jingu-Kyo Remains Iroha Soan
Now then...
We've visited all the checkpoints.
During the actual event,
participants would have acquired all the
hints necessary to solve the mystery by now.
The participants will use the
hints to determine the culprit.
Well, Mori-san?
Have you come up with any good ideas?
W-Well, I...
This is a beautiful garden, isn't it?
Hey, mister.
If they're using the film they
took during the prank for PR,
shouldn't we go over it?
You're right.
Could we do that?
Yes, of course.
Thief!
Damn it!
You'll pay for this!
Idiot.
Are you all right, Mori-san?
Yes, of course.
What an insolent guy, though.
Kanazawa should be a safe place.
Tanimoto-san, you're looking
right at the camera.
Well, I am from the tourism agency.
You'll pay for what you did!
Hey! You're the purse snatcher!
Wait!
Harumi?
Harumi!
Quickly! Call an ambulance!
Got it!
H-Hey! Don't film this!
This isn't staged!
It's for real!
What?
It's no use.
I wonder how Akiyama-san's doing.
I'll ask Ran.
Kanazawa East Hospital
Take care.
Thank you.
Hello, Dad?
I see.
Akiyama-san's injury wasn't
that serious, then.
To be safe, they're going to keep her at the
hospital for a day and examine her brain.
Got it.
I'm glad it wasn't serious.
Mister, let me talk to her.
Hello, Ran-neechan.
Conan-kun?
Huh?
The reception's not very good.
Hello? Hello?
Ran, I need a favor.
What? Dad?
Okay.
Yeah.
Huh?
Got it.
That's what you want me to do, right?
Okay. Bye.
Thanks. You can have this back.
You shouldn't run away with someone's
phone without their permission.
What is it, Ran?
You still have something to—
What? Akiyama-san escaped
from the hospital?!
What?
Did Harumi escape from the hospital?
Yes.
She disappeared while Ran left
the room to take my call.
She left a note saying she had to go
to Yamashiro to confess something.
She's coming here.
Kuranishi, have you tried calling Akiyama?
Yes, but she won't answer her e-mails.
I can't reach her by calling, either.
I wonder what she wants to confess.
Probably that she saw the
culprit's face or something.
In any case, let's split up and look for her.
Don't be hasty. Let's talk.
Where are you?
I'm waiting at the spring footbath.
Do you know where the scissors
that were here went?
I don't know.
This way!
Ran?
What's going on?
My dad told me to disguise myself as
Akiyama-san and draw out the culprit.
Ran-san, I...
Don't think.
Just rest for now.
I'm going to borrow your
smart phone and coat.
Wait. I didn't...
Why you...
It's back.
Uh, oh.
Mister, you should take off your shoes
before putting your feet in the bath.
Yes.
I did instruct her to do that.
Then where's Harumi?
She's asleep in her hospital room.
Hey, Kuranishi!
Did you attack Akiyama?!
Why would you do that?!
Allow me to explain instead.
I first noticed Akiyama-san
wasn't wearing her watch
when she was carried away on the stretcher.
Until just before that
moment, Akiyama-san...
We're a little behind schedule.
Let's head to the 21st Century Museum.
Because it wasn't anywhere
at the crime scene,
I could only assume the culprit took it.
But why?
Then I remembered what Miyazawa-san said.
Akiyama-san and I were secretly filming you.
Was Akiyama-san's hidden
camera inside her watch?
That's right.
She actually had a tiny
camera inside her watch.
Kuranishi-san,
you must have remembered the same thing
immediately after committing the crime.
Perhaps the camera had recorded the crime.
Thinking this,
while pretending to check Akiyama-san's
pulse, you stole her watch.
Quickly! Call an ambulance!
When Conan said he wanted to see
the film you had secretly taken,
I watched the footage carefully,
thinking the moment Kuranishi-san
removed her watch may have been recorded,
but it wasn't.
As a last resort,
I had Ran pretend to be Akiyama-san.
Kuranishi, was it really you?
Why?
Akiyama's your fiancée!
He did it to silence her regarding the
incident that occurred four years ago.
Silence her?
Yes.
The assault of an elderly person and
theft of five million yen in cash
that was on the news this afternoon.
What does that four-year-old
incident have to do with this one?
Akiyama-san herself told
me using those cards.
What?
The code cards?
After hearing the news,
Akiyama-san said she lost her
cards and wrote new ones.
However, she hadn't lost the cards.
Conan picked them up at the crime scene
after they fell out of Akiyama-san's bag.
These are the original cards,
and these are the new ones.
As you can see,
the three cards she wrote
by hand are different
from the ones she prepared beforehand.
I thought perhaps the three
codes had a different meaning,
in addition to indicating
the checkpoint locations.
In date format, the numbers
1056 from the first code
can be read as May 6, 2010.
Additionally, the G and sword can simply
be read together as "jiken,"
which means "case."
May 6, 2010 case?
That's the case that was on the news.
On the second card,
the bottom half of the diamond
and the arrowhead are darkened,
and there is a plus sign between
only these two symbols.
If you place the two symbols
on top of one another,
the dark sections form a star.
As you know, "hoshi" or "star"
means the culprit in police terminology.
So it's a star and a saddle.
The final symbol
reads as "nishi-san" if
you don't subtract the values.
If you read all three
codes together, you get...
May 6, 2010 case, culprit,
Kuranishi-san!
Akiyama-san knew you
committed that crime, didn't she?
I don't know why,
but she knew and hadn't
said anything until now.
However...
It would be a disaster
if the charges are false.
It would ruin the life of the accused.
If she didn't say anything, an
innocent man would be accused.
Akiyama-san realized she
couldn't let this happen,
and decided to confess the truth.
Kuranishi-san, you attacked her in
an attempt to stop her, didn't you?
You're right.
I warned Harumi immediately via e-mail.
If they find out, you'll be complicit, too.
That's why Akiyama-san used the codes
to tell me so you wouldn't notice.
I was so worried Harumi would
tell everyone eventually.
That's why I stayed with her at all times.
But then...
I'm going to tell Mori-san everything.
What?
Let's pay for our crime
and start over together.
Hey, don't!
Harumi!
Then I pretended to look for you,
and met up with the others.
Don't you think it's wrong
to let an innocent person be
arrested to save yourself?
To save yourself,
you even attacked the girlfriend
you planned to marry this spring.
Just how selfish are you?!
I feel terrible for Akiyama-san!
Though people were concerned the mystery
would be canceled due to the incident...
I'll do my best to make
sure that doesn't happen.
I see.
This is the story I'm submitting for the event.
Let me see.
How interesting.
You truly are a great
detective, Mori Kogoro-san.
I found it on my pillow when
I woke up this morning.
What?
Oh, nothing!
I forgot I'd written it,
since it's so easy for someone as great
as myself to come up with a story.
Conan-kun, go to sleep.
Okay!
I wish I could.
Huh? Conan-kun's asleep.
Sheesh.
Kids have it easy.
Episode Preview
I am Mori Kogoro, a detective.
You...
What?!
You said that you'd be home late
since you're working all day today, right?
Let's interview the people waiting in line.
It's them. They're here...
Happy New Year Mori Kogoro
The next episode of Conan is
"Happy New Year Mori Kogoro."
New Year's Week
Next Conan's hint!
New Year's Week.
This year's final "Conan" is...
Don't miss the next episode.
The Friday Night roadshow!
"The Disappearance of Edogawa Conan."
Me?
Me.