The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
Deciphering codes with Heiji.
A mystery that crosses Tokyo and Osaka.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Conan and Heiji's Code of Love
(Part One)
Conan and Heiji's Code of Love, Part One!
This rain sucks!
We wanted to play soccer in the park.
But it started raining
the second we got there.
Well, there was a 50% chance of rain.
We were right to bring umbrellas.
Why don't we play games
at the professor's house?
Yeah, let's!
Speaking of games, how far
did you get in Titan Hunter?
I've got seven Luck.
I got a sword!
Seriously?
Really?
Yeah!
So, what did you want to talk to me about?
Oh, right.
Do you know
what "sister from
another domain" means?
What?
What is that, the setting of a new anime?
No.
Sera seems to be hiding a middle-school-aged
girl who looks just like her in a hotel.
It's been on my mind, so I e-mailed
her about the girl yesterday.
She responded, "She's a
sister from another domain."
Doesn't that mean she's her sister?
But she said she doesn't have a sister.
And what does "from another domain" mean?
Besides, I think I've met Sera somewhere.
You should start by remembering where, then.
I was thinking the same thing, but
all I remember is her snaggletooth...
Ouch...
Damn kids! Watch where you're going!
What is this?
Are they tea leaves?
Don't touch that!
There he is!
Stop!
Who were those men?
Probably cops.
What?
Judging from his appearance,
they were probably chasing a drug dealer.
The things you picked up
that looked like tea leaves
was probably dried marijuana.
What?
Marijuana?
Oh, no! I touched that bag!
Your fingerprints are on it!
It's no big deal that your
fingerprints are on the bag.
Really?
Yeah.
If you explain the situation to the police...
A notebook?
That man must have dropped it.
Yeah.
But there's nothing written in it.
No, there's something small
written on the edge of the page.
The letter E, the number
2, an circled number 2,
and the character "ma"
for "mayaku" or drugs.
Drugs?!
It looks like there was something
written after the "ma,"
but unlike the numbers and letters next to
it, it was written with a water-based pen,
so the rainwater made it bleed.
Huh? There's something written
on the next page, too.
Yeah. There's something on the next page
and the pages after that.
All together, there are twelve lines.
All that can be barely read from the blurred
lines are the "ma" from the first page,
the third line's "tsuki,"  the fifth line's
"Nihon," and the ninth line's "Kyobashi."
What is this?
It must be a code, right?
Maybe they're the code numbers of a drug
smuggling organization's members.
Like E22 or S10.
What's the circle, then?
And what about the "tsuki" and
"Nippon" written after them?
Did you figure it out?
I have no idea.
Holding onto it won't do any good,
so I'll turn it in at a police box.
You're right.
Yeah.
Yes.
Bye bye, policeman!
We're counting on you!
Thanks for the help.
Not at all.
What do you want to do now?
It stopped raining.
Shall we go back to the park to play soccer?
Sorry.
What?
I just remembered I have something
to do. I'm going home.
Okay, got it!
Bye!
See you later!
Conan-kun is a terrible liar.
It's obvious.
We're capable of learning, too.
Anyway...
Haibara-san, we need those.
Please.
Okay, okay.
I came to check it out,
but there's no one here.
It's no good if I don't know the time.
It looks like the only ones
here are these kids
who secretly followed me.
What a coincidence.
Do you have business this way, too?
Coincidence? Yeah, right!
You followed the location of my detective
badge using those spare tracking glasses.
Well, yeah!
You're the one being unfair!
You're conducting an
investigation, aren't you?
Yeah. The codes written in the notebook
are probably the dates and
locations of various drug deal.
D-Drug deals?!
How do you know that?
The biggest clue is these notes
written in water-based ink,
next to the letters and numbers.
The dealer's fingertips were stained with
ink the same color as these blurred notes,
so he's the one who wrote
the water-based ink notes.
That means the codes written in permanent
marker were written by someone else.
It's natural to assume it was whoever
he's conducting the deals with.
His trading partner probably sent
the dealer the code-filled notebooks,
and conducted trades by indicating
the location and date.
He taught only the dealer
how to decipher the code,
so no one else could figure it out
even if they saw the notebook.
Then the water-based ink
notes written by that man...
Yeah.
The dealer wrote the answers
to the code on the side.
He probably meant to burn
or throw it away later.
In other words, the code E22
is associated with "ma,"
E22 → Ma
Y21 → Tsuki
Y21 with "tsuki," and
"G11" with "Nihon."
G11 → Nihon
I realized immediately that they
were subway and station numbers.
What?
E22 is the Oedo Line's
station 22, Azabu Juban.
Azabu Juban
Y21 is the Yurakucho Line's
station 21, Tsukishima.
Tsukishima
G11 is the Ginza Line's
station 11, Nihonbashi.
Nihonbashi
S-Station numbers?
What are those?
Well, let me tell you.
Azabu
They're the circled letters and numbers
displayed next to a station's name.
Really?
Which means you're meant
to read only the character
in the location of the
circled letter or number?
The third number in E22 was circled,
Oedo Line
Azabu Juban
and the third character is Azabu
Juban is the character "ju."
If you read the code up to the fifth line
following that rule, E22 is "ju."
C10 is the Chiyoda Line's Nijubashimae.
Chiyoda Line
The first letter is
circled, so it's "ni."
Nijubashimae
Y21 is the Yurakucho Line's
Tsukishima, so it's "tsuki."
Yurakucho Line
Tsukishima
M09 is the Marunouchi Line's Shinjuku
Sanchome, so it's "san."
Marunouchi Line
Shinjuku Sanchome
G11 is the Ginza Line's
Nihonbashi, so it's "hi."
Ginza Line
Nihonbashi
If you read them in order,
you get December 3rd.
December 3rd
W-Wait! December 3rd is today!
Yeah.
The deal should be going down today,
but I can't decipher the
six lines below the date.
It should be the time and location...
The sixth line's N11 is the
Nanboku Line's Korakuen.
The second number's circled,
so it's "raku."
The seventh line's Y12 is the
Yurakucho Line's Edogawabashi.
The second number's circled
here, too, so it's "do."
Together, they read as "rakudo."
Rakudo
I have no idea what it means.
Then why did you come here?
The eighth line's H02 is
the Hibiya Line's Ebisu.
Ebisu
The entire thing is circled,
so it's "Ebisu."
It says "Kyobashi" next to N22.
Kyobashi
The second number's circled,
so it's "bashi."
Bashi
Ebisubashi
In other words, "Ebisubashi."
I thought the deal would be happening here,
but I may have been wrong.
Why is N22 Kyobashi, anyway?
Mitsukoshimae
Nihonbashi
Kyobashi
Ginza
The Nanboku Line is N,
but there's no station 22.
Kyobashi is on the Ginza Line
and right next to Nihonbashi,
so it should be G10.
And what's the arrow attached
to the circle around Ebisu?
Does that mean it's the next station over?
The stations next to Ebisu
are Nakameguro and Hiroo,
but then it should be H01 or H03, damn it.
Then there are the three last lines.
I02 is the Mita Line's Shirokanedai,
so it's "shiro."
T22 is the Tozai Line's Baraki-Nakayama,
so it's "bara."
But I don't know what C22 is.
The Chiyoda Line ends with
station 20, Kitahayase.
Let me see that.
What?
Hurry up and show me the code.
I-Is that you, Hattori?
Yeah.
The kids called me since you
were on the verge of tears
because you couldn't decipher a code.
As the smarter detective,
I wouldn't mind sharing my wisdom with you.
I'm hanging up.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
Will you let me help you? Come on.
I'll send it to you right
now. Give me a second.
Why did you have to call him?
But isn't he your detective master?
What?
He told us to call any time you need help.
He's not my master.
I did need help, though.
Huh. I see.
It's a code using line and
station numbers, huh?
Interesting.
Whose phone are you using right now?
Oh, Otaki-han's.
We just solved a murder at Shinsaibashi.
Conan-kun's using my cell phone, too...
Did you figure anything out?
Are you sure G11's Nipponbashi?
Yeah. It's the station next to Kyobashi.
I know I have the letter and number right.
Nihonbashi and Kyobashi
are Tokyo subway stations,
so it's no wonder you don't know.
What are you talking about?
Nipponbashi and Kyobashi are the
names of Osaka subway stations, too.
On top of that, there are a
few stations between them.
They're not next to each other.
What?
Also, it's "Kyobashi," not "Kyobashi."
You put more emphasis on the first syllable.
H-Hey, is there really a
Kyobashi over there, too?
It's right in the code. It's N22.
N is the Nagahori Tsurumi-Ryokuchi Line.
Station 22 is Kyobashi.
Does that mean this code is...
Ebisubashi
Wh-What?
You figured out how to decipher the code?
Yeah.
If there are stations in Osaka
called Nihonbashi and Kyobashi,
then this code that uses line and station
numbers isn't limited to one region.
But that means the "December 3rd"
I deciphered from the first five lines
may not be right.
You're right.
In Osaka, we've got tons of stations
with numbers in their names
like Higashi-Mikuni, Yotsubashi,
Tanimachi Rokuchome.
It looks like only Osaka and Tokyo have
a Nipponbashi and Kyobashi, though.
Hey, some of the codes
are aligned to the left
and some of them are aligned to the right.
What?
You're right!
Then maybe one side indicates Tokyo stations
and the other indicates Osaka stations.
In that case,
then it would natural to assume the
western city of Osaka is the left,
and the eastern city of Tokyo is the right.
All five lines you deciphered are on
the left, so you're totally wrong.
But Tokyo's Nihonbashi is G11, right?
Yeah.
Osaka's Nipponbashi isn't G11, is it?
No.
Our Nipponbashi is the Sakaisuji Line's
K17 and the Sennichimae Line's S17.
If it says "Nippon" next to G11,
then it's gotta be your Nihonbashi.
Hei-chan, I got one.
It's a book with Tokyo
line and subway numbers.
I don't need that.
I found them online.
What?!
Don't be like that.
I walked all the way down to a store
on the Shinsaibashi station platform.
The escalator was out of service,
so I had to use the stairs.
I'm exhausted!
What?
The escalator?
That's it! The escalator!
What?
When you ride on an escalator,
in Osaka we stand to the right
and leave the left side open,
but it's the other way
around in Tokyo, right?
The stations aligned to the
right are Osaka stations,
and the ones aligned to the
left are Tokyo stations.
I see.
That's why the codes were
written on the edges of pages.
If you read them all at
once, they look like stairs.
That means December 3rd is correct.
What Osaka stations are the N11
and Y12 that come after that?
N11 is the Nagahori
Tsurumi-Ryokuchi Line's Taisho.
Y12 is the Yotsubashi Line's Higobashi.
The second number's circled in both
codes, so it's "sho" and "go."
In other words, "shogo,"
or 12:00 in the afternoon.
N-Noon?
It'll be 12:00 in less than ten minutes.
What?
S-Seriously?
If the drug deal is happening at Ebisubashi,
then we'd better hurry up and
hide before they get here!
Yeah.
H02 is aligned to the
left, so it's "Ebisu."
If N22 is Osaka's Kyobashi, then the deal
is probably happening at Ebisubashi.
But I don't know why there's an arrow
attached to the circle around H02.
Hey, Hattori.
Is there an Ebisu bridge over there, too?
Huh?
Hattori!
There's one in Osaka, too.
The characters are different,
but there's a bridge called Ebisubashi
where we meet all the time!
I see.
This arrow means it's the left side's...
Osaka's Ebisubashi!
Yeah!
I'm running there right now.
I'll be there in a few minutes.
Amazing!
Not bad!
Way to go, Conan-kun's master!
This is kind of frustrating.
Yeah, but what's "shiroihara?"
What?
The last three lines below the deal location.
It's the answer to I02, C22, and T22.
The right-aligned C22 is Osaka's Chuo
Line's Takaida, so it's "i."
Chuo Line
Takaida
The left-aligned I02 and T22 are Tokyo's
Shirokanedai and Haraki-Nakayama,
Shirokanedai
so it's "shiro" and "hara."
Haraki-Nakayama
Read them together, and
you get "shiroihara."
Shiroihara
Surely it doesn't mean he'll be waiting
with his white stomach hanging out.
No, it's not read Haraki-Nakayama,
but Baraki-Nakayama.
In other words, when you read them
together, you get "shiroibara."
It probably means their sign is a white rose.
Hattori? What happened?
Hattori!
You can't hear him anymore?
Maybe something happened.
Maybe he tried to catch the dealer's
trading partner, and instead...
He's pretty hot-blooded. It's possible.
Hey, Hattori!
Answer me, Hattori!
Hattori!
There are three of them.
I just took a look around Ebisubashi,
but there are three people
wearing or holding white roses,
while waiting for someone.
Seriously?
You should've told me you
arrived at the bridge.
Sorry about that.
There really were a few suspicious
characters, so I got lost in thought.
But are you sure there's a
drug deal happening here?
Yeah, probably.
The guy holding this notebook
had four huge bags of marijuana.
Even if each bag contained only 500
grams, four bags makes two kilograms.
The street value is a
pretty significant amount.
It hadn't been divided into smaller bags,
so it's likely he meant to
exchange all of them at once.
I did consider the possibility
the deal had already happened...
If the meeting time's at noon,
then he hasn't met his trading partner yet.
What did the dealer look like?
It was a bearded man wearing
a knit hat and jacket.
He was the textbook picture of a drug dealer.
Some cop-like guys were chasing him,
so they may have already arrested him.
It's also possible he escaped
and headed your way,
so be careful.
Yeah.
By the way, where's Detective Otaki?
He headed back to headquarters to get backup.
After all, I'm using his cellphone.
But there are only five minutes to noon.
Yeah.
It looks like we'll have to narrow down
his trading partner to one before then.
Just the two of us.
Episode Preview
Isn't this the bad guy?
I agree.
Me, too!
It's one minute past the meeting time.
Those guys...
Who are you? What are you doing?
K-Kazuha!
I'll throw the lot of you
into the Dotonbori River!
Bring it on!
Hey, Hattori!
Conan and Heiji's Code of Love
Part Two
The next episode of Conan is "Conan
and Heiji's Code of Love, Part Two!"
White Rose
Next Conan's hint.
A white rose!
Don't miss the next episode.
Huh? What do you mean, New Year's money?
We'd like some, please!
Me, too, Heiji-niichan.