Detective Conan Episode 764 "Conan
and Heiji's Code of Love (Part 2)"
The Detective Boys, Haibara, and I
ran into a suspicious man being pursued
in the rain by men who seemed like cops.
Damn kids! Watch where you're going!
There he is!
Stop!
The man was apparently a drug dealer,
and I deduced the time and location of his
drug deal from the notebook he dropped.
In other words, the code E22
is associated with "ma,"
Y21 with "tsuki," and
"G11" with "Nihon."
I realized immediately that they
were subway and station numbers.
What?
The third number in E22 was circled,
and the third character
in Azabu Juban is "ju."
If you read the code up to the
fifth line following that rule,
E22 is "ju."
C10 is the Chiyoda Line's Nijubashimae.
The first letter is circled, so it's "ni."
Y21 is the Yurakucho Line's
Tsukishima, so it's "tsuki."
M09 is the Marunouchi Line's Shinjuku
Sanchome, so it's "san."
G11 is the Ginza Line's
Nihonbashi, so it's "hi."
If you read them in order,
you get December 3rd.
However, the code included
mysteries I couldn't decipher,
and I ended up working with
Hattori Heiji over the phone.
Huh, I see.
It's a code using line and
station numbers, huh?
Interesting.
Hey, some of the codes
are aligned to the left,
and some of them are aligned to the right.
What?
Hey, you're right.
Then maybe one side indicates Tokyo stations
and the other indicates Osaka stations.
In that case, it would natural to assume
the western city of Osaka is the left and
the eastern city of Tokyo is the right.
That's it! The escalator!
What?
On an escalator, in Osaka we stand to
the right and leave the left side open,
but it's the other way
around in Tokyo, right?
The stations aligned to the
right are Osaka stations,
and the ones aligned to the
left are Tokyo stations.
Hey, Hattori.
Is there an Ebisu bridge over there, too?
Hattori?
There's one in Osaka, too.
The characters are different,
but there's a bridge called Ebisubashi
where we meet all the time!
Hattori? What happened?
Hattori!
You can't hear him anymore?
Maybe something happened.
Maybe he tried to catch the dealer's
trading partner, and instead...
He's pretty hot-blooded.
It's possible.
Hey, Hattori!
Answer me, Hattori!
Hattori!
There are three of them.
I just took a look around Ebisubashi,
but there are three people wearing or holding
white roses while waiting for someone.
But there are only five minutes to noon.
Yeah.
It looks like we'll have to narrow down
his trading partner to one before then.
Just the two of us.
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
A collaborative deduction
using smart phone images.
How will Hattori respond when he sees Kazuha?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Conan and Heiji's Code of Love
(Part 2)
Conan and Heiji's Code of Love, Part 2!
Ebisubashi
Well?
What do the three people look like?
It's two guys and one girl.
Want me to video chat you?
If the dealer shows up, you'll recognize him.
Keep this phone line open.
Send the images to my phone.
All right!
Can you see me?
Yes.
We can see you.
The image is perfect.
Who are the three people?
Right. The first one
is this scary looking old dude.
He looks like bad news.
He's suspicious. He keeps checking the time.
He has an expensive watch, too.
Speaking of checking...
Look, he did it again!
He took something out of his coat's
inside pocket and is looking at it.
Could it be a cell phone?
He's waving it in front of his face.
Maybe it's some kind of signal.
Maybe he hasn't gotten much sleep.
He keeps yawning.
I don't see a white rose anywhere.
Is it in his right hand?
That's right.
In his right hand, he's carefully holding...
...a bouquet of white roses.
Isn't this the bad guy?
I agree.
Me, too!
Who are the other two?
The next one is this lady wearing
a white rose in her hair.
Her hair is so cute and wavy!
Is she a model?
Is she meeting someone for a date?
She's suspicious.
What?
Look closely.
The bag she's holding.
That's the newest Fusae brand model.
It's unbelievably expensive, but
she stuck a rose corsage on it.
That's not on sale in Japan yet.
I wonder where she got it.
That's what drew your attention?
Huh? She's looking at her shoes.
Did she step on something?
She's crouching.
She put something inside her shoe.
This lady's suspicious.
I agree.
Me, too!
The third person is this gaudy guy
wearing a white rose on his chest.
Hey, he's talking to someone.
Yeah, it's a girl.
For a while now he's been
talking to some girl...
K-Kazuha?
What are you doing?
Hey, Hattori.
That girl looks like Kazuha-chan...
Yeah...
It's Kazuha!
That idiot's getting hit on by
some good-for-nothing guy!
This guy must be innocent, though.
No one's stupid enough to
hit on a girl before a deal.
Could he be one of Kazuha's
law enforcement acquaintances?
You idiot, look closer.
He's got bleached hair, a pierced
nose, and a tattoo on his neck.
Cops don't look like that.
You're right...
There are less than two minutes to noon.
There's no time, Hattori.
Don't rush me.
If it's not the flashy guy,
it's got to be either the
old dude or the girl.
Hey, Hattori!
Can I tell you what I think?
Hattori?
Hey, Hattori!
Hattori!
Shit. I can't focus...
Hattori?
Hey, Hattori!
Are you listening, Hattori?
Hattori?
Quit shouting at me!
If you want to tell me what you
think, spit it out already!
Uh, right.
First, the old man.
The scary looking man with
the bouquet of white roses
isn't the dealer's trading partner.
What?!
He certainly has the most
suspicious face of the bunch.
He was taking something out of his coat, too.
It looked like he was sending
some kind of weird signal.
Yeah.
He was using a hand mirror
to check his bangs.
It just looked weird because he was
using his fingers to fix his bangs
while holding the mirror.
Why was he yawning, then?
He was checking to see if his breath smelled.
He was hiding the bouquet of roses
behind his back while he waited
because he wants to surprise
whoever he's meeting with a gift.
You're right.
If the white rose is a sign,
he would be holding it in a more obvious way.
This old guy probably
is waiting for his date.
They're beautiful.
Are they for me?
You're right!
That's amazing!
Way to go, Conan's master!
Wait a minute.
Most of that was my deduction.
What about the woman wearing
a white rose on her head?
Her shoes seemed to bother her.
She crouched and put something in her shoe.
It must have been a small
weapon or something.
No.
She probably took them off because
they were hurting her feet.
She had a band-aid on her heel.
Even bad guys have to deal
with ill-fitting shoes.
But normally I wouldn't expect someone
to wear ill-fitting shoes to a drug deal.
It's possible during the deal
someone might report them,
and they'll have to run away.
Ill-fitting high heels are
the worst choice of footwear.
Besides, her hair looks like she
just got it done at a salon.
It's not her.
Why not?
Are you saying evil women can't dress up?
The guy's trading partner is
waiting for a drug dealer.
Normally you'd expect him to come wearing
something plain and inconspicuous.
He actually was dressed that way.
It would be a different story if they
were meeting in a deserted alleyway,
but the deal is happening
on the crowded Ebisubashi.
If a badly mismatched couple met there,
they would stand out in the
memories of passers-by.
Besides, the corsage on her
bag doesn't make sense.
If their meeting sign is a white rose,
her corsage would be the same color.
She wouldn't be confusing by
using a differently colored rose.
I see.
Her elaborate hairstyle, ill-fitting
shoes, and rose corsage.
The girl was probably invited to a
wedding or some other kind of party
Over here!
and is meeting her friend here.
He's right again!
Not bad!
Impressive!
That was all me, too.
Wait a minute.
That means the flashy guy talking to Kazuha
is the drug dealer's trading partner.
No way!
I told you before,
but you'd be stupid to hit
on a girl before a drug deal.
Why do you assume he's hitting on her?
It's possible Kazuha-chan spoke to him first.
What? That's definitely not it!
Why would Kazuha talk to such
a gaudy looking drug dealer?
It's possible they know each other.
It's also possible their deal was canceled,
and he's just an ordinary person.
Calm down, Hattori.
Normally you'd notice
these things immediately.
Though I do understand how you feel.
It's one minute past the meeting time.
No way!
The dealer may already be at the bridge!
Hattori, we're out of time.
Kazuha-chan could get caught up in
something if the dealer arrives.
You need to take her and get
out of there immediately.
What are you doing?!
The video chat stopped!
I'm emailing Kazuha.
I'm asking her who the flashy guy is.
Give me a break, Kazuha-chan.
No way. You're not getting away.
Give me a second.
It's from Heiji.
Received Message
What are you doing?
Huh? He wants to know what I'm doing.
What is he doing with his jacket?
The bulge under his arm...
That must be
a gun!
What is he doing with his jacket?
The bulge under his arm...
That must be
a gun!
That guy...
Hey, listen closely.
That flashy guy's
hiding a gun on his chest!
What?!
Whether or not he's the
dealer's trading partner,
he's definitely not just an ordinary citizen.
Hattori, forget about the deal.
You need to take Kazuha by the
hand and get away from there.
Huh? What are you talking about?
She's in danger!
Oh, not you.
I just got a response from Kazuha.
Received Message
"I saw my old neighbor
Yakumaru-san at Ebisubashi.
He said he was in his university's
pharmaceutical department,
but he's dressed so flashy.
He's got a date.
I'm hanging around to see
what his date looks like."
What a stupid message!
He's lying!
A pharmaceutical student with bleached
hair, a neck tattoo, and pierced nose?
No way!
He probably pretended to be a serious
person and approached Kazuha.
Kazuha's dad is the Osaka police chief.
Maybe he's trying to butter her up so
he can get information on the police.
H-Hey!
Who are you?! What are you doing?!
K-Kazuha!
Wait, Hattori! That flashy guy might be...
Hey! Are you listening, Hattori?
Ow!
Let go of me, you idiots!
What do you think you're touching, moron?!
Stop!
Who are you?! Where are you taking me?!
K-Kazuha!
Heiji...
Sorry. Thanks.
What are you doing?
I could ask you the same thing!
What do you think you're doing to my Kazuha?
Heiji...
What?
Looks like you brought a bunch of friends.
A whole bunch of ugly friends.
Hey, wait...
It's too late now!
I'll throw the lot of you
into the Dotonbori River!
Bring it on!
Hey, Hattori!
He hung up.
What?
That gaudy man was a narcotics agent?
Yeah.
They investigate drug-related crimes.
They're called narcs or drug agents.
But isn't that a kind of policeman?
You said he wasn't a cop.
Narcotics agents aren't police officers.
What?
They're agents of the Ministry of Health.
Because they're legally allowed to
conduct undercover operations,
their agents can bleach their hair
or get tattoos and nose piercings.
Naturally they're allowed to have
guns if their jobs require it.
Now that you mention it,
I've heard a lot of narcs are
former pharmaceutical students.
Yeah. That's when it hit me.
Then that man was there to
conduct an investigation, right?
Yeah.
According to the call I just
got from Inspector Otaki,
a drug dealer apprehended in Osaka
confessed the location and sign of his deal,
so that agent dressed up as him and
was waiting for the drug dealer.
I see.
That's why he asked his colleagues
to take her away from the location.
Yeah.
If the dealer showed up, he
would have found it suspicious,
and he didn't want to get her involved.
It sounds like they caught the
dealer at a nearby comic café,
so that settles that.
But is your master all right?
Once Inspector Otaki explained
the situation, they let him go.
That's the least of his worries, though.
Ministry of Health Kinki
Public Welfare Station
General Affairs
Division
Health and
Welfare
Department
Narcotics
Damn narcs.
I can't believe they went
hard on a high school kid.
They could've held back some.
Hey.
On top of that, I got a huge lecture.
Hey, Heiji.
They'll talk to my dad for me?
Don't bother!
Hey, Heiji. What did that mean?
What?
When did I become yours?
What are you talking about?
You said, "What do you think
you're doing to my dear Kazuha?!"
"I'll kill you, damn it!"
I-I didn't say anything that stupid!
I may not have gotten it quite right,
but it was something like that.
Hey, Heiji. Answer me.
Heiji?
Shut up! Do I have to tell you?!
Heiji...
I'm only going to say it once, so listen closely.
The most important thing to me...
...is evidence.
What?
Don't say weird things if you don't
have the evidence to back it up!
W-Wait, Heiji!
What do you mean, evidence?
I know what I heard!
Maybe there's something
wrong with your ears.
My darling, darling Kazuha-chan...
I didn't say that!
So you do remember!
Ow, ow, ow!
My ears are ringing so much, I can't hear you!
Heiji!
Ow, ow, ow!
I know! I'll email Ran-chan!
You idiot, don't do that!
I recorded it...
What do you think you're doing to my Kazuha?!
Episode Preview
Teams Detective Boys and Café
Renno, please get ready.
It's our turn.
It's finally time.
Hey, that old man...
He fell into the Teimuzu River!
This isn't good! He can't swim!
No. There's still something we can do.
We'll listen in on them.
Teimuzu River Kite Flying Case
(Part 1)
The next episode of Conan is "Teimuzu
River Kite Flying Case, Part 1!"
Phone
Next Conan's hint!
The phone!
You're listening to it again?
Don't miss the next episode.
It's apparently his master's weakness.
This is too funny. One more time.