All right!
It's done!
Amazing!
It looks fantastic!
The design is the same as
our Detective Boy badges.
Huh?
Hey, hey, every kite needs a tail.
Without a tail, it'll just spin in circles.
I've already made some.
And they contain a message.
Look.
"If you've got a case on your hands,
contact the Detective Boys of Teitan
Elementary School Class 1-B."
Wow...
The jobs will come pouring in.
Isn't it a good idea?
What about the other tail?
I was planning on unrolling
this one once we got there...
"If you're looking for useful inventions,
contact Agasa Hiroshi of Beika
City 2-chome, 22-banchi."
You even wrote your website on the back.
Why not?
I helped make the kite.
I deserve at least this much.
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
A kite flying event on the banks of a river.
An ingenious trick creates
the illusion of an accident.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Teimuzu River Kite Flying Case
(Part One)
Teimuzu River Kite Flying Case, Part One!
But will it be all right?
What do you mean?
A kite's tails flap in the wind.
No one will be able to read the messages.
We just have to win an award at the
kite flying event we're attending.
An award?
What do you mean?
Kites that win awards for flying the highest
or having the most unique design
are hung in city hall for a month.
It would be a super effective
form of advertisement.
Really?
Amazing!
Let's do our best, Ai-chan!
Ai-chan?
Huh?
Oh, sorry.
What?
L-Let's do our best to fly our kite.
Sure.
Kites!
They look magnificent.
Let's do our best!
Eighth Teimuzu River Kite Flying Event
What?
The song Haibara's listening to?
Yeah. Sometimes she hums really happily.
I really want to know what's
making her so happy.
Was it an anime song?
I think it was one of
Okino Yoko-chan's songs.
It sounded like classical music to me.
Why don't you just ask her?
I did, of course, but she said it was a secret.
Don't worry about it.
It's probably some dumb song
that's popular right now.
I'm sorry
that I like dumb popular songs.
Haibara...
Quit putting on airs and tell them already.
I'm kind of curious, too.
No way. I'll never tell you.
What?!
Hey, Haibara...
If you want to know that badly,
why don't you figure it out
for yourself, Mr. Master Detective?
Huh?
Figure it out?
Hey!
It's almost your turn to fly your kite!
Hey, Professor,
do you know what kind of music
Haibara's been listening to lately?
What?
It might be the theme song
of a drama she's into.
She hasn't been matching
many dramas recently,
but she watched the special on Big
Osaka's Higo a bunch of times.
She was especially into pictures from
when the soccer team he captained
placed second in the high
school championship.
He's very considerate of his juniors.
When he has time, he still watches
his alma mater's matches.
Lately his school's baseball team has
been getting more attention, though.
Higo-san attended a Kanto
high school, didn't he?
Oh, right.
Come to think of it, his teammate
Sanada appeared on the special.
He revealed all sorts of things about
Higo, including his more unusual tastes.
Professor, that's enough.
What?
Sorry, but you'll just have to suffer forever.
Bitch...
Do you think it has
something to do with Higo?
Ai-chan is a huge fan.
But his favorite song isn't
listed on his website.
It's possible it hasn't
been updated yet, though.
Then there's no way to figure it out.
No. There's still something we can do.
We'll listen in on her.
L-Listen in on her?
We'll run a mobile recording
app and leave the screen black.
See? Now she won't know even if she finds it.
Ayumi-chan can hide it on her
person and approach Haibara.
While the three of us are flying the kite,
Haibara will let her guard down.
If she starts unconsciously humming, then
the identity of the song
will be made plain as day.
Conan-kun, you look scary.
That's not detective work.
Isn't that actually a crime?
Next up are Team Detective
Boys and Team Café Renno.
Teams Detective Boys and Café
Renno, please get ready.
It's our turn.
It's finally time.
We're counting on you, Ayumi-chan.
O-Okay...
Let's go!
How's this?
Bring it a little farther back so
the wind hits it from the front!
Okay!
Roger!
Don't step on the tails!
It's finally time.
You can do it!
Are you curious about the song, too?
Y-Yeah.
If you promise not to tell
Edogawa-kun, I'll tell you what it is.
This song is actually...
D-Don't!
Don't say it!
It's wrong to secretly
record a girl's secrets!
Secretly record?
Did he...?
Yeah.
Conan-kun asked me to record you humming.
That dirty detective...
Huh?
All right!
Now!
We did it!
Wow!
It's flying pretty high!
Huh?
Oh, no!
The tail!
It came off!
Damn it...
It's falling!
Seriously?!
Our kite!
Huh?
Hey, watch out!
Renno Ryota (39)
Kite Flying Event Participant
Sheesh.
What? Is there someone next to you?
Some kids.
They dropped their kite.
I told you I was going to a kite
flying event this afternoon.
Are you sure?
There's something wrong with
a wife who trusts a husband
Renno Takami (35)
Ryota's Wife
who lies to her about having
an affair with some woman!
What woman are you talking about?
Bring her to me.
Are you getting mad at me now?
That's not possible.
What?
Last night, my sister sliced
her wrists in the bathroom.
She's lying unconscious and in serious
condition in a hospital bed right now.
She was stupid for believing you'd
actually leave your wife for her,
but I still adore my sister.
Kakura Yuitoshi (41)
Kite Flying Event Participant
We need to talk once this is over.
If you'd like, we could settle this here.
Hey, Renno-san, what are you doing?!
Not over there!
Go farther back!
Sorry.
You should be careful.
Your friend Yatsukoshi was deeply
in love with my sister, too.
Yatsukoshi Takeshi (34)
Kite Flying Event Participant
Keep flying those kites!
Each team has fifteen minutes!
No one turned in a missing phone.
Are you sure you dropped it in
front of these portable toilets?
Yeah, probably.
I think I dropped something when I took out
my handkerchief after using the bathroom.
Why didn't you pick it up then?
U-Um, because I heard an announcement saying
it was our turn to fly our kite.
I see.
Do you remember anyone who was
standing nearby at the time?
Someone tripped behind me.
I didn't see their face, though.
Maybe they thought they dropped their own
phone when they tripped and took it with them.
If they tripped, they must
have been in a hurry.
Probably.
Then maybe it was someone flying their kite at
the same time as Edogawa-kun and the boys.
Then we can call the phone
once their turn is over.
It's no use.
The frame is broken.
Even if we reattach the
tail, it still won't fly.
Damn it.
Maybe...
What?
Maybe we're being punished.
Punished?
You mean for trying to listen in on Haibara?
Hey! What are you doing?!
I-If you keep going—
Huh?
Hey, that old man!
He fell into the Teimuzu River!
Mitsuhiko, call an ambulance!
Okay!
This isn't good! He can't swim!
Someone help!
Over here!
Grab on!
Are you okay?
Was it an accident?
Honey?
What's wrong? Honey?
Honey!
Answer me!
No, this...
...was no accident.
I-If you keep going—
Huh?
Hey, that old man!
He fell into the Teimuzu River!
Mitsuhiko, call an ambulance!
Okay!
This isn't good! He can't swim!
Someone help!
Over here!
Grab on!
Are you okay?
Was it an accident?
Honey?
What's wrong? Honey?
Honey!
Answer me!
No, this...
...was no accident.
He swallowed a bunch of water, and now
he's unconscious and in serious condition.
Yes.
So, who fell into the river?
He's the manager of a nearby café.
Renno Ryota-san, thirty-nine years old.
According to witnesses,
while Renno-san was holding
his kite and backing up,
he had the misfortune of
slipping between the posts
where the rope was cut
and fell into the river.
Hmm.
I see.
The ends of the rope are old and worn.
It probably broke apart a while
ago and was left that way.
It looks like it was just an accident.
We'll let the appropriate
authorities handle the rest.
Yes, sir.
I don't think it was an accident.
C-Conan-kun?
What do you mean, it wasn't an accident?
Detective Takagi, try tying the
two ends of the rope together.
What? Okay...
Huh?
See? They don't reach.
Y-Yeah.
But if they were exposed to
the elements for a long time,
it makes sense that they
would have gotten shorter.
Yeah, but...
The rope on the bottom is so
long there's some left over.
Even if these were connected, the rope
would just hang down uselessly, right?
You're right.
On top of that,
one end of the rope has
been bleached by the sun,
but the other side hasn't.
But why?
It's probably the rope from
the post on the very end.
The rope from the post on the very end?
Yeah.
The tip of the rope on the end
would be worn from exposure.
Someone untied it, matched the
length, and tied it back on here
to make it seem as though the
rope broke a long time ago.
Maybe the underside of the
rope wasn't bleached...
...because it was wrapped around the post.
I-I see.
Mitsuhiko and Genta went to check it out.
We'll know for sure soon.
Conan-kun, you were right!
The rope attached to the post
next to the one of the very end
had a brand new cut on it and wasn't
attached to the post next to it.
Hey!
The post on the other end didn't
have a rope on it, either!
See?
But who would do this?
And for what purpose?
I'm just a kid. I don't know.
I-I suppose not.
Right.
But maybe
someone did it to make the man
who nearly drowned fall in the river.
That can't be.
He slipped and fell.
But that man was holding his
kite and backing up, right?
People don't normally pay much attention
to what's behind them when they do that.
Yeah.
Besides, he thought there
was a rope behind him.
You might watch your feet to make sure you
don't step on your kite's tail, though.
Then if someone drew him to this spot
between the posts without a rope,
wouldn't it be possible to make him fall in?
Y-You're right.
Which means the culprit is...
The most suspicious figure
is that fat man who was helping the
man who nearly drowned fly his kite.
If they were on the same team,
it would be possible for him to tell
the other man where to stand, right?
Not over there!
Go farther back!
Also, there's that large man talking to him.
He was speaking with the man who nearly
drowned just before he fell into the river.
We need to talk after this is over.
If you'd like, we could settle this here.
All right. We'll question them.
Also,
speaking of conversations, before
the man fell into the river,
he was talking to someone on his cell phone.
I-If you keep going—
Huh?
What?
Do you know who he was talking to?
From his phone...
Honey?
What's wrong? Honey?
Honey!
Answer me!
...I heard someone talking.
Maybe it was his wife.
We should contact his home immediately.
But when I answered the phone and told
her her husband fell into the river,
she rushed here.
She rode in the ambulance with him.
Call her back here immediately,
as a material witness
in an attempted murder.
Yes, sir!
This crime was carefully planned.
One of the three people I
mentioned probably did it.
But how did the suspect
carry out their plan
at a crowded kite flying event?
And who committed the crime?
Episode Preview
You think I drew Renno-san to an area without
a rope and made him fall into the river?
He was probably being punished for his sins.
Why would you suspect me?
The culprit may be someone
other than those three.
But there must be some way...
Maybe there isn't?
Teimuzu River Kite Flying Case
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Teimuzu
River Kite Flying Case, Part Two!"
Kite String
Next Conan's hint.
Kite string!
Don't miss the next episode
Why do they call it a kite?
Would you have preferred hawk?
No, maybe falcon.