Detective Conan Episode 766 "Teimuzu
River Kite Flying Case (Part 2)"
The Detective Boys headed to the Teimuzu
River to try to win a kite flying event.
The song Haibara's listening to?
Yeah. Sometimes she hums really happily.
Was it an anime song?
I think it was one of
Okino Yoko-chan's songs.
Why don't you just ask her?
I did, of course, but she
said it was a secret.
Don't worry about it.
It's probably some dumb song
that's popular right now.
I'm sorry...
...that I like dumb popular songs.
Haibara...
Quit putting on airs and tell them already.
I'm kind of curious, too.
No way. I'll never tell you.
No. There's still something we can do.
We'll listen in on her.
During the kite flying event, a man on the
neighboring team fell into the Teimuzu River.
Renno Ryota (39)
Kite Flying Event Participant
Was it an accident?
Honey?
What's wrong? Honey?
Honey!
Answer me!
No, this...
...was no accident.
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
Kites are attached by string.
But what about human relationships?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Teimuzu River Kite Flying Case
(Part 2)
Teimuzu River Kite Flying Case, Part Two!
What?
Yatsukoshi Takeshi (34)
Kite Flying Event Participant
You think I drew Renno-san to an area
without a rope and made him fall into the river?
You must be joking.
I shouted "watch out" and tried to stop him.
Right? You kids saw it, didn't you?
Yeah.
He shouted just before that
man fell into the river.
Hey, what are you doing?!
I-If you keep going—
He seemed pretty worried to me.
But we don't know if
Renno-san heard his voice.
The people around them were shouting
instructions to their teammates, too.
They were pretty far apart.
Is that right?
Yes.
I thought he could hear me, at least a bit.
But after that I backed away from him, too.
Even if he couldn't hear you, you
could still guide him using gestures.
I didn't do anything like that.
If you think I'm lying,
you can watch the video the event operators
took to make sure no one was cheating.
Why did you have to stand so far away?
Because I noticed while watching the other
kites that the wind seemed stronger higher up.
I thought we could send our kite
shooting up by standing far apart.
Each team had a limited amount of time to
fly their kite, so we had to get it in one try.
I see.
By the way, what's your
relationship with Renno-san?
I'm an employee at the
café Renno-san manages.
I came today so we could win our class
event using a kite with our café's logo.
The winners' kites are displayed at
city hall, so it's good advertising.
We'd have pride when we attended
neighborhood association meetings, too.
I see.
Eighth Teimuzu River Kite Flying Event
Yeah, Renno and I talked a little
just before he fell into the river.
What did you discuss?
Kakura Yuitoshi (41)
Kite Flying Event Participant
He had a relationship with my
sister even though he had a wife.
He drove her to attempt suicide, so I asked
to speak with him after the event.
He was probably being punished for his sins.
Then you had motive to make
Renno-san fall into the river.
Doesn't Yatsukoshi have motive, too?
He'd been in love with my
sister since high school.
His wife, who was furious when I told her
about him and my sister, must've
had plenty of motive, too.
Is it true Renno-san was speaking to
his wife on the phone the whole time?
Yeah, it seemed that way.
If I had led him into falling into the river,
wouldn't his wife have
heard me over the phone?
He and I were flying the same kind of kite.
I doubt anyone would listen
to the advice of a rival.
But you saw Renno-san fall
into the river, right?
You didn't think to stop him?
I was pretty far away when he fell.
I thought he had approached
the river to litter.
Litter?
He was carrying an empty
plastic bottle under his arm.
By the way, what is your
relationship with them?
Renno and Yatsukoshi were my juniors
on our high school baseball team.
Even after I graduated, I visited
the club to help them out.
That's how I know Yatsukoshi even
though he's younger than me.
W-Wait a minute!
Why would you suspect me?
Renno Takami (35)
Ryota's Wife
I was speaking to him over the phone
from home using my house phone!
But the person he was
speaking to on the phone
is the only one who could have
led him between the posts.
If you lived in a tall apartment building
and could see this area from there.
What? I live in an ordinary two-story house.
But if you were video chatting,
you could see a little bit,
like the location of the posts.
Listen, if his wife at home
told him over the phone
to go farther back or move
a little to the left,
there's no way he would listen!
She's right...
Did you hear Kakura-san's
voice through the phone?
Yes. He's the brother of my
husband's mistress, isn't he?
I could hear him very clearly.
I already knew my husband was having
an affair with his sister, though.
Did he say anything to direct your husband?
Not really, no.
My husband was busy making excuses to me.
But maybe they spoke secretly.
He did tell me to hold on and moved
the phone away from his face.
Maybe he had a call waiting.
I didn't hear a hold tone.
I did hear some rustling as my
husband was doing something, though.
Could he have received
an e-mail from someone?
He had a call on the line. He
couldn't view his messages.
I threatened to divorce
him if he hung up on me.
Just like he said, Yatsukoshi-san's
not making any overt movements.
Yes. He's just drinking his beverage.
Hey, what are you doing?!
I-If you keep going—
Hey, someone fell into the river!
We can see Kakura-san just after
Renno-san fell into the river.
Just like he said, he's pretty far away.
I can't imagine he led Renno-san
between the posts.
Then that leaves only
his wife who called him.
But like she said, isn't that impossible?
That would mean the culprit may be
someone other than those three.
No. It's clear now.
I'm sure of it.
That person did it.
But I don't have any proof to back it up.
You seem troubled.
You eavesdropper.
What?
Ayumi-chan spilled the beans.
Well...
It seems you're being punished for it.
Your phone has disappeared somewhere.
Seriously?!
Ayumi-chan, you don't have it?!
I dropped it in front of the
bathrooms, and someone picked it up.
Shouldn't you try calling it, then?
Well...
We tried calling it.
At first it rang a few times
before the call ended.
After that, the phone was powered off,
and we couldn't reach it no
matter how many times we called.
Since it's off, we can't
look for it by GPS, either.
Do you remember anyone who was
standing nearby when you dropped it?
U-Um...
Someone tripped behind me,
but I didn't see their face.
That's why I think they mistook it
for their own and took it with them.
Professor, what time was
it when you first called?
After the ambulance left.
Because of the incident, I had
forgotten all about your phone.
I see.
Then there may be some record
of the devil's voice
that used this primitive trick.
We've been telling you, it was impossible
for any of us to make Renno fall in the river!
Like you said, it's possible someone
manipulated the rope between those posts.
But just because my husband was
backing up while holding a kite...
None of us could have led him between the
posts and made him fall into the river.
But the rope seems to have been
manipulated quite recently.
I can only imagine it was done to
make Renno-san fall into the river.
Then how did we do it?
Tell us.
How do you think we led
Renno-san between the posts?
I was working with Renno-san to fly our kite,
but when he fell, I was far enough
away that he couldn't hear me.
You didn't see me make any
gestures to guide him, did you?
I was pretty far away when
he fell into the river, too.
If I had shouted something to him,
his wife on the phone
would have heard it, too.
I was on the phone with
my husband until he fell,
but it wasn't possible for me
to guide my husband from home!
Why do you still suspect us?
But there must be some way...
Maybe there isn't?
What?
They may have been able to do it
if they had psychic powers, though.
Psy-Psychic powers?
F-For today, you can leave after
we conduct a pat-down search.
Y-You can't be serious!
Why do we have to be searched?
It's not as though anyone died.
Pat-down searches are optional, right?
Then I refuse to be searched.
What?
So do I.
I'll pass, too.
Wait...
It's okay.
Once Renno-san regains consciousness,
we'll know immediately who did it.
Is that true, Conan?
Probably.
Maybe he'll even tell us how
they led him between the posts.
But what if he doesn't regain consciousness?
If that happens, we'll have to give up.
We haven't found any clues.
Speaking of which, Conan-kun,
did you find your phone?
No, not yet.
Maybe whoever picked it up
threw it away somewhere.
It would be terrible if they
threw it into the river.
It'll be fine. It's waterproof.
We'll probably know who threw it away, too.
My phone was set to record.
It'll have recorded the voice
of whoever picked it up.
What are you going to do if they
take it home and destroy it?
I'll find it before they do.
How?
I had the professor install a
special transmitter in the phone.
We'll know exactly where it is once
we check the computer at his house.
Right, Professor?
What? Oh, yes...
I don't remember installing a transmitter...
But what if they erase the recorded data?
Don't worry about that. It's locked.
It's a four digit code you
guys will never crack.
This is Conan
Is it "this is Conan"
written in numbers as 5794?
Nope.
I see.
Since you're the "Kaito Kid Killer,"
it must be his criminal number 1412.
No, it's not that.
It's 110.
You're always telling us to call the police.
I said it's four digits.
It's not 4869, is it?
You are a Sherlock fan.
Sherlock
Huh?
O-Of course not.
I'm right.
I said that's not it.
Damn it.
What's going on?
Isn't it 4869?
Enter PIN
Wrong PIN.
It's not working.
That kid...
Did he...?
Sh-Shit!
I-I'm coming out!
I don't have a choice.
I'll have to take it home
and smash it with a hammer.
So it was you,
Yatsukoshi Takeshi-san.
Wh-What are you talking about?
You have Conan-kun's phone, don't you?
Oh...
You mean this?
I thought it was mine and picked it up.
It's the same model and color as mine.
It has a different PIN, and I thought
I hadn't brought mine today,
so I thought it was strange.
Is that all?
No, it's all clear now.
The person who plotted to make
Renno-san fall into the river...
...was you.
Wh-What are you talking about?
I told you, it wasn't possible for me to
lead Renno-san between the posts!
How could I have guided Renno-san
without any overt gestures
when he was standing so far
away he couldn't hear me?
You called him.
C-Called him?
You can talk to people who
are far away using a phone.
Renno-san was on the phone with his wife.
She said she didn't hear a hold tone, either.
Not that kind of phone.
Hello, Ayumi-chan.
Can you hear me?
Yeah, I can hear you.
A string phone.
We found all the materials
for a string phone.
A long string to connect the two people
and plastic bottles to use as receivers.
You wrapped kite string around the bottles,
and pretended to drink while
issuing instructions to Renno-san.
A little more to the left.
A little more. That's it.
Go farther back... Back!
Just like that.
Th-That's impossible.
H-How could I tell him to use a string
phone if he couldn't hear me?
You agreed on some kind of simple signal.
Like using the string phone when you
pulled twice on the kite string.
Renno-san's wife mentioned that.
But maybe they spoke secretly.
He did tell me to hold on and moved
the phone away from his face.
You can't be serious!
Wh-What proof do you have?
To the right. The right.
Untitled
Audio Playback
Can you walk back about ten steps?
Because you put my phone in your breast
pocket, I was able to record everything.
Hey, what are you doing?!
I-If you keep going—
What?
The voice of the devil.
Go to hell.
Hey, someone fell into the river!
A voice pattern profile would reveal
whose voice it is immediately.
It seems Renno-san just
regained consciousness.
We can ask him directly.
I suspect your motive
is related to Kakura-san's sister, as well.
It's incredible, though, isn't it?
Conan-kun.
He's the reason we were
able to solve the case.
I suspected him from the beginning.
Me, too.
Really?
Well, he used a string phone.
It's a uniquely childish idea.
So what is your PIN?
It's a secret.
Mori Detective Agency
I see.
You never found out what song Ai-chan likes.
Yeah.
Keep it down.
Yoko-chan's giving an interview.
Yoko-chan, we have a special
video message from someone.
What? Who is it?
Huh? My type?
In terms of celebrities?
Well, there's no one in particular.
There's a song I often listen to while warming
up, though I won't tell you whose it is.
It's Okino Yoko-chan's new song "Dandy Lion!"
T-Takahiro!
This bearded old man actually
listens to idol songs.
It's indecent.
I see.
Are you a fan of Yoko-chan?
Well, we attended the same high school.
I really got into her music
after giving it a try.
It gives me energy.
It makes it easier to visualize my shots.
The lyrics remind me of dandelions, though.
I get it.
It's called "Dandy Lion" because
it sounds like dandelions.
That's pretty witty.
Go and get lost!
This must be it.
Episode Preview
Juri, I'm against this relationship.
You should break up with him.
Let me show off sometimes, okay?
Masahiko-san.
We can't go looking for anyone in this snow.
The snow piles high on the
shady side of the mountain.
S-Stop, Aya-neechan!
The Lover Gone Missing in a Snowstorm
The next episode of Conan is "The
Lover Gone Missing in a Snowstorm!"
Cooler
Next Conan's hint!
A cooler!
Don't miss the next episode
The next episode features snow country!
Snowmen!
Snowball fights!
Mysteries.
I'll dis-solve them all.