It's snow! It's snow!
It's snow!
Hey, be careful!
Welcome to the Ice Room boarding house.
We look forward to staying with you.
Nice to meet you.
Hey, guys! Don't forget to greet our hosts!
Nice to meet you!
Let's make a snowman!
Yeah!
I'm sorry.
It's fine.
We three sisters loved playing in
the snow when we were children.
Himuro Ryoko (34)
Oldest Sister
That's right.
Himuro Aya (28)
Middle Sister
Children should play energetically outdoors.
I think they have too much energy.
Some children don't have much.
Himuro Juri (25)
Youngest Sister
A snowball fight? That sounds fun.
Bullseye!
You hit him!
Now you've done it, Genta!
You're still a child.
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
As clues disappear in the snow, what
mysterious trick is left behind?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Lover Gone Missing in a Snowstorm
The Lover Gone Missing in a Snowstorm!
Take this!
Haibara, you're not going to throw snowballs?
I'll pass.
I don't feel like it.
What? What are you making, then?
This isn't a game.
I'm making art.
Making art, huh?
I hit him!
That was amazing, Ayumi-chan!
Sheesh.
Huh? Where's Kojima-kun?
I don't see him anywhere.
Oh, Genta...
There!
...went inside to wipe off his face.
You're evil.
Genta-kun's taking a long time.
Is he okay?
Fine. I'll go check on him.
Genta!
Don't be ridiculous!
Juri, I'm against this relationship.
You should break up with him!
S-Stop, Aya-neechan!
Fujita Masahiko (28)
Juri's Boyfriend
You have no right to say that to me.
Why, you—
Shut up!
Wait, Masahiko-san!
Juri, are you okay?
You're awful, Aya-neechan!
I'm sorry you had to see that.
Who was that?
Fujita Masahiko, Juri's boyfriend.
He's a well-known bad boy where we're from.
Both Ryoko-nee and I oppose
their relationship, but Juri...
Genta.
C-Conan!
Huh? You still have snow on your face.
What? Uh, oh.
And the restroom's right here.
Oh, right.
Sheesh. What is he doing?
What are you doing?
Oh, uh... Nothing.
Children shouldn't be in here.
There are sharp and dangerous knives.
Okay!
Ai-chan, those are amazing!
They're impressive.
They're such bold and daring creations.
It truly is art.
They're quite good if I say so myself.
You seem to be enjoying yourself, too.
Let's head back. I'm hungry.
Hey!
Aya-neesan!
Did you have fun playing in the snow?
Yeah, it was fun!
It was the best!
You should've played with us!
Adults don't get to play in the snow.
Thank you for waiting, everyone.
You made all of this?
Ryoko-nee's a really good cook.
Her two sisters are terrible, though.
What did you say?
Now, now.
Let's eat.
Thanks for the food.
Thanks for the food!
Ayumi-chan, you're not going to eat?
I smell garlic.
I don't want to be stinky when
we're staying here overnight.
You're right.
That's odd, though.
None of these dishes seem
like they used garlic.
I'm stuffed.
I'm impressed.
It was very good.
Thank you.
Oh, right.
Juri, it's time for your medicine.
Did you take it yet?
Oh, no.
Thank you, Aya-neechan.
Keep it together, Juri.
I'm glad she's so carefree,
but she can be unreliable.
No way.
What am I going to do?
I-It's not here!
What's wrong?
My medicine is missing.
Did you look hard for it?
Yes.
Is it bad if you don't have your medicine?
She'll probably be fine if she misses a
dose, but we've never run out before.
What are you doing?
All right. I'll get some at the hospital.
They should give you some, right?
But I can't ask you to do that...
I'm sorry, but could you go for it?
Ryoko-nee...
Let me show off sometimes, okay?
Masahiko-san.
All right. Thank you.
Well, I'll be back soon.
Be careful.
I will.
It's snowing pretty hard.
Yeah.
Hello, this is the Ice Room boarding house.
Yes, that's right.
What? Masahiko-san still hasn't arrived?
You're kidding, right?
He should've arrived a long time ago.
I'll try calling him.
I understand.
Well?
He's not answering his phone.
Could something have happened to him?
We can't go looking for anyone in this snow.
Masahiko's car is still here.
Did he walk there?
The weather report said
it was going to snow.
He must've thought it would
be dangerous to take a car.
Masahiko-san!
Masahiko!
Could it be?
That's—!
I see.
I understand.
The police can't come for a
while because of the snow.
They told us to preserve the crime scene.
Okay.
Did he slip?
Looks like it.
The dirt has been scraped away.
He probably fell from there.
Well, it was probably an accident.
The place where Masahiko-san fell...
What about it?
The snow is piled up strangely
in only that spot.
The mountain side is piled high, but
the snow is low on the cliff side.
You're right.
That's not strange at all.
The snow piles high on the
shady side of the mountain.
You're right, but...
Hey, watch out.
I told you.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
What is this?
Is something wrong?
Something's not right.
Why did Masahiko-san put himself in
danger by taking the steep side road?
That's obvious. Because it's shorter.
Really?
Yes.
You can't take a car down that road,
but it's a faster way into town.
We rarely use it because it's so dangerous.
Aya-san, did you go into
town this evening, too?
Hey!
Y-Yeah. I had some business there.
It's my fault.
Because I forgot my medicine,
Masahiko-san is...
It's no one's fault.
It was probably fate.
That guy got unlucky.
He shouldn't have taken the shortcut.
Is someone there?
Monaka Ice
This is...
Are you okay?
Y-Yes. Thank you.
I just had some trouble breathing.
Should I go get your sisters?
I try not to worry them.
They both love me like a daughter.
Enough that they would do anything for you?
What?
Never mind.
There we go.
This is heavy.
Put it down there.
What are you doing?
I said they didn't have to...
We're going to protect them.
It'd be sad if them melted.
So you put them in a cooler?
How nice.
That's it!
That's how she did it!
What is it?
What did you want to discuss?
I actually discovered the
truth behind this case.
Case? Wasn't it an accident?
No, Masahiko-san's death was no accident.
The culprit made Masahiko-san fall to his
death with a trap in this planned homicide.
What?
W-Wait a minute! There were no signs
of a trap at the scene of the crime!
And we stayed together
after Masahiko-san left.
No one had the opportunity
to dispose of the trap.
No one disposed of it.
What?
The trap is still there.
We just can't see it.
Yes, the culprit used snow and ice.
First the culprit pushed the snow on
the side road towards the mountain.
Then Masahiko-san would avoid the mountain
side and pass next to the cliff.
The culprit restricted his path
and placed a sheet of ice they
froze in the freezer there.
I see. Ice is easily hidden in the
snow and eventually melts.
Wait. That means...
Yes. It leaves no physical evidence.
However, the culprit made a mistake.
I found this where Masahiko-san fell.
What is that?
And this.
That's a package of Monaka Ice
that just went on sale yesterday!
That's right. And these are
pieces of the ice cream bar.
Genta secretly took it from
the boarding house's freezer.
Uh, oh! How did you know?
I thought it was strange.
C-Conan!
You still have snow on your face.
Ayumi-chan, you're not going to eat?
I smell garlic.
She smelled garlic even though
there were no garlic dishes
because Genta was the source of the smell.
I was so hungry.
When Genta-kun secretly ate the ice cream,
the culprit was freezing a pan of water
in the freezer to create a sheet of ice.
Genta-kun's crumbs mixed into
the sheet and froze into it.
The culprit used the sheet without
realizing the pieces were there.
There's no other reason pieces of the
Monaka bar would be at the crime scene.
Yes, the culprit must be one of
this boarding house's residents.
I know! The culprit is Aya-san!
We did witness Aya-san
returning from the side road.
Hey!
She returned with nothing in
her hands and her guard down.
In order to set the trap,
she would need a cooler
to transport the sheet of ice
and a shovel to move the snow.
It would be impossible without any tools.
Besides, the culprit wouldn't
have called out to us.
Aya-san didn't do it. She is a witness.
Most likely Aya-san simply saw the true
culprit returning from the side road.
Though she inspected the
side road out of curiosity,
she probably didn't notice
the trap that was set.
If she had, she probably would
have stopped the culprit.
You're wrong! I didn't see anything!
That's enough, Aya.
He's right. I did it.
I'm like a parent to you, Juri.
I had to exterminate the
evil insect clinging to you.
Ryoko-neesan...
Please understand, Juri.
I did it for you.
This crime can't be committed unless the
sheet of ice is removed from the freezer.
The whole time, Ryoko-san was
making dinner in the kitchen,
where the freezer is located.
The culprit must be Ryoko-san
is what I'd like to say,
but unfortunately, Ryoko-san,
you aren't the culprit, either.
Why not?
You love Juri-san like a daughter.
You would never cause Juri-san to suffer
for the rest of her life by killing someone.
You are simply protecting
the true culprit, Juri-san.
What?
I told you I did it!
I'm the one who hid the ice cream bag!
You did it to protect Juri-san.
No!
Aya, you saw me on the side
road in the evening, right?
Isn't that right?
Stop!
That's enough. Don't protect me anymore.
That's right! I killed him!
That's the medicine that went missing...
You had it the whole time.
She lied.
But Masahiko-san volunteered
to get the medicine.
And there's no way to know
he'd use the side road.
It was easy.
You're so persistent.
What do I need to do to get
you to break up with me?
Fine.
You can just pretend.
I want you to save me when I'm in trouble.
Then I'll let you go.
You instructed him to
take the side road then.
Yes. I told him it was a shortcut.
Then what he said then...
Let me show off sometimes, okay?
He was confirming our plan.
That this was what I had in mind.
It's his fault!
Let's break up.
I have a new girlfriend.
You're so gloomy, slow, and boring.
Maybe you weren't raised right.
I... I... couldn't forgive him.
I'm sorry!
Garlic! Why did it have
to be garlic flavored?!
It's surprisingly good.
Isn't it?
What should I do? It's good...
This is for you.
Why do you have a bulb of real garlic?
And where's my ice cream?!
We ate it!
What?
Episode Preview
Haibara wasn't anywhere.
She must've finished shopping by now.
What happened?
If something happened to her...
This belongs to the kitten
that liked Haibara.
Haibara Ai Imprisonment Case
The next episode of Conan is
"Haibara Ai Imprisonment Case!"
Canned Juice
Next Conan's hint.
Canned juice!
You can't judge a man's worth with chocolate!
Don't miss the next episode.
Did you want it just a little, though?
Yes!