Jerry-building at the Airport Village!
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
A surprising trick that transcends
time and space perplexes Haibara.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Haibara Ai Imprisonment Case
Haibara Ai Imprisonment Case!
Haibara wasn't anywhere.
She must've finished shopping by now.
What happened?
If something happened to her,
it must have happened
here on her way home.
Was she hit by a car?
No way!
I can't imagine that
happening to Haibara-san.
Maybe she got in an accident
at a train crossing.
That's impossible!
A scarf?
It's so small!
That's got nothing to do with Haibara.
No...
This belongs to the kitten
that liked Haibara.
How cute!
Higaki Naoshi
Mitsuru
Midoridai, this is Midoridai Station.
There may be space between
the platform and the doors...
What are you looking at, kitten?
It's a terrarium.
Is there something in it?
It's coming out.
It's an Indian star tortoise.
What a beautiful pattern.
Isn't importing those strictly regulated?
Don't worry.
Higaki Mitsuru (35)
I bought it at a proper store.
Oh?
I'm surprised.
Chiro's taken quite a liking to you.
Hey, kitten!
Chiro-chan, where are you?!
In here!
He fell in.
I'm glad we found him.
No one's home.
But we came all the way
here to return her kitten.
Haibara's not here, either.
The curtains are closed, too.
What's wrong?
Maybe he's hungry...
All you got was a single kitten.
Where did Haibara-san go?
Maybe she was kidnapped.
"I have the girl. Bring the money!"
Did someone think there
was money in the house?
Okay, got it.
Thanks, Detective Chiba.
No accidents have been reported
in this area since this morning.
She would've let us know if
something had happened.
Haibara, everyone's worried about you.
Call us.
What happened to me?
Where am I?
What?
It's so late.
I can't believe I was asleep for five hours.
An Indian star tortoise?
This is Higaki-san's house.
That's right! I...
Chiro?
Your scarf got caught.
I'll get you unstuck right away.
Now hold still...
Ma'am?
Midoridai, Midoridai.
This train will stop for five minutes
to wait for the express train.
Murder in the New Chitose Airport General Purpose Restroom?
News
Murdered
Higaki Naoshi-san (42)
Higaki?
Could it be?
Calm down.
I need to escape.
Thanks for the food.
I'm stuffed.
Why don't we take the kitten
to Higaki-san's place again?
But she wasn't home.
She might have come back by now.
Sitting here certainly won't do any good.
We might as well go.
Yeah.
I got it off!
Help!
The culprit's still here!
Huh?
No one's home?
What?
Yeah, I rang the doorbell six times,
but she's not answering.
I don't know what to do. She
asked me to come around now.
I don't have a choice.
Let her know I'll be back
another time, Chiro.
Bye.
He left a message with a cat and left.
It's Detective Chiba.
A curious object was just delivered
to the police box on Airport Street.
What? A Detective Boy badge?
Yeah. A driver fixing a flat
tire in the area turned it in.
Everyone's worried about you.
Huh?
Call us.
It's pretty far.
We've been driving for an hour already.
Actually, it's only been fifty minutes.
Apparently, it was the police
box near the interchange.
We should be there in a few more minutes.
Did Haibara really come this far?
It's hard to imagine.
Some new homes have been
built near the airport.
Apparently their selling points are their
convenience and total soundproofing.
I see the police box!
Airport Village
Totally Soundproof Homes Near the Airport
That's a huge sign!
Apparently most of them have been sold.
This is it.
That's definitely Ai-kun's badge.
Haibara-san probably threw
it on the ground
to tell us where she was when
she was being taken away.
But we haven't heard from a kidnapper.
We can't assume she's been kidnapped.
These are handcuff keys.
Ma'am, is the culprit here?
Are these handcuff keys?
Can you kneel?
Don't move.
Thank you, Ai-chan.
I'll untie you immediately.
I'm with the police.
Is anyone there?
Is this Higaki Mitsuru-san's home?
What happened?
The Hokkaido police asked
me to check on you.
That must have been quite the disaster.
I'm fine. Have you arrested Naoshi's—
The person who killed my husband?
No, unfortunately.
An investigator from Hokkaido should
arrive to ask you about that.
I don't know anything.
I was tied up here in my
home the whole time.
I was hoping to ask you about
your husband's relationships.
I can tell you about that.
That was some bad luck.
Do you feel better?
Yeah. Sorry for making everyone worry.
Not at all. I'm just glad you're all right.
That was some shopping trip.
A coincidence, huh?
That was an awful coincidence for her.
Someone killed her husband while
her house was being robbed.
Yes. I heard about the incident on the news.
But I couldn't move.
I was with Ai-chan.
Haibara.
What?
You called it an awful coincidence, right?
Is that really what you think?
Do you really think it was all a coincidence?
What?
Why did the robber drag
you inside the house?
If they'd just left you alone, you
would've thought no one was home.
And why were you put to sleep twice?
Was the robber really in
this house for that long?
It took time to crack open the safe.
That's what she said, right?
Yes.
When you were put to sleep the
second time, what was she doing?
What?
I'm asking if you ever saw the
robber and her at the same time.
Help!
The culprit's still here!
I couldn't have.
They came up behind me and put a towel
over my face so I couldn't see anything.
I wasn't in any position to worry about—
Wait a minute! Don't tell me you—
You think the woman and the
robber are the same person.
What?
That's ridiculous!
But why would she do that?
She used me to create
an alibi for the murder.
The robbery and murder.
And Haibara, who was
dragged inside the house.
Maybe it wasn't a coincidence,
but all part of a plan.
Are you saying she used Chiro so
I would corroborate her alibi?
No one would suspect her if she traveled to
and from Hokkaido while you were asleep.
What if that was her plan?
That's impossible.
There's no way she could
have committed the crime.
A direct flight to the New Chitose
Airport only takes an hour and a half.
How long does it take to get
from here to the airport?
It takes about an hour by car, so
that's two and a half hours total.
If it's two and a half hours one
way, then a round trip would take...
Five hours!
Waiting for the victim at the airport
would have taken some time, too.
It would take at least five and a half hours.
No, but...
I woke up and saw her just after two.
I was asleep for just barely five hours.
I'm also curious as to why your detective
badge was found on Airport Street.
That's it! The doorbell!
Someone came to the door
and rang the doorbell.
It was around 2:30.
I got it off!
That must have been then!
Yeah, the liquor store delivery!
Huh?
No one's home?
What?
Yeah, I rang the doorbell six times,
but she's not answering.
Wait!
Six times? I only heard it ring twice.
And it didn't ring continuously.
It rang more slowly.
What?
I knew it.
What do you mean?
The doorbell and station announcements
were recordings set to play by the culprit.
Then it all makes sense.
I think I understand what
you're thinking, Edogawa-kun.
There are two houses, aren't there?
Wh-What?
What are you talking about?
I see.
There wasn't enough time for the culprit
to travel to and back from Hokkaido.
But if Haibara-san awoke inside a
different house near the airport...
The ones advertised on the sign!
Airport Village
Totally Soundproof Homes Near the Airport
The Airport Village near the airport?
Yeah. If Ai-chan was being kept
inside of one of those homes...
The culprit wouldn't need as much time
traveling to and from the airport.
That would save two hours.
The turtle made you think
the two homes were one.
The whole terrarium can be transported.
She played the recording of
the doorbell at the fake house
when the liquor store delivery
was supposed to arrive.
I was put to sleep twice so the culprit
could transport me and the turtle.
But how can we prove there were two houses?
There are a ton of homes.
The finish line is in sight.
Can you remember anything else?
Well...
Chiro!
I'm glad I finished that.
What was that?
The can started rolling
in a different direction?
Jerry-building at the Airport Village!
Yes. When I woke up the second
time, the can didn't budge.
I know! That must be it!
Genta, lift the edge of the table slightly.
Okay.
How's this?
Good. Watch this.
It changed direction, right?
How does this relate to Haibara-san's story?
This is what Edogawa-kun's trying to say!
Plastic Bottles Roll
Continuously Across the Floor
Apparently the floors are like a slide.
I found it immediately in the
real estate company's list.
I'm sending you a photo of the house.
You certainly are unlucky.
The fake home you purchased and
remodeled was poorly constructed.
Was Detective Takagi at the Airport Village?
Yes. Jerry-building is a crime.
Takagi-kun happened to be in the area.
Well done, Detective Boys.
Yeah!
She did it for the very ordinary
reason of divorce complications.
I see.
Was the culprit always after Ai-kun?
Yes, it seems that way.
She's smart, strong-willed, and
was often seen scolding you.
She thought she would
make a perfect witness.
Does she scold me that often?
In any case, let the Detective Boys know the
case has been resolved without any issue.
I will.
Goodbye.
Hey, Haibara.
Did something happen? You're smiling.
I suppose.
What happened? Tell us.
Well...
What? Really?
That's great!
Shall we go?
Yeah!
Yes!
Haibara's running off with
a smile on her face...
Hey!
Wait! Tell me what happened, too!
It's a secret!
Hey, wait!
They found someone to adopt
Chiro and the tortoise, huh?
Even if the owner commits a
crime, the animal is innocent.
Episode Preview
Stay back. You'd better stay back.
C-Calm down!
Ayumi!
Ayumi-chan!
Damn it!
Rubber skid marks?
This is...
I knew it.
The Troublesome Emergency Patient
The next episode of Conan is
"The Troublesome Emergency Patient!"
Clippings
Next Conan's hint!
Clippings.
Thanks for the help.
Don't miss the next episode.
I'll save you as many times
as I have to, Haibara-san!
Thanks...