Ai-chan, do you want to come to my house?
We have some cookies my
mom baked yesterday.
Sorry, but I'll pass.
Then I'll eat those cookies.
Genta-kun, you like broiled eel.
I will eat the cookies.
Do they make broiled eel cookies?
That sounds good.
Even if they did exist, I wouldn't eat them.
Wait! Stop!
Stay back. You'd better stay back.
C-Calm down!
Ayumi!
Ayumi-chan!
Damn it!
I'm sorry.
What?
I'm really...
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
Who is wrong and who is right?
The invisible relationship between
a doctor and his patient.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Troublesome Emergency Patient
The Troublesome Emergency Patient!
Beika Emergency Medical Center
You don't know who he is?
No. All he had on him was a knife and wallet.
He had nothing identifying on him.
His fingerprints didn't match
any criminal records, either.
Why was a policeman chasing him?
For questioning.
While being questioned about 100 meters
away from Conan-kun and his friends,
he suddenly ran away.
Since he had a knife, was he
trying to commit a robbery?
Do you think he got in a
fistfight with the policeman?
A fistfight?
The man had an injury on his head.
Apparently he was already unsteady
when he was being questioned.
He was stopped because
he was acting suspicious.
What happened to him?
We're with the police.
What's the patient's status?
He's suffering from intracerebral
hemorrhaging from a blow to the head.
Kido Tatsuhiko (40)
Emergency Medical Doctor
It's a very dangerous and
unpredictable situation.
Did someone hit him?
Or did he fall?
I can't be sure.
I see.
We don't know who he is or what happened.
I'm beat.
Are there signs of dental work or surgery?
Maybe his medical records
can tell us something.
I'm surprised you know about that, son.
Oh, um...
I heard about it from Kogoro-no-ojisan...
Kogoro-no-ojisan?
He's the Sleeping Kogoro.
The great detective Mori Kogoro!
What?
And we're the Detective Boys!
Will that man be okay?
Ayumi, you're on his side?
That's right.
He's a bad man who held a knife to you.
It was shocking and scary, but
he didn't seem like such a bad man to me.
And?
There are no signs of surgery.
I'll have one of our dentists
see about his teeth.
We should have answers for you later.
Excuse me.
Inspector!
Mori-kun.
I see.
You have no clues.
We'll just have to wait for
him to regain consciousness.
What's this thing sticking out of his wallet?
Scoop
Haido Construction Suspected of Bribery
It's a magazine clipping.
See?
That's the political and business
scandal that has the media buzzing.
Could this have something to do with that?
Could someone be trying to kill him?
If that's the case,
they may try to kill him again.
Station officers at the hospital immediately!
Coordinate with Department Two!
Ask the district public prosecutor's
office for assistance, too!
Yes, sir!
This is really blowing up!
I'm not sure what's going
on, but it's exciting!
What do you think?
Yeah...
Ayumi-chan.
Just before he collapsed,
did he say anything to you?
What?
Um...
Now that you mention it....
Huh?
I'm sorry. It's Daddy's fault he's so useless.
I'm really sorry.
Daddy? That guy's your dad?
No, Genta-kun.
Huh?
He was probably confused and mistook
Ayumi-chan for his own child.
The question is whether or not that
has anything to do with this incident.
Yeah.
Conan-kun, let's investigate!
What?
I just can't believe he's a bad man.
I want to help him!
Okay, let's give it a shot.
All right! Detective Boys—
We're in a hospital, Genta-kun.
L-Let's go.
Yeah.
He came from that way, right?
He was being questioned about
100 meters away, right?
Then he ran.
Let's check it out.
Oh, I remember him.
Over there.
He got out of a taxi right over there.
Hurry up! You're in the way!
The person who got in after
him was rather violent.
Maybe he got the injury on his head then.
I'm not so sure.
Ma'am, do you know which
company that taxi belonged to?
Who knows? My eyesight hasn't
been very good lately.
But I remember the rough fellow very well.
What?
Really, ma'am?
Have we found the culprit already?
He's a naughty kid who's been
shopping here since he was little.
Around this time, he should be...
Who are you?
Hello, mister.
Hello!
Wh-What do you want?
You're distracting me. Go away.
Why were you in such a hurry?
What?
You pushed a man out of your
way getting into a taxi.
That man's unconscious right now!
Y-You're kidding, right?
That wasn't very nice of you.
Apologize to him!
W-Wait! I was just in a hurry!
Yeah, why?
Do you think it's true?
He said he was late for work,
and was going to be fired
if he was late again.
There's no way we can believe him.
That's why we're going to
check it out right now.
Also, according to the old woman,
he didn't seem well even
before he was pushed.
At the very least...
He didn't do it.
That's right.
Yeah, he told me to hurry up because
he was nearly late for work.
Do you remember the man riding before him?
The customer before him?
Yeah. He didn't seem well
from the moment he got in.
Where did he ask to go?
Nowhere. He just told me
to follow the car in front.
The car in front?
But I didn't see a car.
So he said, “Fine, I'm getting out.”
That was where we were earlier...
He got out of a taxi right over there.
Where did you pick up the man?
Let's see.
Here it is.
Haido-cho Sanchome.
Haido-cho Sanchome?
That's pretty far away from here.
What should we do? Should we go there?
Yeah, of course.
Will you take us there?
Yeah, sure.
But don't tell anyone.
We keep this place secret.
From our company, anyway.
I see. It's the perfect place to nap.
And the perfect place to slack off.
Did that man get in here?
Yeah. As usual, I was...
Hey, isn't Haido-cho Sanchome...?
Yeah, I was thinking the same thing.
What?
This is the next town over,
but geographically, it's actually
right next to that other place.
What other place?
That.
Beika Emergency Medical Center
The answer is in the hospital.
Let's go!
Are these rubber skid marks?
He told me to follow the car in front.
Could he have meant this car?
If that's true, then what is
that car doing parked here?
Whose car is it, anyway?
Kido
Kido?
This is...
It must be his.
Yeah.
Look. There's something that
could be evidence here.
There are two different types of clothing
fibers stuck to the bench in two places.
Fresh Paint
Now we just need an explanation
for his possessions...
Huh?
Wh-What is this?
Now on Sale
Broiled Eel Cookies
Wow, they do exist! Broiled eel cookies!
Genta-kun, we don't have
time for that right now!
Whoever made this is awfully
stingy or frugal, though.
They even used the back of this flier.
Maybe...
Scoop
Haido Construction Suspected of Bribery
It's the article from last week's magazine.
Yeah. The question is what's behind this.
I knew it.
Inspector, why did you ask me to come here?
Actually, I...
Inspector!
What's the meaning of this, Mori-kun?
Why aren't you investigating
the bribery case?
What? Inspector, you told me to come here
so you could reveal the
truth behind the case...
There it is! The Sleeping Kogoro!
Sleeping Kogoro?
Excuse me.
Allow me to explain.
First, Dr. Kido, isn't that your car?
Yes, but what's going on?
I'll be direct.
The unidentified man ended up that way...
...because of you, Dr. Kido.
Wh-What?
Conan!
Yes!
Ayumi-chan, when that man grabbed
you, did you notice anything?
Yeah. When he grabbed me...
Huh?
I'm sorry. It's Daddy's
fault he's so useless.
I'm really sorry.
What else?
Um...
I smelled something!
You smelled something?
What kind of smell was it?
Was it broiled eel?
Genta-kun!
The same smell I noticed at the hospital.
In other words, it's the common smell
tying the victim to the culprit.
This is ridiculous.
If he smelled like a hospital,
or in other words, disinfectant,
he could've been a patient
at another hospital.
You're forcing the connection
between myself and the culprit,
Mister Detective.
He's right, Mori-kun.
It's not the smell of
disinfectant, but paint.
Paint?
Yes. That smell stuck to the
culprit and victim right here.
The two of them fought here, and the
freshly applied paint stuck to them.
As the fleeing culprit tried
to shake off the victim,
his button tore off.
He was thrown to the ground and hit his head.
Then he descended the stairs to the
vacant lot below and got in a taxi.
Inspector Megure!
Where have you two been?
We had forensics dust this car's windows
for fingerprints at Mori-san's request,
and they match the patient's.
Also, the button Conan-kun found here
is the same as the ones on his clothes.
I'm sorry.
I had them assist me.
That's fine, but why did he do this?
His motive was the magazine clipping.
What? Does this have something to
do with the bribery case, then?
No, it's what's on the back.
Isn't that right, Doctor?
The back?
This is it.
Huh?
“Medical Emergency Sites”
Problems and Solutions
Kido Tatsuhiko
Kido Tatsuhiko (40)
Emergency Medical Doctor
Beika Emergency Medical Center
It's an ad for Dr. Kido's book.
Doctor.
It happened a month ago.
A passenger has suddenly fallen ill.
Is there a doctor on board?
Excuse me, but are you a doctor?
Once again...
What?
You're reading a medical
journal, so I thought...
Please!
My child... My daughter has a fever!
Will you examine her?
I'm sorry, but I'm not a doctor.
What? But...
I have a wife and child.
I couldn't risk my relationship with
the woman with me becoming public.
It should have ended then.
If he hadn't shown up this morning when
I was returning from the night shift...
You are a doctor!
You lied!
He thought my behavior suspicious,
and found me through the
journal I was reading.
Don't tell me you forgot!
My daughter was taken to a hospital
after that at the next station!
But we were too late!
My daughter... Apologize to my daughter!
According to his story, she died because her
chronic condition took a turn for the worse.
It wasn't about whether or not I could
have saved her if I had examined her then.
He couldn't forgive me for lying.
That's what he told me.
And I agree.
So I thought it was divine punishment
instead of coincidence or irony
that he was brought to my
hospital and became my patient.
You may not believe me,
but I wanted to save him.
If I had regarded his daughter
the same way, then maybe...
I...
...regret what I've done.
What's this? Why do I still feel
like something's not right?
Where is the jacket with paint on it?
There, in the trunk of the car.
It's not here.
That's impossible!
It must be here...
I see! That's how it is!
What's wrong, Conan-kun?!
That's murder!
Were you riding in Dr. Kido's car with him?
Morita Natsumi (25)
Nurse
When you said you'd dispose
of the paint-stained jacket,
the doctor refused, didn't he?
Yes.
The doctor may intend to turn
himself in if he saves this man.
If he does that, everyone
will know I'm his mistress!
So... So I...
He's awake!
I'm glad.
Beika Emergency Medical Center
I'm sorry for getting you involved in this.
It's okay. I'm glad you're all right.
Anyway, what's your name?
Oh, right. I forgot to introduce myself.
Forgot?
Huh? Come to think of it, I think
I'm forgetting something...
So cold...
Huh?
What am I doing here?
I guess I should go home.
Huh?
Fresh Paint
I can't move!
Someone help!
Episode Preview
Get out, you hack detective!
You're amazing.
What?
You knew they were a stranger
based only on their name.
Do you mind if we use the teabags we brought?
Oh, but I already have so many.
The Tense Tea Party
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is “The
Tense Tea Party, Part One!”
Herb Tea
Next Conan's Hint!
Herb Tea!
Don't miss the next episode.
What's at the center of the next episode?
A too tense tea party.
Is that wordplay?