The balls were really flowing today!
What a great haul!
I'm so lucky!
I think I'll surprise Ran for always making fun of me for playing pachinko!
I'm home!
The pachinko king has returned!
Hey!
A letter?
What's this?
"I'm going to the hospital."
"At least turn your phone on."
"Ran."
My phone?
Whoops! It was off...
Thirty-four missed calls
and sixteen messages?
Wh-What?!
Mom wasn't feeling well at work,
and she's about to go into surgery!
We're are Haido Central
Hospital, so get here soon!
Ran.
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire on the line to the heart.
Running into Amuro at Central Hospital.
An incident occurs while four ladies are having tea.
Always determining the one truth with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Tense Tea Party
(Part One)
"The Tense Tea Party, Part One!"
Eri!
Haido Central Hospital
Mori Eri-sama
Eri!
Why are you making so much noise?
Wh-Why?
You had surgery.
It was just appendicitis.
The surgery ended a while ago.
The anesthesia wore off, and I just woke up.
It was just your appendix?
It wasn't "just" her appendix!
What were you doing with your phone off?
I'm sure it was horses, mahjong, or pachinko.
You idiot! I was working...
Wasn't it pachinko?
What?
Your jacket has a weird
wrinkle near your butt.
What?
Doesn't that mean you were sitting
in a chair for a long time?
No, I, uh...
Also, your phone must have been off
because you were
somewhere loud enough
that you couldn't hear your phone ringing.
You don't like to set your phone to vibrate
because you think it's gross.
And look. Between your shoelaces...
You have a pachinko ball.
You were definitely playing pachinko.
That's amazing, Conan-kun.
I-I happened to see a mystery
show just like this...
I see.
You were captivated by pachinko
while I was having an emergency.
What?
I-I just meant to go for a little while, but I was having such unusually good luck...
Anyway, you should squeeze
one out so you can leave.
Well, you know...
When you have appendix troubles, they say
you can leave the hospital once you fart.
Don't tell me you think you're being clever.
I thought that was pretty
good, if I say so myself—
Get out, you hack detective!
Sheesh.
I came because I was worried about her, and she's getting mad at me?
Of course she's mad.
Huh?
Is that you, Mori-sensei?
What are you doing here?
Bourbon?
Are you not feeling well?
No, it's my wife.
Why?
What's a member of the Black Organization
doing at Haido Central Hospital?
Could it be?
Could it be?!
What are you doing here?
I heard one of my friends was
hospitalized and came to see him,
but he apparently disappeared.
The nurses told me you'd been here before,
so maybe you know.
Huh?
A man named Kusuda Rikumichi.
Who is that? I don't know him.
I was hoping he'd return
the money I lent him.
Are you sure you don't know him?
Yup.
You're amazing.
What?
Excuse me.
Do you know a patient
named Kusuda Rikumichi?
Kusuda Rikumichi-san...
Beppu Katsuki (41)
Visitor
I'm not sure.
Who is he?
How old is he?
Do you have a photo of him?
Happo Tokie (42)
Visitor
Oh, no. It's fine.
Are you sure?
What about you, Mori-sensei?
What would you do if someone suddenly
asked if you knew someone by name?
Well, I'd probably respond
like those ladies did.
That's right.
Most people don't have total
confidence in their own memory.
That's why before answering no,
they ask for information about
the person besides their name.
That's why you're amazing, Conan-kun.
You knew he was a stranger
based only on his name.
You shouldn't take children so seriously.
Plenty of people will say they don't recognize
someone by name even when they've met.
Some people only know
others by a nickname.
Three, two, one...
Zero!
Mom, the elevator's here.
Okay, okay.
Hurry up.
Is something wrong?
No, nothing.
My nickname is "Zero," so I
thought someone was calling me.
Why Zero? Isn't your name Toru?
Being transparent means
there's nothing there.
Hence Zero.
That's how children come up with nicknames.
Kusuda Rikumichi?
What about him?
Someone in the hallway
just asked if I knew him.
I don't know him, either.
Kosaka Juri (42)
Patient
I have a private room,
and I don't have many opportunities
to speak with other patients.
Anyway, great news!
I hear you're getting out of
the hospital tomorrow.
Yes.
You should've told us.
Doesn't that make our visit meaningless?
Thanks for waiting!
Reina!
Suto Reina (42)
Visitor
You two came?
Let's have some tea.
I got some hot water.
Good idea.
Could you get three teacups
from that cabinet over there?
Is three enough?
I have this cup I'm using.
Oh? Did you buy new cups?
Are you sure we should use these?
Yes. They just look new because I clean
them with baking soda after each use.
You're so precise.
I even bought lemons.
I see you still like lemons.
Do you mind if we use
the teabags we brought?
Oh, but I already have so many.
Why don't we compare a few teas?
Great idea!
Now this is a real ladies' party.
I suppose we can celebrate
your hospital discharge early.
Your wife suddenly developed appendicitis?
Yeah. I shouldn't have worried.
But you shouldn't make light of appendicitis.
I guess.
Could he be...?
These photos brings back memories!
It's from the school festival!
Do you keep all your old
photos on your phone?
Only the ones I like.
Wasn't it this school festival?
When Reina got Sosaki-kun.
Who's Sosaki-kun?
The most popular boy in our class.
Who?
Reina-san, you're so lucky.
That's not true.
The other day I nearly
lost a fortune in stocks.
My husband's just a nouveau riche.
I thought my son had a simple cold during
his exams, but it turned out to be the flu.
Everything was ruined because
we didn't notice in time.
I'm walking on a tightrope.
One wrong step, and I'll be at rock bottom.
Did that scream come from this room?
Yes.
Is something wrong?
Reina?!
Reina!
I can't believe someone was poisoned at the hospital.
By the time the doctor arrived, it was already too late.
Who's the victim?
Haido resident Suto Reina,
Forty-two years old.
Today, she came to the hospital
with two of her high school
classmates to see Kosaka Juri,
another one of her classmates.
Suto-san arrived before her other two friends.
The cause of death seems to be
asphyxiation caused by cyanide poison.
Yes.
But why was she drinking tea at a hospital?
The patient Kosaka-san liked tea,
and they always held tea parties
when the four of them got together.
I see.
Then that means those three had the
opportunity to poison the victim.
But the victim drank several cups
of tea without any problem
when she suddenly seemed to be in pain.
What?
It's possible she had been made to
swallow a poison capsule beforehand.
Then it's possible the crime
wasn't committed here.
Huh? Something's not right.
What?
Look.
The phone dropped over here
had lots of pictures on it,
but the dead lady has
chopsticks in her right hand.
Hey!
You can't just touch things at a crime scene!
What's strange about it, though?
It's normal for people to hold
chopsticks in their right hand.
But the cup that broke on the floor...
Look closely.
There's lipstick on the right side of the handle.
Doesn't that mean she was
drinking tea with her left hand?
Y-You're right...
But why did the victim use her left hand?
It's because she had
something in her right hand.
For example, she may have been
looking at pictures on her phone.
Pictures on...
...her phone?
Yes.
When people focus on one
thing, they ignore all others.
Even if the position of the cup
or its handle were changed,
she would pick it up without noticing.
The culprit must have used this tendency
to make the victim drink the poison
by switching their own
poisoned cup with the victim's.
Switching them?
Yes.
Putting poison in your own cup and
switching it with the victim's
is safer than directly
poisoning the victim's cup.
No one seemed to be using saucers,
so it would be easy to
adjust the cups' positions.
Isn't that right, Mori-sensei?
Y-Yes, I suppose...
This detective again?
Th-There's no way we could switch them!
Only her tea had lemon slices in it.
And look closely at the
color of everyone's tea.
The color?
All three are different.
From right to left, there's
brown, blue, and yellow.
The victim was drinking a reddish tea.
You couldn't get these teas confused.
In any case, if someone poisoned the tea,
there must be a container or
bag used to contain the poison.
Maybe a thorough search of the
room will turn up something.
Yes.
The culprit may still have
it on their person, too.
After we search the three of you,
we'll question you separately
in another room.
Is that all right?
Y-Yes...
Yes, that's right.
I made everyone's tea.
After all, they were my guests.
But all I did was put the tea
bags in cups and add water.
Are you the only one who touched the cups?
No.
Happo-san and Beppu-san got
the cups out of the cupboard.
In other words, it would make sense to
find everyone's fingerprints on the cups.
But why did you make so
many different kinds of tea?
Normally you only use one.
Everyone knows I like herb tea, so
I had received quite a few as gifts.
Happo-san brought some as well.
I thought we could compare teas.
I see.
As the person who suggested you compare
teas and then made the tea,
it was easiest for you to poison the tea.
I-I didn't do anything like that!
Everyone saw me pour the water,
and Suto-san drank nearly half
her tea before she collapsed.
Besides, as I told you before,
she would have noticed immediately
if I had switched my
poisoned cup with hers.
What? Why?
I was drinking a blue herb
tea called "Butterfly Tea."
She would have noticed
if I had switched ours.
Suto-san was drinking a red
herb tea called "Hibiscus Tea."
Do you know what the
other two were drinking?
Yes.
Happo-san was drinking a brown
herb tea called "Peppermint,"
and Beppu-san was drinking a
yellow herb tea called "Chamomile."
Yes, I was drinking Peppermint.
I thought it would be green,
but I was disappointed
when I saw it was brown.
You know, because of the
color "peppermint green."
Juri, who knows more about
tea than I do, was giggling.
But red and brown look pretty similar.
It would've been easiest for you to switch—
They look nothing alike!
Mine was a common brown,
but Reina's was a garish red!
Surely she couldn't have confused these!
Did everyone choose their own tea?
Yes.
We lined them up on the table
and chose what we wanted.
Once we finished drinking,
we wiped the cups with
tissues for our next cup.
Juri had been drinking a
blue tea before we arrived.
She said it was healthy but bitter,
so she didn't recommend it.
How were the four of you seated?
Let's see.
Clockwise it was me, Reina,
Katsuki, and Juri, I believe.
Katsuki and I looked from
either side of Reina
at the cell phone pictures
she was looking at.
Who suggested you look at the photos?
Katsuki!
Apparently Juri had shown
them to her before.
She wanted to show everyone
the next time we visited.
But Reina wouldn't let go of her phone.
Katsuki and I had to look over her shoulder.
She's always been that way.
She's possessive, self-absorbed,
and indifferent.
Her current husband is my ex-boyfriend.
She took him from me.
She took him from me!
Oh, but I didn't want to hurt her.
I see...
Katsuki probably hated her more than I did.
She was upset about the heavy
loss she suffered because of Reina.
Heavy loss?
Of course I was upset.
The stock Reina recommended
to me crashed!
I nearly lost a fortune,
but Reina made a killing selling
all her stock before it dropped!
Y-You have our sympathies...
Now I'm drowning in debt.
She could've told me if she
knew it was going to fall.
Is that why you killed her?
If that would've brought my money
back, I might have considered it!
I don't want to speak ill of the dead,
but I think Juri may have hated her, too.
Juri's son failed his entrance
exam because of Reina.
What do you mean, failed?
Juri and Reina's children are classmates.
They were trying to get into
the same middle school,
but Reina's son, who came over to
study the day before the exam,
was sick with the flu.
Juri's son got it from him,
and he didn't have time to worry
about the entrance exam anymore.
Y-You have our sympathies...
Juri seemed so optimistic about
the results before the exam.
In other words, everyone
had motive to kill the victim.
Yes.
We told you!
None of us would ever do that.
We all resented her,
but Reina had always been that
way, so we just dealt with it.
Hey.
Did anyone leave the room once
you started drinking tea?
Y-Yes.
Tokie and I each left once separately.
I went to the restroom.
Tokie went to buy snacks for the tea.
I believe Juri and Reina were
in the room the whole time.
Reina went to get hot water,
but that was before Tokie and I arrived.
Ow!
When did you—
Do those tea cups belong to the hospital?
Oh, those are Juri's cups.
She said she keeps them sparkling
clean with baking soda.
That means she's the only one who
could have poisoned the victim's tea.
The question is how did she make
the victim pick up the cup?
Episode Preview
The lip of the teacup?
Someone put poison there?
The culprit must have been pretty bold.
What?
Well? Do you know?
Only one person could have applied poison
to their own cup and watched for an
opportunity to switch it with the victim's.
It's you.
The next episode of Conan is
"The Tense Tea Party, Part Two!"
The Tense Tea Party
(Part Two)
Lemons
Next Conan's Hint!
Lemons!
Don't miss the next episode.
Lemons remind me of Shinichi.
Really?
He must be a sour man.
No, I'm not.