Returning home after playing pachinko,
Kogoro-no-occhan learned
Kisaki-sensei was having surgery
to treat a sudden illness and
rushed to Haido Central Hospital.
However, Kisaki-sensei had appendicitis.
When he learned she was fine,
we left her hospital room and...
Huh?
Is that you, Mori-sensei?
What are you doing here?
Bourbon?
Are you not feeling well?
No, it's my wife...
Why?
What's a member of the Black Organization doing at Haido Central Hospital?
Could it be? Could it be? Could it be?!
What are you doing here?
I heard one of my friends was
hospitalized and came to see him,
but he apparently disappeared.
The nurses told me you'd been here before,
so maybe you know.
Huh?
A man named Kusuda Rikumichi.
Who is that? I don't know him.
You're amazing.
What?
Most people don't have total
confidence in their own memory.
That's why before answering no,
they ask for information about
the person besides their name.
That's why you're amazing, Conan-kun.
You knew he was a stranger
based only on his name.
You shouldn't take children so seriously.
Plenty of people will say they don't recognize
someone by name even when they've met.
Some people only know
others by a nickname.
Three, two, one...
Zero!
What?
Is something wrong?
No, nothing.
My nickname is "Zero," so I
thought someone was calling me.
Why Zero? Isn't your name Toru?
Being transparent means
there's nothing there.
Hence Zero.
That's how children come up with nicknames.
These photos brings back memories.
It's from the school festival.
Do you keep all your old
photos on your phone?
Only the ones I like.
Wasn't it this school festival?
When Reina got Sosaki-kun.
Reina-san, you're so lucky.
That's not true.
Suto Reina
(42) Visitor
The other day I nearly
lost a fortune in stocks.
My husband's just a nouveau riche.
I thought my son had a simple
cold during his exams,
but it turned out to be the flu.
Everything would have been ruined
if we hadn't noticed in time.
I'm walking on a tightrope.
One wrong step, and I'd be at rock bottom.
Did that scream come from this room?
Yes.
Is something wrong?
Reina?!
Reina!
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
An herb tea stained with revenge.
Solving mysteries from scratch with Amuro.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Tense Tea Party
(Part 2)
The Tense Tea Party, Part Two!
Inspector Megure!
We finished examining the hospital room,
but we didn't find a container or bag
that could have contained the poison.
I see.
It's likely the culprit threw it away outside.
Also, we didn't find poison
in the spilled tea.
What?
Then how was she poisoned?
Actually, the poison was on...
Was it on the teacup's—
Hey!
What are you doing?
I looked all over the hospital for you!
R-Ran-neechan...
I told you not to wander off like that.
But...
I told you not to do that.
I told you not to fight anymore.
But...
I won't be able to treat you
if you get hurt next time.
After all, I'm going far away.
It'll be goodbye, Rei-kun.
Goodbye, Rei-kun.
Hey.
Hey, are you okay?
Hey!
What's wrong with you?
Mori-sensei...
Is this homicide too much for you, too?
You haven't solved it yet, right?
Then there's no way I have.
You've got that right.
Come on!
We're leaving!
B-B-But the case!
The case?
I heard police sirens earlier...
Did something happen at the hospital?
Yeah.
A lady was poisoned and died.
Inspector Megure and Detective Takagi and
Kogoro-no-ojisan have no idea who did it.
But, Conan-kun, look outside.
The blue sky has turned bright red.
It's time for children to go home.
What?
The blue sky...
Turns red...
Red...
That's it! That's how she did it!
So let Dad and the police handle the case...
Hey.
Come on!
Conan-kun?
I solved the mystery.
She's the culprit.
And I'm sure sure you know
how she did it, too,
Zero!
The lip of the cup?
There was poison there?
Yes. Just around the lipstick stain.
When the victim Suto Reina-san
brought the cup to her lips,
she drank the poison along with her tea.
There were no traces of
poison inside the cup.
Beppu Katsuki
(41) Visitor
You think one of us poisoned the cup
just before Reina drank her tea?
Wouldn't someone have noticed?
Happo Tokie (42)
Visitor
Kosaka Juri (42)
Patient
Nobody did anything like that.
Weren't you listening to Amuro?
The culprit didn't poison her cup.
They poisoned their own cup and
switched it with the victim's.
And we're saying that's not possible!
I was drinking yellow chamomile.
I was drinking brown peppermint tea.
And I was drinking blue butterfly tea.
Even if one of us had swapped our tea
with the red hibiscus tea
Suto-san was drinking,
she would've noticed immediately.
But only the victim had a
lemon slice in her tea, right?
If her view was limited, she may
not have noticed a change in color.
They look nothing alike!
Not that an old man who knows nothing
about herb tea would understand!
Now, now.
In any case, it's a fact that the culprit
killed Suto-san by poisoning her cup.
Because we didn't find the container
for the poison in this room,
Beppu-san and Happo-san, the
culprit must be one of you two,
who left the room one after another.
I see.
After poisoning the cup, the culprit left
the room and disposed of the container.
Yes.
Wait a minute!
I just went to the restroom.
And I went to the convenience
store to buy snacks for the tea.
I even have a receipt.
A search of the restroom's plumbing
and the way to the convenience
store should turn up something.
But the culprit must have been pretty bold.
What?
Conan-kun!
If I poisoned the cup,
I definitely wouldn't leave.
If someone wiped the cup,
moved it, or poured a new
type of tea while I was gone,
I wouldn't know which cup
was poisoned anymore.
You're right.
Then how and when did the
culprit poison the cup?
And where did the container
for the poison go?
We'll have to search the room again.
You don't have to do that.
Huh?
There's one person who could've openly
poisoned the cup and never left it.
Right,
Zero-no-niichan?
Apparently Amuro-no-niichan used to
be called Zero when he was a kid.
Well? Do you know who it is?
Y-Yes.
I think I know from Conan-kun's hint.
She was able to poison the cup
and dispose of the container.
Without leaving the room,
she applied poison to her own cup,
and watched for an opportunity
to switch it with the victim's.
Only you could have done it.
She was able to poison the cup
and dispose of the container.
Without leaving the room,
she applied poison to her own cup,
and watched for an opportunity
to switch it with the victim's.
Only you could have done it.
Kosaka Juri-san.
W-Wait a minute.
How could she have poisoned her own cup?
Juri was drinking tea from
that cup the whole time.
Did you forget?
The poison was on the side you'd drink from
when holding the cup in your left hand.
As long as you're careful
not to use your left hand,
you'll never touch the poison.
Then when did she poison the cup?
She probably brought the poison to the
hospital before she was hospitalized.
She poisoned her own cup the
day her friends were visiting,
and threw the container away
outside her room somewhere.
Right?
Y-You're the one who's forgetting!
Juri was drinking a blue herb tea,
and Reina was drinking a red herb tea!
Even with a lemon,
she couldn't have swapped them!
Yes. That lemon is the key to her trick.
The key?
Yes. The truth is...
Wow, it's really blue.
This butterfly tea sure is mysterious.
Hey!
You're touching evidence again!
I just got this water from the hospital.
And this lemon.
Damn kid! That's enough out of you...
Huh? That's weird!
This tea was blue, but it started
turning red after I added a lemon.
S-Seriously?
This is incredible.
It's like a science experiment.
The acid in the lemon
causes it to change color.
There are other herb teas
that react the same way.
Like blue mallow tea?
When you add lemons,
it changes from blue to pink.
Yes.
Naturally, if acid makes it turn red,
then adding the alkaline baking soda
Kosaka-san used to clean her cups
makes it turn blue again.
In other words, these are
the steps Kosaka-san took.
First, knowing your friends were visiting,
you asked Suto-san to come a little early.
You had her go get hot water
so you could have a tea party.
While she was gone,
you poisoned the side opposite
the one you were using with the
poison you brought to the hospital,
and threw the container
away outside your room.
Once your friends arrived,
you suggested comparing teas,
and waited for Suto-san to
choose the hibiscus tea.
The hibiscus tea is a purplish
red which looks very similar
to butterfly tea when lemons are added.
After Suto-san chose the hibiscus tea,
you put in her cup a teabag
whose contents were switched out
for butterfly tea beforehand, put
a lemon on top, and added water
allowing you to serve Suto-san
butterfly tea the color of hibiscus tea.
I see.
Then how did she switch the cups?
She did it when Suto-san and her friends
were looking at the pictures on her phone.
First she put a lemon in her own
poisoned cup of blue butterfly tea
to make it turn red and nudged
Suto-san's cup with her own.
She pretended to take her own cup
while actually taking Suto-san's,
removed the lemon, and added baking
soda, making it blue again.
Then she nudged the poisoned
cup with her own again,
putting the cup's handle on the left
side from Suto-san's perspective.
Because Suto-san was distracted by the phone,
she knew she could make her pick up
the poisoned cup with her left hand.
Am I wrong?
You make it sound as though you were
watching, but what proof do you—
Huh?
Your left thumb is red.
Did you hurt yourself?
No, I...
There was one other thing the culprit
had to remove from the crime scene.
The lipstick on Suto-san's original cup.
It would be strange to find
lipstick on Kosaka-san's cup.
She quickly wiped it off with her finger, but
lipstick can be difficult to remove without soap.
In other words, if this red color matches
Suto-san's lipstick, it will prove she did it.
If you examine Suto-san's cup,
you'll find proof there as well.
A significant amount of baking
soda was mixed into the tea.
But how did she add the baking soda?
She sprinkled the sugar cubes on the table
with baking soda and hid it in
the bottom of the container.
There's nothing suspicious
about adding sugar to herb tea.
But Juri had no motive to kill Reina.
She may have hated Reina for
making her son fail the exam,
but she wouldn't kill someone over that.
It wasn't just my son that
caught Suto-san's son's flu.
What?
Did you get it, too?
Yes.
I was...
...pregnant then.
What?
My doctor told me the flu can
negatively affect the fetus.
I developed neurosis and miscarried.
At first I thought I was
careless or just had bad luck.
But then I heard what
Suto-san's son had to say...
What's wrong, Tsuneo-kun?
Will you apologize to Toji-kun for me?
Don't worry about it.
You just thought it was a cold, right?
No. I knew it was the flu.
What?
I was getting better.
But my mom said, "Go study!
This is the final stretch!"
"It'll be great for you if it
takes out one of your rivals!"
Don't tell my mom I told you!
How awful...
But it sounds like Reina.
I'm just as awful.
I let you fall under suspicion so
I could get away with my crime.
It's too bad, though.
I chose butterfly tea for
its detoxifying effects.
I thought it might erase the
dark murderous intent inside me
before I committed the crime.
I can't believe she poisoned her own guest.
I wonder if this hospital is cursed.
What?
It sounds like something
happened here before.
Like what?
The announcer Mizunashi
Rena was a patient here.
An injured man caused a panic trying
to force his way into a room.
There was a bomb scare, too.
D-Detective Takagi.
Shouldn't you go back to the station?
Oh, no!
I don't have time to be hanging out here!
You don't know anything about a man
named Kusuda Rikumichi, do you?
Kusuda Rikumichi?
Come to think of it, we found a damaged
vehicle a few days before the bomb scare.
It belonged to a Kusuda Rikumichi.
What?
Apparently he was a patient here,
but he suddenly disappeared.
It's a mysterious case.
There was blood all over the
inside of the damaged vehicle.
Some of the bloodstains were
less than a millimeter across.
Bloodstains less than a millimeter
across from a high speed blood spray...
According to forensics...
A gun.
See you guys later!
Episode Preview
Ran-san, you suddenly decided
to come today, right?
Oh, I know!
You're meeting your boyfriend for a date!
I-It's not like that!
Come to think of it,
I waited for her here then.
You're late.
Sorry. Something came up.
It's you, Kudo-kun.
Kudo Shinichi Aquarium Case
(Part 1)
The next episode of Conan is "Kudo
Shinichi Aquarium Case, Part 1!"
Cell Phone
Next Conan's Hint.
Cell phone!
Ran-san, aren't you excited
for the next episode?
Don't miss the next episode.
But it's just a memory.
I'm actually pretty happy about it.