Beika Aquarium
The dolphins were so cute!
They were jumping like crazy!
What an intense performance!
The professor is awfully late, though.
How far did he go to park the car?
He's probably at Yakisobuns.
What?
There's a hamburger shop called
Yakisobuns near the parking lot.
His nose probably led him there,
since someone I know is
always nagging him to diet.
Then he won't be getting lunch or dinner.
Come on, now.
Yakisobuns sounds good.
I want some, too.
Me, too.
It's okay.
This café has lots of cute dishes like
parfaits with dolphin shaped bananas
and scallop pasta on otter plates.
You know a lot about this place.
Why do you know so much?
Why?
The smell.
Ran-san, you suddenly decided
to come today, right?
Y-Yeah...
Have you been here before?
Oh, I know!
You're meeting your boyfriend for a date!
I-It's not like that!
I just came here with him...
You're blushing!
I told you, I'm not!
If you came with her, shouldn't we
have picked a different aquarium?
I didn't get to see the place
because of what happened last time.
Who are you emailing?
That fat old man, of course.
Haibara Ai
Received Message
Yakisobuns
An email?
How long are you going to keep eating?
She knows...
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
An underwater tunnel like
the bottom of the sea.
An incident occurs while sharks watch.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kudo Shinichi Aquarium Case
(Part One)
Kudo Shinichi Aquarium Case, Part One!
Wow!
There are so many fish!
It's like we're underwater!
It's a shark!
It's so cool!
It's huge!
They're like sharks.
That's what a detective does.
This brings back memories.
That pompous Holmes nut.
It hasn't been a year, but it seems
like it happened so long ago.
But I wonder...
Did Shinichi already have
feelings for me then?
Sorry I'm late.
Professor!
Took you long enough!
You missed the dolphin show!
You have seaweed in your teeth!
So you were at Yakisobuns.
No fair, Professor!
Act like an adult!
Come to think of it, I waited for her
here then in front of these sharks.
You're late.
You can't be late when you invited me.
Sorry. Something came up.
Why didn't you wait at the entrance?
I had to look for you.
I wanted to see the sharks.
Inbox
Getting over my cold
-Sonoko
Dinner tonight
-Mom
I'm feeling a lot better.
Thanks for your concern.
It's an e-mail from Sonoko.
Her cold's a lot better now.
Oh, really?
Let's hurry up and check the
place out for your whatever plan.
It's not the "whatever plan."
It's the Super Aquarium
Romantic Reunion Plan!
First I'll invite my dad to this
aquarium where he'll meet my mom
in this magical place surrounded by fish.
They'll remember how they felt
when they loved each other,
and they'll start living together again.
You came up with this plan.
You suggested an aquarium
since my dad likes fish.
Yeah, but Sonoko's the one who named it.
But couldn't you have come
to check it out yourself?
But I haven't been to the aquarium before.
I didn't want to come alone.
I know you didn't want to come to
this romantic date location with me.
But Sonoko caught a cold.
You were my only option.
It's not that I didn't want to come!
Then let's go to the café, too.
They have lots of cute items on their menu.
Let me know what you think.
Yeah, yeah.
That's just an excuse.
Maybe they shouldn't meet
in front of the sharks.
They have a bad reputation.
I actually wanted to come with Shinichi...
Hey, Shinichi.
What do you think?
About what?
My clothes.
I like this dress.
What?
I-It's not bad.
That's all?
If need an opinion on your clothes
that badly, ask your mom.
You're having dinner with her tonight, right?
Huh?
H-How do you know that?
Oh, wow!
It's a spotted eagle ray!
This is what I hate about Shinichi.
He'll suddenly act like he read your mind,
but he won't explain how he knows.
Answer me!
I haven't told my dad or Sonoko!
How do you know I'm meeting my mom?
You didn't look at my phone, did you?
After you checked Sonoko's email,
you checked a previous message.
I naturally assumed you had plans after
this and were confirming the time.
But you didn't see the screen.
I could tell from your finger's movements.
And that you're seeing your mom, too.
What? That doesn't answer my question.
You've got fashion magazines you
don't usually buy in your bag.
There's a business card
stuck between the pages.
Considering your confidence
in your outfit today,
it's clear you were asked to be a
reader model, had some shots taken,
and bought a magazine because
you were in a good mood.
You can brag you might
be in the next issue.
You should be happy.
They don't give business
cards to just anyone.
You'll probably be in the magazine.
But in this area, model scouts only hang
out around the main street of 3-chome.
That's a little out of the way if
you're coming to this aquarium.
Why did you take that path?
There was somewhere you wanted
to go before coming here.
I knew the answer when I saw your lips.
M-My lips?
Yeah.
They're shining a little.
You don't wear lip balm, so you
probably ate something oily.
There are fast food
restaurants on that street,
so it's possible you missed
breakfast and grabbed a burger.
But since you want to eat at
the café here, that's out.
Which means you had a light snack...
...of supermarket samples.
The supermarket on that street
has great prepackaged foods,
and they're having a sale today.
I'd guess you went to look for products that
might be even cheaper come this evening.
That means you're feeding your dad
prepackaged meals for dinner tonight.
Why would you do that when
you're frugal and good chef?
Because you don't have time to cook.
You're having dinner with someone tonight.
Naturally you'll proudly wear the
outfit that caught the scout's eye.
You're not having dinner
with Sonoko, who's sick.
It was obvious enough from your expression,
but that only leaves your mom.
But it looks like you have
another reason you can't cook.
It looks like you ran here because
your photo shoot made you late.
But don't run anymore today.
What? Why not?
Because, well...
It'll make you sad.
What? Why would running make me sad?
J-Just make sure you don't run.
My name is Ran!
Ran
I was born to run!
Oh, shut up!
Fine, I'll tell you!
Ran, go to the entrance
and get an employee.
What?
Hurry!
Let me through!
Shinichi!
Hey, are you okay?
Stand back!
Move away from him!
This isn't good. He's not breathing.
One stab through the heart.
The weapon is that knife
sticking through a plastic bag.
Shinichi!
I brought someone!
Seal the aquarium's exits
and call the police.
Th-The police?
Hurry!
O-Okay!
Don't let the other guests approach the body.
The body?
Is he dead?
Yeah. Someone inside the
aquarium stabbed him.
But why? I didn't hear a scream.
How did you know?
The smell.
Beika Aquarium
Red blood cells contain a protein that
carries oxygen called hemoglobin.
It's mostly made of iron.
When you lick a cut, doesn't
it taste like rust or iron?
Naturally, it smells like iron, too.
I-I didn't smell anything.
They're like sharks.
Sharks can smell the faintest trace of blood.
Their ears are even sharper,
allowing them to hear frequencies as low
as 40 hertz from two kilometers away.
They approach using their sense of smell,
determine their prey's exact location
by their electric fields, and attack.
They head to the crime scene
when they smell blood.
They use all their senses
to find the culprit.
They tear into their prey with
the sharp teeth of evidence.
That's what a detective does.
I see.
So the self-important young man
commanding the crime scene is you,
Kudo-kun.
Ran and I happened to be at the crime scene.
I asked if anyone saw the
culprit, but no one did.
Oh? You're on a date at the aquarium?
Is that how it looks?
I-It's not like that at all!
I'm joking!
If you get flustered, he'll
think it really is a date.
I'm surprised you can
joke when someone's dead.
It seems the weapon is this
knife next to the body.
He was stabbed through this plastic bag.
The culprit did it to prevent the
victim's blood from getting on himself.
He turned the blade sideways so it would
slip between his ribs and hit his heart.
He carefully withdrew the blade from under
his jacket so blood wouldn't spill everywhere.
He hid the wound with his jacket and left.
Surely the victim screamed.
There must be witnesses.
No. Look at the back of his neck.
Someone pressed a stun gun into his neck.
If he was knocked unconscious before he
was stabbed, he couldn't have screamed.
The blood was still flowing when I arrived,
so he was probably stabbed
a few minutes earlier.
Also, the stun gun is
inside his breast pocket.
This must be it.
The culprit probably drew the victim's
attention to the bottom of the tank
by saying there was an unusual fish.
He hit him with the stun gun while he was
leaning down and knocked him unconscious.
That way the victim slumped against the
tank instead of falling dramatically
so he could take his time
stabbing him to death.
Then the culprit could be an
acquaintance of the victim.
But there's no license or
business card in his wallet.
We'll have to figure out
who the victim is first.
Oh, actually...
The victim is Shumoto Kunihiro,
twenty-six years old.
He works at a gas station in Haido City.
Today he canceled his shift
because he had something to do.
Maybe the victim brought his girlfriend here.
A woman around 160 centimeters tall
in a miniskirt who likes dolphins.
H-How do you know that?
The victim's phone was in his pocket,
so I called a random number
in his contacts and called it.
"I found this phone. Do you
know who it belongs to?"
They told me his name, so I asked, "I'd like
to return it. Do you know where he is now?"
They told me where he works, so
I called the gas station, too.
I told him not to do it.
Uh, well...
It's fine.
I told them the next time
they get a call like this,
they should tell them to take
the phone to a police box.
You're unbelievable.
Did his employer tell you
about his lady friend?
No. I looked at the receipt
inside the victim's wallet.
It's from the aquarium café.
It was issued about fifteen minutes
before the body was found.
Beika Aquarium Café
Receipt
Coffee
Tea
Dolphin Key Chain
The receipt lists one coffee and one tea,
so he must have been with someone.
The time is five minutes
before the dolphin show,
so they probably waited at
the café for it to start.
The receipt also lists a dolphin key chain sold
by the café, but the victim doesn't have it.
I can only imagine he gave it to his girlfriend.
What about the 160 centimeters and miniskirt?
You still don't get it.
What? Don't be mean.
Wh-What do you mean, Kudo-kun?
You can smell women's perfume on the
victim's shoulder, elbow, and thigh.
Women put perfume behind their
earlobes, under their hair,
on their wrists, sides, hem of their
skirt, ankles, and all kinds of places.
If the smell got on the victim
while she was holding his arm,
the smell on his shoulder must come from
the perfume on her earlobes or hair.
The victim is about 180 centimeters tall,
so based on the location of the perfume,
the woman is about 165 centimeters tall.
Since it's likely she wore high heels to her
date, subtract five to eight centimeters.
She's around 160 centimeters.
The smell on his elbow is from
the perfume on her wrists.
The smell on his thigh is from
the perfume on her skirt.
Based on the locations and her height,
she's probably wearing a miniskirt.
Normally you only apply
perfume to one location.
Does that mean she doesn't
often wear perfume?
You can't be sure.
If you wear the same perfume all the
time, you get used to the smell.
Sometimes you'll apply extra
thinking no one can smell it.
That's what my mom told me.
Make sure you don't wear too much.
That's none of your business!
But why won't that woman identify herself?
Her boyfriend is dead.
Who knows?
Maybe they haven't been dating long,
and she doesn't want to get involved.
Maybe she's the one who killed him.
In any case, you should collect all the phones,
cameras, and video cameras from the guests.
Someone may have caught the
culprit stabbing the victim.
Y-You're right.
Do Not Enter
Come on, Kudo-kun!
There are over a hundred of these!
You want us to check all of these?
Most of the images are of fish...
I'm sure they are.
Shumoto Kunihiro
Incoming Call
Calling
Shumoto Kunihiro
Incoming Call
Wh-Why do they keep ringing?
I just called the victim's contacts
that didn't respond before you arrived.
People will turn on their phones
for a police inspection.
Let's call those three and ask them.
Why did they ignore the
victim's calls and emails?
Episode Preview
Someone killed Naho's ex-boyfriend?
It's been over a year since we broke up.
I met him when he hit on me last week.
Ran, let me borrow your phone.
Don't break it.
My dad finally bought me this one.
That's it!
That's why the culprit chose it!
Kudo Shinichi Aquarium Case
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Kudo
Shinichi Aquarium Case, Part 2!"
Your hint is mine -Kaito Kid
Next Conan's...
Someone stole the hint!
I'm just warming up for the movie.
Don't miss the next episode.
Damn you!
Next I'll steal Ran-san's heart.
No, no, no.
No, no.