Before I became Edogawa Conan...
In order to stop her parents' separation,
Ran brought me to the Beika
Aquarium to help prepare for her
"Super Aquarium Romantic Reunion Plan."
But while we were there...
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire
on the line to the heart.
Cell phone movies in an
underwater passageway.
An odd subject reveals the truth.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kudo Shinichi Aquarium Case
(Part Two)
Kudo Shinichi Aquarium Case, Part Two!
Beika Aquarium
I got scared.
Nakagiri Kanoko (27)
Aquarium Guest
I met him when he hit on me last week.
He seemed a little dangerous.
I had a feeling I should stay away from him.
She's wearing a miniskirt, reeks of
perfume, and is about 160 centimeters.
Right?
So you're the one who came to
the aquarium with the victim?
Yes.
I said I liked dolphins, so he
invited me to the aquarium.
So you saw the dolphin show?
Yeah, with him.
But he went to the bathroom during
the show and never came back.
He missed the dolphin show.
I was looking for him to give him
an earful, but that was a shock.
He was on the ground and bleeding.
I had an even bigger shock later.
When I got a call from his cell phone.
Everyone around me said he'd
been stabbed, so I ignored it.
I thought the guy who stabbed
him might be coming for me.
Why did you think that?
He was having a sketchy
conversation on his phone.
Something about,
"I'll definitely get the money."
If you think I did it, you're wrong.
I have video proof.
I took this during the dolphin show.
The front row is soaked!
Hilarious!
The show ended at noon.
You found his body before then, right?
Yes.
I filmed the whole dolphin show!
My voice is on the video!
Isn't this an alibi?
I-I suppose so.
What? Shumoto-kun was the victim?
What is your relationship with the victim?
Ojiro Naho (26)
Aquarium Guest
He's my ex-boyfriend.
It's been over a year since we broke up.
Why did you ignore his call?
He kept trying to get back together.
I was on a date today.
So I turned off my phone.
Then...
Were you with your
boyfriend the whole time?
Yes.
This is him.
You can ask him.
But a lover's testimony is...
Come to think of it...
I was filming when it happened.
R-Really?
It's been ten minutes,
but nothing's happening.
It's coming.
Ran, go to the entrance
and get an employee.
We're in the shot.
What?
Hurry!
Seriously?
Shinichi!
What was that?
That's my boyfriend's voice.
Something happened.
Should we check it out?
No, let's not get involved.
You certainly seem to have taken this video.
Why was Shumoto-kun here?
He was on a date with his girlfriend.
Maybe he called so he
could introduce her to me.
Huh? Are you dating Ojiro Naho-san?
Y-Yeah. How do you know that?
She told us.
And that the man killed here
today was her ex-boyfriend.
What?
Jinbe Kodai (28)
Aquarium Guest
Someone killed Naho's ex-boyfriend?!
Really?!
You know him, don't you?
O-Of course not!
It's news to me!
But your e-mail address was on his phone.
You ignored the e-mail he sent you.
You mean the one that said,
"Contact me immediately?"
I've received prank messages from that
address before, so I deleted it right away.
I've gotten them a lot lately.
"Click to see my secret."
Shady ones like that.
You're saying they came
from Naho's ex-boyfriend?
Yes.
You seemed to have been filming with
her when the incident occurred.
Oh, right.
You mean...
This video?
Ran, go to the entrance
and get an employee.
What?
Hurry!
What was that?
Something happened.
Should we check it out?
No, let's not get involved.
Y-You're right.
There are ten minutes preceding this.
We were going to upload
it to our blogs later.
Inspector Megure.
We compared Nakagiri-san's dolphin
show video to those of other guests.
It was definitely taken
when the incident occurred.
I see.
But why did the culprit choose that tunnel?
Most hallways are too dark
to see more than silhouettes.
Why did they choose that brightly lit tunnel?
Ran, let me borrow your phone.
I forgot mine.
Okay.
But don't break it.
My dad finally bought me this one.
Could you turn around?
What?
Wait, what? What?
What are you doing?
I thought the tunnel might
have some significance.
That's because there are
fish everywhere you look.
It feels like you're at
the bottom of the ocean.
That's why it's a romantic place for a date.
Shinichi?!
That's it!
That's why the culprit chose it!
This place that appears
surrounded by the ocean!
What's going on?
Everyone else has left.
Why do we have to stay?
I showed you my video!
You saw mine, too.
Mine, too.
Yes, we saw them.
But one of them was strange.
It practically told us you had done it.
What?
D-Don't tell me it's my dolphin show video.
Your video was awful.
What?!
It was shaky, and the sound
quality was terrible.
No one could watch that.
I-I couldn't help that.
After all, I...
That's right.
It's only natural.
After all, you're an amateur.
Compared to yours, Jinbe-san's
video was fantastic.
You got a clear shot of a
leisurely swimming shark.
And that makes me the killer?
No. You're just used to taking videos.
You were going to upload
it to your blog, too.
The problem is your girlfriend's.
Ojiro Naho-san's video.
These are the videos.
This is Jinbe-san's and this is Ojiro-san's.
Notice anything?
J-Just that mine's horizontal
and hers is vertical.
Yes.
Normally if you wanted to shoot
a long fish like a shark,
you'd shoot horizontally like Jinbe-san.
You'd want its whole body in the frame.
But Ojiro-san's video is vertical.
The shark quickly cuts through
the frame and disappears.
I-I wasn't trying to film the shark.
That's not all that's strange.
Normally people avoid walking into the
shot when they see someone filming.
Like you see in Jinbe-san's video.
But no one does that in Ojiro-san's.
They walk right through the shot.
It's as though they had
no idea she was filming.
I...
It's no wonder they didn't notice.
She put her phone
in his hat and filmed her video.
You'd have to look closely to notice
a white phone in a white hat.
The video looks like she
took it from behind him.
That's why she chose this tunnel.
With fish on all sides, fish will appear in
the shot no matter which way you shoot.
But wouldn't he notice if
she put that in his hat?
She probably said something was on his hat,
took it off, inserted the
phone, and put it back on.
It takes only a second to remove the phone.
Her video went blurry at one point.
That's when she removed it.
But people subconsciously move their heads.
The video shouldn't be so steady.
Don't worry about that.
After all, her boyfriend...
...is wearing a brace for his injured neck.
He can't suddenly move his head.
H-How did you know?
When I spoke from your side, you turned
your entire body instead of just your neck.
While looking at your video, you held your
phone directly in front of your face.
That's how I knew he couldn't look
down because he injured his neck.
Then while he was filming,
Ojiro-san killed him.
Yes.
She found the victim waiting
for her in this tunnel
and used a stun gun to knock him out.
Then she stabbed him in the heart.
She returned to her boyfriend
and retrieved her phone.
I'm surprised no one saw her.
It didn't matter if anyone saw her.
If she takes off her coat, raises her skirt,
and puts on a hat,
she looks like a different person.
It's dark outside this bright tunnel.
It was easy enough to change.
Unfortunately, there was one
thing you couldn't change.
Yes, these gloves.
Since they're reversible, you've
flipped them inside out to hide it...
I knew it.
The victim's blood is on your right finger.
How did you know?
The photo you took with your boyfriend.
What?
Based on your clothes,
I knew you took it today.
But your gloves were a different color.
No one walks around with two pairs.
And you took it with your right hand.
You also showed the inspector
your phone with your right hand.
You're clearly right handed.
But you removed your left glove and
used your phone with your left.
These facts,
and the fact that some blood
spilled through the plastic bag
the culprit used to stab the victim,
lead to this conclusion.
We'll have forensics examine the...
Hurry up and examine it.
I'd like to wash that man's
blood off as soon as possible.
Then, Naho, does that mean you...?
Yes, that's right.
He threatened to leak embarrassing photos
of me online for breaking up with him.
He said he sent a few to you.
So those shady e-mails...
That's right.
Inside were embarrassing
pictures of me he took.
Though you erased them
without opening them.
How did he have my address?
When I went to his place to break up,
he used my phone while
I was in the bathroom.
"If you don't want your boyfriend, job, and
family seeing these photos, give me money."
"I'm up to my neck in debt."
So I spilled his blood instead.
But I failed.
If I hadn't reversed my gloves,
you may not have known.
No.
It was obvious without them.
What?
In Jinbe-san's video, you were
wearing both of your gloves.
You took one off when you used your left
hand, so they're ordinary wool gloves.
You need to be barehanded
to use a smart phone.
It was proof you'd done something
that required you to wear them.
It was a simple assumption.
You should call it off.
After what happened, you shouldn't
use your Romantic Reunion Plan there.
You're right.
Uh-oh! It's raining!
Let's run home.
Hey, I told you not to run!
Why not?
My phone!
No way.
Why was it inside my hood?
Sorry.
I was thinking of where
the culprit put her phone.
I forgot I put it in your hood.
How could you do this?!
I just got it...
Don't cry.
I'll buy you a new one.
This sucks!
Nothing good ever happens
when I'm with you!
Huh?
Things kept happening when
we went to America, too...
Fine, then.
Tropical Land.
I'll take you there.
Tropical Land?
That's a cheerful sounding place.
They're building one in Tokyo.
I'm sure nothing will happen
at an amusement park.
I'll go if you'll pay for everything.
What?
Okay, then how about if I
win my karate tournament?
Hey, wait.
Last year you placed second.
The third year who won quit the team, right?
It's a promise!
What?
I don't have much of an allowance...
And if you're buying me a phone, get a sea
cucumber strap from the aquarium, too.
Okay, okay!
I was joking.
I can't believe he actually bought one.
I wonder, though.
Did Shinichi already...?
Uh, oh. Now I really want to ask.
BA-DUMP BA-DUMP
Shinichi's phone?
Mori Ran
Incoming Call
What?!
It's from Ran?
Shinichi?
Hey, Ran.
Guess where I am.
I'm at the Beika Aquarium
we visited together.
Where that guy was stabbed, huh?
Anyway, I want to ask you something.
Back then, did you...?
Oh, yeah.
How I told you not to run, right?
What?
Th-That's not it?
I guess there's that, too...
Come to think of it, I've been
wondering about that, too.
You just checked your mom's message
and didn't respond to Sonoko's, right?
You were using your left hand.
You probably hurt your right hand and
weren't dexterous enough
to write an e-mail.
Since you didn't remove your glove,
you probably bandaged your hand.
You were determined to
win your tournament,
so I figured it was just a sprained finger.
Yeah, it was.
It happened during practice.
But how does that prevent me from running?
Because you couldn't link
them with your fingers.
The hooks on your bra.
What?
You only have ones that hook in the back.
H-How do you know that?!
I sat behind you, so I could
see when you leaned forward.
You'd never let your dad
hook your bras for you.
Sonoko had a cold, and you wouldn't
go see your mom just to put on a bra.
In other words, you weren't wearing a bra.
You may not know,
but when you run without a bra, your
breasts bounce all over the place,
making your Cooper's ligaments
stretch and droop over time.
You're an idiot!
I was wearing a sports bra!
What?!
Oh, right.
I forgot she used them for practice.
Besides, even with back hook bras,
you can attach them in front
and rotate them around...
Why would you make me
say that?! You idiot!
I hung up.
Why did she actually call?
Episode Preview
This is "Anxiety."
What do you mean?
The car in front transporting "Scream"
suddenly drove off course and disappeared!
What?
It's like a three panel comic.
Munch's "Scream" was stolen, right?
What?
How do you know?
This was no accident.
The Disappearance of Munch's Scream
The next episode of Conan is
"The Disappearance of Munch's Scream!"
Car GPS
Next Conan's hint!
A car GPS!
Don't miss the next episode.
What beautiful sunflowers.
How dare you?!
See you in the theater.
Prepare yourself, detective.