Lift it.
Okay.
This is Munch's "Despair"?
Yes, and that's "Anxiety."
Who's the Suzuki Museum curator?
Numajiri Hiroshi (35)
Suzuki Museum Curator
Here.
My name's Numajiri.
Here are photos we took of "Despair" and
"Anxiety" before they went on the plane.
Allow me to check them.
"Scream" is arriving at
Haneda Airport, right?
Yes. I'm borrowing it
from a different museum.
They have their own procedure.
What is Numajiri-san doing?
He's checking the photos to see if the
works were damaged in transport.
Those photos were developed on the spot,
so they're harder to manipulate
than digital photos.
That's why we still use them.
Sir, neither "Despair" nor
"Anxiety" have any defects.
Good.
Pack them.
Yes, sir.
I'm going to Haneda to check on "Scream."
Thanks.
You're packing them really carefully.
Yes. Each painting is said to be worth
billions or even tens of billions.
Right, President?
You're the president?
Thanks for coming.
Not at all.
I like Munch.
Shimamura Keiji (50)
Shimamura Shipping President
Shipping three of his
iconic works is an honor.
"Anxiety" and "Despair" are on that truck.
Sounds ominous when you put it like that.
It's me.
This is Numajiri.
Has "Scream" arrived?
Yes, sir.
There were no problems with it,
so I just had it sent to the Suzuki Museum.
Good work.
You head there, too.
Yes, sir.
I knew about Munch's "Scream,"
but I'd never heard of "Anxiety"
or "Despair" before.
Well, "Scream" is Munch's most iconic work.
Munch himself liked it so much,
he created five versions of it.
An oil painting, pastels, a
lithograph, and a tempera painting.
You wanted to display all five "Screams"
at your Munch exhibition, right?
Yes, but one belongs to an individual.
They wouldn't sell it to me.
That's why I chose "Scream," "Despair," and
"Anxiety" for the stars of my exhibition.
Why did you choose those three?
You'll understand when you
see all three at once.
It's me.
Sir, it's an emergency!
Scream... Scream has disappeared!
What?!
What do you mean?
The car in front transporting "Scream"
suddenly drove off course and disappeared!
What?
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
Movies are van Gogh and TV is Munch.
Solving masterpiece disasters
with clever detective work.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Munch's Missing Scream
Munch's Missing Scream!
Hello?
Yes, sir.
I just called the shipping company.
Yes.
No, it's running according to schedule.
It just left the checkpoint
slightly behind schedule.
But Numajiri-kun said it drove off course.
I'll check with him.
Thanks.
What checkpoint?
They park briefly to make sure
the packaging hasn't come apart.
Sir!
Numajiri-kun, you're already here.
Where's "Scream"?
It's not here yet.
I'm going to check "Despair"
and "Anxiety" first.
Thanks.
I'm going to see the museum director.
Okay.
Could I see the photos?
Here.
Huh?
I didn't notice at the airport,
but they're packed differently.
Huh?
Oh, yeah.
They were probably packed
by different people.
Come to think of it, you guys
weren't at Narita Airport.
We took over at the checkpoint.
Kato Munenori (30)
Shimura Shipping Transporter
Where the packaging was checked?
Yes, by someone who hadn't handled
the paintings until then.
You switched drivers there, too?
Yeah, both of us did.
Huh...
If it really was stolen,
we need to do something soon!
But the shipping company says it's
being transported according to plan.
But, sir, it disappeared.
The car transporting "Scream"
vanished from right before my eyes.
How are "Despair" and "Anxiety"?
They're fine.
Sir, if "Scream" really was stolen,
it's not just a financial problem.
He's right.
It would be an international incident.
There's just one more.
This is "Anxiety," huh?
I don't get it.
What?
"Scream" disappeared?
Sonoko, not so loud!
Shouldn't you call him?
The police?
Don't be dumb.
I mean your boyfriend.
What?
I'm not sure that's the right finger.
Does that mean it was stolen?
I don't know.
But if it was, it's a serious problem.
Besides, there's something odd about it.
What is Shinichi doing?
Hello, Dad?
If it was stolen, it may be
too late if we wait too long.
Sir, we have to contact the police.
Come in.
Excuse us.
Is there a problem?
I'm sorry.
I overheard your conversation.
Sir, where is the driver
transporting "Scream"?
Sir!
"Scream"... "Scream" has arrived!
What?!
Well?
It's definitely real.
Of course it is.
I was shocked when I heard it was stolen.
But it was over thirty minutes late.
You can't blame us for worrying.
I'm sorry.
But the contract said road conditions
sometimes result in tardiness.
I know.
I'm sorry for the trouble we caused you.
But why did you drive off course?
We followed the GPS.
I don't think we drove off course.
There's no missing masterpiece here.
That's why I'm apologizing!
You call that apologizing?
What do you want me to do, then?
Huh? What are you doing, kid?
This truck transported "Scream," right?
That's right.
I drove.
You followed a GPS to get here, right?
Yeah, while following the
route the company gave me.
Can I see that route now?
Huh? The route's gone.
Huh?
Maybe your assistant Tanaka erased it.
A GPS records the route you took, right?
What? Oh, yeah.
It's in the history.
Huh? It looks like you teleported
between these two points.
It probably lost its satellite connection.
A car GPS uses satellite signals to
display your car's location on a map.
Sometimes if your connection is
poor, your route isn't displayed.
We call that a lost connection.
Hmm...
You said you switched drivers
at the checkpoint, right?
Yeah.
Where's the checkpoint?
Let's see.
It's right where we lost our connection.
Around here.
Really?
Do you take photos at the checkpoint?
Of course.
After we check if the
packaging's come undone.
Look.
This is "Despair" and this is "Anxiety."
What about "Scream"?
Here.
Do you unpack the paintings
at the checkpoint?
No.
So the packaging's unchanged
from the airport?
Yeah, it should be.
Aren't these all paintings of the same place?
That's right.
These three paintings depict the same
composition on the same background.
Really?
It's like a three panel comic.
Good observation.
That's the triptych I came up with.
Triptych?
It's a group of three paintings
that have some special meaning.
I see.
Did you figure anything out?
Yeah.
Why is that man screaming?
He's not screaming.
He's covering his ears
because he hears a scream.
Whose scream?
Munch explains this work in his journal.
"The sky suddenly turned blood red."
"That's when I saw it."
"The blazing clouds hang over the
ultramarine town like a bloody sword."
"It was as though a fiery and dark
blue field was covering the town."
"Feeling extremely fatigued, I stopped
and leaned against the railing."
"My friends went on ahead,
but I remained there."
"I trembled with anxiety
and shuddered with fear."
"That's when I heard it."
"An endless scream piercing the air."
It probably actually happened
within Munch's troubled mind.
The culprit erased the GPS's history,
and pretended what actually
happened never happened at all.
Hey, kids!
It's time to go.
What?
It's Shinichi.
Hello? Sorry.
I called you earlier, but—
Munch's "Scream" was stolen, right?
What?
How do you know?
Sorry, though.
It turns out we were confused.
No, you weren't confused.
Something did happen.
Thanks for taking time out
of your busy schedules.
Sheesh.
Look closely at the following photos.
These are photos of "Despair" and
"Anxiety" packed at Narita Airport.
Next is a photo of "Scream"
packed at Haneda Airport.
You'll notice the paintings packed at
Narita Airport were packed differently.
That's because they were
packed by different people.
Who packed "Despair" at Narita Airport?
"Despair" was packed by
the president and an employee.
"Anxiety" was packed by two employees.
Now look at "Scream"
packed at Haneda Airport.
They're packed the same way.
That's right.
Why were paintings packed at two
different airports packed the same way?
Because the employees at Haneda happened
to pack it the same way I did.
I see.
Well then, Driver who transported "Scream."
Yes?
Who checked the packaging
of "Scream" at the checkpoint?
It was... President Shimamura.
Are you sure?
Yes.
When we came to take over,
the president was double-checking
the packaging.
What about the drivers who had transported
the painting to the checkpoint?
They'd already headed for their next job.
They weren't there.
In other words, until you arrived,
President Shimamura was
checking the packaging alone.
That's right.
What about it?
I thought it was strange when I heard
you switched drivers at the checkpoint.
You weren't traveling very far, so
why did you have to switch drivers?
B-Because...
Now look at the GPS.
I had the drivers copy the data.
Will you tell us where the checkpoint was?
It's in the area where
we lost our connection.
I see.
You lost your connection.
In other words,
it's possible the vehicle transporting
"Scream" drove off course within that area.
That's why I lost sight of the
car while I was following behind!
What?
You were following it?
Hold on!
You're contradicting yourself.
If they drove off course there, they
wouldn't have reached the checkpoint.
Well done, detective.
You're exactly right.
However, the packaging
of "Scream" was checked.
What do you mean?
In other words, the checkpoint
was never on the course.
Wh-What?
Drivers, please take
everyone to the checkpoint.
What?
Conan-kun!
You were with Shinichi.
Where is he?
He left to handle another case.
What?
He left?
How irresponsible.
I know.
And he brought you all to
the president's house, too.
What?
The president's house?
What's going on?
Shinichi-niichan said to ask Kogoro-no-ojisan
since he's probably figured it out.
What? Really?
Huh? Well, I—
Hey, Sleeping Kogoro!
"Despair" and "Anxiety."
"Scream" driver.
You're sure this is the checkpoint?
Y-Yes.
This is it.
But...
I didn't know it was the president's house.
In other words,
you've never driven from the
airport to the museum before.
Neither had any of the
other drivers you chose,
President Shimamura!
It's reasonable to assume you'd know
the GPS would lose its connection
around your house.
That's why you changed the route to
one without a satellite connection,
and entered it into the GPS.
By setting the GPS to erase its data
once it reached its destination,
you left no evidence.
All that remained was the history
of the lost connection...
The president unpacked "Scream"
here and then repacked it.
That's why the packaging was the same.
But why would you do that?
B-Because...
Shimamura-san, delivery!
What?
Shimamura-san!
Shimamura-san, sorry!
I got your package for—
What?
I-I'm sorry!
I see.
You unpacked the painting to take this photo.
I love Munch.
Especially "Scream."
When you hired me to
transport the real thing,
I couldn't suppress my desire to hang
it in my home and take a picture.
This is a serious problem!
I'm sorry!
This isn't good, president.
This is clearly a criminal case.
We should call the police.
Wait.
President Shimamura.
What's that sunflower painting
in the photo behind you?
That's van Gogh's first sunflower
painting he did in Arles.
When I was younger,
I worked in the United States.
I was allowed to take this photo as
thanks for transporting the work.
In other words, you know the person
who owns that sunflower painting.
Y-Yes.
We're still friends.
All right, then.
I plan to gather van Gogh's sunflowers
scattered throughout the world,
and open a exhibition of the
six sunflower paintings.
Once I've finished planning,
I want you to ask the owner
to let me borrow his painting.
If you'll do that,
I'll overlook this incident.
Y-Yes, sir!
Gladly!
That settles it!
His six sunflower exhibition
was beloved by Japan,
but that's a story for another day.
Episode Preview
Hello? Hello?
Mori-kun, answer me!
Mori-kun!
Looks like he was here.
Police! Don't move!
That sketch was of an escape route.
The Manipulated Great Detective
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is
"The Manipulated Great Detective, Part One!"
Infiltration
Next Conan's hint!
Infiltration!
Don't miss the next episode.
The Munch was okay...
But van Gogh's sunflowers
are just getting started.
Yup.