Let's choose a name for you.
How does Mr. Moustache sound?
Moustache, huh?
What about you?
Should I call you Boss?
The other members call me Mr. Head.
Head, huh?
Does this mean I passed the
induction test, Mr. Head?
I expect great things from you.
I'm counting on you, Mr. Moustache.
Hello?
Yes.
I successfully infiltrated their group.
Now I, Mori Kogoro, can take
down that band of thieves.
Hello? Hello?
Mori-kun, what's wrong?
Did something happen?
Hello?
Too bad, Detective...
Answer me, Mori-kun!
Hello?
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
Kogoro-no-occhan isn't his usual self.
What's the dangerous goal of
his undercover investigation?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Manipulated Great Detective
(Part One)
The Manipulated Great Detective, Part One!
You're awake?
What a cute daughter...
R-Ran!
You bastard! What did you do to her?
That's up to you.
Damn it!
What do you want?
You're so understanding, Detective.
Tell me what you want!
You went through the trouble of disguising
yourself and infiltrating my group.
As planned, you'll work with
my men as a master safe cracker.
What?
The truth is one of my men killed my son.
I want the great detective Mori Kogoro
to identify him before
dawn two days from now.
Wh-What?
At that time, after finishing
this job, I'll be leaving Japan.
You must find him before then.
What happens after I identify him?
Are you going to avenge your son?
That's none of your business.
But if you refuse...
You'll never see your daughter again.
Unless I call him off before the time limit,
an assassin I hired will kill your daughter.
Did you plan this all along?!
Damn it.
But... I believe in you.
Mori Kogoro, I know you're a great detective.
What?
What should I do, Conan-kun?
Mori Detective Agency
Dad hasn't come home yet.
He won't answer his phone.
He's been missing since yesterday!
Calm down, Ran-neechan.
He said he's going to work, right?
Yeah, to meet a client.
Did he tell you who he was
meeting or where he was going?
Well, no...
Come to think of it, he was acting weird.
See you later, Dad.
You're eating here, right?
Huh? Oh...
I'm not sure.
I know you want to drink after work, but...
But I'll probably come home.
What?
I promise I'll come home.
Don't worry.
I'm off.
Dad?
You talked to Inspector Megure, right?
Yeah, just now.
I haven't been able to contact
my father since yesterday.
R-Really?
Have you heard anything from him?
N-No, not really...
If you're worried, we'll look for him.
It's okay. I know he'll come home.
Excuse me.
Inspector!
Inspector Megure was acting
kind of weird, too.
Something's up.
I don't know what it is,
but something's going on.
Could it be?
April 25, 10 o'clock.
Hotel Mole café terrace.
Hey, Mister...
Yesterday I only caught a glimpse of him,
but the famous detective
Mori Kogoro was here, right?
Yeah, he was.
Was he meeting someone?
Who are you?
I wanted to ask him to handle a case.
If he's staying here...
A case?
Sorry, but he's not staying here.
He was sitting there yesterday.
Sir, you have a call.
Oh, thanks.
Hello?
What? Don't take a taxi right away?
What do you...?
I see.
Got it.
Where's the closest subway station?
Was he trying to lose anyone tailing him?
Or was he made to do it?
Subway
Damn it.
There's nothing I can do if I
don't know which train he took.
The taxi stand is...
Here it is.
There's one on the other side, too.
Don't take a taxi right away?
"Right away"?
That's it. What's what he meant.
Taxi Stand
The great detective Mori Kogoro?
I gave him a ride yesterday.
Really?
Will you take me to where he got off?
Sure, I don't mind.
This place?
That's his phone.
Damn, it's no use.
All the data's gone.
These footprints...
Mr. Mouth (28)
Gang Member
What do you think you're doing?!
Mr. Nose (35)
Gang Member
Whoa! H-Hey, wait!
Put me down! Put me down, Nose!
Shut up.
We've got a job. Behave yourselves.
Mr. Eyes (40)
Gang Member
O-Okay...
You're as harsh as ever, Miss Lip.
Miss Lip (33)
Gang Member
When I realized I was dealing with
the same predictable guys,
I couldn't help myself.
What did you say?
You want to get your ass kicked?
I'd like to see you try!
I have instructions from Mr. Head.
We've got another guy.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Mr. Moustache.
It looks like he was here.
These are new unlike the rest of the room.
What was it projecting?
I smell something burning...
These are... a map and sewer plans?
Sorry, but could you stop
at a convenience store?
So nervous you have to piss, old man?
I want to buy gum.
Gum?
I can't open a safe without it.
I need to get away so I
can contact someone...
Huh?
Now we don't need to stop anymore.
Th-Thanks...
Damn it.
All right!
Oh, no!
Don't move or I'll shoot!
I'll kill you!
Don't move!
I'll say it again!
Move and we'll kill you!
Don't move or I'll shoot!
I'll kill you!
Don't move!
I'll say it again!
Move and we'll kill you!
If you don't want to die,
hand over your wallets!
I'll kill you!
Line up! Come on!
They've got guns and knives.
When and where...
...did they come from?
Takagi, Sato.
The situation's changed.
Don't do anything stupid, please.
You're up, Mr. Moustache.
Their wallets aren't worth much.
This way.
I heard there's no safe you can't open.
We're counting on you.
Y-Yeah, leave it to me.
What am I supposed to do?
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing.
I-I've never dealt with this type before.
Not that, the gum!
Huh? What?
Who the hell are you?
What? Um...
Let go! I'll kill you!
Damn it!
Stop!
Inspector, hurry!
Okay, let's go!
Go!
Okay, go!
Stop!
What are you doing?
Mori-san?!
Mori?
The famous detective?
What? Really?
It's him!
He's a thief now?
What?
N-No! I can explain!
Damn it! So that's how it is!
Police! Don't move!
W-Wait, Inspector!
Good work, Mori-kun!
U-Um...
You're resisting?
You won't get away with this!
What?
I-I'll kill you!
Stop! Don't shoot!
Get down on the floor!
Someone stop me!
Now! Arrest them!
Don't let them escape!
Th-That's enough, Mori-kun!
The undercover operation is over!
Several Days Earlier
Infiltrate the gang of thieves?
Yeah.
As you can see, with a little work,
I look like the famous
safe cracker you arrested.
I'll infiltrate their gang and find
hard evidence of their crimes.
We can't miss this chance.
If you succeed,
we'll be able to arrest the thieves that
have been giving the police trouble.
But what if they find out?
Takagi-kun and Sato-kun will blend in with
the casino guests so that doesn't happen.
Yes, sir.
One more thing...
Don't tell Ran about this.
I don't want her to worry.
Got it.
But why would Mori-san go this far?
Because he's a former cop.
Damn it. I couldn't stop myself.
If I'm not careful, I could ruin my career!
Inspector, there's no one over here.
Damn! Where did they go?
There should be no other exits.
A vent?
A rope ladder!
They probably came in this way, too.
That's it! The sewer plans!
You're not getting away!
They went that way!
After them!
Yes, sir!
Chiba-kun, get the sewer plans!
We'll cut them off at the exit!
Yes, sir!
You won't get away!
But why did Mori-kun do that?
The operation isn't over yet.
Not until Ran's safe.
Sorry, Inspector.
Those plans were of an escape route.
Okay, then.
I'll cut them off.
She's definitely one of them.
She must be their getaway driver.
What a safe cracker.
We're taking him with us?
We should kill him instead!
Don't.
Mr. Head recruited him.
We need to ask why.
Hurry!
They're heading straight for us!
Get in.
C-Contact all stations immediately.
Yes, sir.
We did it!
We got away from the cops!
Way to go, Miss Lip.
Head to the location.
But first...
What's up, Lip?
The car's not handling well.
We've got an extra passenger in the trunk.
What?
Say what?
Damn it!
What's wrong?
I'm opening it.
Okay.
Mori Detective Agency
This is Mori Detective Agency.
Inspector Megure...
What?
Dad and Conan-kun?
I'm sorry, Ran-kun.
This wasn't supposed to happen.
In any case, all the stations
are looking for them!
Episode Preview
I had the great detective Mori Kogoro
determine who killed my son one year ago.
There's no way someone like that
would be working for the casino.
Then you're saying Mr. Mouth or I did it?
Damn it!
Don't get in, Ran!
The Manipulated Great Detective
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Manipulated Great Detective, Part Two!"
Blackout
Next Conan's Hint!
Blackout!
Maybe the two of you are actually
watching sunflowers in the theater.
Don't miss the next episode.
We don't have...
...time for that.