Mori Kogoro disappeared.
He was actually working on
an undercover investigation
of a gang of thieves with Inspector Megure.
But when their faceless boss Mr.
Head saw through Kogoro's disguise,
he made a surprising request.
What a cute daughter...
R-Ran!
You bastard!
What did you do to her?
That's up to you.
Damn it!
What do you want?
You're so understanding, Detective.
Tell me what you want.
You went through the trouble of disguising
yourself and infiltrating my group.
As planned, you'll work with
my men as a master safe cracker.
What?
The truth is one of my men killed my son.
I want the great detective Mori Kogoro
to identify him before
dawn two days from now.
Wh-What?
At that time, after finishing
this job, I'll be leaving Japan.
You must find him before then.
What happens after I identify him?
Are you going to avenge your son?
That's none of your business.
But if you refuse...
You'll never see your daughter again.
Unless I call him off before the time limit,
an assassin I hired will kill your daughter.
Did you plan this all along?!
Damn it.
But... I believe in you.
Mori Kogoro, I know you're a great detective.
What?
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
The old man and I find ourselves cornered.
The gang of thieves has a surprising goal.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Manipulated Great Detective
(Part Two)
The Manipulated Great Detective, Part Two!
They still haven't found them?
No, sir.
But it's hard to imagine how they
escaped our emergency deployment.
They must have a secret base somewhere.
They could be waiting there
for a chance to escape.
So the question is where's their base...
Damn! All we got were their wallets!
Mr. Mouth (28)
Gang Member
We'd have more if you'd opened the safe!
Damn it. What are you doing here?
No! Let go of me!
Mr. Nose (35)
Gang Member
Stop shouting! I'll kill you!
I'm scared!
Shut up, kid!
Miss Lip (33)
Gang Member
Stop! He's just a kid.
And you're way louder than he is.
What did you say?
What?
Mr. Eyes (40)
Gang Member
Stop, you two!
Anyway, Mr. Head.
We have a question for you.
What's Mori Kogoro doing here?
You brought him here.
You'd better explain what's going on.
Are you listening, Head?
Do you remember this place?
It's the underground casino
you attacked a year ago.
One of your members was killed there.
I want the great detective Mori Kogoro
to determine who killed
my son one year ago.
He was your son?
That useless brat?
That's news to me.
I'm surprised.
I thought I'd hire a professional.
I'm counting on you, Detective.
L-Leave it to me.
But we have an agreement, right?
It wasn't worth the trouble.
Pim... Mr. Pimple was killed by
the men of the underground casino.
I thought you accepted that a year ago.
Why are you bringing it up now?
This is stupid.
I don't have time for this game.
What?!
It won't open!
What do you think you're doing?
When the time comes, the door
will unlock automatically.
If you try to escape before then...
You'll die.
Wait a minute!
This has nothing to do with me!
I was waiting outside with the car!
I didn't hear about Pim's death until later!
Let's review the circumstances
of one year ago.
Including Mr. Pimple in the
job may have been my mistake.
I-I'm sorry!
Be careful.
Sorry...
Mr. Pimple (18)
Gang Member
He's drawing attention to himself.
He's useless.
I don't know why we sent him in first.
Should I beat him up?
Let's move.
Don't move! Hands in the air!
Do as you're told!
Fight back and I'll kill you!
Put your wallets in there!
Hey, hurry up!
What's going on?!
What's wrong?!
Help!
What?! Gunshots?!
They're back on?
Is he dead?
What happened?
Fire!
Help!
Hurry! I don't want to die!
Run!
Mr. Pimple's unidentified body was
discovered in the burnt wreckage.
That's what you reported to me.
What do you mean?
Look at this.
This is footage from the
underground casino's cameras.
Detective, does anything
seem strange to you?
Huh? Oh, um...
I'm not sure.
You disguised yourselves as
guests and snuck in, right?
Yes.
That's why we sent Pim in first
to hide the guns and knives.
Pim-san was disguised as a waiter, right?
Yes, though you saw how that turned out.
He got himself killed.
That's right.
You got anything else?
The floor's sparkling.
It's made of marble, right?
You're right.
But so what?
Damn it. Pull yourself together.
Hey.
Did you get that cut on your
finger from someone biting you?
Huh?
I-I got this when...
A dog bit me a long time ago.
And your knife?
Huh?
There are bite marks on
your knife's handle, too.
Y-Yeah.
I was threatening it for fun,
and it bit my hand and knife.
That's odd.
There weren't any dogs in the casino.
What?
But the video of Pim-san on the floor...
Help!
What?! Gunshots?!
They're back on!
Is he dead?
What happened?
Pim?
That's it!
The dog you mentioned was actually Mr. Pim!
Look!
There's blood on his mouth!
I-It's a coincidence!
I was bitten by a dog in
the neighborhood, and...
Then show us your knife!
I'll know if they're dog
or human teeth marks!
Don't be ridiculous!
Someone shot him dead!
My knife's got nothing to do with it!
Wow, cool!
This is an automatic, right?
It spits out casings when you shoot
that clatter around on the floor.
That's it. The sound!
Play the video of Mr. Pim getting shot again.
Just after the gunshot during the blackout,
I didn't hear any casings hit the floor.
Help!
What?! Gunshots?!
They're back on?
Which means... it was a revolver?
That's right!
Hold on. This is an automatic.
Maybe you had a second gun.
But it would've been impossible to
get through the metal detectors.
If it were made of... not ceramic
or plastic, but something else...
That's it! Resin!
If the gun were made of resin, the
metal detectors wouldn't find it.
And if the culprit had prepared a resin gun,
then it means the killing was planned.
There's no way someone like that
would be working for the casino
because they didn't know
the casino would be attacked.
First, Mr. Mouth used a knife to make
Mr. Pimple hold still during the blackout
Then Mr. Eyes shot him,
making it look like the casino
employees killed him instead.
Then you're saying Mr. Mouth and I did it?
That's right!
Then let's try it, Mr. Detective...
What?
Isn't that why you built this set, Mr. Head?
What's wrong? Are you tired?
Or are you out of batteries?
Serves him right.
Whatever.
One year ago...
If Pimple was standing
there before the blackout,
then I was standing around here.
Looks like I was here.
I was here.
The blackout lasted ten seconds.
The gunshots happened five seconds
after the lights went out.
Isn't that right, Detective?
Y-Yes.
Let's go.
Okay.
Start!
Help!
What's going on?!
I'm scared!
It's dark!
They're back on?
Time's up.
But this isn't what happened.
We barely made it.
During a blackout,
everyone would be freaking out.
I-I was wrong...
It's nearly dawn.
What are you going to do, Detective?
He's a hack.
We should kill him.
Hey, why did you close your
eyes before the blackout?
But like the other guests,
Pim-san didn't close his eyes.
That's it!
You knew the lights would go out.
No, you set a timer on the switchboard,
so the lights would go out at a certain time.
Don't move! Hands in the air!
Do as you're told!
Fight back and I'll kill you!
Put your wallets in there!
Hey, hurry up!
Don't move!
What?! Gunshots?!
They're back on?
Is he dead?
What happened?!
Fire!
Help!
You started the fire, too,
so you could escape and
destroy the evidence.
You idiot!
I told you to throw that away!
Shut up! This is my partner!
Quiet!
I did my job, Mr. Head!
Now stop the assassin!
Don't hurt my daughter!
I knew it.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Anyway, is the detective right?
Yes. I'm impressed, Detective.
Pim discovered our plan to kill Mr.
Head and take the money for ourselves.
We had to kill him...
Just like we do now!
We finally meet, Mr. Head.
Wh-What?!
Conan-kun?
Ran-neechan, if you're okay,
contact Inspector Megure immediately
and ask for protection.
The old man and I are all right.
We're with the gang of thieves.
We're in a warehouse at the harbor.
I'll send the details to your GPS.
What do you mean, if I'm okay?
Anyway, I should call Inspector Megure.
An automatic sensor system.
You were controlling it with
a remote in your pocket.
What's this?
This is footage from the
underground casino's cameras.
I want the great detective Mori Kogoro
to determine who killed
my son one year ago.
You recorded your voice
and used this remote
to play it back to portray
the faceless client.
Were you trying to avenge your son?
You made fools out of us.
I had him when I was fifteen.
It was a mistake to put him up for
adoption so he could have a better life.
In the end, he was hired
without realizing who I was.
It's ironic.
Achoo!
Sorry, Detective.
Sorry you got involved, too.
I'll tell the assassin to stand down.
Really?
Wh-What are you doing?!
Are you going to die with
them to atone for your son?
Then look at this.
Mr. Pimple is still alive.
Look closely at his mouth.
He's saying something.
Please stop... Mom...
He knew you, Miss. Lip,
were Mr. Head and his mother.
Perhaps he took the job so you
would end your life of crime.
No...
If he were alive, he'd probably
try to stop you again.
Mori-kun!
Conan-kun!
Don't die!
Call the assassin!
Please! Please!
Damn it!
Ran...
You must be Mori Ran-san.
I'm here to pick you up.
Okay.
Get in the car.
Don't get in, Ran!
Damn it!
Run!
Come here, you.
D-Dad...
Ran!
Are you okay?!
Dad, you're hurting me.
I was...
I was so worried...
We made it.
After being shot by Mr. Eyes,
Miss. Lip was rushed to the hospital.
She survived, and the gang
of thieves was arrested.
I was so worried about you two.
Are you listening?
Dad, Conan-kun?
I'm listening, so pour me another.
I'm listening, so let me sleep.
What's wrong with you two?
Episode Preview
Our group was formed to protect the
peace and safety of the people.
Schwing.
The Silver Detectives!
Wh-What is it?
Does that make me you, Conan-kun?
You don't need to force the comparison...
This is getting complicated...
The Detective Boys VS the Silver Detectives
The next episode of Conan is "The Detective
Boys versus the Silver Detectives!"
Hawaiian Shirt
Next Conan's hint!
A Hawaiian shirt!
Let's go to the bank during Golden Week.
Don't miss the next episode.
Why?
Because our profits will "flower!"
Just kidding...