Haibara-san seemed to be doing well.
She said her fever had come down.
She can come to school on Monday.
We didn't have to go see her.
You don't disappoint, detectives.
Thank you so much.
It's fine.
You don't need to thank us.
Finding stolen goods is a cinch
for the Silver Detectives.
Right, guys?
Yes.
Those old guys found a stolen bike.
Looks like it.
But the Silver Detectives?
Our group was formed to protect the
peace and safety of the people.
Schwing.
The Silver Detectives!
In other words, they're a
group of elderly detectives.
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
A surprising group of rivals appears
to challenge the Detective Boys.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Detective Boys VS the Silver Detectives
The Detective Boys versus
the Silver Detectives!
So... you're the famous Detective Boys, huh?
You're embarrassing us.
My name is Akasaka Mutsuhiko.
Mutsuhiko?
Akasaka Mutsuhiko (70)
Silver Detective
Retired Civil Servant
You're Mitsuhiko-kun, right?
Our names are similar.
We're both bound by common
sense and stubborn, too.
Stubborn...
I'm Oshima Ginta.
Ginta?
Yeah. Like you, I'm a spirited glutton.
Oshima Ginta (70)
Silver Detective
Retired Shopkeeper
Who are you calling a glutton?
I'm Emoto Yasuko.
Emoto Yasuko (70)
Silver Detective
Apartment Manager
I'm just like you, Ayumi-chan.
I'm the token female who
just screams all the time.
Huh?
I do more than scream.
Tokunaga Eitaro (71)
Silver Detective
Retired Engineer
I'm Tokunaga Eitaro.
Does that make me you, Conan-kun?
You don't need to force the comparison.
Silver Detectives, it's time to go on patrol!
Yeah!
It's the Kiddie Detectives versus
the Silver Detectives, huh?
The Next Day
What's going on?
Looks like trouble.
Let's call Conan-kun.
We appreciate you telling
us something happened.
But you guys...
What? The old folks were the first ones here?
Huh?
Y-You kids!
I smell trouble...
How did you find a body
inside a stranger's house?
I saw a hooligan tossing a
cigarette butt in the street.
Hey, your cigarette!
When I chided him,
he pushed me and ran off.
I called the Silver Detectives.
And we looked for the hooligan together.
Over there!
There he is!
He ran into that house.
O-Okay...
That house, huh?
He's in that house.
Yeah...
We split up and looked for him.
Wh-What is it?
Is this a murder?
C-Call the police...
If he's alive, call an ambulance.
I'd better check.
All right.
Well?
Is he alive?
No...
He's dead.
I see...
The victim is Kuroda Kiyomasa,
twenty two, the family's only son.
Kuroda Kiyomasa (22)
Victim
He was struck on the head with an object.
He was killed roughly one hour
before you discovered his body.
Why was Inspector Megure scolding you?
This is our first murder scene.
I'm scared!
He must have been hit with this.
Probably with this edge.
They destroyed the crime
scene we needed to preserve.
We're sorry.
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
Did you find the hooligan
you were looking for?
What?
I'd forgotten all about him.
Yeah.
He must've escaped while we
were distracted by the murder.
I wonder why he ran when all you
did was scold him for littering.
He must've done something else.
He seemed like a really bad guy.
He had gaudy sunglasses,
a Hawaiian shirt, and bleached hair.
He had a scar right here, too.
A scar?
As though he'd been cut
with something sharp.
Now that you mention it, yeah, he did.
He was tall, right?
H-He was pretty tall.
He was a tall young man.
The victim Kuroda Kiyomasa-san
had a terrible reputation.
All he ever did was party.
He was probably sponging off someone else.
Whoever was paying him may have killed him.
We'll follow that lead.
Let's go.
Yes, sir!
H-He probably bought this car
with the money he took, too.
No, we can't assume that.
We need to redeem ourselves.
The culprit would've discarded
any incriminating articles.
Finding them will lead us to the culprit.
Let's go!
I doubt they'll find anything.
Let's see if anyone saw anyone suspicious.
Yeah, let's.
Yeah!
They're competing with them...
Tossing things into the river is the
quickest way to get rid of them.
These are the sunglasses
that hooligan was wearing.
Oh, this stain...
Is this...?
Looks like they didn't find anything.
Did you find something?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
The Silver Detectives found
some bloodstained sunglasses.
It was the victim's blood.
What?
In other words, the murderer was
the hooligan we were chasing.
He snuck into that house,
killed the victim, and fled.
Realizing he'd left evidence
at the crime scene,
he hurried back, destroyed
the evidence, and ran away.
Noticing the victim's
blood on his sunglasses,
he threw them in the river
to destroy the evidence.
It certainly makes sense.
You're right.
What did the hooligan look like?
He was blond and wearing a Hawaiian shirt.
He had a scar right here.
He was really tall.
He was a young man.
Start looking for him immediately!
They made an incredible discovery.
They beat us to it.
I'm disappointed.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Don't you think it seems too perfect?
What?
I suppose it does sound rather perfect...
Those old dudes got really lucky.
Why did they form a
detective group, anyway?
Something's not right.
What? The stolen bicycle?
Yeah. How did you find it?
Well, someone told Tokunaga-san
about a stolen red bicycle.
Then we all went looking for it.
Tokunaga-san deduced where a
thief would abandon a bicycle,
and that's where we found it.
Really? Tokunaga-san did?
No, I only told the police
my bicycle was stolen.
But they knew it was missing.
Detectives are amazing.
Thank you!
Let's split up and investigate.
Okay!
Everyone's here.
I'll start.
The Silver Detectives formed one month ago.
Tokunaga-san put out an ad
in the city's PR magazine.
This must be it.
Looking for members!!
It was him.
Now, why did he form a detective group?
I know.
What?
Someone in the apartment
next door had just died.
An old lady named Kano Tae fell down the
stairs at the station and hit her head.
She'd just withdrawn three
million yen from the bank,
so someone attacked her for the money.
Tokunaga-san formed a detective
group to find the culprit.
Unfortunately, that's not possible.
Why not?
Kano-san died in an accident.
She tripped on the stairs because
one of her legs was broken.
So no one pushed her?
That's it!
She broke her leg when a car hit her.
Maybe Tokunaga-san formed a detective
group to find the person who ran her over.
No, I don't think so.
What?
We know who hit her.
It's the recently deceased
Kuroda Kiyomasa-san.
Huh?
What?
But he seemed sincerely apologetic,
so she didn't report him to the police.
Several days later, she died after
withdrawing three million yen from the bank.
That money...
He was probably sponging off someone else.
He seemed sincere despite his reputation.
Could he have planned it all along?
That's it.
Conan-kun?
Did you figure something out?
Tell us.
Only Tokunaga-san had any useful
information about the hooligan, right?
Yes.
It wasn't because they're old.
It's like "The Emperor's Snuff-box."
What's that?
What's a snuff-box?
It's a mystery novel written
by John Dickson Carr,
the king of locked-room mysteries.
We still can't find that hooligan.
Where did he go?
You're wasting your time.
You'll never find him.
What?
Why not, Conan-kun?
Did the hooligan really have
bleached hair and a Hawaiian shirt?
Yeah, he did.
Did he really have a scar here?
Was he tall?
Was he a young man?
Yes, that's right.
What kind of Hawaiian shirt was it?
One with lots of palm trees.
It was yellow.
It was red.
It was blue.
What?
Huh? Your answers don't match.
Th-That's because...
There's a famous mystery novel.
Even though a character hasn't seen anything,
they start to believe another
person who insists they have.
There's no way you saw him.
After all, he never existed.
Right, Tokunaga-san?
What do you mean?
You knew the victim, didn't you?
Because he hit Kano Tae-san with his car.
Who's Kano Tae-san?
Er, Tokunaga-san?
You knew the victim?
You couldn't forgive Kuroda-san.
He deliberately hit Kano
Tae-san with his car.
He won over Kano-san with his sincerity.
He tricked her into giving him money.
Kano-san died because she
went to withdraw money.
Kuroda-san's evil scheme
basically killed her.
You wanted to get revenge on
Kuroda-san with your own hands.
What?
You're out of your mind.
I would never...
You didn't want any witnesses,
so you killed him here.
I would get caught.
People leave their hair everywhere.
That's why you "discovered"
the body first.
Even if you left anything at the crime scene,
you could pretend it happened then.
But the police always suspect
whoever discovers a crime,
so you couldn't do it alone.
You had to get inside to discover
the body, so you needed an excuse.
That's why you formed this detective group.
You waited for an opportunity.
You visited Kuroda-san while
his family was away on vacation.
Then you killed him.
You left the crime scene,
threw the bloodstained sunglasses in the
river, and gathered your detectives.
He ran into that house.
O-Okay...
That house, huh?
He's in that house.
Yeah...
You entered the Kuroda family home
to look for an imaginary hooligan
and discovered the body.
Like amateur detectives,
you "accidentally" erased the
murderer's fingerprints
that never existed in the first place.
Meaning, you formed the Silver Detectives
so you could discover the body
together and avoid suspicion.
Tokunaga-san, you...
Did you really...?
Is it true?
Listen, Conan-kun...
You had to discover the sunglasses to cast
suspicion on your imaginary hooligan.
But such a sudden and incredible
discovery would be too good to be true,
so you fabricated a precedent.
You stole a bicycle and pretended to find it.
I've never seen the victim before today.
But you knew which car
belonged to Kuroda-san.
H-He probably bought this car
with the money he took, too.
It's because you waited for an opportunity.
The police would eventually
notice the connection
between the victim and a man
who discovered the body.
They wouldn't consider it a coincidence.
Once they investigated you,
they would find conclusive evidence.
By then, it'll be too late.
But you still have time!
You can turn yourself in
before they suspect you!
It will lessen your sentence!
Y-You children...
We just want you to admit you were
wrong and atone for your crime.
Tokunaga-san!
When Kano-san died, I visited Kuroda.
I thought if only her leg
hadn't been broken...
You should come pay your respects.
That useless hag.
She should've given me her
money before she died.
Th-The three million...
I just need to hit my
next target with my car.
I learned he had planned it all.
I pitied Kano-san.
I'm sorry. I used you.
It's all right. More importantly...
Let's go to the police.
We'll go with you.
Before it's too late.
Children...
Thank you.
Hey! What's going on?
They want to be our apprentices.
What?
Please make us your apprentices!
We'll buy you eel bowls!
I promise not to scream!
Hey, wait! Please!
If they can run like that,
they shouldn't need senior bus passes.
Episode Preview
Damn it!
I have no idea...
Huh? What are they looking at?
Probably a spring mirage.
Uozu is famous for its mirages.
Stop right there!
Mirage of the Disappearing Angel
The next episode of Conan is
"Mirage of the Disappearing Angel!"
Digital Camera
Next Conan's hint!
A digital camera!
Don't miss the next episode.
Don't be bound by common sense!
Eat light!
Don't scream!
Well, that's impossible.