Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
A mysterious visible mirage
triggers an invisible case.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Mirage of the Disappearing Angel
Mirage of the Disappearing Angel!
Mori Detective Agency
I see...
You want me to find your missing husband.
Yes. This is my husband Aoki Satoru.
Aoki Satoru (52)
Artist
Aoki is an artist.
He's left to paint before without
telling me where he was going.
Aoki Midori (54)
Aoki's Wife
But he always reported his progress.
He'd sent photos of his canvas every day.
I see.
And that stopped the day before yesterday.
Yes. This is the last image I received.
It's beautiful.
But it's a strange painting.
How do you mean?
Aoki only paints what he
sees with his own eyes.
But that painting is otherworldly.
Indeed...
Did he change his style?
I know where Aoki-san is.
The water's beautiful.
You're sure this is it?
Yeah.
Those light blue waves he painted
are a natural phenomenon called
a "firefly squid suicide."
Schools of glowing firefly squids only
wash up on the beach in Toyama Bay.
It was last observed here on this beach.
That's pretty obscure.
I-I saw it on TV...
Sheesh.
But how will we find him now?
We'll start by investigating nearby lodgings.
Darling!
The deceased is painter
Aoki Satoru, fifty-two years old.
Detective Sawada (29)
Toyama Police
Inspector Sakai (58)
I see.
You identified him rather quickly.
Yes, because
his wife was here looking
for him with a detective.
I'm Detective Mori Kogoro.
Mori?
Oh! The Sleeping Kogoro?
Did he drown?
Probably. He died last
night between 8 and 11.
The seas were rough last night.
Yes. And we found this in his jacket.
So he was drunk.
According to his wife,
Aoki-san had a bad leg.
He dragged one leg as he walked.
He probably tripped and fell into the ocean.
Actually—
Huh?
This man has a bruise on his cheek.
Look.
He might have gotten it
when he fell into the ocean.
It's possible someone hit him.
Yes.
Wandering around the crime scene again?
Ishiguro Chuji (57)
Fisherman
Who is that?
A local fisherman named Ishiguro.
He's a hard worker, but he fights a lot.
Excuse me.
We're the police who contacted you earlier.
Yes. Aoki-san has been staying
here since two weeks ago.
Hayashi Taro (57)
Hotel Manager
I had no idea he'd died...
Let me know if you need anything.
Thank you.
Huh?
There's no painting.
I found Aoki-san's painting.
What's it doing in there?
Sunlight, dust, and changing temperatures
are bad for oil paintings.
That's probably why he kept it here.
That's the painting he sent me.
No, look.
He added something.
What?
You're right.
There's something in the sky.
Could it be our house?
It does look similar.
Doesn't this look like an
angel ascending into the sky?
The white thing under it must
be a soul led by the angel.
But I thought Aoki-san only
painted what he saw...
He was probably drunk and hallucinating.
Perhaps he predicted he'd
be called to heaven soon.
Ah, that's Aoki's digital camera.
He photographed everything he painted.
He painted from those photos.
Let me see!
What? Okay...
I knew it.
What are you doing?
The photo he painted from has been erased!
Wh-What?
The firefly squid suicide
happened ten days ago.
There's no data from that day.
You're right.
There's no folder for May 6th.
What? The digital camera's
data had been erased?
Yes. Do you remember anything?
Come to think of it,
last night around midnight...
Yes?
Aoki-san?
The victim was already dead by then.
You didn't see Aoki-san,
but possibly the man who killed him instead.
Why didn't you notice?
I'm sorry.
It was dark...
He was dragging one foot,
so I thought it was him.
That must be it.
The murderer disguised himself as the
victim and came to erase the photo.
Something incriminating
must've been in the photo.
I know!
What?
They must be psychic.
What are you talking about?
They went right to Aoki-san's room, right?
Only a psychic would've
known where his room was.
You're right...
With all the other rooms here, it's
impossible to head straight to that one.
So the murderer had visited
Aoki-san's room before.
His wife seemed pretty depressed.
Should we have let her go home by herself?
Her husband's dead.
She can't help it.
We just have to find who did it.
What?
Akagi Yosuke (21)
Permanent Part-Timer
I just told the police about that.
Actually, I'm not with them...
His wife asked you to trace her
husband's last steps, right?
Y-Yeah.
In that case, yeah, I met Aoki-san.
I've been looking for my missing girlfriend.
I visited that hotel the day before last
to hand out these fliers.
I appreciate your help.
I know it's hard, but don't give up.
Right. Thank you.
Excuse me.
She's long gone.
Give up.
Wh-What did you say?!
It made me furious!
But I haven't seen him since.
I see...
Shirakawa Kazushi (49)
Traveler
I saw him two nights ago.
I was walking along the beach
to witness the famous mirage.
That's when...
He looked deep in thought,
like he was contemplating suicide.
So I spoke to him.
We got along quite well.
That night we got drunk in his room.
Really?
Hey, is this...?
Hey, kid!
You can't look through people's stuff.
Sorry.
Did Aoki-san kill himself?
Huh?
I'd like these, please.
Are they gifts for your family?
Yes, for my wife and daughter.
What's that?
You're the last one...
I saw him yesterday morning when I was
delivering fresh fish to the hotel.
He hasn't touched it at all!
Sorry. He just didn't want it.
What?!
Where is he?!
Us fisherman risk our lives to catch that!
I can't sit quietly while someone wastes it!
So you went to his room?
Yeah, but I didn't lay a finger on him.
Where'd you get those scars?
This? I was in an accident
at sea three years ago.
Since then, I haven't had full control.
Who did it?
None of them have alibis.
Is this really a murder, anyway?
Or an accident? Or a suicide?
Damn it!
I have no idea!
Huh? What are they looking at?
Probably the spring mirage.
Uozu is famous for its mirages, too.
Mirage?
Could that have been...
If that's true, then...
I'm exhausted!
We were walking around all day.
Did you find whoever erased the
video from Aoki-san's camera?
Unfortunately, no.
I see.
It's ready.
This looks delicious!
I caught these fish this afternoon.
Really? You fish, too?
Sometimes.
I used to be a fisherman.
Then I have a question.
Does Ishiguro-san always
wear a black hat at sea?
Yeah. He calls it his lucky charm.
Really?
Oh, right.
Before you leave, why not watch them
fish for firefly squids at night?
The ocean glows blue.
It's incredibly romantic.
What a pain the butt.
Why not? Let's go!
Right, Conan-kun?
Huh?
Uh, yeah!
Hey, mister!
Huh?
What is it?
Kogoro-no-ojisan asked me to do something.
I see.
Got it. I'll keep an eye out.
Thanks.
It's 2 in the morning.
Are we really going?
They leave at 3.
Come on, let's go.
I'm counting on you.
Sure thing. Be careful.
This ends now!
You!
Mori-san, is he really the killer?
What?
You told us the murderer would be coming!
Hot pot, beer, and sake...
This is the Sleeping Kogoro?
I set a trap for the murderer.
Once I return to Tokyo,
I could restore the erased data.
That's why I kept everyone
away from this room.
And the murderer showed up.
Isn't that right,
hotel manager Hayashi Taro-san?
Wh-What are you talking about?
I'm protecting the camera like you asked.
The murderer must meet two conditions.
First, he must be left-handed.
Second, he must be able to operate a boat.
What?
Someone had struck the
victim on his right cheek.
In other words, he caught a
left-handed punch to the face.
But what about operating a boat?
The murderer erased the data
from Aoki-san's camera.
In other words, there was evidence
leading to the murderer in the photo.
Ran, the painting.
O-Okay.
We believed the painting
depicted a hallucination
of an angel leading a soul into heaven.
But Aoki-san only paints what he sees.
Therefore, it must be real.
What? But it looks totally fake.
It's a mirage.
A mirage?
In spring, the air near the water's
surface cools and becomes dense.
Light is refracted,
causing a mirage reflecting the actual
scenery upside-down to appear.
In other words, if you turn
the painting upside-down,
you'll see what actually happened.
Th-This is...
Yes. The white house painted
there is a fishing boat.
The angel flying into the sky is a
woman being pushed into the ocean.
And the soul below it is
the murderer's white hat.
In other words, this painting
depicts a terrible murder.
While reviewing his painting,
Aoki-san must have realized the truth.
He told Akagi-kun to give up on his
girlfriend, gazed thoughtfully at the ocean,
and had no appetite for
breakfast because of that.
Who is the woman who was murdered?
The firefly squid suicide in the
painting happened ten days ago.
Akagi-kun's girlfriend
disappeared on the same day.
Based on her haircut and
clothes, it's probably her.
Aoki-san was killed because he realized this.
The murderer must be a left-handed
man who could operate a boat.
Akagi-kun was handing out
fliers with his left hand.
He's left-handed, but can't operate a boat.
Shirakawa-san locked his
suitcase with his right hand.
Ishiguro-san, who could operate a boat,
doesn't have full control of his left hand.
And when he goes to sea,
he wears a black hat.
In other words, the only
man who knew Aoki-san
was staying in this room and
meets these conditions
is the man who held his chopsticks
in his left hand and showed
us the fish he caught himself.
The hotel manager.
B-But that's not enough to...
Earlier you mentioned...
Did you find whoever erased the
video from Aoki-san's camera?
That camera can record videos.
But how did you know it was a video
and not a photo that had been erased?
Only the late Aoki-san and the man
who erased the data would know.
What about the suspicious figure he saw?
An imaginary person to direct
suspicion away from himself.
At first, it was an accident...
I didn't think anyone was filming.
He told me to turn myself in.
To atone.
That's why...
I thought I erased all the evidence.
Damn it!
Thank you so much.
Cheer up.
Aoki-san helped us solve a case.
Besides, I think he saved a life.
What?
What do you mean, Conan-kun?
I mean Shirakawa-san.
He came to see the mirage, but he
didn't have binoculars or a camera.
He only had two bottles of
sleeping pills in his bag.
He probably went to Uozu to kill himself.
But he was buying gifts for
his family at the hotel.
It's proof he changed his mind.
Aoki-san probably prevented his suicide.
I see. You're right.
You're right.
I'm sure that's it.
Episode Preview
Kusuda Rikumichi? Oh.
The organization spy who infiltrated
Mizunashi Rena's hospital.
What about him?
Tell the FBI to keep it a secret.
The organization's man Bourbon...
Amuro Toru is conducting an investigation.
The Scarlet Prologue
The next episode of Conan is
"The Scarlet Prologue!"
Answer Sheet
Next Conan's Hint!
An answer sheet!
Don't miss the next episode.
Did someone say "pro?"
Did they mean me?
I don't have time for you!