Haido Central Hospital
I can't believe she poisoned her own guest.
I wonder if this hospital is cursed.
What?
There were rumors announcer
Mizunashi Rena was a patient here.
An injured man caused a panic trying
to force his way into a room.
There was a bomb scare, too.
D-Detective Takagi!
Shouldn't you go back to the station?
Oh, no!
You don't know anything about a man
named Kusuda Rikumichi, do you?
Kusuda Rikumichi?
Come to think of it, we found a damaged
vehicle a few days before the bomb scare.
It belonged to a Kusuda Rikumichi.
What?
It was a mysterious case.
There was blood all over the
inside of the damaged vehicle.
Some of the bloodstains were
less than a millimeter across.
Bloodstains less than a millimeter
across from a high speed blood spray...
According to forensics...
A gun.
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
A mysterious case at Haido Park.
A scarlet secret begins to unravel.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Haido Elementary School
Hello?
Oh, Jodie. What's wrong?
Did we say we'd go drinking today?
Have you gotten used to your
elementary school teaching job?
Yeah. Everyone loves their beautiful
teacher who returned from abroad
Shibuya Natsuko (28)
Elementary School Teacher
is what I'd like to say.
But it's a lot of hard work.
I'm supposed to meet some parents after this.
I see.
I guess you can't go drinking tonight.
Yeah, sorry.
Anyway, why are you still in Japan?
Your undercover investigation is over, right?
Hey, I invited you out for drinks.
I've got my own reasons.
Official secrets, right?
That's right.
I'll call you later.
Was that your friend?
Yes. She got involved in a case
while studying abroad in America.
And I saved her.
We've known each other since.
Really?
She also taught me Japanese and helped
me go undercover as an English teacher.
I guess we're teacher friends.
I see.
So who are we waiting for?
Shibuya Natsuko, twenty-eight years old.
Elementary school teacher.
Who is she?
My client and someone who might help
me fill in the last piece I'm looking for.
And what piece is that?
Did someone fall down the stairs?
Let's go.
We can't draw attention to—
This woman...
Yes.
I think I'll complete the puzzle soon.
The Scarlet Prologue
"The Scarlet Prologue!"
Teitan Elementary School
Hey, Conan!
Let's play soccer on the way home!
Huh?
He's not here!
He rushed out when the bell rang.
Over there!
Is someone picking him up?
It must be the man from
the detective agency.
No.
What?
That's an expensive foreign car.
That old man wouldn't rent that kind of car.
Oh, right.
Could it be Jodie-sensei's car, then?
It wouldn't be strange for a
foreigner to drive a foreign car.
Come on.
Forget about that mystery nut.
Let's go home.
The professor said he was buying cake.
It looks like Edogawa-kun doesn't want any.
Let's enjoy it without him.
Let's go!
Yes...
That's the FBI car I saw before.
Your priority is retrieving
the transmitter and bug.
If you hesitate out of curiosity
or some sense of righteousness,
you'll lose everything!
Yeah, I know.
But since he didn't tell me anything,
something must be happening.
Something is happening out of my sight.
Ai-chan!
What are you doing?
I'm hungry! Hurry up!
I'll be right there.
What kind of cake is it?
Let's eat it together.
Yes.
Kusuda Rikumichi? Oh.
The organization spy who infiltrated
Mizunashi Rena's hospital.
He ran when his cover was blown.
Once Shu cornered him,
he shot himself in the head.
Right?
Yeah.
What about him?
Tell the FBI to keep it a secret.
The organization's man Bourbon...
Amuro Toru is conducting an investigation.
Of course!
Did you make me pick you
up just to tell me that?
Yeah. Cell phones are easily tapped.
Besides, there's something else.
Maybe...
Maybe Amuro is...
Three, two, one...
Zero!
Ah, sorry.
I'm going to pull over so I can answer this.
What? Natsuko's gravely injured?
She fell down the stairs at Haido Park?
Which hospital?
I'll head right there.
Actually, we'd like you to
come to the crime scene.
What? The crime scene?
Yes. We're at the scene where she fell.
The history on her phone
we found in the park
showed she spoke with
you before eight last night.
That's right.
I called her then.
Wait. Did she not fall by accident?
No.
According to the person who reported
it from a nearby public phone,
someone pushed her.
Hello? Jodie-san?
A-Anyway, I'll be right there.
I'll meet you at the stairs at Haido Park.
Jodie-san.
Camel! What are you doing here?
You called her from my
phone last night, right?
Yours was dead.
That's why the police contacted me first.
Her history showed you called
one hour before it was reported.
What?
One hour before?
Natsuko didn't fall today?
It happened at nine last night.
She didn't have her wallet or phone on her.
We couldn't identify her
until this afternoon.
But we knew she was a teacher.
We followed that lead and discovered
the victim was Shibuya Natsuko-san.
Later, we found her phone abandoned
inside the park and asked you to come.
How is Natsuko?
She dented her skull.
She made it through surgery,
but she's still unconscious.
I see...
Natsuko-san was probably
attacked for her money
on her way home from work,
and was pushed down the stairs.
Yes. We're investigating that possibility.
Hey.
How did you know she was a teacher?
Oh.
There were a bunch of answer
sheets inside her bag.
Wait, Conan-kun? What are you doing here?
W-We were just on a drive together.
Were those answer sheets blank
without anything written on them?
Huh?
Actually, they were all filled in and graded.
I think some had even scored 100 points
and had flower circles on them.
I don't think she was attacked here, then.
What?
Kobayashi-sensei said you're not supposed
to take home completed answer sheets.
The school doesn't want anyone's
personal information getting out.
Some teachers grade tests at home.
But if they'd already been graded,
she couldn't have been doing that.
Which means she was attacked at school?
I see!
The culprit stuffed the papers
on her desk inside her bag
to make it look like she was
attacked on her way home.
They accidentally included the answer sheets.
If her skull was dented, it's possible
she was struck by a blunt object.
Yes.
They must've thought they could trick
us by pushing her down the stairs.
Come to think of it, Natsuko said she was
meeting a student's parents that night.
What? Is that true?
Yes.
Look through her call
history and e-mails again.
Anyone who had plans to meet her
could be important to this case.
Yes, sir!
Haido Elementary School
Inspector Megure, we found it!
There's a luminol reaction
on the victim's desk.
So this is where it happened.
What about the weapon?
We haven't found it.
The culprit probably took it with them.
Last night, did any other teachers stay late?
Y-Yes.
But, Sugamoto-sensei, didn't you say
you'd give Shibuya-sensei a ride?
Oh, well...
Sugamoto Yoshiharu (30)
Elementary School Teacher
It's dangerous for a woman to
walk around at night by herself.
But when I came to the faculty office...
...because I thought she'd be
ready to go, she wasn't here.
What time was that?
After 8:30, I think.
I asked security to lock up and went home.
What were you doing before then?
I was organizing the gym's equipment closet.
I'm a PE teacher.
Hey.
Sugamoto-sensei, do you have a car?
Huh? Yeah, I do.
Its engine is acting up,
so I came by train today.
Which class are you in?
I don't recognize you.
H-He's from another school.
He's here on a field trip. Right?
Y-Yeah.
Inspector Megure.
I brought them.
These are the people who were
supposed to meet Shibuya-sensei.
There's more than one of you?!
What's going on?
The police barged into my office!
I don't know what's going on,
but I need to get ready for dinner.
Let's hurry this up.
Last night a woman was struck here,
transported to Haido Park,
and pushed down the stairs.
It was the woman you were supposed to
meet last night, Shibuya Natsuko-sensei.
What?!
Is she all right?
Fortunately, the surgery was a success,
but she's still unconscious.
W-Wait! Do you suspect us?
You must be joking!
In any case, will you tell us why you
were meeting with Shibuya-sensei?
We'll start with you, ma'am.
I just came to tell Shibuya-sensei
to stop seducing my son.
Seduce?
Ueno Akiyo (39)
Child's Guardian
I don't care if she's from America,
her skirts are too short.
It's no wonder the children love
her and her skimpy clothes.
But Natsuko's fashion is pretty plain.
He says he's going to marry Shibuya-sensei!
I had to do something!
Your skirt seems rather short as well.
I'm not a teacher.
You're a former teacher.
What time did you meet Shibuya-sensei?
After eight.
What did she say?
She smiled and said she'd be careful.
I left after about ten minutes.
I can't leave my son alone for long.
I came to complain to that
irresponsible teacher.
Kandachi Fujiyuki (41)
Child's Guardian
She marked my daughter's answer wrong
because her handwriting was poor!
I came before nine,
but the lights were out and the gate
was closed, so I didn't see her.
Was it really because of her handwriting?
Yeah. All her wrong answers
were actually right.
She should've scored 100 with a flower
circle, but she gave her a 60 instead.
Natsuko wouldn't do something so unfair.
Want me to show you my
daughter's answer sheet, then?
And she even hired some weird detective.
A weird detective?
Is that right?
Yeah. I followed her so I could talk to her
at home when he grabbed me by the collar.
I didn't have a choice.
She asked me to investigate her stalker.
Bourbon?!
Sorry I'm late, Inspector.
You called him?
His number was in her call history.
Are you two English teachers or something?
Actually, they're FBI agents.
They're helping us with the investigation.
Really?
FBI, huh?
The USA's Federal Bureau of Investigation.
I see you guys in movies
and TV shows all the time.
Their investigators show up at crime
scenes to steal all the credit,
smugly interfere with the investigation,
offend the local police, and annoy the viewer.
What?!
I'm not talking about you.
That's just the story I happened to see.
This kid...
These guys tried to...
Camel.
Calm down.
We don't want him to know the FBI knows
he's a member of the Organization.
Yeah...
What?!
You're the one who reported
Shibuya Natsuko-san's incident?
Yes. In addition to investigating her
stalker, she asked me to serve as her bodyguard.
I meant to watch her take her
usual shortcut through the park.
I wasn't expecting her to fall down the steps.
Y-You said someone pushed
her in your report.
D-Did you see who did it?
Yes, I did.
The silhouette of the culprit standing at the
top of the steps, looking down at Shibuya-san.
Unfortunately, I saw them from inside
my car, and they fled immediately.
I didn't see their face.
Just their silhouette, huh?
Yes.
Later I heard the sound of a car
starting from above the stairs.
They probably put the unconscious
victim in their car,
brought her to the parking space
in the park near the stairs,
confirmed there was no one watching,
and pushed her down the stairs.
They probably couldn't see my car at the
bottom since it was hidden by the trees.
Haido Park has unrestricted access.
Hardly anyone's there after nine at night.
Amuro-san's probably right.
But why didn't you wait at
the scene until we arrived?
The investigation would've
gone more smoothly.
I'm sorry.
I had another client in my car.
They didn't want to get involved.
So you left Natsuko injured at the steps?
Of course I only left after
the ambulance arrived.
Is there a problem?
Jodie-san.
N-Now, now!
Investigator Jodie and
Shibuya-sensei were friends.
I see.
She was your friend?
Then it could be the work of
someone who resented the FBI.
Listen, you...
More importantly...
Let's try questioning everyone again.
So far those three are the only ones who met
or planned to meet Shibuya-sensei last night.
Y-You're right.
We should find the culprit first.
We need to find the person who
knocked Natsuko unconscious
in this faculty office before taking her to
the park and pushing her down the stairs.
You're right.
I'd like to hear every last detail
of what you did last night, too.
Episode Preview
So these are the answer sheets.
It looks like we're the
only ones who noticed.
We?
Right?
Edogawa Conan-kun.
The hospital just called!
Shibuya-sensei's condition has
worsened, and her life is in danger!
Don't die!
The Scarlet Pursuit
The next episode of Conan is
"The Scarlet Pursuit!"
Flower Circles
Next Conan's hint.
Flower circles!
We're solving mysteries together again.
Are you sure you're not investigating me?