As I was warning FBI investigator Jodie
that Organization member
Amuro Toru, codename Bourbon,
was investigating Kusuda Rikumichi,
we were informed her friend Shibuya
Natsuko-san was pushed down some stairs.
We hurried to the crime scene,
and found she was attacked not at the stairs,
but at the elementary
school where she worked.
Three suspects were called
in for questioning.
And then...
She asked me to investigate her stalker.
Bourbon?!
Are you two English teachers or something?
Actually, they're FBI agents.
They're helping us with the investigation.
Really?
FBI, huh?
The USA's Federal Bureau of Investigation.
I see you guys in movies
and TV shows all the time.
Their investigators show up at crime
scenes to steal all the credit,
smugly interfere with the investigation,
offend the local police, and irritate the viewer.
What?!
I'm not talking about you.
That's just the story I happened to see.
This kid...
These guys tried to...
Camel.
Calm down.
We don't want him to know the FBI knows
he's a member of the Organization.
Yeah...
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
Amuro says something strange, but the
mystery of the answer sheets comes first!
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Scarlet Pursuit
The Scarlet Pursuit!
Like I said...
I really was organizing the gym's
storage until after 8:30 last night.
Sugamoto Yoshiharu (30)
Elementary School Teacher
It was late, so I came to the staff office to
walk Shibuya-sensei home, but she wasn't here.
Had you agreed earlier to take her home?
Uh, no.
I just thought she'd feel safer going
home at night with a man around.
You once confessed your feelings for
Shibuya-sensei, and she rejected you.
Sh-She told you?!
No, I heard from the other teachers
when I came here to investigate
Shibuya-sensei's stalker.
You were my prime suspect.
Are you Natsuko's stalker?
No, it's not me!
I protected her from bad guys!
Protected her?
Yes.
I sort of escorted her home every day.
Rather, I made sure she didn't
notice me and watched over her.
It was so cute when she'd
sense me and look around.
I knew I had to protect her.
That's what you call a stalker!
Could she have pointed this
out and made you angry?
N-No! She really wasn't here after 8:30!
Besides, didn't she have graded
answer sheets inside her bag?
As a fellow teacher, I know she's
not supposed to take those home!
Answer sheets?
Ueno Akiyo (39)
Child's Guardian
Oh, yes. When I met her last
night, she was grading them.
Perhaps she was only
half-listening to my warning.
I see.
You mentioned you met with Shibuya-sensei
to ask her not to seduce your son.
What grade is he in?
He's probably a first grader like Conan-kun.
Natsuko mentioned she'd become the
homeroom teacher for class 1-C.
A first grader falling in
love with his teacher?
Sounds cute.
Are you out of your mind?
O-Out of my mind?
I warned her to be more modest precisely
because he's still an impressionable child!
Also, my child is in the
fifth grade, not the first!
What?
He had a crush on a different
class's homeroom teacher?
Shibuya-sensei is fluent in English
because she studied in the United States.
She teaches English to
the upper grade levels, as well.
I see.
It's just like my ex-husband.
He spent his money on a
half-girl he met at a bar.
After taking all his money,
she abandoned him.
I don't want my son to
follow in his footsteps.
But everyone around me is
trying to corrupt him...
C-Corrupt him?
I'm sorry, but could I borrow a handkerchief?
I forgot mine in the taxi on the way here.
Y-You're welcome to use mine.
Thank you.
The taxi?
You don't own a car?
I had to sell it to pay
off my husband's debts.
I still renew my license, though.
Y-Your car was stolen?!
Yeah.
When I tried to go to work this morning,
Kandachi Fujiyuki (41)
Child's Guardian
my garage door was broken, and my car was gone.
Did you report it?
Yeah, immediately.
I had to take the train
to work and a bus here.
Now I'm suspected of murder, too.
It's a huge nuisance.
Natsuko is still alive.
What?
H-Hey, you can't smoke in here!
I see.
You said you came here
before nine last night.
Yeah.
Like I said, the school was
dark and the gate was locked.
It was probably after that stalker or
old woman got her and took her away.
It's possible you took her away
after Ueno-san left and
before Sugamoto-san arrived.
I guess so.
Anyway, I came at the appointed
time, but she wasn't here.
So your appointment with
Shibuya-sensei was around nine?
Yeah.
But there was an unsent message
on Shibuya-sensei's phone reading,
"We're meeting at 8:30. Can you still come?"
Wasn't this meant for you?
I don't know.
If you're asking, then there
must not have been an addressee.
Maybe it was meant for the old lady,
and she arrived while she was writing it.
Even if it were for me,
the equations filling her head with
numbers must have confused her.
It sounds like she was grading tests.
So these are the answer sheets in question.
Yes.
Forensics has them right now,
so all we have are photos.
They may be simple problems, but all
these numbers could confuse a person.
Right?
But what Natsuko said was true.
What?
Look.
That drawing on the top right.
In America, they write "excellent"
on tests that score 100.
But in Japan, they draw flower circles.
I see...
Is that all?
What?
Is that all, FBI?
What do you mean?
What about you, German?
I'm asking if that's all you
can deduce from this photo.
Well, in Japan they draw flower
circles for correct answers.
The answer sheet on top
must be graded correctly.
It looks like we're the only ones who noticed.
We?
Isn't that right,
Edogawa Conan-kun?
Huh? What do you mean?
After you saw the photo,
you started staring right at the culprit.
What? Then...
You know who did it?
Yes, more or less.
But it's finally clear now.
I always wondered why she hired a
detective to investigate her stalker
when her friend works for the FBI.
What do you mean?
Are you calling me unreliable?
M-Maybe she couldn't ask.
We're here on vacation.
On vacation, huh?
If you don't have visas,
you must not have many days left.
If you're finished enjoying the sights,
I wish you'd get out...
...of my Japan.
Hey, Zero.
I mean, Amuro-no-niichan... Come here.
Listen, you're an enemy, right?
Of the bad guys...
Zero.
My childhood nickname really was Zero.
You seem to have the wrong idea about me.
Th-The wrong idea?
Now let's solve this mystery.
First, look closely at the
photo of the answer sheets.
Notice anything?
The wrong idea?
The insight to instantly see the truth.
The way he didn't eliminate
Haibara on the Bell Tree Express.
His attitude contrary to his nickname "Zero."
And the clincher is what he just
said to those FBI investigators.
I wish you'd get out...
...of my Japan.
That conviction.
"Zero" is the nickname given to the
organization that "doesn't exist."
Protectors of Japan's safety and order.
The Security Police.
If he's an SP infiltrating the organization,
I thought he'd help us avoid the worst
if we explained our situation.
But if he's not,
that plan we worked so hard on...
What are you going to do, Akai-san?
Do you feel like taking a gamble?
Of course.
He'll find out.
No, calm down.
He doesn't know yet.
There's still one thing
he can't possibly know.
He'll definitely do something
to find out, though.
But what?
I give up, Amuro-kun.
Tell us. What's wrong
with these answer sheets?
Look closely at the answers on the top
sheet and the one hidden below it.
Take 4+5, for instance.
Both answers are 9,
but the top sheet is marked with a
circle and the other with a cross.
And Hirai Umihiko's answer
sheet is covered with crosses,
but it's scored 100 with a flower circle.
Don't you find it strange?
I-Indeed...
Wait.
Hold on.
There's no way the FBI and
Organization agent Bourbon
would meet at a crime scene by chance.
This happened because...
Jodie-sensei.
What?
Why did you call Shibuya-sensei last night?
We were supposed to go drinking.
Who invited who?
She e-mailed me.
It's strange, though.
Natsuko said she didn't remember sending it.
But the message was on her phone,
and she can be pretty forgetful.
Investigator Camel, you lent her your
phone because hers was dead, right?
Yeah.
I charge it every night, but I use it a
lot, so it's usually dead by evening.
That's bad. Maybe...
Maybe what?
Right, Investigator Jodie Starling?
What?
Please pay attention.
I'm trying to reveal who did
that to your teacher friend.
In Japan, we circle correct answers
and mark wrong answers with crosses.
But in America, they mark
correct answers with crosses.
What?!
Isn't that right, Investigator Jodie?
Yes.
But they're not crosses. They're check marks.
Japan marks correct answers
with checks as well.
It's the same thing.
B-But why are the wrong answers circled?
They mean the answer is wrong,
so you should review the problem.
Not every teacher circles
wrong answers, though.
Does this mean the bottom sheet is Natsuko's,
and the one on top was graded
by a Japanese culprit?
Yes.
And aren't the circles on the top sheet rather
warped and sticking out from the answer spaces?
Yes, but why?
Probably because the culprit was clumsy.
Or was trying to hide something
red with a red pen.
B-Blood!
That's it!
When the culprit struck her,
her blood got on the ungraded sheets.
When he used the red pen to
hide it, it warped his circles.
Correct.
The question is which of
those three people did it.
You know who it is, don't you?
Of course.
It's simple, isn't it, Conan-kun?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
It's the flower circles.
It's obvious who drew the flower
circles when you look at the photo.
Th-The flower circles?
Yeah.
Compare Shibuya-sensei's flower
circle with the culprit's.
The swirls go in opposite directions.
Y-You're right!
The culprit's is counter-clockwise!
Normally they're clockwise, right?
Yeah.
That means the culprit isn't Sugamoto-sensei
who wiped his sweat with his right hand,
or Ueno-san, who accepted Camel-san's
handkerchief with her right hand,
but Kandachi-san, who used his left
hand to turn on his lighter, right?
I see.
A left-handed person's swirl
would be counter-clockwise.
B-But...
I'm left-handed, but I draw my
flower circles from the inside.
I didn't draw those flower—
No.
On both flower circles, the line tapers
off on the inside of the swirl.
That proves they were drawn from the outside.
Besides, didn't you say
she got the time confused...
...because her head was full of numbers?
A grade school teacher
teaches other subjects,
so how did you know she
was grading math tests?
Tell us if you've got an answer other
than, "I saw it at the crime scene."
Sh-She laughed.
When I yelled at her for grading wrong, she
said it was a habit from her time in America.
So you struck her?
I didn't know Japan and
America grade differently!
Natsuko was wrong for not
grading Japanese style,
but shouldn't you have understood
if you saw the answer sheets?
I was so angry, I couldn't think...
So your stolen car...
I lied.
I didn't want cops to find her hair in my
car, so I asked a friend to hold onto it.
E-Excuse me!
The hospital just called!
Shibuya-sensei's condition has
worsened, and her life is in danger!
N-Natsuko!
What are you doing here?
You've concluded your business.
She's still my client.
Besides...
You look like you'd let your tongue slip.
What?
Natsuko, please!
Don't die!
Natsuko!
Jodie, you came.
Y-Yes.
I'm surprised you knew I
regained consciousness.
What?
It's partially my fault this happened,
so I asked them not to tell the school.
This is bad!
Jodie-sensei!
Where's Investigator Camel?
What? Probably with the car.
Kusuda Rikumichi?
Don't know him.
He was a patient at this hospital.
He abandoned his car nearby and disappeared.
I think there's a gun involved.
Have you heard anything?
Who knows?
Oh, right.
The information didn't make it down
to a lowly investigator like yourself.
What are you talking about?
We always share our—
Camel!
What are you doing?
Don't wander off by yourself.
Tsk.
I hope you didn't tell him about Kusuda.
Of course not.
I'd never tell him he
shot himself in the car.
My lips are sealed.
I see.
Thank you.
It happened before I was assigned to
Japan, so I heard about it from Akai-san.
Jodie-san?
Where are you?
Episode Preview
A voice and disguise that
could fool an acquaintance...
The only woman with both is...
He shot himself.
I see.
The Scarlet Intersection
The next episode of Conan is
"The Scarlet Intersection!"
Kusuda Rikumichi
Next Conan's hint!
Kusuda Rikumichi!
That's a curious hint.
Don't miss the next episode.
Camel, your lips are coming unsealed.
Seriously? That's bad.