Detective Conan Episode 781
"The Scarlet Intersection"
Investigator Jodie's friend Shibuya Natsuko-san
was attacked and rendered unconscious.
When we rushed to help, three
suspects were called in, and...
I didn't have a choice.
She asked me to investigate her stalker.
Bourbon?!
Later, Bourbon and I determined
the identity of the culprit.
E-Excuse me!
The hospital just called!
Shibuya-sensei's condition has
worsened, and her life is in danger!
N-Natsuko!
Natsuko!
Jodie, you came.
Y-Yes.
I'm surprised you knew I
regained consciousness.
What?
It's partially my fault this happened,
so I asked them not to tell the school.
This is bad!
Jodie-sensei!
Where's Investigator Camel?
What? Probably with the car.
Kusuda Rikumichi?
Don't know him.
He was a patient at this hospital.
He abandoned his car nearby and disappeared.
I think there's a gun involved.
Have you heard anything?
Who knows?
Oh, right.
The information didn't make it down
to a lowly investigator like yourself.
What are you talking about?
We always share our—
Camel!
What are you doing?
Don't wander off by yourself.
Tsk.
I hope you didn't tell him about Kusuda.
Of course not.
I'd never tell him he
shot himself in the car.
My lips are sealed.
I see. Thank you.
It happened before I was assigned to
Japan, so I heard about it from Akai-san.
Jodie-san?
Where are you?
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
What happened then?
A suspicious pair have a
dangerous conversation!
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Raiha Pass
The Scarlet Intersection
The Scarlet Intersection!
Haido Central Hospital
The Previous Day
Huh?
Jodie-san?
Camel!
Jodie-san.
Is everything okay?
What do you mean?
Amuro's a member of the Organization.
We saw his car leaving the hospital.
He didn't sweet talk any
secrets out of you, did he?
N-No.
Didn't you just say that?
What do you mean?
You said the exact same thing a moment ago...
What are you talking about?
I just got here from Natsuko's room!
What?!
Then, when I saw you earlier...
A voice and disguise that
could fool an acquaintance.
There's only one woman...
...with both.
You're late.
I thought you weren't coming.
I had trouble finding a scarf like hers.
I see.
So, how'd it go?
Your man Kusuda...
You were right.
He shot himself.
Inside his own car.
So... That is what happened after all...
What? Vermouth?
The Jodie-san I saw earlier
was her disguised as you?
Bourbon must have asked you something.
Yeah, but I didn't tell him anything.
He tried to shake me by saying the info
hadn't reached a lowly investigator like me.
He provoked you so you'd relax your guard
and let something slip
when Jodie-sensei showed up.
He manipulated you.
H-Hold on.
Does that mean Vermouth knew we'd
come here and was waiting for us?
Yeah.
Everything's gone according to
Bourbon and Vermouth's plan.
What do you mean?
It started with the e-mail you
received from Shibuya-sensei.
Their scheme started there.
Her invitation to go drinking?
Subject: Invitation
Let's go drinking!
Natsuko
You said Shibuya-sensei didn't
remember sending that e-mail, right?
Y-Yes...
Then Bourbon probably sent it
from Shibuya-sensei's phone.
What?
Stealing a phone from an FBI
investigator sounds difficult.
But taking a grade school teacher's
phone unnoticed was probably easy.
If he'd met with Shibuya-sensei
several times as a detective,
he would've had plenty of chances.
But why would he send that message?
So you'd call Shibuya-sensei
using Investigator Camel's phone.
What?
If you're going drinking, you'll meet at night.
He knew your phone would be dead by then.
They were watching us.
B-But why my phone?
Any FBI investigator would've worked.
If something happened to
Shibuya-sensei that night,
the investigator whose
number was in her history
and Jodie-sensei would
be called to the scene.
I see.
From the beginning, they meant to get
intel from the agent who accompanied me.
But Natsuko was injured after Kandachi-san
pushed her down the park stairs.
What if that hadn't happened?
Maybe they meant to hit her with a car.
Bourbon said he was driving his.
Either way, they meant
to injure her outdoors.
Outdoors?
Yeah, so they'd know how you were dressed.
How I'm dressed?
They can prepare a mask from photos,
but that doesn't work for the
outfit you're wearing today.
It's easier to see and take pictures of you if
you're outside than in a building or a car.
Once the disguise was ready,
they called to say Shibuya-sensei took a turn
for the worse, bringing you to the hospital.
They drew Camel's attention
to separate him from you.
So Vermouth, disguised as me,
could get information out of you.
S-Sorry...
But, Conan-kun, when did you first notice?
When the hospital called.
A patient involved in the case could
have information for the police.
But they're only allowed to tell
relatives about a patient's condition.
Why didn't you tell me?
I wasn't sure yet.
It was possible she was
disguised as Shibuya-sensei.
Really?
But what about Bourbon?
What did you tell her?
Uh, right.
It was about Kusuda Rikumichi, their
spy who infiltrated the hospital.
That he shot himself inside his car.
That's all?
Y-Yes.
On the way here, Conan-kun drew my
attention to it, so it was on my mind.
But how does that information help them?
If the man they thought was
captured by the FBI is dead,
they don't have to worry about him talking.
Or could it mean something else?
Right, Conan-kun?
C-Conan-kun.
Conan-kun?
Hey, Conan-kun?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
So who's Kusuda Rikumichi?
He was a member of the Organization.
But what does it matter if a man
without a code name shot himself?
How would you kill yourself with a gun?
Well, I'd place the muzzle against my temple.
Yes, leaving a clear bullet hole in
your skull even if your body burned.
What?
Don't you remember?
When Kusuda disappeared,
there was another man who was
shot in the head and burned.
Y-You don't mean...
Yes. FBI investigator...
...Akai Shuichi.
Impossible!
You're saying he's alive?
Yes, if I'm right.
Sorry, but you're wrong.
His death was confirmed.
Confirmed by the Japanese police
at the request of the FBI.
Didn't I tell you?
The fingerprints from Akai's
corpse that Kir shot in the head
at Raiha Pass, and burned
along with his car,
matched Akai's fingerprints left
on the detective boy's phone.
I see. But how did you get
fingerprints from a charred body?
Because he burned with his hand stuck inside
the pocket of his flame retardant jacket.
That's the kind of man he was.
When he shot me with a shotgun,
he had one hand in his pocket.
Shooting a shotgun one-handed?
Sounds like him.
But it's possible the hand was in the
pocket so you'd find fingerprints later.
If you doubt me so much, would you like to
see a video of the moment Akai was shot?
You mean the movie taken by the
hidden camera on Kir's neck?
Yes. You can clearly see
him draw his last breath.
What's wrong, Kir?
Finish him.
But I shot him in the lung.
Even if I leave him, he should
only last about thirty minutes.
The head.
Shoot him in the head.
Then we'll know for certain his life is over.
Roger that.
Before she shot him in the head, he said...
To think you went this far...
I'm surprised, too.
Speaking as a fellow actor,
he hadn't planned to say that.
It's what he truly felt.
It wasn't a performance.
But I'm disappointed you
dragged me into this farce.
To think you went this far...
I see. So that's how it is...
I'll prove to you whether or not
I'm right beyond any question.
So you know where to find his ghost?
No, not yet.
But once I get a lead, it'll take
me less than a day to investigate.
Did Conan-kun stay home from school today?
Yes. He's in bed with a cold.
What? But we're having curry for lunch today!
You're worried about that?
But it's curry!
It even comes with pudding!
He was sneaking around with
the professor last night.
I'm not sure he actually has a cold.
Mori Detective Agency
Conan-kun!
When do the Macademy Awards start?
Wait, what?
Dad, Conan-kun's still not home from school?
He called to say he was staying at the
professor's place so he didn't need dinner.
No way!
We were going to watch the
Macademy Awards together...
Who cares about a foreign
film award ceremony?
But Shinichi's dad is nominated
for Best Original Script!
Isn't it exciting?
Maybe for you, but why would that kid care?
I guess you're right...
Sheesh. Anyway, get dinner on the table!
I'm starving here!
Let's start with Best Supporting Actor.
Presenting this year's award is
last year's winner, Johnny Bip.
Kudo
Yes?
Delivery.
Good evening.
Nice to meet you. I'm Amuro Toru.
I see...
But this isn't the first
time we've met, is it?
I'd like to talk.
May I come in?
Sure, but just you.
I'm sorry, but could your
friends wait outside?
I don't think I have enough teacups.
Don't worry about them.
They like waiting outside.
But depending on your answers,
we may all end up coming in.
R-Raiha Pass?
We're going to the place
where they killed Akai-san?
Yes.
I think we'll find something there.
That expression he made when he learned
they'd learned Kusuda shot himself.
And the way he lost his cool during
the flower viewing incident.
There's must be something there.
Episode Preview
Do you like mysteries?
Let's start there, then.
But the dead man touched that
phone after the thin man, right?
But Akai-san touched that phone before we
allowed them to recover Mizunashi Rena.
The Scarlet Return
The next episode of Conan
is "The Scarlet Return!"
Raiha Pass
Next Conan's hint:
Raiha Pass!
You think Okiya-san likes
the Macademy Awards?
Don't miss the next episode.
To think he'd be this big of a fan, right?