Haido Central Hospital
Camel!
Jodie-san.
Is everything okay?
What do you mean?
Amuro's a member of the Organization.
He didn't sweet talk any
secrets out of you, did he?
N-No.
Didn't you just say that?
What do you mean?
So, how'd it go?
You were right about your man Kusuda.
He shot himself.
Inside his own car.
I knew it.
What? Vermouth?
The Jodie-san I saw earlier
was her disguised as you?
When Kusuda disappeared,
there was another man who was
shot in the head and burned.
Yes.
FBI investigator
Akai Shuichi.
Impossible!
You're saying he's alive?
Yes, if I'm right.
Kudo
Yes?
Delivery.
Good evening.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Amuro Toru.
I see...
But this isn't the first
time we've met, is it?
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
We've never seen a battle like this.
Amuro and Okiya go one-on-one.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Next up is the award for Production Design.
Presenting the award is Mr. David Carpenter.
Have a seat.
Thank you.
David, the work you've done
this year has been fantastic.
Your performance in your
latest film was incredible.
Your voice was trembling when you
received the award last year.
Thank you for waiting.
You ended up with the nickname
"Trembling David."
Do you like mysteries?
Yes, I suppose.
Let's start there, then.
It's a simple corpse swap trick.
Really? That's a standard trick.
The Scarlet Return
"The Scarlet Return!"
A man was shot in the head at Raiha Pass.
He was burned along with his car.
The fingerprints taken from his right
hand, which barely escaped the fire,
matched the fingerprints on a boy's phone
he had picked up while he was still alive,
verifying the dead man's identity.
But it's strange.
What's strange?
The fingerprints on the phone.
The man was a lefty,
but for some reason his right hand's
fingerprints were on the phone.
Don't you find that odd?
Maybe he had something in his dominant
hand when picked up the phone.
Or he was forced to pick
it up with his right hand.
Why would that be?
Because another man had picked
up the phone before he did.
And that man was right handed.
Another man?
Yes.
Though, in reality, they meant to
make three men pick up the phone.
Now, I have a question.
The first man was a fat, greasy fellow.
The second was a skinny
man with a neck brace.
The third was an old man with a pacemaker.
Of these three men, only one of their
fingerprints were on the phone.
Whose do you think they were?
The second thin man.
The fat man's fingerprints were wiped off.
They didn't want to make the
other two pick up a greasy phone.
The old man would worry
that the phone's radio waves
could cause problems with his pacemaker,
so he likely didn't pick it up at all.
That's right.
But the dead man touched that
phone after the thin man, right?
Shouldn't his fingerprints be on it, too?
What if he made sure that wouldn't happen?
The man anticipated this would happen,
so he coated his fingertips...
...with a film.
That's right. Shu must have coated
his fingertips with a clear adhesive.
To be safe, on both his hands.
What do you mean?
When he grabbed Conan-kun's phone.
The coating on his fingers prevented his
fingerprints from getting on the phone.
That's why Shu dropped that can of coffee.
The coating on his fingers
made them slippery.
Then whose fingerprints were on the phone?
Not Shu's.
Kusuda Rikumichi's, the man who
touched the phone before him.
Which means the corpse shot in the
head and burned at Raiha Pass...
Yes. It was Kusuda Rikumichi's body.
I'm not exactly sure, but Shu must've had
the body dressed like himself in his car,
pretended to get shot by Mizunashi Rena,
and switched places with the body.
I see.
That's a very interesting mystery.
But how did the man who
pretended to be shot leave?
Before I answer that,
could you turn off the TV?
This is an important
conversation we're having.
Can't we leave it on?
I'm interested in the results
of the Macademy Awards.
So how did the man leave?
He was probably working with
the woman who shot him,
so he sneaked into her car and escaped,
out of sight of the men
watching them from a distance.
So they were being watched.
Yes, and the men watching them were fooled.
After all, the man was
bleeding from his head.
Bleeding from his head?
But that was fake as well.
The man who was shot always
wore a black knit hat.
Your neighbor invents devices
that could put MI6 so shame.
He could easily create a device that would
shoot blood out when a blank was fired.
So he asked the woman working with
him to shoot him in the head.
No, one of the observers told
her to shoot him in the head.
He knew he would.
The observer always finished
people off that way.
I don't believe it.
Akai-san touched that phone before we
allowed them to recover Mizunashi Rena.
Did Akai-san already know she
would be ordered to kill him?
Yes.
Shu knew that much.
He's quite the clever man.
He sounds like the
protagonist of a spy novel.
But someone else came up with this plan.
Using the phone covered
in his fingerprints...
You can borrow my phone for a while.
No, it wasn't Shu.
Yes.
Someone else.
Could it be?
Jodie-sensei.
Uh, you know...
Do your best.
What the man said before
he was shot proves it.
To think you went this far...
So he said.
"To think you went this far?"
It sounds to me like he was
lamenting his bad luck.
Yes, that's the obvious interpretation.
But if you add something to
the end of his statement,
it meaning changes.
"To think you went this far
in your prediction."
Yes. He was praising the boy
who had come up with the plan.
I see. Interesting.
We'd better hurry.
What?
We've got some strange cars on our tail.
What has Akai-san been doing since then?
Do you know who he might be?
Maybe someone who uses the same phrases?
Phrases?
You know, Akai-san would always say, "The
odds are 50/50, so we're in the same boat."
Are you all right?
But blame for this accident is 50/50.
You're also at fault for not paying
attention to your surroundings.
The rest was simple.
After the incident at Raiha Pass,
I just had to look for any suspicious
persons who suddenly appeared around the boy.
And that's how I ended up here.
I'm still not sure how the boy and this
house's owner Kudo Yusaku are related.
But it seems you were able to
move in thanks to that boy.
It's him!
What?
I told you about him before.
The strange man with glasses I ran
into at the Beika department store.
I'm waiting for their call.
My friends are currently pursuing your
friends in an attempt to capture them.
I figured you'd come clean if your
friends' lives were at stake.
But perhaps you'd be willing to remove
your mask before I receive the call,
Okiya Subaru-san.
Rather, FBI investigator...
Akai Shuichi.
But perhaps you'd be willing to remove
your mask before I receive the call,
Okiya Subaru-san.
Rather, FBI investigator...
Akai Shuichi.
If that's what you want,
then I have no choice.
I appreciate it.
No way!
They're barricading the road with cars!
Clench your teeth so you
don't bite your tongue!
What are you doing?! After them!
Yes, sir!
Way to go, Camel.
Who the hell were those guys?
They must be working for them.
Now that they know Shu's alive, they'll
capture and use us as bait to draw out Shu.
You mean I ruined Akai-san's plan because
I let it slip that Kusuda shot himself...
We don't have time for remorse.
Focus on getting them off our tail.
It's just like what happened two years ago.
I did it again.
I'm sorry, Akai-san.
What do you think you're doing?
I have a bit of a cold. Can I put my mask on?
I'd hate to make you sick, too.
Not that mask.
I'm telling you to remove
your disguise, Akai Shuichi!
Disguise? Akai Shuichi?
What are you talking about?
Next up is the award for
Best Original Script.
The winner of this distinguished award
is a bestselling author for his
first attempt at a screenplay.
Famous for writing the "Night
Baron" series, Mr. Yusaku Kudo.
The title of the film is "The
Scarlet Investigator."
All right! Shinichi's dad won!
Award for Best Original Script
Author Kudo Yusaku wins Macademy
There's even a news flash.
Isn't it amazing, Dad?
You're drooling in your sleep.
You're both fathers, so
why are you so different?
This isn't good.
The steering wheel keeps
turning to the right.
What do you mean?
I must have damaged the tire and bent
the rim when I went up over that rock.
The air's leaking out of the tire.
What?
At this rate, they'll catch us!
What are you planning?
What do you mean?
Just at a glance, there
were two in the entryway,
three in the hallway, and five
hidden cameras in this room.
Are you going to record this
and send it to the FBI?
Or is there someone in
another room watching us?
Do something, Camel!
They're right behind us!
There's nothing I can do...
I'm sure Akai-san could
manage something, though.
Shu...
Does this person look or sound like me?
You can disguise your face
and use a voice changer.
Where on earth are you?
A voice changer?
This afternoon I researched this area
to see if your neighbor Professor Agasa
had any popular inventions that
he suddenly stopped selling.
It was the choker voice changer.
Once on your neck, it allows you to use your
throat's vibrations to change your voice.
Stalkers found it useful for prank calls.
Why didn't you tell us?
Yes. It's just small
enough for you to hide...
Tell me, Shu.
...under your turtleneck.
Damn it. The tire's nearly flat!
This is the end.
It's over.
Open the roof.
What?
Open it, Camel.
Y-Yes, sir!
Shu!
Akai-san!
A-Akai?
What the hell?
Hey! Pull back!
We need orders!
Your phone is ringing.
Oh...
What's going on? Took you long enough.
What?
A-Akai?!
Five seconds.
What?
Up ahead, there's a 200 meter
stretch of straight road.
Once we're there, keep the
car steady for five seconds.
We'll end this stupid chase.
R-Roger.
Where have you been?
Why are you in the car?
Everything's gone exactly
according to the kid's plan.
Episode Preview
You mean Conan-kun?
Yeah.
They knew you'd come to Raiha Pass since
you were beginning to doubt my death.
This is crazy.
The car's shaking because
the tire's losing air.
I can account for regular movement.
The Scarlet Truth
The next episode of Conan
is "The Scarlet Truth!"
The Macademy Awards
Next Conan's hint.
The Macademy Awards!
Don't miss the next episode.
How are you feeling, kid?
I'm busy right now.
Don't talk to me.