You can disguise your face
and use a voice changer.
A voice changer?
Open the roof.
What?!
What?
A-Akai?
Five seconds.
What?
Keep the car steady for five seconds.
We'll end this stupid chase.
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
A risky strategy with lives on the line.
Who will find the truth?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Scarlet Truth
“The Scarlet Truth!”
Th-That boy?
You mean Conan-kun?
Yeah.
In order to secure me without resistance,
they're trying to capture
one of my close associates.
To maintain secrecy,
they came while you were out driving
and isolated from other FBI agents.
They knew you'd come to Raiha Pass since
you were beginning to doubt my death.
Camel.
The 200 meter straight is
after the next right turn.
Roger.
I'll keep the car's steering wheel and
speed steady once we make the turn.
This is crazy!
The car's shaking because
the tire's losing air.
You can't possibly aim a gun.
It's not a problem.
I can account for regular movement.
Shu.
The right turn!
I'm counting on you, Camel.
The straight!
Roger.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
They're not following.
We must have lost them.
Way to go, Akai-san.
Camel.
Huh?
Turn back.
What?!
Yes, sir.
W-Wait. You're kidding, right?
What? Akai fired a gun?
What about the pursuit?
Most of the cars aren't
in any condition to drive.
Anything will do. If any of
them still work, go after him!
If we let him escape, there's no
telling where he'll disappear to next!
Could you be quiet?
The owner of this house just won
an award and is about to make a speech.
Not that I've ever met him.
Thank you. As you just
heard, I'm Kudo Yusaku.
The only reason I was able to win this
award is because of the director, staff,
and actors who turned a new scriptwriter's
screenplay into a movie.
And we mustn't forget the man who
inspired “The Scarlet Investigator.”
Oh? It's based on a real person?
Yes. Unfortunately, my wife's
obsessed with him right now.
He's a handsome, polite, and a cool dandy.
It's almost a waste that he's in the FBI!
Or so my wife tells me.
Shinichi's dad is kind of cute...
B-But we can't pursue him
under these circumstances.
Are you okay?
A-Akai...
Akai? H-Hey!
Is Akai there?! Hello?!
Don't blame me.
You're the ones who came after us.
If I hadn't done that, people would've died.
But I have a proposal.
Will you trade me that phone
for the gun I just fired?
What's going on?!
What's the situation?! Answer me!
It's been a while, Bourbon.
No, wait. You're Amuro Toru-kun now, right?
Akai Shuichi...
To make up for ruining your friends'
cars, I have a gift for you.
It's the gun Kusuda Rikumichi
used to shoot himself.
If you investigate how he acquired
it, you might find something.
This is Japan.
You're better suited to it than the FBI.
You know who I am?
I suspected you since you were
part of the Organization.
But letting it slip to the kid that your
nickname is “Zero” was a mistake,
Furuya Rei-kun.
Not many names produce
the nickname “Zero.”
It was easy to find you.
You probably meant to turn me over to them,
raise your prestige, and get closer
to the heart of the organization.
But let me tell you something.
Don't get distracted by what's in front
of you and pursue the wrong prey.
I'd rather not have you for an enemy.
Also...
I still feel bad about what happened to him.
Let's go, Camel.
Furuya-san, what should we do?
Should we go after him?
No.
Now that they know who we are,
it's dangerous to pursue them any further.
I still feel bad about what happened to him.
Sorry. It's seems I was mistaken.
I'd better go.
All right.
Before I go, can I ask you something?
What is it?
Why did you let a suspicious man
like myself inside the house?
You seemed determined to talk
whether I wanted to or not.
I did think you were a rather
talkative deliveryman.
I see.
So who were they?
I'm not following.
They work for someone else, but just like us,
they are wolves trying to
take a bite out of them.
No bugs inside the house.
Hey, it's over.
I'm so tired...
You were supposed to follow the plan.
It went well, though.
For the most part I spoke using
the voice changer in this mask.
When I was told to remove it or faced
tough questions, I coughed twice,
and you answered through the speaker
embedded inside the device.
When I wanted to speak, I coughed once.
With all the coughing, he couldn't
have told the difference.
We did a great job.
I think I deserve the Best
Supporting Actor award.
Yeah, yeah.
Though the woman working onscreen right
now is probably most deserving of the award.
Mr. Kudo, what do have planned next?
I-I'm working on it...
These elevator shoes are killing my feet,
and the voice changer makes my neck itch.
I'm sick of this!
You should be grateful to your mother.
After doing my disguise, she took a flight
to the Macademy Award ceremony to play me.
Yeah. She's good at disguising
herself as family.
The Haibara disguise she did
for me wasn't bad, either.
Well?
Is the FBI agent I stood
in for coming back here?
Yeah.
There's someone he needs to protect.
It's perfect.
You managed to disguise yourself.
Thank you.
I won't need to come every
week to check on you anymore.
I appreciate your help.
Though I'm disappointed to lose
my excuse to come see you.
Hey...
Sh-Shu?
Is that really you, Akai-san?
Yeah. This is still my voice, right?
But otherwise you look
like a different person.
But when I use this choker voice
changer, I become Okiya Subaru.
Y-Your voice changed.
It's thanks to Professor Agasa, who made this
voice changer, the disguises of Yukiko-san,
wife of the home's owner Kudo Yusaku,
and Edogawa Conan-kun, the boy
who came up with this plan.
But what's your relationship with Shu?
Well, actually...
They're my distant relatives.
Akai-san was looking for an inconspicuous
apartment, but it happened to burn down.
So I suggested Yukiko-obasa—
Onee-san's home since no
one's living here anyway.
Wouldn't your son Kudo Shinichi-kun be
shocked to find a stranger living here?
I've explained the situation to my son.
Right, Shin—
C-Conan-kun.
Yeah.
Anyway, Yukiko-san...
Are you okay on time?
Your departing flight should be leaving soon.
What?
Whoa! Look at the time!
See you later, Shin... Conan-kun.
Shin Conan-kun?
I'm surprised, though.
I can't believe James knew about this.
I didn't mean to tell him, but...
Were you on the phone with Mizunashi Rena?
Yes. She asked if we could meet in private.
I'd better call Jodie-kun
and set up our own plan.
Wh-What's wrong?
He noticed the coating on my fingertips.
Then why didn't you tell us?
I told you before.
To fool your enemies, you
must first fool your friends.
And they did in fact investigate you.
If you'd told them I was alive,
they would've found out.
M-Maybe so, but...
Though I did take a bit of a gamble
so he could realize our situation.
You mean Bourbon, Amuro Toru?
Yeah. I thought he'd come alone.
But just like the kid predicted,
he came with his real allies.
It looks like his hatred for me
is rooted deeper than I thought.
His hatred for you?
You mean what you mentioned
to Bourbon over the phone?
G-Guys.
Conan-kun!
What are you doing here?
Uh, I just...
We came to have Subaru-san
solve a mystery for us.
A mystery?
Conan-kun, we shouldn't talk in the hallway.
Why don't we have them come in?
Y-Yeah, okay.
Yeah!
Excuse the intrusion!
Do you still have some of that curry?
Yes, some.
All right!
Shu, you can cook?
Yukiko-san taught me.
I save money on food, and
it's a good change of pace.
Really?
First the professor poured warm tea
into four stainless steel mugs.
On three out of four paper coasters, he
drew skulls with a black ball point pen.
Then he turned the coasters over
and placed a cup of tea with lemon
juice on the coaster without a skull.
On the other three coasters, he put
cups of tea with vinegar in them.
Vinegar?
Then the professor said
he gained psychic powers,
and he'd find the cup without vinegar
without smelling any of them.
He picked up a cup and
happily gulped the tea down.
When we looked at the coaster,
it didn't have a skull.
I see.
You shuffled the cups, right?
Yes, along with their coasters while
the professor had his back turned.
And he really put vinegar in them?
Yeah. We tried the other cups.
But they were so disgusting, we nearly puked.
Was that pen the kind you can erase?
Yes.
But he didn't do anything to
them after drawing the skulls.
Let's ask the members of the United
State's Bureau to solve this mystery.
What?!
I told you.
There's no way Akai's alive.
Yes. It seems I didn't need to worry.
You'd better not do this kind of thing again.
I won't.
But if something comes up,
I'd appreciate your help.
After all, I'm one of a few
people who know your secret.
I'm sure the members of the Organization
would be shocked to learn you're the boss'—
Keep talking, and I'll blow your
brains all over the windshield.
That's not a good idea.
It won't be easy to clean up.
It's not a problem.
This isn't my car.
I didn't mean my brains.
Didn't I tell you?
If I die, your secret will be
leaked to the Organization.
Oh, that's right.
Don't worry. Your secret is safe with me.
No one will find out.
No one?
Didn't the FBI suspect you after
you picked a fight with them?
Without any proof, there's
nothing they can do to me.
It's within my expectations.
The only unexpected thing was...
Amuro-no-niichan.
You're an enemy, right?
Of the bad guys.
Going forward, you should probably
avoid acting out of line.
Gin seemed concerned about
rats in the Organization.
Hondo, the FBI's Akai,
and that man makes three.
You know, the secret police agent who
was erased before we got his name.
I think his codename was...
Scotch.
Wasn't it?
Huh? There's no scotch.
Since you prefer whiskey, I thought
you liked scotch as much as bourbon.
I've been into bourbon lately.
Speaking of bourbon, did he really mean
to turn you over to the Organization?
If you explained how you were captured...
He probably thought I wouldn't
talk with you as hostages.
Anyway, did you figure out
Professor Agasa's psychic trick?
No.
I've been thinking about it...
But nothing comes to mind.
The key to the trick is the pen.
The pen?
Yeah. The professor drew the skulls
with an erasable pen, right?
The frictional heat generated by rubbing
the ink with rubber makes it disappear.
In other words, heat makes the ink disappear.
No matter which cup the professor chose,
the heat from the tea made
all three skulls disappear.
But the remaining three
cups of tea tasted weird.
There was vinegar in all
four cups from the start.
He just pretended his tasted good.
Oh...
But isn't that...
Cheating?
Once you know how a trick works,
that's what most of them are.
I suppose.
And?
Why did you have us check if anyone
was following us and come here?
Surely you didn't just want to show
us your improved talent for disguises.
No.
This morning I received a message
from Kir, Mizunashi Rena.
What?
Then they don't know you're alive.
Probably not.
But her message contained only three letters.
Three letters?
Was it an abbreviation?
No. It's the name of a liquor
you're very familiar with.
R-U-M.
Rum. One of their codenames.
Rum?
When I was in the Organization, I
heard the name a couple of times.
It seems he's the bosses' close adviser.
A-A close adviser?
But we haven't heard anything about that.
Since she sent only one word, it
was probably an urgent message.
She couldn't afford to tell you.
In any case, tell James
someone big is on the move.
Someone bigger than Gin.
Welcome to—
Liar.
You're one to talk.
Episode Preview
What?
We can't wait for the police!
I'll catch the culprit and save TB!
TB dies at sundown tonight!
Emi-san, who's Romeo?
Will you go away? You're annoying me.
They're the one who did it!
Wait, Sonoko!
Welcome to Club Orihime
The next episode of Conan is
“Welcome to Club Orihime!”
Initials
Next Conan's hint.
Initials!
You owe me one, Shinichi.
Don't miss the next episode.
Me, too.
We haven't seen each other in
forever, and you're being mean.