Huh?
Eimi-chan!
Oh, sorry! Wrong person!
She fences, too.
Wow. That's cool.
Now where is she?
Wouldn't it be faster to ask?
Don't be stupid.
They'll know we snuck in, then.
Whoa, there...
Sonoko, we can't just come in here.
Yeah, this is bad. We're going to be late.
Sonoko-chan!
Chikada Eimi (17)
Kuwanoki High
Third Year Student
What?
Eimi-chan!
Club Orihime
This is it!
Are you okay, Eimi-chan?!
Your hair... How cruel.
Who did this to you?
They came up behind me.
I didn't see their face.
They're not getting away with this.
Watch out, you two.
In the end, we couldn't find the culprit.
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
A romantic advice club receives
warnings about incidents to come.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Welcome to Club Orihime
"Welcome to Club Orihime!"
The incidents had already occurred
three days prior and the day before.
Three Days Earlier
Godai Megumi (16)
Kuwanoki High
Second Year Student
Yesterday
Furthermore, they'd been
warned about the incidents.
Tamai Chie (18)
Kuwanoki High
Third Year Student
7/8 MG will suffer my wrath!
They were dated with the days they occurred.
7/10 CT will face retribution!
The letters were the victims' initials.
The letters were sent to "Club Orihime,"
a romantic advice club opened at the
school by Eimi-san and her classmates.
Named after Italy's "Juliet Club,"
the club's policy of accepting
letters instead of e-mails
was popular among the female students.
And this morning, they received another...
7/11 EC will be brought to justice!
It was dated with today's date.
Believing the initials EC referred
to herself, Chikada Eimi,
she asked her new friend Sonoko
who she met at her job for help.
They won't get away with this!
Pranks with hot peppers and toy
spiders are innocent enough.
You should be fine now.
But cutting a girl's hair is
a real crime! It's assault!
Thank you.
She's right.
We should call the police.
Wait!
I'll handle this!
What?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I just noticed this was here.
Did the culprit leave it behind?
Let me see.
TB dies at sundown tonight!
What?
At sundown?
That's about two hours from now.
What are we going to do, Sonoko?
We can't wait for the police!
I'll catch the culprit and save TB!
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Um, nothing.
Anyway, let's get started.
Based on the escalating threats and time
limit, it didn't seem like a prank.
But we didn't have access to personal
information like the student roster.
We had to split up and look for clues.
If the T stood for her given name,
there were countless possibilities
like Tae, Takako, Tamami, and Toshiko.
Tae
Takao
Tamami
Toshiko
But not many family names start with B.
Baba
Bando
Bito
We found girls named Baba,
Bando, and Bito immediately.
But none of them felt threatened
or even knew about Club Orihime.
It's no use!
There's less than an hour before sunset!
Eimi-san...
Sonoko, it's not too late to call the police.
This could turn into a disaster.
Yeah, but...
Okay.
I'll start over.
There was something I found odd
about this, and that was...
First, the hair stuck to the window sill.
Could it be?
I found it!
I knew it.
And the other thing is that.
I found it.
Tamai Chie      Godai Megumi
The first and second victims.
What is this?
Dear Romeo
Hey! What are you doing, kid?
Uh-oh.
You shouldn't read people's
letters, Conan-kun.
S-Sorry... I just wanted to help.
Eimi-san, who's Romeo?
Huh?
Kariya Yuto (17)
Kuwanoki High
Third Year Student
Oh, Romeo.
Wherefore art thou Romeo?
He ignored me.
Kariya Yuto-kun, valedictorian
and hottest guy at school.
They received countless letters
from girls madly in love with you.
But it's only natural, right?
What?
Where were you an hour ago?
You cut that girl's hair with a utility
knife in Club Orihime's room, didn't you?
Huh?
I don't know what you're talking about.
An hour ago, I...
I found your utility knife. Meet me behind
the gym so I can return it to you.
That's the same handwriting
as the warning letters.
Did you go?
It's true that I lost my knife.
And buying a new one's too much of a hassle.
And?
I waited about five minutes, but
no one came, so I came back here.
That's all.
You expect me to believe that?
You made up this story
so you'd have an alibi.
Think what you want.
I don't care if you believe me.
Are we finished? I don't have time for games.
You're applying to a state school, right?
What? Yeah.
And you're wasting my time.
Honestly, you're a nuisance.
Will you go away? You're annoying me.
I just know it. He did it.
Really?
He really pissed me off!
What's with the attitude?!
That's why?
What a terrible personality! It must be him!
Calm down, Sonoko.
Eimi-san, did you write
any letters about Romeo?
What?
Oh, right. All the victims
have Romeo in common.
No, I... give advice.
Besides...
There's no way you'd fall
in love with that guy.
There's no time.
We need to find proof that he did it.
I never...
Sonoko, I thought we were looking for TB.
But we can't find them.
Besides, wouldn't it be
quicker to catch the culprit?
Yeah, but...
I've been wondering...
Are TB really the victim's initials?
What did you say?
What do you mean, Conan-kun?
Well, "Club Orihime" is named after
Italy's "Juliet Club," right?
What? Yes, it is.
Maybe the initials on the
letters have something to do
with the characters from
Romeo and Juliet, then.
The first letter's MG could
be Romeo's house of Montague.
And if the second letter's CT
are Juliet's house of Capulet...
You know a lot about Shakespeare, kid.
Uh, I... I looked it up.
See?
Huh. I'm impressed you noticed, Conan-kun.
Neither house allowed
Romeo and Juliet's love.
They only cared about
their house's reputation.
I get it. So that's why...
Wrath
Retribution
They said "wrath" and "retribution."
That's right.
Then the third letter's EC
don't just stand for Eimi-san.
EC, EC...
Was there a character like that?
Maybe EC is Prince Escalus.
He banished Romeo when
he was accused of murder.
It says so right here.
So that's why it says "justice."
I remember now.
His friend was killed during a
quarrel between the two houses.
And Romeo avenges him.
And his friend's name is...
Mercutio.
Yeah. And the man who killed him is...
Tybalt!
Yes, TB.
In other words, "death to TB"
means Romeo will kill Tybalt.
Which means...
Which means he's the culprit!
Wait, Sonoko! Who's TB?!
Well...
We'll find out once we ask him.
Wait, Sonoko!
Is he in the bathroom?
Hey, you!
The guidance counselor asked to see him?
Yeah, but not directly. He e-mailed him.
Could it be?
Yeah. It's just like that note.
He's fabricating an alibi.
Huh? Where's Eimi-san?
Where did she go now?
We finally found the culprit.
Conan-kun's missing, too.
Even the kid?
Sonoko, how did Romeo kill Tybalt?
How...?
Well, in a fencing duel just like...
What?
I forgot.
Because of her fencing skills,
Eimi-chan was asked to play
Tybalt in a production
of Romeo and Juliet at last
year's school festival.
Which means she's TB?
Oh, no! Romeo's going to kill Eimi-chan!
We need to find her.
Eimi-chan!
Eimi-san!
Did you find her?
No. Oh, come on!
Sonoko!
Eimi-chan!
Stop!
Run, Eimi-chan!
What?
No way.
Wh-What's going on?
Did... Did you lie to us, Eimi-san?
Lie to us?
Did you use us?
What did you say?
I don't get it.
Explain the situation, Eimi-chan.
I... I feel it.
I feel it.
Sonoko.
I guess I'll explain the situation.
Eimi-chan, why did you have us
meet today at that time and place?
What?
Because...
Because we agreed to meet Eimi-san there.
You said she was punctual.
Did you forget, Sonoko?
I knew it.
Sonoko?
What? Oh, right.
And we witnessed your attack, Eimi-chan.
Was it a coincidence? No.
You deliberately had us come on time so
you could show us the act you put on.
What?
You stole it from Romeo, or
Kariya-kun, so you could set him up.
But if he did it, he wouldn't have
left that at the scene of the crime.
That's why you had to
throw it out the window.
Considering you meant to use it again
later, it was two birds with one stone.
That's why Conan-kun found the hole left by
the knife in the flowerbed under the window.
Naturally, you're the only
person who could have thrown
the knife into the flowerbed
at that time from that location.
Then you e-mailed Kariya-kun
so he wouldn't have an alibi
and planned to end your own
life as though he had killed you.
No way...
Eimi-chan, you wrote all four letters.
You planned to make us believe an incident
inspired by Romeo and Juliet's characters
would occur so you could fulfill
your true goal of killing yourself.
Why, Eimi-san?
Yeah. You got me wrapped up in this
when I've got nothing to do with it.
Why?!
So you forgot.
What?
It was only a month ago.
I wrote you a letter saying I wanted to
talk alone, and you sent me a response.
I waited so long for you
where you told me to wait.
I promised I would.
But you didn't come.
Something must have come up.
Something you couldn't tell me.
Or so I believed until the other day.
You were laughing at me.
It took a long time for me to realize
you'd bet on whether or not I'd
come and how long I'd wait.
After all...
After all, I believed in Romeo.
That's so mean.
So what?!
Who cares about Romeo?!
You're just intoxicated by some fairy tale.
You must be stupid!
Stop, Eimi-san!
Ran!
There's no reason for you to die or
commit murder over this person.
But you wanted someone to notice.
That's why you asked me for help.
Somewhere in your heart,
you wanted me to stop you.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's okay. Look.
Everyone's worried about you.
Inbox
Re: Re: TB
Is TB okay?
Re: TB
I can't find them...
Sub: Re: Re: TB
Did you find TB?
Please save them.
Inbox
Re: Re: TB
Is TB okay?
Re: TB
I can't find them...
Sub: Is TB okay?
I'm worried about TB.
I asked around, but
nobody knows who it is.
Inbox
Re: Re: TB
Is TB okay?
Re: TB
I can't find them...
Sub: Re: TB
Did you find TB?
I'm asking my friends,
but we can't find them.
We got messages from the two
girls you got involved, too.
The say they hope nothing
worse happens to TB.
But it was my fault...
If you're going to apologize,
we'll go with you.
Right, Sonoko?
Yes, of...
O-Of course, Eimi-chan.
Hey, Dad.
You're out of beer and
snacks, so go buy more?
How about a side of Suzuki Sonoko's
amazing deductive skills?
You know, I don't really
remember this one, either.
What? You heard her?
She's got nothing on your
deductive abilities?
Actually, they're both me.
Episode Preview
I need to think.
Check, Haneda Shukichi.
This rook will break your attack
and shatter your formation.
This is a lance piece.
I see.
So that's what it means.
Taiko Meijin's Match of Love
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "Taiko
Meijin's Match of Love, Part One!"
Lance
Next Conan's hint.
The lance!
Both Ran and my Romeos are so far away!
Don't miss the next episode.
You think you're Juliet?