Tokiwa Hot Springs
Come in.
Taiko Meijin, it's nearly time.
Don't call me that.
I'm about to win that title.
But everyone already calls you Taiko Meijin.
You've already won the other six titles.
One can't be too careful.
I've taken this Meijin match to a 3-3 tie,
but I barely beat the Meijin
in yesterday's final game.
But the commentators said you have the
advantage because you beat his attack.
And the Meijin seemed
unsure of his sealed move.
R-Really?
Oh, a photo.
Is this your girlfriend?
S-Something like that.
Yumi-tan...
That weird envelope? It's gone.
Two Days Ago
What?
You never called me after that.
Wh-When I gave it to you, didn't I tell you
not to open it until I got all seven?
Yeah, so I threw it away unopened.
You threw it away?!
I meant for you to hold onto it!
Anyway, why'd you invite out this
beautiful policewoman on her day off?
What? Oh...
I'm about to get all seven, so I wanted
to make sure you had the envelope.
That's all?
W-Well, yes.
For now.
I'm leaving!
Y-Yumi-tan?
W-Wait!
Huh? Are you Taiko Meijin?
What?
It is you.
I'm a huge fan.
Could I get your autograph?
Thank you.
Huh?
Yumi-tan!
Let's play a game, Haneda Shukichi.
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
A cowardly letter about a kidnapping leaves
everyone pondering the match and the case.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Taiko Meijin's Match of Love
(Part One)
"Taiko Meijin's Match of Love, Part One!"
It's nearly time.
Nearly time?
Time for what?
You guys met him once.
Taiko Meijin, Haneda Shukichi's
Meijin title match.
Apparently the only title
he's missing is Meijin.
He has a Sextuple Crown?
Is that like baseball's Triple Crown?
Yeah. Once he regains the Meijin title
today, he'll have a Septuple Crown.
He'll be the second person
to achieve the feat.
Then the seven Yumi-san
mentioned before...
Is that what it is?
Yeah, probably.
Since he'll have all seven, she'll
know what's inside the envelope.
I wonder what's inside.
Probably a marriage registration form.
Is Yumi-san getting married?!
That's amazing!
We don't know that yet.
Hello?
Hey, Conan-kun. How are you?
Sera-no-neechan?
What's going on?
I just moved to a new hotel.
I was wondering if you
wanted to come hang out.
I'm at the Hotel Hyde Pride.
It's pretty close to the detective agency.
I can't. I'm in a car right now.
What? Did something happen?
No. We're just visiting power spots together.
Taiko Meijin. Taiko Meijin!
Taiko Meijin!
I'm not a Meijin, and the
game is about to start.
But I was told to give this to you before
you resumed playing on the second day.
A letter?
A strange man delivered it yesterday morning.
He said you'd accept it once
you saw who it was from.
Miyamoto Yumi
It's from Yumi-tan?!
But why would she write me a letter?
It's time to reveal the sealed move.
The sealed move is 5-6 silver.
I need to think.
Sextuple Crown Haneda!
Wh-Where are you going,
Sextuple Crown Haneda?
To Tokyo, please.
Huh?
What?
I have your girlfriend.
If you want to save her, you
must decipher my game record.
I'll wait until your clock time runs out.
Don't tell anyone. Don't contact the police.
Signed, the Headless Shogi Player.
First game.
One of seven shrines is attacked by thieves.
The sanctuary is emptied on the second day.
The priest's daughter hiding in
the well is kidnapped as well.
See enclosed photo.
Y-Yumi-san...
I used four hours and two minutes
in the final game of the first day.
Even with the hour I took for lunch,
I still have less than six hours.
I'm sorry for making you wait again.
But I promise...
I promise I'll come for you, so wait for me!
This should be the right place,
but where is the well?
Four hours and ten minutes left.
I need to find the well before then.
Huh? Taiko Meijin.
Y-You...
What's wrong? Isn't your Meijin match today?
Actually, I...
Don't tell anyone
I-I just needed a change of pace.
Isn't the match being held
at a hotel in Yamanashi?
Yes, so I took two hours so
I could come here to pray.
Wow, it's Taiko Mejin!
Can I have your autograph?
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Come on, please?
Huh? Isn't that Taiko Meijin?
Really? I'm a huge fan.
No way. His Meijin match is today.
So it's just a lookalike?
See? Even if anyone's watching,
it'll just look like we're fans.
There's no way you'd come here
on the day of your match,
so people will think you're a lookalike.
You're right.
Could you tell me why you really came here
while pretending to give me your autograph?
A-All right.
No way!
Yumi-san was kidnapped?!
Seriously?! She was kidnapped?!
These kids...
Did you find anything at the well?
A-Actually, I don't know where it is.
Wait, you know where it is?
Yeah. There's only one well at this shrine.
In fact, we were just there.
Apparently visiting it brings you good luck.
Haneda Shukichi's Clock Time
3 Hours 58 Minutes Remaining
This shrine's best-known well is
Kiyomasa's Well dug by Kato Kiyomasa.
Huh.
Kiyomasa served Hideyoshi.
He was a valorous warrior.
He's also known for building Kumamoto Castle.
He even beat a tiger once.
A TV star who was using a photo of the well
as her screen saver suddenly became popular,
and now it's known as a
power spot for good luck.
But doesn't Taiko refer
to Toyotomi Hideyoshi?
How do you not know that
when you're Taiko Meijin?
Why?
Taiko is just a nickname.
I don't get it, though.
How do you know this text
indicates this shrine?
One of seven shrines is attacked by thieves.
The sanctuary is emptied on the second day.
The priest's daughter hiding in
the well is kidnapped as well.
The seven refers to the
seven major shogi titles.
Meijin
Meijin, Ryuo, Kio, Osho, Oza, Kisei, and Oi.
Meijin       Ryuo
Kio
Kio            Osho
Meijin       Ryuo
Oza
Kio            Osho
Oza            Kisei
Meijin       Ryuo
Kio            Osho
Oza            Kisei
Oi
The sender called himself
the Headless Shogi Player,
and instructed him to
decipher his game record.
Shogi was originally not about capturing your
opponent's king, but stealing his treasure.
The empty sanctuary means the
king or treasure has disappeared.
Ryuo
Kio            Osho
Oza
Oi
Of the seven titles,
the two that don't contain the character
for "king" are Meijin and Kisei.
Meijin       Ryuo
Kio            Osho
Oza            Kisei
Oi
If it took two days for
the treasure to disappear,
then it must be one of the
matches played across two days:
Kisei Match
the Meijin match, Ryuo match,
Oi match, or Osho match.
Meijin Match
2 Days
The only title match without
"king" in its name,
that's played across two
days, is the Meijin match.
In other words, a shrine whose name
contains "meijin," or Meiji Jingu.
Meiji Jingu
Isn't that why you left your title
match to come here, Taiko Meijin?
Y-Yes.
Since the priest's daughter hiding
in the well was kidnapped,
I thought I could find a clue about
Yumi-san's abduction around the shrine's well.
The culprit said he'd wait
until your time ran out.
How long is that?
About three hours and fifty minutes.
So our time limit is around 3 PM.
Then there's no time to waste.
Let's go back to Kiyomasa's Well.
Yeah!
If there's a line, I can wait by myself.
It's okay. It was most popular a while ago.
And Kiyomasa and Taiko both
loved festivals and shogi.
Maybe we'll gain something
from going together.
Though the real Taiko
wasn't as strong as you.
What? Sextuple Crown Haneda
took a taxi to Tokyo?
I-Is it true?
Where did he go from there?
I don't know.
I've tried calling his phone,
but he won't answer.
He doesn't have it.
An unspoken rule forbids him from
using a cell phone during a match.
In our age, you can look up moves using
cell phones, which are small computers.
I don't know what happened, but he said
he needed to think before he left.
He hasn't thrown in the towel against
Meijin Katsumata Chikara yet.
Let's wait for the man attempting to beat me,
take all seven titles,
and become a living god.
Wow! There's a huge line.
There's even more people than before.
We'll have to wait to see the well.
Sorry for getting you involved in this, kids.
I'm hopeless.
There's no waiting in shogi,
but I've always made her wait.
I made Yumi-san wait when we met, too.
Wh-What are you talking about?
Are you talking about how you met Yumi-san?
Tell us.
Don't you understand that
Yumi-san's been kidnapped?
It'll help pass the time while we wait.
Will you tell us?
A-All right. It happened ten years ago...
I'd just finished my ranking match
and was riding the Toto Loop Line.
The match left a bitter taste in my
mouth, and I was mentally exhausted.
When I awoke...
Hey, you. Hey.
I-I'm sorry. Was I asleep?
Yeah, and drooling on my shoulder.
What? D-Drooling?
Anyway...
Huh?
Get off the train. Isn't this your stop?
O-Oh, yes.
B-But how did you know?
You've got a ticket.
What? Oh...
Well, I'm going this way.
Thank you very much!
What? Counter-clockwise?
Wasn't she just on a clockwise-running train?
Miwako?
Did she...?
Sorry. I feel asleep on the train
and missed it by five or six stops.
I'm heading back the other way now.
You can head to the karaoke box without me.
Y-You waited for me?
What?
E-Even though your own stop passed,
you waited for me to wake up.
Yeah. You were just too cute
while you were sleeping.
I guess that turned into a sappy story.
But as a man of the impatient world
of shogi, her smile was so...
Huh?
Y-Yumi-san...
She's a good person...
I was moved.
You'd better save Yumi-san!
In the name of your Meijin title!
A Meijin never loses!
A-Actually, I'm not a Meijin yet.
We're next.
Please keep your hands out of the well.
Okay!
Which means it's around the well somewhere.
There's something among the rocks.
This is an incense chariot piece.
Is that the clue the culprit left behind?
Yeah.
It says "second game" on
the bottom of the piece.
Does the incense chariot ring a bell?
No, not really.
What?
There's a weird diagram
on the back of the piece.
A diagram?
What is this?
Check, Haneda Shukichi.
You're forced to take my promoted pawn.
Then this captured rook will break your
attack and shatter your formation.
My victory is unstoppable.
It has been certain...
...since ten years ago.
Doesn't this kind of look like a face?
A-A face?
Yeah, like this.
Maybe a little.
Right? Maybe it's the culprit's face.
That can't possibly be right.
First we need to decipher the meaning
of the numbers inside the circles.
Seven and three...
Even if seven's the seven
titles, what's three?
The only thing that comes to mind is
the third-level professional league.
It's Detective Sato.
Th-The police?
Hello, Conan-kun?
It's Sato. Do you know where Yumi is?
She's missed work two days in
a row, she hasn't been home,
and she's not answering her phone.
You don't know where she is, do you?
Don't contact the police
Hello? Conan-kun?
Yeah, we know. We're
looking for her right now.
What?!
Yumi-san got really drunk a couple nights
ago and took a taxi to a strange town.
She lost her phone and wallet,
so she called us from a pay phone
with the change in her pocket.
But she ran out of money, and the call ended.
So she's been wandering around
somewhere for two days?
I know Yumi-san will find
some way to contact us.
You should get a patrol car
ready for when she does.
You're right. Got it.
You heard him. Can you do that?
Yes, ma'am. I'll talk to my superiors.
I'm counting on you.
Yes, ma'am.
That Yumi...
Why doesn't Yumi-san just go to a police box?
Now a patrol car's ready to go.
So we just have to decipher this code.
We need to figure out what
the seven and three mean.
Does the incense chariot mean anything else?
Apparently it's supposed
to help with easier births.
It's what they used to call
red light district workers.
What's a red light district?
Is it a fun place?
It sounds kind of dirty to me.
Uh, I...
And? Why were red light district
workers called incense chariots?
P-Probably because it's
also known as the lance.
You mean like the weapon?
It's like the spears or
lances you see in games.
But why do they call it that?
Because the piece moves in a
straight line any number of spaces.
Just like a lance.
Wait. Wasn't Kato Kiyomasa...?
Then this seven and three...
I see.
So that's what it means.
Oh, it looks like you figured it out.
You do plan to tell the rest of us, don't you?
Professor, bring the car around.
O-Okay.
We'll tell you once we get there.
It's in the middle of a slope
with a terrifying name.
Are you sure you want to come?
Haneda Shukichi's Clock Time
3 Hours 4 Minutes Remaining
Episode Preview
Yu-Yureizaka?!
This move will fork his
king and silver general.
Yes. Yes, yes.
The winning 4-8 rook.
The pieces on this board...
...signify those seven.
And based on this rook's position...
...Yumi-san is being held captive at...
Get to the car!
Taiko Meijin's Match of Love
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Taiko
Meijin's Match of Love, Part Two!"
Next Conan's hint.
The number 7!
What's your favorite shogi piece?
Don't miss the next episode.
The rook!
The bishop!
Broiled eel!
You're jumping all over
the place like a knight.