On the second day of his Meijin
title match, Haneda Shukichi,
also known as Sextuple Crown Taiko Meijin,
received a letter before the match.
Inside, he found a code and
a photo of his ex-girlfriend,
and kidnapping victim,
Lieutenant Miyamoto Yumi.
In order to save Yumi-san,
Haneda left his match and headed to
the shrine indicated in the code.
There he ran into the Detective Boys as
we were visiting various power spots,
and we began working together
to rescue Yumi-san.
Check, Haneda Shukichi.
You're forced to take my promoted pawn.
Then this captured rook will break your
attack and shatter your formation.
My victory is unshakable.
Haneda Shukichi's Clock Time
3 Hours 4 Minutes Remaining
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
Deciphering coded letters
found at historic sites
brings us closer to
checkmating the kidnapper!
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Taiko Meijin's Match of Love
(Part Two)
"Taiko Meijin's Match of Love, Part Two!"
Y-Yureizaka?!
Why did they name it something so terrifying?
Apparently it's because the desolate
slope is flanked by temples.
It's written on the side of this post.
You're right.
Oh. I thought the slope led to hell.
Our destination is a graveyard
in the middle of the slope.
What?!
Right, Taiko Meijin?
Yeah.
The code we found at Kiyomasa's
well was written on a lance piece.
In other words, the seven and
three refer to lances or spears.
Kato Kiyomasa's seven lances refers
to the seven generals he recruited
to strengthen his forces at the battle
of Shizugatake known as the Seven Spears.
Additionally, the three lances refers
to the Three Great Spears of Japan,
Otegine, Hinomotogo, and Tonbogiri.
The man who was one of the Seven Spears
and owned one of the Three Great Spears
was Fukushima Masanori, who received Hinomotogo from Toyotomi Hideyoshi.
While drinking with Kuroda Kanbei's
retainer, he won the spear in a bet.
Yes.
The upside down T piercing
the overlapping circles
is the cartographic symbol for graveyards.
I see. So Fukushima Masanori's
grave is up ahead.
Yeah.
Do you have any ideas, though?
What?
About who kidnapped Yumi-san.
Since he called himself the Headless Shogi
Player, he must be connected to shogi.
Not really.
Could it be?
4-8 rook. 4-8 rook.
This move will fork his
king and silver general.
I'll win.
Take my promoted pawn.
Let me play this winning move.
My wife is waiting for me in the hospital.
She's waiting for news of my victory.
I'll rise to rank B.
I can move her to a bigger hospital.
Yes. Yes, yes.
The winning 4-8 rook.
Wait...
There's no waiting in shogi!
What?!
Wh-Why is my promoted pawn still there?
What was that sound?
I'm sorry.
I was playing with the pieces
while thinking and made a noise.
What?
But taking two turns is against the rules.
Please resign.
A post-match discussion won't be necessary.
That foul man is a sextuple crown?
Don't be ridiculous!
I was so dumbfounded, I wasn't
there when my wife died.
I became unable to play
and hit rock bottom.
Come. Let's replay that
match, Haneda Shukichi.
That is, if you can find this place.
That's a weirdly shaped tombstone.
It's actually a memorial pagoda.
The small thing next to it
is his son Masatoshi's grave.
But there's nothing here.
Since it's a memorial pagoda, isn't
his actual grave somewhere else?
Yeah, in Nagano, Kyoto, and Wakayama.
There's one in Hiroshima, too.
But considering time restrictions,
I thought it unlikely that he'd send us
to another prefecture after Meiji Jingu.
There's something behind the grave.
It's a shogi board.
What?
Heave ho.
I finished taking a bath.
You're asleep?
The TV remote?
Shogi?
There are pieces stuck to the board.
But why use a nail?
He probably wants us to come to
the place indicated by the nail.
Is this some kind of strategy?
No. This formation doesn't look familiar.
What's curious is the rook and
bishop pierced by the nail,
and the overlapping
gold and silver generals.
Also, there's only one
each of the other pieces,
but for some reason there are two bishops.
I have no idea what any
of this means, though.
Yeah.
Maybe it's a "he."
From over here, it looks like
the character for "he."
It looks like the number 7 from over here.
7 seems more likely.
The first code was about the
seven major shogi titles,
and the second was about
Shizugatake's Seven Spears.
She's right.
Show-off
There's something written
on the side of this piece.
It says "show-off."
Lazy
There's something on the bottom
of the gold general, too.
It says "lazy."
The pierced rook and bishop
say "show-off,"
and the gold general on top of
the silver general is "lazy?"
I got it.
The gold general riding the silver
general is a lazy slacker.
The bishop is making itself look powerful
by wearing the rook, so it's a show-off.
After all, the rook is the
strongest shogi piece.
Wow, Mitsuhiko-kun!
That must be it!
So, what does it mean?
I didn't get that far...
It's odd, though.
The gold general is a hard worker
that moves as much as the king,
and the bishop is a powerful piece
that can move any distance diagonally.
It doesn't need the rook to look strong.
Two and a half more
hours until the time limit.
If you want to save Yumi-san
and return to the match,
you have only about thirty more minutes.
I'm not going back.
What?
But didn't you say you were going to think?
You're giving up?
If I didn't say that, I would have lost.
With no clock time left, I thought
Yumi-san might be in danger.
Besides, I might get another
chance at the septuple crown.
Y-You're right.
For now we should prioritize
rescuing Yumi-san.
It's almost like he knows who we are.
What?
Don't you agree?
We were originally a six person group.
Then we were joined by a seventh.
Joined by...
...a seventh...
We're just like the pieces on the board.
How do you know a piece joined later?
It's the bishop.
You only start with one bishop.
Yes. Just like us, it's weighed down by
a difficult problem and unable to move.
No, you're wrong.
The newest member of the group...
...isn't that bishop!
What?
Eight became six.
And a new member joined.
That must be it.
The pieces on this board...
...refer to those seven.
And based on this rook's position,
Yumi-san is probably being held captive at...
Hurry back to the car!
What?
Did you figure it out?
Yeah. Yumi-san's in Haido-cho!
Haneda Shukichi's Clock Time
2 Hours 18 Minutes Remaining
The Seven Deadly Sins?
That's what the shogi
pieces were referring to?
Yeah.
The Seven Deadly Sins were
originally the eight sins of...
...gluttony, lust, greed, sorrow,
wrath, sloth, vanity, and pride.
Vanity merged with pride, and
sorrow merged with sloth.
Envy was later added to make the modern
seven, just like the pieces on the board.
But which pieces refer to which sins?
There were two bishops.
The pierced bishop had "show-off"
written on it, so it's vanity.
Based on the other bishop's
position, it's envy.
Right, Taiko Meijin?
Yeah.
Since the bishop can only move diagonally,
it can only land on certain squares.
Because the bishop was on that square, it
must have been captured and placed there.
In other words, it's the newcomer envy.
I see.
The gold general labeled "lazy" is sloth
overlapping the sorrowful silver general,
and the rook overlapping
the vain bishop is pride.
Also, the rook was placed in an
aggressive and high-handed position.
High-handed is another
word for prideful people.
Yes.
I don't get it, but where
are we supposed to go?
The rook pierced by the nail is pride.
In English, it's "pride."
The only place around here with pride
in its name is the Hotel Hyde Pride.
Yumi-san's being held there.
What a considerate kidnapper, though.
He left all those clues.
He made sure we'd know even if
someone pried off the pieces.
Even in the worst case scenario, we had
to know what that forward rook meant.
The kidnapper's probably desperate
for Taiko Meijin to arrive.
But is that really the last place?
Yeah. Until this point, the codes were
labeled the first, second, and third game.
Since we solved one through
three, in a Meijin title match,
you win if you take the fourth match.
We're at the hotel, but where should we look?
Don't worry. The culprit
wants Taiko Meijin to come.
We can probably ask at reception.
Ah, Haneda-sama.
We were told to escort you once you arrived.
I've brought Haneda-sama.
The door's lock is covered with tape.
He wants us to come in.
Hey, wait!
Yumi-san!
If you're here, say something!
That's far enough.
Only Haneda Shukichi is allowed to enter.
If you violate that rule, the bomb
I set inside the sofa will explode.
I warned you not to tell anyone,
but you brought friends.
Well, at least they don't
look like police officers.
So it was you, Tanimori-san.
It's time to replay that
match from ten years ago.
Have a seat.
I'm sure you've forgotten, but I had
you in check with my 4-2 promoted pawn.
Same position, king.
I haven't forgotten that match
once in these ten years.
Take your promoted pawn with my king.
All right.
Then my winning 4-8 rook will explode.
Now I've forked your king and silver general!
I win!
Keiko, I finally did it.
I finally got my revenge
for ten years ago, Keiko.
4-7 bishop.
What?
4-7 bishop?
Same position, rook.
5-1 king.
5-3 lance and check.
6-2 king.
4-2 rook and check.
7-1 king.
Now my king is safe, and yours is checkmated.
When I realized I could win,
I got excited, and my fingers slipped on the
piece I was playing with, making a sound.
4-7 rook was a brilliant comeback move.
Either way, I would have lost.
I'm sorry. I overheard you calling
the hospital before the match.
What?
Regardless of my wife's condition, I
can't get there until the match is over.
Tell my wife I'm doing my
best, so she should as well.
Wanting to end the match quickly,
I was unintentionally rude to you.
What? Then you said that...
A post-match discussion won't be necessary.
...so I could head to the hospital sooner.
I'm a loser all around.
I-In any case, we should disarm the bomb!
It's all right.
It was just a bluff.
She's just drugged and asleep, Taiko Meijin.
Yumi-san.
Yumi-san. Yumi-san!
Huh?
What? Ch-Chukichi?
Yumi-tan!
Where am I?
Inside a patrol car.
Conan-kun called us.
He asked me to come get you since
Haneda-san saved you from your kidnapper.
Come to think of it, where's
that guy who kidnapped me?
He took Agasa-san's car to
turn himself in to the police.
So where's this patrol car headed?
The hospital.
You were held captive for two whole days,
so you should at least get checked out.
He didn't do anything perverted to me.
After I left the café, he
drugged and kidnapped me,
but he let me use the
bathroom and even fed me.
But that was amazing, Haneda-san.
You have an important match today,
but you left it to save Yumi-san.
What match?
My Meijin title match was today.
Meijin title match?
Where and when is that?
I'd need to get to the Tokiwa
Hotel in Yamanashi by three.
But there's only an hour and half left, so...
Chukichi, don't underestimate this car.
Hey, you in front!
Change lanes and get out of the way!
Quit lollygagging and move!
Y-Yumi-tan, this can't be good.
We're already in Yamanashi.
You in the patrol car! Stop!
I knew this would happen.
Your credentials look genuine,
but what are you doing?
You're in Yamanashi.
There's a reason for this...
If we don't hurry, Chukichi will
be late for his Meijin title match.
Meijin title match?
Taiko Meijin!
Yes?
Remember me?
You gave me your autograph
in a café the other day.
What's going on? Is Chukichi famous?
He sure is.
Tokiwa Hotel
Taiko Meijin, good luck.
2:57.
We made it.
Huh? It's missing!
What is?
My photo of you throwing a peace sign.
I must have dropped it somewhere.
Who cares about that? Get in there.
But it's my good luck charm.
I lost last year's title
match because I forgot it.
How's this?
Seems more effective than a photo, right?
Y-Yes!
Now go show them what you've got.
I will!
I had no idea comedic storytelling
had Meijin title matches, though.
Storytelling?
You know, the kimono he's wearing.
It must be an amateur storytelling
Meijin title match.
Thirty seconds.
Thank you for waiting.
I don't mind, but are you all right?
You've used up all your clock time
and have less than a minute to play.
Yes. Right now, that minute feels limitless.
There was a police car parked
in front of the hotel.
Do you know what happened?
Who knows?
I certainly don't.
What?
What's with the creepy reaction?
Taiko Meijin Acquires Seven Crowns!
Episode Preview
Wow, it's huge.
Aren't you excited?
Uh, yeah.
Who is she?
The Oiso Nagami-ojosama we just mentioned.
What? My necklace...
You were just swimming.
Could it be in the pool?
The Mystery Sinking in the Midsummer Pool
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The Mystery
Sinking in the Midsummer Pool (Part 1)!"
Diving Cylinder
Next Conan's hint.
A diving cylinder!
After the thrilling shogi mystery...
Don't miss the next episode.
Comes an incident at the pool!
Looks like rain on our parade.