Can we really trust this Edogawa Conan kid?
He seems clever enough, but...
It'll be fine.
And? When is he coming here?
He should be arriving soon.
You told him to come alone, right?
Yeah.
I reminded him not to invite the kids.
He's here.
Be careful.
If he's not worth our time,
then we'll have to leave this place
and find a new base of operations.
Yeah, I know.
Hide in the bathroom until you're sure.
Coming!
I've been waiting for you, Conan-kun.
Hey.
We came with him.
What?
You didn't come alone?
Yeah. When I told them you
mentioned this hotel has a pool,
they wanted to come, too.
What? Should we not have come?
Oh, no.
I'm just surprised because I wasn't told.
You can go to the pool without me.
I'll get ready and head there.
Okay.
Sorry.
Idiot.
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
Shards of glass in the pool.
A strange sound is heard
during an invisible incident.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Mystery Sinking in the Midsummer Pool
(Part One)
The Mystery Sinking in the
Midsummer Pool, Part One!
Wow, it's huge.
It's a little smaller than my villa's pool.
Just how big is your villa?
I'm so excited to see Sera-san in a swimsuit.
I wonder what she's wearing.
Yeah...
Maybe a sporty one piece.
Aren't you excited, too?
What?
Uh, yeah.
I'm already more than satisfied.
Sera-chan's pretty flat, though.
Sera-chan?
Doesn't she seem like a Sera-chan?
I guess.
Sera-chan's fine.
That's what they called me when I was a kid.
A bikini...
You don't have breasts,
but you do have guts.
Guts?
Huh? Sonoko-ojosama?
It's been a while.
Who are you?
Samaki Raito (30)
President's Secretary
I'm President Oiso's secretary Samaki.
Oh, right. We've met at a few parties, right?
You remember.
Thank you.
Samaki!
Come here, Samaki.
Right away.
Who is she?
Daughter of the President
Oiso we just mentioned.
Oiso Nagami-ojosama.
Oiso Nagami (31)
President's Daughter
Huh?
Oiso? Like Oiso Finance?
Yeah.
Honestly, they're just one of our subsidiaries.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
What is it?
Could you rub oil on me?
I let her handle it, but she scratched me.
I-I'm sorry.
Who's the one bowing to her?
That's Nagami-ojosama's younger sister,
Oiso Hamaka (28)
Nagami's Half-Sister
Hamaka-ojosama.
So they're sisters.
Isn't she being too subservient for a sister?
Yeah.
She's the daughter of a mistress.
Her mother died of an illness, so
the Oiso family had to take her in.
The man standing behind
her is the hotel's manager,
Toyoshima Ensaku (56)
Hotel Manager
Toyoshima-san, I think.
President Oiso owns the hotel,
so maybe he's showing them
the recently remodeled pool.
Oh, you're good. That's it.
You're nothing like the
man who tried this first.
I-I'm not used to this kind of thing.
Maybe it's no wonder you're so good.
I'm sure you rub oil all over her, too.
What?
What do you mean?
I know you're a couple.
I know you're planning to take
half my father's fortune, too.
W-We're not!
Miss, don't you think you're
overthinking things?
Shut up!
I know you've been secretly letting
them use this hotel for their trysts.
I hope you haven't forgotten
you're my fiancé.
What?
In any case, I'm telling father about this.
Sister...
I don't want to hear your excuses.
Actually, your necklace...
What? N-No way!
You were just swimming.
Could it be in the pool?
Seriously? Don't you know
how much that's worth?
Kick the guests out of the
pool and block off this area.
What?
Don't forget to check the guests' bags, too.
Someone may have stolen it.
B-But...
Raito, bring me snorkeling gear.
You're going to look for it yourself?
Wouldn't it be quicker to drain the pool?
You idiot.
What if it gets washed down the drain?
Kick all the guests out so we can look for it!
Got it?!
It's no use.
I'll never find it by snorkeling.
Samaki, bring me a scuba tank.
Okay.
I thought you might say
that, so I brought one.
And you.
You're in the way of my search,
so get out of the pool.
B-But, miss, wouldn't it be
faster if we all helped?
Oh, shut up.
This is so annoying!
I'll look for it myself, so everyone get out!
Are all rich girls so selfish?
You're different, right?
Y-Yeah.
Thank you.
Sorry.
I wanted to play in the pool,
but then that happened.
It's not your fault, Sera-san.
It's Sera-chan, remember?
I guess it's okay since the
hotel's lunch was really good.
Yeah.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
The hotel's bellboys seem
excited about something.
Did something happen?
What?
Nagami-ojosama...
...is missing?
Wasn't she looking for
her necklace in the pool?
I-I thought so, but she suddenly disappeared.
We searched the changing room
and bathroom next to the pool.
She hasn't gone home, either.
Hey, what's that?!
Th-There's something in
the middle of the pool.
What?
Is... is that a person?
Nagami...
...ojosama?
Hey, what's that?!
Th-There's something in
the middle of the pool.
What?
Is... is that a person?
Nagami...
...ojosama?
I-Impossible!
Could it be?
Miss?
Call an ambulance and the police.
Right!
Miss?
Nagami?
Wake up.
Nagami.
Nagami!
That's odd, though.
There was nothing in the pool
when we looked ten minutes ago.
Yeah.
What?
Ow!
Wh-What is this?
There are shards of glass
on the bottom of the pool.
G-Glass...
...shards?
Did she drown?
Yes. According to the coroner's report,
she died between noon and 1 PM.
I don't understand, though.
This pool is shallow enough to stand in.
How did she drown?
She was wearing a tank and weights
on her hips so she wouldn't float.
Nagami-ojosama said she wanted
to focus on searching the pool.
Ojosama?
The victim is Oiso Nagami-san,
daughter of Oiso Finance's president.
A president's daughter, huh?
And? What was she doing
at the bottom of the pool?
She was looking for her necklace.
We noticed it was missing
while rubbing suntan oil on her.
We thought she may have dropped
it while swimming in the pool.
Once we evacuated the guests from the pool,
the four of us searched the
bathroom, changing room, and pool.
But my sister said she
wanted to search alone.
We did as she said, and then this happened.
I see.
So it could have been an accident.
Yes.
It's possible she had some kind of
accident while wearing the heavy weights.
If she panicked and lost the mouthpiece
she was breathing through,
she could have drowned.
I don't think so.
What?
They said there was nothing in the
pool ten minutes before she was found.
Right, bellboys?
Yes.
Is that true?
The three of them and two of us came
to the pool to look for Nagami-ojosama,
but we didn't find her.
When we came back ten minutes later,
she was at the bottom of the pool.
Do you know when that was?
I think it was after 2 PM.
Didn't she die between noon and 1 PM?
Y-Yes.
Which means after drowning her around
1 PM, someone hid the body somewhere.
And at 2 PM, they sank her body in the
middle of the pool without being seen.
Right?
Was it possible for someone
to have done that unnoticed?
We split up to search, so
I doubt it was possible.
Besides, the receptionists at the counter
check everyone who enters and leaves.
I don't think they saw anyone suspicious.
Yeah, but...
There was something weird
on the bottom of the pool.
Something weird?
There were a bunch of glass
shards at the bottom.
You stepped on them and cut
the bottom of your foot.
Right, manager?
Yes.
I-Is that true?
I carried her tank to the side of the
pool, but when I tried to get out...
Ow!
I felt a sharp pain on the bottom of my foot.
When I looked underwater, I saw a
bunch of glass shards at the bottom.
Wh-Wh-What?
Drain the pool.
We'll talk after.
Y-Yes, sir!
They certainly seem to be glass shards.
But why are there so many?
Were these here when you were
searching the pool with Nagami-san?
No.
They weren't.
We would have noticed if they were.
With all these pieces, we won't know what
the original shape was unless we repair it.
You're right.
It's an aquarium.
A-An aquarium?
There are four corner pieces
like the one you're holding,
and four L-shaped pieces like the
one Inspector Megure is holding.
What?
You're right.
There are four each.
Put it together in your head,
and you get an aquarium.
I-I see!
This is making less and less sense.
Why was there an aquarium in the
pool, much less a shattered one?
Inspector.
There was a long fishing line
caught in the pool's drain.
Fishing line?
Yes. It's about fifty meters long.
What was that doing there?
Hamaka-san!
What was the necklace Nagami-san lost like?
It had a lot of diamonds.
Maybe the culprit was trying to do something
by recreating the necklace
with fishing line and glass.
The fishing line seems a bit long for that.
You could loop the end and
attach some glass shards.
Maybe they drew her somewhere
by pulling it through the water.
I-I suppose it's not impossible.
Keep investigating the pool.
Yes, sir.
Meanwhile, we'll ask exactly how they
ended up looking for the necklace.
Those three individuals
connected to Nagami-san.
So you all rubbed suntan oil on Nagami-san?
Yes, but she said I was
terrible and told me to stop.
That's enough. You're terrible.
I accidentally scratched
her and made her angry.
Ow! Why did you scratch me?!
I was the last to do it.
But we noticed her necklace
was missing and stopped.
Oh! Sister, your necklace...
What? No way!
You were just swimming.
Could it be in the pool?
Seriously? Don't you know
how much that's worth?
Kick the guests out of the
pool and block off this area!
What?
I thought it would be possible to take off her
necklace while rubbing suntan oil on her.
But all three of you were made to do it.
My sister liked that kind of thing.
What?
She made men zip up the backs of her dresses.
She would make you touch her
forehead because she felt feverish.
It was cute the way she enjoyed
watching people's reactions.
Th-That's cute?
I bet other girls hate her.
Is that what girls are like?
Sera-san, you're a girl, too.
Remember, it's Sera-chan.
Right.
Naturally, I knew she would
insist on searching alone.
She was very particular
about everything she did.
I accepted her selfishness
as part of her individuality.
I see.
But didn't Nagami-san say
her fiancé Samaki-san
and sister Hamaka-san were a couple?
I know you're a couple.
I know you're planning to take
half my father's fortune, too.
She said the hotel manager was
letting them use the hotel to meet.
Shut up!
I know you've been secretly letting
them use this hotel for their trysts!
If that's true, that would
be motive for murder.
It's a misunderstanding.
My sister was overthinking things.
Her birthday was coming up.
We were planning to celebrate in the
suite since she loves this hotel.
We discussed decorations and food.
Since it was a surprise, we
didn't tell Nagami-ojosama.
Because we were meeting in that room,
she got the wrong idea and said those things.
She's always been the jealous type.
Always?
Yes.
We were high school classmates,
and we'd been dating since then.
She really did like that room, so
I'm not surprised she was angry.
That much?
Yes. She's even kicked out guests with
a reservation to stay in that room.
So we had no motive to kill her!
We were going to celebrate her birthday!
If you doubt us, ask the hotel staff.
We discussed the party decorations with them.
We'll be confirming that later.
First, I'd like to hear what you were
doing after you left Nagami-san alone.
Episode Preview
This is an impossible crime!
Right, Takagi-kun?
Huh? Where's Takagi-kun?
Detective Takagi's here.
What?
In the pool.
After drowning Nagami-san, who was
searching for her necklace alone...
I-It disappeared!
Just like Conan-kun did.
The Mystery Sinking in the Midsummer Pool
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is “The Mystery
Sinking in the Midsummer Pool, Part Two!”
Bubbles
Next Conan's hint!
Bubbles!
In the lounge you'll find
bubbles in your champagne.
Don't miss the next episode.
Alcohol?
You're underage.