Detective Conan Episode 788 “The Mystery
Sinking in the Midsummer Pool (Part 2)”
Sera Masumi invited Ran, Sonoko, and I
to visit her at the hotel she's living at.
We decided to hang out at the pool,
but the daughter of the hotel's owner,
Nagami-ojosama, kicked out the other
guests to look for the necklace she lost.
Oiso Nagami (31)
President's Daughter
After lunch, we returned to the pool and
discovered Nagami-ojosama was missing.
Then...
Hey, what's that?
Th-There's something in
the middle of the pool!
What?
Is... Is that a person?
Nagami...
...Ojosama?
But didn't Nagami-san say
her fiancé Samaki-san...
Oiso Hamaka (28)
Nagami's Half-Sister
Samaki Raito (30)
President's Secretary
...and sister Hamaka-san were a couple?
She said the hotel manager was
letting them use the hotel to meet.
I-It's a misunderstanding.
My sister was overthinking things.
Her birthday was coming up.
We were planning to celebrate in the
suite since she loves this hotel.
We discussed decorations and food.
Toyoshima Ensaku
(56) Hotel Manager
Since it was a surprise, we
didn't tell Nagami-ojosama.
Because we were meeting in that room, she
got the wrong idea and said those things.
She really did like that room, so
I'm not surprised she was angry.
That much?
Yes. She's even kicked out guests with
a reservation to stay in that room.
So we had no motive to kill her!
We were going to celebrate her birthday!
If you doubt us, ask the hotel staff.
We discussed the party
decorations with them.
We'll be confirming that later.
First I'd like to hear what you were
doing after you left Nagami-san alone.
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
Someone says something odd by the pool.
The truth comes rising to the surface.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Mystery Sinking in the
Midsummer Pool (Part Two)
Midsummer Pool, Part Two!
Reception
Yes.
Only the staff entered the pool
after we were ordered to close it.
The manager, Hamaka-ojosama, secretary
Samaki-san, and those two bellboys.
Before Nagami-ojosama was left
alone, we let those girls through.
We forgot something.
We just wanted to see what was going on.
After Nagami-san said she'd search alone,
who was the first to return here?
I believe it was Manager Toyoshima.
He said he wanted to check on Nagami-ojosama.
Do you know when that was?
After 12 PM, I think.
She had just received an e-mail.
Oh, right. Let's see...
That was 12:05.
What was she doing then?
She was looking for her necklace.
It took her a while to notice I was there.
But when she noticed, she said that
I was in the way, so I quickly left.
I see.
What about after the manager left?
Well...
The next person was Samaki-san.
I see.
She was taking a while.
I was going to tell her to
let someone else do it.
But I didn't see her in or near the pool.
I thought she might be in the
bathroom, so I waited by the pool.
She showed no signs of returning, so I left.
Do you know when you left?
No.
We don't know, either.
We don't keep notes.
But Hamaka-ojosama, who arrived
when he left, left at 12:54.
She asked us the time as she was leaving.
Why?
I had a 1 PM reservation
for lunch at this hotel.
Samaki-san asked me to check
the bathroom and changing room.
She wasn't in either, though.
She wasn't at the pool,
either, so I panicked.
I couldn't trust my phone's clock,
so I asked to check the time.
By the way, where are the
bathroom and changing room?
Over here.
The changing room and showers are
between reception and the pool.
The bathroom's back there.
You could hide a body here.
Yes. The two receptionists
can't see back here, either.
What happened next?
We called the manager and Samaki-san.
We called the bellboys, too, and
they split up to look for her.
Where was Nagami-san?
She wasn't in the pool.
We searched showers and lockers, too.
We even searched the men's
rooms while calling for her.
We couldn't find her after
an hour of searching,
so we asked the receptionists if
they really didn't see her leave.
That's when they came.
While we were explaining the situation,
the bellboys saw her body in the pool.
I see.
By why did you come back to search the pool?
She wasn't there when you
looked together, right?
I guess I had a bad feeling.
I thought I heard a strange
noise coming from the pool.
It sounded like some big bubbles.
I knew it.
The drain's grate is screwed in place.
Look, Conan-kun.
There's a hook stuck in the
wall directly above the drain.
It's in the exact center
of the pool wall, too.
Hey! What are you doing?!
I'm sure of it.
That's who did it.
In summary,
the victim Oiso Nagami-san said she'd search
for the necklace she lost at the pool alone.
After kicking the three of you out, at 12:05,
the manager Toyoshima-san
came to check on Nagami-san.
She said he was in the
way and made him leave.
Next, when the secretary Samaki-san came,
he didn't see Nagami-san in the pool.
Hamaka-san arrived as Samaki-san left,
and he told her to check the
changing room and bathroom.
She confirmed she wasn't there at 12:54.
Later, the three of you and the two bellboys
split up to search but couldn't find her.
Ten minutes after that,
the two bellboys returned to the pool
and found Nagami-san in the water.
Are those the correct times
and sequence of events?
Ah, yes.
I think so.
Nagami-san died between noon and 1 PM.
During that time, only you three
entered and left the pool area.
One of you must have done it.
But if the body was in
the pool the whole time,
then someone would have found
it while you split up to search.
Furthermore, it's hard to
imagine someone put the body
in the middle of the pool unnoticed
while you were searching.
This is an impossible crime.
Right, Takagi-kun?
Don't you agree?
Huh? Takagi-kun?
Detective Takagi headed to the pool
after talking to Conan-kun and Sera-san.
What?
While you were in the bathroom, he
was carrying around a big aquarium.
He said it was for an experiment.
What is he doing?
Not Sera-san. Sera-chan!
Right.
Also, he said we should all
come see the experiment.
Apparently it will expose the murderer.
Hey! Takagi-kun!
He's not here.
And why is there water in the pool?
We finished investigating, so we thought
we'd try Takagi-san's experiment.
What experiment?
It's...
Don't give it away.
I don't know what you're up to, but...
Hey, Takagi-kun!
Come out and explain yourself.
Hey! Takagi!
Sheesh.
Where is he?
Detective Takagi's here.
What?
In the pool.
H-He's not there.
Where is he?
Do you see him, Conan-kun?
I can't see him right now, either.
But if you cut the fishing
line attached to this hook...
A-An aquarium?
D-Detective Takagi?
Could you see me?
No, but why?
Because the light was reflected.
What?
Both water and air are clear, but water
has a different refractive index.
When light passes from the highly refractive
water to the less refractive air,
if you look at the boundary between
the water and air head on,
all the light is reflected like a mirror,
and you can't see objects on the other side.
Why don't we try it?
You can see my ten yen coin
inside the aquarium, right?
Yeah...
But if you turn a cup upside down and put
it over the coin while there's air inside...
I-It disappeared!
That's amazing, Conan-kun.
It's just a science experiment.
You probably learned
about it in grade school.
Really?
They teach this complicated stuff
to first year grade school students?
Detective Takagi used the same trick.
Because he was inside an upside
down aquarium filled with air,
we couldn't see him in the pool.
Oh?
But couldn't you see him from directly above?
Yeah.
If you view the boundary between
the air and water at a low angle,
it doesn't reflect the light.
But this is a pool.
You can't look from directly above.
You're right.
After drowning Nagami-san, who was
searching for her necklace alone,
the culprit placed an aquarium
over her body and secured it
using a fishing line passed through
the drains on both sides of the pool.
Then they tilted the aquarium,
slipped their hand in,
and released the air from Nagami-san's
tank to fill the aquarium.
Fishing line is elastic, so it could
handle the aquarium being tilted.
But how did they drown her?
It was simple.
They said something to her so
she would let her guard down,
grabbed her neck from behind, removed
her mouthpiece, and held her under.
With the tank and weights,
Nagami-san sank easily.
No one could hear her scream underwater.
Right, hotel manager Toyoshima Ensaku-san?
Did you lower her guard
by pointing at the pool
by your feet and saying
her necklace was there?
But can you really secure an aquarium
with a single fishing line?
Wasn't it full of air?
If you make four grooves and set the
line in them, it won't float easily.
And if you attach the end of the line to a
hook attached near the surface of the pool,
even if you're not in the water, you can cut the
line, make the aquarium float, and reveal the body.
Just like Conan-kun did.
Toyoshima-san drowned Nagami-san
when he came to check on her,
sank her body and hid it using
the trick we just described.
When everyone finished searching, he
cut the line, and revealed the body.
But the aquarium made a pretty
big noise when it floated up.
He shouted something as he was doing it.
Like, “Where are you, Nagami-ojosama?”
Everyone else looking for
her was shouting, too.
The sound was barely audible.
But the aquarium was broken.
Not in the middle of the pool
near her body, but by the edge.
Come to think of it, when did he move it?
It had to have been when they pulled
Nagami-san's body out of the pool.
But the only thing the manager
was carrying was the tank.
Maybe he stuck his foot in the aquarium
and dragged it along the bottom.
What?
After bringing it to the edge, he struck
it with the tank and shattered it.
Everyone else was watching her body,
and it would have been barely
audible in the water.
But the manager hurt himself
on the broken glass.
Would he have done that on purpose?
I think so.
No one would think the man who
hurt himself would do that.
But if the police were going
to find the aquarium anyway,
I'd smash it so they wouldn't know its shape.
You really are a tricky little kid.
You won't grow up into a moral adult.
I was just imagining if I had done it...
Is that really the problem here?
Do you have proof?
Yeah, the fishing line.
When he cut it, he had to quickly reel in the
line attached to the drain on the other side.
Manager Toyoshima's fingerprints
should be all over it.
But isn't fishing line really thin?
Maybe individual lines.
But he probably gathered it
together while reeling them in,
so his fingerprints should
match up to a few places.
You can find that, right, forensics?
Of course.
B-But he had no motive to kill her.
That's right.
We discussed celebrating
her birthday together.
I didn't want to celebrate,
especially not in that suite.
What?
I had a much younger sister.
She reserved the room with her husband
because they wanted just once to stay there.
They were celebrating their
son's third birthday.
The room has a good view,
and that day's fireworks display would
have been visible from the balcony.
But suddenly,
Nagami-ojosama said she wanted to view the
fireworks from that room with her friends.
My sister's family had to
move to another hotel.
On the way there, they got in
an accident, and they all died.
No...
So you resented her for that?
For that? Of course not.
That day, she didn't stay in that room.
Do you know why?
Because her friend's car she was taking
to the hotel caused an accident.
Yes. That woman was riding in the
car that killed my sister's family.
B-But how did you find out?
She called me that day.
She was riding in her friend's
car when it caused an accident,
but she didn't want to get involved.
She asked me to pretend she had been
in the suite since that afternoon.
Since then, I'd been waiting
for my opportunity for revenge.
For her to come to this pool.
Removing the necklace that would
set my plan in motion was a gamble.
But heaven was on my side.
In the end, though, those young detectives
exposed the murder I planned so carefully.
It was all for nothing.
Sorry.
You came to see me, but
I wasn't much of a host.
You couldn't help it. There was a murder.
It's just like what happened
at the “Which Sweets SHOW.”
You make people appear and
disappear out of thin air.
You're like a magician.
A magician?
I'm not the magician.
Huh?
You're a magician.
L-Listen...
Sera-chan, have we met before?
You just said Sera-chan!
Sorry.
You can call me Sera-chan.
She says it's fine.
Yeah.
Well, see you later.
Okay.
Bye.
Let's get out of here, too.
Huh?
That girl...
I think I've seen her before, too.
Episode Preview
Yasumi-san!
So it was an accident?
We've got nothing to do with this.
So that's how it is.
There's more to my reasoning.
There are a few mysteries left.
The Queen's Weather Forecast
The next episode of Conan is “The
Queen's Weather Forecast!”
Prank
Next Conan's hint!
A prank!
Don't miss the next episode.
I'm going to study to become
a weather forecaster.
Wow.