Detective Conan Episode 789 "The
Queen's Weather Forecast"
Nichiuri TV Office
It's going to stop drizzling soon?
Yes. We've calculated the wind, temperature,
humidity, and atmospheric pressure.
The results say the skies
should clear in an hour.
Detective versus Weather Reporter
That's a bold claim.
It's no wonder they call you the 100%
accurate beautiful weather forecaster.
I'm impressed.
Don't you solve cases in a similar fashion?
O-Of course!
In order to expose the ingenious
trips of criminals, I...
Uh, trips?
Sheesh!
I'm sorry. He'll get it eventually.
No problem. It's funny.
Right?
Yes. This will make a good show.
He's wonderful.
T-Tricks!
Yes, I will solve any trick and
any suspicions within an hour.
Propelled forward by the
years spent together.
Charging full speed ahead
without slowing the pace.
Not even this popular weather forecaster
can predict if it's an accident or a case.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Queen's Weather Forecast
"The Queen's Weather Forecast!"
Sheesh.
Solve any suspicion or trick in an hour?
I know she's beautiful,
but you need to calm down.
Huh? Where did the kid go?
An hour might not be enough for the old man.
What did you say?
I heard with my own ears.
I'm sure of it.
Sekine Yasumi (27)
Charismatic Weather Forecaster
Really?
Got it. Thanks.
That's that.
Kodama Yukio (49)
Nichiuri TV Producer
Oh, right. I'll send you the
proposal for your next show soon.
I look forward to it.
Yamaguchi Takuya (35)
Yasumi's Manager
Shinohara-san, did you check the stage?
Shinohara Hiroko (28)
Nichiuri TV Assistant Director
Yes! Everything looks good.
We're restricting access to the
stage so no one goes near it.
Really? Good work.
Would you like to check?
No, I trust you.
Mori-sensei, I hope you'll
appear on my show again.
Sure, gladly!
There you are.
Yasumi-san, we start shooting
right after the break.
Very well. Excuse me.
Good work.
Here, mister. I bought you a drink.
Thanks.
This is your backwash.
Yasumi-san still has work?
Yup. She's shooting a video next door.
This is what she's shooting.
She's appearing on a misty stage as
snow falls steadily all around her.
How wonderful!
It's meant to invoke images
of a weather forecast.
She's the queen of weather forecasts.
I bet she's quite popular.
Shall we go?
Yeah.
What?
Mister, over there!
Yasumi-san!
Sekine-san!
Don't move!
Stay where you are!
The left side of her hair...
Mister, look at that.
What is this?
Hold on.
Is this a... d-dying message?!
Which means...
Get the police!
Call the police!
This is...
Yasumi-san's hair accessory.
What's it doing over here?
She died immediately from the fall.
Why, though?
Was there something wrong with the set?
You were the last one to check it, right?
I was, but nothing stood out.
Producer Kodama Yukio-san.
Victim Sekine Yasumi-san's
manager Yamaguchi Takuya-san.
AD Shinohara Hiroko-san.
The three of them were near the scene.
According to the staff, this
structure was deteriorating,
and they planned to tear it down next year.
I see.
Inspector, I got it.
After meeting with me,
Yasumi-san took a break.
Then she had plans to shoot a video.
But before her break, she decided
to come check this stage.
She leaned against the railing,
but a section had deteriorated,
and she fell to the first floor.
So it was an accident?
Yes, it's likely.
Looks like we didn't need to call you.
Then what about Yasumi-san's dying message?
She scratched it on the floor with her bloody
hand while writhing in her final moments!
Ouch!
I pricked myself on the roses' thorns.
What are you doing there, kid?
Sorry.
Now I'm tangled in the tinsel.
What are you doing?
Huh?
There's a popped balloon over here.
Come to think of it, didn't you hear
a popping sound before the scream?
Yeah, a loud popping...
What? Balloon, tinsel, roses.
What is it?
Are we through?
We need to switch out the studio set.
Besides, we were all over
there when Sekine-san fell.
We've got nothing to do with this.
Right?
Yes.
Very well. Everyone—
No!
What?
You can't fool Mori Kogoro.
This may look like an accident, but it's not.
What do you mean, Mori-kun?
Someone set a trap for Yasumi-san.
A trap?
Yes. Look at the stage's decorations.
First, you tie this tinsel
to one of the stage's supports.
Then you tie this end to the
opposite side of the stage.
There.
Ran, walk across the stage.
What?
Right here, please.
Okay.
Didn't you hear this sound
before Yasumi-san's scream?
Yes.
That's right.
She came to check the stage and
fell for this malicious trap.
Shocked, she staggered to the railing, and...
Which means it was murder.
No, this isn't enough to make her fall.
The trap was simply set to frighten her.
And it led to this tragedy.
Then who did this?
When did you finish setting up the stage?
Yamaguchi-san, you said you'd be
here until the early morning, right?
What? Uh, yes.
Is something wrong?
I actually fell asleep.
By the time I woke up, they
had just started recording.
You fell asleep?
Yes, but I couldn't tell Yasumi-san.
I'm sorry.
Then we still don't know
who set the trap or when.
Who was the last person to check the stage?
I was the last one.
But I didn't notice anything.
You said you didn't see anything then.
Are you sure?
Y-Yes.
The truth is this was stuck to the tinsel.
D-Duct tape?
You could find that anywhere!
Then shall we investigate the fingers
and footprints left around the trap?
We may find definitive proof of who did this.
Inspector, call forensics.
Yes, sir.
We'll collect fingerprints
and saliva samples from you.
No. I can't do it!
Why not?
I just can't.
That's enough, Shinohara. Stop.
I know you did this.
I overheard your conversation
in the kitchen yesterday.
How awful of Yasumi-san.
Changing the studio set
by tomorrow is insane.
I have to do it.
But I won't take this lying down.
I'll embarrass Yasumi-san
tomorrow with a balloon.
I couldn't say anything because I thought
it would embarrass our company.
Hiroko-san, is that true?
That's right!
I set up that balloon!
I hated her.
She acted like a selfish queen.
Right, Yamaguchi-san?
Even you...
If there's anything wrong with the set
again, I don't want to see you again!
She was arrogant and selfish.
This isn't what I described.
Make a new one by tomorrow.
I wanted to make a fool out of that
arrogant woman in front of everyone!
But I never thought...
I never thought this would happen.
We'll accompany you to the station.
All right.
Something doesn't seem right.
The other sound I heard.
Her hair that was disheveled
on only one side.
The hair accessory.
This is... A smoke machine?
So that's how it is.
Th-There it is!
Dad?
Your reasoning until now was wrong, right?
No. Unusually enough, I was right.
What? Right?
Unusually?
Excuse me.
There's more to my reasoning.
There are a few mysteries left.
Mysteries?
Yes. Conan told me Yasumi-san said
she wouldn't check the stage.
However, in reality she
did and fell for the trap.
Don't you find that odd?
Indeed.
But if you think of it this
way, it all makes sense.
Yasumi-san already knew about the trap.
Huh?
Hold on. How?
The true culprit told her.
The true culprit?
Yes. This person told her beforehand
about the balloon trap.
They advised her to pop it before filming
to make a fool out of Hiroko-san.
Make a fool out of me?
Yes. Yasumi-san meant to
torment you even more.
Additionally, the culprit
told her she would be safe
if she stood off to the side near the railing.
Yasumi-san did as she was told
and triggered the balloon trap.
Naturally, she wasn't surprised.
But in the next moment, she triggered
a second trap set by the true culprit.
A second trap?
Yes. Hey, Conan!
The snow falls steadily and
the scene fills with mist.
The queen of weather forecasts.
That was the stage set by Yasumi-san.
Look at this.
There's a machine over here.
A smoke machine?
Yes, a smoke machine.
The other mystery left behind
is the whooshing sound
heard after the popping balloon.
Some of you must have heard it as well.
When the culprit heard the balloon
pop, they turned on the machine.
It was set to maximum power.
Detective Takagi, will
you turn the machine on?
Sure.
Wh-What is this?
The culprit covered Yasumi-san
with the carbon gas mist
at great intensity.
Unable to open her eyes, she
was forced to back away.
However, the dilapidated
railing was right behind her.
It must have been broken beforehand.
Then she fell.
Hold on, Mori-kun.
There's no evidence the gas got on her.
The gas evaporated immediately.
But only the left side of
Yasumi-san's hair was disheveled.
Additionally, her hair accessory
flew to the far wall.
A blast of gas from her left
must have disheveled her hair,
and blew off her hair accessory.
The culprit set their own
trap behind Hiroko-san's trap,
and used her to avoid suspicion.
Mori-kun, who is the true culprit?
It's simple.
It was someone who knew of Hiroko-san's plan.
Kodama-san!
What?
You said you overheard it.
You're saying I did it?
Eavesdropping makes me a murderer?
Not only that, but you told Yasumi-san
about it to lead her into your trap.
I've had enough.
Do you have proof?
You're wearing a marvelous brown suit today.
What?
Paired with your brown shoes,
you look truly fashionable.
Did you polish them this morning?
So, what?
Because it's drizzling and humid
today, your shoe polish didn't dry.
The mouth of the smoke machine was
pointed towards the dilapidated railing.
After the incident, the culprit had to turn
the funnel back to its original position.
You left your brown shoe
polish on the machine.
Y-You're wrong. It proves nothing!
Shinohara-san.
Y-Yes?
How do you turn on the machine?
Manually or wirelessly.
Wirelessly?
Takagi-kun!
Stop. Don't do this.
I found it!
Why do you have that?
Damn it.
Kodama-san, why?
She was a terrible woman.
She realized I'd been embezzling
the program's funds.
She threatened me with the proof she found.
She made me set up new programs for her
and hand over the production funds.
Again and again...
I refused to be her slave.
I can't believe the drizzle gave it away.
The drizzle? You're wrong, Kodama-san.
I thought it was you for another reason.
Before she fell, Yasumi-san
realized you had deceived her.
She used her remaining strength
to leave a dying message
using a special symbol
so you wouldn't notice.
The weather symbol... for snow.
Kodama Yukio-san, you're the only man
with snow, or "yuki," in his name.
I see.
She truly is the queen of weather forecasts.
Damn that woman...
The skies are clear. Yasumi-san's
forecast was right.
And I solved the case within an hour.
I'm glad the skies cleared up.
Yeah.
But what's tomorrow's weather, Dad?
Huh? Tomorrow's weather?
No way. He may be able to solve mysteries,
but he can't predict the weather.
What's that? Sure I can.
Tomorrow's weather is...
It'll be sunny tomorrow, too!
Die, Kanzaki!
Episode Preview
He was inside Bekapon.
Bekapon?
That's Beikado's mascot, right?
You think one of our employees did it?
This case of friendly fire
doesn't make any sense.
Bekapon's Bleeding Service
The next episode of Conan is
"Bekapon's Bleeding Service!"
Uniform
Next Conan's hint!
A uniform!
Don't miss the next episode.
It's Bekapon, not Bekashi.
Is he a Beika City character?