Regarding the request you
made the other day,
Mori Detective Agency
a thorough investigation
revealed, Kanzaki-san,
that not a single person hates you.
Kanzaki Yukio (23)
Supermarket Beikado Employee
B-But someone called to say they'd kill me.
You mentioned a couple calls like that, but
I think it was a joke played by your friends.
A-A joke?
Everyone I asked had only
good things to say about you.
They were just teasing you.
That doesn't surprise me.
Udagawa Katsumi (41)
Supermarket Beikado Floor Manager
So no one is trying to kill Kanzaki-kun?
You're Udagawa-san, right?
I understand your concern for your employee.
But if they really meant to harm
him, they wouldn't send a warning.
It only puts him on his guard.
And it doesn't help the culprit at all.
What?
Supermarket
Beikado
But several days later...
Die, Kanzaki!
Conan's detective skills solve
the most unsolvable of crimes.
Times may change, but the
starting point remains the same.
The culprit's goal behind stabbing a
store's marketing character is a mystery.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Bekapon's Bleeding Service
Bekapon's Bleeding Service!
Supermarket
Beikado
I'm sorry for asking the
same question over and over.
Mori-san...
Inspector Megure, who was stabbed?
Employee Shimomura Gyosuke-san,
twenty-five years old.
Like Kanzaki-kun, he's one of my employees.
An ambulance took him to the hospital.
Is it true the culprit
mistook him for Kanzaki-san?
Yeah.
It's because he was inside Bekapon.
Bekapon?
That's Beikado's mascot, right?
Fujii Hiroshi (50)
Supermarket Beikado Store Manager
I'm Fujii, the store manager.
Every Sunday at Supermarket Beikado,
Bekapon distributes fliers and balloons to customers.
Normally we have Kanzaki-kun
wear the costume.
You do?
Yes. I was supposed to today, but
I had a stomachache this morning.
After talking to floor
manager Shimomura-kun...
What? You want me to wear
the Bekapon costume instead?
Shimomura Gyosuke (25)
Supermarket Beikado Employee
You're the youngest employee
after Kanzaki-kun.
Please, Shimomura-san.
The kids are looking
forward to seeing Bekapon.
Oh, no! My stomach...
The medicine I gave you is strong.
Go rest in the break room
after you visit the bathroom.
S-Sorry.
It's an emergency. We're counting on you.
Be in front of the store at 11.
If those are your orders,
I don't have a choice.
Right, Bekapon?
10:50. I should get going.
Sheesh. I know it's my job,
but I don't want to do it.
Akaiwa Teruko (62)
Cleaner
Die, Kanzaki!
I see. The culprit said, “Die, Kanzaki.”
Yes, he did.
The culprit knew Kanzaki-san
normally wears the costume.
But not realizing someone else
happened to be filling in today,
he attacked Shimomura-san thinking
it was Kanzaki-san and fled.
He mistakenly assaulted the wrong target.
He attacked the wrong man.
That threat wasn't a joke, Mori-san.
And Shimomura-san got caught
up in the crossfire.
I didn't investigate thoroughly enough.
I wonder why the culprit attacked him
while he was wearing the costume, though.
He won't get blood on himself
through the costume.
Maybe, but...
He attacked the wrong man
because of that plan.
But he'll realize soon enough
that he attacked the wrong man.
Th-Then he'll attack me next?
Yeah, but don't worry.
I'll find him before then.
I swear on my job that I will.
M-Mori-kun?
M-Mori-san?!
Whoa, there.
How are you going to find him, old man?
Inspector Megure.
I didn't see anyone dressed like the witness
described on the security camera footage.
But... But I know I saw him.
He had a yellow jacket and red pants.
He probably took off his ski mask and
got out of those conspicuous clothes.
Either the culprit took them with him, or
if it was the work of a store employee,
then they could still be hidden
in the store somewhere.
You think one of my employees did it?
Your employees knew Kanzaki-san
normally wears the costume.
I-I suppose...
Sir, let them investigate us thoroughly.
Both to see if we're hiding the
clothes and to clear our names.
All right.
I understand. Our employees will cooperate.
Examine everything including
our personal belongings.
Thank you.
Takagi-kun, Chiba-kun.
Yes, sir.
I'll start by questioning you, Kanzaki-san.
All right.
This attack on the wrong
man doesn't make any sense.
I have no idea who did it.
That's why I hired Mori-san.
You must have some idea, though.
First there's the warning.
Why did the culprit bother to send one?
A yellow jacket and red pants.
Do you suppose the culprit is a young guy?
He may have deliberately dressed
conspicuously to make us think that.
Since the security cameras didn't catch him,
he must have changed into the
conspicuous clothes to attack,
and then back into his original clothes.
Why would he go through the trouble?
Normally wouldn't you attack
in the street at night?
Looks like it's not here.
We'll have to examine
their personal belongings.
Okay.
Sorry for asking a floor
manager to move stuff.
We're missing two young men.
We don't have a choice.
There.
So hot.
Udagawa-kun, you're drenched in sweat.
Why don't you take off your jacket?
You could at least roll up your sleeves.
I have a bit of a cold.
Anyway, the police are awful.
I can't believe they suspect us.
You're right.
Bekapon is taking the day off.
I'm sorry. Bekapon took the day off.
What?
And most suspicious of all is someone
else happened to wear the costume
the day the culprit carried out his threat.
Wait a minute.
What if it wasn't a coincidence?
That would explain everything.
Izumi Tenko (24)
Supermarket Beikado Employee
What? Are Kanzaki-kun and
Shimomura-san friends?
Yeah. I was told to ask.
Kanzaki-kun is a kind optimist.
And Shimomura-san is the exact opposite.
So they didn't get along.
I suppose not.
What are you doing?
He's running errands for Mori-san.
What did Mori-san say?
I'm not sure exactly.
Thanks, lady.
You're still here?
Where were you when
Shimomura-san was attacked?
Why?
The old man told me to ask.
Mori-san did?
Mori-san suspects the employees, too.
But Kanzaki-kun was resting in
the break room when it happened.
What?
After 11AM, Izumi-kun...
There you are, sir!
I came to check on Kanzaki-kun
since I'm worried about him.
He's fast asleep.
More importantly, sir...
Shimomura-san was stabbed!
What?!
I can prove his alibi.
Make sure you tell Mori-san.
Okay.
How's your stomach?
Thanks to your medicine, I'm all better.
Then can you come back to the floor?
Yes, sir.
I'll be there after lunch.
So Mori-san suspects me.
N-No...
There was no warning.
I faked being sick to get
Shimomura-san inside Bekapon,
and tried to kill him while making it
look like I attacked the wrong man.
That must be what he thought.
Yeah, I sure did.
There was really a warning, right?
Yeah. The first time they
called my cell phone.
But the second was more shocking.
What?
Is there a Kanzaki-sama here?
Yeah, that's me.
This is Kanzaki.
Kanzaki.
I will kill you.
How did he know I'm here?
Huh? Kanzaki-kun.
You're here, too?
Why do you look so pale?
I got scared and told the floor manager.
He recommended I hire a detective.
So that's why you hired the old man.
And about your stomachache...
Until I got to work, I felt fine.
Around 9 AM, we were having
a meeting while drinking tea.
Kanzaki-kun, could you distribute
fliers as Bekapon near the station...
O-Ouch....
What's wrong?
Sorry. I'm going to the bathroom.
I suddenly started feeling terrible.
Is there anything that could've caused it?
Not really.
I was cleaning because I was
told to clean that area.
Really?
I was surprised, though.
I got caught up in the incident
just after I started.
Just after you started?
I started working here yesterday.
I'm new.
That's why they chose her.
So that's how it is.
And this room is the only
possible hiding place.
Damn it.
Where are the red and yellow clothes?
That's it.
That's why they...
Supermarket Beikado
Inspector, I heard you know who did it!
What?
What are you talking about?
You called everyone together
because you found out who did it.
What? But you called me—
This must be the famous Sleeping Kogoro.
Um, who accidentally stabbed
Shimomura-san thinking it was me?
It wasn't an accident.
He always meant to attack Shimomura-san.
What?
What do you mean?
The culprit wanted to erase
Shimomura-san from this world.
But if he simply killed him, the killer's
motive would have led us to him.
To prevent that, he tried to make
us believe he accidentally killed
Shimomura-san instead of Kanzaki-san.
If he was an accidental victim, we
wouldn't investigate Shimomura-san.
In other words,
this was a planned murder disguised as
a mistake to avoid a police investigation.
Right, Udagawa-san?
What?
The floor manager?
With Shimomura-san hovering
between life and death,
it's not murder but attempted murder.
Wh-What proof do you have?
The situation tells me everything.
First, you called to threaten Kanzaki-san.
Kanzaki, I will kill you.
Huh? Kanzaki-kun.
You're here, too?
You called me?
I don't know what you're talking about.
You encouraged Kanzaki-san to hire me.
You needed someone to corroborate the
threats made on Kanzaki-san's life.
You used a famous detective like
myself to verify the story.
Today you gave Kanzaki-san a stomachache by using tea spiked with laxatives,
ordered Shimomura-san to wear the
costume instead, and tried to kill him.
Die, Kanzaki!
To make us think it was a mistake,
you needed someone to hear
you say, “Die, Kanzaki.”
That's why you instructed
me to clean that area.
It was a coincidence!
A coincidence.
New employee Teruko-san
was the perfect choice.
A veteran employee might
recognize it as your voice.
After stabbing Shimomura-san,
you fled into this break room.
What?
Kanzaki-san was here, but
you were fast asleep,
probably because of the sleeping pills
you were given with the stomach medicine.
Just when you changed out of your ski
mask and clothes and into your uniform...
There you are, sir!
I came to check on Kanzaki-kun
since I'm worried about him.
He's fast asleep.
This is nonsense!
Why would I try to kill Shimomura-kun?
I didn't have time to determine your motive.
If I didn't hurry, you would get
rid of the damning evidence.
Damning evidence?!
You mean the yellow jacket...
...and red pants?
And the ski mask.
With the commotion caused by the incident,
you didn't have time to
take them out of the store.
But if he hid them somewhere,
he wouldn't have said that.
Sir, let them investigate us thoroughly.
Because searching the store
would have been fruitless.
Right, Udagawa-san?
You're still wearing them right now.
Wearing them?
That's why you can't take off your uniform.
Udagawa-kun, you're drenched in sweat.
I have a bit of a cold.
Let go!
Please excuse us!
It's reversible?
He sewed a yellow jacket onto
the inside of his uniform.
Which means...
I knew it!
He didn't change into different clothes.
After committing the crime, he simply
flipped his jacket and pants inside out.
We know how he hid the clothes,
but what about the ski mask?
I can only imagine Udagawa-san has it on him.
You're right.
I know I shouldn't be laughing, but...
You shouldn't wear a hat as underwear.
That can't be good luck.
Why?
I couldn't think of any other way to hide it.
That's not what I meant.
Why did you attack Shimomura-san?
I just appointed you the manager of
the new Beikado branch that's opening.
That's exactly why.
Shimomura noticed I was
embezzling our profits.
Surprisingly enough,
he threatened to report me.
To finally become a manager, he had to die.
Fool!
This is Megure.
Really? Got it.
Shimomura-san is going to live.
That's great.
Yeah.
Because the costume was so
thick, the wound wasn't fatal.
If only I'd stabbed a little deeper.
What was that?
Get this disgraceful-looking
idiot out of here!
Yes, sir.
A disgraceful culprit indeed.
Gather round, everyone!
Take a look at this band-aid.
Your friend Bekapon is invincible.
Beka, Beka-Beka.
Beka-Beka, your friend Bekapon.
They're using Bekapon to promote sales.
Episode Preview
The suspect and escorting
officer have both gone missing.
What is Takagi doing?
You're Konaka Chie-san, right?
I'm Detective Mori Kogoro.
Something's not right.
“Detective Takagi On the Run in Handcuffs”
The next episode of Conan is “Detective
Takagi On the Run in Handcuffs!”
Stalker
Next Conan's hint!
A stalker!
I can't ignore the next episode's title!
Don't miss the next episode.
This could be bad.
Conan-kun!