Don't be ridiculous!
L-Let go!
Hey, what are you doing?!
Someone call the cops!
Crap.
Are you okay?
What? O-Oh, yes.
Hey, you. Are you okay?
Yeah, I guess.
What on earth happened?
It was just a fight.
Solving crimes with sharp detective skills.
Love and cases never change.
An active duty cop on the run in handcuffs?
Takagi Wataru has a very long day.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Detective Takagi On the Run in Handcuffs
"Detective Takagi On the Run in Handcuffs!"
Three Days Later
That hurts, moron!
I told you to quit pulling!
Someya Ryuta (28)
Behave yourself, Someya!
I'm taking you to the Metropolitan
Police Department.
Thanks for taking care of this.
Good work.
Man, that's scary.
What if we fall?
Let's try it out.
What are you doing? Stop, Someya!
Fall! Fall!
Good work, boys.
Too bad. He doesn't have a gun.
I'm not given a gun just to escort
a suspect involved in a fight.
Oh, man! This is just like that...
What did you say?
Nothing. It's nothing.
Get out.
That hurts.
Hey, Kishida-kun. Are you okay?
Yes...
We'll wait here for backup.
Call the department.
Got it.
This guy's got one.
Hey! What are you—
You!
Pick up the keys and unlock these cuffs.
Hold on!
N-Now even if you shoot
us, you can't get away!
B-Bastard...
Then I'll do this!
No, you don't!
D-Detective Takagi!
Wh-What?!
T-Takagi and the suspect fell into a river?!
T-Takagi-kun?
Order an emergency deployment
and search the area.
Yes, sir!
Damn it. Break already!
Police handcuffs aren't so easily broken.
Give up.
Huh?
It's not working. I already checked.
What? Damn it.
Aw, never mind.
Ow, ow!
Ow, ow, ow...
Hey, quit messing around!
Why are you so unmotivated?!
Can't you try harder to run?!
What?
Don't you have a goal?
A goal?
Isn't that why you tried to run?
You were born in the town
we just passed through.
You had nowhere left to run,
but according to local authorities,
you bought a ticket back into the city.
Where were you trying to go?
I'm not trying to do anything.
I just didn't want to get arrested yet.
Don't be absurd! Look at this!
We're connected to each other!
Just like that!
Huh? What do you mean, that?
I'm telling you...
I'm worried.
Yeah, me, too.
I hope his bad habit doesn't come out.
Bad habit?
A movie?
Yeah, a movie.
It's called "Running in Handcuffs."
You've heard of it, right?
What the hell is that?
What?! You're kidding,
right?! You don't know?!
That masterpiece will go
down in cinematic history!
It's a masterpiece!
What about that movie, anyway?
Two men handcuffed together come to
understand each other even while fighting.
A friendship that transcends social
boundaries is born in this soulful masterpiece.
By the way, I've seen the DVD 12 times!
So, Someya, if you're hiding
something, we're connected now.
Tell me—
Enough. Shut up.
Yes, that's it.
We have to start by fighting.
This is going well.
I told you to shut up!
Let's go.
Look. You do have a goal.
Shut up!
Ow, ow, ow...
Mori Detective Agency
Here's our next story.
Dad, Conan-kun!
This morning, a suspect being escorted and
the officer escorting him have both gone missing.
Missing are Someya Ryuta, twenty-eight
years old, arrested for assault and battery.
Patrol Officer Takagi Wataru
Suspect Someya Ryuta
Also missing is the MPD Section One
officer escorting suspect Someya,
What is Takagi doing?
Patrol Officer Takagi Wataru.
Conan-kun, this man...
According to reports, they...
Yeah.
The guy from the restaurant.
Seriously, on a Sunday?
The police have already canvassed this place.
Yeah, but I'm curious about something.
Yeah, the police already came.
I told them I don't know where Someya went.
Is there anything else?
Was the woman here a customer?
What woman?
The woman sitting over there
while you were fighting.
Nashimoto Yasuo (28)
Oh...
I wonder if I should say this.
Konaka-san was being stalked by Someya.
Huh?
What?!
He was stalking her?
I tried to stop him.
That landed me in trouble.
Did you tell the police?
No. She was really scared of him.
Do you know where Konaka-san lives?
Yeah. She told me since we were talking.
Do you think he's headed for...?
Yeah. That's why he ran.
You're Konaka Chie-san, right?
Konaka Chie (23)
I'm Detective Mori Kogoro.
A detective?
Could you answer a few questions?
I'm sorry, but I've got a
cold and am not feeling well.
Are you sure it's not because
you're afraid of that man?
It's okay. My father is a great detective.
I'm sorry.
Wait!
Dad!
Thanks for calling.
How are things over there?
Same as ever.
Our search hasn't turned up anything.
I'm worried about Detective Takagi.
What?
Oh, yeah. Thanks.
Anyway, discovering why
Someya ran is a great find.
If he wants to hurt her,
he's sure to turn up here.
Yeah, it's likely.
What's going on? Something's not right.
But what is it?
Cut the handcuffs with the train wheels?
Are you serious?
Yeah, I'm serious.
There was a similar scene
in that movie, but...
Seriously?
It's here.
What do you think you're doing?!
There wasn't enough space under the train.
You would've been crushed.
Don't be ridiculous!
It's true! I'm not lying!
Shut up!
Someya, take this.
Use this, Someya.
What is that?
The officer picked up the
keys to my handcuffs.
This one is for these.
Quit messing around...
Hurry. At this rate, we'll both fall.
At least save yourself.
Hurry up!
Piece of shit!
S-Someya, you...
The key.
Give me the key.
Sure...
I-It's gone.
I dropped it.
Wh-What?
Sorry.
Why are you apologizing?
Are you stupid?
Anyway, you saved me! Thanks!
A cop shouldn't be thanking a suspect.
Y-You're right.
But if you hadn't saved me, I...
Sheesh. I didn't have a choice.
We're connected.
Yeah.
Sato-san!
Someone spotted them!
Where?
Is Detective Takagi okay?
They're at a drive-in on
the prefecture border.
Local authorities sent us
this security camera footage.
What is this?
They practically look like friends.
His bad habit...
Huh?
What?
Never mind. It's nothing.
So? Where's the truck now?
It's in the city, but they
haven't found it yet.
So we'll have to wait here.
Do you have a girlfriend?
What about you?
I guess, yeah.
I might, too.
I see. So...
Hey, will you let me use a phone?
What?
Then I'll turn myself in.
I mean, I'll go to the police with you.
Really?
I told you, there's nothing
I can do like this.
Got it.
Let me use your bathroom.
Go ahead.
Look! Chie-san is on the phone with someone.
Is it Someya?
She hung up.
Did Someya invite her somewhere?
Yeah. After threatening her not to tell
the police, he's going to hurt her.
Oh, no.
Crap!
Chiba-kun, call for backup.
Roger.
Could he be...?
Inspector, this is Chiba.
Conan-kun?
Excuse me!
Where's the waiter who
Someya-san hit the other day?
Nashimoto-san?
He just got a call and went
into the changing room.
Nashimoto-san!
Huh?
Where did he go?
Nashimoto
What is this?
So that's how it is.
Crap.
Hey, kid.
If you're looking for Nashimoto-san, he's
apparently at the abandoned Haido-cho factory.
What?
This note was on the table.
Haido-cho Abandoned Factory
What's going on, Someya? Explain yourself.
Aren't you turning yourself in?
I will, once I settle things with him.
Tell me what you're—
Crap!
What's going on?
She belongs to me!
I won't let you have her!
Go!
C-Conan-kun?!
What are you doing here?
Who is he?
He was her stalker.
What? Stalker?
Someya-san caused the incident because
he was trying to protect her.
What? S-Someya?
He ran? C-Crap!
I don't think he ran.
What?
Didn't Someya-san make two calls?
What? Yeah, he did...
That's it! Someya called that guy
and the girl he was stalking.
That's right.
Why not trust him, Detective Takagi?
Yeah.
I can't wait any longer.
I'm calling a search.
Wait, wait. Just a little longer!
Ten more minutes. No, just five.
Open your eyes already, Takagi-kun.
This isn't a movie.
I know that, but...
What?
Huh?
S-Someya...
You're a cop. Don't make that face.
No, not that...
What?
I told you...
Man, you're hopeless.
I could never run.
We're connected.
Yes, that's it!
You did it!
Yes! That's it!
All right!
Stalkers are rotten people.
On top of that, he even fooled us.
Someya-san ran to protect Chie-san
while still in handcuffs.
He broke his chains,
but his soul wasn't stained.
Yeah. He was actually a nice guy.
Yeah, his soul wasn't stained.
Though he broke his chains.
Why do you keep saying that?
He broke his chains,
but his soul wasn't stained.
Stained
Stained, chains.
Chains
You know, because handcuffs.
Just kidding!
He really strained those chains!
That's enough out of you.
Episode Preview
Which means on top of the desk...
It's the usage details of a bank's ATM.
An alibi?
The money was supposed
to be deposited by 2 PM,
but when I checked the
ATM, there was no money.
What?
Three First Discoverers
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is
"Three First Discoverers, Part One!"
Cigarettes
Next Conan's hint!
Cigarettes!
With three discoverers...
Don't miss the next episode.
The case is as good as solved.
I wish you were right.