And?
Why did you have us check if anyone
was following us and come here?
Surely you didn't just want to show
us your improved talent for disguises.
No.
This morning I received a message
from Kir, Mizunashi Rena.
What?
Then they don't know you're alive.
Probably not.
But her message contained only three letters.
Three letters?
Was it an abbreviation?
No. It's the name of a liquor
you're very familiar with.
R-U-M.
Rum. One of their code names.
Rum?
When I was in the Organization,
I heard the name a couple of times.
It seems he's their boss's close adviser.
A close adviser?
But we haven't heard anything about that.
Since she sent only one word,
it was probably an urgent message.
She couldn't afford to tell you.
In any case, tell James
someone big is on the move.
Someone bigger than Gin.
Solving crimes with sharp detective skills.
Love and cases never change.
Three adults being watched by a child.
Their eyewitness testimony turns into a case.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Three First Discoverers
(Part One)
"Three First Discoverers, Part One!"
By the way, did you see
yesterday's Tokyo Derby?
The Spirits versus Noir match, right?
I did! Hide got a hat trick, right?
That's right! It's no wonder
he's their star player!
Rum?
Yeah.
"Daccha?"
Darling...
Not the comic character, the liquor.
You know, the stuff pirates drink.
I've no idea what you mean.
I told you before. I don't
know much about liquor.
R-Right...
To get information on Rum, close adviser
to the Black Organization's boss,
we'll need to wait to hear
from Mizunashi Rena-san,
who's infiltrated the Organization, or ask
undercover public safety officer Amuro-san...
But...
I know the Organization's
number two's code name is Rum.
Number two?
At the very least, that's what
I heard while I was there.
I never met them, though.
Wh-What were they like?!
Are they a man or a woman?
I said I never met them.
While I was in the organization,
I heard all kinds of descriptions.
A large brawny man.
An effeminate man.
An old man.
Some people claimed they
were all his doubles.
A large man, an effeminate
man, and an old man...
Hey! Don't tell me Rum's searching for me.
N-No...
The Organization uses types of liquor
for all its code names, right?
I was just wondering if there
was someone named Rum...
What about Rum?
What?
You were just talking about it.
That Rum is looking for someone.
Tell me. I'm curious.
What? Uh, Rum... rum...
Ramune!
Ramune?
I bet you're thirsty after
playing soccer in the park.
So I was looking to see if the shop
over there was selling ramune.
Ah, you mean the drink?
Normal juice is fine.
Y-Yeah...
Huh? That kid is still there.
What kid?
Look.
The boy standing in the other street.
He was standing there on our way to the park.
He was staring into the distance then, too.
What is he looking at?
Maybe someone's about to
fall from a high place.
Let's ask him.
Okay!
He's looking at an apartment?
Hey, you. What are you...?
The lady...
They killed the lady!
What?
Did you see someone kill her?
No, but she told me.
Three men are going to
visit the lady's apartment.
If she doesn't come out after they leave,
she's probably been killed,
so I should call the police.
So the woman...
She's not coming out!
It's been about thirty minutes
since the third man left.
Did you call the police?
Not yet. I'm too scared.
Do you remember what the
three men looked like?
Y-Yeah...
There was a really big man,
a young guy with long hair like a girl,
and an old man with white hair.
What?
A large brawny man.
An effeminate man.
An old man.
Hey! Do you think...?
It's too much of a coincidence.
But Rum always had another special trait.
The descriptions of his appearance were
varied, but the trait was always the same.
I can't remember what it was...
In any case, show us to the woman's room.
It's that apartment, right?
Okay.
What's your relationship with the woman?
Is she a relative?
No.
I don't know her.
What?
She's a total stranger?
Yeah. She'd talk to me when I
was playing alone in the park.
Since I moved here, I don't have any friends.
But your parents know about the lady, right?
No. I don't have a dad or mom.
Really?
Yeah. While I was on a field trip,
they got involved in a "robin murder."
A robbery and murder.
I'm staying with my uncle,
but he's too busy to play with me.
So after seeing how lonely you were,
the woman decided to play with you.
Yeah. I asked to come to her house to
play before, but she wouldn't let me.
But today she made an
exception and invited me.
She writes stories for TV shows.
She told me all about the
story she was going to write.
She's a scriptwriter?
Ma'am!
There's no answer.
Excuse me.
It's unlocked!
You can't go in!
She told me if she didn't come out, I should
let the police handle it and stay outside!
Does that mean...?
I knew it...
Ma'am! Ma'am!
Don't come in!
Haibara, call the police.
Got it.
Shouldn't we call an ambulance, too?
No. Look around her feet.
If this were really a suicide, there would
be a stool or something by her feet.
Since that's missing, it means someone
killed her and made this look like a suicide.
It was probably one of the
three men this kid saw.
If it's been about thirty minutes since
the third man left, we're too late.
No...
That's odd, though.
Even though he was panicked
enough to forget the stool,
there are no signs he
left the room in a hurry.
And I don't see the Yoshikawa lines left
behind when a strangulation victim struggles.
I'd understand if he strangled
her after putting her to sleep.
But who would plan that
much and forget the stool?
An envelope?
A bank envelope.
It's new, too.
Which mean in the wallet on the desk...
There should be the money she withdrew.
But there's barely anything in here.
Usage Details
All that's inside is the
bank's ATM usage details.
According to this, she withdrew
500,000 yen three hours ago,
but the money's nowhere to be found.
Which means he killed her for the money.
In any case, it's clear this sloppy crime
wasn't their work.
Yeah.
I see...
So you were watching this apartment
at the woman's request,
and after three men came and left,
you came here to find her like this?
Y-Yeah.
The deceased is scriptwriter
Komai Yasue-san.
Yes, sir.
If this is murder, we'll have to
find people among her associates
who may have resented her and call
them in for a lineup with this kid.
We have the names of the three people
the victim was meeting here today.
What?
They're in the scheduling software
installed on the computer on the desk.
This afternoon she met Sakaba Ronbei,
Habanaka Kuramichi, and Shibakaru Denji.
Is that true?
Yes. It's written on the notebook in the
drawer and calendar, so it's probably correct.
Also, we can't find the 500,000 yen the
victim withdrew from the bank today anywhere.
So they killed her for the money,
made it look like a suicide, and ran.
Find out who they are and call the station.
What's wrong?
Th-They're here...
The three men who came to
the woman's room are here!
What?
S-Seriously?
Could you point them out while keeping
your face hidden behind the railing?
O-Okay...
Let's see...
Did you find them?
Yeah.
That stocky man over there, that long-haired
man to the side, and the old man behind him.
Inspector Megure!
Got it.
Takagi-kun.
Yes, sir!
Give me a break, officer.
I just came to check out the
incident in the neighborhood.
Why am I being questioned?
We're just passers-by.
Or do we look like wanted men?
No, a witness saw you visiting the
victim's apartment between 2PM and 3PM,
the presumed time of her death.
The witness also said the victim
Komai Yasue-san asked him
to watch the apartment because one of the
three men coming to visit may kill her.
Kill her? Isn't this a suicide?
A suicide?
Normally a hanging is a suicide...
How do you know the victim hung herself?
Uh, well...
It seems I can't hide it.
Shibakaru Denji (63)
I am Shibakaru Denji.
We became drinking buddies after
a chance meeting at a bar.
This photo proves it.
She said she was worried so I came to talk,
but I had no idea it had driven her to suicide...
So she was already dead when you arrived?
Yes, so I have no idea what
she was concerned about.
If you want to know, try asking these two.
Not that I know who they are.
I-I...
Sakaba Ronbei (31)
I came to get the money she borrowed.
We're old friends, so I
lent her a bunch of money.
But now I need that money,
so I asked for it back.
Was the amount 500,000 yen?
What? H-How do you know that?
So this is the man who took the money.
Excuse me...
Habanaka Kuramichi (40)
I'm actually a producer at TV Tohto.
I hired Komai-san to write a script for
this fall's special mystery program.
She said the script was ready,
so I came to pick it up.
Where was the script?
It was just inside the door,
so I took it and gave it to my AD.
Was she already hanging then?
Yes...
I don't know what was worrying her,
but the script was due, so I didn't
have time to think about it.
Yeah, but...
Wouldn't you normally call
the police if you saw that?
Why didn't you?
He's right. No matter what you had to do...
You'd call the cops.
Especially if you knew the victim.
Why didn't you?
Surely you didn't have a reason
you couldn't call the police.
N-No...
Mind your own business, kid!
Who is that boy in the glasses?
Mind your own business.
They were the first ones
to discover the body.
Though it seems you're the
actual first discoverers.
In any case, we'd like to question you
separately, so come inside one at a time.
Oh, I've got an alibi!
An alibi?
The money was supposed
to be deposited by 2 PM,
but when I checked the
ATM, there was no money.
So I came here to get it myself.
I see.
I got scared when I saw her dead
body, so I rushed back to the ATM.
I had to pay off my card today, so I
was forced to use the money I had.
How is that an alibi?
ATMs have security cameras.
If you compare the time between
when I left and came back
with how long it takes to get
from here to the bank and back,
you'll know I didn't have time to kill her.
That's not quite an alibi, but
it will help the investigation.
Is the bank nearby?
Yeah, it's pretty close.
I'll go with him to the bank to check.
Thanks.
Is it all right if I smoke while we wait?
I've got a portable ashtray.
Go ahead, but the wind's picked up.
Don't scatter the ashes.
All right.
That's a huge flame.
Sorry. Did I get you with the smoke?
No, it's all right.
You really don't remember the
order in which they came?
No. I know it's them, though.
We'll need to question them more.
I see.
He really was on the ATM's
security camera footage?
Yes.
We can smoke?
I'll have one, too.
But, sir, he was away from
the ATM for forty minutes.
It's hardly an alibi...
It takes less than twenty minutes
to get there and back.
Then why did he mention it?
He nearly escaped a few times.
I think he may have been after that.
Damn it.
Would you like to use mine?
Thanks.
Sheesh. You don't need to glare.
I won't try to escape anymore.
It was just a joke.
Oh, uh...
Sh-Shall we get those interviews over with?
All right.
You're first.
Who, me?
Fine. Go easy on me.
I see.
Episode Preview
Figure anything out?
Yeah. The person who caused this
incident and the name of that kid.
Hey, Detective Takagi.
I think you should search the room harder.
What?
There's definitely 500,000
yen in there somewhere.
What?
Also...
Could I borrow 20,000 yen?
Three First Discoverers
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Three
First Discoverers, Part Two!"
500 Thousand Yen
Next Conan's hint!
500,000 Yen!
How many broiled eel bowls is that?
Don't miss the next episode.
Eel's gotten expensive lately.
You really do like those.