Detective Conan Episode 793 "Three
First Discoverers (Part 2)"
We met a strange boy staring
intently at an apartment.
According to him,
a "considerate lady" was killed.
At the apartment, we discovered
the body of Komai Yasue-san,
whose death may have been
made to look like a suicide.
But then...
What's wrong?!
Th-They're here...
The three men who came to
the woman's room are here!
Solving crimes with sharp detective skills.
Love and cases never change.
The discoverers failed to report the crime.
The case comes to a money-related
and surprising conclusion.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Three First Discoverers
(Part Two)
"Three First Discoverers, Part Two!"
What are we going to do?
We can't attend the interviews.
That's obvious.
It's okay.
I stuck a Detective Boys badge
in Detective Takagi's pocket.
I thought so.
You're the one who stole the
500,000 from the room.
S-Sorry...
Where did you find the money?
Around there.
Under the feet of her hanging
body, the bills were rolling—
Sakaba Ronbei (31)
I mean, they were scattered.
Are you sure you didn't kill
her before stealing the money?
Along with her phone.
Her phone?
There's a charger, but no phone.
Sir, could Komai-san have stood on the bills?
500,000's not enough.
10 million would be about
10 centimeters tall, though.
Indeed.
Next!
You, the large man. Come in.
The victim weighs approximately 47 kilos.
If the culprit lifted her
body to hang it, then...
Habanaka Kuramichi (40)
He's our prime suspect.
Tape on the soles of his sandals?
I told you earlier.
I only took the script left in the entryway.
Was it really in the entryway?
Forensics said they found
three sets of footprints.
Well, actually...
A bag of manuscript paper
was left by her feet.
I felt bad, but I entered the
apartment in my shoes to pick it up.
Under her feet again.
It's unusual for someone to be using
manuscript paper in this day and age, though.
Indeed.
All the errors and corrections
make them hard to read.
I always have my AD type up the
scripts before I read them.
By the way, how many pages were there?
It's a two hour special,
so about a hundred pages.
They weren't folded or rolled up, were they?
No.
A hundred pages of standard paper
are about 1 centimeter tall.
It's not enough for her to stand on, either.
Why didn't you call the police right away?
I'd like to keep this off the record, please.
She's actually the ghostwriter
of a famous scriptwriter.
I thought it would cause problems if the
script was made public as part of the case.
I see.
I wanted to send her off on her own soon,
but the scriptwriter fell in love with the
realistic and original crimes she wrote.
By the way, what's the title?
It's the "Moonless Night Thieves" series.
I know that one!
They use impressive means to steal
from evil wealthy individuals.
But in the final episode, they killed the
couple they robbed, and the group disbanded.
Yeah. That part really affected me, too.
Affected you?
Oh, but in this script, they were
supposed to get the group back together.
The couple they thought they
killed was actually alive.
R-Really?
I never thought it would become
her posthumous work, though.
We got in a fight.
It was a couple days ago at a bar.
You mean you got in a fight with Komai-san?
Yeah.
The truth is, she asked me to
come here so she could apologize.
Shibakaru Denji (63)
The bar's owner and other
customers saw us fighting.
I doubted anyone would believe me if I
said I found her hanging when I got here.
That's why you left without reporting it?
Yeah.
I had no idea that boy
watched me come and go.
What caused the fight?
It was a stupid argument.
We just got a bit noisy
because we'd been drinking.
Hey, answer it already!
Your phone's ringing!
But that's not our ring tones.
Oh, it's mine.
I forgot I changed my
ring tone the other day.
You don't need to answer it?
It's from a bar hostess.
Figure anything out?
Yeah.
The person who caused this incident, and
that the name of that kid is Ganno Mamoru.
How do you know that?
Three years ago, a group of
thieves broke into a family home,
killing the wife and husband and making
off with two million yen in cash.
Web News
Follow up Report on Robbery
and Murder: Bereaved Family
Ganno Mamoru-kun
He's the couple's only child.
A quick search of the web turned him up.
He happened to be on a field
trip and escaped unscathed.
Since the incident, the
thieves have been missing.
But the numbers on the cash
happened to be written down.
It's finally over.
We can leave now, right?
I need to get back to the station.
Actually, uh...
Detective Takagi...
I think you should search the room harder.
What?
There's definitely 500,000
yen in there somewhere.
What?
Also...
Could I borrow 20,000 yen?
What?
According to eyewitness testimony,
after watching the three of you
come to and leave this room,
the witness came here to find the dead
scriptwriter Komai Yasue-san hanging.
Because there was nothing
to stand on near her feet,
she must have been murdered and
made to look like she'd killed herself.
By one of you three.
Wh-What have I been telling you?!
She really was dead by the time I got here!
I took the money around her
feet, but I didn't kill her!
I just took the manuscript
papers by her feet.
I didn't do anything wrong.
Likewise, she was already dead by the time I
came in, and I didn't take anything with me.
Could you tell us the approximate
times you came to the apartment?
I'm not sure.
She asked me to come after two,
but I don't know the exact time.
She told me to come around two as well.
When I called her cell from a pay
phone, that's what she told me.
I didn't make an appointment with her.
So even though you all came after
two, none of you ran into each other?
It's a coincidence.
That's a reasonable enough coincidence.
Maybe they agreed beforehand...
...not to reveal when she
asked them to come.
After all, they seem to know each other.
Know each other?
When the old man lit his lighter, it made a
huge unwavering flame despite the wind.
It's because the big man was standing next
to him to block the wind for him, right?
Uh, I...
But the smoke was making him cough.
He probably doesn't like cigarettes.
Why would he do that?
It means the old man is
just that important to him.
I see.
That's why he approached
him to block the wind.
Since he was outside, as long as he didn't get
too close, the smoke wouldn't bother him.
And when the long-haired man borrowed
the lighter, he turned down the flame.
S-So, what?
How did you know the old man keeps the
flame strong on his lighter before lighting it?
Well, because...
Besides, while he was smoking, the big
man approached him to glare at him.
Like he was telling him not to smoke.
The long-haired man got scared and
put out his barely smoked cigarette.
These three must know each other.
S-So what if we do?!
Didn't I tell you earlier?
By agreeing on your stories, you're
trying to hide when you came here.
If you all say the lady was
already dead when you arrived,
then that would mean the first
person killed her and is lying.
Y-You're right.
That's why the old man
stole her phone, right?
You didn't want the police to
know in which order you came.
Wha-?
She probably e-mailed you asking you to come.
By e-mailing instead of calling, she could
give you precise times down to the minute.
That's why none of you ran into each other,
even though you were summoned
around the same time.
B-But how do you know he took her phone?
It took the old man a while to notice it
was his phone that was ringing, right?
And he hung up without answering, too.
That's because it was the lady's phone.
The picture he showed us was
probably on her phone, too.
How do you know about the call?
I-I heard it through the wall.
I've got good ears.
I'd better get the badge
from Detective Takagi later.
Shibakaru-san, may we
examine your cell phone?
B-But it really is mine.
Well, it doesn't matter if the phone
tells us in what order they arrived.
It doesn't matter?
Detective Takagi, did you get it?
Yeah.
A notebook, tape, and 20,000
yen in thousand yen notes.
What are you going to do with this stuff?
I want to perform an experiment.
Can I use the room?
S-Sure...
Give me a hand, guys.
It's something like an
arts and crafts project.
What?
Here. I'm finished, Conan-kun.
Thanks. Just leave it there.
Okay!
Is this really related to the investigation?
Lining up the corners is hard.
P-Probably...
Is this good enough?
Yes, very good.
Okay, it's done.
We're all set.
All set?
All you did was make tubes out of 20
thousand yen notes with tape and line them up.
I bet the long-haired man
has seen these tubes before.
You almost said the money was rolling
around under the dead woman's feet.
If those were scattered on the floor, you
certainly would call it "rolling around."
Is that true?
Yeah, I guess.
So what's this experiment?
You put the notebook on top of the bills.
And if you carefully get on...
See? You can stand on top of it.
Wow!
Why, though?
I weight 18 kilograms.
Each tube can support
about 1 kilogram, so...
That's it! Komai-san stood on this.
Komai-san weighs roughly 47 kilograms.
By putting a hundred sheets of
manuscript paper in an envelope
and placing that over 500 thousand
yen's worth of rolled up bills,
she created a stand that
would support her weight.
I see.
After kicking the stand
aside and hanging herself,
Sakaba-san pocketed the rolled up bills,
and Habanaka-san took the
envelope of manuscript paper,
which got rid of the stand and
made it look like a murder.
By having Shibakaru-san take the phone,
we wouldn't know she invited the three
of them within minutes of each other.
If anyone saw you coming or going,
we would suspect you murdered her.
Oh.
So it was a suicide.
You scared us.
But there's still no proof.
The proof is stuck to the sole
of the long-haired man's sandal.
What?
It's the tape the lady
used to roll up the bills.
Seriously?
It's really there.
It took a long time to get to the bank's ATM
because you were removing
500,000 yen's worth of tape, right?
Y-Yeah...
The lady's fingerprints
should be on the tape,
and traces of tape should be on the
500,000 he deposited at the ATM.
Go to the bank at the ATM and
confirm this immediately.
Yes, sir.
That's amazing, Conan-kun.
You're just like Shinichi-kun.
A-Actually, I asked
Shinichi-niichan about the case,
and was just reading what
he wrote back to me.
So that's how it is.
Does this mean we're free to go?
We can leave, right?
I've got work to do.
We still need to ask why she did this.
Oh, right. I should return this phone.
I only took it because I didn't
want you to suspect me.
Forgive me.
I don't know why she killed herself
and made it look like we did it,
but in my case, it was probably
because of the fight at the bar.
In my case, it was probably because
I suddenly asked for my money back.
The stress she was experiencing
because she hadn't set out on her own
yet was probably a factor as well.
See you later.
W-Wait.
This leaves a bad taste in my mouth, though.
She gave her life trying to frame that shady
trio, and you exposed the trick so easily.
Actually, her true aim was...
What?
What is this?!
Director Habanaka!
Are the contents of the confession true?!
C-Confession?
It was written in Komai Yasue-san's
script you gave to your AD!
Along with Habanaka Kuramichi,
Shibakaru Denji, and Sakaba Ronbei,
she was a member of a gang of thieves
that performed a series of robberies!
What?!
She also wrote the photo
proving it is on her phone,
and the money you stole is
inside a Tohto Bank ATM!
N-No, this must be some kind of mistake.
Why don't we have a long chat at the station
about whether or not it is a mistake.
Web News
Murder and Robbery Case Ends
with Confession from Gang Member
By the way,
they found the 500,000 she withdrew from
the bank inside a cushion in her apartment.
Huh.
But she had the 500,000
she stole a long time ago.
Why go to the trouble of doing that?
So the police would notice
the 500,000 was stolen.
Otherwise they wouldn't
have figured out the trick.
So she did it so the case would be solved.
Yeah.
She probably meant to make the
three of them murder suspects,
expose their crimes while under police surveillance,
present the evidence, and have them arrested.
I'm surprised you knew she hadn't
touched the 500,000, though.
In their final robbery and
murder, they stole two million.
A fourth of that is 500,000.
If she regretted the murder
and quit her life of crime,
I figured she wouldn't have used the money.
Also, I had several reasons for
knowing they were the thieves,
but the decisive reason was
what the old man Shibakaru said.
I had no idea that boy
watched me come and go.
The inspector looked at all of
us when he mentioned the suspect,
but the old man knew it was
the boy, Ganno Mamoru-kun.
It's proof he knew Komai-san was close
to their victims' son Mamoru-kun.
Don't you think it was cruel of her
to make him the witness, though?
Apparently, they were threatening her.
If she didn't want Mamoru-kun
to know she was a thief,
she had to pay them or keep writing scripts,
or they'd kill Mamoru-kun if
she didn't return to the group.
That's why she made him the witness.
She thought the police
would protect a witness.
She probably meant to atone with
her own death, but she was wrong.
On top of killing his parents, she made
Mamoru-kun lose the friend he'd finally made.
Lose?
Come to think of it, that's
what they all said.
That he was missing one.
He?
Rum.
He injured an eye in some kind of accident.
Either his right or left
eye is an artificial eye.
Episode Preview
Hide!
We get along like cats and dogs.
Sorry you lost your jobs.
What's this?
It's fog.
Is everyone okay?
Ryo-san, where are you?
Bodyguard Mori Kogoro
The next episode of Conan is
"Bodyguard Mori Kogoro!"
Fog
Next Conan's hint!
Fog!
He's a bodyguard?
Don't miss the next episode.
And she's an actor.
It's like a movie.