Hide!
Gotcha. Is that all you've got?
Huh?
C-Crap!
That's enough.
Ouch...
Good work.
You failed to disinfect the room.
Disinfect = Inspect
and Verify Safety
Minus twenty points.
You let the package enter the room alone.
Package =
Person Being Protected
Minus thirty points.
You fought a perp without authorization.
Perp
= Perpetrator
Minus twenty points.
You also missed the second perp.
As a result, you allowed the package to die.
Your score's not even worth evaluating.
You fail.
Dobashi Arimasa (45)
Dobashi Security Guard Rep
How many times do I have
to tell you, Mori-san?
You're not a cop or a detective.
You're not defending the law or
justice, just the life of the package.
Y-You're exactly right.
I'm ashamed of myself.
Let me try one more time!
I mean, please!
Well spoken.
Places, everyone!
All right!
Solving crimes with sharp detective skills.
Love and cases never change.
A highly suspicious film shoot.
The old man bodyguard makes a narrow escape.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Bodyguard Mori Kogoro
“Bodyguard Mori Kogoro!”
Sawazaki Reina (28)
Actress
Arimura Chisato (25)
Nichiuri TV AD
Here, Reina-san.
Have some coffee.
Can't you do something about that?
Kushizaki Kenzo (45)
Nichiuri TV Producer
Isogawa Hideo (40)
Nichiuri TV Director
Are you sure it's all
right for us to join you?
I can't have my bodyguard
riding in a different car.
Haneki Ryo (40)
Actress
I might be killed this time.
I hired you to be my bodyguard so
you could simultaneously protect me,
and use your detective skills to
determine who's trying to kill me.
Leave it to me.
It's the reason I trained with the security
company affiliated with your agency.
Why did they have to come, though?
You must be thirsty.
Help yourselves to some of Haneki
Ryo's special vegetable juice.
Kusumoto Kazuya (35)
Ryo and Reina's Manager
Thank you.
Thanks for the drinks.
Dramas are a different story, but
I've actually got a lot of free time.
I'm glad I have someone to talk to.
We're the ones who are glad.
We only came to watch,
but now we're traveling with the
famous actress Haneki Ryo-san.
Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah!
Lake Nakajima
Auberge Muto
Thank you for coming, everyone.
Muto Kimie (30)
Muto's Wife
Muto Shohei (33)
Owner of Auberge Muto
You must be exhausted from your long trip.
Thank you.
I look forward to working together, Muto-san.
Indeed. Take your time.
I'm off to disinfect the premises.
Thanks, Mori-san.
It's all right, Mori-san.
We've already disinfected the interior.
Ch-Chief Dobashi?!
Dobashi-san, you're here, too?
I heard you took the day off, so I
thought you were with your family.
You have a daughter, don't you?
Don't worry.
My daughter and I have an understanding.
What a coincidence!
I happen to have a daughter as well.
Mori-san, today is also your Dobashi
Security Guard graduation exam.
I-Indeed it is!
Way to put on the pressure.
It's so reassuring to have two
good men looking out for me.
I feel like a princess.
Yeah, a princess way past her prime.
R-Reina-san...
In that case, Dobashi-san,
look after Princess Reina.
I feel safe enough with just Mori-san.
Come on, Dad.
Then Kusumoto-chan is enough for me.
That won't do.
I'm not a bodyguard.
I'm joking.
Isn't Reina-san famous
for being a troublemaker?
Yeah. They say she's always
starting fights at work.
On top of that—
We work at the same agency, but
we get along like cats and dogs.
That's well known as well.
But I might be the bigger problem.
I don't get along with anyone.
I wonder why everyone hates me.
Do I try too hard even
though it's not a drama?
Do I take too long?
Not at all.
This program wouldn't exist without you.
I've heard the news, Kusshi.
Rumor is we'll be canceled.
Our numbers are down, too.
N-No... Rumors are just rumors.
Sorry. If you lose your
jobs, it'll be my fault.
She's making the most out of all of us.
She's paid more than her
skills and time are worth.
Now, now, Isogawa-chan...
That voice!
Reina-san?
Disinfected, my ass!
That's not possible!
Are you all right?
Wh-What is this?
I've had enough!
What happened, Reina-san?
It's probably that.
I-I'm sorry. There are a lot
of stray cats around here.
We'll clean the room again right away.
Hey, you know I can't handle
them, Kusumoto-chan.
She's allergic to cats.
I'm sorry.
I told Mori-san about you.
No, it was my mistake.
I should have let Mori-san handle it.
I'm sorry.
What? Did something happen?
Not really.
I just realized I'm not being protected
since I'm not the package or whatever.
Cheers!
They're both so beautiful.
I'm not surprised.
Yeah.
It's hard to believe they're
like cats and dogs.
They really are actresses.
Cut! Okay.
We're switching scenes after this.
Shouldn't we retake the shot first?
S-Sorry.
You're so disorganized.
Don't make me stay up all night for this.
It's not good for my skin.
That's right. Ryo-san's
way beyond past her prime.
Let's retake the scene.
Good work.
Tomorrow after the breakfast shoot,
we'll be shooting by the lake.
Thanks, everyone.
Who's walking around at this hour?
That's Ryo-san's room.
That's enough!
What is this?
Kusumoto!
Hey, wait!
There's no point in running.
I've already called the police.
Is this about the transfer?
Yeah. I wanted to work on the set, but you
asked the higher ups to give me a desk job.
So that's why you've been trying to kill her?!
No! This was the only attempt I made.
What?
There are still plenty of
other people who resent you.
No...
What's wrong?
Dad?
Uh, um...
This is just...
The wind is nice.
It feels so great.
Is it okay to keep shooting?
He said there are lots of other
people who resent Ryo-san.
I think that's why they're
still on their guard.
Cut!
Okay!
Get the boats ready for
the next scene, please!
Mist has been forecast for later today.
It makes the oars harder
to use, so be careful.
What? Why?
As you can see, the mountains
around here have a unique shape.
The wind that blows down from them
has a subtle effect on the waves.
How scary.
Dobashi-san, phone for you.
The results of the investigation must be in.
Investigation?
Kushizaki-san, send the two extras.
Got it.
Conan-kun, Ran-san, you're up.
Okay!
Let's go.
Huh? What is this?
What's going on?
Huh?
The fog's so dense.
Is everyone okay?
This is Arimura.
The oars aren't working.
We've lost sight of Ryo-san's boat!
Wh-What?!
Mori-san. Make sure the package is all right.
A-Actually, my oars aren't working, either!
I can't see the package!
Dad, are you okay?
Leave it to me!
I'll make sure the package is safe!
Wait. I just received some
unbelievable investigation results.
It's regarding the present matter.
It's possible she made the whole thing up.
What?
An informal decision has been made
to release her from the agency.
Apparently she seems to have realized this.
She plotted to make up a
story the media would love.
That can't be!
The problem is she's convinced that her
bitter enemy has realized this as well.
C-Could it be?
Ryo-san is trying to kill Reina-san?
Wait, Conan-kun!
I'll row!
It's no use. The oars aren't working right.
Do you see anything, Conan-kun?
No, nothing.
This sound...
What is that?
It's no use. We're being swept away.
That's it. So that's how it is!
Conan-kun, look.
Damn it. The wind's blowing me away.
That's...
Those are...
This is Ryo-san's.
That's the crew's.
Ryo-san! Where are you?!
Reina-san?
She's just unconscious.
Did Ryo-san...?
Everyone got washed up here.
It's too dangerous.
You wait here, Ran-neechan.
Don't, Conan-kun! I'll go with you.
Ryo-san?
Stay back, Mori-san!
Is it true?
Don't move!
What?
Dad!
Mister, are you okay?!
Hide, you two!
Mori-san.
Who is that?
Where's Reina? Where is she?
What?
Is that her?
She pretended to be unconscious
and waited for me to pass.
That's not it.
No, that's not possible.
That cat-hater could never make it this far.
Anyway, how did you know the
boats would get washed up here?
What?
So that's how it is!
Ryo-san, do you trust me?
Of course. You're my bodyguard.
Okay. In that case...
Ryo-san, hide behind that tree!
Don't, old man.
You haven't even disinfected it.
Wh-What?
Dobashi-san?!
Dad, are you okay?
You did it, mister!
Dobashi-san, you must have investigated
the direction of the wind and waves,
as well as where a boat would get
washed up when the fog was out.
In other words, you disinfected the area.
You came here with the motorboat
you prepared beforehand,
which would be unaffected
by the wind and waves.
So that sound we heard was a motorboat.
All to kill Ryo-san.
By making it look like she
tried to kill Reina-san,
killed me when I got in her
way, and then killed herself.
Also, you mentioned an investigation.
You made that up.
You asked someone at the office to
call you at a predetermined time.
It didn't matter what they said.
It'd be easy enough to find out.
There you are, everyone.
We made it ashore,
but we got lost in the fog.
We thought we heard gunshots.
Did something happen?
What will you do, Dobashi-san?
You can't keep all these people from talking.
It happened last month.
My daughter auditioned
for a drama and was cut.
Out of disappointment, she tried
to kill herself the next day.
She was one of the judges.
As her father, I wanted
to avenge my daughter.
Hold on. That wasn't me.
What?
I wasn't feeling well that day and
had someone judge in my place.
Wh-Who?
Me.
I'm sick of this place!
I tripped to avoid a cat
and lost consciousness.
And I'm so itchy, I can't stand it!
Y-You did that to my daughter?
If you're going to kill someone,
it should be me. Get it right.
Anyway, your daughter misses you.
What?
Reina's been visiting your daughter
in the hospital for three days.
You knew?
It sounds like something you'd do, not me.
But, Dobashi-san, you didn't
even know about that.
You have an understanding
with your daughter?
Is that what this is? Murder?
You didn't do it for your daughter.
You did it for yourself.
You did this to prove to
yourself that you're a father!
You've failed at being a
bodyguard and a father.
Not that I'm in a position to judge you.
Dad.
That's right. You failed, too, Mori-san.
What?
You failed as a bodyguard.
You used me as bait.
Well, that was...
You're fired as of today.
You should go back to where you belong.
All right...
Thank you, Detective.
Mori Detective Agency
Haneki Ryo Retires!!
Establishes New Talent Production Agency
Sawazaki Reina Becomes Haneki
Production's First Client
Ryo-san's establishing her own agency?
Apparently Reina-san is going to become
her agency's first exclusive actress.
This is it.
What? I thought you were fired, Dad.
Training School
I'm going to get more experience and
become Yoko-chan's personal bodyguard!
So that's what you're after...
The old man never learns.
Episode Preview
Crap!
What's going on?
Ayumi was kidnapped.
What?
I'm going after him!
The Secret of the Missing Young Lady
The next episode of Conan is “The
Secret of the Missing Young Lady!”
French Doll
Next Conan's hint!
A French doll!
I'm up again, huh?
Don't miss the next episode.
Why?
Because we're dealing with a young lady.
You'll just get fired again.