Solving crimes with sharp detective skills.
Love and cases never change.
A smiling woman suddenly vanishes.
Will the hearts of the
Detective Boys reach her?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Secret of the Missing Young Lady
"The Secret of the Missing Young Lady!"
It certainly is suspicious.
Yeah. The husband must've killed his wife.
That's what I think!
I'm not so sure.
What?
It's the middle of a residential neighborhood.
You think someone would transport a
body there in the middle of the day?
Indeed.
I guess so.
Conan-kun!
You're leaving already?
Sorry, I've got something to do.
Later!
Come to think of it, the "Detective
Samonji" series goes on sale today, doesn't it?
What's more important to him, us or books?!
I'm leaving, too.
What? You, too, Ai-chan?
Wh-What?
This is the house.
It's kind of creepy.
Let's check it out.
Is nobody home?
There's no car parked here, either.
Only the musician husband and
his wife live here, right?
Yeah. The husband is half-Japanese.
He often travels for performances,
so he's not home much.
Hey, look!
Is this...?
It looks like blood.
Hey, you.
What are you doing?
Makabe Jun (38)
Musician
You can't just enter people's homes.
Our ball rolled into the
yard while we were playing!
Right? Right?
You're Yoshida-san's daughter.
Uh, um...
What happened to your car?
Oh, it's out for repairs.
I scratched it while driving
in an unfamiliar place.
That's my wife's blood.
I-Is your wife okay?
Of course.
She's just not feeling well.
She's sleeping right now.
You don't need to worry.
Is something wrong?
Oh, no!
Is that right? That's good, then!
So it was nothing after all.
But I really saw it.
He's lying.
What?
I saw it.
There wasn't a single one of his
wife's shoes in the entryway.
Does that mean she's not at the house?
Yes, but that's not enough.
Hey, isn't that the same house?
Happy Everyday!
A scream?
Really?
Yeah. It happened just
before this time yesterday.
It was quiet after that,
so I didn't pay it much mind.
Did you see the wife then?
No.
Come to think of it,
I haven't seen her lately.
Did something happen to her?
No, not in particular.
The husband really did kill her.
She must have screamed when it happened.
We should go catch him!
But...
We're dealing with a murderer.
Are you sure we can handle it?
Hey!
This is the house?
Conan!
Haibara-san!
You came!
I happened to pass by.
So did I on my way to the bookstore.
Isn't the bookstore in the other direction?
More importantly, there's an emergency!
And that's that.
What do you think, Conan-kun?
He must have done it!
I'm not so sure.
What?
Why not? We even found bloodstains!
That doesn't mean he killed her.
She may have just hurt herself.
The same goes for the scream.
We shouldn't assume something happened
just because someone heard a scream.
The wife's shoes are probably
in the shoe cupboard, too.
The sun's starting to set.
We should...
Seriously? What an awful driver!
It's entering that house.
Hey!
Sheesh.
You guys, that's enough—
Sorry I'm late.
Where's Yuri-san?
In the mountains.
Who's Yuri-san?
That's the wife's name.
What's wrong?
Did you see a group of weird kids?
Kids? I don't know.
I see. That's fine, then.
Let's go. I'm hungry.
Edogawa-kun...
Yeah. Looks like we'll have to reconsider.
You mean...
But we still don't know it's a murder.
It'd be a different story if we found
solid proof like the wife's body, though.
Then let's find it!
This is a job for the Detective Boys!
But how are we going to find it?
Well...
Ayumi-chan!
The key to the back door.
Now we can get inside.
But how?
Who cares? Let's go.
If we don't hurry, they'll come back.
Hold on.
What now, Conan?
Didn't I tell you?
We don't know if it's a murder yet.
Entering without permission
is a crime, though.
You're worried about that now?
He definitely killed her!
That's all the more reason not to go.
It's too dangerous.
I agree with Edogawa-kun.
I don't want to die here.
But...
What should we do, Mitsuhiko?
Hey! What are you doing, Yoshida-san?
You guys can leave.
I'll search the house alone.
Ayumi-chan, why do you care so much?
Until recently, I'd been friends
with the wife, Yuri-san.
Yuri-san treated me like her own child.
I came to this house to play all the time.
That's why she told you
where to find the spare key.
Yeah.
But Yuri-san suddenly started
avoiding me six months ago.
I know she must have had a reason,
but I couldn't do anything for her.
So I...
Conan!
Conan-kun!
Fine.
Don't blame me if something happens.
Anything over there, Haibara?
All clear for now.
If anything happens—
Let you know, right?
Thanks.
This looks like the bedroom.
See? There's no wife here.
What's wrong, guys?
It's just a doll.
Seriously?
No children live here, right?
Why would there be a doll here?
That doll wasn't here before.
Hey, Conan...
What's up, Genta?
This isn't blood, is it?
He's back!
Hurry!
Shit. Turn off the lights!
What are you doing, Genta?
He's headed your way!
Incoming Call
That's Yuri-san's phone.
No!
Don't do it, Ayumi-chan!
Crap!
He's at the entrance!
Hurry!
Ayumi-chan, in here.
Crap, he's coming.
Damn it, Genta...
Is someone there?
Incoming Call
Where are the others?
They're still inside.
What?
It's okay. I have an idea!
Yes?
Who is—
Hey!
Now!
This way!
Hurry!
Is someone there?
My Detective Boys pin.
What? Where's Ayumi-chan?
Found it!
Crap!
Damn it!
What's going on?
Ayumi was kidnapped.
What?
I'm going after him!
This is...
How awful.
Did Ayumi-chan...?
What are you talking about, Mitsuhiko?
Just look at this, though!
No.
This blood is dry.
It's not Yoshida-san's.
It must be the wife's blood.
Yoshida-san was kidnapped
because she saw this.
Which means...
Yes. Yoshida-san's life is in danger!
Did you hear that, Edogawa-kun?
Yeah. You guys call the police!
I'll save Ayumi-chan!
What? I...
Damn it...
Ayumi!
Stay away!
Ayumi-chan!
Conan-kun!
Help me, Conan-kun!
Get down, Ayumi!
Ow!
Conan-kun!
Ouch...
You're hurt?
It's nothing serious.
Sorry. It's my fault...
Thanks to you, we caught the culprit.
Are you all right, Makabe-san?
Are you the girl who collapsed
at Makabe-san's house?
Huh?
Makabe-san just called.
He said a girl collapsed at his house,
and he wanted me to examine her.
Huh?
Clinic in the Mountains
So by "in the mountains," he meant...
Are you all right, Darling?
Yeah. Anyway...
Ayumi-chan?
Y-Yuri-san?
Huh?! What...?
Um...
We're sorry!
It's all right.
Your kick was a bit powerful, though.
Sorry!
You made quite the fuss.
I can't believe you thought Yuri-san was dead
when she was in the hospital giving birth.
And how could you mistake
my brother and I for lovers?
Why would you think I'm this guy's mistress?
Hey, now...
But you were hugging and kissing.
What?
We were just saying hello.
You mean this, right?
They don't do that in Japan.
It's no wonder you were confused.
Yeah, but—
Now, now...
Anyway, I'm sorry for scaring you.
But why did you hide that
you were having a baby?
I actually miscarried once.
It hurt me a lot, and it caused
trouble for other people.
This time we decided not to tell
anyone until we had the baby.
So the husband lied and the wife
stopped playing with Ayumi-chan
because you were trying
to hide the pregnancy.
Yes.
It looks like I made you worry.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
But I suddenly started bleeding the
day I was supposed to give birth...
So that's where the blood
under the bed came from.
Yeah. It was somewhere it wouldn't
be seen, and I was shocked, too.
I forgot to clean it up.
So the scream the milkman heard...
That must have been then, too.
So I saw your husband carrying your
unconscious body to his car, and I...
I'm really sorry!
Ayumi-chan.
Here. Hold the baby.
It's so cute.
Come visit anytime.
What? Really?
But I...
Sure. After all, aren't you
this child's big sister?
Yeah!
Detective Samonji Series
Intent to Kill
Sold Out
I totally forgot.
Episode Preview
His watch is broken and stopped at 11:50.
I think he was wearing leather
shoes when I saw him this morning.
He had that photo out, huh?
Someone cornered Kanbayashi-san
by the window and pushed him.
Why was Kanbayashi-san
standing in this window?
The Lovebird's Ruse
The next episode of Conan is
"The Lovebirds' Ruse!"
Scar on the Face
Next Conan's hint!
A scar on the face!
What are lovebirds?
Don't miss the next episode.
A close couple who are always together.
And they're scheming something, huh?