Inspector, we believe he fell from there.
The window on the fifth
floor hallway was left open.
The victim's footprints
were on the sill, too.
That must be it, then.
The question is why he fell.
M-Mori-kun?
We spotted you and thought
we could be helpful.
This kid did, that is.
Kanbayashi Chosaku (38)
Mystery Writer
Is this the author...?
Kanbayashi Chosaku-san.
He was renting an office on the
fifth floor of this building.
Kanbayashi Chosaku? He's a modestly
successful mystery writer, right?
Not modestly!
Kanbayashi Seiko (35)
Kanbayashi's Wife
Sugiyama Kiyoshi (58)
Building Doorman
My husband was first-rate!
What?
That's his wife, Kanbayashi Seiko-san.
She already came to confirm it was him?
No. She apparently discovered the body.
The wife found her husband's body?
Why, Darling?
Why did this happen?
Solving crimes with sharp detective skills.
Love and cases never change.
Lovebirds are the closest of
couples, but what are they hiding?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Lovebirds' Ruse
"The Lovebirds' Ruse!"
Could you explain the events leading
up to you discovering the body?
All right.
This morning as I was going out, my
husband asked me to do something.
Some work documents should
arrive before noon.
Can you bring them to my office?
What? But...
I know.
You can bring them after your show.
I took the documents that were delivered
and left home at exactly 12.
I called to say I was on my way,
but he didn't answer his phone.
I thought he might be feeling unwell, so
I had the doorman unlock the door for me.
He's not here.
I don't think he went out.
She arrived around 12:20 and discovered
the body immediately after that.
His watch is broken and stopped at 11:50.
He probably fell at this time.
Thirty minutes before he was found.
But why is he wearing gloves?
These gloves look new.
And then there are the sneakers.
I think he was wearing leather
shoes when I saw him this morning.
What?
And what's this scrape on his face?
He probably scraped his face
on the ground when he fell.
Then shouldn't there be
grit stuck to his face?
Either way, the autopsy
might reveal something.
And I'm sure an investigation of
Kanbayashi's office will turn up something.
Oh? You look pretty young in this photo.
Yes. We didn't have much
money when we got married.
We could barely afford those fox
and raccoon dog stuffed animals.
He had that photo out, huh?
Was Kanbayashi behaving
strangely this morning?
Not really.
He only stepped out for five
minutes to buy cigarettes.
It's your anniversary?
Yes. I have my wife to thank
for the man I am today.
I'd be too embarrassed to tell her, though.
I'll be right back.
He said that?
It's the opposite.
Kanbayashi made me so happy.
It doesn't sound like there
was trouble between them.
Based on the gloves and
sneakers he was wearing,
your husband must have been working on
something when he accidentally fell.
So it was an accident.
But, Inspector Megure...
There's nothing outside that window.
I see.
So he couldn't have been working.
Which means he was murdered.
Huh?
Someone cornered Kanbayashi-san
by the window and pushed him.
But, Mister...
That's impossible.
What?
It's the weekend.
Only Kanbayashi-sensei was in the building.
Even if someone snuck in, the only way in
was the service entrance, and I was there.
Right, you little brat?
Then that leaves suicide.
It's plausible.
He said his manuscript was due today.
Perhaps he had writer's block
and did it impulsively.
He was suffering so much,
but I didn't notice.
It's my fault.
You do sometimes hear about writers
doing that when they can't write.
But if he did it on impulse, wouldn't he have
jumped from here instead of the hallway window?
Is it true that he's dead, ma'am?
Ikejiri Fumito (35)
Editor
Ikejiri-san?
I came by to see how the manuscript was
coming along, and they told me he's dead.
This is Kanbayashi's editor.
I know this is a bad time, but I need to
figure out how to handle the situation,
so I'd like to see the manuscript.
Y-You...
It's his job.
And if it is suicide...
Huh?
I-It's finished.
You're right.
But when I called this morning, he...
I'm stuck.
It'll be finished at four at the earliest.
But he finished by the time he died at noon.
He was probably teasing you, Ikejiri-san.
His final joke, huh?
It may not be suicide, then.
An accident, murder, and suicide.
None of them make any sense!
We're still missing something.
There must be some kind of clue in this room.
Envelopes?
These are documents.
Usually he had them sent here.
So why did he make an exception today?
What are you doing?
That's a receipt from a
nearby convenience store.
Isn't it weird?
Gloves 1 Pair
MINI SEVEN 1 Carton
He bought gloves and a carton
of cigarettes this morning.
Which means somewhere in here...
Look, I found the cigarettes!
But Kanbayashi-san went
out to buy some, right?
Ten minutes before he fell.
It certainly is strange...
He'd do that sometimes.
He would get so focused on
work, he'd forget that he had some.
You heard her.
Well, I'm heading back to the office.
We'll figure out how to handle this later.
Excuse me, ma'am.
I just thought it a bit strange.
He hadn't had the photo out before?
As if.
Their relationship was long over.
His wife wanted a divorce, but the stingy
writer didn't want to pay alimony,
so he'd been avoiding the discussion.
Really?
After growing tired of him, his wife
became obsessed with Korean celebrities.
Don't tell anyone, okay?
O-Okay.
Ma'am!
Yes?
According to my sources, your
relationship ended long ago.
I sense the key to solving the
mystery of his fall lies there.
It was rocky at times, but we
patched up our relationship.
I can't believe you're bringing that up now.
Uh, well...
Mori-kun.
Mori-san.
Um, I...
Sheesh!
Something's not right.
Murder, suicide, an accident.
None of them make sense, and
nothing seems quite right.
And why was Kanbayashi-san
standing in this window?
There's a window directly opposite this one.
That's it!
That would explain everything.
It should be right around here.
The men's bathroom?
The windows...
It's about two meters across.
You could jump if you wanted to.
Cleaning Checklist
The building is cleaned every
day at 7:00, 11:00, and 5:00.
As long as you put it back
before then, it's fine.
And regardless of when
the documents arrived,
Gathering of Korean stars!!
he knew his wife would
leave home after noon.
It's a twenty minute walk from home to here.
And between them is... Beika Greens?
Beika Greens
Even in the middle of the day,
it's dark with the shadows of the trees.
But he underestimated the two
meter distance and failed.
What?
The wife is lying?
Lying about what?
The wife said she left home
at exactly 12:00, right?
But a neighbor spotted her
leaving earlier at 11:20!
Which means she could've
been here by 11:40.
Kanbayashi fell at 11:50.
If she arrived at 11:40,
she could have pushed him!
But even if she made it here, she couldn't
have gone inside without the doorman noticing.
I'm not sure we should suspect her.
She lied about a fact
as critical as the time!
Y-Yes, but...
What's going on?
The wife could have arrived at 11:40.
11:40? That's when Kanbayashi-san...
Could it be?
If that's true,
then the scrape on his face...
This is it!
M-Mori-san!
She'll show her true colors
if we question her!
But, Mori-kun...
Damn it, there's still one
more thing I don't know!
I did leave the house
at 11:20 the first time.
The first time?
I was in a hurry to deliver the
documents and forgot to lock up.
I came partway before turning back.
The second time I left was at exactly noon.
So that's what happened.
You heard her, Mori-kun.
Th-That's too convenient!
Let's get a con-beer-nient beer!
Kanbayashi Nagasaku's death is mysterious
indeed, but I've finally solved it.
Kanbayashi Seiko-san, your
husband nearly killed you.
Me?!
What?!
His motive was probably
because he met a new woman.
No...
However, he would be the prime
suspect if he simply killed you.
So Kanbayashi-san fabricated an alibi.
First he asked you to bring the
documents to draw you here.
Normally he had documents delivered here,
but he had them sent to the house instead.
At 11:40, Kanbayashi-san pretended
to go out to buy cigarettes,
went into the neighboring building,
opened the window in the fifth floor men's
bathroom directly opposite the window,
and returned as though nothing happened.
Then he planned to change into sneakers,
jump to the bathroom window,
exit through the building,
wait for you at Beika Greens, and kill you.
After returning the way he came...
I finally finished.
He'd give Ikejiri the manuscript.
Once he closed the window in the
men's bathroom, he would be finished.
Since it's the weekend, no
one would use the bathroom.
After 11, cleaning services
don't come until 5PM,
so no one would notice
if he did it before then.
His wife's body would be discovered,
and her time of death would be
determined to be around noon.
But the doorman would testify that
Kanbayashi-san was inside this
building from morning until evening.
He left for about five minutes, but
since it's not enough time to travel
to and back from the scene of the
murder, he wouldn't be suspected.
He finished the manuscript
beforehand because he wouldn't
have time to write after he
went out to commit a murder.
It was another tool to make us
believe he wasn't trying to kill me.
It was all a scheme to get
away with killing his wife!
That's right.
But despite putting on gloves and sneakers,
Kanbayashi-san failed to jump across
to the window like he planned.
He made a mistake and fell.
Which means it was an accident.
What an idiot. I'm an idiot, too.
I had no idea I was such a
bother that he wanted to kill me.
Ma'am...
You can stop acting now, ma'am.
What?
What do you mean, Mori-kun?
Kanbayashi-san didn't fail the
jump because he made a mistake,
but because you blocked him!
After leaving your home at 11:20,
you arrived here at 11:40.
You saw Kanbayashi behaving strangely then.
You were already suspicious because
he sent the documents to your home,
so you followed Kanbayashi-san and
realized what he was planning.
You used his plan against him.
There!
Which means that his fall was murder.
I didn't...
Then you and the doorman
discovered the body together.
Without a third party with you,
suspicion would fall on you.
A wife benefits most from
her husband's death.
She gets the insurance money.
This is profoundly malicious conjecture.
I believe you'll find proof in the
neighboring building's bathroom.
We found Kanbayashi-san's eyebrow
hairs in the deck brush.
And this was on the floor.
It's a woman's hair.
A DNA test should make things clear.
My idiot husband had been
trying to kill me for a long time.
That's why I did the same...
...to him.
I didn't think anyone would find out.
I'd wanted to kill him for a long time.
All I did was shove the brush
in my idiot husband's face.
How dare you? You killed a man!
They're both to blame.
They both wanted to kill each other,
but pretended to be happily married.
They were both trying to outfox the other.
Ma'am, will you tell me one thing?
Kanbayashi-san's plan failed because
you left home forty minutes early.
Your beloved Korean stars were on TV.
Why didn't you wait until
the end of the episode?
Because, Mori-san, I came
up with a good idea.
A way to kill my idiot husband and
make it look like an accident.
I wanted to put it into
action as soon as possible.
You know what they say.
Strike while the iron is hot!
Hey, wait!
What's wrong with that woman?
She's terrifying.
Episode Preview
Make any noise, and I'll kill you!
Hand over the jewels.
Crime Plan
A crime plan?
Oh, no! "The Mirage" is doomed!
I won't let this beat me.
Found it.
But the most vital thing is missing...
In that case, this is the
birth of detective Funachi!
The Dreaming Girl's Confused Deduction
The next episode of Conan is "The
Dreaming Girl's Confused Deduction!"
Printing Paper
Next Conan's hint!
Printing paper!
Ah, a young girl dreams
of finding her lovebird.
Don't miss the next episode.
What's wrong?
Sato-san!