Nakai Funako (22)
College Student
Yesterday a person disappeared!
I would appreciate if you could look for him!
You said that yesterday,
and I turned you down.
I'm busy here.
I don't mean to be rude, but you don't
look the slightest bit busy to me.
What?
I don't believe I'm getting
through to you, so once again!
Crime Plan
A crime plan?
I told you, it's got to be fake.
And it's not like you know the
guy who disappeared, right?
Well, no...
But I happened to see him on the street.
The Mirage
And he was the spitting
image of "The Mirage,"
a character from a popular otome game!
So you followed him and
secretly took his picture.
Well, yes...
Detectives don't help stalkers.
No one cares about your mirage or whatever.
Get out of here.
He's "The Mirage."
Why not go to the police?
A good suggestion, but I cannot.
I don't have the time.
What?
Which means this is the
birth of Detective Funachi!
Solving crimes with sharp detective skills.
Love and cases never change.
An unusual client who calls herself Funachi.
A simple request to find someone
turns into a surprising case.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Dreaming Girl's Confused Deduction
"The Dreaming Girl's Confused Deduction!"
Hikone
Hikone-sama? Are you there?
Hikone-sama?
I can't go any farther...
Is Hikone-san the name of
the guy who disappeared?
Um...
You're the boy from earlier.
I'm Edogawa Conan.
I hadn't introduced myself yet.
My name is Nakai Funako.
Call me Funachi.
Funachi-san?
No need for honorifics.
I borrowed the name Funachi
from the heroine
who adores "The Mirage"
in a famous otome game.
I know there are copyright issues,
but I hope you understand it comes from
a place of great respect and inspiration.
Additionally, based on the game's
world view and setting...
I can't keep up.
And?
What?
Since when has Hikone-san been missing?
When I came here the evening
of the day before yesterday,
the door was unlocked and no one was inside.
I believe it's been empty since then.
Two whole days, huh?
What is this?
The lock is broken. Recently, too.
I actually noticed that as well.
Do you supposed it was a burglar?!
Whoosh
Boom!
Gasp
"Wh-What are you—"
But after "The Mirage" was bound...
Rather, Hikone-sama, where did he go?!
Bound?
Could it be?!
Excuse me!
He's not here.
Not here.
Not here!
Which means...
Twinkle!
What are you doing?
Assist me, Edogawa-sama!
Hikone-sama may be buried under here!
E-Edogawa-sama?
Actually, since this is the second floor,
I don't think that's the slightest bit possible.
What? Oh, that's right.
There I go again.
She suffers from delusions.
Or mirages, as it were.
Stay here.
What?
Hello!
Kiyose Takashi (20)
College Student
What?
Do you know where your
neighbor Hikone-san went?
No. Is that my neighbor's name?
Have you noticed anything unusual?
I don't know.
Nashida Akio (40)
Former Office Worker
Hey, shut up!
What's with all the noise out here?
Sorry. I'm looking for
your neighbor, Hikone-san.
Hikone?
I don't know who you're talking about.
Wait, wait!
What's going on?
You worried me for a moment there.
Please shut the door, Edogawa-sama.
Okay.
What was that?
I thought I felt someone watching me.
Is something wrong?
Uh, no.
Funachi, is the reason you can't go to
the police related to that notebook?
Could it be that you're a
detective as well, Edogawa-sama?
Yeah. I'm always helping the old man.
In other words, my concerns about
confidentiality have been eliminated.
Yeah.
Then take a look.
Is this Hikone-san's?
Yes. I believe it's handwritten.
"No, Funachi! Anything but that!"
So I chided myself, but out
of concern for Hikone-sama,
I entered this place
yesterday and found that.
What is this?
So once a month the jewels are
swapped out for more valuable ones.
That's October 24.
That's today.
Today is the day he plans
to commit that crime.
He's detailed how the jewels
are brought in, too.
Could this be an actual crime plan?
However, I was unable to find a store
matching the one in the notebook.
Hold on...
Oh! Around now, Hikone-sama
must be wearing a mask
and holding a pistol...
"Scream and I'll kill you!"
"Hand over the jewels!"
Put the jewels in this bag!!
...and threatening the employees!
What should Funachi do?
Doesn't this seem odd upon closer inspection?
I am stunned.
This and this are backwards, too.
Backwards?
The locks on the doors and
cases wouldn't work this way.
That's it.
Maybe the store's name is, too.
Ishigami.
I found it!
And this location is only a
two or three minute walk away!
Really?
I knew you could do it, Edogawa-sama!
That was some impressive deduction
and following of clues.
But what shall we do?
Huh?
Should we call?
Or shall we go there?
But if we ran into Hikone-sama
as he's committing his robbery...
Bang!
Rustle, rustle!
Please stop, Hikone-sama!
What is it? Something's not right.
Is that...?
Becoming an Author
How to Write Novels
Guide to Novels
Could it be?
Found it.
But the most vital thing is missing.
No, it's here!
Could it be?
Tenbun Publishing
Hello?
This is Tenbun Publishing's "Tenbun
Monthly" editorial department.
Could you put Hikone Kazuma-san on the phone?
Um, he's out right now.
You must be his family.
The novel "Crime Plan" he
brought in the other day
was evaluated during an editorial meeting,
and we've decided to publish it.
Could you tell him to call me back?
The advent of the shocking truth!
Got it. Bye.
This means these are his mistakes,
and that notebook contains the results
of his research for his writing.
Yeah, I think so.
In other words, this is just
one of my usual coincidences.
My usual...
Kaboom!
And disappointment.
Hikone-sama must have some imagination
for me to mistake this for reality!
It would be no exaggeration
to call it godlike!
I-I don't know about that...
And there are still too many questions.
More than anything, Hikone-san himself
has been missing for two days.
Ishigami Jewelry
Make any noise, and I'll kill you!
Hand over the jewels.
Could it be?
Edogawa-sama?
What do you mean? What could it be?
N-No way! Could it really be?!
Detective Takagi!
Conan-kun.
Did someone steal the jewels?
Uh, well, yeah...
New jewels were being
brought in today, right?
A robber who entered the basement
boiler room through the sewer...
Stole the jewels being brought in, right?
How do you know that?
I knew it.
What I feared has come to pass.
Are the lies true, or is the truth a lie?
I don't know what's happening anymore!
Wh-Who is she?
We just stationed officers in the
sewer and at all connected exits.
That's exactly what the robber wants.
What?
Make it look like he left the way
he came, but flee above ground.
That's his plan.
His plan?
Yeah.
Look.
Th-This is...
The gun is fake.
That's part of his plan, too.
Come to think of it...
Funachi, let me see the notebook again.
All right.
This is it!
"Make them believe I fled, eliminate
planner nearby, and return to everyday life."
"This is the perfect crime."
That's it.
Is the true culprit someone else?
What?
Oh, no! "The Mirage" is doomed!
I won't let this beat me.
Let's catch the true culprit, Edogawa-sama!
Wait! Where are you going?!
Where am I going?
This way, Funachi!
Conan-kun?
Detective Takagi, come with us!
What?
Got it!
What's this? Who the hell are you?
You're Nashida-san, right?
Do you have a minute to talk?
The police?
Wh-What am I being accused of?
Funachi, why did the paper
fly into the air then?
What? Oh...
It's a mystery.
A gust of wind suddenly
blew through the room.
But Hikone-san's window was closed, right?
That's why the paper didn't fly
when we first opened the door.
Could it be?
I found it!
The wind must have blown through there!
Nashida-sama, you were watching Hikone-sama
write his novel through that space.
You set your sights on the computer here,
broke the lock, entered
the room, and stole it.
What the? Is that true?
D-Don't be ridiculous!
You can search my apartment, then.
If it's not in your apartment,
perhaps you pawned it.
I believe there's a pawn shop nearby.
Are you sure you don't have a pawn ticket
and cash in your pocket right now?
Isn't that why you're in high spirits?
You stole and read this crime plan, robbed
the jeweler, and killed Hikone-sama!
Wh-What? Stop joking around!
Tell us the truth, then.
I did steal the computer.
I pawned it, too.
But by the time I entered,
the lock was already broken!
Really?
I'm not lying!
I didn't steal the jewels. It's true!
Funachi, was it the first time
the papers flew into the air
when Nashida-san opened his door?
What?
There's one over here, too!
That's right.
I sensed people watching
me from both sides then.
And the true culprit is...
Wh-What do you want?
Don't play dumb! You were watching.
What?
Do you have a minute to talk, Kiyose-san?
About what?
If you look through that hole,
couldn't you see Hikone-sama's back,
or rather, his computer screen?
Did you not decide to rob the jeweler,
break the lock and enter, read his
notebook, and put it into action?
Don't be absurd!
What proof do you have?
Look at all this mud.
You should have worn your
boots the whole time.
I got it!
If you had returned through the sewer,
you wouldn't have gotten mud on you,
but you did because you ran above ground.
Above ground?
Two parallel streets run
between here and the jeweler,
but we didn't see Kiyose-sama
while traveling along one of them.
I believe the other is still
muddy from yesterday's rain.
What's this?
Is that...?
It matches.
It broke off into the hem of your
pants when you broke the lock.
Then there are the jewels.
I'll get a search warrant, and...
They're probably there.
Kiyose-sama, you didn't have
those coin locker keys earlier.
That's it. There was a station on the way.
He stored them in a coin locker there.
I was fired from my job.
Money... I wanted money!
But that doesn't make it
acceptable to kill someone!
Don't be stupid!
I didn't kill anyone!
Then where is Hikone-sama?
Who are you?
No way!
So he is okay.
What?
Are you Hikone-san?
The police?
How did you know he was all right?
Because his room was clean.
I couldn't imagine he was attacked here.
If he was attacked outside,
they would have stolen his keys,
so they wouldn't have
needed to break his lock.
Which means...
Typical Edogawa-sama!
You truly are godlike! No, God himself!
What?
Is that so?
Sorry for all the trouble I caused.
Anyway, where have you been for two days?
I was fed up with my lack of talent,
so I've been wandering around.
But I ran out of money,
so I had to come back here.
It's pathetic. I've had enough of my dream...
No, my fantasy of writing a novel.
I'm going back to the countryside.
But that fantasy has become reality.
Rather, that dream.
What?
The publisher called.
"Crime Plan" is going to be published.
Yeah, right.
Really?
Yup.
Wow.
All right!
Huh?
Aren't you Funachi-san?
You know her?
I covered a game store a while ago.
She gave a far more detailed
explanation than the employees.
So you were lying about spotting
Hikone-san in the street?
Funachi...
Rather, I simply believed he
couldn't possibly remember me,
so I made the calm and
objective decision to...
Are you the one who saved me?
Are you a cop?
Huh?
Or a detective?
I...
Thank you!
Let me thank you by taking you out to eat.
What?
Can I write about you in my next work?
Tell me more, Funachi.
What?
Could this be a happy
ending for you, Funachi?
Th-This is unexpected.
I'm sorry that I must reject you.
But the 2D can never become 3D.
"The Mirage" will never be real!
Wait, Funachi!
Funachi! Funachi!
Wait!
So how did the case turn out?
It was the birth of an otome game detective.
Funa!
Episode Preview
Huh?
What?
Mixed up in a suicide?
A stranger invited you out?
They told me to be in front
of this building at eight.
Detective Takagi said the
location they tried to drop him
and the location he actually
fell were different.
You're thinking something
unbelievable, aren't you?
What do you mean, unbelievable?
The Moving Target
The next episode of Conan
is "The Moving Target!"
Love Letters
Next Conan's hint.
Love letters!
Don't miss the next episode.
Mister, have you ever received one?
Of course not.
I have.
What?