Uh, oh. It's this time already?
Crap!
He hasn't noticed!
Please make it!
Huh?
What?
What happened?
Are you all right?
What?
I'm glad you're okay.
Uh...
You were nearly crushed by that
man falling from the roof.
What?!
Looks like he's okay, too.
Fukurokoji Sadao (43)
Office Worker
Fukurokoji Sadao-san...
I wonder why he fell.
I think he was trying to kill himself.
Kill himself?
He'd always talk about it at the bars.
Nothing I do ever goes right.
I wish I'd die already.
Something like that.
Komatsu Hitoshi (28)
Office Worker
I nearly got mixed up in a suicide?
I've always had bad luck.
Yeah, some people are like that.
Solving crimes with sharp detective skills.
Love and cases never change.
Waiting to meet someone for a casual date.
The slightest divergence sends their
fates in different directions.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Moving Target
"The Moving Target!"
It was an attempted suicide.
That's got nothing to do
with the Detective Boys.
Either way, we want to
check out the crime scene.
It happened in our territory.
Yeah.
It's up ahead.
What?
What's Investigation Section One doing here?
That's him!
So the kid with glasses
was Conan-kun after all.
I'm glad you're here.
We wanted to ask you about last night.
So it wasn't just an attempted suicide.
No. The entrance had been
closed over the holidays.
The only way to the roof was
to take the emergency stairs.
But...
Fukurokoji-san was so
drunk he couldn't stand.
Then he couldn't have climbed the stairs.
It would've been impossible.
Someone must have carried the plastered
Fukurokoji-san to the roof and thrown him off.
Then...
It wasn't an attempted suicide,
it was an attempted murder.
We think the culprit blended
in with the crowd and left.
Did you see anyone suspicious?
I see.
Can we see the roof?
I might remember something.
This is the spot.
It's directly above where he fell.
There are scratch marks, too.
What are scratch marks?
Those. See where the dirt has
been wiped off the railing?
Fukurokoji-san's clothes must have
rubbed against it when he fell.
But why did the culprit bother
to carry him to the roof?
They were trying to make it
look like a suicide, right?
There are easier ways to...
There are scratch marks here, too.
Which means the culprit initially
tried to drop him from here,
but he resisted and ended
up dropping him over there.
Could he have resisted when he was plastered?
Inspector!
Fukurokoji-san was drunk and doesn't
remember anything that happened last night.
Also, he said that since he's a
loser in our competitive society,
there shouldn't be anyone who resents him.
But the fact of the matter
is that he was nearly killed.
We'll try to figure out where
Fukurokoji-san went last night.
The culprit made contact
with him somewhere!
Yes, sir!
You look unconvinced.
Yeah, something's not...
That man.
This is it.
It was right here.
This is where I was nearly squashed flat.
Yukigaya Daisuke (28)
Office Worker
I get it. I know you're unlucky.
You told your friend
about your bad luck, too?
You're from last night.
This is Yukigaya Daisuke.
I'm proud to call him my friend.
You don't have to say that to kids, too.
I've got to get going.
Later!
He agreed to stop by since
we were in the area.
He's great at his job, athletic, and
from a rich and distinguished family.
He's confident in everything.
We started working at the same
time, but we're nothing alike.
After all, he's never
experienced any kind of setback.
So perfect people do exist.
How do you feel about people who
haven't experienced setbacks?
If you can make it through
life that way, why not?
Compared to him, I have terrible luck.
You just happened to come
here last night, too.
I didn't happen to come here,
I was waiting for someone.
I got a love letter from
a woman I don't know.
Maybe it was because of all the
fuss, but she never showed up.
A stranger invited you out?
She told me to be in front
of this building at eight.
That's why I waited by the entrance at first.
But then my watch stopped.
The battery's dead!
What time is it?
I think there's a clock over there.
The time, the time.
When I came here so I could see
the clock, he fell off the roof.
I've got pretty bad luck.
He started here.
This place is directly under
the other scratch marks.
What is it, Conan-kun?
Detective Takagi said
Fukurokoji-san resisted,
so the spot the culprit
initially tried to push him
was different from where
he was actually pushed.
There's another interpretation.
Huh?
What?
The culprit's target moved.
The culprit was trying to
kill not only Fukurokoji-san,
but also trying to kill Komatsu-san by
making it look like he was mixed up in a suicide.
They were trying to get
rid of two people at once.
That explains why the culprit
lured Komatsu-san here...
...with the love letter, and had to
carry Fukurokoji-san to the roof.
In other words, the culprit is someone who
resents both Fukurokoji-san and Komatsu-san.
Someone has a grudge against you, right?
What? I...
No one has a grudge against me.
Could you show us the love letter, then?
What?
We've never received one
before, so we're jealous.
I thought we'd find a clue about the culprit.
But anyway...
"I've always been drawn to the way you
don't let your bad luck get you down."
"Please go out with me."
"Thirteen days from now, I'll be waiting in
front of Beika Building One at eight o'clock."
"Sincerely, the one who secretly
watches you with love."
There's no name. Who would take this
seriously and go out to meet them?
I know!
You're wrong. It's one-sided,
but there's a girl I like.
I went so I could tell her
I couldn't go out with her.
Anyway, this is the part I don't get.
"P.S. Please bring this letter
with you to our meeting."
Why?
To take it back, right?
It's evidence.
Taking it back would have been impossible.
If their plan had succeeded, there
would have been a huge fuss.
Why did the culprit tell him to do this?
I'm hungry. Let's go eat.
What?
I agree!
You guys should come, too.
I'll treat you to a kid's meal.
He's not a bad guy.
Maybe not, but someone tried to kill him.
That's the restaurant.
Sakiko-chan is nice.
She's so bright and vivacious.
Is she the one...
...you have one-sided feelings for?
H-How did you know?
That was delicious.
I couldn't eat another bite.
Nagai Sakiko (24)
Waitress
I have lunch here every day.
It's close to my office.
What? Your office is around here, too?
But Yukigaya-san said...
What about Yukigaya?
Now that you mentioned it,
he hasn't been coming lately.
He used to eat here all the time, too.
I'm going to the bathroom.
You must have some idea, Sakiko-san.
What?
You saw through me?
About two weeks ago, he
asked me out on a date.
Yukigaya-san did, that is.
Why don't we go see a movie next Sunday?
But since I turned him down, he
stopped coming the very next day.
Over being rejected for a date?
He must have felt embarrassed.
But Yukigaya-san's a cool guy.
Why did you say no?
Because I can't stand confident people
like him who think they have everything.
One vote for yes.
Koma-chan is nice, though.
What?
He believes in God.
He says if bad things keep happening,
something just as good is
bound to happen eventually.
He says it's because God isn't unfair.
People who truly believe
that are so wonderful.
Oh, no! I'll bring your desserts
and drinks right away!
It's not one-sided. Sakiko-san
likes Komatsu-san, too.
It looks like everyone
around them knows it, too.
He's the only one who hasn't noticed.
Komatsu-san is a huge idiot.
I know who did it.
It was Yukigaya.
What?
They said he stopped by Komatsu-san's
place since he was in the area, right?
It would make sense if he
hadn't been here in a while.
But he comes around here every
day since his office is here.
It does seem unnatural, but...
But if you consider he visited Komatsu-san to
see if he realized he committed the crime...
And if he did it, then I think I know
why he had Komatsu-san bring the letter.
But the culprit tried to kill
Komatsu-san and Fukurokoji-san.
That's why I'm still only 50% sure it's him.
If he comes up in the police
investigation as well, then it'll be 100%.
So a suspicious man came up in your inquiry?
Last night, Fukurokoji-san
was drinking alone at a bar.
As usual, he was saying he wanted to die.
At some point a man approached him.
I want to die...
Really? I want to die, too.
Right? I know.
Let's go to another bar.
Another bar!
They left the bar.
Apparently the man's clothes were
worn out and his hair was disheveled.
That doesn't sound like him.
He was tall, right?
Like an athlete.
You can't hide your body type.
Yeah.
It must be him.
But in the end, we don't think
he's connected to the incident.
Why not?
We checked with Fukurokoji-san.
Now that you mention it, I
did hit it off with someone.
But I'd never seen him before.
That was their first meeting?
That's right. I'd understand if there
was trouble between them, but...
Bye, Conan-kun.
We didn't reach 100%.
They're physically similar,
but there's no motive.
It was their first meeting.
You were wrong.
That's it! The culprit wasn't trying
to kill two birds with one stone.
What do you mean? He actually...
You're thinking something
unbelievable, aren't you?
What do you mean, unbelievable?
I wouldn't put it past someone like him.
Apparently you want to talk to me.
I wonder what it's about.
I brought him since you asked.
Huh? Sakiko-san!
Yukigaya-san, you've never
experienced disappointment, right?
That's amazing.
I don't know about that.
But if that's who you are,
it must have been really shocking when
Sakiko-san turned you down for a date.
What?
That happened?
So what?
That's why you came up with that plan.
Komatsu-san.
It was Yukigaya-san.
He's the one who wrote the love letter
and dropped Fukurokoji-san from here.
What?
He pretended to be a woman
and sent the letter.
Last night, he led the plastered
Fukurokoji-san out of the bar,
carried him to the roof, and tried
to drop him on top of Komatsu-san.
Ultimately, though, he failed
to kill him as planned.
There's no way he would do that.
After all, why would he try to kill me?
For what end?
How would I benefit from killing Komatsu?
It would be a blow to Sakiko-san.
You were right.
To me?
If his plan had succeeded, Fukurokoji-san and
Komatsu-san would have been beyond saving.
If Sakiko-san saw the letter,
she would have been shocked.
It would mean he suffered an unfortunate
death because he was lured out by a woman.
Excuse me! I know that man!
Why, Koma-chan?
You idiot, why?!
Then you would've laughed scornfully at
Sakiko-san for getting what she deserved.
Isn't that what you wanted, Yukigaya-san?
That's why you had to have
him bring the letter.
It was the most critical tool
for making Sakiko-san sad.
No...
Uh, why would Sakiko-chan be sad if I
died holding a love letter from a woman?
Notice already.
What?!
Is it because I turned you down for a date?
Just over that?
He couldn't forgive you.
Not a confident man who'd never
experienced disappointment.
Hold on.
Why did he try to kill Fukurokoji-san?
You haven't explained that.
It didn't matter who it was.
If you'd dropped a block, the police would
have know it was a premeditated murder.
That's why you had to drop a human.
Not even the police would imagine someone
using a living human as a weapon.
A weapon?
Fukurokoji-san was dropped only
to take Komatsu-san's life.
As a human weapon.
What?
You searched for someone you could
use and found Fukurokoji-san.
Since he always said he wanted to die,
no one would find it odd if
you dropped him off a roof.
They'd just think he finally killed himself.
There's no point in keeping
trash like him alive.
In fact, just him existing
in this world is unsightly.
Yukigaya, you...
Yukigaya-san, we have some questions for you.
It's over!
Didn't you tell us to
come at four, Conan-kun?
Didn't I say 3:30?
And what's over?
He acknowledged that he attempted
to murder the two men.
But without evidence, I...
Rather, you can't corner the culprit.
And because this culprit is
a very exceptional person,
there is no inconvenient evidence anywhere.
That's not true.
We collected this initially, but
we had no one to compare it to.
Hair...
It was stuck to Fukurokoji-san's
jacket button.
It probably happened then.
We'd like one of your hairs for reference.
I can't believe I left a
trace on that trash's jacket.
Even if it is my hair,
I have plenty of excuses.
But I'd never do anything so unsightly.
After all, it wouldn't be like me
to end the story without beauty.
You...
Who is this man?
Koma-chan, you got a
love letter from a woman?
Koma-chan, what's this about?
Is this a case of misfortune
turning into fortune?
Or a godsend?
All's fish that comes to the net.
All things come to those who wait.
The faithful will be saved.
I guess this means God does exist.
I love you!
Episode Preview
Huh?
Is it some kind of case?
Is the vacant lot past there?
No, we're heading for...
A locked room.
Just saying the word excites me!
All right! Detective Boys, let's move!
I know! I figured it out!
What?
The Detective Boys' Locked
Room Mystery Battle
The next episode of Conan is "The
Detective Boys' Locked Room Mystery Battle!"
Water
Next Conan's hint!
Water!
Gushing water.
Don't miss the next episode.
Hot baths.
Flowing ideas.
Parched throats.