The professor is surprisingly dependable.
I agree.
I had no idea he had such a rich friend.
I was surprised.
Apparently the professor saved their
company with one of his inventions.
That's why they did him this favor.
He makes inventions for
adults sometimes, does he?
That's not a nice way to put it.
Thanks to them, we get to practice soccer.
His joke quizzes can be a
nuisance sometimes, though.
You said the place is the site of
a demolished mansion, right?
Won't it be hard to practice
if the ground is uneven?
It was pouring rain last night, too.
I know.
Lightning struck a few times
and the power went out.
It was scary.
Don't worry.
We'll be fine even after it rained.
Aside from the pool, the ground has been leveled.
The drainage is good, too.
Huh?
Is it some kind of case?
Is the vacant lot past there?
No, we're headed right over there.
Solving crimes with sharp detective skills.
Love and cases never change.
A mysterious locked room with no ceiling.
The Detective Boys hold a mystery battle!
Always determining the one truth with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Detective Boys' Locked Room Mystery Battle
"The Detective Boys' Locked
Room Mystery Battle!"
Professor!
What?
Oh, it's you kids.
Professor, what happened?
A man was found dead in
the pool of this empty lot.
It's a murder?!
Earlier I came to unlock this
place so you kids could get inside.
There was a man floating in the pool.
There was a body in that pool?
Scary.
Does that make you the
first discoverer, Professor?
Yeah, I suppose it does.
We shouldn't get in their way.
Let's talk over there.
Was it a murder or an accident?
Was there water in the pool?
Yes, but it's shallow.
It's from last night's rain.
How big is the pool?
It's for a family, so I think
it's about ten meters.
It's two courses wide.
And this gate is the only
way to get to the pool?
Yeah.
But when I got here,
the gate was locked up tight.
Who has the keys?
According to my friend who lent
us this place, this is the only key.
Then how did the dead person get in?
Inspector Megure is troubled
by that very question.
How did it go?
The entrance has been closed for
the entirety of the past three days.
But the victim died last night before midnight.
Did you determine how he died?
We're waiting on the autopsy for the details,
but we believe he was killed by
a blow to the back of the head.
If it was a murder, then we don't
know how the culprit escaped.
Precisely.
That means this empty lot is a
locked room without a roof!
A locked room.
Just saying the word excites me!
It's fine that you're excited,
but if this is a crime scene,
we can't use it to practice soccer.
But he died in the pool, right?!
We're not going to use the pool!
You think the police will see it that way?
Conan-kun's right.
Both the victim and culprit had to pass
through this lot to get to the crime scene.
Until the case is solved,
it's closed to the public.
What?! Seriously?!
But the game is next week!
Isn't there anything you
can do, Inspector Megure?
I'm sorry, but no.
Though it'd be a different story if
you Detective Boys solved the case.
The inspector is cold.
And the professor went through
the trouble of getting us this lot.
We don't have a choice.
Then let's solve the case!
What?
Inspector Megure said the same thing!
Whoa, now. He was joking.
If we can figure out how the victim got
here, the inspector will consider it!
She's right. Let's do it.
Let's do it!
It's for soccer, Conan-kun!
All right! Detective Boys, let's move!
Wait, where are we going?
Here's a plan of the place
I got from my friend.
Will this help?
It sure will!
This gate was locked, right?
It looks like there's a road on the other side of the fence behind the pool.
There's an eight story building right there.
No, there's a narrow road
running between them.
It's not wide enough for a car, though.
What if you climbed the fence from
that road and entered the lot?
That's impossible.
There's embedded glass and
barbed wire on top of the fence.
Hold on.
I see a crane over there.
It looks like the neighbors are getting
ready for some construction, too.
What if you used the crane, then?
You could hold onto the end and go over the wall.
That's not possible.
The crane arrived this morning.
I know!
The pool must have a drain, right?
You could sneak in through there.
It wasn't large enough for a human.
And it was covered, too.
On top of that, it was covered in garbage.
That's why the rain water built up inside.
Then he must have come from the sky.
If you flew here on a helicopter
and climbed down...
Fly a helicopter at night?
They're really loud.
Hey! What are you doing?!
It's so noisy!
Stop making so much noise!
Hang gliders don't make any noise.
You wouldn't be able to
land in such a small space.
What about RC helicopters?
About ten should do it.
Is it possible to fly that many RC copters?
Wouldn't a hot air balloon work?
Hot air balloons float using
air heated by the burners.
And it was pouring last night.
There was lightning, too.
Then use an airship!
I like airships, too!
This isn't about what you like!
That's fine, but aren't you forgetting
something important?
What? What is it?
Why did he go through so much
trouble to sneak into the pool?
Right?
Well, yeah.
Maybe instead of entering the empty lot,
the victim was trying to sneak
into somewhere else.
You know the answer, but
you're only dropping hints.
What? Sneak into where?
That's it! There was never a murderer!
I see.
He was killed by a blow to
the back of the head, so...
I know! I figured it out!
Damn it!
I'm the only one who doesn't know!
Here's a hint: the pool was empty at first.
What? That's obvious.
The rain last night collected in the pool, so...
That's it!
The victim wasn't hit.
He fell from the neighboring building and
hit his head on the bottom of the pool.
To put it grandly, the weapon was the Earth.
I read a mystery like that once.
All right! We solved the problem.
Let's tell Inspector Megure to
investigate the neighboring building.
Unfortunately, Detective Boys, we
reached that conclusion as well.
Yikes...
You already investigated the building?
We did.
There's no mistaking we did, but...
Through the seventh floor,
all the windows are fixed shut.
There's a bay window on the eighth floor!
He fell from that window!
But that window doesn't open, either.
What?
It won't budge.
I heard some disquieting rumors,
so I had my window altered.
Just yesterday, in fact.
We found that out during our canvassing.
Then where did the dead person fall from?
What about the roof?
That's not it, either.
There's a high fence surrounding the roof, and it's made so no one can enter.
He couldn't have fallen into the pool from there, then.
Yeah.
I don't get it!
Hold on.
Were the disquieting rumors
the old woman heard...?
Oh, that?
It was on the news.
There's a robber breaking into buildings.
I heard about that.
They call him the Gecko, right?
Yeah.
If the man who fell was the Gecko,
then he fell not from a window,
but from the building wall.
They call him the Gecko because
he can climb any wall.
I was so scared.
Of course you were.
How diligent of you to fix your window shut.
We determined the identity of the man.
He was the Gecko.
Where did the Gecko
practice climbing any wall?
By rock climbing, probably.
What? What about bolts?
Rock climbing.
Haven't you seen it on TV?
It's a sport in which people climb
walls using bumps on the wall.
I know what that is.
They just made a training gym in Beika-cho.
Oh, that?
That thing like rock climbing where
they climb walls bare-handed?
According to our investigation, the Gecko
made money working as a street artist.
More words I don't know!
They're people who put on
performances in the city.
The Gecko's trick was crossing from one
building to another on a tightrope.
That's amazing!
But while crossing between two
buildings on either side of a river,
he made a terrible mistake.
After that, he became possessed by fear and
was unable to perform the same trick again.
Unable to earn money,
the Gecko returned home and started
using his agility to break into buildings.
But even if he could climb the walls, he
couldn't break into the buildings, right?
That's it.
He must not have known the
window had been remodeled.
He must have intended to
enter through the bay window.
But if was a veteran thief,
wouldn't he have done his research?
I'm sure he did, but the window
was remodeled yesterday.
I see.
The window hadn't been altered
yet when he did his research.
He struggled his way up the building,
but when the window wouldn't open,
he was surprised and slipped.
Would a professional fall
over something so small?
Now that you mention it,
it does seem unnatural.
But he actually did fall.
It doesn't make sense to us, either.
If we could explain that one
thing, the case would be solved.
It's a shame.
I doubt you'll get to practice
tomorrow, either.
What should we do?
Are we giving up on playing soccer?
What?
Wh-Who said we're giving up?
That's right.
Let's rack our brains one more time.
That's right!
After all, we have a secret weapon!
Right?
What?
She means you.
M-Me?
Witnesses?
Yeah. Were there any witnesses?
Unfortunately, the power was
out in this area at that time.
The substation malfunctioned
because of the lightning.
That must be why.
The Gecko was struck by lightning and fell.
That doesn't make sense.
The lightning would have struck
the top of the building.
No, that.
What?
Huh? What?
There's a lightning rod right there.
There should be a ground wire running from the lightning rod to the ground.
And the Gecko...
But all three lightning strikes
struck the substation.
Really? That's too bad.
Too bad.
What?
Hey, how about this?
The Gecko reached the eighth floor.
Yes, and then?
Then he looked into the
room through the window.
A-And then?
The old woman was there.
And when she turned around...
That's not possible.
I've known her for a while,
but she's a quiet, kind woman.
Her legs are weak, so she uses a cane
and wheelchair to get around.
But she likes keeping tidy, so she's always
doing the laundry when she's got time.
Awaji Tomoe (72)
That's what Awaji is like.
I see.
And the power was out.
He wouldn't have been able to see inside.
Oh, right.
Professor, you've been to the
old woman's room, right?
Sure. I'm the one who introduced
Inspector Megure to her, too.
I'm sorry.
The sofa and curtains are soaking wet.
My hand shook when I grabbed
the hose while doing the laundry.
No one wants to get older.
You came all the way here, but
I have nowhere for you to sit.
We're not staying long, so don't worry.
So, Awaji-san, you didn't notice anything?
No. I'm sorry I couldn't help you.
Everything by the bay window was wet?
But if the power was out, he wouldn't
have been able to see inside.
Sure he could.
What?
If lightning struck, he'd be able to see.
The substation was struck three times.
That's it. I got it.
What? Did they figure something out?
Excuse the intrusion, Awaji-san.
Sorry about the sudden visit.
As you know, this morning
the body of a thief,
known as the Gecko, was found in the
pool of the demolished mansion next door.
At first we thought it was a murder,
but we determined he died when
something caused him to fall
while climbing this building to sneak in,
and hit his head on the floor of the pool.
So why did the Gecko fall?
True to his name, the Gecko committed
several thefts by climbing the wall
and breaking in through windows.
It's hard to imagine the Gecko
falling over a mere slip.
Last night's lightning must
have been quite shocking.
Oh, yes.
You may not have been struck,
but the noise must have been loud.
Yes. I was just starting to do my laundry.
Then the power went out, and you
started to return to the living room.
That's when the lightning struck.
When you looked out the window,
you saw a man stuck to your window.
You reflexively sprayed
the man with your hose.
The window doesn't open, so there's no
way the things outside would get wet.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to do it.
I know.
You're not responsible for
anything that happened.
But until we knew what happened,
we couldn't close the case.
That's all.
You don't need to worry.
Thank you.
Here we go!
There!
Got it!
Pass!
Okay, Ayumi-chan!
No way!
Hey!
How long are they going to keep playing?
Probably until they can't
see the ball anymore.
I see.
Episode Preview
Listen up.
I'm trading this money for Reina's body.
How does the culprit mean to transport the ransom?
Isn't 100 million yen pretty heavy?
Heavy? It's only about ten kilograms.
If they've got a car, it's no problem at all.
They'll be there in ten minutes.
Roger that.
After That 100 Million Yen
The next episode of Conan is
“After That Hundred Million Yen!”
Ants
Next Conan's hint!
Ants!
100 million yen in eel bowls?
Don't miss the next episode.
If one is 2,000, that's 50,000!
That's some fast calculating.