Detective Conan Episode 800 "After
That Hundred Million Yen"
Wait, Detective!
I'm still not convinced.
Tanaka-san.
Don't you agree?
The kidnapper told us,
"Don't tell the police."
"If you do, the child is dead!"
Tanaka Suzuko (50)
Saeki Family Housekeeper
If he finds out you stuck a
GP-whatever in his bag and car,
Saeki Reina (5)
Saeki Family's Only Daughter
there's no telling what the kidnapper
will do to their daughter!
Don't you agree, ma'am?
Yes, but...
Tanaka-san, we understand how you feel.
We want to get Reina-chan back
safely just as much as you do.
We'd appreciate your cooperation so
we don't fall behind in this case.
Suzu-san, we should do as the police say.
Very well.
Saeki Kenzo (55)
Saeki Hiroko (30)
Listen up.
I'm trading this money for Reina's body!
If they say they'll return the hostage
later, don't give them a cent!
But if I refuse, there's not telling what
the kidnapper will do to Reina-chan.
You don't need to refuse.
Just quietly hand him the money.
Hold on, Detective!
That's easy for you to say
since it's not your money,
but we're talking about 100 million here!
If they take my money and I
don't get my daughter back...
But the kidnapper is human, too.
Surely he'll appreciate our
good faith and return her.
Should we really be letting the
housekeeper transport the ransom money?
I hope she doesn't get fired after
doing as the kidnapper says.
I'm off, then.
We're counting on you!
Ma'am!
You have some dust on your sleeve.
Thank you.
Solving crimes with sharp detective skills.
Love and cases never change.
The ransom for a kidnapping case
arrives at a surprising location.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
After That Hundred Million Yen
"After That Hundred Million Yen!"
I have your daughter Reina-chan.
If you want her back, one
hour from now at 10 AM,
have Tanaka Suzuko-san bring 100 million
yen to Beika Central Park by herself.
If you tell the police, the girl is dead.
The car is on its way.
She'll be there in five minutes.
Roger that.
I don't see anyone behaving
suspiciously at the moment.
All right.
Let's go over it again.
If the kidnapper appears with the hostage,
rescue the hostage and
apprehend the kidnapper.
If he appears alone, don't do anything.
We'll let him go and follow him.
Let him go?
Detective, what about the 100 million yen?
Calm down, Saeki-san.
We know what we're doing.
We've done what we need to do.
Let us handle this.
The GPS transmitter is in the bag with the
100 million yen, and there's one on the car.
There's even one in the brooch
Suzuko-san is wearing.
No matter what the kidnapper does...
This is Tanaka.
Yes, I just arrived at the park.
I have the money.
Is Reina-chan all right?
What? The name and birthday of
Reina-chan's ballet teacher?
Why would the kidnapper ask about that?
He's making sure it's the real Suzuko-san.
Her teacher's name is
Ishikawa Miyuki-sensei.
I believe I heard her
birthday is Valentine's Day.
Th-The sandbox?
All right. You want me to dig in the
west corner of the sandbox, right?
The sandbox?
There it is.
I found it!
Yes, there's a map.
Is this the site of the demolished
car factory in Haido-cho?
The kidnapper has a station wagon and new
bag at the demolished Haido-cho factory.
He's going to make her
switch bags and cars there.
The kidnapper must have expected
them to call the police,
and is worried they might
be using transmitters.
Damn it! He's smart.
Get to the demolished factory
and attach transmitters
to the station wagon and
bag the kidnapper prepared.
Do whatever it takes to get it
done before Suzuko-san arrives.
That's the demolished factory.
Is that...?
Inspector! It's too dangerous for the
investigators to approach the car!
Dangerous? What do you mean?
Look!
There's no cover around the
target vehicle anywhere!
The investigators' movements
will be in plain sight!
Got it.
Don't approach the car!
Wait until you receive instructions!
Now we won't be able to use
transmitters on the bag or car.
Hey, mister.
How does the culprit mean
to transport the ransom?
Isn't 100 million yen pretty heavy?
Heavy? It's only about ten kilograms.
If he's got a car, it's no problem at all.
But if he's worried about transmitters,
he should know the police would
make note of the bill numbers.
Well...
There are security cameras
everywhere these days.
He'd be caught immediately if
he tried to use those bills.
Uh...
Inspector, this is Takagi.
Suzuko-san has transferred the ransom,
and she's leaving in the station wagon.
Hello?
Are you familiar with the Matsubara
jewelry store in Kuin-cho?
The Matsubara jewelry store in Kuin-cho?
Yes, I'm familiar.
Use the ransom money to buy a 100
million yen's worth of diamonds there.
What? You want me to buy
diamonds worth 100 million?
I see. He's going to exchange
the cash for diamonds.
Will I really be able to buy diamonds worth
100 million yen without advance notice?
Don't worry.
I've ordered ten diamonds
under President Saeki's name.
Impossible! I didn't order those!
I'll call you later.
The kidnapper put a lot of thought into this.
Ten diamonds can be hidden in a pocket,
and they can be exchanged for money.
For bills with numbers unknown
to the police, no less.
Let's call the jewelry store and
stop them from selling the diamonds.
No, we can't.
We don't want to defy the
wishes of the kidnapper.
Matsubara's an idiot!
We've known each other for years!
It's 100 million!
I'm a regular at his store.
He could have at least checked with me!
Please be careful.
They're worth quite a bit.
I will.
Say hello to President Saeki for me.
Matsubara Akira (50)
Matsubara Jewelry Store Owner
Thank you.
Hello?
Did you buy the diamonds?
Yes, ten diamonds the size
of my pinkie fingertip.
What should I do next?
Head slowly towards Sakura Street,
and turn left at the first traffic signal.
Turn left at the first traffic signal.
Got it.
What's there?
Toto Central Station.
It's a terminal station serving
private rail, TR, and subway lines.
He'll have plenty of escape
routes to choose from.
He could take a long distance bus, too.
Head to Toto Central Station immediately.
We'll be relying on the
information Suzuko-san gives us.
What? I'm not going to Toto Central Station?
Where, then? Tell me.
What's wrong?
Why are you so flustered?
N-No reason.
I just want to see Reina-chan
as soon as possible.
I see. I'd like to release Reina-chan
as soon as possible as well.
But...
Tanaka-san, you're wearing
a wire, aren't you?
I know you are.
You've been repeating me a
lot in our conversations.
At first I thought you were doing it to
confirm what I said, but it seems I was wrong.
You're reporting the situation
to the police, aren't you?
No, I would never.
As promised, we haven't told the police.
Are you sure there isn't
a pin mic in your brooch?
I've been watching you through binoculars
since the beginning, and it's been bothering me.
If you want me to return Reina-chan,
throw it out the car window.
The police will only interfere
with our trade going smoothly.
Very well.
Suzuko-san!
Damn it! It's broken.
She's not answering her phone, either.
Inspector Megure!
What? You lost her?
Yes. The kidnapper prepared
a bicycle beforehand,
and Suzuko-san rode it through the alleyways.
This situation has turned
into what we feared.
In her desperation to save the hostage,
she's lost her sense of judgment.
Where did she take the jewels
worth 100 million yen?
To the kidnapper, of course.
What if the kidnapper and
Suzuko-san are working together?
What?!
Th-Then she ran off with the
jewels worth 100 million yen?
Have she been deceiving us
since yesterday's kidnapping?
That can't be.
Ma'am!
Ch-Child, what are you doing here?
The diamonds.
Where are the diamonds?
He said I'd find a bottle
tied with red ribbon.
He told me to put them in there
and send it down the river.
Are those the kidnapper's instructions?
Yes. I came to this pier because he told me
to, and I found a bottle tied with red ribbon.
I did as he said.
Did you notice anything else unusual?
Now that you mention it, for some reason the
cleanly washed bottle was covered in ants.
Ants?
Yes, a whole bunch of them.
Ma'am, the police are probably worried.
You should call them soon.
Oh, right.
I see. So that's how it is.
Reina! Reina!
Champagne.
You're in a good mood, mister.
Did something good happen?
Wh-What are you doing here, kid?
Mister, did you know there
was a kidnapping today?
No. Was it on the news?
No, I don't think anyone has the story yet.
I see. The jewels were put in a
bottle and sent down the river.
Yeah.
And? Were they able to save Reina-chan?
Yeah. She was released that evening.
That's good.
If after losing the ransom,
their daughter hadn't come home...
That's actually not what happened.
What?
Look. I brought the bottle
with the jewels in it.
And inside...
...are the ten diamonds.
But it's strange, isn't it?
Why did the kidnapper release Reina-chan
if he didn't get the diamonds?
Wh-Who knows?
And the other weird thing is you couldn't
buy ten diamonds this big with 100 million.
They're probably fake diamonds.
I see. Then the housekeeper Suzuko-san
must have swapped them out for fakes.
Suzuko-san must have been
working with the kidnapper.
That's why Reina-chan was released.
You're wrong.
What?
If Suzuko-san were working
with the kidnapper,
then there would be no need to
prepare these fake diamonds.
All she'd have to say was, "I gave
the kidnapper the diamonds."
Y-You're right. Then who?
Don't play dumb.
You're the one who sold these pieces
of glass to her for 100 million.
Matsubara Jewelry Store
owner Matsubara Akira-san.
Wh-What are you talking about?
I did sell diamonds worth 100 million
to the housekeeper Suzuko-san, but—
There are two reasons you chose Suzuko-san
to transport the ransom money.
First, Reina-chan was the
apple of Suzuko-san's eye.
You believed she'd do as you told
her if it was for Reina-chan.
Second, if the wealthy Saeki-san or
his wife had transported the ransom,
they might have figured out
the diamonds were fake.
But the housekeeper Suzuko-san
rarely sees large diamonds,
so you believed it unlikely
that she would figure it out.
After selling her the fake diamonds,
you instructed Suzuko-san to put them in
this bottle, and send it down the river.
If anyone found out the diamonds were
fake, you'd fall under suspicion.
It seems Suzuko-san was
too frightened to notice,
but this bottle is much
lighter than normal bottles.
Even a normal bottle was
unlikely to be collected,
but in order to bring that possibility as
close to zero as possible, you used this bottle.
A sugar glass bottle used as
props in movies and TV shows.
This bottle would melt or be smashed to
pieces while floating down the river.
The fake diamonds would sink to the bottom
of the river and become unrecoverable.
Then you could openly use the
100 million you acquired.
After all, you got the money through
a proper business transaction.
It was a good idea.
Normally, ransoms are handed
over at the very end.
But you tried to collect it while
the ransom was being transported
right under the noses of the police.
Wh-What about proof?
Do you have proof?!
The proof is that bottle.
Sugar glass bottles have limited
uses and a short shelf life,
so each one has to be handmade.
If you trace how the bottle was
acquired, your name will turn up.
Besides, thinking they'd sink
to the bottom of the river,
you probably carelessly handled the fake
diamonds and left your fingerprints on them.
If I break this bottle,
there won't be any proof—
They're here.
Mori Detective Agency
Huh? What's wrong, kid?
Got a cold?
Yeah.
I just felt a chill.
Then take some medicine and stay warm.
Yeah, I will.
Come to think of it, when Ran tried
to wash your clothes this morning,
she said she found a fish in your pocket.
You didn't go swimming in a river, did you?
Y-Yeah, right.
Right.
Not even a kid would do
that in this freezing cold.
That's actually what I did.
Episode Preview
Help me.
The incense burner is missing?
The precious heirloom should be right here.
It's from the thief.
"If you want your heirloom incense
burner back, prepare 10 million yen."
"I'll contact you tomorrow."
You can look forward to it.
I'll make sure this favor is repaid in full.
The Tottori Sand Dunes Mystery Tour
(Kurayoshi Arc)
The next episode of Conan is "The Tottori
Sand Dunes Mystery Tour, Kurayoshi Arc!"
Incense Burner
Next Conan's hint!
An incense burner!
Don't miss the next episode.
Where are you off to in such a hurry?
Not sure. I received an urgent request.
There's another professor!