Tottori Station
Invited by the old man, we've
come to Tottori prefecture.
We're here!
Yeah.
By why Tottori?
Why?
Well, see...
Tottori Sand Dunes
To abandon you in the sand dunes!
C-Conan-kun!
First Super Mystery Award
Mystery of the Sand Dunes
The first Super Mystery Award!
I decided to apply to this.
A kid is tied up and left
alone in these sand dunes.
But how will he escape his dangerous
situation in this suspenseful story?
I'm here to come up with how he does it.
I don't know why you suddenly
decided to write novels...
...but that story won't work.
It won't work?
Yeah.
Because someone would rescue me right away.
Right?
What?
Countless tourists come here.
Then this is a plain old
sightseeing trip now.
We'll start by visiting the
sand museum just over—
Dad!
Solving crimes with sharp detective skills.
Love and cases never change.
Like the sands of the Tottori sand dunes,
the mystery of the robbery
can't quite be caught.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Tottori Sand Dunes Mystery Tour
(Kurayoshi Arc)
"The Tottori Sand Dunes Mystery
Tour, Kurayoshi Arc!"
Sand Museum
Hey!
What is this?
They're just lumps of sand!
You're ripping people off by
making them pay to see it.
R-Ripping them off?
These are works of art.
I wasted my money and time.
That clock is slow.
That can't be.
One...
...oh five.
That clock is right.
Who do you and your pervy
mustache think you are?
Move.
Hey!
What's her problem?
It looked like she was
picking a fight on purpose.
She's probably stressed out.
How is this a ripoff?
How can they build these
ridiculous things out of sand?
After putting them on display for a year,
they tear them down and build something else.
What a waste.
Maybe their transitoriness is
meant to be part of their appeal.
Seeing all this art makes me hungry.
What?
Tottori is known for its pears
and leeks, but most of all...
Crab!
Right?
There's a place nearby
called the Kanikkokan.
Tottori Karo Kanikkokan
I'm going to eat my fill.
Yeah.
But this place...
We can look, but we can't eat?
Seems like it.
Sh-Should we go to Kurayoshi next?
Kurayoshi Station
It's takes about thirty minutes to
get there on the limited express.
Shirakabe Dozo-gun Akagawara Building 10
Thanks for waiting.
I checked our bags.
The Edo and Meiji Era
warehouses are this way.
You can feel the history in this city.
Yamane!
Mori-san?
We worked together once
on a robbery investigation.
When you worked for the MPD, right?
Thank you for help on the case.
Okamoto Ryo (25)
Tottori Police
Kurayoshi Station Detective
Yamane Katsuhiko (36)
Tottori Police
Kurayoshi Station Detective
He's the great detective.
The man our chief is always bragging about.
What's up?
Okamoto.
Yes, sir.
Someone reported a robbery.
What?
They're not answering.
Would it be all right if I looked around?
Yes.
Help me!
What happened?
I'm Yamane of the Kurayoshi Station.
Are you the one who called?
I'm Kumado Shuko.
The eldest son's wife.
And the robber?
I was knocked out, so...
He escaped while you were out, huh?
Thank you for your help.
The incense burner is missing!
The precious heirloom should be right here!
It was stolen?!
I've done something irredeemable.
Don't cry. Tell us what happened.
Huh? There's something on the floor here.
What?
Fool!
You can't even properly
watch the house by yourself?
Kumado Iwao (68)
Head of the Kumado Family
I'm sorry.
Kumado-san.
This is Kumado Iwao, head of the family.
This is the famous detective...
Mori Kogoro.
I happened to be nearby with
my daughter and the boy.
Do I have to introduce my side, too?
My eldest daughter, Makie.
Kumado Makie (35)
Kumado Family's Eldest Daughter
She's divorced.
You didn't need to say that.
My eldest son, Soichi.
He helps me with my business,
but he's completely unreliable.
Kumado Soichi (32)
Kumado Family's Eldest Son
What? Father!
My second son, Junji.
He's an idiot who wastes
all his time goofing off.
Kumado Junji (28)
Kumado Family's Second Son
I can't disagree with that.
And with Soichi-san's wife Shuko-san
and Kazuma-kun, there's six of you.
Anyway, you didn't lock the doors?
I did, but...
Kumado Shuko (29)
Married into the Kumado Family
Around one, after putting Kazuma to bed
and returning to this room, suddenly...
Kazuma!
When I awoke, I was tied up.
I called the police on my cell phone.
And then you noticed it was stolen?
Yes.
It seems only the incense burner was stolen.
The robber only wanted the incense
burner from the beginning.
That's why it's strange.
It was clearly visible, right?
He should've stolen it and run.
There was no need for
him to tie up Shuko-san.
So why did he go to the
trouble of tying you up?
Don't ask me.
There's no way to know what
the robber was thinking.
Stay out of this, boy!
What a terrifying old man.
Have you found any clues?
According to forensics, neither the
front nor back door were forced open.
The robber may have entered
using a spare key.
A spare key?
The robber was someone with access to a key.
And this was found under the sofa.
Shuko-san said it wasn't there
when she cleaned this morning.
We believe the robber left it behind.
It's been bothering me.
Father, wasn't Naomi-san wearing
that pendant yesterday?
Naomi?
She was wearing it yesterday.
Now that you mention it...
I remember that, too!
Who is Naomi?
Senda Naomi.
Until two years ago, she was our housekeeper.
Yesterday, she arrived suddenly
from Tokyo asking for money.
But our dad turned her down.
Who would lend her money?
That unfortunate woman ran off
with our money when she quit!
She ran off with your money?
It wasn't much, so we didn't
submit a damage report.
So she stole our heirloom to get back
at us for not lending her the money.
That sounds like something
that wicked woman would do.
If she was a former housekeeper...
She could have made a spare
key while she worked here.
Do you know where Senda Naomi-san is?
I have her phone number.
What?
Senda Naomi (30)
Kumado Family's
Former Housekeeper
This is Senda Naomi-san?
Hey, pervstache!
You were robbed around one, right?
I'm sure of it.
Then it wasn't her.
We met near the sand dunes around that time.
That's why I said I didn't know.
B-But this...
I dropped it when I came here yesterday.
But when I cleaned this morning—
Why would you lie about that?!
Stop!
Don't lie!
Stop that!
Are you all right?
I'm not lying.
Hello?
A delivery?
I'll be right there.
It's all right. I'll go.
Soichi-san, it's for you.
You always hated me.
So you tried to set me up.
I would never.
Thank you for ganging up on me.
You can look forward to it.
I'll make sure this favor is repaid in full.
She's going to kill me.
What?
You're exaggerating.
In the first place, it's your
fault for making things up.
The battle starts now.
About Senda Naomi-san...
She's a wicked and violent
woman, but she has an alibi.
She's got nothing to do with the case.
Then why was her pendant on the floor?
Because—
Stop asking for instructions
over every little thing!
Why do I even pay you?
Huh? I received an e-mail?
Received Message
from: The Masked Leek
to: Kumado Iwao
Who's the Masked Leek?
It's from the thief.
"If you want your heirloom incense
burner back, prepare 100 million yen."
"I'll contact you tomorrow."
You just said it was worth a million yen.
It was a white lie.
Its commercial value is
no more than 100,000.
But its the symbol of the Kumado family head
that's been passed down for generations.
It's a priceless object.
Get 100 million yen first thing tomorrow.
Y-Yes, sir!
So that's how it is.
I'd like to ask what you were all
doing and where you were around 1 PM.
What? You suspect us?
It may not be worth much, but you
can demand a lot of money for it.
Only family members would know that.
And more damning than anything
is that mysterious pendant.
After Senda Naomi-san dropped it
yesterday, the robber picked it up.
Today they entered the house, robbed it,
and left the pendant behind to make
it look like Senda Naomi-san did it.
I wouldn't put that past you.
Nor you. I'm sure you want
money to fool around.
If we're talking about not having
the money to do what we want,
then you two are in the same situation.
M-Maybe so, but I would never do that!
Oh? All three are starved for money?
That's enough!
And what right does a detective
have to meddle in my affairs?
I just want to help solve the case.
Would that be a problem for you?
Y-You don't think I did it, do you?
Your situation is the same
as that of these three.
This is all your fault, you moron!
You're the reason we're
being suspected over money!
We picked up quite the bad luck charm.
There's no need to say that.
Shuko is a victim!
So what?
Nothing.
I'll make some tea.
Her job as a bride ended when
I received my heir Kazuma.
It must be rough. You don't belong here.
Maybe so, but I can't leave.
My father-in-law has made Kazuma his heir.
He'd do anything to keep him.
If the alternative is being
torn away from Kazuma,
I have to continue staying
with the Kumado family.
Maybe, but...
Everyone has their own reasons.
And a detective can find
the robber, solve the case,
and give Shuko-san some
relief from their criticism.
Mori-san.
Yeah.
The head of the family came to Daigakuin
Temple around noon yesterday.
Daigakuin Temple
This is the grave of Satomi Tadayoshi,
who served as inspiration for
Nanso Satomi Hakkenden.
Every year he offers his services for the
associated festival, so he came to chat.
He was here for about thirty minutes.
Until 12:30.
What did he do after?
He said he'd visit the Akagawara Building 15.
He came around 1:30?
He came to offer advice on our merchandise.
He's passionate about local business.
His crucial alibi for one o'clock is missing.
And his home is a stone's throw away.
Special Express Yakumo
Runs Between Okayama Station
to Izumo-shi Station
Yonago Station
Tottori Hanakairo Flower Park
My sister knows Kumado Makie-san.
That's how you recognized her.
She entered around eleven
and left around three.
Then like she said, around one
she was somewhere in the park.
Assuming she was here the whole
time between eleven and three.
You're right.
The second son Junji-san
wasn't lying when he said
Kaike Hot Springs
he'd been staying here at Kaike Hot
Spring since the previous night.
The problem is yesterday morning
after he checked out of the inn.
He said he stayed around here
and that he had witnesses.
Yonago-shi Tourism Center
This is the man I saw yesterday.
It's definitely him.
Watch where you're going!
But that was around three, so...
It's just like Makie-san.
Misasa Hot Spring
So their alibis are missing
a chunk in the middle.
Yeah. Neither one had a
witness for one o'clock,
so it's possible that they went home once
before returning to where they were.
It takes thirty minutes
to get from Yonago
where the flower park and
hot spring are to Kurayoshi.
So they could all be guilty.
The head of the family, too?
As a local influential figure,
he visited places here and there,
but they're all near his home.
He could have gone home
anytime if he wanted to.
That just leaves Shuko-san's
husband, Soichi-san.
Jinjo no Yakata
That must be the place they mentioned.
Yes. Soichi stopped by because he was
in the area around one yesterday.
He does have an alibi.
It would be painful if the
robber were her husband.
Oh, no. Are you confused?
Yesterday at one we were eating
noodles together, Tanaka-chan.
This morning Soichi asked me to lie.
A detective suspects me in a certain case,
but I don't have any witnesses
to back up my alibi.
Help me, Tanaka. Please!
Why hasn't he called?
The robber can't move.
Not only are the police waiting to
catch him when you make the exchange,
but now there's a detective involved.
You still insist the robber is one of us?
Considering someone asked a friend to lie...
Can't you remember anything about the robber?
He's back.
What are you talking about?
Nothing.
Kotani Yasunobu-san Returns Home
The doctor who unfortunately died in
South Africa at the beginning of the month,
Kotani Yasunobu-san, made
his silent return home today.
Dr. Kotani, who was from Tottori, graduated
from Toto University Medical School...
He's the doctor who had been practicing
medicine there for a long time.
So he was from Tottori.
Did you know him, Shuko-san?
What?
We were high school classmates.
This isn't important right now.
This is Kumado.
Thanks for having me yesterday.
This is Naomi.
Is Shuko there?
This is Shuko.
I'll show you the hell that awaits
people who try to frame someone else.
Why would she say that?
I'll be your bodyguard.
What?
Oh, no. She's probably just harassing me.
Well, if you don't think it's necessary...
Is that woman really not
involved in the case?
But she has an alibi.
It seemed deliberate, though.
I wasted my money and time.
That clock is slow.
Now that you mention it...
It was a coincidence.
When I woke up this morning,
it was in front of the entryway.
He returned it!
What's going on?
Why did the robber return the incense
burner without receiving any money?
This case is no ordinary robbery.
Episode Preview
Therefore, one of you is the robber!
Now that this is back, it doesn't
matter who the robber is.
I wonder why the robber
returned the incense burner.
Wait a minute. This robbery...
Could it be?
What?! They went to see Senda Naomi?!
Oh, no!
The Tottori Sand Dunes Mystery Tour
(Tottori Arc)
The next episode of Conan is "The Tottori
Sand Dunes Mystery Tour, Tottori Arc!"
Pendant
Next Conan's hint!
A pendant!
How was your ride on the camel?
Don't miss the next episode.
Pretty hump-fortable.
Hey, Professor...