Ran, the old man, and I came to Tottori
where we came across a robbery.
Shuko-san, bride of the local
distinguished Kumado family,
was attacked by someone, and their
heirloom incense burner was stolen.
Though former housekeeper Senda
Naomi-san was initially a suspect,
her alibi proved her innocence.
As the old man suspects one
of the family members did it,
for some reason, the stolen
incense burner was returned.
Solving crimes with sharp detective skills.
Love and cases never change.
A robbery with too many mysteries.
Who is the culprit standing on the dunes?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Tottori Sand Dunes Mystery Tour
(Tottori Arc)
"The Tottori Sand Dunes
Mystery Tour, Tottori Arc!"
The culprit has given himself away.
The culprit knew the police would
come if he stole something.
But because he was confident he could
blackmail you for money, he stole it anyway.
However, something unexpected occurred.
The arrival of God's gift
to detectives, Mori Kogoro.
Huh?
Knowing he didn't stand a chance, he gave up.
As I'd expose his identity if he held onto
the treasure, he hurriedly returned it.
And only the members of the
Kumado family know I'm involved.
Therefore, one of you is the robber!
Kumado Junji (28)
Kumado Family's Second Son
So you returned it because the
detective scared you, Sister.
Kumado Makie (35)
Kumado Family's Eldest Daughter
You mean you did.
Or was it my older brother?
Kumado Soichi (32)
Kumado Family's Eldest Son
It wasn't me!
Kumado Iwao (68)
Head of the Kumado Family
That's enough!
Now that this is back, it doesn't
matter who the robber is.
Kumado Shuko (29)
Married into the Kumado Family
I-Indeed.
We can't just let him go.
Okamoto Ryo (25)
Tottori Police
Kurayoshi Station Detective
Yamane Katsuhiko (36)
Tottori Police
Kurayoshi Station Detective
This is a robbery, after all.
I wonder why the robber
returned the incense burner.
What? I told you, he gave up.
It'd be bad if he held onto it,
so he returned it in a hurry.
Then he could have thrown it
away instead of returning it.
Yeah, but...
He's a conscientious thief.
How will we determine
which one of them did it?
We'll follow your theory and
thoroughly investigate their alibis.
There were limits to how
much we could investigate.
Whoever doesn't have an alibi did it.
It's only a matter of time
before we see results.
I'll let them handle that while
I investigate someone else.
Is there anyone who knows a
lot about Senda Naomi-san?
What?
She certainly is suspicious.
I don't know Naomi's acquaintances.
And all her family passed
away a long time ago.
Didn't she say she has an uncle?
What?
Is that right?
I think he works at the Nashikkokan.
Tottori 20th Century Pear Memorial Hall
Nashikkokan
Senda Naomi-san is definitely suspicious.
She seemed to be deliberately
fabricating an alibi.
There's that, too,
but I was wondering why she visited
the house the day before the incident.
She went to borrow money, right?
Hey, I think that's him.
This is one of Japan's greatest
20th century pear trees.
And...
Adachi Kozo (55)
Naomi's Uncle
That's great, but...
You're here about Naomi, right?
I've heard she's deep in debt.
See? That's why she went to borrow money.
But there's no way they'd lend her money.
Who would lend her money?!
That unfortunate woman ran off
with our money when she quit!
Oh, right.
Maybe she had a special reason for going.
Like dirt on a member of the Kumado family.
Hello?
G-Got it. I'll be right there.
I'm sorry. Something seems to have come up.
You have some idea, don't you?
Do you? Tell us.
I once scolded her for gossiping
about the family that employs her.
I saw her secretly meeting
with a man on the sand dunes.
Senda Naomi (30)
Kumado Family's
Former Housekeeper
She puts on a virtuous face, but that
doesn't stop that woman from doing it.
It happened two years ago,
just before she quit.
That idiot! She called it juicy information.
Juicy? He means as blackmail, right?
But was Shuko-san really having an affair?
The problem is she was secretly meeting
a man, and someone witnessed it.
If Naomi-san threatened to tell,
Shuko-san would have no choice
but to pay to keep her quiet.
But Shuko-san doesn't seem
to have that kind of money.
That's it. So that's why.
Shuko-san was tied up during the incident.
Huh? What do you mean?
All four of them have alibis?
There are witnesses who say they saw them
around 1 PM when the incident occurred.
The head of the household Iwao-san,
the eldest daughter Makie-san,
the eldest son Soichi-san, and
even the second son Junji-san.
So they're all innocent?
But only a member of the family had a key
and could have gotten the pendant
Senda Naomi dropped the day before.
Wait a minute. This robbery...
Could it be?
You, too?
It seems I came to the same
conclusion as this kid.
But you both only have your deductions.
At the moment, there's no evidence.
But I think we can overturn the story
that the incident occurred at 1 PM.
Kumado-san, huh?
Yeah, it was exactly at 12:00
when I made my first delivery.
But no one was home, so I left a note.
I got a call later asking to re-deliver
the parcel, so I delivered it again.
Is that all?
Sorry to interrupt your work.
Shuko-san was in a hurry to get
it, so I thought it was strange.
Hello?
What? A delivery?
I'll be right there.
It's all right. I'll go.
It's because she didn't want anyone else to
answer and discover it was a re-delivery.
And that she was home alone, but
couldn't receive the package at noon.
By that time, Shuko-san was probably...
...already tied up.
So that's what happened.
It started two years ago,
when Senda Naomi witnessed Shuko-san
secretly meeting a man on the sand dunes.
Naomi-san began using that
to blackmail Shuko-san.
And each time Shuko-san
desperately raised the money.
But it couldn't last forever.
They plotted to work together to steal the
incense burner and blackmail the family.
After waiting for the family to leave,
Shuko-san hid the incense burner somewhere.
Then she let Senda Naomi
in through the back door,
had Naomi bind her hands and feet, place her
pendant under the sofa, and break the pot.
They decided that she was attacked
by the robber around 1 PM,
and Senda Naomi fabricated
an alibi for that time.
I wasted my money and time.
That clock is slow.
Sorry, Kazuma.
I'll call for help right now.
Shuko-san waited and then called the police.
It was to make us believe she was
tied up because a robber broke in.
The most important part
of this fake robbery
was not letting anyone know
they were working together.
They pretended to fight over the pendant.
They made us believe they were
not accomplices, but enemies.
They're in the same boat.
It's over.
But, mister, why did Shuko-san
return the incense burner?
Huh? I told you, my arrival made her give up.
You think she'd give up that easily?
After all, she needed money, right?
To keep her from talking, right?
And then...
I'll be your bodyguard.
What?
Oh, no. She's probably just harassing me.
If she wanted to make us
believe they were enemies...
It would be normal if she
asked for protection,
because there's no telling
what Naomi-san might do.
Quit babbling!
Once we make her face my reasoning,
we'll know everything!
What? She went to see Senda Naomi?
Yes, just now.
I just received a call from Senda Naomi-san.
She's still upset about the other day.
I'd like to go and apologize.
Go on. Soichi and I will watch Kazuma.
She was invited out by Senda Naomi.
The timing was good, too.
If the incense burner hadn't returned, my
father wouldn't have let her go so easily.
That woman!
Because she messed up this time,
she's plotting her next scheme!
No way!
But if that's true, then Shuko-san wouldn't
tell her family she's going to meet Naomi-san.
Where did she go?!
She mentioned Uradome Coast.
The coast?
I'll stop her!
Did something happen to Shuko?
That's it. Now I get it!
I hope we make it.
The real case is about to happen!
Uradome Coast
Arasuna Shrine
Hand it over already.
I'll give it to you farther ahead.
You're both here.
There's a sheer cliff up there, isn't there?
It'd be awful if you fell.
Let's go some place else.
To the sand dunes
where everything began two years
ago that lead to this fake robbery.
What do you mean by fake robbery?
We can't keep this up anymore, Naomi-san.
I've seen through everything.
She's the one who planned it!
Maybe so, but who pushed her to that point?
What were you going to make
Shuko-san do this time?
What do you mean, this time?
What were you going to...?
Dad.
I knew it.
She acquired 100,000 yen,
so she said she'd give it to you.
That's what Shuko-san said
when she invited you out.
That's right.
What?
It was the other way around.
Shuko-san invited Naomi-san out to
the coast to fulfill her true goal.
So you saw through everything.
What are you talking about?
What do you mean by her true goal, Dad?
Two years ago, why did you secretly
meet with a man, Shuko-san?
If you hadn't done that, you
wouldn't have been blackmailed.
My husband is a good, kind man.
He's also the eldest son of
a local distinguished family.
When we fell in love at first sight and
got engaged, my parents were delighted.
But soon after our marriage,
I realized it was a mistake.
I considered divorce, but when
I thought of my parents...
Then one day, my high school classmate
Kotani-kun invited me out.
You mean the doctor?
At the beginning of this month,
he died in South Africa.
I'm going to South Africa.
It's just like you always said.
Come with me.
What?
I know the situation you're in
because I've always loved you.
I may have considered it
if you had asked sooner.
I have a child inside me.
When I learned that, I decided to
dream only of this child's future.
That I'd give up on everything else.
I see.
I'll pray from a distant country
that you'll have a good child.
Thank you.
Kotani-kun, take care.
He's a handsome man, ma'am.
If they saw this, they'd throw you out.
But because the child inside you is a boy...
By any means necessary, my father-in-law
would take my child from me.
You didn't want to be
separated from your child.
The blackmail taking advantage
of that feeling began then.
But there were limits to how
much money you could raise.
In the first place, hush money
was only a temporary solution.
That's why you came up with a way
to keep her eternally silent.
What? Then Shuko-san's true goal...
You were trying to kill me?
I thought I had no choice.
But there must have been something
that made you make up your mind.
I thought it might be the
report on Kotani-san's death.
The doctor who suffered an unfortunate death
in South Africa at the beginning of the month,
Kotani Yasunobu-san, made his
silent return home today.
So that man was a doctor named Kotani.
When she learned his true identity,
I feared I'd never be able to escape.
So you decided to kill her.
Then you came up with this fake robbery
as a way to get away with murder.
What does he mean?
I presented the idea to Naomi-san.
We'll steal the heirloom incense burner,
and blackmail the Kumado family
for a large sum of money.
I promised to give her all
the money if she'd let it go.
Even if the police got involved,
as long as they got the money together,
she said she's steal it in the night.
Believing her story,
you returned to Tottori to help her with
her plan and carried out the fake robbery.
And this went just as planned as well.
Why would you lie about that?!
Stop!
Don't lie!
You can look forward to it.
I'll make sure this favor is repaid in full.
She's going to kill me.
You thought it was a plan to make it
seem like you weren't accomplices.
That's what we discussed.
It was something else entirely.
Shuko-san's aim was to lie about giving you
the money, invite you out to the coast, and...
Hand over the money.
Once she fulfilled her goal, Shuko-san...
No matter how much I apologized, Naomi-san
wouldn't forgive me for the other day.
She threatened to push me off the cliff.
I was desperate to protect myself.
Before I knew it, I...
You did say she might kill you.
I wouldn't put it past that violent woman.
This is a case of self-defense.
You're not in the wrong.
We, the police, know that
better than anyone.
You planned to murder Naomi-san and escape
punishment by claiming self-defense.
This fake robbery was planned
entirely for that purpose.
You mean I was called back to
Tottori just so I could be killed?
But to carry out this plan,
you had to go out alone.
However, the head of the
household wouldn't leave
amidst the tension caused by
the missing incense burner.
That's why she returned the incense burner.
And that's why you turned
down our protection.
She wouldn't be able to move if
a detective were following her.
But it was all for nothing.
You saw through everything.
But, Dad...
Yeah. It's not attempted murder.
But she actually tried to kill me!
She didn't!
She only planned it, but she
didn't lay a finger on you!
But the result is the same.
What?
We can't pretend the fake
robbery didn't happen.
I'll be tried for that crime.
Because I stole their precious
heirloom incense burner,
I'll be kicked out of the Kumado family.
I'll be separated from Kazuma!
No...
And there's nothing a detective can
do about another family's matters.
You have me!
I'll cut ties with my family.
I'll make my brother Junji
take over the Kumado family.
You, Kazuma, and I can start
a new family together.
Darling...
You may not have noticed,
but I really do love you.
Don't push me!
Okay.
Shuko!
I'll wait for you with Kazuma.
Okay.
That's great.
Mori-san, I truly am proud of you.
Dad! Did you hear that?
Probably not.
Crab, gonna eat crab...
What?
On the other side of there, isn't it...
The ocean.
Mister!
Dad!
Episode Preview
Is that—?!
Seriously?
Is it true, Genta-kun?
I'm sure of it.
When I go to buy an eel lunch, he always
buys an extra large seaweed lunch.
Him! That's him!
Hey, want to get some eel?
What about the arson?
Who's there?
Edogawa Conan, a detective.
The Pitfall of Fire Precautions
The next episode of Conan is "The
Pitfall of Fire Precautions!"
Children's Park
Next Conan's hint!
A children's park!
Don't miss the next episode.
Dad...
Fire!
Make sure you're careful around it.