Fire safety!
This feels so nostalgic.
It's like a historical drama.
No, this is what you call Showa.
I can't believe grade school kids are
talking about nostalgia and the Showa era.
Anyway, it's been bothering me.
There's been a string of them, right?
You mean the arson cases.
There was one four days ago,
and another two days ago.
And once every two days means...
Yeah. Tonight—
What's going on?
Is that...
Seriously?
Hello? There's a fire!
Yes! Something's on fire!
Was that man we saw earlier...?
He could be the arsonist.
No way.
Huh?
I know that guy.
What?!
Solving crimes with sharp detective skills.
Love and cases never change.
The hand of an arsonist sneaks up on a
children's park free of fire hazards.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Pitfall of Fire Precautions
"The Pitfall of Fire Precautions!"
Is it true, Genta-kun?
I'm sure of it.
When I go to buy an eel lunch, he always
buys an extra large seaweed lunch.
That's not what I meant.
You're sure he's the arsonist
from yesterday, right?
If he's someone else,
we could get in trouble.
Found it.
Series of Fires at Children's Park
Culprit on the Run
Fourth Incident Produces Casualty!
That's last year's case.
It's been bothering me, too.
It's been happening at the same places,
including yesterday's location.
Yeah. They're children's parks in
a three by three kilometer area.
The fires started over
the course of two weeks.
Though the fourth case produced a casualty,
and the suspect was never
arrested, the incidents stopped.
And one year later, in the same places
using the same methods, it's started again.
It could be a copycat.
Yeah, but it could also be that
last year's arsonist is back.
Him! That's him!
Shh! Not so loud, Genta-kun!
That's definitely the man from yesterday!
Kamaishi Suguru (25)
Job-hopper
The usual, please.
Sure thing. Your usual extra large
seaweed lunch, coming right up.
Yatabe Harue (48)
Part-time Employee
Your kinpira is the best.
No, I'm not just saying that.
Seriously? You're giving me that much extra?
Aw, shucks!
Is it because we're both left-handed?
Here's your change.
Thank you, ma'am!
You're hopeless.
You should eat a salad sometime.
Whoa! Have I set a flame in your heart?
Am I the arsonist of forbidden love?
What?
Just kidding!
See you later.
He's goofing around.
He's definitely suspicious.
Let's expose his true identity.
The Detective Boys are on the case!
Yeah!
What are you going to do?
Shouldn't we let the police handle this?
What? Yeah, I guess...
But he was only near the
scene of the crime yesterday.
Then we'll have to make sure.
Yeah.
I'm hungry.
You just had three pork buns
from the convenience store!
I should've had an eel lunch, too.
Yeah, yeah.
What are we going to do if he goes to bed?
So far the fires have been
happening every other day,
so there might not be one tonight.
Uh, oh.
He went to bed.
Oh, well.
Okay, let's go.
We lost him.
Damn.
Where did he go?
Through the third incident yesterday, the
fires have been starting in the same places.
If the fourth is about to occur, then...
It'll be in the same place as the fourth fire.
Hey, wait!
Let's go, Genta-kun!
But I'm hungry...
This is where the fourth fire started.
Last year, the first victim was found here.
A drunk office worker sleeping while
wrapped up in a construction tarp died.
Parks are creepy at night.
They should add more lights.
It's still pretty bright since
there's a high-rise apartment.
But with all these people living
here, were there really no witnesses?
It is on the side of the north-facing alley.
It's out.
That was close...
We escaped by a hair.
We're saved.
Are you okay?
The arsonist!
Hey, I just saved you. Don't call me that.
Wait, damn. He got away again.
Again?
Is that what happened yesterday, too?
Yeah. I was so close.
Why?
What?
Did you think this could be
related to last years fires, too?
Is that why you've been on the lookout?
Uh, yeah.
So why would you do that?
Because...
It's only natural.
If it is the same person as last
year, I need to catch him myself.
And who are you kids, anyway?
We're...
The Detective Boys!
The Detective Boys?
Thank you for rescuing us from danger.
Sorry for mistaking you for the arsonist.
You should've said something sooner, mister!
We're on the same side!
The same side?
Yeah, that's right!
I'm a one-man detective squad who rose up
to protect this city from the evil arsonist!
A one-man detective squad?
I don't think you need "squad"
if there's only one of you.
I see.
That's all for today.
I'd better be going, then.
What?
You're leaving?
What about the arsonist?
Leave it to the one-man detective squad!
It's too dangerous for just you kids!
We should work together.
We're protecting the city.
Don't be so standoffish, mister!
Is there some reason that
wouldn't be good for you?
O-Of course not.
Then it's decided!
Our new detective team has been formed!
All right!
Sheesh. I don't have time for kids—
What?
Good morning!
Yeah...
Sumire Park
This is the scene of the first fire.
Last year that swing was set on fire.
And this year it was this seesaw.
So, what are we doing here?
We're reviewing the case.
For example, how did the fire start?
And we'll find witnesses to question.
If there were witnesses,
wouldn't the police have arrested
the arsonist a long time ago?
Right, mister?
Well, yeah.
Anyway, I haven't had breakfast yet.
Me, neither!
You had your breakfast!
I did, but I'm already hungry again!
Damn.
What are we going to do?
The police would have already
conducted a general investigation.
Yeah, you're right.
Tsutsuji Park
Last year, these monkey bars were set on fire.
And that arched bridge was the second fire.
Indeed.
Man, I'm hungry.
Maybe I'll have some ramen.
Me, too!
Toward Beika
It's not time for lunch yet, Genta-kun!
The investigation comes first!
You, too, mister!
Sorry, sorry.
Himawari Park
This is the third and the day
before yesterday's crime scene.
The jungle gym was set on fire.
Last year it was that horse.
Aw, I'm hungry.
Eel
Hey, want to get some eel?
What?!
Yeah!
Walking
Is this a coincidence?
Is something wrong?
Wow, wow, wow!
Th-This looks delicious!
And I got extra!
Are you sure we can have some, too?
Don't be shy.
I got paid.
Thank you.
I'll order you some eel liver soup, too.
Eat up.
Excuse me!
Thanks for the food!
Damn it!
Damn.
He got us.
Yeah.
What's wrong, you two?
Huh? Where is he?
He gave us the slip.
Gave us the slip? Why?
Maybe there's some reason
he doesn't want us around.
What do you mean?
Could it be?
N-No way! Does that mean he's...
The arsonist?!
Closed
He tricked us.
How mean.
It was tasty, but I won't forgive him.
His obsession did seem unnatural.
Because...
It's only natural.
If it is the same person as last
year, I need to catch him myself.
Either way, he's definitely
connected somehow.
Oh, right.
Last year...
Fourth Incident Produces Casualty!
This is...
What's wrong?
Guys, let's go!
Conan-kun?
Ai-chan!
H-Hey, wait!
This is yesterday's crime scene.
You guys stay there.
What?
I knew it.
I see. So that's how it is.
So where did the key figure go?
That's the question...
Huh? That's it!
Ninja Fortress
Yesterday we couldn't see
since it was nighttime,
but this isn't a coincidence.
It's a countdown.
What do you mean?
These letters circled in red
were left at every crime scene.
At the first scene...
What are we going to do?
The police would have already
conducted a general investigation.
Yeah, you're right.
Houses for Lease
Suppose you read that character as "to."
To
At the second scene...
Man, I'm hungry.
Maybe I'll have some ramen.
Toward Beika
He
"He."
At the third scene...
Hey, want to get some eel?
Walking
Ho
"Ho."
And this is the fourth crime scene.
Ninja Fortress
Ni
"Ni."
To, he, ho, ni...
Is it counting down
"irohanihoheto" backwards?
Irohanihoheto
Tohehoni
Yeah. In other words, the
crimes will continue.
He's planning a fifth one.
It was the same last year.
But after someone died
during the fourth incident,
he was either frightened or scared off by
the investigation, and canceled his plans.
At the fifth crime scene, there's probably...
But why does he always
choose children's parks?
And set fire to playground equipment
like seesaws and slides?
Could it be?
Iroha Toys
This is...
Iroha Toys...
Iroha Toys
Here, too?
It's here, too!
And on this!
They all say Iroha Toys!
I knew it.
It's likely the equipment burned at the other
parks were made by the same company, too.
Look.
Iroha Toys
Their factory is nearby.
What does this mean?
Do you know where he went?
Do you know where the next one will be?
Yeah, the location of the
fifth and final fire.
It's closed because it's Sunday.
Isn't that...?
Look.
The arsonist!
He's left-handed!
It's him after all!
Haibara, dial 110 and 119.
Got it.
Hey!
Conan-kun!
Where are you going?!
The police will be here soon!
Wh-Who are you?
Edogawa Conan, a detective.
You should give yourself up,
arsonist and lunch shop lady.
What?!
No way!
Then what about the guy?
They're both left-handed, but she's the
one who could drive that van, not him.
I knew it.
Why, ma'am?
Here's your change.
Thank you, ma'am!
You're hopeless.
You should eat a salad sometime.
Is this kerosene?
Yeah, right.
Closed
Ma'am...
Where'd she go?
A year and a half ago, a child playing
at the park was badly injured
because of a defect in
the equipment made here.
The company dumped all the blame on me,
the factory manager, fired me,
and denied all knowledge of the matter.
It was no joke!
You were the factory manager?
Why did you leave behind
the Iroha countdown?
Why bother?
To get my revenge.
To make them regret what they did.
If they'd offered a single
apology, I would have stopped.
But it looks like you were
the only ones who noticed.
I'm an idiot.
Don't be ridiculous!
Because of you, a man is dead!
Have you forgotten?
Is this for real? Is this for real?!
I seriously thought your
kinpira was delicious.
I loved it.
Arrest me, too.
What?
You actually witnessed last
year's fourth fire, right?
What?
Yeah, the kid's right.
No way.
Seriously?
But why?
This.
Nearby House Robbed!
A robbery?
Yeah. I did that.
You did?
He's a thief.
That's right.
And that place was the scene of his crime.
Right next to the crime
scene where the man died.
Since then, I've quit robbing houses,
but I was afraid of being arrested.
I didn't report it until now.
I told myself I didn't see the arsonist's
face clearly and lied to myself.
But I always regretted it, thinking
that if I'd turned myself in then,
the arsonist would have been arrested sooner,
and that man would have been avenged.
Then the fires started again.
That's why I decided to capture the
arsonist myself and then turn myself in.
But anyway, I'm surprised you noticed, kid.
Huh? Oh, that's because...
You asked the old man for help, right?
Yeah, that's right.
When I explained the thief's methods,
and your actions to him over the phone,
the Sleeping Kogoro figured it out.
The Sleeping Kogoro?
I see. So that's how it was.
There's no way I could escape him.
He sure got me!
And so, peaceful nights returned to the city.
The news reported that the
playground equipment accident
that happened a year and a half ago that
sparked everything was being re-investigated.
Fire safety!
I know.
Episode Preview
No way.
Seriously?
I know about you, too.
What?
I already did that.
What about this cameraman?
What's he doing here?
I'm the one who chose Iwami.
Conan and Ebizo's Kabuki Juhachiban Mystery
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "Conan and
Ebizo's Kabuki Juhachiban Mystery, Part One!"
Ichikawa Ebizo
Next Conan's hint!
Ichikawa Ebizo!
Don't miss the next episode.
Next year is...
...Detective Conan's...
...20th anniversary...
...exciting kabuki experience.
One hour long.