Ladies and gentlemen, Happy New Year!
On behalf of the Conan family,
I'd like to thank our viewers for their support
which has enabled us to make it to 2016.
2016 Detective Conan TV
Broadcast 20th Anniversary
This year also marks the 20th anniversary
since Conan first began airing.
To thank you for the last twenty years,
we've prepared a number of special plans.
First among these are two
weeks of one hour specials.
We hope you enjoy the first and second parts.
Our appropriately super
duper special guest is here.
I am Ichikawa Ebizo.
Ichikawa Ebizo XI
And now, our two-part New Year's Special,
which we present to you for your enjoyment.
With the same feelings we've
always held still in our hearts,
we fly powerfully into our twentieth year.
In the brilliantly gorgeous world of
kabuki, a legendary mask summons a case.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Conan and Ebizo's Kabuki Juhachiban Mystery
(Part One)
"Conan and Ebizo's Kabuki
Juhachiban Mystery, Part One!"
Over here, Mitsuhiko!
There!
Hey!
What were you aiming for?!
You suck!
What? That was my best shot of the day.
You should've passed.
What are you doing?
Why do boys like playing with balls so much?
Who knows?
Mitsuhiko, don't trap it! Volley!
Here I go!
You never disappoint me.
Brake fluid?
There's a railroad crossing up ahead.
Call someone.
I know.
Idiot!
This is bad.
What?
Toto Paper Recycling Plant
Someone clearly messed with the brakes.
Hosoo Takuya (47)
HO Holdings President
I know that, but I'm in a hurry today.
Why don't you take your time telling
us about what happened at the station?
I'm sorry, but I really don't have the time.
Can I open the trunk?
Hey, kid!
Conan-kun!
What on earth did you do?
I'm terribly sorry this happened
because of my lack of supervision.
I tell him every day not to bother
other people, but this brat never—
I mean, this child never listens.
Will you forgive us?
What are you talking about, Mori-san?
What? Didn't the car crash because he
flew into traffic on his skateboard?
No. This boy stopped my car
when it was out of control.
What? Really?
But Sonoko called to say
she happened to see it.
Sonoko! Sonoko, where are you?
The brakes were manipulated
so they wouldn't work.
What? That's attempted murder.
We should secure the scene
immediately and get forensics here.
That's what we were doing.
Oh, right.
Sonoko.
Hey, kid. Nice work.
You're always jumping to conclusions.
But the car crashed after the
kid jumped into the street.
I thought he was finally
showing his true colors.
What does she think of me?
Are you President Suzuki's daughter?
Hosoo-san?
You know each other?
My dad is a huge kabuki fan.
I've met him a bunch of times
at kabuki after-parties.
So he works in the kabuki world.
You don't seem like you'd have
anything to do with kabuki, though.
I've dined with Ebizo-san
a bunch of times, too.
Seriously?
No way!
Ebizo? Is that sushi restaurant any good?
So ignorant.
What are you talking about, Dad?
She's talking about Ichikawa Ebizo-san.
So it's a sushi restaurant in Ichikawa?
Kogoro-ojisama, that's enough.
Kogoro-san?
Are you Mori Kogoro-san?
The famous detective?
Yes. I am the great detective Mori Kogoro.
Can I help you?
What a coincidence.
Ebizo-san is actually a big
fan of yours, Mori-san.
Really?
I've never been to that
sushi restaurant, though.
The brakes?
You mean it wasn't an accident?
The police are investigating that right now.
I'll have to go talk to them later,
but I can't not deliver this.
Takahashi Hitoshi (40)
Hosoo's Secretary
Last night, weren't you the
last one to leave the garage?
Yes.
Did you notice anything strange then?
Like what?
Like suspicious characters
or something like that.
No, I would have noticed if there were.
No Performances Today
Yabusaki Yoshiyuki (57)
President
Hosoo-san, I've been waiting for you.
I brought some acquaintances with me.
Is that all right?
Of course.
I'm Yabusaki, the president.
Nice to meet you!
The president? Like of a bank?
In the kabuki world, the person who manages
all the actors is known as the president.
I'm not surprised she knows so much.
Say something, please!
They're all here.
This calls for celebration!
It's Ebizo-sama.
What play are they doing?
It's "Nanatsu Men"
of the Kabuki Juhachiban.
"Nanatsu Men"?
Ichikawa Ebizo II performed it in 1742,
but it hasn't been performed that often.
What's it about?
In recent years, it was
performed in 1893 and 1983.
And seven years ago, Ebizo-sama
performed it himself.
It's set in the mansion
of Major General Yoshida.
The mask maker Gagoze Akaemon—that's
Ebizo-sama's role—
is being awaited by Princess Sakura.
Who's Princess Sakura?
But first, who's Akaemon?
Akaemon arrives...
Answer me!
And he takes masks out of five boxes
and dances according to each one.
What are the five masks?
What? Uh...
Found it.
The old man, the clown, the Hannya demon,
the old woman, and finally the Buaku demon.
It's a symbol of evil.
Then there's Kumei-something-something...
In any case, he's a bad guy.
While he's trying to steal
the Yoshida family treasure,
Akaemon appears while
wearing the Buaku mask.
Saemon is shocked, and the boxes are
closed and can't be opened again.
Is that what's written there?
Shut up, kid.
In any case, it's an incredible play.
If the title means Seven Masks,
then why are there only five boxes?
You shut up, too, old man.
"Nanatsu Men" is a complicated play.
Complicated?
Yes. I heard the only script was lost
in a fire during the Edo Period.
Nanatsu Men
They didn't have copy machines back
then, and it wasn't copied by hand.
Then the story that exists today...
It was passed down from person to person,
so it's a bit different from the original.
Who cares as long as it's interesting?
It's not like anyone saw
the first performance.
Well, it was performed during the Edo Period.
And so Ebizo-san decided to
create a modern "Nanatsu Men".
We're working pretty hard on it.
I won't bite.
Hosoo-san, I've been waiting for you.
Ebizo-san, it's Sonoko!
Sonoko who?
I'm Suzuki Sonoko.
Oh. Oh, right.
No way.
Sorry I'm late. Here it is.
Let's open it over there.
Ebizo-sama...
Everyone else, gather round.
Sonoko.
So this is it?
The two-faced mask.
Is it real?
Exciting, isn't it?
Who will open it?
That's obvious.
Iwami Shinnosuke (29)
Playwright
Ebizo-san, open it.
Kaneko Eiji (37)
Cameraman
Hold on. I'll get a different angle.
Hey, be careful.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm opening it.
This is it?
It's beautiful.
It's a miracle.
Splendid.
This must be the angle.
This two-faced mask...
The expression changes based
on your viewing angle.
It's impressive.
This mask was made during
the Kamakura Period.
We don't know who made it,
but it's made from the
very same wood used
to restore the Buddha at Todaiji
Temple between 1185 and 1195.
In other words, it was made from the
wood leftover from making the Buddha.
Even trees have DNA, huh?
Our president bought it
from a foreign collector.
What? For how much?
At least a hundred million—
Takahashi.
The amount doesn't matter.
We can't have Japanese cultural
assets going overseas.
Previously, Hosoo-san showed
me the two-faced mask,
so I decided to use it in this play.
You're performing "Nanatsu Men"
of the Kabuki Juhachiban, right?
Ebizo-san, why did you decide
to perform "Nanatsu Men"?
Conan-kun!
I'm so sorry. Oh...
I'm Mori Ran.
Don't try to push yourself on him.
Dad, be quiet.
Conan-kun?
Mori Ran-chan?
Dad?
Which means you must be Mori Kogoro-san!
Since you're such a big
fan, I brought him here.
I'm so happy!
Wh-Why?
I can't believe Ebizo-sama
is a fan of the old man.
There, there.
I'm a huge mystery fan.
While performing in London, I went
to Baker Street every chance I got.
I've always admired the detective
skills of the Sleeping Kogoro.
I-Indeed! I don't know what to do
with all the admiration I receive.
Mister, your Japanese is off.
Conan-kun.
Huh?
I know about you, too.
What?
I clearly remember when
you defeated Kaito Kid.
Grade School Student Wins Again!!
Kaito Kid fails and flees
Is he the Kid Killer?!
You'll grow up to be a detective, too.
Wow, you think so?
Earlier you asked why I chose "Nanatsu Men".
Yes.
People wear all kinds of masks.
Kindness, rage, and jealousy.
And I'd like to try to expressing those.
I suppose it's a human mystery.
That's wonderful.
I'm on my way to the rehearsal space.
Mori-san and everyone else,
would you like to come with me?
Oh, we should get—
Yes, please!
Okay, I get it!
Ran-neechan, he's going to pass out.
Interesting.
I'll hold onto this.
Is the rehearsal space in another building?
No, it's above us in the kabuki theater.
This is it.
Rehearsal Space
Wow, the floors are sparkling.
Good morning.
I'll go put this in a locker.
Thank you.
Good morning.
Do we have guests today?
It's the great detective Mori Kogoro-san.
Mori Kogoro? You mean the Sleeping Kogoro?
What's a detective doing here?
Has there been a murder?
Don't say that. He's just here to watch.
For this part, look at me before standing.
Got it.
Should I say my line after?
Yes, once you've stood up completely.
And when you say this line,
try to threaten me more.
That was too gentle.
Okay. I'll think about it.
Are kabuki stories becoming
more and more modern?
Do you know what a star system is?
The most important thing in kabuki is to draw
out the acting skill and appeal of an actor.
To make this a true Ebizo-san performance,
we all work on the script
and performance together.
So it's always fresh.
Brand spanking new.
Naturally, while maintaining the
specialty of the Ichikawa school.
President.
Don't bother the actors.
I'm not an amateur.
It's too late for that.
I'm already this involved.
Don't be so stingy and tell me.
This always happens.
I don't have the authority to tell you.
Is that Mori-kun?
It's Megure.
I-I-Inspector!
I just received forensics' report.
They found several sets of prints on the car.
What? Are you sure?
Want me to stop?
Not at all. Keep going.
So it was the brake hose.
Since it was deliberately manipulated,
they were trying to kill him.
That's the obvious answer.
We want to investigate
the garage at his home.
If he's with you, could
you bring him with you?
Got it, boss.
Hosoo-san, the police called.
They want to talk to you at your home.
Quickly, to the hospital.
Are you all right?
Iwami? What's wrong?
He suddenly seemed to be in pain.
In any case, we need to
get him to the hospital.
Good plan.
Takahashi, take my car.
Y-Yes, sir.
Maybe this was too much for him.
I know he's an up-and-coming playwright,
but he can't rewrite "Nanatsu Men".
I'm the one who chose Iwami.
I have faith in his abilities.
Really? Sorry, then.
As you can see, that's all for today.
Yes, sir.
Good work.
Conan-kun.
Are you interested in kabuki now?
Yeah, I'm super interested.
I'd like to come back
again. Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah, I'd love to come back.
Ebizo-oniichan, would that be okay?
That's fine.
Come hang out again.
It's no wonder he's Ichikawa Ebizo XI.
He's in a class of his own.
Last night we had a meeting at
the office, and then I went home.
Did you take the same car then?
Yes, though my secretary
Takahashi was driving.
Tomorrow I'm going to stop by Ebizo-san's
place before going to the office.
I'll take this car, so you
take the station wagon.
Yes, sir.
When I get home, Takahashi always cleans
the inside of the car before leaving.
How long did Takahashi-san
stay here after that?
I was in my study, so I don't
know when Takahashi left.
He didn't even say goodbye?
What about security cameras?
The camera that covers this
area would be over there.
It's recording, right?
Of course.
Could you show us the tape?
This way, please.
It's on a hard drive, so between all ten,
I have seventy-two hours of footage.
Conan-kun.
Let's leave so we don't get in their way.
I knew this would happen.
Anyway, his house is incredible.
I'd love to live here.
Cleaning it would be brutal, Ran-neechan.
Oh, right.
And it's not like anyone would help me.
A convenience store, huh?
That place...
If I could afford to live there,
I'd have maids to clean for me.
She's still thinking about that?
Hello?
Yeah, I'm awake.
That's why you called me, right?
Yeah. Yeah, got it.
I'll do some research.
It's fine. I have my methods.
Stop complaining.
You want information, right?
I already did that.
What about this cameraman?
Okay.
Got it. The playwright, too.
I'll send it to your phone by morning.
What? What are you talking about?
I'm not interested.
Yeah, yeah. Good night.
Ebizo
What should I wear?
Good morning.
President, good morning.
You're early.
We've got practice this morning.
There's a lot to do before props arrives.
Good work.
What?
Wh-What's wrong?
It's gone.
The two-faced mask I left in here is gone.
Who is it?
Hello?
Hosoo-san. Why are you calling
so early in the morning?
Yes.
What?
I understand. I'll be right there.
What's wrong?
Was that Hosoo-san?
Yeah.
His secretary Takahashi-san
committed suicide.
Mori-kun.
I asked him to come.
Why did Takahashi-san commit suicide?
We aren't sure it's a suicide yet.
Excuse me.
Mori-san.
I heard you're not sure it's a suicide.
Did you find something?
This is it.
What is this string?
It was wrapped around the
radiator's electric fan.
As you can see, it's cut.
And?
It was wrapped around Takahashi-san's neck.
His neck?
That's awful. If the string hadn't snapped...
From here, he passed it through the driver
seat's headrest and wrapped it around his neck.
The end was tied to the steering wheel.
I see.
So when the engine was started, the
string was wound in and strangled him.
I'm amazed he was able to start the car.
It doesn't look like he
was strangled right away.
What?
The radiator's electric fan doesn't
start right after the engine.
Oh, right.
It takes time for the coolant to
heat up and trigger the sensor.
Yes, especially during this
season when it gets cold.
It takes time for the fan to start moving.
Why? Why go through the trouble?
Was he afraid?
Wait, no.
It's murder.
I knew it.
You don't need a time lag to kill yourself.
Every once in a while, we agree.
But first, we need to determine
the cause of death.
If we're not careful, something
weird might come out of his stomach.
You mean it might not be strangulation?
The two-faced mask was in that case.
How long have you been here?
I-I'm not sure...
This happens every time.
Children shouldn't see this kind of stuff.
Hey, wasn't the mask in that case?
Are you listening?!
I'm listening.
I know what I saw.
Yesterday, President Yabusaki
put it in that case.
I'll hold onto this.
The kabuki theater.
We work at the same company.
You can't right now.
But...
Please try to understand.
Please.
Shoji Yukari (32)
HO Holdings Accounting Secretary
Miss.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Shioji-kun.
Sir.
Did Takahashi-san really...?
I see.
Good morning, Detective Shiratori.
Ah, Conan-kun.
The mask is missing?
You're always quick to figure things out.
Minowa Takuzo (55)
Security Guard
What's wrong?
They took my finger prints.
Do they think I did it?
No, they'll take prints from
everyone who entered this room.
The boy is right.
If we find anyone else's fingerprints,
it will help to advance the investigation.
Really?
Though I doubt we'll find anything this time.
You didn't find any?
No. Apparently the culprit wore vinyl gloves.
According to Tome-san, if they were leather,
they would have left behind
a print of their texture.
Vinyl gloves?
Those are easily acquired.
Was the mask in there?
It's Yabusaki-san's locker.
He discovered it was missing this morning.
Mister, can I ask you a question?
What is it?
From here to the side entrance...
Hey, Detective.
Ebizo-san.
Have you figured anything out?
Mori-san is saying Takahashi-kun
didn't commit suicide.
Yeah.
Not only has there been a theft,
but now there's a murder, too.
We're not sure yet, but if it was a suicide,
don't you think it's weird the two-faced
mask wasn't in the case left in the car?
You're right.
If Takahashi stole it himself,
it would have to be in there.
A third party clearly took it from the scene.
Did they want to sell it
or keep it for themselves?
It has to be someone who knows
the value of the two-faced mask.
And someone who knew the mask
was in the president's locker.
That narrows it down quite a bit, doesn't it?
Yeah.
Is there something bothering you?
The locker was opened really violently,
but all the other locks are pristine.
The other locks?
Yeah.
Minowa-san left last night at 23:30.
The entire building's security
system was activated,
and the front door was
locked at the same time.
Plenty of people have cards,
but if only Minowa-san and the receptionist
have keys to the lock beyond that...
They're a master lock picker?
That's what it would mean.
They entered without damaging
a modern cylinder lock,
so why would they pry open such
a simple locker with a bar?
I see. It certainly is odd.
So it was someone able to acquire the key.
Apparently they know where the
security cameras are located, too.
What? You can even tell that?
Ah, right. You've been
searching for that route.
Yeah.
There are cameras in here, and while the
security is tight around the dressing rooms,
I could make it to the room with the locker
without being seen as long
as I didn't use the elevator.
I guess that makes sense.
After all, there's nothing
valuable in the president's room.
Do you know what this is?
What do these numbers mean?
Minowa-san said it's the
code to the front door.
This morning it was on
the floor of that room.
Why didn't he give it to the police?
Could Mori-san investigate this for me?
The police suspect me, right?
But they don't.
He was serious.
What?
Look on the back.
The back?
It's the script from our
previous performance.
This is a script?
Cutting up scripts we don't need
and using them as notepaper.
The playwright Iwami did that.
Your seatbelt.
Got it.
Let's go, buddy.
Buddy?
Detective, is Iwami your prime suspect?
Not if he acted alone.
The case started when somebody manipulated
the brakes on Hosoo-san's car.
Next came the secretary Takahashi-san, again
manipulating a car in a complicated way.
And if the bar used to destroy the locker
was a wheel spanner that you'd
find in an onboard toolkit...
I see. So the culprit knows a lot about cars.
It's hard to imagine Iwami-san did it
since he doesn't have a driver's license.
When did you find out Iwami
doesn't have a license?
Oh, it wasn't me. Kogoro-no-ojisan
had someone look it up.
You say that,
but are you sure you're not actually solving
cases while hiding behind Mori-san?
That's not funny...
President's Office
Your bodyguard?
My car's brakes were destroyed,
and I was nearly killed.
And this time, my secretary
Takahashi was actually murdered.
We haven't ruled out suicide yet.
He wasn't the type of man to commit suicide.
Even when I chewed him out, the next day
he'd act like nothing had ever happened.
It's possible they might still come for me.
I understand. I accept.
That's great.
Come in.
Excuse me.
Good morning, President.
I have two messages for you.
I've just been tasked with
protecting the president.
You're Mori Kogoro-san.
Yes, the great detective.
What shampoo do you use?
Could you leave us?
I'm sorry.
We'll be finished soon, so could
you wait in the meeting area?
But there's no telling
where they'll come from.
If you know someone with aim that
good, could you introduce me to them?
What?
I'm joking.
I see. And you are?
I'm Shioji Yukari.
I'm in charge of accounting.
She knew who I was.
Shioji Kaori.
She sure smelled nice.
Hoaji Hospital
Iwami was brought here.
Ideally I'd like to talk to
him without causing a fuss.
What do you mean?
Ebizo-san, you kind of stand out.
They won't know it's me if I wear this.
It definitely won't work.
Really?
Dr. Terashima, please come
to the medical office.
Once again, Dr. Terashima, please
come to the medical office.
No matter what he does,
he can't suppress his aura.
This floor?
Room 11.
Iwami Shinnosuke-sama
Stop, Iwami-san!
Don't do it!
Someone! Someone come help!
Iwami!
What are you doing?!
You!
What do you think you're doing, Iwami?
Ebizo-san...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry...
Are you okay?
Yeah.
He's such a difficult patient,
I don't know what to do.
Huh?
Dr. Kikuchi.
Again?
Yes.
Perhaps it's my fault.
I thought highly of his talent and chose him.
But from his perspective, I may
have been putting pressure on him.
Ebizo-san.
I'll conduct the rest of
the investigation myself.
Why?
Suspecting your friends and
coworkers must be difficult.
You're only a child.
But you can read minds.
I knew it was you, Ebizo-san.
Yes.
Iwami-san was given a sedative.
The doctor says he'll be all right.
Thank you.
You're welcome!
What are you going to do now?
I'll give you a ride.
Thanks, but I'm good.
I'll do the rest myself.
Got it.
I'll tell everyone to answer honestly
if you come to ask any questions.
Work hard, little detective.
I will.
Hoaji Hospital
Did Iwami-san almost jump yesterday?
How did you know?
When the doctor came in, he said "again."
Oh, right.
It was during his nighttime IV check,
so it must have been around three.
Don't be absurd!
I'll quit, you idiot!
I'm done with this play!
Iwami-san!
Watch out!
Let go! Let go of me!
No!
So it was an attempted suicide?
It seemed like he might have been faking it.
We get patients like that from time to time.
Why are you sniffing around?
What are you doing?
I'm a cameraman.
Recording this performance is...
...my job.
I've got nothing to do with it.
But you've already stuck your nose in it.
You won't get off that easy.
Mister, are you a detective
instead of a cameraman?
When you look at someone
through a viewfinder,
you can clearly see what
they are inside and out.
That's why being a cameraman
is such good money.
Before the cops hid him behind blue sheets, I
got this from the rooftop of a nearby building.
And this one.
You've got a nice look in your eyes.
Did he leave a note?
If it was a suicide, it ends here.
If it was a suicide, he would
have done it more simply.
You're pretty sharp, kid.
Thanks.
Be careful.
If you get your enemies and friends
mixed up, it could cost you your life.
What does that cameraman know?
Outstanding.
Thank you for waiting.
Shioji Kaori-san.
It's Shioji Yukari.
I'd like to discuss Takahashi-san in private.
What?
Mori-san, I'm going to Ginza to talk business.
Please come with me.
O-Of course.
Shall we go, Kaori-san?
It's Yukari.
Shioji-kun has accounting work
to do, so she needs to stay here.
Aw...
Mori-san.
Y-Yes, sir.
We can't get in touch with Kaneko-san.
That's a problem.
You mean Kaneko-san the cameraman, right?
Yeah.
I just ran into him at the hospital where
the playwright Iwami-san is staying.
Really?
Thanks, Conan-kun.
Is something wrong with Kaneko-san?
There are a lot of unfortunate
rumors about him.
Really?
Mori Ran
Calling
Ran.
What is it, Ran-neechan?
Where are you right now?
I guess you have something more fun to do
than play soccer with us like you promised.
Hey, wait.
Ran-oneesan told us all about it!
She said you went to the Ichikawa
sushi restaurant by yourself!
That was a funny story about Kogoro-san.
And you got sushi with Kanizo!
Ebizo!
Give that back!
I won't be able to go home for a while.
What's wrong?
Did you give it to Mori-san?
Yeah, I'm about to.
I'm begging you.
At this rate, I won't be able to sleep.
Oh, right. Do you have
Kaneko-san's cell phone number?
Kogoro-no-ojisan asked me to get it.
So you answer when I call you.
I didn't recognize the number.
Call it a hunch.
I knew it had to be you.
Weren't the police calling you, too?
They say detectives have good noses.
As a detective, there's a
lot I'd like to ask you.
Like what?
Like how you got pictures of
Takahashi-san's dead body.
Sure thing, Detective.
What is he doing here?
Who is it?
Crap!
Episode Preview
Someone stole the two-faced
mask I borrowed from Hosoo-san.
But we cannot let this discourage us.
No matter what, we will
make this play a success.
The least suspicious person is
actually the most suspicious.
Dad, it's an emergency.
What about the kid?
He's missing?
Conan and Ebizo's Kabuki
Juhachiban Mystery
(Part 2)
The next episode of Conan is "Conan and
Ebizo's Kabuki Juhachiban Mystery, Part Two!"
Jacket
Next Conan's hint!
A jacket!
Don't miss the next episode.
Together...
...the five of us...
...are 30 years old!
Uh?