Shioji Yukari
Iwami Shinnosuke
Hosoo Takuya
Yabusaki Yoshiyuki
Ichikawa Ebizo
Mask One
Mask Two
Mask Three
Mask Four
As soon as the new year started, I
got caught up in an unexpected case.
It all began when I saved
an out-of-control car.
The owner of the car, Hosoo Takuya,
was the manager of a trading company.
Hosoo Takuya (47)
HO Holdings President
He was delivering his culturally significant
two-faced mask to a certain individual.
That person was currently one of the most
popular kabuki actors, Ichikawa Ebizo-san.
Ichikawa Ebizo XI
Ebizo-san, who is friends with Hosoo, planned
to use the mask in February's performance.
However, the mask, which was entrusted
to president Yabusaki-san, was stolen.
On top of that, Hosoo's secretary Takahashi
Hitoshi-san was found dead inside a car.
Takahashi Hitoshi (40)
Hosoo's Secretary
Beside him was the now empty case
that had contained the mask.
There are several suspects.
The playwright Iwami Shinnosuke-san.
Iwami Shinnosuke (29)
Playwright
Kaneko Eiji (37)
Cameraman
The cameraman Kaneko Eiji-san.
Yabusaki Yoshiyuki (57)
President
The president Yabusaki Yoshiyuki-san.
And finally, the accounting manager at
Hosoo-san's company, Shioji Yukari-san.
Shioji Yukari (32)
HO Holdings
Accounting Secretary
Naturally, I went to look for the culprit.
But I was attacked by someone
in an alleyway in Ginza.
With the same feelings we've
always held still in our hearts,
we fly powerfully into our twentieth year.
Where are the mask and Conan?
A magnificent finale takes
place on the kabuki stage!
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Conan and Ebizo's Kabuki
Juhachiban Mystery
(Part Two)
"Conan and Ebizo's Kabuki
Juhachiban Mystery, Part Two!"
Where am I?
I'm all right.
There's nothing wrong with me.
I'm in a basement somewhere.
Is that a boiler?
Judging by its size, I'm probably
two or three stories underground.
This building is being demolished.
I don't have my phone.
It's not working.
This is bad.
What? The can opener?
You ate the canned salmon the
other day while you were drinking.
Canned salmon?
Yeah, I ate it.
Hey, wait.
I didn't use the can opener.
They've got pull tabs these days!
So, what are you opening?
What am I opening? Canned tuna.
Canned tuna is practically the
poster child of pull tabs.
Does tuna even come in
cans without pull tabs?
But they were three cans for fifty-eight yen.
What?! Fifty-eight yen?!
Is that really tuna?
Don't eat those!
They'll make you sick!
Thank you for waiting.
Oh, right! Now I remember.
The kid.
Canned peaches?
He wouldn't give me any
when I asked for a bite.
All right. I'll ask him.
Those long meetings must be rough.
That was about four hours.
It does take longer when you're
dealing with foreigners.
There are a lot of documents
that need to be looked over.
And they're in English, too.
Could you look over this as well?
Check
Yes, yes.
Sheesh.
All right.
I wouldn't have made it out
if I weren't in this body.
Did they stop?
Okay, let's get this done today!
We'll get dinner and start working at seven!
Yes, sir!
This is the electrical room.
Lucky.
I should go while I have the chance.
You're going back to the rehearsal space?
Yes. Ebizo-san said he wanted
to talk to us and the staff.
Talk, huh?
Are you sure this is okay?
We're being treated to dinner
just for bringing a can opener.
It's supposed to be their dinner, too.
Is he still not answering his phone?
This is really good!
Tuna salad and tuna spaghetti.
It's all tuna.
Today is supposed to be tuna day.
You mean the tuna festival.
What's the tuna festival?
Is his phone ringing?
Yeah. I feel like something's wrong.
Yeah.
Should I call Shinichi?
I don't think you can.
What?
If Edogawa-kun has his GPS on...
You'd know where he is?!
Of course.
I'll never forgive him if he's having
sushi at Ichikawa by himself.
You're still not letting that go.
Ai-chan, have you found him yet?
Calm down.
Okay. His GPS is on.
There he is.
Where?
Ginza.
So it's a sushi restaurant in Ginza.
Let's move away from that.
It's an alleyway in 3-chome.
What's he doing there?
That's odd. He's not moving.
Maybe he dropped it.
Then he would at least call us.
He's not a child.
What?
Let's go.
Yeah, let's go.
Okay, let's eat quickly!
Later!
But... You don't have to say
it all at the same time...
All right!
Getting out of a building is easy.
Huh?
Hey, wait! Seriously?
It's being crushed from above.
Somebody please notice!
Okay, let's get started!
Hey!
Someone help!
As you know, someone stole the two-faced
mask I borrowed from Hosoo-san.
And Hosoo-san's secretary
Takahashi-san is dead.
The playwright Iwami-kun
is in the hospital as well.
The least suspicious person is
actually the most suspicious.
What? Did you say something?
No, nothing.
I intended to entertain audiences
with a new interpretation of the
Kabuki Juhachiban's "Nanatsu Men."
I regret that this project I
began has turned out this way.
But we cannot let this discourage us.
No matter what, we will
make this play a success.
I appreciate your support!
Yes!
Ebizo-san.
Iwami?
You've been discharged from the hospital?
I can't sit in the hospital
while the rest of you work.
I won't run anymore.
The least suspicious person is
actually the most suspicious.
In this work, the other four actors will
make a quick change into modern clothes.
It's meant to express how
humans haven't changed.
Iwami, I'll need some good lines for this.
Yes, sir.
Everyone, do you have a minute?
Inspector Megure.
Is this really the place?
Definitely.
What's Conan-kun doing here?
There are just a bunch of
bars on the other side.
So he can drink now?
We're not allowed to drink!
It's such a grown-up flavor.
Try calling him.
Okay.
Are you calling him?
Yeah, it's ringing.
I don't hear anything.
He could have it set to vibrate.
Be quiet, guys.
There you are!
Have you found the kid?
Wh-What's your problem?
It's in here?
I hear it.
Conan-kun!
There it is.
What's it doing here?
He must've been duped by a fox.
What?
Please don't say that, Sonoko-san!
Let's look for him.
Ask Inspector Megure for help.
What?
He's clearly gotten caught up in something.
Get out your badges.
Split up and keep calling Edogawa-kun.
Let's go, Sonoko.
Wh-Where?
Okay.
How much battery does it have left?
Only Hosoo-san and Takahashi-san's
prints were found on the car and case.
The culprit was willing to kill
to get his hands on that mask.
If I had been more careful...
It's not like that.
There are three plausible scenarios.
First, Takahashi-san stole the two-faced
mask and tried to sell it to a third party.
But the culprit killed
him and stole the mask.
If that's true, then why did the culprit
make it look like Takahashi-san committed suicide?
It would be odd to spend so
much time setting that up.
Is he trying to confuse me?
Can I help you?
Well, deductions are never perfect.
Scenario number two.
Thinking he could sell the
mask, the culprit stole it...
Minowa Takuzo (55)
Security Guard
I-It's wasn't me!
Mori-san isn't talking about you.
Ahem!
Thinking he could sell it, he contacted
Takahashi-san and negotiated to sell it back.
After receiving the money, he killed him.
After all, he saw his face.
And to shift the blame onto him,
he made it look like a suicide.
In that case, why would
he contact Takahashi-san?
If he wanted money, wouldn't
he have sold it to Hosoo-san?
He's definitely treating me like the enemy.
Which means...
Did anyone like that contact you?
No.
You could be the culprit.
It's definitely not a suicide, right?
Definitely not.
He's trying to make his crime
look like a suicide now?
The car and engine were both wiped clean.
Indeed.
A man about to kill himself wouldn't
bother to wipe away fingerprints.
You're right.
Right, my butt.
He's dug his own grave.
Ran.
Dad, it's an emergency.
I'm busy right now.
We can talk about the can
opener when I get home.
It's not that!
I'm looking for Conan-kun,
not the can opener.
What about the kid?
What? He's missing?
Is that really that unusual?
Maybe he's just taking more time
in the bathroom than usual.
Excuse me.
Who is this?
Yes. Ichikawa?
You mean Ebizo-san?!
Yes, yes.
Got it. I'll be right there.
What's going on?
Conan-kun has gone missing
somewhere around 4-chome.
Conan-kun is missing?
This is my turf, so I'm
going to go look for him.
It's decided.
Criminals always pretend to cooperate.
Cooperate?
Pretend?
Let's assume someone kidnapped him.
It's definitely connected to
the two-faced mask somehow.
Could you show me the phone you found?
Yes.
The last call it received
was from Ran-san at 4:05.
He said he was at the kabuki theater then.
Then we missed each other.
This is right after that.
He called someone just eight minutes later.
Call History
Since there's no name,
he must've entered the number.
We tried calling the number, but it was off.
Who are you?
Haibara Ai, a member of the Detective
Boys and Edogawa-kun's adviser.
You're Conan-kun's adviser?
Adviser?
Impressive.
It's someone who gives advice to a leader.
Anyway, I thought the number
might be on your phone.
Ai-chan's voice is cuter than normal.
I see.
It could be in my contacts.
The number alone doesn't
ring any bells, does it?
I used to be able to remember all of them.
I'll enter the number.
Then this.
Kaneko Eiji
It's Kaneko.
Kaneko-san? You mean the cameraman?
I called a staff meeting
earlier, but he wasn't there.
I made it through!
Once I make this wider...
It's working!
Damn it!
Let's try going to Kaneko's house.
Where is it?
President Yabusaki should know.
Edogawa-kun?
Conan-kun!
Guys!
You came!
Look for a building that's being demolished!
It's nearby!
Ow.
I'm in the basement of a
building being torn down!
Edogawa-kun!
Where are you?! Which building?!
Conan-kun!
We lost the signal.
I heard him say he's in a basement.
Conan!
And he said it was nearby.
A building under construction in this area...
That's it.
Someone let Mori-san and
the others know about this.
They should be at the kabuki theater.
You go, Mitsuhiko.
What? You go, Genta-kun.
I'm worried about Conan-kun.
Then we'll decide with this.
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot.
Shoot! Shoot!
Why do I have to go?
Is that it?
I'll stop them.
All right, keep up the pace!
Hey, you!
Stop the construction!
What?
What's going on?
An earthquake?
Hey, you're Ebizo-san.
The basement!
There's someone in the basement!
Wh-What?
Th-This way.
Conan-kun!
I'm in here!
There he is.
Watch out!
Are you in there?!
Yeah!
I'm here to rescue you, buddy.
Ebizo-san.
Does this not move?
The frame was crushed.
It'll take more than a person to move.
Get a wire!
We'll handle it.
Just do it.
Pass a hook through here and wind it back up.
If anything happens, we'll be in
trouble with the entire country.
Conan-kun!
Ran?
Are you okay?! Are you hurt?!
Yeah, I'm fine!
Don't worry!
Thanks, Ran.
Conan-kun, pass this under the door.
Pass it to us through the space underneath.
Okay.
Way to go.
Stand back.
Okay!
We're ready. Now pull slowly.
Boss, it won't work!
The second floor is falling!
Pull!
Keep it in place!
Masa, get the right side!
Roger that!
Conan-kun.
Ebizo-san.
Honestly, you cut it pretty close.
Really? You looked like you're
relieved help came quickly.
No way.
Conan-kun!
Save it for later!
We need to get out of here! It's dangerous!
Get out of here!
He really is tough.
You're sure?
Yeah. There was a camera in
the room on the bottom floor.
Normal people don't use cameras
with lenses like that.
Which means it was Kaneko.
We're looking for it right now.
If it is there, I'm sorry.
We checked the basement's locks, but...
It's not your fault.
You're victims as well.
What a dastardly culprit.
Sonoko-san and the others just left.
You didn't give them a ride?
They'd rather get a ride with Sonoko-san.
Of course.
We found something!
We found Kaneko Eiji's body, and...
I don't believe it.
Can it be fixed?
Even if we did...
It was inside Kaneko-san's camera bag, huh?
Yes, next to the body.
So he stole the mask, and while trying to
finish off the kid who was closing in on him,
he got caught up in it.
That can't possibly be right.
I'm sure that's what the
culprit wants us to think.
You didn't leave with the others?
It's bedtime for the kids, but the
adults still have a lot to do.
Here.
Thanks.
If you had your glasses, it wouldn't
have taken any time to find an exit.
Yeah. I wasn't wearing
my suspenders, either.
I panicked.
You were drawn there by someone
who may have been the suspect.
That wasn't like you.
It's because I was sure it wasn't him.
Huh? Ai-chan, why are you here?
I thought you were with
Sonoko and the others.
They left me here.
No way.
Just kidding.
Come down here.
Detective Chiba will give you a ride home.
What are Kogoro-no-ojisan
and the others doing?
They're going back to the rehearsal space
with Inspector Megure and the police.
You're taking a bath when
we get home, Conan-kun.
Okay.
It must've been hard being
trapped in there for hours.
Yeah.
Why don't you have her give you a bath?
Shut up.
What are they talking about?
I didn't have time to bug them.
Here.
Huh?
When was the last time you saw Kaneko-san?
This afternoon in my hospital room.
He came after Ebizo-san
and Conan-kun visited me.
What did Kaneko want to talk about?
W-Well...
Be honest.
All right.
You went to the theater during
the night, didn't you?
What are you...?
You don't have to hide it.
So, did you steal the mask?
You didn't steal the
two-faced mask, did you?
A-Absolutely not.
If I did, I wouldn't be telling you this.
Is it true that you came
here during the night?
I couldn't stand being alone at the hospital.
I did sneak out.
But I had nowhere to go.
Before I knew it...
But I lost the paper that I
wrote the door code down on.
So I went back to the hospital.
You don't know without the paper?
I'd never come at that time before.
Excuse me.
I-I'm the one who gave Iwami-san the code.
Will I be arrested as his accomplice?!
I didn't steal anything.
Minowa-san.
Y-Yes?!
Please sit down.
Okay!
So Kaneko-san took pictures of you.
Nice shot, right?
It's of you entering the building.
After all, you had to go the hospital
because you couldn't write a script.
If the mask disappears,
the play will be canceled.
That's what you thought, right?
Iwami, you really didn't go
to the locker room, right?
No, I didn't go there.
The paper with the door code was in there.
M-Mori-san, the boy gave
you the note, didn't he?
No, I don't know what note
you're talking about.
Y-You're so mean!
Crap.
Excuse me.
We just got Kaneko's history off his phone.
Hosoo-san.
Today at 3:05, did you
receive a call from Kaneko?
3 PM?
Weren't you in a meeting at
the Beika Hotel at that time?
You're right.
Since I was in a meeting,
it must've been on silent.
Ah, I do have a call from
a number I don't recognize.
That must be from Kaneko.
Has he ever called you before?
No.
"I have the mask."
"How much will you pay?"
Isn't that why he called?
I see.
So it was Kaneko.
No, Kaneko-san was just a pawn.
Someone else was controlling him.
The attempted murder of Hosoo-san,
the stolen two-faced mask,
the death of the secretary Takahashi-san, the
kidnapping of Conan, and Kaneko-san's death.
They're all connected.
There is no case I cannot solve.
Gather all the concerned parties.
I'll explain the truth behind this case.
What?
A-Are you sure, Mori-kun?
Don't you think it's too soon?
My detective skills will save the
investigation time and money, Inspector.
You're that confident, huh?
You want everyone to come now?
President, let's rehearse on the main stage.
We can wait until tomorrow afternoon.
Now? But the stage isn't ready yet.
That's fine.
Have everyone come, please.
Very well.
I'll call them immediately.
What about the two-faced mask?
Even if it's broken, we'll still use it.
I'm so excited to see the Sleeping Kogoro's
detective skills with my own eyes.
The old man's running out of control.
Now I need to gather the
evidence by tomorrow.
Fine, let's do it.
Where's my "thank you?"
When did you bug them?
I used to be able to remember all of them.
I'll enter the number.
Then this.
You bugged Ebizo-san?
It's all right.
I'll remove it tomorrow.
Yeah, if he's wearing the same jacket.
That's it. That's how...
I figured it out.
They're the culprit.
Could you examine this for me?
Where'd you get this chip?
It was in Kaneko-san's camera.
What?
Sorry I'm late.
How long were you planning on leaving
this helpless little girl alone?
Yeah, yeah. Helpless, right?
So, what was on it?
I'm almost done.
It's finished.
How can you criticize others when you
stole this out of someone's camera?
Yeah, yeah. Sorry for the trouble.
Maybe I'll develop a new drug.
It's huge.
How many photos did he take?
Well, he is a cameraman.
What did you say you were curious about?
All of it, but we should
start with Takahashi-san's...
Who's that?
Have you seen him before?
No, I don't know him.
I'll look it up.
Thanks.
There's no time.
Being trapped in there for
half a day really set me back.
Zoom in on that.
What about this?
Not the center, the bottom left.
Bottom left?
They're the same.
Does this belong to the culprit?
Yeah, it's theirs.
It must be there.
Hey, wait!
We're visiting the crime scene again?
Wasn't it a little farther down?
Yeah, when I started chasing it.
It'll be clear once it's light out.
Let's head down to the railroad crossing.
If you hadn't stopped him, he would've
headed straight into the crossing.
She's right. He wouldn't
have been able to stop.
Haibara.
I found it.
I see.
Let's get the police's help and
solve this Nanatsu Men case.
Hello?
Conan-kun, you haven't gone to bed yet?
Mori-san did?
Yeah. Yeah.
You want me to investigate it, right?
No problem at all.
Bye.
What is it, Conan-kun?
Shouldn't you be in bed?
Yes. Mori-san did?
The convenience store?
Yeah. Kogoro-no-ojisan asked
me to have you investigate it.
Also...
You shouldn't be walking around at night.
Could you come pick me up
without telling anyone?
Sorry.
How old are you?
We're first year grade school students.
Times may change, but humans shall
never let go of their emotions!
Marvelous!
We could open the show tomorrow.
You're such a great actor,
it's a shame, Ebizo.
But this is what you've decided to do.
I'll go get ready.
Thanks.
Why don't you put him to sleep already?
Sometimes the old man is actually right.
Mori-san, I did my homework.
Was that an adequate opening
performance to your detective show?
It's time to reveal the deduction
of the great Mori Kogoro.
How's this?
It's all right.
She's enjoying this, isn't she?
This case begins with the
cameraman Kaneko Eiji-san.
He was somebody's pawn and
was killed in that basement.
The culprit must have struck him
with one of the blocks lying around.
Wow, he's actually right.
Kaneko-san, who stole the two-faced
mask from Takahashi-san...
Okay, time to switch.
...was being manipulated by the culprit,
who was desperate to get his
hands on the two-faced mask.
That's right.
It was you, Ichikawa Ebi
Bring them back on.
Okay.
Did he say my
I-It's the Sleeping Kogoro!
We'll save the story of the Ichikawa sushi
restaurant's shrimp for another time.
No one asked.
He must really like it.
I'm hungry.
The deduction I just
described of Takahashi-san
stealing the mask does not
apply to this situation.
Who did it, then?
Iwami-san.
The ATM's camera caught
you withdrawing cash
from the hospital ATM and
giving it to Kaneko-san.
You gave him money?
I'm sorry. He caught me entering
the building at night.
Kaneko-san knew you didn't steal the mask.
What?
But he threatened him anyway?
He knew he'd pay up if he did.
Yabusaki-san and Minowa-san.
Don't worry.
Neither of you were
threatened by Kaneko-san.
The culprit had to have been someone
who was being threatened by Kaneko?
This is the shot of Iwami-san
entering the kabuki theater.
When Iwami-san was shown this photo,
he did as he was told and paid.
But Kaneko-san's camera also
captured what happened next.
This.
Look closely.
Iwami-san isn't holding
a case or anything else.
Kaneko-san only showed
you what benefited him.
Kaneko-san's camera told me
everything I needed to know.
Then that leaves...
Hold on a minute.
Didn't you hear what Mori-san just said?
Those who weren't captured by Kaneko-san's
camera aren't the culprit.
Hosoo-san, how do you know he
didn't take a picture of you?
Did I say that?
There's no way I'd be on his camera.
There's no way because you paid
him a large sum for the chip.
Stop joking around.
Have you forgotten that someone tried
to kill me by manipulating my car?
Mori Kogoro's Nanatsu Men!
Mask one!
Takagi Wataru
MPD Investigations
Section One Sergeant
This morning I investigated that slope again.
I found that the drops of brake fluid
started at the top of the hill,
and there was no fluid before that point.
Why did you take that road?
The most direct path from your house to the
theater is a straight and mostly flat road.
Why did you go out of your
way to go up that slope?
Also, nearby I found tape
with brake fluid on it.
Tape with brake fluid on it?
That's it.
As a car enthusiast, Ebizo-san,
have you figured it out?
Opening a hole in a brake hose isn't easy,
so you wrapped tape around the hose you
manipulated in your garage beforehand
Hold on.
You saw the footage of the
security cameras at my house.
I didn't go to the garage.
I see.
Mask two!
Shiratori Ninzaburo
MPD Investigations
Section One Inspector
There's a convenience store
in front of your house.
I compared your footage to
their security camera footage.
Video cue.
Got it.
This is footage from the same time.
On the left is the footage of the
outside we received from Hosoo-san.
On the right is the
convenience store footage.
You can see how it's the
same road at the same time,
but the car appeared only on one side.
Can you think of anyone who would have
access to the hardware in your home?
Who would do that?
Mask three!
Chiba Kazunobu
MPD Investigations
Section One Sergeant
The two-faced mask was
secured at Haneda Airport.
We also questioned the buyer Richard-san.
Apparently he purchased the mask from
Hosoo-san for a large sum of money.
Hosoo-san, do you remember what you said?
We can't have Japanese cultural
assets going overseas.
What did you mean by that?
I can do whatever I want
with my own possessions!
That's no reason to call me a murderer!
Now.
Got it.
Mask four!
Megure Juzo
MPD Investigations
Section One Inspector
Shioji-san told me everything.
Shioji?
He had me make that fake mask.
But the president instructed me
to take special care of the real mask
until the day of the performance.
Ebizo-san, didn't you know?
Yes.
I tried to convince myself that it was
because it was broken, but I knew.
Shioji.
You did this!
I see. I get it.
It's money, right? You wanted money!
I was dating Takahashi-san!
But you...
Hosoo-san, I know your company
hasn't been doing well.
You sold the mask for money and took out
a life insurance policy on Takahashi-san.
An insurance policy on Takahashi-san?
Yes.
Sometimes it's not paid out
in the case of suicide,
so in order to ensure it would be so
soon after taking out the policy...
Murder was a better choice.
What proof do you have that I did it?!
Isn't this your button, Hosoo-san?
I'm always telling them that if
they're ever kidnapped or attacked,
to leave some kind of mark on their attacker.
You can even bite down on
whatever they throw over you.
Yeah. Your teeth marks or saliva
can serve as evidence later.
Why's he being so clever?
What's wrong, Mori-san?
You of all people should know better.
Shioji, tell him when I changed my jacket.
I should get going.
Sir, the button on your sleeve.
When did that come off?
I was wearing a new jacket
when we went to the hotel.
Kid, when did you get that button?
Tell me.
Are you willing to use a child to
pin Kaneko's murder on me, too?
Mister, when did I say jacket?
He's so mean.
Hosoo-san, Conan only said that the
culprit covered him with something.
Finish him.
Got it. I'll show them in rapid succession.
This button of yours was found in the engine
room of the car where Takahashi-san died.
These are the traffic drums
next to the railroad crossing.
You intended to crash into these.
This is the inside of your garage.
You can see the disposable gloves you used
to keep the brake fluid off your hands.
This is the building your
previous office was in.
It's the building that's
currently being demolished.
The basement contained the staff office.
No wonder you knew so much about it.
What's this?
This is a shot of you picking
up Iwami-san's note.
How?
That was found in the locker room.
How do you have those pictures?
Kaneko-san saved all the pictures
he sold to you on his computer.
He was going to use them
to blackmail you again.
My company is going to go under.
No company is worth taking
human lives to save!
The place you're standing
in now is a place for those
who hone their craft daily and hold
themselves to a high standard.
A man like you doesn't belong here!
Mori-san!
Y-Yes?!
I'm impressed!
You truly are the great Mori Kogoro!
Dad, that was kind of cool.
Only kind of cool, though.
What are you talking about?
We need to arrest him.
Please!
Please let me incorporate the
Sleeping Kogoro into my next play!
I'm sure it'll be great!
L-Let go of me!
Who's going to play me?
Episode Preview
Now all that's yours is mine.
N-No! No more!
Calm down, ma'am.
Psychiatric tests aren't 100% accurate.
I... I... didn't kill anyone!
The Ventriloquist's Illusion
(Part One )
The next episode of Conan is
"The Ventriloquist's Illusion, Part One!"
Speaker
Next Conan's hint!
A speaker!
Don't miss the next episode.
I'm awesome at ventriloquism!
Give it a try.
Okay! I'm Genta!
We can't tell with just your voice.