Mori Detective Agency
Tengan Riichi (40)
Ventriloquist
It's him.
He's the one who ordered me to kill
my beloved wife with my own hands!
Don't you have anything to say?!
Don't say such scandalous things, Partner.
You and I are one.
I am you, and you are me.
You ordered yourself to do it.
Stop messing around!
I-I can't breathe.
What are you doing, Partner?
Stop, Partner.
Die! Die, die!
Now all that's yours is mine.
Who shall I possess next?
With the same feelings we've
always held still in our hearts,
we fly powerfully into our twentieth year.
The partner and puppet of a master
ventriloquist moves on its own?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Ventriloquist's Illusion
(Part One)
“The Ventriloquist's Illusion, Part One!”
The Terrifying and
Bloodcurdling Ventriloquist
Tengan Riichi's Dark Performance
It's just a doll, but that
was scary, wasn't it?
Yeah. Ventriloquism is amazing.
Though I guess I do something similar, too.
The Sleeping Kogoro's
Detective Show
Anyway, why did the popular ventriloquist
on the verge of his big break,
Tengan Riichi-san, hire you, Dad?
Who knows?
He said he'd fill me in after the show
and invited me to today's performance.
What on earth is going on?
What was today's performance about?
Just before the curtains went up,
he said he was changing the program.
Do you think he knows about us?
Togawa Haruomi (28)
Tengan's Apprentice
I-It can't be.
He's been acting strangely lately.
He's been muttering to himself.
Tengan Kazuko (35)
Tengan's Wife
Isn't he just practicing?
Without his doll?
What?
I'm scared of him.
Someday he might actually...
S-Surely not!
Excuse me. Where is Tengan-san's dressing room?
You're Mori Kogoro-san.
Get out!
Get out from inside of me!
Stop!
Please stop, sir!
Darling!
Stop!
You and I are one.
You can't force me out, Partner.
I-Is this not an act?
It's real?
I'll do exactly what you want to do.
If you can't do it,
I'll do it for you, Partner.
No! No more!
Calm down, ma'am.
Stop! Please stop!
Please get out from inside of me!
No way!
Dissociative identity disorder.
In other words, he has a split personality.
If you won't leave, then...
I'll do this!
Stop!
Let go! Let go of me!
Wait, ma'am.
Since he's under the effect of sedatives,
the doctors want him to stay here tonight.
Please stay by his side.
You do it, then!
I'm sick of this!
Besides, that doll is right next to him.
His partner!
Isn't that enough?
Apparently, Tengan-san has regained
consciousness and is asking to see you.
I hope you'll forgive my
disgraceful display, Mori-san.
I am ashamed.
Don't worry.
Right now I'm Tengan Riichi.
He's not here.
You mean...
They suspect that I have dissociative
identity disorder or a split personality.
But they can't say for certain that I do.
The doctors were vague.
You do the same thing, Partner.
You've always been shy and unable
to speak your true feelings.
I'm even the one who proposed to your wife.
Really?
It's embarrassing, but if not for him...
No, if I'd never encountered
ventriloquism, my life would be...
...at rock bottom, Partner.
What do you want Kogoro-no-ojisan to do?
Oh? You look like a pretty smart kid.
What's your name?
I'm Edogawa Conan.
This is Ran-neechan.
What?
Nice to meet you, Mr. Partner.
The pleasure's all mine.
So, your request...
The truth is...
Are you sure you want to tell him, Partner?
Shut up!
He's doing that himself, right?
I think so.
Hey, now.
The truth is I may kill my
own wife at his urging.
What did you say?
When I'm home alone, I can hear him even
though I'm not practicing ventriloquism.
Kill her, Partner.
Kill your wife, Partner.
Stop! Please stop!
Kill her. Kill her.
Kill her.
I can only imagine his
voice comes from inside me.
The part of him that's inside me.
In other words, it must be me.
Hey, now.
That was supposed to be our secret, Partner.
Shut up!
You can't expect me to keep quiet!
That woman is having an
affair with your apprentice!
I'm scared of him.
Someday he might actually...
S-Surely not.
If they love each other,
I'm willing to get a divorce.
You're lying, Partner.
It's true.
Liar.
It's true!
I... I would never kill her!
Uh, was that...?
I don't know.
What?
I don't know what's happening anymore.
I don't know if I'm playing the doll,
or if he's speaking from inside of me.
I'm afraid of him. No, of myself.
I'm afraid of what I'll do
if I lose consciousness.
Like my performance program,
someday I might...
So I want you to watch me, Mori-san!
Watch me so I don't kill my wife!
I see.
I understand. So that's
why you wanted to hire me.
Please, Mori-san!
I'm sorry.
But, Tengan-san, I'm a detective.
Consulting with the medical specialists
here would be a more sensible choice.
Yeah.
But...
I'm sorry.
Very well.
Togawa, bring the car around.
What? I thought you were
staying here tonight.
He said to bring the car around!
Sheesh. You're as useless as ever.
Very well.
Mori-san, I'm sorry for making you come here.
I'm going to get changed.
Later, you third-rate detective.
Huh?
At least answer the phone, Dad.
Hello? Yes, it is.
Togawa-san? Oh, Tengan-san's...
Thank you for last night.
What? Tengan-san killed his wife?
What?
Please help him, Mori-san!
Please help my master!
You took sleeping pills and were asleep?
Yes. I was afraid I'd lose myself.
I've been taking them every day lately.
So this morning, you were roused
by your apprentice and attendant,
Togawa Haruomi-san,
who came to pick you up for work,
and realized your wife had been killed.
Yes.
Last night when you returned from the
hospital, was your wife still out of the house?
Yes. Lately she's been
going out at night a lot.
She seems to come home while I'm asleep.
She's enjoying the nightlife, the nightlife!
When that cheater died,
my partner was snoring in bed.
You got that, you third-rate cop?
I-Is this...?
I killed her.
The man inside me ordered
me to kill my wife.
Hey, you're saying that after
I backed up your alibi?
And stop blaming me, Partner.
I'm just a doll.
You're the one who actually
did the deed, Partner.
This looks familiar.
What?
Uh, nothing.
Anyway, does he really have
dissociative identity disorder?
Maybe he's trying to make us think that so
he won't be found criminally responsible,
or we'll drop the case against him.
It's not totally unthinkable.
After all, psychiatric
tests aren't 100% accurate.
What to do?
In that case, leave it to me, Inspector.
I, the great detective Mori Kogoro, will
determine the truth behind this case.
Leave it to me.
The victim was here.
And the weapon was here.
Only Tengan-san's fingerprints
were on the weapon, right?
Yeah.
Based on their position, he grabbed the trophy
that was sitting here, raised it over his head,
and brought it down on the
back of the victim's head,
who was sitting on the
couch and drinking sake.
What's this?
What are you doing here, anyway?
I just wanted to help.
Go home already!
Wait, Mister!
Look at that.
On top of the speaker.
What?
Is this a speaker?
There's one over there, too.
And over there.
And they're wireless. Which means...
There must be a recorder somewhere
sending sounds to them.
I found it!
It has a timer.
Hey, you can't just—
Kill her, Partner.
Kill your wife, Partner.
Th-This is...
Mister.
Yeah. I'll report this to the inspector.
We found your fingerprints on
this recorder and these speakers.
Can you explain this, Togawa-san?
Th-They're mine.
They've been missing for about a week.
Where did you find them?
They were set up in the living
room of Tengan-san's apartment.
It was set to periodically play this.
Kill her, Partner.
Wh-What's the meaning of this?
Set up? Periodically play?
Is this what my master mentioned?
Togawa-san, you're trying
too hard to feign ignorance.
What? What do you mean?
During your voluntary appearance and search
at the station, we found this inside your bag.
Those are mine.
I lost these a while ago, too.
What were they doing there?
What indeed?
But there's another problem.
Do you know what this
is that's stuck to here?
Is it blood?
What?
Yes. The DNA test indicated
that it's the victim's blood.
It probably got on them during the attack.
During the attack?
You think I killed her?
Togawa-san, where were you
around 2 AM this morning?
2 AM?
I was practicing at home.
Practicing? You mean ventriloquism?
My master said he'd check my
progress first thing in the morning,
so I was up almost all night.
Were you alone?
Yes! Of course!
This is the spare key to Tengan-san's
apartment that you were holding onto.
Y-Yes.
But as his apprentice and
attendant, I need it.
Either way, you have no alibi
for the time of the crime,
and you could freely enter and
leave the scene of the crime.
B-But I...
By the way, I heard you and the
victim had a special relationship.
Is it true?
I-It's true that something
happened between us.
My master scolded me every day for my
inexperience, and she was kind to me.
And she felt lonely because
he was always so busy.
It was just once.
Just a one-time mistake.
But the victim wouldn't leave you alone.
You became anxious for your future as a
ventriloquist and thought she was in the way.
N-Never!
So you killed her.
You made Tengan-san believe he
had dissociative identity disorder,
and tried to put the blame on him.
No! I regret my relationship with his wife.
I respect my master.
I would never do that!
It's true.
I... I... didn't kill her!
He's one tough nut to keep denying
it in the face of all that evidence.
But we've already requested
an arrest warrant.
It's just a matter of
time before he confesses.
I should be thanking you, Mori-kun.
I nearly arrested the wrong
man. Thanks for the help.
I see, I see!
Thanks for the help, huh?
And it was all thanks to me? Well, well.
Murder Charges Dropped
Is the Popular Ventriloquist Innocent?
I'm terribly sorry for the trouble I caused.
From the bottom of my heart,
I apologize for the trouble and concern I
caused to all concerned parties and my fans.
There's no need to apologize, Partner.
You're a victim of infidelity and
bereaved husband of a murder victim.
I'm surprised the serious looking
Togawa-san did it, though.
You can't judge a book by its cover.
The same goes for his
relationship with the victim.
I was surprised about that, too.
What is this?
Why do I feel like something's wrong?
In any case, that settles that.
All thanks to me, the Sleeping Kogoro, also
known as the great detective Mori Kogoro.
Wait, I didn't sleep this time.
Huh? Why not?
Well, I guess I don't sometimes.
I'm going out for a drink.
Don't drink too much, and make
sure you come home early.
I know, I know.
You have no idea, do you?
Please help him, Mori-san!
Please help my master!
Would someone trying to put the blame
on Tengan-san ask the old man for help?
And...
You don't have any idea?
Episode Preview
Of course not.
I have no idea what it was doing in there.
That's it.
This is what was making me feel uneasy.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Partner.
Make me offer a toast, too.
Yes, it's impossible.
The blood.
The Ventriloquist's Illusion
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is “The
Ventriloquist's Illusion, Part Two!”
Trophy
Next Conan's hint!
A trophy!
Don't miss the next episode.
Let me handle your ventriloquism needs!
That hits so close to
home, it's not even funny.