Popular ventriloquist Tengan Riichi's
performance depicted a ventriloquist,
possessed by his partner,
the doll, who murders his wife.
But Tengan-san fell victim to dissociative
personality disorder, or a split personality,
Tengan Riichi (40)
Ventriloquist
and asked the old man to watch him
because he feared he'd murder his wife.
The old man turned him
down, but the next morning,
his wife was found murdered in a manner
similar to the one in his performance.
However, Tengan-san was
quickly found innocent.
Believing his apprentice Togawa
Haruomi killed her to bury his affair,
Togawa Haruomi (28)
Tengan's Apprentice
the police requested a
warrant for his arrest.
However...
Would someone trying to put the blame
on Tengan-san ask the old man for help?
With the same feelings we've
always held still in our hearts,
we fly powerfully into our twentieth year.
The ventriloquist and his partner, the doll.
The truth behind the case lies in the
question, "Who is the star?"
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Ventriloquist's Illusion
(Part Two)
"The Ventriloquist's Illusion, Part Two!"
How many times do I have to say it?!
I respected my master.
I would never set him up like that.
Never!
Then what's this?
Didn't you use this to make Tengan-san
believe he had a split personality disorder?
Th-That is mine.
I used it to practice ventriloquism.
But it disappeared at some point.
I had no idea it was set up there.
Do you really have no
idea why these glasses
stained with the victim's blood
were hidden in your bag?
Of course not.
I lost those recently, too.
I have no idea what they were doing in there.
It's true.
That's too bad.
I thought it'd be better for you
to admit to your crime before
the warrant we requested arrives.
How could I?
I really didn't do it!
What? From Mori-san?
Takagi? It's me.
There's something I want
you to check for me.
Oh, Dad.
You're going to catch a cold.
Huh? Conan-kun?
Where's Mori-san?
He has something else to investigate,
so he told me to come check this out.
What?
Hurry up and open the door, Detective Takagi.
Oh, sure.
Give me a second.
That's it!
This is what was making me feel uneasy.
Is something wrong, Conan-kun?
This photo was taken in the living room
where the murder took place, right?
What?
Oh, yeah. Looks like it.
What about it?
When the suspect Togawa-san found
the body of Tengan-san's wife,
he used a spare key to come in, right?
Yeah. He came to pick up
Tengan-san for work as usual,
and when nobody answered the doorbell,
he entered using his spare key.
Then he found the body in the living room.
He woke Tengan-san, who was
sleeping in the other room,
and called the police and
Mori-san to ask for help.
At least, that's his story.
But he has a spare key.
He could've snuck in while
Tengan-san was sleeping
while under the effects of the
sleeping pills he always used.
It's also possible that the victim, who he
was having an affair with, invited him in.
Though we're not yet sure if
he stayed at the crime scene
after committing the crime
or returned in the morning.
The trophy that was used as
the weapon was here, right?
It looks like it was displayed
somewhere else originally.
What?
Look.
The dust is shaped differently
from the weapon.
You're right.
And originally the trophy
was sitting back there.
This was here?
That's a perfect match.
The photo in the entryway
shows the same thing.
What?
Detective Takagi, there's
something I want you to confirm.
Huh?
Y-Yes. Yes, I see.
I understand.
I had them ask the suspect Togawa Haruomi.
Tengan-san received that trophy the first
time he finally won the national contest.
He always displayed it in the front
since it was valuable to him.
But it was moved to the back, and the trophy
used as the weapon was placed in the front.
And then there's the location of the phone
he used to call the police and Mori-san...
I believe I used the phone in the entryway.
I didn't want him to hear me say
that he may have killed his wife.
What? The bag?
I don't know. I was panicked,
so I don't know where I put it.
I think I left it in the living
room and left to use the phone.
Hey, what's this?
Oh, forensics said it was
probably fibers from a glove.
A glove?
We think he wore them during the murder,
so his fingerprints wouldn't get on
the trophy covered in Tengan-san's.
Huh.
Have they already found the gloves?
No. We didn't find anything
in his house or in the area.
He probably threw them away somewhere.
That's odd.
Who would hide the glasses on his person,
without even cleaning them,
while throwing away just the gloves?
Is that all, Conan-kun?
I need to head back to the station.
Were you able to confirm
Mori-san asked you to check?
Yeah. Thanks, Detective Takagi.
I need to go report to him, too.
See you later.
I don't get it.
He's the real culprit. That much is certain.
But I still don't know
the most important part.
I need to figure that out.
That's from this afternoon.
I'm terribly sorry for the trouble I caused.
From the bottom of my heart,
I apologize for the trouble and concern I
caused to all concerned parties and my fans.
There's no need to apologize, Partner.
You're a victim of infidelity and
bereaved husband of a murder victim.
That's it! So that's how it is!
I finally figured out the critical piece.
The old man was...
No, we were tricked by him.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Partner.
We did it, Partner.
Make me offer a toast, too.
What are you looking for, Partner?
Could it be the speakers and recorder?
You won't find those here.
The police seized those a long time ago.
Sh-Shut up!
I will, Partner.
If you don't want to talk, I can't.
Shut up!
You and I are one.
I am you, and you are me.
Don't you know that, Partner?
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
N-No...
Am I actually...?
Impossible!
It's not possible! It's impossible!
Yes, it's impossible.
Because you're definitely sane, and you
definitely planned to kill your wife.
M-Mori-san...
No, the Sleeping Kogoro?
I knew you set up speakers and
a recorder somewhere in here.
What do you think you're doing?
I killed my wife?
Spare me your jokes.
I'm busy practicing for
my encore performance.
He's right.
You'll need to properly
explain yourself, Mori-kun.
Though we did put a hold on that
arrest warrant like you said.
After all, only proper
explanations hold up in court.
I know, Inspector.
Allow me to describe the truth behind
this case that I have discovered.
Didn't Togawa kill my wife?
He made me believe I had a split
personality disorder and framed me.
That was precisely your plan.
Your clever plan to initially
cast suspicion on yourself,
have me clear your name,
and frame Togawa-san.
Wh-What did you say?
Didn't you change your plans and put
on that performance to mislead me?
C-Could it be? Then...
Yes. Tengan-san is the one who set up
Togawa-san's stolen recorder and speakers
and told him he'd check his progress the next
day so he'd practice alone and have no alibi.
Now let me explain how
he committed the crime.
The trophy he used to kill his wife is
normally at the back of the sideboard.
Before the crime was committed, it was
swapped with a trophy of great value to Tengan-san.
If Togawa-san were the murderer,
it would be a meaningless act.
It shouldn't have mattered which
trophy he used as a weapon.
Couldn't he have done it to frame me?
No, he must have.
There was no need for him to do that.
Tengan-san, only your fingerprints
were on the weapon.
Of course, that's because you
grabbed the weapon barehanded,
so you'd fall under suspicion first.
Furthermore, you even confessed
that you killed your wife.
What need would he have
had to do anything else?
W-Well, I...
After committing the crime,
you put on gloves and put the victim's blood on
Togawa-san's glasses, which you stole beforehand.
In the morning,
you were woken by Togawa-san and pretended
you had just learned of your wife's death.
Then while Togawa-san was calling the
police and me for help in the entryway,
you donned the gloves again and placed the
bloodied glasses at the bottom of his bag.
That's probably when the fibers from your
glove got caught on the frames of his glasses.
So that's what that was.
Then you pretended to
have a split personality,
and claimed the doll ordered you to do it,
initially casting suspicion on yourself.
I killed her.
The man inside me ordered
me to kill my wife.
Hey, you're saying that after
I backed up your alibi?
Then you had me discover
the recorder and speakers.
Is this a speaker?
You transferred suspicion to Togawa-san,
and had the police discover
the glasses to seal the deal.
This is absurd.
What proof do you have?
The proof is in the gloves.
What gloves?
The gloves Tengan-san wore
while placing the bloodied glasses
in Togawa-san's bag that I mentioned earlier.
Later, Tengan-san, you hid the gloves.
Considering the timing, you could only
have hidden them in the living room,
where the crime took place.
Oh, really?
Have you found them, then?
No. Not even the police found it during
their inspection of the crime scene.
That's right, Mori-kun.
Of course not.
After all, those gloves never even existed.
Then why don't we ask your partner.
You know where he hid
them, don't you, Partner?
Don't worry, Partner.
I'll never tell them that I've
got them. My lips are sealed.
That's enough jokes.
Detective Takagi!
Yes.
I found the gloves.
Is that blood?
I-Impossible! I already threw those away!
I'm sure you did.
Those are fake, of course.
Fake?
Tengan-san disposed of the actual
gloves once he was acquitted.
But you should've thrown away the doll, too.
However, he's your partner
who's been with you for years
and even helped you win a national contest.
I doubt you even considered it.
C-Could it be?
Yes.
While you left your doll here to meet
with your staff in another room,
I had it examined.
Traces of fibers matching the ones found on
the gloves were collected from inside the doll.
The victim's blood was on them.
Furthermore, another person's
sweat was collected from the fibers,
and DNA was detected.
It was probably on the gloves.
Tengan-san, if necessary,
we can get a warrant for a sample of your
saliva or hair and wait for the test results.
That won't be necessary.
I couldn't believe my wife was
cheating on me with my apprentice,
even though I finally won
the national contest.
My pride wouldn't allow it.
Mori-san, how did you know?
The doll told me, of course.
What?
Because you hid the gloves inside him,
his expression was different from usual.
Now all that's yours is mine.
Who shall I possess next?
There's no need to apologize, Partner.
You're a victim of infidelity and
bereaved husband of a murder victim.
In fact, the doll...
No, you and the doll were telling
the truth from the start.
The one and only truth.
You can't expect me to keep quiet!
That woman is having an
affair with your apprentice!
I killed her.
I killed my wife.
You used your confession to
commit the perfect crime.
What's going on?
I remember coming here, but...
Inspector, where are you?
What's this new evidence you found?
I really did nearly arrest
the wrong man this time.
Thanks for the help, Mori-kun.
I see, I see.
I helped you again, did I?
I had no idea you were capable
of ventriloquism, though.
What? Ventriloquism?
Uh, oh.
Didn't you produce the doll's voice just now?
Like you said, we were still in possession
of the speakers and recorder.
I suppose I am!
For me, ventriloquism is as
easy as talking in my sleep.
In his case, it really is.
Episode Preview
First, look at this photo.
What is this?
A sickle. And speaking of
animals that have sickles...
Ka...
Kamaitachi?
Dad?
Heiji, what happened?
You're both bleeding.
Hey, that cut....
Could it be?
The Kamaitachi Inn
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is
"The Kamaitachi Inn, Part One!"
Outdoor Bath
Next Conan's hint!
An outdoor bath!
Don't miss the next episode.
The next episode features
Hattori-kun and Kazuha-chan.
You might not get an appearance, mister.
Even though there's an outdoor bath?