Detective Conan Episode 808
"The Kamaitachi Inn (Part 1)"
I'm asking about a case.
Mori Detective Agency
Haven't you got any bloodcurdling-ly
interesting cases?
Oh, well...
There is something, but I haven't
found any information yet.
And I can't get Hattori caught up in
investigating Rum of the Black Organization.
Hey!
Are you listening, Kudo?
Yeah.
Are you sure you haven't lost your edge
since confessing your feelings
to the detective agency girl?
You know, your instincts
for sniffing out cases.
Or your antenna, you could call it.
Do you have anything, then?
If I did, I wouldn't be calling you!
No, you must have something.
What?
And you're bringing it to me.
Why?
Untitled
Playing
I could ask you the same thing!
What do you think you're
doing to my Kazuha?!
With the same feelings we've
always held still in our hearts,
we fly powerfully into our twentieth year.
Right in front of mine and Hattori's eyes,
stabbings happen one after another.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Kamaitachi Inn
(Part One)
"The Kamaitachi Inn, Part One!"
You're right.
You can really taste the
ginger in this kuzuyu.
It warms you up.
Doesn't it?
It said in an article that this
inn's kuzuyu is really good.
What do you want, anyway?
The kuzuyu.
It's suppose to be good for hangovers, too.
I meant surely you didn't invite
the great detective Mori Kogoro
to an inn deep in the mountains of
Nagano just to eat this slimy stuff!
Well, no.
You've got a case, right?
Yeah.
First, look at this photo.
What is this?
A person. No, an animal?
It's kind of creepy.
Look closely at what it's got on its back.
A sickle. And speaking of
animals that have sickles,
there's a demon that rides in on whirlwinds
and cuts people clean in half.
The kamaitachi.
Ka...
Kamaitachi?
But I thought kamaitachi
have sickles for fingers.
Isn't this a person carrying a sickle?
Look at his feet.
The water's spraying.
The background is the outdoor
bath here at this inn,
but this is a photo taken from the same
angle by the writer who published the photo.
Compare them.
He's clearly walking on
the surface of the water.
H-He's right.
Maybe he lined up a couple
transparent platforms in the bath.
The water here is clouded
like the Shirahone Hot Spring,
which makes all kinds of tricks possible.
He didn't do anything to the bath.
And the photo was taken with analog
film, which is difficult to edit.
I even had an expert look at it,
so it's definitely the real thing.
Are you the writer who took this photo?
Nakama Daigo (35)
Writer
Yeah. I'm Nakama Daigo, a
writer for IZUNA magazine.
I'm here today to take a picture
of the kamaitachi myself.
I see.
It's gotten really cold lately.
What does the cold have
to do with kamaitachi?
The kamaitachi legend is
popular in snowy regions.
So if it snows tonight, he might
come riding in on the snow and wind.
I'm leaving!
What?!
It'll be fine.
Even if he does appear, we can beat
him up with my aikido and your karate.
W-We're talking about a creature armed
with a sickle that flies around!
He'd get us first!
It's all right.
The kamaitachi never existed
in the first place.
You're here because you received so many
complaints about your phony photo, right?
Koyanagi Midori (26)
Writer
Besides, that photo was mixed in
with a bunch of voyeuristic photos
of the outdoor bath printed in another
one of your publisher's magazines.
It's so dubious, I could laugh.
Then why are you here?
I write for a rival magazine, so I came
to write an article on your hack writing.
Naturally, I won't let you
stage anything, either,
to make this non-existent
kamaitachi seem like it exists.
He does exist.
Ono Kohei (7)
Landlady's Son
I saw the kamaitachi running
across the hot spring.
Is that true?
Yeah. I tried to chase him,
but I can't walk on water.
In fact, I almost drowned
because I couldn't move,
like a spell was cast on me or something.
When I woke up, I was lying down
in the hallway, soaking wet.
Really?
Oh, Kohei.
What are you doing?
Mom.
Did you already finish decorating the room?
Ono Takami (34)
Inn Landlady
We're celebrating your birthday
tomorrow with your friends.
Yeah. I'm about to do it.
Then go and do it.
Okay.
Jeez, your hands are badly chapped.
Are you okay, Takami?
Yeah. I've been working more since
my husband passed away last year.
Are you two...?
Do you know each other?
Yeah, we were classmates in middle school.
Sorry for publishing that
weird photo in the magazine.
I hope it hasn't caused you trouble.
No. Thanks to the photo, we've
been getting more guests.
Though because of the kamaitachi, fewer
people have been using the outdoor bath.
Ono Bonzo (72)
Ladylady's Father-in-law
Kamaitachi, my ass.
This couldn't be worse.
Sir.
Hmph. That monster will only bring
in more customers for a while.
It's not a fundamental solution
to our money problems.
That's the only way to
bring in more customers.
Right, landlady?
I already told you I'm not doing it.
Well, once the fuss dies down and you
can't keep the business open anymore,
you'll change your mind.
Though it'd be a different story if that
kamaitachi actually killed someone.
N-Nyotaimori?
He wants you to get naked so customers
can eat sashimi off your body?
Yes. He said it'd double
the number of guests.
I've only ever seen that
in dirty historical dramas.
If it got out, you'd be charged
with public indecency.
I'm sure he's only joking.
When we got married, my family and theirs
merged our inns, and business was good.
But since my husband died,
a lot of regulars stopped coming,
and it's true that we're in the red.
But, Takami, you can't do a nyotaimori.
Why don't you sell something, then?
Like antique pots or something.
Come to think of it,
there is a large sickle in the
storehouse that a famous swordsmith
modeled after a foreign grass sickle.
Wouldn't that be worth good money?
About how big is that sickle?
The blade is 60 centimeters long.
The handle is as long as I am tall.
C-Could it be?
The sickle the kamaitachi
was carrying in the photo?
Where's the storehouse?
Next to the outdoor bath.
Show us there.
Okay.
Well? Pretty interesting, right?
Yeah.
Then give me the audio file.
No, not yet.
Let's go, Conan-kun.
Heiji, we'll leave you behind.
Oh, okay!
Got it.
It should be around here somewhere.
But it's not here.
This storehouse is covered in dust.
You'll start a fire if you smoke in here.
Don't worry.
Why don't we split up and help you look?
O-Okay...
Oh, fine.
Ow!
Sheesh.
Huh?
It's snowing!
Wow, you're right.
But snow means...
The kamaitachi is coming, right?
Didn't you say you were
going to wait outside?
Isn't this it, Takami?
Yes, that's it. This is the sickle.
It certainly is antique.
Looks valuable.
My late husband said it
was worth 10 million yen.
Huh? What?!
The light bulb broke.
Ow!
What?
Dad?
Heiji?
I don't know what happened,
but something cut my arm.
And the back of my hand.
You're right.
You're both bleeding.
That was the lady writer's voice.
Where is she?
Hey, are you okay?
Did something happen?
Hey, that cut....
Could it be?
The kamaitachi!
Hey, Kazuha.
Did you call the cops?
Yeah, they said they'd be right here.
But I wonder if they'll believe you
were assaulted by a kamaitachi.
Either way, they've got three people
right here who were cut by something.
It'll be fine.
Since we're in Nagoya, the
Nagano police will be coming.
Oh, right. Inspector Yamato Kansuke.
That's right.
That super smart one-eyed inspector
will arrest the kamaitachi in no time.
Yeah.
One-eyed?
Come to think of it,
Haibara mentioned the number two of the
Black Organization's special trait...
While I was in the organization,
I heard all kinds of descriptions.
A large brawny man.
An effeminate man.
An old man.
He injured an eye in some kind of accident.
Either his right or left
eye is an artificial eye.
Inspector Yamato is one-eyed and a big guy.
His hair is long enough that he ties it back.
And since he walks with a cane,
he might look old from a distance.
No way. Inspector Yamato
couldn't possibly be...
The police are here.
Tada!
Gunma Police Inspector
Yamamura has arrived!
Aren't we in Nagano?
We're just on the border of Gunma.
This is my jurisdiction.
Inspector Yamato couldn't come?
I thought we'd get to see Yui-san.
Hey, wait.
Why are you so disappointed?
The flaming dog case, the kappa case,
and even the vampire case...
I helped solve all those
cases from the shadows.
If the culprit is a kamaitachi, then of course
they'll send me, Demon Hunter Yamamura.
Demon Hunter Yamamura
Though in our scientific age of orbital
elevators that will take you to space,
there's no way kamaitachi exist.
I feel like I've heard that before.
Now show me to the storehouse where
you were assaulted by the kamaitachi.
Though I'm sure it's some kind of mistake.
This guy is infuriating!
I see. You came here to
look for an antique sickle.
Then this light bulb suddenly
exploded, and in the darkness,
someone cut the back of
Mori-san's right hand,
the Osaka accented kid's left arm,
and the left cheek of the
writer Koyanagi Midori-san.
Yes.
Did anyone have anything sharp at the time?
Well, I was holding the antique sickle.
The light bulb shattered just
as I found it and picked it up.
Then perhaps you swung that
sickle around in the darkness.
You idiot!
If he swung that around, we would've
been cut way worse than this.
Then why don't we check the sickle for blood?
I will, of course.
Was there someone standing near the
light bulb who could have broken it?
Maybe, but I didn't see anyone.
There was nobody there.
We were standing in the doorway then.
Just before the light bulb broke,
everyone was looking at the sickle.
Is this the only light bulb?
No.
There's usually another by the entrance,
but it wouldn't turn on when we
entered the storehouse today.
Come to think of it, this storehouse
doesn't have a lock, does it?
No. The door is old and rotten.
All we ever stored in this storehouse
we planned to demolish was rice.
But you said the sickle
was worth 10 million yen.
That's just what my late husband said.
My father-in-law thinks
it's just a piece of junk.
A few days ago, a burglar broke
into the storehouse again.
I tried to replace the
door and put a lock on it,
but my father-in-law said we didn't
need to since we're in the red.
What did the burglar take?
Nothing we couldn't live without.
Ah!
This must be the sickle in question.
It looks exactly like something an ancient
demon would use, but don't worry.
I, Demon Hunter Yamamura,
will catch him immediately,
so you needn't be worried sick-le.
A pun...
What? The kamaitachi appeared?
Lucky. I wanted to see him, too.
Don't say that.
Some people were hurt.
When I nearly drowned in the hot spring,
I was probably saved by the kamaitachi.
I wanted to thank him.
Anyway, did you finish decorating the room?
No, not yet.
I can't do it like Dad did by myself.
But I'm too busy to help you right now.
Want us to help you, then?
Leave the decorating to us.
Really?
Thank you.
It's okay.
Let's go.
Okay.
How old are you going to be?
Eight!
Eight, huh?
Come to think of it, you really celebrated
your son's birthday every year.
I saw the photos on the inn's homepage.
Yes, my husband loved big events.
During a party for my husband's
survival game friends,
they got water everywhere while
shooting each other with water guns.
It was a disaster.
Really?
Hey, Kudo.
What do you think of this case?
Well, I'm sure someone
did it in the darkness.
But if nobody was carrying anything sharp...
The weapon was probably...
...a fragment of the shattered light bulb.
We still don't know how
they broke the light bulb,
but they definitely used a piece of a
different light bulb that they had all along, right?
Yeah. By throwing it on the
floor after cutting everyone,
they could make it look like one of
the pieces that was broken off then.
After examining the sickle for
blood, the results determined
that there was none.
I'm not surprised.
And? Did you examine the shards of the
light bulb scattered on the floor, too?
Yes, though there was
nothing unusual about them.
What? There wasn't blood on them?
You really did examine them, right?
Of course.
We gathered up all the pieces and
reassembled them into their original shape,
but there wasn't any blood anywhere.
That's impossible.
Then how?
The only unusual things we found were
cigarette butts and a piece of chewed gum.
I believe an old light bulb simply shattered
and happened to hit the three of you.
Then we should've felt
pain the instant it broke.
But there was a delay between them.
Th-That's the girls' voices!
Did you hear that sound before they screamed?
That sounded like something
breaking and bursting!
A-Are you all right?
What happened?
Th-The lamp suddenly broke.
And then the balloons we put up popped.
Th-This inn must be...
...haunted!
Wasn't that the old man?
I-I think so.
D-Did the kamaitachi get him?
Where is he?
At this hour, probably in the annex.
Hey, wait. Isn't there a faster way?
The fastest way is through the outdoor bath.
Shit. There's still water in here.
It's not time to clean yet.
Is that building on the other
side of the fence the annex?
Yes.
Hey, wait.
Does that gate look slightly open to you?
I-It's the kamaitachi!
The kamaitachi rode the
wind across the water!
That's not possible.
It doesn't look like there are any
transparent platforms in the water.
There's still water in there.
There's a hallway connecting
the annex to the main building,
but it's being remodeled right now.
It's a bit out of the way,
but we could go outside and come
back in through the back door.
Let's head there, then.
That's the annex.
Since only our footprints
are here, that means...
No one has been this way.
Sir!
Are you all right?!
Get the lights.
Okay!
What? It's not turning on.
What's up with that sliding door?
It's broken as though
something cut through it.
Could it be?
Episode Preview
Then why is there blood above the cut?
To make it look like the kamaitachi did it.
Th-The suspect is a kamaitachi.
Don't be stupid.
Demons don't bother with breaking
windows or shutting off breakers.
I see. So that's how it is.
That's why they...
The Kamaitachi Inn
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is
"The Kamaitachi Inn, Part Two!"
Kuzuyu
Next Conan's hint!
Kuzuyu!
Kazuha-chan, how are things with Hattori-kun?
Don't miss the next episode.
Well, actually—
We're out of time. See you next week.