Detective Conan Episode 809
"The Kamaitachi Inn (Part 2)"
Invited by Hattori Heiji, we came to
a famous hot spring inn in Nagano.
In the storehouse of the inn,
Hattori, Kogoro-no-occhan,
and inn guest Koyanagi Midori-san
were cut by something sharp.
Koyanagi Midori (26)
Writer
And then...
Sir!
With the same feelings we've
always held still in our hearts,
we fly powerfully into our twentieth year.
The duo's deduction reveals the identity
of the kamaitachi who runs on water.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Kamaitachi Inn
(Part Two)
“The Kamaitachi Inn, Part Two!”
S-Sir!
Sir!
Don't enter the room.
Ono Bonzo (72)
Ladylady's Father-in-Law
He's already dead.
Since rigor mortis hasn't set in yet, it's
been less than thirty minutes since he died.
But what's this sickle doing here?
I thought the Gunma Police were examining it.
Since we didn't find any blood
when we examined it earlier,
I thought it was unrelated to the case
so I put it back in the storehouse
and sent forensics home.
I see. So the culprit could have
taken this sickle at any time.
Huh? Something's not right.
What?
This sliding door was cut by the sickle
sticking out of the old man, right?
Yeah, probably.
Then why is there blood above the cut?
A person's bound to bleed if you cut them.
But, if there's blood on the door,
that means he stabbed the old
man before cutting the door,
and then stabbed the old man again.
Y-You're right.
It's an act.
To make it look like the kamaitachi did it.
In that case,
was preventing the lights from
turning on part of the act, too?
The annex's breakers were switched off,
and there were strange marks
left where the culprit entered.
Strange marks?
This way.
This is probably where the culprit entered.
The glass is broken.
So, where are these strange marks?
Those are my footprints leading
from the veranda to the fence,
but see how a shallow semicircle of
snow has been dug out next to it?
Isn't that because the culprit erased his
footprints with the blade of the sickle?
Even I know that, but the real problem
is what lies beyond this fence.
Beyond it? You don't mean...
Th-The outdoor bath?
Take a look. The semicircular
depression ends here.
In other words, when the
culprit committed the crime...
He ran across the water as
if he was riding on the wind.
I-Impossible. Such a stunt—
I-It's the kamaitachi!
Nakama Daigo (35)
Writer
There really is a kamaitachi!
Don't be stupid.
This must be some kind of trick of
a flesh-and-blood human, of course.
Th-The kamaitachi...
The kamaitachi appeared?
Is it true, Heiji?
How do you know?
Inspector Yamamura just came here...
...and told us.
Th-The suspect is a kamaitachi.
It was just an idiot pretending
to be a kamaitachi.
But wasn't it the kamaitachi that
destroyed the room we decorated?
The fluorescent light suddenly shattered,
and all the balloons we put up popped.
BB pellets.
What?
There are BB pellets on the floor.
Come to think of it, your late husband
played survival games, didn't he?
Ono Takami (34)
Inn Landlady
Yes.
Where is his air gun now?
Aside from valuables, all my husband's
possessions are in the storehouse.
Then the culprit must have taken it from the
storehouse and shot through the sliding door.
One of the sections can be flipped open.
But even though there were ten balloons,
they popped at nearly the same time.
No one could do that in the dark.
Well, with enough shots,
you could probably pop ten.
I don't think it was the BB
pellets that popped the balloons.
There are only three on the floor.
What's this smell?
What's up?
Do you smell something?
Be careful, you two.
The shards of the light bulb
are still on the floor.
Shit. My watch flashlight is going out.
I'll have to use my phone's light.
Untitled
Playing
What do you think you're doing to my Kazuha?
What?
What about me?
Not Kazuha, c-cooking.
Doesn't it smell like
someone's cooking something?
You're killing me here.
Sorry.
That's not food. That's the smell
of a bathroom or cleaning detergent.
Ono Kohei (7)
Landlady's Son
Also, it was cold because it got
covered in rainwater or something.
Hey, that's right. It got on me, too.
And the windows weren't
even open. Weird, right?
Either way, we know nobody here did it.
When the old man screamed, we were
all standing in front of this room.
But I'm impressed you knew it was
the old man just from that scream.
I just thought it might be and asked
the landlady for confirmation.
I'd heard a similar scream before.
When? Where?
When a TV station came to report on the inn,
we were offering free foot
massages to our guests.
But with the cameras around,
our guests declined,
so my father-in-law had no
choice but to accept a massage.
The way he screamed in pain then
sounded very similar to that scream.
You recorded that program, didn't you?
Yes. You should be able
to view it in the office.
Take us there.
Okay.
Everyone else stay together in one room.
Sheesh.
There's something I wanted to tell you,
but this kamaitachi has ruined everything.
What? What did you want to tell me?
Well, actually, the other day on the
Ebisu Bridge in Osaka, he said...
“What are you doing to
my darling Kazuha?”
“I'll freaking kill you!”
D-Did Hattori-kun really say
that to the investigator?
I might be a little off, but
that's more or less what he said.
Wh-What did Hattori-kun do after that?
He managed to throw me off the scent.
But I think Heiji might...
He might...
Henchman
Might actually think I'm his henchman.
What?
Masters say that kind of stuff all
the time in historical dramas.
Like, “Don't touch my darling henchman.”
Kazuha-chan!
I don't think Hattori-kun
thinks you're his henchman.
H-Huh?
This looks like a rather brutal massage.
Yes.
They do sound exactly the same.
By the way, did any of the guests
bear a grudge against the old man?
He was very generous towards his customers,
so I think they probably liked him.
By the customers, you mean...
Yes. He was very hard on me,
the waitstaff, and cooks.
I heard there was a head chef who
he practically threw out of the inn.
Do you remember that person's name?
I don't know.
I heard about it when I
married into the family.
Apparently, they had a child.
By the way, do those two
writers stay here often?
Yes. Koyanagi-sama comes only occasionally,
but Nakama-kun stays all the time.
Come to think of it, they were
both here that day one year...
...when Kohei nearly drowned
in the outdoor bath.
What?
The storehouse was first
broken into that day, too.
Between taking Kohei to the hospital and
the police arriving, it was total chaos.
I didn't even have time to clean
the outdoor bath that day.
Did they do anything strange that day?
Not in particular.
Though they do seem a little
different this time.
Previously Nakama-kun didn't have a mustache,
and Koyanagi-sama wasn't wearing glasses.
Couldn't they just have felt
like changing their appearance?
You're right.
This snow isn't letting up, though.
Yes.
Aw, shit!
It's been one hour and twenty-eight
minutes since we found the body.
If we don't solve the mystery
behind the trick soon,
the snow will change the
area around the crime scene.
How do you know the exact time?
It was dark for a while.
My watch is painted with luminous
paint that allows me to—
I see. So that's how it is.
That's why they...
Um, this may be a bad time...
But since it's cold, would
you like some kudzu gruel?
Ah! I appreciate the offer.
That would warm us up.
I see.
So that's how it is.
If you look closely...
...ghosts are never what they seem.
What? Recreate the incident?
Yeah. Upon hearing the old man's
scream, we came to this outdoor bath,
which was a shortcut to the
annex where he was staying.
But since we had to cross the
bath to get to the annex,
we decided to exit the inn and come
back in through the back door instead.
Naturally, it was after we confirmed there
were no transparent platforms in the water.
Now let's go outside and head to
the annex through the back door.
Hey, aren't you coming?
No. It's cold outside,
and the annex is far way.
Sheesh.
This is how we came to the annex,
but the breakers were switched off,
and it was pitch black inside.
When we turned on a light,
we saw the cut sliding door,
and when we entered the room,
we found the murdered old man.
This is how it went, right?
I think so.
But what is this supposed to tell us?
Doesn't it mean there's someone
who could have gotten here quicker...
...than the people who took the back door?
Wait, what are you doing here?
It was faster to come
through the outdoor bath.
What?
The outdoor bath?
Yeah.
But your clothes don't seem that wet.
Did you take off all your clothes and
wade butt-naked through the bath?
N-No.
I ran across the water.
Can you really do this?
Yeah.
Here I go.
Hey!
What?
H-He just ran across the water.
Seriously?!
See?
Th-There must be a transparent
platform or something in the water.
Wait, what? Huh?
Th-There's no platform.
Why is the water so slimy, anyway?
It's kudzu gruel.
What?
Kudzu gruel?
Yeah. Though to be precise,
it's in a phase between liquid and
solid before it becomes kudzu gruel.
It's a phenomenon known as dilatancy.
If you apply a weak gentle force,
it feels like a sludge-like liquid.
But if you apply a strong force at once,
it becomes rock hard like a solid.
As proof, remember how Kohei-kun
said he nearly drowned...
...when he tried to chase
after the kamaitachi?
That's because the water
then was the same as right now.
It's like a bottomless swamp.
I-Indeed.
So the culprit came through here?
Yeah.
What?
Then they met up with us
after killing the old man.
Isn't that right,
writer Koyanagi Midori-san?
What?
That's why you switched off the annex's
breakers and cut the sliding door.
It'd be easier for you to meet up with us...
...if we were distracted by the sliding
door when we turned on the flashlight.
But what about the kudzu powder?
It would take a massive amount of kudzu
powder to make this special water.
A few days ago, the storehouse was robbed.
She must've stolen it then.
But what was she going to do with all the
kudzu powder she mixed into the water?
The water in this hot spring
flows directly from the source.
With enough time, it would
wash away on its own.
Then, the person who destroyed Kohei's
birthday party decorations...
Was Koyanagi-san.
If she didn't cause a fuss to draw
the cops away from the storehouse,
she couldn't get the sickle.
But how did she pop the balloons?
With a water gun.
What?
Kohei-kun said it smelled like a
bathroom or detergent, remember?
It was probably the smell
of lemons or something.
Maybe she put fruit juice in
the water gun and shot it.
Fruit juice dissolves the
rubber used in balloons.
The missing water gun probably
belonged to your late husband, too.
Didn't you keep it in the storehouse
along with his air gun?
Yes.
You may have forgotten,
but before the incident, someone
cut my cheek in the storehouse!
And I wasn't standing near
the light bulb when it broke!
Besides, couldn't anyone else have
performed the trick you just described?
Chewing gum.
What?
You stuck some on the light bulb, right?
While deliberately bumping your head on the
lampshade and pretending to be annoyed.
My science teacher said if you stick
something on the surface of an old light bulb
to create a difference in temperature,
they become prone to shattering.
Besides, the culprit probably used
Heiji-niichan's luminous watch...
...and the light from Kogoro-no-ojisan's
cigarette to cut them in the dark.
But why were you cut when you didn't
have anything that produced light?
B-Because...
Because you cut yourself.
With a box cutter blade or something
similar you have hidden under your nails.
You could hide the blood on your nails...
...by pressing it to your face and
smearing blood on your hands.
Besides, you created the opportunity to
go to the storehouse in the first place.
You made us believe there could be
a kamaitachi and call the police.
Then you used a water gun and air gun
to destroy the birthday party room,
in order to draw the police away from the
storehouse where the sickle was kept.
When we gathered in front of the birthday
party room, you played the old man's scream.
P-Played?
Yeah. She recorded the old
man's scream from the TV report...
...with a smartphone or something,
and set it to play on a timer.
To finish things off, while we were heading
to the annex through the back door,
she ran across the water,
arrived at the annex before us,
and stabbed the old man
to death with the sickle.
Then she cut the sliding door, switched
off the breaker, and met up with us.
And if a police officer was among us,
the police would prove for you that
you couldn't have committed the crime.
Did I get anything wrong?
W-Wrong?! There's no evidence to
prove anything you're saying!
You normally wear contacts, right?
What?
The landlady said you weren't
wearing glasses before.
I heard on TV that people
who aren't accustomed...
...to wearing fake nails have
trouble putting in contacts.
What?
Isn't that why you're wearing glasses today?
Which means normally you
don't wear fake nails.
You probably don't have any spares.
Which means it should still
be stuck to your nail.
The blood from when you
cut me and Mori-no-occhan.
B-But why would you kill my father-in-law?
Your chapped hands.
What?
My mother's were chapped, too.
From being tormented by that old man.
Does that mean the cook who was
cruelly fired by the old man was...
That's right. She was my mother.
What?
My mother started looking
for a new job right away,
but word had spread that
she'd been fired from here.
No one would hire her.
She worked so hard to feed me.
In the end, she died two years later.
But why was she fired?
Because the master of this inn,
who was good friends with my mother,
was offered a marriage proposal.
The girl was the only
daughter of another inn.
If they got married, they could merge
their inns and expand their business.
W-Was that-?!
That's right!
If not for you, my mother wouldn't have
suffered and died the way she did!
You were one of my targets, too.
What?
But when I saw how your hands were
chapped like my mother's, I decided not to.
Besides, I didn't want that
boy who nearly drowned...
...in the outdoor bath to experience
what I went through.
Does that mean you're the one who sent that
photo of the kamaitachi to the magazine?
Yeah. I wanted to see if I
actually could walk on water,
and I thought if rumors
spread about the kamaitachi,
guests would stop using the outdoor bath,
making it easier for me to execute my trick.
But why a kamaitachi?
Because her hatred was driven
by her mother's chapped hands.
What?
The kamaitachi legend was
originally though to come...
...from cuts on the skin
created by the vacuum...
...in the center of whirlwinds, but now the
established theory is that the sudden cooling...
...caused by the heat of vaporization causes
the skin to split open and become chapped.
That's why kamaitachi legends
are common in snowy regions.
I-I heard about it on a monster show on TV.
Look.
As promised, I erased the audio file.
File Deleted
Thanks.
You're such a good kid, Conan-kun.
Hattori-kun.
Huh?
I heard from Kazuha-chan.
You said, “What are you
doing to my Kazuha?” right?
This again?
It wasn't “my,” it was “you bastard.”
I said, “You bastard, what
are you doing to her?”
What?
Kazuha's like a darling little sister to me.
My... You bastard...
Well, that's that.
Heiji, you idiot!
What did you say?
K-Kazuha-chan!
It takes one to know one!
Idiot, idiot, idiot!
You're an idiot!
Kudo got to confess in
front of Big Ben in London.
I can't accept that I said something
so important on the Ebisu Bridge.
By the way, the kids in the Detective
Boys copied that audio file.
What?
Haibara uses it as her ringtone.
H-Her ringtone?
What do you think you're doing to my Kazuha?!
Episode Preview
I am Bishamonten.
It's the woodpecker strategy, Ran-chan.
One-eyed?
Destroyer of the woodpecker.
You don't know?
He claims he was forced to shoot.
Could this person really be...?
A god of war.
The Darkness of the Prefectural Police
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is “The Darkness
of the Prefectural Police, Part One!”
Kawanakajima
Next Conan's hint!
Kawanakajima!
Don't miss the next episode.
Let's hear it one more time.
My Kazuha!
Or maybe it's too much.