Nagano Prefecture Mt. Saijo
Wait. Wait a minute.
I'll apologize. I'll apologize!
Besides, think about it.
If this gets out, you won't get off easy.
Your life will be over.
Those desperate to live, die.
Those desperate to die, live.
I am Bishamonten.
The god of war who will
destroy the woodpecker.
With the same feelings we've
always held still in our hearts,
we fly powerfully into our twentieth year.
The sounds of woodpeckers are heard
across an ancient battlefield.
An incident occurs that
shakes the police force.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Darkness of the Prefectural Police
(Part One)
"The Darkness of the
Prefectural Police, Part One!"
Hey, this place you said
you wanted to stop by...
Yeah. We came all the way out to Nagano.
We can't leave without stopping at
the the Kawanakajima battlefield,
where Uesugi Kenshin fought Takeda Shingen.
Yeah!
But, Dad, have you always
liked history that much?
What? You didn't know?
Come to think of it, the other day
Okino Yoko played Princess Yu,
the woman who fell in love with Yamamoto
Kansuke, general of Takeda's army,
on a historical drama special.
Also, speaking of Nagano,
there's Shinshu soba.
Hey, what was that strategy called?
You know, the one they used in
the battle named after a bird.
The woodpecker.
It's the woodpecker strategy, Ran-chan.
Detective Yui!
The woodpecker strategy involved,
like the woodpecker that pecks wood
and lies in wait for insects to
come out from the other side,
one part of Takeda's army
attacked Uesugi's forces
that had taken up position
in the mountains at night.
As they hurriedly descended
from the mountains,
the other half of his army
attacked and flanked them.
Supposedly Yamamoto Kansuke suggested
this famous strategy to Takeda Shingen.
Right, Kan-chan?
It's not like I came up with it.
Of course, Uesugi Kenshin expertly saw
through this disappointing strategy,
and drove Takeda Shingen into a predicament.
I told you, I didn't come up with it.
What are the three of you doing here today?
Is it a case?
No. We were canvassing the area,
so we stopped by on our way back.
Besides, Inspector Yamato
said he'd never been before.
Nagano Prefectural Police
Inspector Yamato Kansuke.
One-eyed and of a large build.
Long-haired and walks with a cane.
The closest person to the description of Rum,
the number two of the Black
Organization that Haibara mentioned.
Could he really be...?
What, kid? Is there something on my face?
Uh, no.
Hey, Yamato!
What are you doing here?
Saegusa Mamoru (37)
Nagano Prefectural Police Inspector
You'd better not be on a date with your
childhood friend Uehara while you're on the clock.
I-It's not like that!
Saegusa-san, what are you doing here?
Oh, right.
We're on our way to the
hideout of a wanted robber.
We thought we'd pay our respects
to Shingen before we go.
We're not here to waste time.
After all, I'm not Aburakawa.
My name isn't Aburakawa.
It's Akiyama.
Akiyama Shinsuke (26)
Nagano Prefectural Police Sergeant
Didn't I tell you?
Last year my parents got divorced,
so I took my mother's maiden name Akiyama.
Sorry, sorry.
Anyway, have you seen our squad leader?
Your squad leader? Isn't that Takeda-san?
Kano Shoji (45)
Nagano Prefectural Police Lieutenant
Yeah. He was supposed to meet us
here, but we haven't found him.
He's not answering his phone, either.
Where on earth is he?
Maybe he got the wrong place.
He's getting pretty old.
Maybe so.
Let's try somewhere else.
Sorry to have bothered you.
Oh, right. If you see Takeda, tell him this:
Even if it's an order from the higher ups,
I'll never go back to that squad,
even if it kills me.
Yeah, I'll tell him.
But you're perfect for our squad.
It's too bad, really.
Did something happen with that Takeda guy?
Yes, a while ago.
Anyway, if you're visiting
the Kawanakajima battlefield,
want us to show you around?
What? Really?
Well, the investigation
meeting isn't for a while.
Even if we headed back to headquarters,
we'd just be drinking your awful coffee.
How rude!
The chief said my coffee's
been getting better.
That was the previous chief of section one.
I believe our current chief prefers tea.
He likes tea with that face?
You're not one to criticize
other people's faces.
In any case, shall we hurry?
Kansuke Shrine
First, this is the Kansuke Shrine where
Yamamoto Kansuke is said to have died.
And this is Kansuke's grave.
Yamamoto Grave
And this is the Doaibashi where Kansuke's
head and body matched up perfectly.
M-Matched up?
Yeah.
Kansuke's servants stole
back several of the heads
of allied generals that were taken
by the enemy during the battle.
But since they were all covered in blood,
they didn't know which was Kansuke's.
But when one of the heads matched up
perfectly with Kansuke's still armored body
that was left on the battlefield,
they knew it was Kansuke's head.
That happened here on this bridge.
R-Really?
Say...
This is more of a tour of famous locations
related to Yamamoto Kansuke
than a tour of the battlefield.
Well, actually...
It can't be helped.
When you have a childhood friend
with a name as similar as Yamato
Kansuke, it's only natural to be curious.
Despite their similarities, however,
I hope he doesn't do anything
like die recklessly
over a failed strategy like
the real Yamamoto Kansuke.
Of course, you don't seem like the
type to be frustrated by failure.
What did you say?
Now, now, you two.
It's nearly time.
Why don't we finish the tour by
seeing the Chikumagawa River?
Okay.
Wow.
What a beautiful sight.
And the river is beautiful, too.
I can't believe a battle
once took place here.
Come to think of it, I think
there's a poem about the river.
"The bones of the dead lying in the water
conjure images of warriors in
the water of the red river."
The red river?
What does it mean?
It's unclear if this was a tributary
feeding the Chikumagawa River,
but over a thousand men are said to have
died in the battle of Kawanakajima.
But Asai Retsu wrote this
poem based on the legend...
...that the river in front of the shrine turned
red with the blood of the fallen warriors,
for three days and nights
to put their souls to rest.
Since the battle, the river has been
known as Akagawa, the Red River,
and the shrine has been
known as Akagawa Shrine.
It's an exaggeration.
There's no way a river could
turn red for three days and...
Blood?
Is that...
...a person's head?
Uehara, call forensics immediately.
Yes, sir.
Hey, was it really a human head?
Yeah.
It belonged to someone we knew.
What?
This is Nagano Prefectural Police
Section One Inspector,
and Takeda Squad Leader,
Inspector Takeda Shigeru.
But where's the body?
Here.
Unfortunately, not only was it burned,
but it's been slightly damaged as well.
We won't be able to match the head to the
body like they did with Yamamoto Kansuke's.
Ch-Chief Takeda?
By who?
Why?
Judging from the body, it was
burned over half a day ago.
So why did just the head come down the
river from the bridge we were on earlier?
Maybe because it was hung
from the bridge's railing.
What?
Over there.
There's something that looks
like a string hanging down.
The culprit probably put the head
and fake blood inside a plastic bag
or something and set it up
so the string would break
and fall into the river after
a certain amount of time.
He probably put rocks in
the bag so it would sink.
We even heard a splashing
sound, so that must be it.
Right, Kogoro-no-ojisan?
What? Y-Yeah.
But why fake blood?
Real blood would have congealed and
wouldn't have flowed down the river.
But why go through the trouble?
He probably wanted to make it easier to spot.
I spotted it because I happened
to be looking at the river.
But otherwise, it would've just looked
like trash floating down the river.
U-Um, there was an unnatural
bloodstain on his forehead.
When we sprayed luminol
on it, a strange mark...
What?
Is this the letter X?
No, it's no ordinary X.
It looks like an animal's footprint.
It's a woodpecker.
Woodpeckers need feet that allow
them to cling tightly to trees.
That's why their claws are shaped like an X.
You didn't know?
A-A large one-eyed man?
Whoever did it must have
really hated Takeda.
Though we can't be sure if
this is really his body.
No, it's all right.
From the tip of his shoe that barely
survived the fire, we found his right big toe.
We should be able to do a DNA comparison.
I see. Do it immediately, then.
Kuroda Hyoe (50)
Nagano Prefectural Police Section One Chief
Come to think of it, wasn't the Takeda
Squad supposed to take a warrant...
to the hideout of a wanted bank robber?
We couldn't get in touch
with him all morning.
He wasn't at Hachiman Shrine where
we supposed to meet him, either.
We didn't have a choice, so we entered
the robber's house ourselves.
But he seemed to know we were coming,
because it was already empty.
After that, we split up to
look for Squad Leader Takeda.
Then we heard someone found a body.
You don't think he ran ahead to
confront the robber himself, do you?
A-And got himself killed instead?
Takeda would never do that.
He was willing to kill in
order to arrest a suspect.
I'm more interested in the woodpecker
footprint left on his forehead.
We need to figure out what it means.
Maybe he used a woodpecker's foot
just because he wanted to make an X?
It does look like a kill mark.
Your deductions are as violent as ever.
Does anyone know what woodpeckers
might have to do with Takeda?
No.
Not in particular.
The Woodpecker Society.
When I was part of the Torada family,
my late husband mentioned something.
Apparently there's a group in
the Nagano Prefectural Police
known as the Woodpecker Society.
I've never heard of it.
What kind of group are they?
When I told him I was an
ex-cop, he clammed up.
He didn't speak very well
of the group, though.
I see. In any case, if he burned
the body under this bridge,
someone may have seen a fire or smoke.
Saegusa, Kano, Akiyama, canvas the area.
Yes, sir.
Yamato, Morofushi, and Uehara.
Find anyone who may have a grudge
against Takeda because of a case.
Got it.
Look closely.
Like Yamato said, if that woodpecker's
footprint is a kill mark,
the suspect could be planning
to come after us next.
And Detective Mori, I've heard about you.
I'm sorry, but I'm going to have you go
with Uehara and the others for a while.
You're the one of the people
who discovered the body.
Y-Yes, sir!
Of course.
Hey, Detective Yui.
What is it, Conan-kun?
There's something I want to ask you later.
Nagano Prefectural Police Headquarters
What? He was unconscious for
almost ten years in the hospital?
At the police hospital?
Section One Chief Kuroda was apparently
in some kind of serious accident.
I see. No wonder he's been
temporarily transferred at his age.
Yes. Normally you're transferred from the
MPD to the local police when you're younger.
Then that burn...
It probably had something
to do with the accident.
And his right eye is false.
Apparently the nurse who removed the
bandages on his face was paralyzed with fear.
The stress from the accident
turned his jet black hair white.
He was like a different person.
A different person?
He said that since he woke up, he has trouble remembering little details.
Are you interested in the
section chief, Conan-kun?
Not really.
I don't blame you if you are.
He looks like the head honcho
of some organization.
Your face isn't much better than his, though.
Shut up already.
Well? Did you find anything?
Yes. I reviewed all the cases Takeda-san
worked on the reference room computer.
The two cases in which Takeda-san shot
and killed the suspects stood out.
He... He killed them?!
Yeah. The first case happened nine years ago.
A man on drugs was shooting
off a gun in the city.
The second happened six months ago.
A man was holed up inside
a bank with hostages.
They both died when Takeda
shot their brains out.
And both cases were submitted to
the prosecutor with dead suspects.
Then maybe someone close to
them resented him for it.
That's what I thought, but the parents
of the man who holed up in the bank
killed themselves over their son's
crime, and he had no siblings.
And the parents of the man who fired
the gun nine years ago died of illness.
All that's left is the suspect's
grandmother who's over eighty.
That grandma could never commit that crime.
Come to think of it, did you see
any suspicious smoke or persons?
What?
I thought that bridge was on your
rehabilitation course for your leg.
Today I had some stuff to do, so I didn't go.
Sorry. I've got something to do again.
E-mail me if there are any
developments in the case.
Kan-chan?
Inspector Yamato called her
"that grandma" earlier.
Does he know the culprit's grandmother?
Yeah. The man who fired a gun
in the city nine years ago
was actually one of Inspector
Yamato's childhood friends.
I remember him and Kan-chan often playing
until the sun set when they were kids.
I was almost a little jealous.
You were jealous, weren't you?
Don't tell Kan-chan.
Okay!
I see. That's why he said that at the shrine.
I'll never go back to that
squad, even if it kills me.
It's because Takeda shot
and killed his friend.
Yes.
Right in front of his eyes.
What?
Kansuke-kun was there at the scene
as a member of Takeda's squad.
Of course, since the incident had produced
casualties, he said he was forced to shoot.
Where is it? Where is it?
The report on that case should be...
Found it. This is it.
Death by gunshot wound to the head.
That's it. So that's how it is.
I need to tell them about this quickly.
Hey, where's Yamato?
Where did that bastard go?
Did something happen?
Saegusa's group discovered something
during their canvassing.
This morning a witness saw someone who
looked like Yamato near the bridge.
What? But Kan-chan—
Rather, Inspector Yamato said
he didn't go there this morning.
In any case, we need to talk to him.
Yamato Kansuke
It's Kansuke-kun.
Kansuke-kun.
Is Kano-san there?
He's asking where Kano-san is.
Kano-san said he was going home
because he noticed something.
He keeps spare copies of reports
of cases he's worked on at home.
He seems to have gone home.
What about Kano-san?
I had over ten missed calls from Kano-san.
He's not answering his phone.
Something must have happened to him.
I'm on my way there. Meet me there.
Hey, wait.
What's wrong?
He felt something was wrong,
since he received a number of
missed calls from Kano-san,
so he's heading to Kano-san's house.
I see.
Then let's head there as well.
Yes, sir.
Morofushi.
Yes?
Don't let Yamato out of your sight.
What?
Today's the day that shooting
happened nine years ago.
It's the day his friend died.
You understand what I'm
trying to say, don't you?
Yes.
It's unlocked.
Kan-chan's shoes...
Where is he?!
Kano-san!
I am Bishamonten.
Kan-chan.
The god of war who will
destroy the woodpecker.
Episode Preview
Only three woodpeckers remain.
Three remain
Komei, are you...?
That's right, Kansuke-kun.
It's you.
You find surprising elements to help
solve cases and back up his reasoning.
The Sleeping Kogoro's bag of wisdom.
That's what they said about you
at the station, Edogawa Conan-kun.
"The Darkness of the Prefectural Police
(Part Two)"
The next episode of Conan is "The Darkness
of the Prefectural Police, Part Two!"
Rope
Next Conan's hint!
A rope!
What sound do woodpeckers make?
Don't miss the next episode.
Knock-knock, knock-knock.
I'm still in here.