While visiting the Kawanakajima
battlefield in Nagano,
we ran into Nagano Prefectural
Police Inspector Yamato
and his associates, who showed us around.
When we arrived at the Chikumagawa River,
we discovered a human head
floating down the river.
The head that had a woodpecker's
footprint pressed into its forehead
with blood belonged to Nagano
Prefectural Police Inspector Takeda.
Furthermore, Lieutenant
Kano of Takeda's squad
was found hanging from his neck in his home.
With the same feelings we've
always held still in our hearts,
we fly powerfully into our twentieth year.
What happened within the organization?
Detectives become victims one after another.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Darkness of the
Prefectural Police (Part 2)
"The Darkness of the
Prefectural Police (Part 2)!"
Th-The god of war...
...who destroys woodpeckers?
What are you talking about, Kan-chan?
I didn't say it.
It's what was written in the
e-mail I received from Kano-san.
Received Message
I am Bishamonten.
The god of war who will
destroy the woodpecker.
Kuroda Hyoe (50)
Nagano Prefectural Police Section One Chief
The cause of death seems to be suffocation
resulting from pressure to the neck.
Based on postmortem
lividity and rigor mortis,
he likely died between one hour
to one and a half hours ago.
Based on the presence of Yoshikawa lines on
his neck that appear when a victim struggles,
Kano-san was likely strangled
from behind by someone...
...who then wrapped a rope around his
neck and hanged him from the ceiling.
Saegusa Mamoru (37)
Nagano Prefectural Police Inspector
Couldn't there have been several culprits?
It took three of us to get Kano-san down.
Akiyama Shinsuke (26)
Nagano Prefectural Police Sergeant
Y-Yeah.
No. If you sat the body in a
chair placed on top of the desk,
a single person could hang him.
Even someone with a handicapped leg.
Indeed.
Is that a ringtone?
Isn't this Kano-san's?
There's an e-mail from Takeda-san
on Kano-san's phone.
What? Is it from Chief Takeda's murderer?
Most likely.
What does it say?
"Only three woodpeckers remain."
Three remain.
I see.
Since a woodpecker's footprint
was left on Kano's forehead,
it's likely that his remaining three
targets are members of the police force.
Bring it on.
Let's show him what happens when
you make enemies with cops.
Yes, sir.
Inspector Yamato.
What do you think of this rope
that was around his neck?
Now that you mention it...
It is strange.
Kan-chan, put on some gloves.
I already touched him when
I took him down. Does it matter?
By the way, Kansuke-kun,
there's a witness claiming
they saw you near the bridge
where Takeda-san's body was discovered.
I said I haven't been to the bridge.
They must've mistaken someone else for me.
You don't look like someone who'd
be easily confused with another.
The same goes for you,
Section One Chief Kuroda.
What? He was murdered?
You mean that Kano guy we met this afternoon?
Yes. He was found hanging in his house.
I was looking for people who may have
resented Lieutenant Kano
with Inspector Takeda.
It led us to the shooting nine years ago
and the man who holed up
inside a bank six months ago.
Kano-san was in Takeda's squad both
nine years ago and six months ago.
But I thought most of the family members
of the culprits Takeda shot were dead,
and the only one left is
the shooter's grandmother.
Yeah, but she could never
cut off someone's head,
or hang a strangled man from the ceiling.
So we don't have a prime suspect, then.
No, there is one.
What?
Nine years ago, his friend was
shot right in front of him.
You mean...
And he objected to the
shooting six months ago.
Komei, are you...
That's right, Kansuke-kun.
It's you.
You suspect me?
Even parasites inside a
lion will eat their host.
You bastard...
There's no way Inspector Yamato did it.
You know that, don't you,
Inspector Morofushi?
You've known each other since
childhood, and you're great friends.
Great friends?
That's news to me.
Yeah. I don't think of us that way, either.
I'll be investigating on my own from now on.
Tell that to Chief Kuroda.
Do as you please.
Kan-chan?
Huh? Did I say the wrong thing?
Come to think of it, I heard Yamato was
your mentor when you first became a cop.
You'd better not side with
him just because of that.
Our squad chief may have been killed,
but you're still a part of the Takeda Squad.
Y-Yes, sir.
Hey.
Kano came home because he
noticed something, right?
Y-Yeah.
Do you remember what prompted that?
I'm not sure.
He had his finger up to
his forehead for a while
and then suddenly seemed to have an epiphany.
His forehead?
I think the woodpecker's footprint
on Chief Takeda's forehead
must have reminded him of something.
What happened next?
The two of us split up to keep canvassing.
We let Section Chief Kuroda
know about it, too.
Also, he sent an e-mail to Inspector Yamato.
Though apparently he was so concerned
with Kano-san's missed calls
that he hadn't read it yet.
Wait, why do we have to
talk to this kid, anyway?
Then Kansuke-kun could have known
that Kano-san returned to his home.
Hey! Do you actually suspect Kan-chan?
Is that a problem?
Yeah, a huge one!
That's right. There's no way Inspector
Yamato of all people would murder someone.
Aburakawa-kun, is that your phone?
It's Akiyama. Try to remember it already.
Besides, it's an e-mail, not a phone call.
What?
What is it, Akiyama-kun?
Uh, nothing. I-I'm going to go change.
I got pretty wet from canvassing
in the rain. My house is nearby.
You'd better come back soon.
Got it.
Come to think of it, his
mom lives around here.
Yes. I believe she runs
the salon on the corner.
I am Bishamonten.
I am...
The god of war who will
destroy the woodpecker.
The burned body under the bridge and
Inspector Takeda's head were a match?
Yeah, with the big toe of his right
foot that barely survived the fire.
Where are the others?
Inspector Yamato decided to investigate
on his own for various reasons.
Morofushi, I told you not to
let him out of your sight.
Sorry, but he and I just
don't seem to get along.
Where are Akiyama and Saegusa?
Akiyama-kun went to his mother's home
to change out of his wet clothes.
Since he hasn't come back after some time,
Inspector Saegusa left to check on him.
Morofushi? This is Saegusa.
Did something happen?
You won't believe this!
After changing at home, he got in
his car and headed for Mt. Saijo!
Mt. Saijo?
Yeah, the cottage where the
wanted robber was hiding out.
I'm on my way there now.
Meet me there.
Sheesh.
Why are you coming with us?
Why not? Anyway...
Why is there a spare tire in your back seat?
For some reason we've been getting
a lot of flat tires lately.
It's there for convenience.
Is it in your way?
No, I'm okay.
Huh? That tire...
I am Bishamonten.
The god of war who will
destroy the woodpecker.
He's not at the cottage.
We don't have a choice.
We'll have to search the area.
There!
H-Help...
He's being dragged behind a car!
My phone...
My phone!
Akiyama!
Who would do this?
Before the car dragged him off
the cliff, Akiyama-kun said...
My phone...
Didn't he?
Call Akiyama's phone.
Okay.
I found it.
This does seem to be Akiyama-kun's phone.
He received one message at 5:32 PM.
I remember that.
After reading the message, Akiyama-kun
left for his house so he could change.
Then he headed to Mt. Saijo from home
instead of returning to the station.
What does the e-mail say?
"I found the murdered Takeda's phone
among a certain person's possessions,
and I'm using it to write this message."
"They're a member of the police force,
so make up an excuse to come to
the cottage at Mt. Saijo."
"We'll discuss the details there."
Yamato Kansuke
"Yamato Kansuke."
Kan-chan sent the e-mail?
He's the one who brought
Akiyama here and killed him?
Can we get in touch with Yamato?
No. On my way here, I tried calling him
numerous times, but his phone seems to be off.
Let's put out a BOLO for him.
Yamato must be the suspect.
Not necessarily.
After all, the e-mail wasn't sent
from Inspector Yamato's phone.
The culprit could have sent it
pretending to be Inspector Yamato.
Besides, if Inspector Yamato is the culprit,
then I don't think he'd
leave a phone that would
serve as evidence without
even looking for it.
Wh-What are you talking about?
Sorry. He got into our car at some
point, but this boy is actually—
You find surprising elements to help
solve cases and back up his reasoning.
The Sleeping Kogoro's bag of wisdom.
That's what they said about you
at the station, Edogawa Conan-kun.
R-Really?
But it's possible we arrived
as he was looking for the phone,
and he was forced to leave.
It's possible that Akiyama
did some quick thinking.
See? I knew it.
Yamato's number is blocked.
Blocked Contacts
Yamato Kansuke
Realizing Yamato was going to kill him,
Akiyama did this so the
evidence wouldn't be erased.
No way...
Or else the suspect did
it to make us think that.
Yeah. That's what I thought, too.
Until I received a call from forensics.
A call?
Yamato's fingerprints were found
on the rope used to hang Kano.
We'll put out a BOLO for
him as a murder suspect!
W-Wait a minute.
Inspector Yamato touched the rope
to get Lieutenant Kano's body down.
They weren't just on the part of
the rope wrapped around the light.
They were also found on the
rope wrapped around his neck.
It's proof that he used
that rope to strangle Kano.
No way.
Morofushi, did Yamato touch the rope then?
No. I was standing by the
body until forensics arrived,
but nobody touched the rope around his neck.
And when you consider the witnesses claiming
to have seen someone who looked like Yamato
near the bridge where
Takeda's body was discovered
and that Yamato resented the
Takeda Squad over the shooting
that happened nine years ago and
the bank case six months ago,
a BOLO seems appropriate to me.
But Inspector Yamato
would never kill someone!
We should prioritize
justice over emotions right now.
If we let him get away
now, we might regret it.
Okay. Set up checkpoints.
We'll capture Yamato one way or another.
Don't go easy on him just
because you know him.
Think of him as a murderer who's
killed three cops in a row.
Let's head back to headquarters
and hold an investigation meeting.
What about Akiyama's body?
The ground is muddy because
of the rain, and it's dark.
The body can be collected in the morning.
Saegusa, you're riding with me.
Morofushi's will be a bit tight
with the spare tire in the back.
Hey.
Is it true that Inspector Yamato
took Lieutenant Kano's body down?
Yes.
Kan-chan stood on a chair, and
Akiyama-kun raised the body a little.
But Inspector Yamato has a bad leg, right?
He's tall, and he tends to act
without considering the consequences
if he thinks he can save someone.
Come to think of it, he did
the same thing the other day.
The other day? Did something
similar happen before?
Yes.
The parents of the man who
holed up inside the bank
couldn't stand the abuse they were
receiving from their neighbors,
so they hanged themselves.
When Kansuke-kun arrived at the scene,
he got on a chair and took them down.
Unlike in Kano-san's case, he untied
the knots attached to the beams.
How was the rope used to
hang Detective Kano tied?
Well, he was hanging from a rope
made from two connected loops.
The upper loop was wrapped
around the light's bar.
Kansuke-kun grabbed the upper loop with
both hands and removed it fro the lamp.
Did that rope look like this?
Yeah, it did.
When the body was lowered to the floor, do
you remember where everyone was standing?
Inspector Morofushi and Akiyama-kun
were crouching near the body.
The others were standing
a short distance away.
Did anything happen then that
might have distracted everybody?
Now that you mention it,
a message from Takeda-san's phone
thought to be sent by the suspect
was sent to Kano-san's phone,
which was in the body's coat pocket.
It said, "Only three woodpeckers remain."
And when you compare that with the message,
"I am the god of war who will destroy the
woodpecker," that Kansuke-kun received earlier...
That means excluding the
murdered Akiyama-san,
the culprit planned to kill two more people.
But who and for what purpose?
What's all this woodpecker stuff about?
I can't say for sure yet, but I
think I know who his next victim is.
What?
It's the names.
I'm not sure why,
but all three people who've been
killed so far have names very similar
to generals who were killed at
the fourth Kawanakajima battle.
Inspector Takeda, who was murdered
first, is Takeda Nobushige.
Lieutenant Kano Shoji, who was
killed next, is Hajikano Tadatsugu.
Detective Akiyama Shinsuke,
who was just killed, used to go by
Aburakawa, so he's Aburakawa Nobuyoshi.
Who are the other two?
Saegusa Morinao is only one letter
off from Inspector Saegusa Mamoru.
And then there's the man who felt
responsible for the failed strategy
and threw himself at his enemies, the
Takeda army general Yamamoto Kansuke.
What?
Who are you saying hates Kan-chan?
It may have something to do with
the bank case six months ago.
Can you tell me more about it?
You mean the case where Inspector
Takeda shot the suspect.
The suspect was actually
about to surrender himself
after responding to the police's
efforts to persuade him.
But the Takeda Squad surrounding
the area decided to act.
Realizing this, the suspect began
firing his gun inside the bank.
Takeda-san felt forced to enter
the bank and shot the suspect.
Kansuke-kun was furious with
Takeda-san over the incident.
Don't tell me you think it's okay to
kill suspects just because you're a cop!
...he said.
Come to think of it, the suspect's
phone was lost during the case, too.
Apparently he was talking to
someone right until he got shot.
He said something like,
"If I get caught, you're finished."
"They'll know where we got the
gun and find out about X."
Find out...
...about X?
Is that true?
Yes. Akiyama-kun let it slip the other day.
You didn't know?
Oh, right. Inspector Saegusa might know
more since he's on the Takeda Squad.
Huh?
Kano Shoji
Why is Lieutenant Kano's
address under "ta?"
Kano-san's name used to be Tsuchiya,
but he took his wife's name
after he got married.
Tsuchiya...
X...
What does the suspect want, anyway?
What does he have against the
dead of the Kawanakajima battle?
No.
Not the dead, but X.
Though it seems Kansuke-kun would
be on his hit list either way.
Where have you been?
I was worried about you.
Sorry.
Sheesh.
Did you get in touch with Yamato?
No, not yet.
We were talking the whole time.
Chief Kuroda, we got a tip from someone who
says they saw someone who looked like Yamato.
I'd like to go check it out,
but no cars are available.
Perfect timing.
Morofushi, can you lend me your car?
Actually, I...
Is there a problem?
No. It's just that Saegusa-san
is a slightly reckless driver.
Morofushi.
Yes, sir.
It's an emergency. Let him use it.
That's an order.
Yes, sir.
Go ahead.
Thanks.
If the information's credible,
let us know right away.
Yes, sir.
I am Bishamonten.
The god of war who will
destroy the woodpecker.
Received Message
Go like the river.
Yamato
"Go like the river."
Kansuke-kun...
Episode Preview
I received this e-mail from Kansuke-kun.
I'll reveal what I know about X!
How do you know about X?
X?
That's what I thought at the time.
I didn't know the Woodpecker
Society was called X.
Kan-chan...
I came to pick you up like you asked, Yamato.
The Darkness of the
Prefectural Police (Part 3)
The next episode of Conan is
"The Darkness of the Prefectural Police (Part 3)!"
Woodpecker
Next Conan's hint!
A woodpecker!
They make such a nice sound with their beaks.
Don't miss the next episode.
I guess you could say they
like pecks on the lips.
Seriously?