Detective Conan Episode 813 "The
Shadow Approaching Amuro"
Poirot
Thanks for waiting.
Here are your ham sandwiches.
Hey.
You've been watching that
customer this whole time.
What?
Really?
Yeah.
I'm surprised you noticed
while reading about the races in
the paper and eating breakfast.
Well, I am a great detective.
He's not dressed like a salary man.
But he's at a café before work hours start.
Is that what's bothering you?
Some people are like that. We're like that.
But he ordered sandwiches
instead of the breakfast set
most customers order at this hour
without even looking at the menu.
Does that mean he's a regular?
But he's not speaking to
Amuro-san or Azusa-san,
and he's been watching the
counter this whole time.
It's simple.
He's interested in Azusa-chan.
Oh, of course. You really
are a great detective.
I could handle that mystery
before I even have breakfast.
No, while I eat breakfast!
Actually, he's been watching not Azusa-san,
but Amuro-san this whole time.
Why?
With the same feelings we've
always held still in our hearts,
we fly powerfully into our twentieth year.
An unexpected figure closes in on Amuro
Toru, who works at the Poirot Café.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Shadow Approaching Amuro
The Shadow Approaching Amuro!
What? We're playing games at
the professor's house again?
That's all we've been doing lately.
What do you want to do, then?
You were assigned homework
today. You should do that.
Then like Haibara-san says,
we should do our homework first.
No way. Let's play games.
Conan-kun?
He was at Poirot this morning.
He probably lives or works nearby.
Why are you so interested in that man?
Because he's interested in everything.
But there's always a case
when Conan-kun is interested.
Thank you.
He's coming out.
If you're so curious, let's follow him.
Great idea!
Sounds more interesting than
playing games at the professor's!
It sounds like something the
Detective Boys would do.
Okay, let's go!
Okay.
Don't let him notice you.
Hey, guys.
Conan-kun and Ai-chan, hurry.
I'll pass.
Don't follow him for too long.
You should go home and do your homework!
This is your fault.
Make sure those kids get home.
Huh? Conan-kun.
You're alone?
Oh... Yeah.
The man who just left?
Yeah.
I don't know his name, but he
has been coming a lot lately.
What does he do?
I don't know...
He's gone. He disappeared.
He must have gone into a store.
Okay! Let's split up and
check all the stores!
Yeah!
He was watching me?
Yeah, it looked that way to me.
I'm sure it did. I saw the same thing.
And he even followed me the other day.
He followed you? When?
Three days ago, I think, when I
went shopping at the supermarket.
And?
And what?
You're just ignoring him?
Well, it's not as though
he's done anything to me.
A member of the organization...
Do you think he could be?
Probably not.
But you don't know all the members
of the Black Organization, right?
Well, no.
But I didn't get that feeling from him.
Is it possible he's a public
security officer like you?
I see you love investigating as much as ever.
Hey, how'd it go?
I didn't find him.
We checked all the shops, right?
Yeah, but he wasn't at any of them.
He must've disappeared.
I'm serious.
He disappeared in the shopping area.
Yeah, yeah.
He must be hiding something.
Hey, it's Amuro-no-niichan.
What's your problem, Haibara?
I just remembered I have
something to do. I'm leaving.
What? Ai-chan!
This is your fault, Genta-kun!
How?!
It's the guy!
What's going on?
Indeed. Why is he following Amuro-san?
This is getting more and more suspicious.
What are you doing?
There's a dead end up ahead.
Do you have business with me?
Not really. I have business this way.
This is a dead end.
You've been coming to Poirot a lot lately.
Why are you following me?
Hello?
Amuro-san, it's an emergency!
What?
Go buy some ice cream!
Ice cream?
We accepted an order for an ice cream soda,
even though the manager
forgot to order some!
Go buy some as soon as you can!
I'm counting on you, detective.
He disappeared again!
It's the same shopping area as yesterday.
Let's search all the stores again.
Yeah!
Could it be?
Thanks for waiting.
Here are your ham sandwiches.
He ordered sandwiches instead of the breakfast
set most customers order at this hour.
He was at Poirot this morning.
He probably lives or works nearby.
He was watching me?
Yeah, it looked that way to me.
I'm sure it did. I saw the same thing.
And he even followed me the other day.
He followed you? When?
Three days ago, I think, when I
went shopping at the supermarket.
Conan-kun!
It's no use. He wasn't in any of the stores.
I couldn't find him, either.
How about this store?
He's not in there.
He disappeared again?
No.
What?
He'll appear soon.
What? Soon?
Hey, Conan!
He's late. Could it be?
What?
Amuro-san knew he was following him, right?
Yes. What about it?
That's it.
Hey, Conan!
Amuro-san!
Conan-kun.
Mister, you're...
...a baker, aren't you?
Huh?
A baker?
Yesterday, he had sandwiches here
in the morning and evening.
Yes, sandwiches made by Amuro-san.
He always keeps his fingernails clean.
You're right.
And he has a distinctive
mark on his forehead.
What is that mark on his head?
Is it from a hat?
It's from elastic.
That's right. A hat with an elastic band.
It's the type of hat worn by
cooks who work with starchy foods,
like bread or noodles, in the kitchen
instead of interacting with customers.
Now that you mention it,
there's one in the shopping area.
It's no use. He wasn't in any of the stores.
I couldn't find him, either.
How about this store?
There was a bakery.
A baker who doesn't interact
with customers makes bread
early in the morning and makes more
as necessary in the afternoon.
He's not dressed like a salary man.
But he's at a café before work hours start.
Is that what's bothering you?
Some people are like that.
In other words, his job allows him a lot
of free time in mornings and evenings.
That's it. He didn't disappear,
he went inside the bakery.
So he was an employee, not a customer!
Naturally, if you wait outside
the bakery long enough,
he'll change in the back
and show himself again.
At least, that's what I thought,
but he didn't appear no matter
how long we waited before.
Hey, Conan!
He's late. Could it be?
What?
Amuro-san knew he was following him, right?
Yes. What about it?
When Amuro-san noticed him, I thought
he might make a desperate final play.
A final play?
You wanted to ask him directly, didn't you?
About how Amuro-san makes his sandwiches.
What?
Really?
I heard that lately the sandwiches
here have been delicious and cheap.
When I came to try them,
I was shocked...
...by how delicious they were!
The ham sandwiches were especially fantastic!
I wanted to make sandwiches
this delicious myself.
But no matter how much I watched
you, I couldn't figure it out.
So I followed you and examined the bread,
ham, lettuce, and mayonnaise you bought.
But you weren't buying anything special.
Even when I tried to make them
with the same ingredients,
I couldn't achieve the same flavor.
How do you make such delicious sandwiches?
It's all I thought about every day.
I thought I'd go crazy.
How?! How do you make such
delicious ham sandwiches?!
Mister, that's Amuro-san's trade secret.
There's no way he'll tell you.
I know. I know, but...
I don't mind telling you.
What? Really?
Cheap ham is fine.
But choose the leanest pieces possible.
Then coat them in olive oil.
That's it. The rich flavor of
the ham comes from olive oil.
Yes, but that's not all.
I use ordinary mayonnaise as well.
What? Miso?
So that's why there was
miso in the refrigerator.
Just use a pinch of miso.
Putting miso in mayonnaise tastes good?
Olive oil and miso are
an excellent combination.
I see. The sauce complements
the olive oil covered ham.
This is ordinary hot water,
and this is ordinary lettuce.
What?
Have you noticed that if the
inside of the sandwich is cold,
you only feel the coldness
instead of tasting the flavors?
Yeah.
You're right.
I wasn't thinking about
that while I was eating.
Now you don't have to worry about that.
But it'll make the lettuce soft.
You don't have to worry about that.
No way!
Using water the temperature
of bath water is the secret.
Furthermore, the lettuce will
keep its crispness for longer,
even if kept between bread if you do this.
Amuro-san, who on earth are you?
Now for the bread.
This type of bread is fine.
What?
That's what you were using?
It cuts the price in half.
W-Well, yeah, but...
But the flavor...
Actually, slightly stale bread is better.
What? Why?
This is my secret.
A steamer?
Try touching the bread inside.
Wow. It's so soft!
I steam them slightly
before making sandwiches.
The bread will absorb all
the moisture it lost.
I see. That's why they were warm
even though you didn't toast them.
And it keeps the cost down.
Amuro-san was taking his
café job seriously, too.
That's the miso mayonnaise sauce.
But this softness doesn't last long.
It's good for eating in the store,
but not great for takeout.
I'm a baker.
I can do something about the bread, so...
So please let me sell your
sandwiches at my store!
What?
Mister, you're asking for too much.
Sure.
Seriously?
You fell in love with my ham sandwiches.
You're the kind of man I want to sell them.
They're ready. Go ahead.
Thanks for the food!
It's delicious!
It's so soft!
This sauce is delicious!
You're right. The bread is warm,
and it's not cold on the inside.
This is it. This flavor.
I think selling them in the store at Poirot
and selling them to take home
at your bakery is a great idea.
Thank you.
I'll develop a bread that stays soft for hours,
and do my best to faithfully recreate these.
I swear I won't sully Poirot's name.
Thank you.
Actually, if you're going
to use the Poirot name,
we should get permission
from the manager first.
Excuse me.
This is Amuro.
Hey, Bourbon.
Vermouth.
I heard you've been conducting
a secret investigation recently.
An investigation? Into what?
I wouldn't be calling you if I knew.
Of course.
Don't take it too far.
Apparently he has his eye on you.
He has his eye on me? Who?
Gin.
Episode Preview
What are you looking at?
Shono Kyona's blog.
Come to think of it, she mentioned something...
...that suggested Kitami Saya's
secrets were on her blog.
Yeah.
In any case, open the door!
But...
Kyono-san?
The Actress Blogger's Locked Room Case
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The Actress
Blogger's Locked Room Case, Part One!"
Fresh Cream
Next Conan's hint.
Fresh cream!
The movie Detective Conan:
The Darkest Nightmare
Don't miss the next episode.
opens in theaters today!