I'm counting on you, Professor.
Come on!
We have a winner!
Two passes to the Hotel
Beika West cake buffet!
Congratulations!
With the same feelings we've
always held still in our hearts,
we fly powerfully into our twentieth year.
The words she writes in her blog
aren't as sweet as desserts.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Actress Blogger's Locked Room Case
(Part One)
"The Actress Blogger's
Locked Room Case, Part One!"
Those look delicious!
There are all kinds of cakes.
Can we seriously eat as many as we want?
Yeah. After all, it's a cake buffet.
Professor, you have some
incredible luck with lotteries.
We were actually going for the
assorted high-end sirloin cuts.
What? Really?
Yeah...
A cake buffet, huh?
Ran would probably be jealous if she heard
about it, so I guess I won't tell her.
I got a ton of cakes.
Genta-kun, you took too many.
I'll get some cakes, too.
What?
You're limited to two.
B-But...
Okay, just two.
Well?
What happened with that police officer?
What?
You sent me a picture asking if I
recognized that man with the scary face.
Oh, Section One Chief Kuroda.
He said a lot of suspicious things,
but it was all to catch the culprit.
I did wonder why he knew
so much about me, though.
You find surprising elements to help
solve cases and back up his reasoning.
The Sleeping Kogoro's bag of wisdom.
That's what they said about you at
the station, Edogawa Conan-kun.
But since he's part of the
Nagano Prefectural Police,
we'll rarely have any dealings with him.
We shouldn't have to worry about it.
Really? That's fine, then.
Thanks for the food!
So good!
It's delicious!
Genta-kun, you should slow
down when you eat.
But if I don't hurry,
they'll run out of cakes.
You're planning on eating more?
Whoa. What is this?
A helicopter?
That's one of the Petite Falcons
that are popular right now.
But where did it come from?
I'm sorry.
Did I hurt you?
What? No...
I just bought that at the toy
shop in front of the hotel.
When I turned it on, it started flying away.
Wait, are you the actress Kitami Saya-san?!
You were in "Gomera!"
Hey, you're the girl who got her
blood sucked by the enemy monster!
Keep your voices down.
Kitami Saya (24)
Actress
No one knows I'm staying at this hotel.
We can take a picture together
after I get you a new cake.
All right!
You're as crooked as ever.
You're planning to increase
your blog's popularity
by taking a picture with those
kids and uploading it, aren't you?
Perhaps you'll title it "With the
kids I met at the cake buffet."
Shono Kyona (25)
Actress
Th-That wasn't my intention.
Hey, isn't that Shono Kyona and Kitami Saya?
No way! I heard they hate each other.
Come to think of it,
they've been competing for popularity
on their blogs because of a TV show.
I think the loser has to shave her head.
What?
Shave her head?
Seriously?
Naturally, I'll win.
You don't know that.
Oh, you haven't seen my blog?
I discovered one of your secrets.
If you don't want me posting it,
you should hurry up and forfeit.
And you already have short hair.
Shaving your head should be no big deal.
But...
I'm going back to the room.
Weren't you going to take pictures
of yourself eating cake?
I can't imagine taking
the same pictures as her.
Go buy what I told you to get!
O-Okay...
Huh? Is that you, Sakurako-san?
C-Conan-kun!
What are you doing here?
Aren't you a housekeeper?
Her manager caught a cold.
My agency was asked to look
after her until she gets better.
Yonehara Sakurako (23)
Housekeeper
But why are those two
staying in the same hotel?
They don't seem to like each other.
Because they're co-starring
in a romantic drama
set at this hotel that's
starting this spring.
I know the one.
It's called "Top Class," right?
It got pretty good reviews,
so they're making a sequel.
Really?
What's it about?
Two women reveal their true selves
to try to bring each other down.
Want to watch? It's pretty interesting.
R-Really?
Uh... I'll pass.
Well, I'd better go.
I need to go shopping.
E-Excuse me.
After you deliver that to her,
could you come see me in room 504?
There's something I want
to discuss about her.
Oh, okay.
See you later, then.
Hey, Conan-kun.
What are you looking at?
Shono Kyona's blog.
Come to think of it, she
mentioned something
that suggested Kitami Saya's
secrets were on her blog.
Yeah. That's why I've been looking,
but it's just her playing with a dog,
introducing her favorite comics, and cooking.
There aren't any secrets anywhere.
Hey!
What is this!
I told you to get a super
fine bristled toothbrush.
I-I'm sorry. That's all they had.
I'll go look for a replacement immediately.
Forget it.
Filming starts at six. Come wake me at five.
I'm going to nap until then.
O-Okay! Got it.
Just so you know, if anyone else comes here,
I'm not opening the door for them!
Make sure you come at five to wake me!
Got it?
Y-Yes!
Let's see. Room 504, 504...
There it is. This is it.
A heart?
Ow! Ouch...
Oh, I'm sorry!
Are you okay? Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
Oh, there's something stuck to your door.
What? What is that?
Could it be from a fan?
What did you want to discuss?
Actually, it doesn't matter anymore.
Sorry.
What?
I'm stuffed.
Dinner's next.
Already?
You're overeating, Genta-kun.
It's an emergency!
In any case, open the door!
But...
Did something happen, Sakurako-san?
Conan-kun.
Kyona-san won't answer the door no
matter how many times I ring the bell.
What?
That's really bad.
Saya-san.
I don't have any scenes today, but
Kyona-san starts shooting in thirty minutes.
She needs time for makeup, too.
She needs to be on set.
You heard her! Unlock the door
immediately using the master key!
Y-Yes, ma'am.
Kyona-san, what's wrong?!
They're going to start filming.
Kyona-san! Kyona-san!
You're in here, aren't you?!
Kyona-sa—
What's wrong?
Bellhop, call an ambulance and the police!
What?
Got it!
What's this?
Conan-kun, that's her key card, right?
Yeah.
But that doesn't make sense.
This hotel's doors don't lock automatically.
What?
How did the murderer lock this room?
It's a locked room, then?
What's this white stain?
Whipped cream?
Which means...
Wh-Who could have done this?
Could the culprit be...?
Who would do something so cruel?
Could it be?
Y-Yes...
I was asked to come wake
her at five in the evening,
but she wasn't answering the door no
matter how many times I rang the bell.
I went to ask reception to unlock the door,
and had the bellhop unlock the
door using the master key.
Th-That's when I found Kyona-san collapsed
in this bedroom and bleeding from the head.
I see. But, Sakurako-san,
aren't you a housekeeper?
I was asked to take care of her until
her manager gets over her cold.
I can't believe this happened
at another one of my jobs...
Do you think I might be cursed?
Uh, well...
As far as I'm concerned, Conan-kun,
who's at every crime scene you are,
seems far more cursed to me.
When did she die?
Forensics believes between 4:00 and 4:30 PM,
she was struck repeatedly on the
head with a thin rod-shaped weapon.
But is it true that the key card was here in
a hotel without automatically locking rooms?
Y-Yes.
Then that makes this a locked room murder.
B-But it doesn't make sense.
Kyona-san said she wouldn't
open the door for anyone else,
so I had to come wake her at five.
Why did she open the door?
For nobody else?
That sounds like a strange
way to make that request.
I know.
It's a stalker.
She was almost attacked by a stalker
pretending to be one of the staff.
Since then, she stopped inviting
even acquaintances into her room,
except for the person she
designated beforehand.
I read about that in a magazine, too.
Must be hard being famous.
By the way, aren't you an actress as well?
She's Kitami Saya-san,
the actress who was supposed to appear
in the drama alongside Kyona-san.
The drama's set in this hotel,
so she's staying here, too.
I heard at the front desk that
Kyona-san wasn't answering the door.
I was worried, so I came with Sakurako-san.
But I had no idea that
this had happened to her.
In any case, we're going to
investigate the room more closely.
Saya-san, Sakurako-san, and Conan-kun,
since you discovered the body,
could you wait in Saya-san's room?
Okay.
All right.
Saya-chan, is it true?
Was Kyona-san really killed in her room?
Yes. The police are in her room right now.
Wait. Seriously?
What about today's shoot, then?
You moron!
There's not going to be a
drama, much less a film shoot!
Please ask my makeup artist to leave.
Huh? Saya-san, your makeup artist was here?
What?
Of course!
The focus of today was Kyona-chan and
Saya-chan's reunion at the hotel!
Really?
Then why did you say that, Saya-san?
Say what?
You said you didn't have any scenes today.
What?
As though you knew today's filming
would be canceled anyway.
I-I was confused.
Oh, so it was just a mistake.
That can't be helped, then.
It's her.
The problem is the key card
that was inside the room.
Key cards can be slipped under
the door even after locking it.
But no matter how hard you did it,
it wouldn't reach a room in the back.
Could she have transported it
using the toy helicopter? How?
And how did she get into the room
when Kyona-san said she would only
open the door for Sakurako-san?
It seems unlikely that she'd invite her
in since they were arguing earlier.
In any case, I still don't have enough
pieces to assemble this puzzle.
Huh?
Is this room right under Kyona-san's?
What?
Kyona-san's room was room 604.
Yes, it seems that way.
The room is mostly laid
out the same way, too.
Yes.
By the way, what was
that thing on your door?
It was a prank played by a fan.
What are you talking about?
Some weird envelope.
It was stuck to Saya-san's door.
What kind of envelope?
There was a large black heart drawn on it.
It was taped just under the peep hole.
Do you want anything to drink?
I have some basic stuff.
I'll have an iced coffee, please.
I'll have some tea.
Okay.
It's incredible, though.
I can't believe they set you up in
this huge room while you're filming.
The drama was going to
promote this hotel as well,
so the hotel arranged for the two
leads to stay in these rooms.
Though since the drama is canceled,
I'll probably have to leave tomorrow.
Yeah...
Conan-kun, what are you looking at?
Saya-san's blog.
What?
I was just thinking yours is really
different from Kyona-san's.
Different how?
Kyona-san is in all the pictures on her
blog, but Saya-san's not in most of hers.
And even when she's in
them, she's really small.
Unlike Kyona-san, I don't like to
promote myself through pictures.
If you want to see me, watch my dramas.
Huh...
By the way, what did you do with that?
With what?
The Petite Falcon.
You were flying it around the cake buffet.
Oh, that?
It wasn't flying right, so
I threw it away somewhere.
What? What a waste.
Now we can't fly ours together.
T-Together?
What?
They're here!
My friends can come in, right?
Excuse the intrusion!
I bought you a Petite Falcon.
Thanks.
That thing is really hard to fly.
It doesn't fly as well as we thought.
I believe it takes quite a deal of skill.
Let me see.
Wow!
This is easier than I thought.
Uh, oh. It's stuck in the AC.
Is there some kind of stick?
Here.
Thanks.
You'll get stuck again if
you keep flying it inside.
Why don't you take it somewhere more open?
You're right.
Well, we're going outside to play.
Tell the police for us.
Hey, wait!
Well?
Have you figured out how she locked the room?
No, not yet.
But I know how she got in and
what she used for a weapon.
What? It's really her, then?
Yeah, definitely.
No way!
But she seems so nice.
Women are different on the inside.
The murder victim seemed
malicious, rude, and vulgar,
but if you look at her blog,
you'll see she had a surprisingly
sensitive and conscientious side, too.
What? Where'd you get that?
Her nail polish bottles were
arranged in numerical order.
They're even a brand that you have
to turn over to see the number.
What?
Wait a minute. Then that photo...
I see. So this is the secret she discovered.
But would she murder her over this?
Wait a minute.
Wait.
In English, this...
I see. I get it now.
I know why she had to kill Shono Kyona-san.
Episode Preview
What? A rice cooker?
That's it. So that's how it is.
The culprit locked the room without
using it for its intended purpose.
You'll see how she entered the room
if you look through the peep hole.
Sheesh.
Who is it this time?
What? Agasa-san?
The Actress Blogger's Locked Room Case
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The Actress
Blogger's Locked Room Case, Part Two!"
Toy Helicopter
Next Conan's hint.
A toy helicopter!
Thanks for making the movie a huge hit.
Don't miss the next episode.
Bring on the night!
It's "Nightmare," not "Night More."