Hit and Run of Love
We visited a cake buffet after Professor
Agasa won tickets in a lottery.
While there, we met Kitami
Saya-san and Shono Kyona-san,
Kitami Saya (24)
Actress
two actresses competing for
popularity on their blogs.
Shono Kyona (25)
Actress
However, concerned that Kyona-san wasn't
getting up in time for her film shoot,
Yonehara Sakurako-san asked a
hotel bellboy to unlock the door.
Kyona-san, what's wrong?
They're going to start filming.
Kyona-san! Kyona-san!
Kyona-sa—
What's wrong?
Bellhop, call an ambulance and the police!
What?
Got it!
What's this?
Conan-kun, that's her key card, right?
Yeah.
But that doesn't make sense.
This hotel's doors don't lock automatically.
What?
How did the murderer lock this room?
It's a locked room, then?
What's this white stain?
Whipped cream?
Which means...
Wh-Who could have done this?
Who would do something so cruel?
Could it be?
With the same feelings we've
always held still in our hearts,
we fly powerfully into our twentieth year.
The key to solving the locked
room case is an ordinary toy.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Actress Blogger's Locked Room Case
(Part Two)
"The Actress Blogger's
Locked Room Case, Part Two!"
Well?
Have you figured out
how she locked the room?
No, not yet.
But I know how she got in and
what she used for a weapon.
What? It's really her, then?
Yeah, definitely.
No way!
But she seems so nice.
Women are different on the inside.
The murder victim seemed
malicious, rude, and vulgar,
but if you look at her blog,
you'll see she had a surprisingly
sensitive and conscientious side, too.
What? Where'd you get that?
Her nail polish bottles were
arranged in numerical order.
They're even a brand that you have
to turn over to see the number.
What?
Wait a minute. Then that photo...
I see. So this is the secret she discovered.
But would she murder her over this?
Wait a minute.
Wait.
In English, this...
I'm hungry again.
What? Already?
Didn't you just say you were full?
Professor, can't you make anything?
Shouldn't you go home
and eat a proper dinner?
But my parents are at a meeting
for the shopping center.
They're coming home late tonight.
My mom gets mad when I eat too much,
so let's get some kind of snack.
You had all that cake earlier,
and you still want snacks?
Genta-kun, you're such a glutton.
Would you like some cheesecake, then?
I bought the ingredients so I
could try making it tomorrow.
Excellent.
Professor, yours is for breakfast tomorrow.
Breakfast...
But won't it take time to finish?
Apparently it takes only thirty to
forty minutes in a rice cooker.
What? A rice cooker?
Yes. Cooking rice isn't the only
thing a rice cooker can do.
It can even bake delicious cakes.
That's it. So that's how it is.
The culprit locked the room without
using it for its intended purpose,
to seal away the mistakes of the past.
This case certainly is full of mysteries...
The victim said she wouldn't open the door for anyone but her assistant, Sakurako-san,
but the culprit entered the
room and murdered the victim.
And despite the doors of this
hotel not automatically locking,
the key card was in the bedroom,
which is far from the door.
We have no idea how the culprit
escaped after committing the murder.
On top of that, we still haven't found the
rod-like weapon used to kill the victim.
All we know is that the victim
is actress Shono Kyona-san,
and that there will be a great
commotion about this later...
Should we ask the commissioner
for instructions?
Yeah.
Who is it?
I don't know...
Now, hold on...
Agasa-san?
What do you want?
C-Conan-kun?
Huh? Where's Agasa-san?
Professor Agasa is waiting
for you in room 504.
What?
Directly under this one
in the murderer's room.
D-Directly under this one?
That's actress Kitami Saya-san's room.
Yeah, it is.
Listen, Conan-kun.
I'm sure it's difficult for you to
understand, but the room was locked, and...
I-Inspector!
The commissioner just called to
say to do as Conan-kun says...
What?
I-I demand an explanation!
Why am I being suspected
of killing Kyona-san?
The key card was in the middle of her
room, so it's a locked room case, right?
On top of that, Kyona-san said she'd
only open the door for Sakurako-san.
Shouldn't she be your prime suspect?
W-Well, yes...
But Agasa-san...
You'll see how she entered the room
if you look through the peep hole.
Sheesh.
Who is it this time?
What? Agasa-san?
What? Th-That's... impossible...
What on earth...?
What on earth is going on?
All right!
What?
You got tricked!
It was a huge success!
W-Was that you kids?
Yes, indeed.
We recorded a video of
the professor on a phone
and played it back in front of the peep hole.
Th-Then when I saw the professor
earlier, was that...?
That's right.
I had Conan-kun do the same thing...
Just like Saya-san did when
she entered Kyona-san's room.
I see.
Saya-san recorded a video of
Sakurako-san with her phone
and used it to enter Kyona-san's room.
B-But I just met Sakurako-san today!
I didn't have time to
record a video like that!
Right?
Y-Yes.
Sakurako-san, when Saya-san
asked you to come to her room,
wasn't something stuck to her door?
What? Yes, an envelope...
An envelope?
Yes.
There was an envelope with a
large black heart drawn on it
stuck to Saya-san's door
just below the peep hole.
Saya-san said it was from a fan...
There was a phone inside the envelope.
By opening a heart-shaped hole in the case,
lining up the phone's camera with
the hole, and setting it to record,
she was able to take a video of
Sakurako-san ringing the doorbell.
Both Kyona-san and Saya-san's rooms
are at the end of the hallway.
The background in the video would
look just like her hallway.
B-But...
What about the key card?
It was next to the body in the bedroom!
This hotel's rooms don't automatically lock,
so how did the culprit lock
the door after leaving?
By using this toy helicopter you
were flying around the cake buffet.
A-A helicopter?
Could I borrow this room's key card?
O-Okay...
First, you tape a long string to
the rotor shaft of the propeller
and the end of the helicopter.
After wrapping tape around the end of
the string attached to the rotor shaft,
stick the tape on the key card.
Once you gently tape the helicopter to
the bedroom floor, you're ready to go.
All you have to do is pass the
two strings under the door,
slide the key card into the slot of the
locked door, and turn on the helicopter.
The rest is up to you guys!
Okay.
It's in.
All right! Start it up!
All right!
Here we go!
Ignition, on!
When you turn on the helicopter,
the string is wound around the rotor shaft,
and the key card slides under the door.
Once all the string has been wound up,
the force detaches the key card from
the string and falls to the floor.
I-I see. Instead of flying the helicopter,
she used it to wind up the string.
Yeah.
To finish the trick, you just pull the string
attached to the back from outside the room.
Hey! Pull, guys!
Got it!
The helicopter will be pulled off
the floor and towards the entrance.
If you pull really hard
once it reaches the door...
There!
See? Now you can retrieve the string.
Y-You're right...
As proof, remember the white cream
on the floor next to the key card?
Yeah.
That's because there was cream on the
skids on the bottom of the helicopter.
Saya-san's helicopter crashed into
the cake Genta was about to eat.
But, Conan-kun, the helicopter's
still in the room.
Yeah. That's why Saya-san dropped her hat
the moment she entered Kyona-san's room.
What?
She pretended to miss the hat rack.
And if she stuck double-sided
tape on the inside,
it should stay even if
she put it on the rack.
So it's probably still there.
Inside her hat is the Petite Falcon
she used to commit her crime.
There's even string wrapped around it.
He must be right.
Y-You're wrong!
It wasn't me!
I-I stuck the double-sided tape
on there so my hat wouldn't slip.
Yeah, that's right. It must've gotten stuck
there by coincidence when I dropped it.
Then why did you stand on the table?
What?
When my Petite Falcon got caught in the AC
vent, you stood on the table to get it for me.
Wow!
This is easier than I thought.
Uh, oh. It's stuck in the AC.
Is there some kind of stick?
Here.
Thanks.
There were cups on the table, so
normally a person wouldn't stand on it.
I-I...
And right in front of us,
there was even a selfie stick.
A selfie stick?
You can attach your phone to the end of a
selfie stick to take pictures of yourself.
It's a kind of tool. You can extend it to
take pictures of yourself from far away.
And it doubles as a weapon.
Most of the pictures on Kyona-san's blog are
selfies, but Saya-san's has none at all.
So that's most likely
Kyona-san's selfie stick.
Tell us, Kitami Saya-san...
What is Kyona-san's selfie stick
doing in your room covered in blood?
Isn't it obvious?
She discovered my secret,
so I used that stick to make sure
she'd never open her mouth again!
Y-Your secret?
Look. She uploaded my secret to her blog.
While pretending to introduce
her favorite comics.
Where's the secret?
It's right next to her face!
"The Hit and Run of Love!"
In Japanese, "hit and run"
is a baseball term, but abroad...
It means to hit someone with your car.
Yes, that's right.
Two years ago, I ran over
some drunk man with my car.
I'd been hiding it, but when I forced
my way into her room, she told me.
What's wrong with you? Has it been an hour—
S-Saya-san...
Where's Sakurako-chan?
She's not here.
Saya-san, what's going on?
There's nothing to say!
Hey, wait. Stop shouting.
Oh, I know.
Did you figure it out the code
in that photo of the comics?
Well? What are you going to do?
Will you surrender our contest, or
will you let your secret be exposed?
You might actually look
good with a shaved head.
You might get a sudden influx of nun roles.
It might make you even more popular.
And you'd have me to thank
for it, wouldn't you?
You should be grateful.
Saya-san, I'm not sure Kyona-san
knew about the hit and run...
What?
B-But the photo...
She said there was a code in the comics...
The code wasn't "The
Hit and Run of Love,"
but the series next to it
called "Looking to You."
She's usually precise, but that series
alone was arranged out of order,
and there were two copies of volume 11.
If you match the volumes to the 50
characters of the Japanese alphabet,
read volume 29 as it is, and read
from the left, it forms a sentence...
"Saya is 29 years old."
That's the only code she created.
That you'd taken five years off your age.
N-No...
But blinded by bias, all you could
see were the words "hit and run."
In baseball terms, a hit
and run is a risky play.
It seems your risk didn't pay off.
Agasa-san, that was another impressive
display of detective work.
Thank you.
Not at all.
By the way, Conan-kun...
I was surprised to learn
you know the commissioner.
What? But isn't the commissioner
of Section One Matsumoto?
Well, actually...
I knew you'd help solve the case.
The Sleeping Kogoro's bag of wisdom.
Who are you?
I'm Kuroda Hyoe. I've taken over as
commissioner of Section One of the MPD.
It's nice to meet you.
Thank you.
It's nice to meet you as well.
And it's nice to see you
again, Edogawa Conan-kun.
Episode Preview
There's no such things as aliens.
They do exist! My dead dad said so!
It's an alien! Help!
There might be something
behind last night's incident.
Looks like it's our time to shine.
The Disappointing and Kind Alien
The next episode of Conan is
"The Disappointing and Kind Alien!"
Cold Medicine
Next Conan's hint!
Cold medicine!
A person who takes cold medicine...
Don't miss the next episode.
...but just watches...
What are they doing?
They're watching out for a cold.
Yeah, yeah.