Detective Conan Episode 816 "The
Disappointing and Kind Alien"
Susan Trummelperman (22)
Office Worker
Nakashima Arisa (23)
We are extraterrestrials.
We would be pleased if you took a photo
to commemorate our meeting
and released it to the public.
He's even tapping his neck.
And referring to himself as "we"
when there's only one of him.
This is hilarious!
Wow!
Get closer!
We are extraterrestrials.
Wow, cool!
An alien?!
It's an alien! Help!
What's that?
He fell!
An ambulance?
Are you all right?
Hey, are you okay?!
Hanzaki Yasuo (42)
Hang in there! Are you okay?!
Are you okay?! Hey!
No way...
N-No way...
With the same feelings we've
always held still in our hearts,
we fly powerfully into our twentieth year.
The sudden appearance of an alien
leads to a surprising case.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Disappointing and Kind Alien
"The Disappointing and Kind Alien!"
It makes you doubt if he
has any common sense.
How could he kill someone by
pretending to be an alien?
What a good-for-nothing adult.
I know. I have no idea what he was thinking.
You're wrong!
Don't speak so poorly of Takedera-san.
Matsumoto Kota (6)
Beika Elementary School First Year
It was my fault... probably...
Who are you?
I'm Matsumoto Kota.
What do you mean, it's your fault?
Takedera-san always plays with us at
the children's center on his days off.
Aliens come to Earth not to invade our planet, but to become friends with us!
Takedera Hitoshi (26)
Office Worker
They want to get along with humans?
Yeah, so us Earthlings should—
He's making up stories again.
There's no such things as aliens.
They do exist! My dead dad said so!
I think that's why...
I see.
He was hoping to find witnesses
so word would spread.
Yeah.
So he wasn't good-for-nothing.
He was a nice, kind man.
Sorry for insulting him.
But ultimately he caused an accident.
He'll probably regret it
for the rest of his life.
What's going to happen to Takedera-san?
Hey, miss.
Are you the people who were present
when the accident occurred yesterday?
Yes.
Who are you kids?
I'm Takedera-san's friend.
I see.
Could you tell us what happened last night?
Sure. Actually, would you like to see?
What?
This is the alien?
There's this video, too.
An alien?!
It's an alien! Help!
Could you show me the photo again?
Sure.
Could seeing this alien
really have scared him?
It's clearly a poorly-made costume.
We knew what he was because
he called himself an alien.
He said, "We are extraterrestrials."
Yeah...
But the late Hanzaki-san...
...descended the stairs, was surprised
when he saw the alien below,
and fell when he tried to run.
But how did Hanzaki-san know it was an alien?
Because he called himself an alien, right?
Saying, "We are extraterrestrials."
You think he could've heard
that from all the way up here?
It certainly is strange.
I wonder what Hanzaki was doing here, too.
He probably wasn't visiting the
temple since it's abandoned.
There might be something
behind last night's incident.
It's not just an unfortunate accident.
Looks like it's our time to shine.
Yeah.
First we should investigate this Hanzaki guy.
Who are you guys?
Together...
...the five of us are...
...the Detective Boys!
What? My neighbor Hanzaki?
Yeah. Your downstairs neighbors said he
was friendly with his next door neighbor.
Well, neither of us had anything
to do since we're unemployed.
What was he like?
Tamai Tsuneyuki (40)
Hanzaki's Neighbor
An unlucky fellow.
Six months ago he was laid off
from the factory he worked at,
and last night he was
supposed to get paid, but—
Oh, whoops.
"Whoops" what?
Well, whatever. They're just kids.
Hanzaki was blackmailing someone.
What?
Blackmail?
Yeah. He went out last night
to get money from them.
That's why he was at Beimyoji.
Now that Hanzaki-san is dead,
this person X he was blackmailing
must be relieved.
Could X have killed Hanzaki-san, then?
What?
Do you know who he was blackmailing?
No way. You want to
investigate for yourselves?
He never locked his front door.
What?
It's not locked?
Yeah. He said he had nothing worth stealing.
There aren't any clues about who X is.
This room sure does stink of cigarettes.
He was a heavy smoker.
Where are these characters
from? He has so many.
They're karaoke giveaways.
He went all the time.
Maybe he was blackmailing
someone at the factory.
I think it was last month...
I'd rather work than blackmail someone.
You need to help me get a job.
Then I'll forget all about what happened.
He was trying to get rehired at
the factory he was laid off from.
Probably.
If they had the power to do that...
It could be his former
superior at the factory.
Huh?
Did Hanzaki-san work for
Sanko Heavy Industries?
Sanko Heavy Industries
That's a top-ranking company.
Of course not. Hanzaki worked for
one of Sanko's subcontractors.
I'd like to go determine who X was, but
since it's Sunday, the factory is closed.
I feel relieved.
We'll just investigate something else.
There is something I want
to ask about the alien.
Beika Police Station
We understand that you did it for Kota-kun,
but I was wondering where you
got the idea to become an alien.
I'm actually not the one
who came up with the idea.
What?
I asked for advice
from a fellow member of the children's
literature club from my college days,
my friend Omi Akira.
He's a good, innocent kid.
You should become an alien, then.
Let someone see you and
get your picture taken.
Have them spread the word
that aliens really do exist.
That's a great idea.
Omi Akira (26)
Office Worker
You should do it as soon as
possible. Tomorrow, even.
Yeah. I'm glad I asked you for advice, Omi.
I just took his idea.
Omi-san certainly does have
some interesting ideas.
We once put on a play for
children about aliens.
We are extraterrestrials.
We made the costume for that play.
So that's why it was so non-threatening.
It was made for kids.
So it wouldn't scare them.
Omi probably feels bad about
last night's accident, too.
He recommended that I appear
around eight at night.
He recommended that location, too.
But everything backfired...
Just to confirm, your
friend Omi-san is the one
who recommended that the alien appear at
8 PM at the bottom of the Beimyoji steps?
Yeah. Omi knows the area pretty well.
He lived there until he got a job...
...and started living at the Sanko
Heavy Industries employee dorm.
Sanko Heavy Industries?
Would we be able to see Omi-san
if we went to the employee dorm?
He said he goes to the gym on his days off.
Why do you want to see Omi?
Sanko Heavy Industries Beika Dorm
Omi-san went out last night at 7:30.
It's just a twenty minute walk
to Beimyoji from here.
He'd easily make the alien's
8 PM appearance.
Apparently, he works in the
production management unit.
He's also responsible for
coordinating with subcontractors,
so he's in a position to
influence hiring decisions.
Omi Akira-san must be X.
It wouldn't be strange if he
associated with Hanzaki-san,
and it's possible Hanzaki-san had
something on him and was blackmailing.
But there's something I don't get.
What are you talking about?
You still have doubts?
Omi-san asked Hanzaki-san to come to
Beimyoji at 8 so he could give him the money.
Then he convinced him to start
walking down the stone steps.
That's an alien!
What?
He had him spot the alien
played by Takedera-san.
Run! He'll get us!
It's an alien! Help!
He made him panic so he would fall.
That explains why Hanzaki
thought that was an alien.
Since Omi-san said it was.
In other words, this was a
premeditated murder carried out
by Omi Akira-san to silence
Hanzaki-san, who was blackmailing him.
Yeah, but...
What?
There wasn't any guarantee
that he would panic.
And would an alien that non-threatening
really scare an adult?
I guess not...
But he really was scared.
He screamed.
That's what I don't get.
There's no reason he should've been scared.
Could Omi-san have set something up?
You can't expect me to know the answer to—
Genta-kun!
Ow!
Are you okay?
What?
Ear, Nose,
and Throat Clinic
Could it be?
Beika Ear, Nose, and Throat Clinic
You were right on the money.
Now we can corner the killer.
He even left evidence.
But we could've found the killer sooner
if his neighbor would've told us.
What?
He must've realized what was
going on with Hanzaki-san.
There was no way. Not even the
news reported that he screamed.
But when I borrowed his bathroom, he told me.
He shouted, "It's an alien! Help!"
He must have realized the inconsistency then.
Shit.
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Then I'll tell the police.
Stop!
The world will believe you're
an idiot who came to check out
the crime scene, and
accidentally fell yourself!
I won't let you kill anyone else!
What I said made you realize
it was murder, right?
Then you followed us and figured
out who the killer was...
So you could blackmail him!
I'm out of work. I couldn't help myself.
It won't do you any good
if you get yourself killed.
You're absolutely right.
What did you kids want to talk about?
Omi?
What are you doing here?
The Detective Kids asked me to come here.
The Detective Kids?
Omi-san knew the late Hanzaki-san
through his job at the factory.
Really?
Blackmailed by Hanzaki-san,
Omi-san decided to silence him.
Huh?
Listen, kid.
As evidence of that, he
even tried to kill me!
What?
I was just trying to teach you a lesson
since you were throwing around
nonsensical accusations.
I obviously wasn't actually
trying to kill you.
You definitely were! Right?
Quiet.
We just saved your life. Why don't
you go to the police already?
Y-You're right.
Last night's death was an accident. Right?
He was scared by my alien costume.
The women who witnessed it told
the police the same thing.
But, Takedera-san, normally no one would
believe that costume is an alien.
Not unless you heard the person
wearing it call himself an alien.
"We are extraterrestrials."
But Hanzaki-san couldn't
have heard you from up here.
There are only four people in this world
who could've recognized that as an alien.
Takedera-san, who played the alien.
The women who heard him
call himself an alien.
And Omi-san, who suggested
the idea in the first place.
But Hanzaki thought it was an alien, too.
That's why he became
frightened and screamed—
He couldn't have.
That's quite the assumption.
Only he'd know what he thought it was—
Hanzaki-san's throat hurt.
Both his neighbor and Hanzaki-san
thought it was a cold at first.
But it was acute inflammation of the vocal
cords due to overworking his throat.
He couldn't even speak normally.
There's no way he screamed.
Then the scream I heard...
It could only have been the man who
knew you were playing an alien
and was here with
Hanzaki-san, Omi Akira-san.
You...
Last night Omi-san asked
Hanzaki-san to come here.
After knocking him out, he waited
for Takedera-san's alien to appear.
An alien?
It's an alien! Help!
Then he pushed him down the
stairs and killed Hanzaki-san
making it look as though he was
frightened by the alien and accidentally fell.
You couldn't just let him fall to his death.
The police might have suspected foul play
and thoroughly investigated the incident.
To make them believe it was an accident,
you needed witnesses like
Takedera-san and the two women.
Isn't that right, Omi-san?
Omi, don't tell me you...
He's delusional.
You know how powerful children's
imaginations can be.
Apparently he doesn't
know about the evidence.
Last night one of the women who
witnessed the incident took a video.
If the police analyze the
voice recorded in the video,
they'll know whose voice it was.
I had no idea his vocal cords
were giving him trouble.
I appreciate the money, but I need you
to get me a job at the factory, Omi-san.
That annoying raspy voice of his...
I thought it was an act to intimidate me!
Then Omi, it really was you?
Hanzaki saw me shoplift something
from a convenience store.
As an employee of Sanko Heavy Industries,
even a crime as petty as shoplifting
could land me in serious trouble.
I was just thinking about how to silence
him when you asked me for help,
and the idea came to me.
I realized I could use this naïve idiot,
who still cares for kids and is satisfied
working at a third-rate company.
Naïve idiot?
Did you call shoplifting petty?
Tsuburaya-kun, let him have it.
Okay. Omi Akira-san, you're
a good-for-nothing adult!
We are extraterrestrials.
He really doesn't look like an alien at all.
Y-You think so?
Real aliens are cooler.
Yeah.
I-If they even exist, I mean.
They'd be cooler than this guy.
Probably.
Yeah.
Yeah!
What kind of alien calls himself an alien?
Episode Preview
They said they'd come to get their things.
So they took everything in the room.
I'm Mori, a detective.
A detective?
I have some questions about
Kawaguchi Motoko-san.
Terakado-san had some concerns
regarding Kawaguchi.
I know exactly what's going on!
The Missing Fiancé
The next episode of Conan
is "The Missing Fiancé!"
Cuff Links
Next Conan's hint.
Cuff links!
The movie must have been tough for Ran-san.
Don't miss the next episode.
You, too. Wait, me, too?