Detective Conan Episode 17
"The Missing Fiancée"
I still think she needs to disappear.
Terakado Shigemi (67)
Spinster
The problem is what comes after that.
How to get rid of the body.
Matsuo Ryuji (23)
Mover
If we want to make sure she'll never be
found, we'd have to bury her in the mountains.
I agree, but I'm too old.
Let me handle it.
Thanks.
Rest in peace,
Kawaguchi Motoko (25)
Office Worker
Kawaguchi Motoko-san.
I want you to find Kawaguchi Motoko.
Mori Detective Agency
She's my fiancée who's suddenly disappeared.
Toriumi Haruki (33)
Kawaguchi Motoko's Fiancé
No matter how many times I
call her, she won't answer.
Toriumi Haruki-san...
O-Of the Toriumi Conglomerate?
Well, yes. Eventually I'm
going to take over everything.
So you're the son of a distinguished
family whose future is laid out for him.
I hate to say it, but while it
was love at first sight for me...
This engagement meant single office
worker Kawaguchi Motoko-san
would be marrying into money.
I can't imagine her giving
that all up and running away!
Motoko must have gotten involved
in some kind of incident!
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
A man's fiancée suddenly disappears.
Dangerous conversations as dusk approaches.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Missing Fiancée
"The Missing Fiancée!"
An incident, though?
I wonder what it is.
What are you doing here?
I got the day off school.
That's the apartment.
H-Hey!
Don't go without me!
Three nights ago, I got a
call from Kawaguchi-san.
She said she'd suddenly decided to move.
She couldn't tell me where
she was moving to, though.
In any case, she said she'd have
movers come pick up all her stuff.
Okubo Katsuko (45)
Apartment Landlady
The day after, like she said over
the phone, the movers came.
And took all her things.
The mover gave me this key and said
whoever hired him asked him to return it,
so I didn't find it strange.
But not being present for your own move...
...isn't a normal occurrence.
I see. Sorry to have interrupted your work.
Her office said the same thing.
Three nights ago,
she called her boss to suddenly
announce that she was quitting.
Even though she hadn't mentioned
anything about it during the day.
So Kawaguchi Motoko-san suddenly
disappeared from her home and workplace.
What on earth is she doing?
Excuse me...
Where's Motoko?
Kawaguchi Motoko-san seems to have moved out.
Suda Kumi (25)
Kawaguchi Motoko's Friend
What? She mentioned that three days ago.
Three days ago?
I'm Mori, a detective.
I'm Motoko's friend Suda Kumi.
Suda-san, did you see Kawaguchi
Motoko-san three days ago?
Yes. We ran into each other
in the city in the evening.
Was there anything strange about her then?
Huh?
Kawaguchi Motoko-san has been
missing since that night.
But when I saw her, she
seemed like her usual self.
She smiled and said she was on her
way to see Terakado Shigemi-san.
Terakado Shigemi-san?
Someone who lives at Beika Housing.
She's an older woman who lives alone,
and she sometimes goes to check on her.
Wait, does that mean Motoko went missing
after she visited Terakado-san?
In any case, we'll try
meeting with Terakado-san.
She may be the last person who saw her.
I hope we find some clues.
Yeah. And how long are you
going to keep following me?
Can I help you?
You must be Terakado Shigemi-san.
I'm Mori, a detective.
A detective?
I have some questions about
Kawaguchi Motoko-san.
Oh, I know her well. I owe her so much.
It happened about a year ago.
Are you not feeling well?
N-No. I'm a bit dizzy.
I'm old, so it happens once in a while.
Where do you live? I'll walk you home.
Huh?
She's always looked after me
since then. I'm grateful to her.
But I haven't seen her in about a month.
She didn't come here three days ago?
The water's boiling.
Can I go now?
Sure...
Could she have changed her plans?
She jumped when you called
yourself a detective.
Yeah. Could she have something to hide?
Aren't you the detective Mori Kogoro-san?
Yes, that's me.
Uno Mitsue (55)
Terakado Shigemi's Neighbor
I knew it. You really are him.
I believe a young woman may have visited
your neighbor from time to time.
You mean Kawaguchi?
Yeah, her.
I think she came in the
evening three days ago.
What?
So she did come.
Yeah, so why did she say she didn't?
That Kawaguchi girl was causing
trouble for Terakado-san.
Wasn't she helping her?
She said she was grateful.
At first, yes. But she began asking
for money every time she visited.
What?
I think it happened last week...
That wicked woman.
I'm going to teach her a lesson.
Oh, that's right. I was
taking out the garbage.
So she hated Kawaguchi Motoko-san.
When you consider she tried to
hide the fact that she visited,
it seems like something must have happened.
Hey, Shigemi-san.
I'm sorry I have to ask every time,
but it's just before payday...
The question is: how do we prove it?
What did she do with the body?
She couldn't keep it around forever.
But transporting a body would
be too hard for an old person.
That's Terakado-san's friend
who sometimes visits.
Terakado-san's?
I think she said he's a mover.
A mover?!
Oh, no! I'm such a blabbermouth.
What a conveniently well-informed neighbor.
It's not just the neighbor, though.
Yeah, that's him.
He's the mover who came to pick
up Kawaguchi-san's things.
I knew it.
I know exactly what's going on!
Hey, mister.
Terakado Shigemi murdered
Kawaguchi Motoko-san
for continuously extorting money from her.
Then she pretended to be Kawaguchi
Motoko-san and made a of couple calls.
She told her landlady that was was moving.
She told her boss she was quitting.
That way no one would find it suspicious
even if she suddenly disappeared.
Her friend, the mover,
helped her get rid of the body.
They probably stuffed the body in a futon
bag and carried it out of the apartment.
Then he pretended Kawaguchi
Motoko-san hired him
to transport her things to make
it look like she had moved.
That's the truth behind this disappearance!
That all makes sense, but...
Isn't that why it's so strange?
Strange?
The moment you began your investigation,
her friend Suda Kumi-san appeared.
Then she told us about Terakado Shigemi-san.
And when we visited her,
we met her rather well-informed neighbor,
who kept giving us more information.
On top of that, even the mover showed up.
It's all too convenient.
It's like they're trying to push you as
quickly as possible to the conclusion
that Terakado Shigemi-san murdered
Kawaguchi Motoko-san,
and disposed of the body.
Now that you mention it...
Which means...
Probably.
Terakado Shigemi-san and Matsuo Ryuji-san,
you erased Kawaguchi
Motoko-san from this world.
Impressive. Well done, Detective.
But if you don't find the body,
you can't have us arrested.
Mister!
I brought them.
Actually, she didn't really disappear.
The four of you worked together
to make it look like she had.
So you realized we made up the murder.
We wanted to save Motoko-san
from her fiancé Toriumi-san.
Yeah.
That's right.
From Toriumi-san?
At first Motoko-san was
drawn to Toriumi-san, too.
That's why she accepted his proposal.
But she couldn't handle the way he believed
everything would go as he wanted,
so Motoko asked to break
off their engagement.
But Toriumi-san...
It's too late.
What?
I already introduced you to my friends
and acquaintances as my fiancée.
What will people think of me if
we break off our engagement?
I refuse to participate in
something so embarrassing.
It doesn't matter if you love me or not.
There was nothing Motoko-san
could do anymore.
She knew what kind of man Toriumi-san was.
No matter where she went,
he'd use his money and power
to find her and bring her back.
There was no escaping someone like him.
Some men are just that horrifyingly selfish.
So you worked together to come
up with a way to save Motoko-san.
I enlisted Ryuji-kun, who helped me
along with Motoko-san one year ago.
We came up with the idea
of faking her murder.
If you made it seem like she'd
been murdered and her body hidden,
even Toriumi-san would have to give up.
And Motoko-san would begin a
new life in some town far away.
We thought it would work.
And once Motoko-san disappeared,
as you expected,
Toriumi-san hired a detective
to find his missing fiancée.
She's my fiancée who's suddenly disappeared.
Based on the statements of Kumi-san
and my neighbor Mitsue-san,
you suspected me and Ryuji-kun.
Once he reported to Toriumi-san that the
two of you made Motoko-san disappear,
your plan would be complete.
We don't care if Toriumi-san
reports us to the police.
They won't find a body anywhere.
Where is Kawaguchi Motoko-san right now?
She's hiding and waiting until
we tell her our plan succeeded.
I understand how you feel, but what
am I supposed to tell my client?
Why don't you tell him the truth?
That Kawaguchi Motoko-san was so
desperate to cut ties with him
that she was willing to fake her own murder.
So I should tell him to break
off the engagement like a man?
I know you can do it.
Mori-san.
Mori-san!
I'll bring Toriumi Haruki here
so you can tell him the truth.
Then I promise I'll convince him to
give up on Kawaguchi Motoko-san!
Shigemi-san, we should call Motoko-san.
You're right. We have to tell her.
But I'm not sure she'll come.
She's still not answering.
Still?
Three nights ago, we secretly sent her off.
It's okay. I know it'll work.
I'll call you once I figure
out where I'm hiding.
You haven't been able to get
in touch with her since then?
I tried calling her several times, too.
Maybe she hasn't found anywhere yet.
I hope she's not ill.
Yeah.
Could it be?
They must have left some kind of trace.
Did you drop something, too?
What? Me, too?
Someone was looking for something
there two mornings ago.
Ultimately, they didn't find it, though.
What did that person look like?
So they did leave something behind.
A cuff link.
These two murdered Motoko and hid the body?
Yes, but they made it up.
I'm turning them in to the police.
I told you, they made up the murder.
Then have them bring Motoko here!
We can't get in touch with her.
See?! I'm calling the police.
Actually, Toriumi-san...
Mori-san?
The Sleeping Kogoro?
Let's try calling Kawaguchi Motoko-san.
Conan!
Okay!
Hello? Kawaguchi Motoko-san?
I'm—
Impossible...
This is a farce!
That's exactly what this is.
An act to confirm your reaction.
You knew Kawaguchi Motoko-san wouldn't
be able to answer the phone.
S-So, what?
You knew about the fake murder.
Realizing Kawaguchi Motoko-san
was planning something,
three days ago, you secretly followed her.
When you asked her what she was
planning, she confessed everything.
She hoped you would
understand her desperation.
A fake murder?
After sending her off, you met Motoko-san...
I never saw her! In the first
place, I never followed her!
Conan! Show us.
Okay! You mean this, right?
Your secretary confirmed that you
received these special-order cuff links
three days ago in the afternoon.
Two days ago, you were looking for
them in the street early in the morning.
Did you drop something?
Which means you must have lost them
the day before, or three nights ago.
In other words, you were there that night.
Yours and Kawaguchi
Motoko-san's fingerprints
are on the cuff links,
meaning the two of you met.
They probably went flying when you
tried to drag Motoko-san into your car.
You realized from Motoko-san's confession
that you could use her plan
against her and murdered her.
Wh-Why would I do that?!
Not even you would want to
marry a woman who hates you.
But you had to keep up appearances, so
you couldn't break off your engagement.
However, if your fiancée were killed,
you wouldn't have to marry her.
Then I should've just
gone along with her plan.
No, you needed Motoko-san to
actually disappear from this world.
Someone may eventually have realized that
your allegedly dead fiancée was actually alive.
After killing her with your own hands and
hiding the body, you hired me to find her.
Knowing I'd find Terakado-san
and her friends before long,
you waited for my call so you
could report them to the police
and tell them you saw them hiding something
that looked like a body and where to find it.
Once it was found according
to your description,
Terakado-san and her friends
would be accused of the crime.
No!
I did see Motoko, but we parted
ways immediately, and I went home!
I'll answer it.
Yes. Yes.
He'll know what it means
if I tell him that, right?
Apparently, he exited at the Kofu interchange.
I had your movements last night investigated.
You exited at the Kofu interchange
and got on some mountain road,
so you could dispose of the body in your car.
Where is Kawaguchi Motoko-san?
Where is she?!
You're not getting away!
Where is Motoko-san?!
B-But...
But I—
If only you hadn't become engaged to me!
We'll make sure you can rest in peace.
Toriumi Conglomerate Heir Arrested
Appearances, my butt.
What a petty man.
I never got paid!
You're a petty man, too.
Episode Preview
Lisa Purple-san is really popular.
Did you see anyone coming from that dock?
They got in a red truck and headed that way.
A red truck? Got it!
"Kogoro's Pursuit of Rage
(Part One)"
The next episode of Conan is
"Kogoro's Pursuit of Rage, Part One!"
Recycling Shop
Next Conan's hint!
A recycling shop!
Mister, show us your new trick!
Don't miss the next episode.
A man who gets angry while he's sleeping!
Hey, wait!