Risa! Risa! Risa!
Risa Purple-san is really popular.
That's right. She was originally
a charismatic underground idol,
and everyone loves her.
It's popular to cosplay as her right now.
Her most charming feature is this mole.
We should thank Kogoro-no-ojisan
for making today happen.
I know. We were invited because he
was hired to be Risa-san's bodyguard.
Risa Purple (21)
Idol
I feel like I'm dreaming!
I can't believe so many people came.
Yamane Ginji (38)
Risa's Manager
I'm glad she's gaining more
fans, but as her manager,
I'm worried some thugs
might try to attack her.
Leave that to me.
I, Mori Kogoro, will protect Risa-san with
my life, no matter who dares to attack her.
Bianca, where have you been?
Sorry, sorry.
Risa!
Bianca.
Bianca (26)
Concert MC
Risa, let's get this concert started.
Sakuta Junichi (34)
Beika Cable TV Director
Okay, Bianca. Let's go!
Thanks for waiting, everyone!
I'm your MC, Bianca.
Thanks for having me today.
Now let's call Risa Purple onstage.
Three, two, one...
Risa!
Thanks, everyone!
Risa! Risa! Risa!
What do you think you're doing?!
What are you doing, Dad?
Risa-san, this way.
Sakuta, turn on your light!
It's an emergency!
Risa Purple has been kidnapped!
Stop!
Th-That's...
Ran!
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
A woman is kidnapped on a concert stage.
But the kidnappers mistakenly
abduct Ran-neechan.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kogoro's Pursuit of Rage
(Part One)
"Kogoro's Pursuit of Rage, Part One!"
Hey! What are you doing with my daughter?!
Stop! Give me back my daughter!
Mister, hurry!
Kid, get off.
I'm worried about Ran-neechan, too!
Your concern won't help her!
Let me handle this!
Mister, there.
Damn!
Mister, look.
Risa
Risa?
It must be a message
Ran-neechan left behind.
Is she trying to tell us they
mistook her for Risa-san?
No, it's probably a clue to the
identity of the kidnappers.
The kidnappers couldn't have gone far yet.
They're not getting away!
Excuse me.
Recycling Shop
Yes?
Did you see anyone coming from that dock?
There should've been two
men and one woman.
The men may have been carrying her.
Oh, with the purple hair.
Yes, that's them.
They got in a red truck and headed that way.
A red truck? Got it!
I'm going to borrow your car.
What?
She's been kidnapped.
It's an emergency.
Hey, wait.
Old man...
Red truck, red truck...
So the kidnappers mistook Ran-san for
Risa-san and kidnapped her instead?
Yes, most likely.
The stage was pitch black, and
Ran-san was cosplaying as Risa.
At first, I thought Risa-chan
had been kidnapped, too.
Inspector, it seems someone pulled the
fire alarm and turned off the breaker.
Inspector, take a look at this.
This looks like the light from a stun gun.
A stun gun?
Yeah. They probably used it to
knock Ran-san out and kidnap her.
Do you work with her agency?
No, I'm Sakuta, a director
for Beika Cable TV.
I've been filming Risa-chan's events
for about five years since
she was an underground idol.
Could you submit this video to the
police to aid in our investigation?
Sure, but I've already sent it to
another TV station as news material.
What?
It should be on the news soon.
The investigation has just begun.
We can't have you indiscreetly
taking the story public.
It's Megure.
Mori-kun, where are you right now?
I'm pursuing the kidnappers!
What?!
They appeared to have fled in a red truck
along the canal towards the clock tower.
Got it. Along the canal towards
the clock tower, right?
Have we found Ran-kun's phone signal?
It's definitely hers.
The car carrying Ran-san is
traveling towards the clock tower.
Call headquarters.
Be on the lookout for a red
truck driving along the canal.
Yes, sir!
Inspector Megure, I left Conan at the
motorboat the kidnappers abandoned.
Could you pick him up for me?
Got it.
Conan-kun is at the dock.
Go pick him up immediately.
Got it.
The kidnappers were careless enough
to accidentally kidnap Ran.
They must have left some
kind of evidence behind.
That's...
Inspector, the truth is
the agency had been receiving
threatening phone calls since last week.
Threatening phone calls?
Someone claiming to be a fan
demanded that we free Risa,
and said they felt bad that we
made her work for so little pay.
That if nothing changed, something
terrible would happen at the concert.
That sounds like they were
predicting today's incident.
But it's a misunderstanding.
I have no complaints about the agency.
We believe it was the
delusion of a maniacal fan.
Do you know who the kidnappers might be?
Yes. Since Risa debuted
as an underground idol,
there's a man who has
attended all of her events.
Come to think of it,
there is that suspicious guy who comes
to all her photo and handshake events.
A suspicious man...
Thank you. I appreciate your help.
Red truck, red truck...
Where are you? Where are you?!
Are you okay?
I'm just in a hurry since I'm late for work.
I had no idea he was in such a hurry. Sorry.
This just in.
Someone appears to have been kidnapped
from idol-singer Risa Purple-san's concert.
We received this video of the concert
just after the kidnapping occurred.
Take a look.
It's an emergency!
Risa Purple has been kidnapped!
I feel like I've seen that
man somewhere before.
Pause. Zoom in on his face.
That's him! It's definitely him!
Somewhere...
It's him!
Takeyama Takichi (43)
Recycling Shop Owner
This is him.
He's the suspicious man who
comes to all her events.
I'm sending you an image of the suspect.
Find out what you can.
Ran.
So the kidnapper was riding
in the car Mori-san took?
Yeah. He said Ran-neechan's hair was purple.
There should've been two
men and one woman.
The men may have been carrying her.
Oh, with the purple hair.
Yes, that's them.
But this had fallen between
the boat and the dock.
They probably dropped it while
they were getting off the boat.
If he were just a witness who had
nothing to do with the kidnapping,
he never would've said her hair was purple.
Way to go, Conan-kun.
It's thanks to the message Ran-neechan left.
Message?
She was trying to write "recycling shop,"
but they must've carried her off the boat
after only managing to write "Risa."
Recycling shop...
There was a refrigerator in the
back of the recycling truck,
so the larger man must've trapped
Ran-neechan in there and hidden in the back.
They used something to gag her, so she turned
on her phone so we'd know where she was.
I see. That's why her signal was
moving towards the clock tower.
There never was any red truck to begin with.
Hey, Kogoro-no-ojisan!
Mister!
Hey, kid!
It's an emergency. I figured
out who the kidnapper is.
The man driving the recycling truck, right?
What? How do you know that?
Ran-neechan was trapped inside
the refrigerator in the back.
What?! Inside the refrigerator?!
Damn! I can't believe I didn't realize Ran
and the kidnappers were riding with me!
Mori-san, we can use a GPS
to track Ran-san's location.
Get in.
Yosaburo, be gentle with Risa-chan.
Yes, boss.
What? This isn't Risa-chan!
What?
Who the hell are you?!
What's your problem?
You're the ones who mistook me for her!
Who are you?
Wh-What's this?
Her cell phone is on.
The police could find us.
Ihara Yosaburo (28)
Recycling Shop Employee
Sir, then...
Yosaburo, you don't mean...
I hate to say it, but we have no choice.
She's seen our faces.
Ran-neechan's phone signal disappeared!
What?
Mori-san, do you know where they were headed?
The car's bumper was dragging along the road.
If we follow this trail, it
should take us to their hideout.
But, Mori-san, then we should take the car.
This is Takagi.
We've identified the suspect.
Takeyama Takichi, 43 years old.
He runs a recycling shop.
He has only one employee, but he's 190
centimeters tall and likely his accomplice.
He's Ihara Yosaburo, 28 years old.
I'm sending you the data now.
Got it.
Yes, I understand.
Sakuta-san, we've received a lot of requests
for interviews regarding the incident.
Shouldn't we return to the agency?
You're right.
Wait a minute.
You still have more questions?
I figured out something
that was bothering me.
Bothering you?
The fire alarm the kidnappers pulled
was located in the hallway
between the stage and greenroom.
Normally the door is locked from the
hallway, preventing access from the stage.
In other words, the kidnappers
couldn't have pulled the fire alarm.
Which means one of us triggered the alarm?
That's impossible.
When the fire alarm sounded,
we were all onstage.
That's right.
Even Risa-san and her manager and
Bianca were recorded by this camera.
Yes, you're right. One of the kidnappers
must have pulled the fire alarm.
But if they were able to enter the hallway,
that means the door was unlocked from the inside.
So one of us unlocked the door?
It's hard to imagine anything else.
Did anyone go out into the hallway
before the concert began?
Now that you mention it, Yamane-san,
you were gone for a while.
I just went to make a phone call.
I didn't unlock the door.
So this is the kidnappers' hideout.
Ran, where are you?!
I'm here to rescue you!
The kidnappers are crazy
fans of Risa Purple-san.
Mori-san, I received a
call from the inspector.
The kidnapper is Takeyama
Takichi, 43 years old.
The other is his employee Ihara Yosaburo.
This is him! Takeyama Takichi!
This is Takeyama's Takichi's Facenet.
Facenet?
Shigaki Risa?
Shigaki Risa is Risa Purple's real name.
The kidnapper was exchanging
e-mails with Risa Purple.
"Takeyama-san, please. Please save me."
"Please take me from the stage
on the day of the concert?"
"Pull the fire alarm
and cause a commotion?"
Th-This is a blueprint of the event space.
Does that mean Risa Purple planned this
kidnapping and had Takeyama carry it out?
That's ridiculous!
Why would an idol work with a fan
to create this kind of commotion?
Because it would gain her the
attention of all of Japan.
Attention?
This incident has been all
over TV and the internet.
Risa Purple's name has spread not just among
her fans but across the entire nation.
Takeyama responded fifteen minutes ago.
"Risa-chan, we accidentally kidnapped
some girl we don't recognize."
"What should we do?"
If it was an accident,
they should let her go!
"We're taking the refrigerator
to the graveyard."
"Please call us."
The graveyard?
Could that be the graveyard?
I see. It's a graveyard
for TVs and computers.
So they abandoned her in a heap of garbage?
They probably planned to release Risa here.
Then they'll let Ran go, right?
No, probably not.
Since Ran has seen their faces, it's
hard to imagine they'll let her live.
The less forethought someone has,
the more capable they are of just about
anything when they feel cornered.
Even if that means taking someone's life.
Where am I?
What was that? What's going on?
I'm scared.
Dad, Conan-kun.
Help me.
Episode Preview
Hey! Where's Ran?!
We lost our only way to save her!
Help me...
My daughter surely has no value to you.
Though she doesn't tell her father anything,
I'm sure she dreams of a happy future.
And you're trying to take that
future from her right now!
Kogoro's Pursuit of Rage
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Kogoro's
Pursuit of Rage, Part Two!"
Mole
Next Conan's hint!
A mole!
Next time, the old man
and I will take them on!
Don't miss the next episode.
Will we win big at the races?
That's not what I meant.