When Kogoro-no-occhan was hired to be
idol-singer Risa Purple's bodyguard,
Ran and I were invited to her concert.
At the concert, two men mistook
Ran for Risa and kidnapped her.
Then the old man and I pursued the kidnappers
and tracked down their hideout.
But there we saw plans for a kidnapping
arranged by the kidnappers
and Risa Purple herself.
"Takeyama-san, please. Please save me."
"Please take me from the stage
on the day of the concert?"
"Pull the fire alarm and
cause a commotion?"
Th-This is a blueprint of the event space!
Takeyama responded fifteen minutes ago.
"Risa-chan, we accidentally kidnapped
some girl we don't recognize."
"What should we do?"
If it was an accident,
they should let her go!
No, probably not.
Since Ran has seen their faces, it's
hard to imagine they'll let her live.
The less forethought someone has,
the more capable they are of just about
anything when they feel cornered.
Even if that means taking someone's life.
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
Mori Ran has been kidnapped.
How will they attempt to save her life?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kogoro's Pursuit of Rage
(Part Two)
"Kogoro's Pursuit of Rage, Part Two!"
Arrest Risa Purple immediately!
If she's the one who planned this
kidnapping, she must know where this is!
Inspector Megure is explaining the
situation to Risa-san right now.
I can't wait! I'll get it out of her myself!
Kid, let's go!
Hey, there's something funny
about this Facenet picture.
What picture?
In her posters, the left side of her
face is always facing the camera.
So, what?
Risa Purple's most charming feature
is the mole under her left eye.
That's why she always shows the left side
of her face in every picture she takes.
But this picture is taken
from her right side.
It doesn't make sense for her
to upload a picture like this.
Does that mean someone was
pretending to be Risa-san,
and exchanging emails with Takeyama?
It's an answering machine.
Come to think of it, Takeyama's Facenet
did say that he wanted her to call.
The culprit pretending to be Risa-san may
be planning to leave some kind of message.
I can't come to the phone right now.
Please leave a message after the tone.
They're entering a security code.
The culprit's trying to listen to
their messages from the outside.
What?
You have no new messages.
Damn it!
Hey, where's Ran?! She'd better be all right!
Hey! Answer me!
Uh, oh...
Now that the culprit knows about
us, they probably won't call again.
What should we do?
That's it. That's him!
That's the man who chased
me out of the concert hall!
Takeyama Takichi (43)
Recycling Shop Owner
Yosaburo! This happened because
of the mistake you made!
But, sir, unlike you, I'm not
interested in Risa Purple.
Ihara Yosaburo (28)
Recycling Shop Employee
I don't know her face very well.
Don't insult Risa-chan!
What are you doing?
If we get caught, Risa-chan
will get in trouble!
It's okay. They won't find her here.
I-I can't breathe.
Dad, Conan-kun. Save me.
I don't use Facenet!
Risa Purple (21)
Idol
And I didn't send those comments
or messages to my fans!
That's right! Someone must
be pretending to be her!
Risa is finally starting
to gain some popularity.
She wouldn't gain anything from
causing a commotion like this!
Yamane Ginji (38)
Risa's Manager
It's nothing but trouble!
That's enough, you two. Stop filming this.
Sakuta Junichi (34)
Beika Cable TV Director
But everyone's following this news story.
Bianca (26)
Concert MC
It's the top news story online right now.
I appreciate your cooperation, but don't
forget that the investigation is still ongoing.
You still think one of us is
working with the kidnappers?
I didn't say that.
I just want to confirm the facts.
If someone hadn't unlocked the door,
the kidnappers wouldn't have been
able to pull the fire alarm.
Yamane-san, you said you went out into the
hallway just before the concert started.
Yes. Like I said before, I just went to make
a phone call. I didn't unlock the door.
Who did you call?
Who on earth were you calling
when you should've been busy
with the concert that was about to start?
I-I...
Yamane-san, please.
Don't hide anything. Tell us the truth.
Inspector.
Mori-kun, Conan-kun!
The manager was calling Takeyama,
one of the kidnappers.
Takeyama?
Hey, don't underestimate us!
We know who you are!
If you leave another threatening message,
you won't get off with just a ban!
I'll beat the shit out of you
and turn you over the cops!
Got it?!
Yamane-san...
I'm sorry...
I told you not to be so rude toward my fans!
I've asked you so many
times to stop doing that.
Yamane-san, why did you have
Takeyama's phone number?
I saved his number when I received
one of his phone threats.
Of course, I didn't know it was Takeyama.
But I couldn't stand the threat of violence
he left just before a concert, so to be safe...
Was there anyone in the hallway
when you placed this call?
No, I was alone.
I couldn't see the fire
alarm from where I was.
I don't know if anyone was there or not.
Try to remember!
It's important!
Mister, violence is wrong!
Anyway, we need to figure out
where that place in the photo is.
Y-You're right.
Ran is probably here.
Where is it?
I'm not sure exactly.
I believe it's somewhere Takeyama and his
accomplice were illegally dumping garbage.
They threw away the refrigerator they
trapped Ran-neechan inside there, too.
We've determine the service area
the kidnappers called from.
The base station covers the area
from Beika Pass to Teimuzu Valley.
It's a pretty broad area.
Have them search the area from the
skies with a helicopter immediately.
Yes, sir!
But places that people are likely to
illegally dump garbage are hard to spot.
I don't think you'll be able to find it
by searching at night with a helicopter.
Conan's right.
And if the refrigerator is closed, she'll
run out of oxygen in just a short amount of time.
Ran won't last until tomorrow morning!
We have a search team
of 500 men ready to go,
but they can't start until we
narrow down the search area.
Inspector, I have an idea.
An idea?
I'll send a message to the kidnappers.
I'll ask them to spare Ran's life.
I'll show them the honest feelings
of their victim's father.
We have no choice but appeal to
the consciences of the kidnappers.
I understand how you feel, but how
on earth are you going to reach them?
I need a favor from you.
A favor?
Could you broadcast my message to
the kidnappers on your program?
On our program?
Sure, but we're a cable channel.
Our viewership is limited.
It's unlikely that your message
will reach the kidnappers.
Even if the odds are slim, we have to try.
Just sitting and waiting
won't save Ran's life!
Very well. We'll start making
preparations immediately.
Inspector.
Ran-kun's life is on the
line. Give it your best shot!
Thank you!
Old man, I'm counting on you.
Rainbow
Conan-kun.
We're starting soon. You should come inside.
Okay. Risa-san was originally
part of a group, huh?
Yeah. At first there were seven of them.
They kept reforming their
group, but it never took off.
We're live in three, two...
As I'm sure you all know already,
today someone was kidnapped
from Risa Purple-san's concert.
It's an emergency! Risa
Purple has been kidnapped!
The video you're about to see is a message
from the father of kidnapping victim Mori
Ran-san, Mori Kogoro-san, to the kidnappers.
I'm Mori Kogoro, a private detective.
I know you mistook my daughter
for Risa-san and kidnapped her.
My daughter surely has no value to you.
You may think she's just another problem.
But to me, my daughter is
an irreplaceable treasure.
My daughter is only 17 years old.
Though she doesn't tell her father anything,
I'm sure she dreams of a happy future.
And you're trying to take that
future from her right now!
My daughter has done nothing wrong!
Please think calmly about this
and at least spare her life!
I don't want you to become murderers.
You may believe silencing my daughter will
allow you to escape, but you're wrong.
Because I have evidence of
the real culprit's identity!
Evidence of the real culprit?
Before the concert, my daughter took
pictures all over the concert hall.
Among several of those photos,
it's very likely that she took pictures of
someone standing where no one should be.
Of someone who shouldn't be there.
Not even I know who that is.
But this should be enough for you to
understand what I'm talking about.
The true culprit should know
those photos are solid evidence.
At dawn, the police will mobilize
a 500 man search party.
They'll request assistance from the
fire department, mountain rescue,
and even the Self Defense Force.
But if they discover the corpse of
my daughter then, you'll be finished!
You'll be burdened with a
crime you can never atone for.
Please spare my daughter
before it comes to that.
That is my only request.
That was an impressive broadcast.
I hope it reaches the
consciences of the kidnappers.
I don't know that it will, but if
there's evidence on Ran's phone,
they'll definitely act to destroy it tonight.
He set a trap for the real culprit.
A trap?
Kogoro-no-ojisan made up that Ran-neechan
took pictures that could serve as evidence.
He made it up?
It was a dangerous gamble, but
it's the only way we can save Ran.
Setting a trap is good and fine, but if the
real culprit wasn't watching the broadcast...
They were definitely watching.
Right, mister?
Yeah, definitely.
Inspector, the real culprit is on the move.
What?
How did you know they were the real culprit?
They left evidence on
this answering machine.
Yeah.
The answering machine?
Will I get a bonus for this, sir?
You should be worrying about
Risa-chan, not your bonus.
Someone's coming. Hide.
Hello?
I thought that ringtone
was yours, Bianca-san.
When the manager was leaving a
message on the answering machine,
you could hear it very faintly.
Hey, don't underestimate us!
We know who you are!
If you leave another threatening message,
you won't get off with just a ban!
I'll beat the shit out of you
and turn you over the cops!
Got it?!
Bianca, what are you doing?
It's starting soon.
I'll be right there.
That was a phone call from the
director Sakuta-san, right?
Y-Yeah. I was worried because we were
about to start and I didn't see Bianca.
I will protect Risa-san with my life
no matter who dares to attack her.
Bianca, where have you been?
Sorry, sorry!
Risa!
You did say something along those lines.
Sakuta-san, did you know about this place?
No. Bianca said she might know where
Takeyama's illegal dumping ground was,
and I thought we could get a scoop.
You're the real culprit?!
You can't escape.
Yosaburo, let's run for it!
Yes, sir!
You bastards!
Where's Ran-neechan?!
Tell me!
Where's my daughter?!
Where is she?!
At the bottom of the pit!
Conan, let's go!
Ran-neechan!
Ran!
Wake up!
Ran-neechan!
Ran!
Wake up, Ran-neechan!
Ran! Ran! Ran!
Ran... Ran...
Ran-neechan...
Conan-kun...
Dad...
Ran!
I've been saved.
Thank goodness.
Ran, Ran! Ran!
Dad, you're hurting me.
Sorry.
I knew you'd be wearing platform sneakers.
What?
You knew the concert hall would be
filled with water from the sprinklers,
so you wore shoes that wouldn't slip.
You've only ever worn platform sneakers
when you were an underground idol.
How do you know that?
You were jealous that your
junior Risa-san became popular.
That's right.
I thought if Risa was kidnapped, as the event
MC, I would get attention and fame, too.
I thought it would be easy to fool
Takeyama since he came to all her events,
but things didn't go so well.
Mori Detective Agency
I'm Mori Kogoro, a private detective.
I'm glad you're feeling better, Ran-neechan.
Thanks.
Even Shinichi was so worried he called
me while I was in the hospital.
Really?
Anyway, I didn't think you
loved me this much, Dad.
How many times are they going to show that?
But your eyes are so red.
Those are some impressive acting chops.
Of course.
Despite what you might think, I was
an aspiring actor when I was younger.
Acting? You were acting?
No, of course not!
You brat, why would you say that?
Wait a minute, Dad. Tell me the truth.
Oh, right! I have so many things to do today!
See you later!
Wait, Dad!
I spilled the beans...
Episode Preview
How many people have
you tricked like that?!
I-I'm not tricking anybody. I'm just
telling you about some great loans.
Dad, wake up!
What's going on?
The secretary left by herself.
What?
Gunfire?
Wh-What?
The Seven People in the Waiting Room
The next episode of Conan is
"The Seven People in the Waiting Room!"
Station Poster
Next Conan's hint!
A station poster!
The next episode is set
in a station waiting room.
Don't miss the next episode.
Seven people with special circumstances.
Are there any shops at this station?