A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
Trapped inside a station waiting room,
seven people with backstories
worthy of a TV drama.
Always determining the one truth with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Seven People in the Waiting Room
"The Seven People in the Waiting Room!"
Ofumoto Station
5 Hours Earlier
6:30 PM
Anyway, I'm surprised
we've been suddenly struck by a
typhoon the day we return to Tokyo.
I know. I'm so surprised.
Hokari Yuichi (35)
Salesman
I can't believe I'm here with the great
detective, "The Sleeping Kogoro."
Thanks for waiting, everyone.
Inagaki Kikuo (58)
Ofumoto Station
Stationmaster
Ueno Masako (28)
Ofumoto Station
Employee
It must be tough since the
weather reports were so wrong.
Hurry up and give
everyone a towel.
Yes, sir.
Takegami Hitoshi (54)
Factory Manager
It's just like my life. A chain of
"sudden" and "wrong" events.
Just for you, I have a cheap, cheap loan.
It's guaranteed not to fail,
and even comes with insurance.
How many people have you tricked like that?!
I-I'm not tricking anybody. I'm just telling you about some great loans.
I was taken in by one of you,
and it ruined my factory!
No, it was torn down by the bank!
I don't represent a bank.
Carl Morris (26)
Backpacker
Let me help you.
I appreciate the thought.
So modest.
Like hot springs, it is
one of Japan's specialties.
I love Japan!
Ofumoto's Attraction
Train Station Hot Spring
Your Japanese is very good.
Your word choice is a bit weird, though.
To travel across a country
and learn the language,
that is my specialty.
Kurusu Noriko (40)
Assemblyman's Secretary
Could you all be more quiet?!
Sheesh. This is why I hate the countryside.
Uh, what time is the next train?
There should be more Tokyo bound trains, right?
I'm sorry,
but I just got word that all inbound and
outbound trains have been suspended.
Right?
Yes, sir.
Seriously?
You must be joking!
Who's going to take responsibility
if I miss the lecture tomorrow?
My boss is at the next station waiting for me!
Your boss?
Isn't that him?
Assemblyman Yuhara Shonosuke, huh?
Which means you're...
Yuhara-sensei's secretary, right?
He arrived early to prepare for tomorrow.
By the way, who wrote that sign?
I did.
You?
Yes...
My boss's name is too small.
Fix it. Also, I'm borrowing your phone.
But...
I'm sorry, but we can't use the
phones because of the typhoon.
Right?
Yes, sir.
Which means we have to
spend the night here?
That sounds fun!
You can't be serious!
This is getting crazy...
Conan-kun, are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Is it time for dinner yet? Dinner.
Shimao Fune (70)
Local Resident
Yeah, dinner. I'm hungry.
Don't you have a cafeteria?
Sorry.
We have light snacks and
sweets in the souvenir corner.
Go boil some water, and get blankets
for the women and children.
Yes, sir!
Wait. I'll go with you.
Sorry she's not more considerate. She's
still new and needs my supervision.
Please make yourselves at home
until the trains resume running.
Can I go to the hot springs?
Of course.
Excellent! Everyone, would
you like to join me?
Hot springs? But the bus left a while ago.
He means the hot springs at the station, Dad.
Train Station Hot Spring
It's raining in the bath, too.
If only we had some sake.
That would be excellent.
Conan-kun, want to come over
here? I'll wash your back for you.
I-It's okay, Ran-neechan! I'm fine!
Excuse me.
Me, too.
There weren't any locks on the lockers.
You can't be too careful of
people traveling on a budget.
Harsh jokes are one of Japan's specialties, too.
All right. After my bath, I'm getting some local sake in the souvenir corner.
I knew it.
Huh? What's this?
Let me see.
What is this?
"Mori-sensei, someone will
be killed here tonight."
If this is true, we don't
want the killer to know.
Isn't this a prank, though?
They just wrote it to make us
think something will happen.
Maybe whoever wrote this
couldn't write the killer's name.
The culprit is—
Yeah, but who wrote it?
A whodunit. Investigating
that is a detective's job.
You were listening?
I admire Watson.
If you need a detective's
assistant, allow me to help you.
But it's possible he's the one who wrote it.
He got out of the bath first.
What is it? Is something wrong?
It could be him, too.
Nothing. It's private.
Hey, mister. Where were you
when we were in the hot springs?
What?
Hey!
Don't ask strangers such rude questions!
Sorry. He loves to copy me
and pretend to be a detective.
I was here the whole time.
I don't have anywhere to go
or anything to do in my life.
Is there anyone who...?
I'll back his story up.
He was sitting there the whole
time mumbling stuff like that.
Which means you were here, too?
Yeah. Though we might be working
together and lying to you.
Hey! What do you mean, working together?
I'm kidding.
I'm just playing along
with their detective game.
I can't even send or receive e-mails here!
As long as I'm playing along,
I'll tell you something else.
Actually, if you're really a detective,
you'd have noticed by now.
What?
He's a con artist.
He's a pickpocket.
Wh-What?
Y-Yeah, right.
D-Do you have any proof?
A heap of pamphlets for different companies.
Those are a con artist's tools of the trade.
Also, pretending to pick up
something a person has dropped
in order to approach them
is an old pickpocket trick.
And inviting people to the baths.
She's right, but...
Is it time for dinner yet?
Ma'am, you just ate. You
even ate my cup noodles.
Who are you?
Did you forget? I was so nice to you, too.
Grandma,
I'll get someone to come pick you up
once the phones are working again.
Oh, Masako-chan. Thank you.
She's just pretending she forgot?
What an unpleasant old woman.
Is Sue-chan well?
My grandmother passed away last year.
Then let's have dinner now.
You're such a useless wife.
Yes, yes. I understand.
Damn! Everyone's starting to look suspicious.
11:10 PM
Where are you going?
I don't have time for this.
I need to meet with my boss.
I'll get a taxi somewhere.
There are no taxis.
Please don't try to leave.
What's that? Why are
you ordering me around?
Move!
Huh? What?
Close the door!
She's gone.
Could it be?
Dad, wake up!
Hey, Dad!
What? What's going on?
The secretary left by herself.
What?
That's...
Mister, do you have the note?
Huh? Did I drop it?
Did she pick this up and read it?
Could it be?
Conan-kun?
I'm going with you!
Me, too!
Fine, then.
I can't imagine her walking
out into this storm.
She could be waiting it out somewhere.
Let's look for her!
H-Hey! Don't run off by yourselves!
Sheesh.
Gunfire?
Over there!
Huh? H-Hey!
Th-This is...
What's wrong, Conan?
Wh-What?
This is a murder.
Though I feel sorry for the victim, Noriko-san,
to preserve the crime scene, I put a blanket over her and left her where she was.
M-Murdered? What do you mean?
She was probably shot to death.
But why her? Who did it?
Don't worry. I, Mori Kogoro, will find the killer from among these suspects.
W-Wait a minute! Why am I a suspect?
Holmes would never suspect Watson.
You have motives.
The victim identified you for who
you are, so you wanted to kill her.
N-No!
Is it time for dinner yet? Hey...
Who are you?
Someone actually wrote me this note.
And the note describes this murder?
So the murder was predicted
and you still couldn't stop it?
What a crappy detective.
It wasn't a prediction. Someone
was asking him for help.
But he couldn't stop it. It's the same.
That's true if they were talking
about this murder.
I'd like to confirm your alibis once again
and examine your personal belongings.
While Conan and I were outside, where were you and what were you doing?
And...
The gun?
The killer must've thrown it
away or hidden it by now.
Well, since you're not Holmes,
it can't be helped.
I was in the back of the station.
Since I was alone, I have no alibi.
Also, here are my things.
I was alone on the station platform,
too. I don't have an alibi.
And you've already seen what's
in there, but go ahead.
What about you?
I-I was in the bathroom. No, the shop.
I was thirsty and wanted something to drink.
Were you alone?
Yeah. No, that old lady was there.
She was taking my food.
It'll be hard to confirm that.
And I'm not letting you examine my things.
A detective doesn't have that right.
Well, you're not wrong.
But I'm not a detective.
Wh-What are you doing?! Hey!
You bastard!
Huh?
Is something missing?
Uh, no. Nothing like that.
Sheesh. You got my hopes up.
We'll have to perform an experiment.
Wow. Your handwriting is beautiful.
You want to compare the handwriting?
That's right.
I don't think it'll work.
It's easy to fool a test like that.
No, it just might work.
Even if you try to change your handwriting,
there are some habits that can't be changed.
Why didn't I notice? They're
the one who wrote it.
It's a power outage.
Crap!
Masako-san!
How awful! Who would do this?!
She's still breathing.
Ran-neechan, find a towel and a first aid kit!
Got it.
Nobody move!
What's this?
Did she write that?
Yeah. Look at that.
The assemblyman's sign.
June 5 (Sun)
14:00~
Special guest assemblyman
Yuhara Shonosuke-sensei
will be coming!
Mori-sensei, someone will
be killed here tonight.
The culprit is—
Sensei
It's the same!
An impostor
This piece is torn, too.
The killer must've done it.
They tore it off because their
own name was written on it.
It's the old woman.
Nothing she said made any
sense. She's been exposed.
Huh? The old woman is missing.
Did she run?
What's wrong, Ran?
Th-The old lady?
Was it really her?
D-Don't do it. Give that back.
Today is flammable garbage
day. You can't throw this out.
You're such a useless wife.
Oh, it's so heavy.
Nice catch!
Impressive.
Is this your gun? I smell gunpowder.
You must be the killer.
I-I was just testing it out in the
mountains before I came here.
You were practicing shooting, huh?
N-No! Since my factory went out of business,
the loan sharks had been threatening me
into illegally manufacturing altered
firearms, but it wasn't going well.
I thought I had no choice but to
die out here, but I couldn't do it.
But I'd never shoot anyone. I'm not the killer!
It's true!
It does look like a modified gun, but we can't compare the bullets here.
Besides, he's not the "impostor."
Since there's no way there'd be a taxi out
here, why did the victim go outside?
Wait. When she was leaving...
What was she trying to see?
I can't see very well.
That's it. That's why she went outside.
What is that?
A photo's been taken down?
Was she killed because she saw it?
Then the killer took it down afterwards.
Which means...
That's it. That explains why they reacted
to the old woman that way, too.
Then there's one more thing.
Masako-san realized something
when she looked at this poster,
and she was attacked during
the blackout immediately after.
That must be it. She realized
who the killer's real target is.
The trains are finally running again.
Now where's my secretary?
Yuhara Shonosuke (65)
Assemblyman
What do you want?
Wh-What was that?
That's it. The "impostor"
was the stationmaster.
That's who the note was talking about!
That's right. If she wasn't careful,
he would hurt someone.
Even while being threatened by the impostor,
Masako-san tried to find an
opportunity to let you know.
But he noticed, and she became his victim.
How awful!
This man's the one who's awful!
Yamazaki Kozo (60)
Construction Worker
Because of Yuhara, my son died!
He made him take the blame for his
corruption and drove him to suicide!
So you killed her because
she discovered your identity?
That woman didn't speak up.
She knew my son was
innocent, but to get ahead...
She got what she deserved!
You must've been surprised
when you thought the old woman
had discovered your identity.
Yeah, but I needn't have worried.
I did it all to avenge my son.
But it's never okay to take someone's life!
And Masako-san...
There's no way your son would've wanted this!
This wouldn't make him happy!
Not ever!
The station employee, Masako-san,
was sent to the hospital and survived.
That's the real station master, huh? Good.
They're criminals after all, too?
Wanted
Hokari Yuichi
Con Artist
Distinguishing characteristics:
Impersonates a salesman
Wanted
Carl Morris
Thief
Distinguishing characteristics:
Impersonates a backpacker
Hurry up with breakfast.
You're such a useless husband.
What? Hey! Hey, wait!
Huh? Dad? Where are you going?
I'm nobody's husband!
Oh, well. I guess we'll have to leave him here.
Episode Preview
Yes. On that night, he stole
30 million yen from Beika City.
They demanded that you stop construction?
They hid the body somewhere
in Dongaraji Temple!
You killed your own father, didn't you?!
What?!
So you could illegally live off his pension!
The Hidden Secret of Dongaraji Temple
The next episode of Conan is "The Hidden Secret of Dongaraji Temple!"
Dongaraji Temple
Next Conan's hint!
Dongaraji Temple!
Where does the temple's name come from?
Don't miss the next episode.
Because you don't gotta worry! I'm on the case!
Seriously?