Detective Conan Episode 821 "The
Hidden Secret of Dongaraji Temple"
Have you seen this man?
Four days ago, on Tuesday night...
Beika Finance
Yes. On that night, he stole 30
million yen from a bank in Beika.
I'm sure you know already, but
two hours after the robbery,
the culprit Shishido Takashi
died in an accident,
but the 30 million yen he
stole is still missing.
It's no use.
We may not recover the money today, either.
Let's check by the station.
Okay.
Whoa!
Hey, it's you.
What are you doing, mister?
Did a new pachinko parlor open?
You idiot! I've been summoned
to Dongaraji Temple.
They received a phone threat.
Someone sent Dongaraji
Temple a phone threat?
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
Today's episode is set at Dongaraji Temple.
A dangerous secret hides inside the temple.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Hidden Secret of Dongaraji Temple
"The Hidden Secret of Dongaraji Temple!"
They demanded you stop remodeling?
Yes. Construction started just yesterday,
but late last night, we got a call.
Adachi Ryozen (60)
Dongaraji Temple
Head Priest
Hello?
Stop construction immediately.
If you don't, you'll be cursed.
I reported it to the police, but...
Just the threat of a curse isn't
enough to make the police act.
It'll be too late if we wait
until something happens,
so we've halted construction temporarily,
and were hoping you could
find whoever made the threat.
I understand. Leave it to me, Mori Kogoro.
I'm kind of curious. I wonder what
kind of threat the temple got.
Wait a minute!
Mother, are you accusing me of lying?
How could a single person
appear in two places at once?
That sounds like an interesting conversation.
There's nothing interesting about it.
Yesterday afternoon,
Toratani-san who lives down the street,
was lying in the sun at Chuo Park.
I told you, you mistook someone else for him.
Toratani Eisaku-san was at
Nishiguchi Park at the time.
I saw it with my own eyes.
Which means one of you mistook
someone else for him.
But I didn't just see him.
It was from far away,
but we greeted each other.
So did I!
One person in two places at once?
I see.
So two men suddenly became flustered
when they saw construction had begun?
Yes.
Yesterday evening, I saw two men when I
passed by the gate of Dongaraji Temple.
You're right.
This is bad, Brother.
So they made a phone threat to
make them stop construction.
It could have been them.
Do you know who they were?
They're brothers called Kinta and Ginsuke.
What?
They're Toratani-san's
sons, from second street.
Toratani Eisaku
This is it.
What are you doing, kid?
What?
Mister, what are you doing here?
Toratani Ginsuke (31)
Toratani Family Second Son
Toratani Kinta (33)
Toratani Family Eldest Son
What does a detective want with us?
There seems to be some reason the
construction at Dongaraji Temple
wouldn't be good for you.
What?
Did you make a threatening phone call?
It wasn't me. That's that.
I'm not finished here!
Is Eisaku-san home?
What? Why are you asking about our dad?
I heard a strange story.
There are two people who claim
to have seen him at the same time
at Chuo Park and Nishiguchi Park.
Ginsuke, did you...
You, too, Brother?
I'm not sure what's going on,
but we'll know once we meet him.
He's out right now.
Our dad is full of energy,
so he's always going out.
He's always going out.
Always?
I'm more interested in
you two than your dad!
Threatening someone is a crime, and...
Uh, oh.
You get a bunch of newspapers delivered.
We don't get papers delivered.
That was a special day.
Hey.
In any case, we've got nothing
to do with Dongaraji Temple!
They seem totally guilty to me.
They're definitely hiding something.
According to the neighbors,
the Toratani family and Dongaraji Temple
have nothing to do with each other.
Aside from being near each other.
But that family is a little strange.
There's three of them living
there, but nobody works.
Eisaku-san is old, so I understand him,
but the brothers Kinta and Ginsuke have no
motivation and never keep a job for long.
How are they paying for food?
With Eisaku's pension.
The brothers are living off his pension?
What a pathetic couple of brothers.
What are they going to do when their dad...
I got it!
Eisaku isn't alive anymore!
What?
He probably died from some sudden illness,
but the brothers didn't report
it to the public office.
They'd lose his pension if they did.
And they hid the body somewhere
in Dongaraji Temple.
But since construction started,
the body might be unearthed,
so they halted construction.
That's insane. You don't
have a shred of evidence.
Wait. If he suddenly fell ill,
they would've called an ambulance
instead of worrying about his pension...
The two of them killed
him with their own hands!
What?
He probably nagged them for not working!
Why are you layering delusions
on top of delusions?
But if you assume they're hiding
Eisaku-san's death, it does explain that.
Explain what?
Apparently Eisaku-san would
always go sit in the sun
at Chuo Park and Nishiguchi
Park on sunny days.
It would be suspicious if
he didn't keep up the habit,
so they pretended to be their father.
One of the brothers appeared here,
while the other went to Nishiguchi Park.
But because the brothers hadn't
discussed it beforehand,
they ended up appearing in two
different places at the same time.
Ginsuke, did you...
You, too, Brother?
When you look at it that way,
it does explain their actions.
If you wanted to see Eisaku
and he's not around anymore,
they had to trick you
into thinking he was out.
Our dad is full of energy,
so he's always going out.
He's always going out.
Toratani Eisaku
What now?
You killed your own father, didn't you?
What?
And you buried the body at Dongaraji Temple
so you could continue to
illegally live off his pension!
Looks like we're right.
I feel sorry for the late Eisaku.
Hey, is breakfast ready yet?
What?
Is breakfast...
Toratani Eisaku (70)
Kinta and Ginsuke's Father
Oh, we have guests.
I hope my sons aren't bothering you.
What?
That's our dad.
That's...
He's not a ghost. He's got feet.
Of course.
I'm always telling him not to irresponsibly
suspect people, but you know how kids are.
You saw him?
Four days ago on Tuesday night?
Yeah, it was near Dongaraji Temple.
Dongaraji Temple
I'm glad Eisaku-san is all right.
Although he was asking about breakfast
when it's already afternoon.
Those brothers must be the
ones who stopped construction.
But if they didn't bury a body, then why?
If we can't figure that out...
Huh? Detectives Takagi and Chiba.
They're looking for the 30 million
yen that vanished, right?
Did they get a tip that
someone saw the culprit here?
I got it! They hid the money!
What?
The brothers were working with the robber.
After the robbery, they took the 30 million
and hid it somewhere in Dongaraji Temple.
It's not impossible.
You get a bunch of newspapers delivered.
We don't get papers delivered.
That was a special day.
Those papers were from the
day after the robbery.
They were probably curious about
how the investigation was going.
They tried to hide that, too.
That must be it, then! I'd
better tell Takagi and Chiba.
Hey!
Apparently, the culprit Shishido
fled this way after the robbery.
Then he handed the money to his accomplices
so he wouldn't get caught
by the security checkpoints.
That's not possible.
What?
Shishido didn't trust others, so
it's unlikely he had accomplices.
Yeah.
Really?
So he couldn't have been working with anyone?
It certainly would be great if we
could tie the phone threat case
you're working on to the 30 million,
but you don't always get what you want.
Let's check out the other side.
Got it.
Now that I think about it, it is weird.
Even if they hid it here somewhere,
instead of going through the trouble
of stopping the construction,
they should just go get it.
If they weren't working with him, then...
They must've stolen it from him!
What?
Their dad's pension wasn't
enough for them to have fun,
so they stole the money from him
and hid it at the nearby temple.
He's out of control.
They've got guts to steal from
a robber, but I'll catch them!
But those brothers didn't seem
bold enough to commit a robbery.
People can do anything if they have to.
Mister?
Four days ago on Tuesday night?
You didn't see them?
The brothers should've been wandering
around here looking for their prey.
He's setting them up to be evil brothers.
Isn't that the day Eisaku-san
disappeared again?
Oh, right.
Disappeared?
Toratani-san has dementia.
At night he sometimes
wanders around the city.
His sons went looking
for him that night, too.
So they did it while they were looking for
their father and hid it at Dongaraji Temple.
They didn't hide him.
They found him at Dongaraji Temple.
Yeah.
Found him?
Yes, Eisaku-san.
Sorry for all the trouble.
It's fine. I'm glad you
were able to find him.
He was at Dongaraji Temple today.
Oh.
He was burying a backpack.
We have no idea what he's talking about.
You don't have a backpack to bury, Dad.
Eisaku buried a backpack at Dongaraji Temple?
So those brothers had nothing
to do with it from the start.
Wait, could it be? Hey...
The dad is behind everything!
I knew it...
Your reasoning doesn't make sense, mister!
So the old man fell victim to temptation.
He robbed the robber!
Hey! Are you here, Dad?
If you're here, answer us!
Then he buried his treasure
somewhere in Dongaraji Temple.
But then construction began.
He wanted to go get it, but
something was stopping him,
so he made a phone threat
to stop construction.
If he buried and hid the treasure,
he wouldn't be telling
everyone about the backpack.
Right?
People start saying things they
shouldn't have as they get older.
What?
I'm turning their father in to the police.
Well, whatever...
No, I can't just let him go.
Think. I probably already have
all the necessary pieces.
He was burying a backpack.
Could that have been...
And the brothers realized that.
Then it all makes sense.
But why did they have to
pretend to be their father?
People start saying things they
shouldn't have as they get older.
They feared he would say something.
It's starting to come together.
All that's left is...
I have business with your father!
This is probably where he was.
Huh? Crap!
Mori-san.
I, Mori Kogoro, shall identify the
culprit who left the phone threat
and find the missing 30 million
yen in one fell swoop!
Both of these crimes were
carried out by Tora—
Tora... Tora... Tiger!
Mori-san.
The incident occurred four nights ago
when Toratani Eisaku witnessed a
certain sight while wandering around.
He saw a man burying a backpack
here at Dongaraji Temple.
A backpack? You mean Shishido?
He hid the 30 million here?
He told his sons and neighbors about it.
He was burying a backpack.
No one knew what he meant until the next day
when his sons realized what he was saying.
30 Million Yen Stolen
Culprit Killed While Fleeing.
Where is the Missing Money...?!
This robbery happened nearby, huh?
I wish I had 30 million yen.
The backpack the robber
stuffed the money in...
Dad, this guy was burying
this last night, right?
That's what I said.
The police haven't found it yet.
Naturally, you thought to pocket the money.
Where did he bury it?
Where at Dongaraji Temple?
Where was it?
We just have to wait for
his memory to return.
It comes and goes.
But if we leave him alone...
You became worried.
Eisaku might tell anyone that he
saw the backpack being buried.
And if he did, it might reach
the ears of the police.
Fearing this, you kept him inside
so he wouldn't see anyone.
They imprisoned their own father?
W-We just didn't let him go outside.
W-We didn't tie him up or anything.
So no one would find
out you imprisoned him,
you pretended to be Eisaku
and went to the park,
though it's amusing that you ended
up in two places at the same time.
However, construction at
Dongaraji Temple began,
and your treasure was in
danger of being dug up.
Stop construction immediately.
If you don't, you'll be cursed.
You lumps of worldly desire!
Mori-san, you were right.
The two cases were connected.
So then...
Where did he bury the backpack?
Where was it?
Of course.
The robber fled here to escape the police.
He thought he would bury the
money he stole to hide it.
Naturally, he chose a place
where no one would see him.
Where no one would see him?
That would mean not even Eisaku saw him.
Right?
Shishido thought no one would see
him there, but Eisaku-san did.
It could only have been there
behind that ginkgo tree.
But Eisaku wouldn't have been
able to see him behind that tree.
While wandering around that night, Eisaku
didn't come directly to Dongaraji Temple.
What do you mean?
Where was he, then?
Not even Shishido expected someone
to be on the roof at night.
Hey, Dad! Are you here?
I found him, Brother.
Don't make us worry so much.
He was burying a backpack.
What?
Let's go home.
Come to think of it,
he did mention that the view of the
sunset from up there was exceptional.
He'd go up there all the time,
so he must've that evening, too.
It's here.
That's it. It was here.
You've already seen it. It's too late now.
Yeah.
You're still talking, you damned fools?
It's true.
The head priest said he wouldn't mention the
phone threat if they agreed to work for him.
Pull yourselves together.
Anyway, Eisaku-san seems happy.
Come on, pull yourself together.
You, too, Brother.
Episode Preview
Hang in there, Dad!
Ai-chan...
All right! I accept the job!
They're both here.
Shall I have him come to
your table when he returns?
Thanks.
Yoko-chan!
Asuka-san! Asuka-san!
The Suspects Are a Passionate Couple (Part 1)
The next episode of Conan is "The Suspects
Are a Passionate Couple (Part 1)!"
Higo and Yoko
Next Conan's hint.
Higo and Yoko!
Does "passionate couple"
refer to Higo and Okino Yoko?
Don't miss the next episode.
Y-Yoko-chan!