And?
You really don't recognize him?
Recognize who?
Commissioner Kuroda.
Oh.
No.
Considering you don't, you were
clinging to me pretty tightly.
Seeing his horrifying face up close
would have an effect on anybody.
Oh, really?
So she was just scared of his face.
That's right.
His face was horrifying.
I was seriously scared.
I almost cried.
R-Really?
It's probably fine.
If Kuroda really was Rum like you suspect,
and saw my face from that close,
he would've realized I'm Sherry,
the woman who betrayed the society.
And they'd be forcing their way
into the professor's house by now.
But the e-mail the professor just
sent me was all about dinner.
That's fine, then.
But you can never be too careful.
Hey, what's wrong?
Hey, Haibara?
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
What has shocked Haibara Ai?
Her information signals
the start of a new case!
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Suspects Are a Passionate Couple
(Part One)
"The Suspects Are a Passionate
Couple, Part One!"
Did something happen to the professor?
Higo Ryusuke
Okino Yoko
Their Passionate Love Exposed!!
Seriously? It's just a gossip article.
You scared me.
What?! Is this true?!
Seriously?
This is a major couple.
I bet they'd make beautiful J-Leaguer babies.
If they had girls, they'd be idol-singers.
Yeah!
Ai-chan, don't you agree?
A-Ai-chan?
You're white as a sheet.
I don't think she's breathing.
Wait a minute.
If he's seeing Okino Yoko,
that must mean...
D-Dad?
Mori Detective Agency
Hang in there, Dad!
I knew it.
We still haven't been able to
get in touch with their agencies,
and haven't been able to get a
comment from either one of them.
According to Higo's teammates,
they both graduated from
the same high school,
and that may be the reason
they've hit it off.
Before getting depressed about it,
maybe you should confirm if it's true.
You investigate affairs all the time.
You idiot!
A detective shouldn't conduct those
investigations to satisfy his own curiosity!
That's my policy!
Then
will you do it if I hire you?
Ai-chan...
Whoa, whoa...
I want you to conduct a background check
on Higo Ryusuke and Okino Yoko.
What?
Free of charge, of course.
All right!
I accept the job!
What is this?
But how are you going to find them?
Unlike ordinary people, we
don't know where they live.
They said no one's been able to get
in touch with their agencies, either.
You idiot!
Normally they'd issue some kind of safe
comment in this kind of situation,
but if they can't,
it means they don't realize
people are talking about it,
and they could be seeing each other today.
But normally wouldn't someone
e-mail or call them?
Yoko-chan's manager said she frequently
doesn't realize her cell phone is off.
And Higo-san turns off his
phone when he's not working.
Which means...
We just have to search the
terms "Okino Yoko,"
"Higo Ryusuke,"
"date,"
and today's date.
See?
There it is.
Someone posted to their
blog that they saw them
at a restaurant in Haido City.
But they were just buying
men's watches together, right?
Maybe Yoko-chan asked Higo-san
to choose a present for her younger brother,
and she took him out to eat to thank him.
Yoko-chan doesn't have a younger brother.
And...
Why would she make Higo-san choose?
I don't get it.
Y-You're right...
Then maybe they really are dating.
Sorry!
Forget what I said.
Why don't you try going to the restaurant?
He didn't write the restaurant's name.
Come to think of it,
I heard one of Higo-san's soccer club
seniors retired from the J-League
and opened an Italian
restaurant in Haido City.
What is it called?!
B-But we don't know if
they're actually there...
They're both here.
Considering how they're acting,
it's no wonder Ran decided to pass.
Hey, what are you typing?
The number of times that
woman has smiled at Higo-san.
Weren't you listening to Okino Yoko's songs
a bunch of times because you liked them?
I just deleted all of them.
And?
Is that guy his senior from the soccer club?
What?
No.
Higo-san's senior was a wing back for
the Tokyo Spirits named Asuka Teiya.
He was even chosen to represent
Japan at one point.
I think he's the restaurant's sommelier.
That bastard...
Why is he trying to get Yoko-chan drunk?
What?
Where's Asuka-san?
The owner is out buying wine.
Yamada Akimichi (43)
Sommelier
He should be back soon.
Shall I have him come to
your table when he returns?
Yes, thanks.
Take your time.
Banba Reiko (27)
Waitress
Please excuse me.
I've brought you your dessert.
I-I'm sorry.
That waitress is an amateur.
She was probably enchanted by Higo-san.
Now I've done it.
Isn't that the owner's friend Higo?
You'd be in a lot of trouble if he were here.
I'm fine.
He's never gotten mad at me before.
Don't let it get to your head
just because you're the owner's girl.
And don't let it get to your head
just because you're my ex-boyfriend.
Konoe Yasuto (28)
Waiter
The owner sure is late.
I thought he'd be back by now.
Should we look for him?
You're right.
Konoe-kun and I will search the back room.
Yes, sir.
Banba-san, could you search the storeroom?
Got it.
He's not here.
Normally he naps here on this couch.
He didn't seem to be getting
enough sleep lately.
Come to think of it,
weren't you arguing with
the owner last night?
He complained that the wines
I buy are too expensive.
It's his restaurant, so it can't be helped.
He wasn't at the storeroom, either.
Shall we wait a while longer, then?
Yeah.
Okay.
They asked me again when
Asuka-san would be arriving.
This is a problem.
Shall we look for him again?
We'll check the bathroom,
too, just to be safe.
Yeah.
I-I'll search the bathroom.
Thank you.
He's not in the storeroom.
He wasn't in the bathroom, either.
I found the owner.
He's napping on the couch.
Seriously?
Yeah.
He has a blanket pulled up over his head.
Does he not know that his friend is here?
It can't be helped.
Let's wake him in ten minutes.
It's been nearly ten minutes.
I'll go to the back room
and wake up the owner.
Okay.
I got an e-mail from the owner.
"Could you bring Higo and Yoko-chan to
the storeroom without anyone noticing?"
So he woke up on his own.
I'll go get them.
Thanks.
What's going on?
It looks like they're going somewhere.
Don't you think that idol woman
is standing too close to him?
That soccer bum is just a slow walker.
I'm going to have a smoke in the bathroom.
Hey.
Normally you can't smoke
in the bathroom, either.
But I smelled cigarette smoke when
I went to the bathroom earlier.
What?
Really?
Yeah.
That was Yoko-chan's scream!
Where did those two just go?!
T-To the underground storeroom.
That soccer bum
better not have done
anything to Yoko-chan!
Yoko-chan!
Hey, Asuka-san?
Wake up!
Hey!
Asuka-san?
Asuka-san!
The victim is the restaurant's owner,
Asuka Teiya-san, thirty-one years old.
He was killed during the
hour between 7 and 8 PM.
The cause of death is blood loss
due to a severed carotid artery.
The weapon is the box cutter
found next to the body.
One of the box cutters has gone missing
from the back of the restaurant,
so that's likely what it is.
I see.
So the body was discovered by
J-Leaguer Higo Ryusuke-san
and idol talent Okino Yoko-san,
who were visiting the
restaurant as customers?
Yes.
What were a couple customers
doing in the storeroom?
We were brought here by a waiter.
He said he received an e-mail from
Asuka-san asking to bring us here.
You knew the victim?
Yes.
Asuka-san was an OB of my
high school soccer team,
and I had arranged to meet him
because I had a favor to ask of him.
I graduated from Konan High as well.
So you didn't receive an e-mail
directly from the victim?
No.
We weren't that close.
I lost my cell phone somewhere.
I think I brought it to
the restaurant, though.
There's something else I'd like to ask you.
Are you two dating?
Huh?
What?
What are you asking them?
You haven't heard?
All the talk shows are blowing up over them.
See?
Apparently Okino Yoko-san
and Higo Ryusuke-san's
passionate love has been exposed.
Hey, what's your answer?!
What is going on?!
What?
Wh-What are they doing here?
They happened to be at the restaurant.
In any case,
why don't you try questioning
the other restaurant staff?
They were running around since
before the body was found.
Running around?
Oh, right.
The owner was late coming back,
so the three of us split up to look for him.
Sometimes he'll secretly return and nap
in the back room of the restaurant.
Some of our customers wanted to see him.
The first time was around seven, I think.
He and I searched the back.
I had her search the storeroom.
The back room?
Yeah, this room the staff
uses as a waiting room.
So where was he napping?
On this sofa.
But the first time we came,
there was just a blanket.
There wasn't anyone here.
So the owner wasn't in the
storeroom when you searched it?
Right.
But we looked for him again
about ten minutes later.
I searched the back room this time,
and the owner was here then.
The owner was?
Yes.
He was sleeping on the sofa,
with a blanket covering his head.
His shoes were next to the sofa,
so it must have been him.
But...
But why was the owner...?
What happened next?
After hearing what she told us,
I went to wake him about ten minutes later.
He wasn't sleeping on the couch then.
I received an e-mail from
the owner at that time.
It said, "Could you bring
Higo and Yoko-chan
to the storeroom without anyone noticing?"
What time was that?
Around 7:30 PM.
I went to get the two of them,
but he didn't respond when
I entered the storeroom.
I thought he may have returned to
the back room since we took so long,
so I left them in the storeroom to go there,
but only Yamada-san was there.
While the three of us were discussing
where the owner could've gone...
We heard Yoko-san scream.
Just as we were heading to the storeroom,
Detective Mori appeared.
Spit it out!
You made Yoko-chan come to
this restaurant, didn't you?!
Actually, no...
You're the one who invited him, right?
What?
What are they investigating?
So you discovered the body
while waiting in the storeroom?
Yes.
The waiter wasn't coming back,
so while we were looking
around the storeroom...
I think it was around 7:50.
7:50 would be just barely within
the presumed time of death.
Yeah, which makes them suspects, too.
What?!
In any case, everyone,
we'll question each of you separately.
Like I said earlier,
I couldn't have committed the murder.
The first time we looked for the owner,
I came to the back room with Yamada-san,
and the second time I went to the men's room.
I took the two of them to the
storeroom towards the end,
but I only called his name
when I entered the storeroom.
I didn't go far into the room.
But while Banba-san was serving
food and wine to the customers,
you could've pretended
to go to the bathroom
and secretly gone to
the storeroom instead.
That's impossible.
The storeroom is always locked,
and the key hangs on the
wall off the hallway entrance,
where all the staff can see it.
Why is it kept somewhere so visible?
There were previously staff members
who would sneak off to the
storeroom and back room to smoke,
so he did it to prevent that.
The owner didn't like cigarettes.
So this room was always locked?
Yeah, and the rear entrance.
Only the owner had a spare key.
Did the victim have the spare key on him?
Yes, in his pants pocket.
But we weren't able to
find the victim's phone.
Forensics is searching
the storeroom right now.
I see.
In any case, it wasn't me.
Besides, I didn't resent the owner.
Apparently you're the one who
was smoking in the restaurant.
What?
I just heard from the waitress.
The owner was furious with you.
Was that your motive?
N-No, I...
If you're the murderer,
could you hurry up and confess?
What?
Th-The other two were much more
likely to have motives than me.
The sommelier Yamada-san was arguing
with the owner over wine last night,
and the waitress Banba Reiko
was the owner's woman.
W-Woman?
Maybe she killed him over a messy breakup?
Yes, that's right.
I was dating the owner,
but we never spoke about breaking up.
But the waiter Konoe-san
said lately the owner stopped
going home with you.
That's because he was staying here,
to come up with a way to keep
the restaurant profitable.
He was staying here to do that?
That's right.
That's why the owner's locker on the end
is full of changes of clothes.
She's right.
There's even a change of shoes.
Konoe-kun's only saying
that because he's my ex.
He's jealous.
Y-Your ex-boyfriend?
But if he was wearing a blanket over
his head while sleeping on the sofa,
you couldn't see his face, right?
No, I guess not.
Then couldn't you have put
something under the blanket
to make it look like he was sleeping there?
What?
How would that benefit me?
So you could make it appear as
though the owner were still alive,
when you really killed him the first
time you searched the storeroom.
When I searched this room,
the sommelier Yamada-san
searched the storeroom.
Wouldn't that plan fail if
Yamada-san found the owner's body?
You know, this room is really tidy.
Of course it is.
After work,
the owner would often clean it by himself.
So the owner was a neat freak?
Yes.
Even after I cleaned,
I would hear him running the vacuum.
He was probably cleaning away fine
dust that nobody else would notice.
What?
When I searched the storeroom?
The owner wasn't there,
but like Konoe-kun,
I only called his name from the entryway.
So he may already have been murdered
in the back of the storeroom?
Yes, I suppose.
By the way,
I heard you argued with the owner last night.
Yes.
Lately the restaurant hasn't been doing well,
so the owner said he wanted
to stock cheap wines instead.
I simply expressed my
concern over doing that
at a place that's trying to be
an authentic Italian restaurant.
So you killed him.
Huh?
So you could buy your expensive wines.
I-I wouldn't be able to buy them
either way with the owner dead!
Inspector.
We found quite a few cigarette
butts in the bathroom's trash can.
Isn't the bathroom nonsmoking, too?
Yes.
It was probably Konoe-kun.
He previously got in trouble with
the owner for smoking in this room,
so I believe he was secretly
smoking in the bathroom.
In the bathroom,
he could pass it off as our
customers smoking instead.
So that's why the bathroom
stank of cigarettes.
Come to think of it,
when I suggested we search the bathroom,
he said he would do it.
Maybe he didn't want us to know the
bathroom smelled like cigarettes.
There are five suspects,
but those three are the most suspicious.
But how did the culprit
carry out the murder?
Episode Preview
There's a tiny hole.
Hey, is that blood?
Only Higo-san or Yoko-san,
who were waiting in the storeroom,
could've committed the crime.
What?
W-Wait a minute, inspector.
They wanted a third party to confirm
that the owner wasn't in this room.
Give yourself up!
The Suspects Are a Passionate Couple
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The Suspects
Are a Passionate Couple, Part Two!"
Vacuum Bag
Next Conan's hint!
A vacuum bag!
Don't miss the next episode.
Yoko-chan!
It doesn't make sense.
We'll never accept that they're a couple!
You're perfectly in sync.