The news reported that J-League
athlete Higo Ryusuke-san
and idol Okino Yoko-san were
having a passionate love affair.
Unable to believe the news,
Haibara and Kogoro-no-occhan
tracked them down,
and found them at an Italian
restaurant in Haido City.
Apparently they had come to see
the owner of the restaurant
and their senior from high
school, Asuka Teiya-san.
That was Yoko-chan's scream!
Yoko-chan!
Hey, Asuka-san?
Wake up!
Hey!
Asuka-san?
Asuka-san!
So the owner wasn't in the
storeroom when you searched it?
No.
Banba Reiko (27)
Waitress
But we looked for him again
about ten minutes later.
I searched the back room this time,
and the owner was there then.
Th-The owner was?
Yes.
He was sleeping on the sofa
with a blanket covering his head.
His shoes were next to the sofa,
so it must have been him.
What happened next?
After hearing what she told us,
Yamada Akimichi (43)
Sommelier
I went to wake him about ten minutes later.
He wasn't sleeping on the couch then.
I received an e-mail from
the owner at that time.
It said, “Could you bring
Higo and Yoko-chan
to the storeroom without
anyone noticing?”
What time was that?
Konoe Yasuto (28)
Waiter
Around 7:30 PM.
I went to get the two of them,
but he didn't respond when
I entered the storeroom.
I thought he may have returned to
the back room since we took so long,
so I left them in the storeroom to go there,
but only Yamada-san was there.
While the three of us were discussing
where the owner could've gone...
We heard Yoko-san scream.
There are five suspects,
but those three are the most suspicious.
But... how did the culprit
carry out the murder?
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
A case and a couple hiding an unclear truth.
What happened in the back of the restaurant?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Suspects Are a Passionate Couple
(Part Two)
“The Suspects Are a Passionate
Couple, Part Two!
Well?
What are you planning
on doing to Yoko-chan?
Huh?
Wh-What am I going to do?
That's not what I'm asking.
When you entered the storeroom
where you found the body,
are you sure it was locked?
Yes.
The waiter unlocked it for us.
After calling Asuka-san's name several times,
he told us to wait, left us there,
and didn't seem to be coming back.
Inside the storeroom were canned goods
from foreign countries
that I'd never seen before.
While we were looking around,
I noticed something that looked like
blood on the floor in the back.
When we went to see what it was...
W-We found Asuka-san
dead on the floor.
I see.
By the way,
Higo-san, you said you lost your cell phone.
Do you know where you might have lost it?
I'm not sure.
I often forget it on tables at restaurants.
Come to think of it,
the waitress did change the tablecloth
after she spilled wine on it.
Then there's the bathroom.
I keep it in my pocket with my handkerchief.
After taking out my handkerchief,
sometimes I'll leave just
my phone in the bathroom.
Doesn't that ever happen to you?
I suppose.
It does!
It totally does!
I forget my phone all the time!
You never forget yours.
So you never got in touch with the owner
while you were at the restaurant?
No.
But you could've borrowed
Yoko-chan's phone.
I-I... did bring my phone,
but I forgot to charge it before
I went to sleep last night.
The battery was dead by
the time we tried to call.
It happens all the time, right?
Never!
What?
It does!
It sure does, Yoko-chan.
O-Okay...
By the way,
what were you going to ask the victim
to do when you saw him today?
Oh...
Actually...
Huh?
This is the blanket Asuka-san was
using while he was sleeping, right?
It should be.
What about it, Conan-kun?
There's a tiny hole right here
and a dark red stain around it.
What?
Hey, is that blood?
It doesn't seem to be.
It smells like wine.
Seriously?
You scared me.
This is an Italian restaurant.
But what is it doing here?
Since I could clearly tell
what it was from the smell,
it didn't get there that long ago.
At most just a few hours ago.
Which means it could have
something to do with the case.
Even after I cleaned,
I would hear him running the vacuum.
He was sleeping on the sofa with
a blanket covering his head.
But the first time we came,
there was just a blanket.
There wasn't anyone here.
Hey! Are you listening?
That's it.
Which means maybe...
In here.
I found it!
There's a hole.
And this one is slightly
stained with wine, too.
Conan-kun, you can't do that.
I knew it.
They fabricated their alibi
in an instant,
using a useful tool
they had on them.
To summarize what everyone has said,
the owner of the restaurant,
Asuka Teiya-san, was late to return,
so the sommelier Yamada-san,
the waiter Konoe-san,
and the waitress Banba-san
decided to look for him.
Yamada-san and Konoe-san
searched this break room
in the back of the restaurant,
but the owner wasn't here.
Banba-san searched the storeroom in the
basement, but he wasn't there, either.
Y-Yes.
Ten minutes later,
the three of you decided to
look for the owner again.
This time Yamada-san searched the storeroom,
Konoe-san searched the bathroom,
and Banba-san searched the back room.
That's when Banba-san found the owner
sleeping on the sofa in the back room,
with a blanket pulled
up over his head, right?
Yes.
The blanket was covering his face,
but his shoes were next to the sofa.
Ten minutes after that,
Yamada-san came to the back
room to wake the owner,
but he was already gone.
That's when Konoe-san received
an e-mail from the owner,
instructing him to bring
Higo-san and Yoko-san
to the storeroom without anyone noticing.
Konoe-san took them to the storeroom
and called for the owner,
but there was no response,
so he left them there to look for the owner.
After that, while waiting in the storeroom,
you found the owner's body.
Is that right?
Yes.
The back room and storeroom
were always locked,
and the keys were hanging
in the hallway entrance
in plain view of the staff,
making it impossible to take
them without anyone noticing,
and only the owner had a set of spare keys.
Furthermore,
when Konoe-san took Higo-san
and Yoko-san to the storeroom,
if the storeroom was locked properly,
only those waiting in the storeroom,
Higo-san or Yoko-san,
could've committed the crime.
What?
W-Wait a minute, Inspector.
I don't know about that soccer bum,
but the lovely Yoko-chan
would never murder anybody.
But considering the circumstances...
The owner was probably
actually a huge fan of Yoko-chan,
and was hiding in the storeroom,
waiting for her to be alone
so he could attack her.
But since the soccer bum was still there,
they got in a fight, and he killed him.
Yoko-chan's just so nice
that she's protecting him.
That would mean she's helping
a criminal avoid arrest.
Surely you can excuse
her for that, Inspector.
M-Mori-kun?
And excuse me if I have
an extra glass of wine.
Don't tell me...
you believe that ridiculous story, do you?
I find your attitude even more unbelievable.
Don't you think it's strange?
What's strange?
The number of people who searched
the back room the first time.
What?
At first glance,
you could tell whether or not
there was someone in this room,
but Yamada-san and Konoe-san
searched the room together.
The storeroom has rows of
shelves and plenty of blind spots.
They could've sent more people to search it,
but Banba-san went alone.
That certainly is odd.
They did this because
they wanted a third party to confirm
that the owner wasn't in this room,
so that the trick they used
in the murder would work.
They did this because
they wanted a third party to confirm
that the owner wasn't in this room,
so that the trick they used
in the murder would work.
Which means...
Yamada-san and Konoe-san,
one of you is the killer.
Y-Yamada-san is the one who said
we should search the room together.
R-Right?
I-I did instruct him to do that.
After all,
this room has lockers and cupboards as well.
Did you think the owner
might be hiding in them?
It's not impossible.
Besides,
what good would having him
confirm the owner wasn't here do?
He and I were only here for a few minutes.
No, it wasn't for a few minutes.
It was only for a moment.
And in that moment you set it up.
The false image of the
owner sleeping on the couch,
with a blanket pulled over his head.
Th-That's absurd!
Are you saying I stuffed something
inside the blanket then?
I didn't do anything like that, did I?
N-No.
In the first place,
there was nothing he could've
used next to the sofa.
I bought the items you requested, Mori-san.
A blanket, an ice pick, a vacuum bag,
and five sets of heavy clothes.
But what on earth are you
going to use these for?
It's time for an experiment.
Conan,
do what I told you to do.
Got it!
First put the clothes inside the vacuum bag.
Use a vacuum to remove the
air from inside the bag
so it flattens out.
That's it.
That's what the owner was doing when
I heard him running the vacuum.
Then put the vacuum bag
with clothes on the sofa.
Put the blanket over it,
and you're ready to go.
Look.
It just looks like there's a
blanket on the sofa, right?
Y-Yeah.
But if you stab it with the ice pick...
so it reaches the bag on the bottom...
Air begins entering the bag through the hole.
See?
Now it looks like someone
is sleeping under it.
Y-You're right.
Now you just have to pull
out the owner's shoes
that were hidden under the sofa,
and you're all set.
He would've had enough time to do
that without Konoe-san noticing
while they were leaving the room, right?
B-But Konoe-kun could've pulled
off that trick as well.
What?
No, you're the one who did it, Yamada-san.
Because...
The was a small hole stained with wine
in the blanket in this room.
It proves that you used it to
put a hole in the vacuum bag.
A sommelier's essential tool,
your sommelier knife.
You pierced the blanket
using the tip of the corkscrew
of your sommelier knife.
That's why there was wine
around the holes in
the blanket and clothes.
Wait a minute, Mori-kun.
According to my sommelier friend,
the corkscrew doesn't go all
the way through the cork.
Otherwise, pieces of the
cork get in the wine.
Though the corkscrew sometimes
goes all the way through
old corks in expensive wines,
this restaurant doesn't
stock any wines like that.
W-We don't!
We're not a three star restaurant!
S-So someone must've done this to frame me.
You're right.
Normally there is no wine on
a sommelier knife's corkscrew,
but that's only if Yamada-san
were a real sommelier!
After uncorking the wine at
Higo-san and Yoko-chan's table,
you left it on the table
without smelling the cork.
A sommelier would never do that.
Known as bouchonne,
about one in every ten or twenty wines
are degraded or smell like cork,
due to the cleaning solution
left over from creating it.
Why didn't you check if that was the case?
You also smoke cigarettes.
A sommelier who values his sense of taste
would never smoke.
The cigarette butts in the men's
bathroom were all of the same brand,
but some were left long
and had the filters chewed,
while others were smoked down to the end.
In other words,
they were the cigarette
butts of two different men.
And based on the quantity,
they were left by staff
members and not customers.
Konoe-san probably smoked half of them,
but Yamada-san, you smoked the others.
An examination of the saliva
on the filters should reveal
that you're a fake sommelier.
You thought to commit this murder
when you saw the phone
Higo-san left in the bathroom,
didn't you?
After reading his e-mails,
you learned that Higo-san and Yoko-chan
were meeting the owner today.
So you came up with a plan,
took a vacuum bag of five heavier sets
of the owner's clothes out of his locker,
placed them on the sofa,
and laid the blanket over them.
Then you sent him an e-mail asking
him to pick up additional items
to delay his return so
the other staff members
would suggest that you look
for him because he was late.
Sure enough, you decided
to look for the owner.
First you and Konoe-san
searched the back room,
so he could confirm the owner wasn't there.
While leaving,
you opened a hole in the vacuum
bag so the blanket would inflate,
and took the owner's shoes
out from under the sofa.
Later you sent a message
from Higo-san's phone,
asking him to wait in the storeroom
because you wanted to
meet with him privately.
Then you pretended to search
for the owner once more,
went to the storeroom, and killed him.
You tricked Banba-san and Konoe-san
into thinking the owner was sleeping
with a blanket covering
his head in the back room.
Ten minutes later,
as you were heading to the
back room to wake him,
using the phone you stole
when you murdered the owner,
you sent a message to Konoe-san,
so he would bring Higo-san and
Yoko-chan to the storeroom.
You removed the clothes
from the vacuum bag,
left in the back room and put
them back inside the locker,
and destroyed the evidence
of the trick you used.
Am I wrong?
E-Evidence?
Where are the vacuum bag and cell phone?
In the garbage can in the kitchen!
I just found them,
and forensics is examining them right now.
You probably went to the kitchen when
the owner's body was discovered,
and threw away the vacuum bag and
phone you'd been hiding in your jacket.
But you didn't have time to put on gloves,
so your fingerprints should be all over them.
Now give yourself up!
You killed him, didn't you?!
I-I didn't have a choice.
The owner found out.
I'd been putting fake labels on cheap wines,
and selling them as expensive ones.
I put the profits in the business,
and gave some kickbacks
to the wine makers, too.
I told him customers of a former J-Leaguer's
restaurant were of no importance!
They wouldn't know the
first thing about wine,
so we should increase our profits this way!
But...
The owner wouldn't listen.
In fact, he said he'd accuse me of fraud.
Of course he did.
Asuka-san was a fair and honest player,
who didn't receive a single red card
while he played in the league.
So what were you going to ask the victim for?
One of our former teachers from when
we were high school students is retiring.
The two of us bought a watch
to celebrate his retirement,
and we were hoping Asuka-san
would write a message to go with it.
Asuka-san is the first celebrity
Konan High produced.
You should've told us sooner.
We tried...
But we were interrupted.
That was me.
So you're not dating, then?
No, I'll be married to
soccer for a while longer.
And I have singing and acting.
I see.
Good luck, you two.
Thank you!
In any case,
I'm sorry for all the trouble we caused.
And Mori-san,
you identified the man who
did that to Asuka-san.
And thanks for helping
solve the case, Conan-kun.
And you.
Thanks for finding that evidence.
Nice assist.
I wish you could take
Takahiro's place on the team.
Thanks, Ai-chan.
What are you doing?
Let's get the park and start playing soccer!
What?
Seriously?!
But it looks like rain!
No matter how hard you try,
a woman can never play on Higo-san's team.
That's Yoko-chan's song.
Amamiya Sho & Maki
Episode Preview
There are so many toys!
The two of you live in this house together?
Yeah, we're best friends
and brothers who love toys.
Right?
Toys are the best!
Someone help!
Crap.
My shoes and tranquilizer watch
are both out for repairs!
The Detective Boys Get Out of the Rain
The next episode of Conan is “The
Detective Boys Get Out of the Rain!”
Doll House
Next Conan's hint!
A doll house!
Don't miss the next episode.
Thanks to Higo-san,
the whole world looks so brilliant.
That's great.