Amamiya Sho & Masaki
This is bad.
What are we going to do, Bro?
I'm thinking.
Shut up for a minute!
Excuse us!
Is anyone home?
Hurry up!
I'm about to wet my pants!
You can do it, Genta-kun.
Just wait a little longer.
Is anybody home?
Huh?
It's open.
All right!
Excuse the intrusion!
Hey, Genta!
Bathroom, bathroom...
Wow, there are so many toys!
This place truly is a toy museum.
Where is it?
Hey, there's someone here!
Please let me use your bathroom.
S-Sure, gladly.
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
It's the kind of toy museum
everyone has dreamed of.
But there seems to be
something wrong with it.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Detective Boys Get Out of the Rain
"The Detective Boys Get Out of the Rain!"
Look! Isn't that Gomera?
It's pretty big!
Bro, why'd you let them in?
I couldn't help it.
In any case, let's get them to the
bathroom quickly and kick them out.
Hey.
Isn't that the bathroom?
Seriously?
All right.
This isn't the bathroom.
Mister, you're Amamiya Masaki-san, right?
What?
Amamiya Sho & Masaki
It was written on the sign out front.
And this is your brother Sho-san, right?
You were calling him "bro" earlier.
Yeah, that's right.
I'm Amamiya Sho, the older brother.
A-And I'm his younger
brother, Amamiya Masaki.
The two of you live in this house together?
Yeah!
We're best friends and
brothers who love toys.
Toys are the best!
Forget that.
Where's the bathroom?
Oh, sorry.
This is it.
You idiot, that's a tub-shower.
Sorry.
We just moved here.
Where is the bathroom?
That's why you're both wearing gloves.
Sorry to bother you while you're moving.
Y-Yeah.
Well, you know...
Ah, found it.
Here it is.
I'm saved.
I feel relieved.
As long as we're here, why don't we
stay here until the rain lets up?
Good idea.
Maybe if we help them move—
We can't.
Huh?
Let's head back.
What?
The professor will worry
if we don't get back soon.
Now let's go.
Okay...
Sorry to have bothered you.
No problem...
Take care.
Someone help!
Damn it.
That woman woke up.
This isn't good!
Guys, hurry!
Wait!
What's going on?
You're not getting away.
Run!
They're robbers!
What?
Crap.
My shoes and tranquilizer watch
are both out for repairs!
Damn it.
Forget them, Bro.
We should ignore the kids
and get out of here.
You moron!
There's got to be gold
somewhere in this house!
I'm not leaving before I see
the treasure for myself!
Let's go!
Fine...
The initials on the matching
sweatshirts were K and M?
Yeah, and there was a woman's dress.
The actual residents are probably
Kakeru
Maki
a man named Kakeru and
a woman named Maki.
Then that scream we heard earlier...
Let go!
Genta-kun!
Damn it.
Isn't there something we can use?
Let go!
Get down, Genta!
All right!
Genta, hurry!
Got it.
Please help!
In here!
She's in here.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Amamiya Maki (26)
I just lost consciousness.
You're Amamiya Maki-san, right?
Who are you?
You're just a bunch of children?
We're not just children.
We're the Detective Boys.
What?
Crap, they're here!
Damn it!
They got away because you took too long!
What are you doing, idiot?
Hurry up and look for them!
I-I know.
Damn it.
Where are they hiding?
Anyway, this house is amazing.
I know.
It's full of toys.
My husband is like a
child in an adult's body.
He's a toy collector.
Where is your husband now?
I don't know.
He should've been home,
but I was taking a shower.
Oh, right.
Where's your phone?
They said they cut the phone line.
They took my cell phone, too.
And we left our phones at the campsite.
So we can't contact anyone on the outside.
It's strange, though.
Normally a patrol officer
stops by around this time.
It's really raining hard today.
Maybe the patrol officer is running late,
or he's busy handling a
landslide somewhere else.
No—
I heard voices over there!
Damn it! Isn't there anything
we can use as a weapon?
I'm sorry.
For getting you involved, too.
It's not your fault, Maki-san.
What should we do with them, Bro?
Isn't it obvious?
We're going to tie them up, and...
Hold it right there!
S-Seriously?
You idiot, it's just a toy!
Yes, it used to be.
But my husband enjoys modifying
these kinds of toys.
Would you like to try it out?
Now.
She got me!
Are you guys okay?
Yeah.
She shot me in the chest!
I'm going to die!
You idiot! Don't die on me!
Wait, you're not even bleeding!
Damn it.
Sorry, Bro.
They tricked us.
Stop, damn it!
Hurry!
I'm going to freaking kill them!
Over here!
Damn kids!
You're not getting away!
You little brat!
Damn it. What is this?
It's an extremely powerful adhesive
used to build plastic models.
Now, Genta-kun.
S-Someone help!
They're trapped.
The stairs are covered
in the balls they threw.
Yahoo!
You can't be serious!
It's too dangerous, Bro.
Shut up!
Come with me!
Bro, in front of you!
No, behind you!
You've got to be kidding me!
Bro!
Now's our chance.
Hurry!
Yeah!
That's...
Could it be?
Conan-kun?
You guys leave without me!
This is...
Kakeru-san!
Did they...?
A-Are we...
going to end up like her husband?
That's up to you.
Right?
Some guy called "God" online
said there's a bunch of gold in this house.
God?
Are you saying God told
you to rob this house?
Are you guys out of your minds?
What did you say?
Where's the gold?
If you don't tell us, we'll kill you!
All right. It's here.
Now we can pay off all our debt.
Of course.
Now we can say goodbye to our debt.
But won't the police come after us next?
I'll take the cops over them any day.
Besides, if we silence
the woman and the kids,
they'll never find us.
There's a lot in here.
This one is wonderful.
Yeah, it just might work.
How about this one, Conan?
Not bad.
You look even more handsome than usual.
What did you say?
I'm joking.
How can you all be so carefree
at a time like this?
Because Conan-kun is here.
He always overcomes every desperate
situation, no matter how bad it is.
Hey, bro.
Are we really going to kill the kids, too?
Maybe we should ask God first.
It's too late for that.
They saw our faces.
We have to kill them.
I-I-It's a monster!
Don't run, idiot! Kill it already!
Sh-Shut up!
You've done nothing but order me around!
I'm sick of it!
Wh-What did you say, you bastard?!
All right!
Guys, let's run.
Huh?
You tricked me.
You damn kids!
Ayumi!
Ayumi-chan!
Genta-kun!
Conan-kun!
Ouch...
You're not getting away this time, you brat.
Ugh.
These guys stink.
We haven't been able to bathe in forever.
How sad.
That must've been hard.
It was.
Guys, the police will be here soon.
Hey, wait a minute.
We didn't kill anybody.
It's too late for excuses!
W-We're not lying.
We just pretended to kill him to scare you.
You won't fool us anymore.
What?
Where's the other boy?
Conan-kun?
He was here until a minute ago.
Where did he go?
What are you doing?
What?
What are you doing, Conan-kun?
So...
You're the one who murdered your husband,
Maki-san.
Rather,
the one who planned this crime and
the mastermind of the robbery,
"God."
Where is this coming from?
It fell into place then.
The name "God" came from those two
who hardly seem like the religious type.
Some guy called "God" online said
there's a bunch of gold in this house.
Hey, Bro.
Are we really going to kill the kids, too?
Maybe we should ask God first.
God
But if you assume the God they referred to
was the online handle of the
person who planned this crime,
it all makes sense.
God
They were being commanded
by a mastermind named God.
And if you rearrange the letters
of the romanized spelling,
you get Maki.
Your name, Maki-san.
People often rearrange the
letters in their names,
and use anagrams when
creating an online handle.
That's a far-fetched argument.
Yeah. But...
You, Maki-san, are the only one
who could've killed your husband.
What do you mean?
Your husbands body had lost a lot of blood.
Judging by his appearance,
the murderer had likely gotten a
lot of blood on themselves, too.
Enough that they had to take
a shower to get it all off.
But neither of them appeared to
have the victim's blood on them.
Then maybe they took showers—
That's right.
They haven't bathed recently.
Naturally, they haven't taken
showers in this bathroom, either.
They even mistook this shower
room for the bathroom.
They probably didn't even know where it was.
In other words, there's only one
person who took a shower here.
Th-That doesn't prove anything.
The victim's blood should have
gotten not just on your body,
but also on the clothes you were wearing.
I thought it was strange.
Only the dress was damp.
You must've washed the blood off in a hurry.
I'm sure you know,
but no matter how much you wash
something, a blood test will—
That's enough.
That's right.
I killed my husband.
That freak who kept turning the wealth
he was supposed to
will to me on stupid toys!
I was supposed to frame those two,
who came to rob the house,
at the time I indicated by telling them
where to find the fake gold bars.
I was going to have the
patrol officer arrest them
when he arrived while
they were wasting time.
Under the circumstances,
it would've appeared that my
husband was killed by the robbers,
and I was a miserable victim.
Isn't that would anyone would think?
The situation has changed
because of this damned rain,
but it doesn't matter.
You're going to die, too,
at the hands of those robbers!
Huh?
Conan?
Conan-kun?!
Run, guys!
What?
Maki-san?
What's going on?
Conan-kun is in trouble!
Idiots!
Run away!
I'll start by killing you first!
Crap!
This isn't good!
All right.
Go!
Get out of the way!
I don't even want to look
at toys for a while.
Me neither.
Yeah.
You kids sure did a good job this time.
How about it?
As a reward, I could buy some toys for you.
We don't want any.
Episode Preview
Kimishima Ryuji-san, forty-eight years old.
He's the second president of a
food manufacturing company.
Why did you have to die and leave me behind?
What do you mean?
Ryuji can't swim at all.
This was a clear cut murder!
Mori-san?
There's one other person.
The Tidal Park Comeback Case
The next episode of Conan is
"The Tidal Park Comeback Case!"
Rise and Fall of the Tide
Next Conan's hint!
The rise and fall of the tide!
Detective Takagi, give us a reward!
Don't miss the next episode.
We don't want toys!
We want eel over rice!
They're toying with him.