Is it happening yet?
It's already started.
Liar.
Nothing's changed.
It takes time for it to change.
You need to be patient.
Patient, huh?
This lake is a tidal lake.
It's made by drawing in water from the ocean.
In other words,
the scenery changes with the
rise and fall of the tide.
It's just like the Hamarikyu Gardens.
Yeah.
So, what's the difference in tidal level?
Um... About two meters.
Which means you'll be submerged, kid.
So will you.
The flood bridge is about
to come out of the water.
Hey, there it is.
Okay, let's head to the next attraction:
all the fresh seafood you can eat!
Hey!
What is it, Conan-kun?
There's someone collapsed on the bridge.
Huh?
What?
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
A lake in a park connected to the sea.
An incident occurs when the tide ebbs.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Tidal Park Comeback Case
"The Tidal Park Comeback Case!"
Did you figure out who he is?
Kimishima Ryuji (48)
Food Manufacturing Company
Second President
We did more than that.
He's Ryuji-san, forty-eight years old.
Motoi Teruhiko (45)
Chiba Prefectural
Police Officer
There isn't anyone around
here who doesn't know him.
He's the second president of a
food manufacturing company.
Huh.
Did he drown?
No, look closely at his neck.
What?
It looks like he was
strangled with something.
Which means he was strangled to death?
Was this a murder?
It could be, but it could
also have been an accident.
An accident?
Something could have gotten
caught around his neck.
Hey, isn't there something
wrong with his shoes?
What?
Oh.
He's wearing his shoes on the opposite feet.
Why would he do that?
Detective Motoi.
Keitoku Kazuri (28)
Chiba Prefectural
Police Officer
I bought the park's groundskeeper Tanba-san.
Oh, hello.
We have a few questions for you.
He couldn't answer her
question, so he ran away.
Were you at the park during
low tide this morning?
Tanba Eijiro(65)
Park Groundskeeper
Yes.
Was there a body there at that time?
Of course not.
Which means it's likely the body
washed in through the flood gate.
That's the victim's wife Aoi-san.
She's a beautiful woman.
I suppose.
They say she's a former
gravure idol or actress.
I see.
Darling!
Why did you have to die
Kimishima Aoi (28)
Ryuji's Wife
and leave me behind?
Such terrible acting.
Who's that?
The victim's brother, Yuta-san.
He's an executive at the same company.
Kimishima Yuta (50)
Ryuji's Brother
By the way, had your husband's
behavior changed at all recently?
No, I don't think so.
What about you, sir?
I don't know.
I only saw my brother once in a while.
Even though you work at the same company?
I'm an executive in name only.
By the way, what's the cause of death?
We're waiting for the autopsy's results.
You can at least tell if it's
murder or an accident, can't you?
We're not sure yet.
We'll most likely investigate
both possibilities.
What?
You mean he was murdered?
We can't deny the possibility.
Just to be sure,
where were the two of you last night
around ten when Ryuji-san died?
I-I was with a friend.
What's your friend's name?
U-Um...
Nishikikoji Kazuma.
Is he an actor friend?
What about you?
I was out night fishing.
Is there anyone who can back up your alibi?
No. I took the cruiser out to sea alone.
What's wrong?
Why are you sighing?
What I actually wanted
to eat was fresh seafood.
He's still going on about that?
Mori-san.
Apparently, Aoi-san has something to tell you.
What's it about?
It's about his brother.
His brother?
Yes.
His brother
doesn't seem to have been
very fond of Ryuji-san.
Was there some reason for that?
He thought he would take over the company,
but their father named Ryuji-san,
the younger brother, his successor.
I see.
Is there anything else?
The cruiser his brother mentioned earlier
was paid for by Ryuji-san.
What?
He was paid plenty in director's
fees and stock dividends,
but it was never enough for him.
He was always asking Ryuji-san for more.
The cruiser...
Could it be?
There's something I want to test.
Lend me a hand.
Y-Yes, sir.
Excuse me...
Wait, Dad.
Sheesh...
Hey!
Paper bags go in here.
Cans go in there.
Plastic bottles go in there.
Yes, sir!
Understood!
Treat nature and the environment with care.
Treat Nature and the Environment With Care
Got it?
Sorry!
Even the police are no
match against this old man.
Young people these days...
Hey, Tanba-san!
You're late!
Sugao Keisuke (26)
Electrician
Sorry.
It took forever to finish my previous job.
I don't need your excuses.
In any case, you've caused
me a lot of trouble.
This time something even
worse than garbage washed up.
Like what?
A person.
What?!
A-A person?
You mean...
Is that why the police are here?
That's right.
Now hurry up and fix it.
Is this where you control
the flood gate from?
That's right, kid.
The flood gate is opened and
closed using this control panel.
It's no use.
It won't close.
Did someone break it?
It doesn't look like it.
Who threw away their garbage here?
There's some here, too.
That old man seems like he yells a lot.
And here.
You mean Tanba-san?
He sure does, but he's not a bad guy.
Maybe he's just too serious.
He's been working at this
park since I was a kid.
He's like the master of the place.
Really?
Row!
Got it!
Conan-kun, where have you been?
I got lost.
Anyway, how's the experiment going?
Row!
Yes, sir!
Faster!
What do you think, Mori-san?
That's enough for now.
Let's try talking to Yuta-san now.
What?
It's true that I didn't like my brother.
I see.
But I didn't have a reason to kill him.
Why not?
Think about it.
Thanks to him,
I was getting paid to have fun.
If he died,
I'd actually have to work to support myself.
But now that Ryuji-san is gone,
aren't you next in line to be president?
I guess so.
Though it'll probably just be a title.
I'll let someone else handle it.
Anyway, Mori-san,
Ryuji couldn't swim at all.
He doesn't fish, either.
So why did he die in the ocean?
Maybe the murderer killed him in the ocean,
so they could frame someone else.
What do you mean?
Don't you know already?
It's that woman.
You shouldn't believe anything she says,
alibi or otherwise.
After all, she's a former actress.
She fooled my brother, too.
Excuse me.
The old man's going to be mad.
Styrofoam?
That's...
Those are rope fibers.
Which means...
A rope?
Yeah.
Did you see one this morning
while patrolling the park?
No, I didn't.
Really?
Yes.
Around what time do your patrol
the park in the morning?
After five.
That's pretty early.
Old people wake up early.
Tanba-san.
It was the battery.
The battery?
You hadn't switched it
out in a while, had you?
I put in a new one.
I see.
By the way, Tanba-san,
I heard today's your last day.
Thank you for your years of hard work.
No,
thank you.
I see.
So this old man is retiring today.
It's not here.
Well, it's not like I didn't expect it.
Treat Nature and the Environment With Care
I see.
So that's how it is!
Well, in other words...
It's the water ski principle.
Water ski?
Mori-san, what on earth do you mean?
While being pulled behind a motorboat,
the rope he was holding
wrapped around Ryuji-san's neck.
He was dragged by the neck at high speed
and died.
So was it a murder or an accident?
Is there anyone who goes water
skiing in the middle of the night?
No.
Which means...
That's right!
This was a clear cut murder!
Look out!
Mori-san?
What's wrong?
That certainly would be a clear cut murder,
but water skiing wouldn't
have actually been possible.
What?
Th-Then...
It was an accident?
In the first place,
I'm not entirely sure Ryuji-san
died in the ocean.
What?
If he didn't die in the ocean,
where did he die?
He died in the park,
near the arbor.
So if the body didn't wash in from the ocean,
does that mean it was in
the park the whole time?
No,
it did wash in from the ocean.
Wh-What do you mean?
How could he have washed in from
the ocean if he died in the park?
A corpse can't move on its own.
Someone moved the body to
the lake using Styrofoam.
Normally the lake and ocean
are separated by the flood gate,
so the culprit first opened that.
Then Ryuji-san's body washed out
through the flood gate on the tide
and into the ocean.
Then they closed the flood gate.
However, due to a malfunction
with the control panel,
the flood gate didn't close.
The cause was a bad battery.
Because of this, during the next high tide,
Ryuji-san's body washed back
in through the flood gate,
fell out of the Styrofoam box,
and sank above the flood bridge.
But why would the murderer
bother with all of that?
Was there some reason the murderer
didn't want the body
to be found in the park?
Yes, that's right.
What reason?
More importantly, who's the murderer?
Detective Keitoku, show them the image.
Y-Yes, sir.
It was a coincidence,
but I found a photo of
Aoi-san uploaded to an SNS.
It was taken around the same time
as the victim's time of death.
This proves Aoi-san's alibi.
Next, Yuta-san...
You know it's forbidden to
chum the waters here
for recreational fishing purposes.
Of course.
If someone caught you doing it,
you'd be in serious trouble.
I doubt you'd try anything in an
area that's so closely watched.
You're innocent as well.
Wait a minute, Mori-san.
If it wasn't the wife or the brother,
then who was it?
There's one other person.
Tanba Eizaburo-san.
Wh-What are you talking about?
How rude!
Um, isn't he the park groundskeeper?
What's his motive?
Why would he murder Ryuji?
He didn't have a motive.
And Ryuji-san wasn't murdered.
It was suicide.
Suicide?
That's impossible.
If it was a suicide, he should've
reported it to the police.
Why would he go through all that trouble?
Because...
...Tanba-san is retiring today.
He had served as the park's
groundskeeper for years.
He wanted to leave his last day
of work feeling accomplished.
But then he discovered Ryuji-san's body.
At this rate,
his special day would be ruined.
Thinking this,
Suicide Note
Tanba-san decided to transport
the body out of the park.
However, the body was heavy,
and it would've taken too long for
Tanba-san to move it on his own.
So,
he thought to use the tide...
...to send him out to sea.
Sheesh.
What an awful world we live in.
Not only have we stopped
respecting our elders,
but now we accuse them of crimes.
If you think abandoning a
dead body isn't a crime,
you'd be wrong.
Do whatever you want.
Without proof,
I'll never be found guilty.
By proof, do you mean the rope?
One that matches the marks
left on Ryuji-san's neck.
What is it?
That rope may have been incinerated.
No, it wasn't.
Why not?
The rope was a heat-resistant
polypropylene rope.
Naturally, it's nonflammable.
And when you consider the environment,
Tanba-san never would have
burned it in the incinerator.
He would have put it out with the
rest of the nonflammable garbage.
I found it, Mori-san!
Tanba-san,
do you still insist on feigning innocent?
There was something wrong with me.
Today was a special day.
It was all the more reason to report it.
You're absolutely right.
Oh, right.
There was a suicide note by the body.
"Aoi, Yuta.
I'm sorry it had to come to this."
"I invested in stocks to gain
more capital for the company,
but I went bankrupt?"
N-No...
Fresh-Caught and Fresh
All You Can Eat
Seafood
My seafood...
Done for the Day
All the seafood I can eat...
That's a serious tide of tears.
I don't think the flow will stop for a while.
Episode Preview
It looks like they fell.
Yeah.
Mister.
Miss!
Are you all right?
It's a robbery murder.
A robbery murder?
What?
It's a secret.
S-Sorry.
I just got curious.
Do you want to see it no matter what?
Y-Yeah.
The Beauty, The Lie, and The Secret
The next episode of Conan is "The
Beauty, The Lie, and The Secret!"
Cigarettes
Next Conan's hint.
Cigarettes!
Don't miss the next episode.
Dad, you're ogling girls again.
I'm not ogling anybody.
What a terrible liar.