It's completely dark out.
It's your fault for taking
forever to eat dessert.
You're one to talk.
It's your fault for chatting with
the pretty waitress forever.
What?
I was kindly listening to her problems.
Ran, call an ambulance!
And the police!
Got it!
It looks like he fell.
Yeah.
Mister!
Miss!
Are you all right?!
Damn it.
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
A beauty lurks in the shadows of a case.
The mysterious reason
behind the victim's fall.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Beauty, The Lie, and The Secret
"The Beauty, The Lie, and The Secret!"
MPD Beika Police Station
I see.
So that man suddenly attacked you?
Yes.
Takizawa Misaki (28)
I ran towards the emergency staircase, but...
I was so frightened.
I thought he was going to kill me.
So you're sure that's the man
you saw during that case?
Yes, that's definitely him.
Inspector, what case are you referring to?
A robbery murder.
A-A robbery murder?!
What?
One week ago, a robber broke into
Takizawa Misaki-san's house
through the second floor balcony
in the middle of the night.
Takizawa Akira (58)
He threatened her husband Takizawa Akira
into opening the safe in the study,
and stole precious stones
worth 100 million yen.
Then he murdered Takizawa.
I awoke when I heard the sound
of the glass table shattering,
and rushed to my husband's study, but...
And the man who just attacked
Misaki-san is the culprit?
Yes.
He's Yaginuma Takeshi,
a bartender at a jazz café.
Yaginuma Takeshi (32)
The late Takizawa had visited
the shop several times.
He was one of our suspects,
and we were going to bring in
Misaki-san in for a line up.
I see.
So he tried to beat you to the
punch by silencing Misaki-san.
Yeah.
Come in.
Inspector,
while searching Yaginuma's shop,
we found this in a storage
space under the floor.
What is that?
Look closely.
Were these stolen from the safe in your home?
Yes, definitely.
Inspector, that clinches it.
Indeed.
It's unfortunate we weren't
able to arrest the culprit,
but once we submit the case to the
prosecutor with a dead suspect,
that should close it.
That's great news, Misaki-san.
Thank you.
Yeah, but...
Misaki-san, why did you park your car there?
What?
The first and second floors of
the parking lot were empty.
There wasn't any reason for
you to go to the third floor.
I thought you might've had some reason to—
Hey, kid!
What are you pestering her for?
Did you get a good look at Misaki-san's car?
If she parked a car that nice
somewhere obvious, it'd get stolen!
That's why she went up to
the third floor to park it!
Got it?!
Right, Misaki-san?
Y-Yes...
Ouch...
I'm sorry.
I've never ridden in such a cool
car before, so I was curious.
Your name's Conan-kun, right?
Yeah.
Do you like cars?
Just once I'd like to
ride in a car like that.
I'll give you a ride sometime, then.
When?
Don't be so persistent!
But I might never see Misaki-san again.
Fine.
Shall we go for a drive right now?
But, Misaki-san...
It's fine.
I didn't want to be alone right now, anyway.
Hooray! All right!
You're the first one, Conan-kun.
Huh?
The first man to ride in my car.
Your husband never rode in it?
Takizawa had a bad heart.
He said the way I drove frightened him.
Really?
I'm sorry.
Sometimes I feel like
speeding down the highway.
Maybe I'm looking for thrills.
R-Really?
Misaki-san, do you smoke?
No, I don't.
Why?
Look. These are cigarette ashes, aren't they?
If your husband had a bad heart,
he probably didn't smoke.
Neither do you.
I wonder who smoked this cigarette.
Maybe it's not cigarette ash.
It's probably just dust.
Conan-kun, when you grow up, are you
going to be a detective like Mori-san?
Yeah, probably.
Don't.
That's a secret place.
S-Sorry. I just got curious.
You're curious about everything, aren't you?
Do you want to see what's
inside no matter what?
Y-Yeah.
It can't be helped, then.
I smoked that cigarette.
I kept it secret from my husband.
Secret?
Yes.
He didn't like cigarettes.
When we got married,
I lied and said I didn't smoke.
Really?
So you lied even though
you were getting married.
Happiness is built on lies and secrets.
When you grow up, you'll understand.
Lies and secrets, huh?
Oh, right.
Misaki-san, your house is big, right?
What? Yes.
I'd like to go there, too!
Take me there.
But I haven't tidied up since the incident.
I'm afraid to be home alone,
so I've been staying in a hotel.
It'll be fine, then.
You're not alone today.
What?
Conan went to Misaki-san's house?
Yeah.
He just called to say he was stopping by.
What's wrong with that kid?
Sonoko just told me that
Takizawa-san's family
have been land magnates for
generations, and they're millionaires.
So, what?
So when he married a woman
thirty years his junior,
everyone accused Misaki-san
of being a gold digger.
That's what you call petty suspicions.
Misaki-san is a victim whose
husband was just murdered.
Yeah, but...
Anyway, when did that brat
turn into such a womanizer?
Wow, there are butterflies.
Takizawa loved nature.
He longed to live in the countryside.
Really?
So that's why the garage is full of plants.
But I don't like it.
I hate bugs.
Conan-kun,
I'm going to go get changed.
Have a seat somewhere.
Okay!
The crime occurred in the second floor study.
Crap.
The study must be that way.
So this is the study.
This is...
Which means...
You shouldn't enter any rooms
without permission, Conan-kun.
Sorry.
There were lots of old records,
so I couldn't help myself.
Takizawa loved jazz.
Would you like something to drink?
All I have is orange juice, though.
He said listening to jazz at a high
volume helped eliminate his stress.
Oh, right.
So that's why this room
has a soundproof door.
Soundproof?
Yeah.
When I came in, I noticed the
door was really heavy and thick,
so I knew right away.
Really?
Huh?
That's weird, though.
Didn't the sound of the glass
table shattering wake you?
That's right.
But if the soundproof door was closed,
you wouldn't have been able to hear that.
It was open then.
That's not possible.
If Takizawa-san was murdered
while listening to his records,
the door would've been closed.
How do you know that?
There's still a record on the turntable.
Since he took such good care of his records,
he wouldn't have left a record
out if he wasn't listening to it.
You're right.
Then it could've been Yaginuma
who opened the door.
Yaginuma-san?
After stealing the jewels,
maybe Yaginuma tried to
take Takizawa to my room,
so he could silence the both of us.
Even though you were asleep?
I'm not Yaginuma, so I wouldn't know.
Here's your orange juice.
I have one more question.
When you ran here after hearing
the glass table shatter,
the jewels had already been stolen, right?
Yes, of course.
But look closely
behind the cabinet door
where the safe is.
There were shards of glass
from the table behind it.
So, what?
The cabinet door had to have been closed
for shards from the table to get here.
But if the door were closed, the
safe couldn't have been opened.
In other words, the safe was opened
after the table was shattered.
After Takizawa-san was murdered.
Then how did Yaginuma open the safe?
Wasn't it you?
Didn't you open the safe?
I wasn't expecting that.
What, then?
Are you accusing me of lying?
That's not the only lie you told.
You said you saw the culprit's face
as he escaped through the balcony
when you came to this room,
but that's not possible.
Impossible?
But I saw it.
The pool's mercury lamps
would've back lit anyone
standing on the balcony.
You can't see my face clearly, can you?
In other words,
you didn't actually see the culprit.
You were only able to say
Yaginuma-san committed the crime
because you were his accomplice.
You instructed Yaginuma-san
to steal the jewels,
and murder your husband.
Then you called him to the
parking lot, murdered him there,
and pushed all the blame onto him.
Conan-kun, you're so cute.
Maybe I'll take you to someplace far away.
I bet you'd fit in my suitcase.
I'm only joking.
Sorry.
They'll worry if you don't answer your phone.
Hello?
Hey, kid!
Where are you?!
I'm still at Misaki-san's house.
What?
You're not staying there overnight, are you?
You don't need to worry, Mori-san.
Misaki-san?
He'll be a little late,
but I'll make sure Conan-kun gets home.
I'm so sorry for the inconvenience.
You can just
drop the kid off somewhere.
Here.
How long have you thought I killed Yaginuma?
From the beginning.
The palms of Yaginuma-san's
hands were spotless.
His palms?
Yeah.
Anyone would try to grab onto something,
if they were falling down some stairs.
The stairs were pretty dirty,
so his hands would've gotten dirty
if he tried to grab onto something.
Yaginuma-san's hands were clean, though.
But he had cigarette ashes on his chest.
In other words,
Yaginuma-san was smoking
until just before he fell.
And that points to only one conclusion.
That Yaginuma-san approached
you while he was smoking,
and...
Bug spray causes unbearable pain
when sprayed from a close distance.
While he was covering
his hands with his eyes,
you pushed him from behind.
That's some impressive detective work.
But...
If you're right,
that means you're standing
in front of a murderer now.
Not only that, but you're alone with her.
Aren't you afraid?
What?
You would kill me?
But if I don't go home now,
you'd be the prime suspect.
I'm not so sure.
If I say I dropped you off near your home,
everyone will believe me.
You think so?
That's right.
After all, I have no motive to kill you.
So you're going to keep lying forever.
Didn't I tell you?
Happiness is built on lies and secrets.
I don't agree.
But I've been lying to
you about something, too.
What?
When I put my phone in my pocket earlier,
I pushed the callback button.
Mori Kogoro
In Call
Misaki-san!
Don't do anything stupid!
I've already called the police!
They'll be arriving soon!
Give yourself up!
Too bad, Misaki-san.
Who on earth are you?
Edogawa Conan, a detective.
According to her statement,
Yaginuma and Takizawa Misaki were old friends,
and had been planning this murder
since before she got married.
I see.
Anyway, Conan-kun, you were
a big help again this time.
Did Kudo-kun provide you
with instructions again?
What?
Y-Yeah, I guess.
But his instructions put Conan-kun in danger.
What in the world is he thinking?
But that was...
Yeah, that's right.
What was he going to do if
something had happened to him?
Now, now.
The case has been solved.
And Conan-kun is all right.
Sheesh.
If he'd just let me handle the case...
You just had a dirty thought, didn't you?
Y-You idiot, I didn't
have any dirty thoughts!
You totally were.
You were imagining being alone
with Misaki-san, weren't you?
P-Please, you two...
I-I wasn't thinking about that. I just...
Just what?
I-I just...
Just?
Inspector, shall we celebrate the
resolution of this case with a drink?
D-Don't drag me into this!
Don't change the subject, Dad!
Inspector!
Can't you wait to fight until you get home?
Episode Preview
Do you want ramen for dinner, Conan-kun?
Okay.
Could you cancel my spot
at tonight's French dinner?
She's choosing ramen over French cuisine?
You there! What are you doing?
Almost as if he was conducting
some kind of ritual.
R-Ritual?
So scary...
Ramen to Die For 2
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is
"Ramen to Die For 2, Part One!"
Ramen Ogura
Next Conan's hint!
Ramen Ogura!
Ramen with red bean paste?
Don't miss the next episode.
No, Ogura is just the shop's
name. It's my second time here.
Really?