Oh, yeah.
Did you see the God of Ramen
Championship on TV last night?
Yeah, I did.
I wanted to try the miso ramen
that made it to the final.
I preferred the shio ramen.
No way!
The shoyu ramen that won the
competition must taste the best.
Conan-kun, which ramen did you like?
Who, me?
The tonkotsu ramen, I guess.
Tonkotsu, huh?
Come to think of it, the tonkotsu
ramen seemed pretty good, too.
Yeah.
High school girls get way too
excited over ramen specials.
The curliness of the noodles
is just so exquisite.
And the tonkotsu broth is so rich.
And the char siu pork is so soft.
Uh-oh.
Talking about ramen made me want some.
Me, too.
Shall we go, then?
To my regular ramen place.
Huh?
What?
Maybe we shouldn't though.
You won't be able to eat dinner later.
Come to think of it,
my dad said he was going out to
drink with the neighbors tonight.
Do you want ramen for dinner, Conan-kun?
Okay.
Hello? It's me.
I'm eating dinner with Ran and Sera tonight.
Could you cancel my spot
at tonight's French dinner?
She's choosing ramen over French cuisine?
Bye!
I've dreamed about eating ramen on the
way home from school with my friends!
Really?
That's not much of a dream for a rich girl.
I promise it tastes good, though.
After all, the flavor's
apparently to die for.
What?
Could she mean...?
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
Three high school girls visit Ramen Ogura.
The flavor to die for results in an incident?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Ramen to Die For: 2
(Part One)
"Ramen to Die For: 2, Part One!"
Ramen to Die For
Ramen Ogura
So it is this place.
Hello!
Welcome!
Boss, I brought friends today.
Hello.
Hey!
Thanks for coming, Mari-chan.
My name's Masumi, not Mari.
Huh? Is that right?
Hey, Conan-kun.
It's been a while.
Are you by yourself today?
No, I came with them.
Oh, you've been here before?
Yeah, before they moved here.
There was a murder then.
Yes, the culprit probably still has
Saizu-san's possession that
they covered in poison.
It's not like they were hypnotized.
There was no guarantee they would touch—
They'd definitely touch it!
As soon as you enter a warm
place like a ramen shop,
they cloud up like this.
So you solved a poisoning case?
Way to go, Conan-kun.
It wasn't me.
It was Kogoro-no-ojisan.
But you helped him solve the case, Conan-kun.
Here are your Judge of the Afterlife ramens.
Thanks for waiting.
It looks so good!
What is this? It's seriously good.
You're right.
Right?
So what's it going to be?
Do you want an order of fried rice
and pot stickers to go today, Mari-chan?
I told you, my name's Masumi.
And I guess I'll have some.
Sure thing.
Sera-chan, are you going to eat
rice and pot stickers for dinner?
You'll get fat.
No, no. It's for breakfast.
The food here is good even when it's cold.
Are you sure it's not for the person
living in your hotel room?
Yeah, it's for my boyfriend
who secretly lives with me.
What?!
It's just a joke.
Excuse me.
Shono Yuna (34)
Hostess
Could you pass me the
vinegar in front of you?
This one's empty.
Could you pass me that soy sauce, then?
Mizushina Sosuke (29)
Part-time Worker
This one's almost out.
You should use up the old
one before asking for more.
But it'll all be gone soon.
Whoops.
Nakanishi Osamu (48)
Office Worker
The pepper's actually empty.
Hey, bud.
Could I get some more pepper?
You got it.
That's way too much.
Thank you.
Hey, did the three people who
just left come in together?
No.
They're all regulars,
but they just happened to
come at the same time today.
What?
Do you think the three
of them are suspicious?
Suspicious?
The other day,
an incident occurred while
the three of them were here.
A bunch of police officers
came into the shop.
An incident?
A woman who lived in the neighborhood
was the victim of a robbery murder.
Oh, right.
They still haven't caught the culprit yet.
Are the three of them suspects?
Yeah, the cops said something like that.
And apparently they were
taken to the station.
Really?
But if they were here eating ramen today...
Doesn't that mean they were innocent?
But the police still seem to suspect them.
A couple of lady cops with
slanted and droopy eyes
come in practically every day.
Slanted...
And droopy eyed...
Lady cops?
Could it be?
Well? How did the three of them seem?
H-How did they seem?
Did they seem to be doing better than normal?
Did they have any expensive
clothes or bags or accessories?
They could be for all I know.
We're just a ramen shop.
Even if they ordered two bowls
of ramen instead of one,
it wouldn't tell you much about
their financial situation...
What about their clothes?
I don't think they were
dressed any differently.
Yumi-san and Naeko-san?
Huh?
Ran-chan.
And Conan-kun's with you.
You chased the culprit of the
robbery murder into the shop?
Just the two of you?
Yeah.
A week ago while Yumi-san and
I were patrolling the area,
we spotted a suspicious
figure outside a house.
You there!
What are you doing?
Hold it right there!
I'll run after him,
so you circle around in the car.
We'll flank him!
Got it!
I circled around and waited for them,
but only Yumi-san ever showed up.
There was a get-together at
the shopping center that day,
so most of the shops had their lights
off, and there weren't many passers-by.
The only place open
was this "Ramen to Die For Ramen Ogura."
So the customers in the shop then
were the three people who just left?
Yeah.
Later we stopped the three
of them in the shop.
We had Miwako and Takagi-kun
go to the house where we
spotted the suspicious figure.
The homeowner was found dead,
and bleeding from her head
in the entryway of her home.
On top of that, the windows were broken,
and the inside of the house was trashed.
The woman was a hostess.
When you consider she was
attacked on her way home
from picking up something she
forgot from her workplace,
the victim probably ran into
the robber in the entryway.
It escalated into a fight,
and she was murdered.
Then...
Wouldn't the last customer to rush
into the shop be the culprit?
Actually, just like today,
the three of them arrived
at roughly the same time.
And the lady cops didn't
show up until a while later.
What?
I thought Yumi-san ran after the culprit.
Apparently, she tripped
while chasing the culprit.
Yumi-chan, you can be so clumsy sometimes.
All I did was mix up the sauce and soy sauce!
Your droopy eyes aren't as cute
when you're angry, you know.
Excuse me.
Do you two...
...know each other?
Yeah.
She used to come to our shop before we moved,
with her boyfriend with the round glasses.
He's talking about Haneda-meijin.
He's my ex-boyfriend!
Oh, is that right?
But you made such a nice couple.
You haven't gotten back together?
But things seemed to be going well.
I don't care about him anymore.
He always said he was busy
when I tried to ask him out.
Well, a Seven-Crowned King
probably would be in high demand
for TV and magazine interviews.
It sure is strange, though.
Why do so many men with
round glasses like ramen?
My brother wears round glasses,
and he loves ramen.
See?
And if they have stubble,
it's practically guaranteed.
My brother has stubble, too.
He's pretty handsome,
so if he shaved and dressed properly,
he'd probably get all the girls.
But he normally wears track suits.
I know.
He looks like a failed entrance exam student,
but he's actually smart.
His memory is exceptional, too.
He instantly memorized my phone number.
He always says, "I'm the best in Japan
at memorizing those kinds of things."
"No, maybe even the best in the world."
What?
Stories about idiots aside,
I only tripped because of the hose.
The hose?
While I was chasing him,
the culprit threw a hose at me.
It was about two meters long.
It got caught in my legs, and I tripped.
It wasn't because I'm clumsy or anything.
What kind of hose was it?
It was a thick one with a
three centimeter diameter.
The victim probably used it
to water their flower beds.
It was missing from her yard.
At first we thought it was the murder weapon.
Why did you think it was the weapon?
Wasn't the victim's head bleeding?
When we first saw the culprit,
they were swinging the hose around
in the entryway of the victim's house.
Since there were signs that packing tape
had been stuck to the end of the hose,
we thought they had taped something
to it and bludgeoned her to death.
But there wasn't any blood on it anywhere.
The culprit was swinging...
...a hose?
The culprit was swinging the hose around?
Were they really doing that in
front of the victim's house?
Yeah, that's right.
They were swinging it
so intently you could hear it in the dark.
Almost as if they were conducting
some kind of ritual.
R-Ritual?
So scary...
I mean, isn't that it?
If that hose wasn't the weapon,
what else could they have been doing
with the hose next to the body?
Then what killed the woman?
She was pushed.
When she ran into the robber in
the entryway, they got into a fight.
The medical examiner said that when she fell,
she probably hit her head
on the edge of the stairs.
But weren't there signs that packing tape
had been stuck to the end of the hose?
If the culprit had taped something
to the end of the hose,
and used it to threaten her,
maybe the victim fell
while trying to avoid it.
That's not possible.
The woman was still wearing her shoes,
so it's clear she ran into the robber
before she entered the house.
They didn't have time to put
together some kind of weapon.
Which means
the culprit taped something to the end of
the hose after they committed the murder.
In other words,
they prioritized taping something
to the end of the hose and swinging
it around over running away.
Y-Yeah, I guess that's what it means.
It must've been a signal!
Maybe they were signaling their
robber friends with the noise!
Like, "Trouble! Run!"
What?!
Calling their phones would be faster
than taping something to
a hose to make some noise.
Besides,
if they'd decided on a signal,
they would've brought
something to make the noise.
They wouldn't have used a hose.
You...
You're right...
But how did you know the
hose came from that house?
Because the shape of the faucet in the yard
matched the shape of the end of the hose.
Which means the culprit was forced
to use that hose for some reason.
What could be more important
than fleeing the crime scene?
So when you chased the culprit
into this ramen shop,
the three of them were here.
You examined their belongings, right?
Apparently they were taken
to the police station.
Yeah.
They willingly accompanied
Miwako and Takagi-kun.
Then didn't one of them have
packing tape on their person?
Actually, the culprit
threw the tape at me when
they threw the hose.
Oh.
You should've said so from the start.
Do you know what the three of
them had on them at the time?
Huh?
Oh, yeah.
I wrote down what Takagi-kun told me.
The hostess Shono Yuna-san had
a wallet, cigarettes,
a lighter, a cell phone,
chewing gum, a handkerchief, tissues,
and her house key inside her handbag.
The part-time worker Mizushina Sosuke-san
had a coin purse, a cell phone, a mask,
his house key, and a glasses
case inside his jacket pockets.
The office worker Nakanishi-san
had a wallet, a house key, a cell phone,
company documents, and a hand towel
in his clothes pockets and briefcase.
Nobody had anything of value.
You searched the inside
of the shop, too, right?
Yeah, briefly.
But we didn't find anything.
How about gloves?
If one of them is a robber,
shouldn't they have had gloves?
Oh, actually...
Forensics found some suspicious gloves
in the sewer on the way here.
They were pretty dirty,
so they weren't able to
determine who wore them.
They concluded that Miike and
I had let the culprit escape,
and the three suspects were released.
But we're still upset about it, so we've
been investigating the three of them!
You got a problem with that?
N-No...
B-But if the lady cops associated with
that case came here every day,
do you really think the culprit would
bother coming here to eat ramen?
If I were the culprit,
I'd be too scared to come.
Are you calling us careless, then?!
N-No...
We'd never say that.
Right?
True...
Right.
I think the hostess Shono-san is suspicious.
What?
Wasn't the victim a hostess, too?
That could be related to the case.
Hold on, Sayo-chan.
We already investigated that lead.
The victim Tonda Atsuko-san
and Shono-san
used to work together.
But they'd lost contact since Shono-san
started working at another shop last year.
Apparently there wasn't any
connection between them.
But if they used to work at the same store,
she probably knew when she'd leave for work.
That certainly makes it
easier to rob someone.
In that case, Nakanishi-san's
just as suspicious.
Nakanishi-san was a regular
at Tonda-san's store.
He often requested her,
so he probably learned a lot about her.
And I think Mizushina-san probably knew
when Tonda-san went to work, too.
The convenience store he worked at
is right across the street from her house.
Although the convenience store
was shut down a few days before the murder.
So is it true that none of them have been
acting any differently since the murder?
I'm not sure.
Shono started putting a lot
of vinegar in her ramen,
for some cosmetic reason.
Mizushina started ordering
dumplings all the time.
And Nakanishi started ordering two
bowls of ramen instead of one.
None of those seem related to the case.
What did the robber steal from Tonda-san?
We're not sure.
There were signs that someone had
tried to break open the safe,
but there was still a
bunch of cash inside it.
Someone had gone through
the dresser drawer
where she kept her jewelry,
but a lot of them were still left.
Maybe it was the earrings.
Earrings?
Tonda-san used to come here sometimes.
One time she came here really drunk
and loudly bragged about them.
Look at these, boss.
My earrings.
Huh?
Boy, those are amazing.
Were they a gift from one of your regulars?
Yeah, that's right.
Together they're worth a million yen.
I always keep them in the back of my dresser,
but today's my birthday,
so I decided to wear them.
Congratulations.
Well, an unpopular and
disappointing hostess,
a worthless salaryman
who only ever comes to drink
and never gives me any presents,
and a creepy kid who stares at me
through the convenience store window,
could never get their hands on
anything like this treasure.
That's what she said.
That's it.
Why didn't you tell the police about that?!
I-I just remembered.
Speaking of remembering things,
there was another customer here
around the time of the incident...
A-Another customer?
Here?
Huh?
What?
There was another customer here
besides Shono, Mizushina, and Nakanishi?
Who could it have been?
Episode Preview
Didn't I tell you earlier?
Yumi-san and I flanked the culprit
who was running down the street
in front of this shop and
chased him into here.
A-Actually...
Not click-click, but click... click...
Every time they took a step?
That's it.
Sera-chan?
Conan-kun?
H-Hey...
Ramen to Die For: 2
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is
"Ramen to Die For: 2, Part Two!"
Vinegar, Soy Sauce, and Pepper
Next Conan's hint!
Vinegar, soy sauce, and pepper!
Go ahead with your romantic monologues.
Don't miss the next episode.
Chukichi.
Kazunobu.
Shu-nii.
What? That's it?