Lured by the previous day's ramen TV special,
we ended up going to Sera's regular
ramen spot on the way home from school.
There we met Shono Yuna-san,
Shono Yuna (34)
Hostess
Mizushina Sosuke-san,
Mizushina Sosuke (29)
Part-time Worker
and Nakanishi Osamu-san.
Nakanishi Osamu (48)
Office Worker
Each of these unusual customers used
large quantities of vinegar, soy sauce,
and pepper in their food respectively.
According to officers Miyamoto
Yumi and Miike Naeko,
who arrived as the three
of them were leaving,
they were suspects in the robbery
murder case that happened in the area.
A week ago while Yumi-san and
I were patrolling the area...
You there!
What are you doing?
Hold it right there!
I circled around and waited for them,
but only Yumi-san ever showed up.
There was a get together at
the shopping center that day,
so most of the shops had their lights
off, and there weren't many passers-by.
The only place open was this
"Ramen to Die For Ramen Ogura."
Then wouldn't the last customer to
rush into the shop be the culprit?
Actually, just like today, the three of
them arrived at roughly the same time.
And the lady cops didn't
show up until a while later.
What?
I thought Yumi-san ran after the culprit.
Apparently, she tripped
while chasing the culprit.
I only tripped because of the hose.
The hose?
While I was chasing him,
the culprit threw a hose at me.
At first we thought it was the murder weapon.
Why did you think it was the weapon?
Wasn't the victim's head bleeding?
When we first saw the culprit,
they were swinging the hose around in
the entryway of the victim's house.
The culprit was swinging...
...a hose?
Speaking of remembering things,
there was another customer here
around the time of the incident...
A-Another customer?
Here?
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
A fourth dangerous customer was in the shop?
Who is the culprit who swung
the hose around their head?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Ramen to Die For: 2
(Part Two)
"Ramen to Die For: 2, Part Two!"
W-Wait a minute!
There were only three customers here
when we ran into the store that day.
Yeah, because about a minute
before the three of them arrived,
he finished his ramen and left.
Yumi-chan's boyfriend, that is.
This place has the best ramen.
What? Haneda-meijin was here?
B-But that's not possible.
Didn't I tell you earlier?
Yumi-san and I flanked the culprit
who was running down the street
in front of this shop and
chased him into here.
If her boyfriend left just before
the culprit entered the shop,
Yumi-san or I would've seen him.
Right?
W-Well, actually...
What?
You ran into him in the street?
This is while you were
pursuing the culprit, right?
Well, yeah.
He ran up to me when my feet got tangled
in the hose the culprit
threw at me and I tripped.
Ow, ow, ow...
Are you all right?
Ch-Chukichi?
Y-Yumi-san?
What are you doing here?
What about you?
I'm chasing a suspicious figure.
Did you pass anyone like that?
Yeah, just now.
But it was dark. I only heard their
footsteps and saw a silhouette.
A silhouette, huh?
Also, it looked like they threw
away some kind of packing tape.
Packing tape?
In any case, the area's
dangerous. You should go home.
I'll fill you in on the details later.
And I haven't called him since.
After all, the case hasn't been solved yet.
No wonder you took so long even
though all you did was trip.
You should've told me.
Sorry.
He was breathing normally,
so I knew he wasn't the culprit.
I didn't want to get him
involved in the case.
Yeah, but just because he
was breathing normally...
What?
Yeah.
I'm not sure a police officer
should've let him go
without doing anything about it.
B-But...
But if he was eating ramen here
until just before the incident,
Chukichi must be innocent, right?
Yeah.
So your boyfriend's name is Chukichi, huh?
He's my ex-boyfriend.
Then why don't you call him?
Doesn't your boyfriend have a good memory?
My ex-boyfriend.
Sheesh. I guess I don't have a choice.
I'll try calling my brother, too.
He's the one who told me about this place,
so he might've seen those three before.
Yeah.
Maybe he'll know who did it after
hearing about it over the phone.
Yeah, right.
Hello, Yumi-tan.
Sorry I couldn't make our date the other day.
There was something I had
to do on your day off.
That's not important.
Do you remember
a week ago when we ran into each other?
I tripped while pursuing a suspicious figure.
Oh, sorry.
Someone's calling.
Give me a second.
Hey, Bro.
Sheesh.
What?
You're on the phone with someone
important, so call you back?
Hey, wait!
Huh?
You're already done with your call?
Who was that?
Your new girlfriend?
No!
Damn, he hung up on me.
Their conversations are
weirdly synchronized...
Well, whatever.
Anyway, is there anything
you haven't told me
about the person you passed by?
Anything I haven't told you?
Now that you mention it,
they were making a weird sound
with every step they took.
A click-click sound.
What?
They made a weird click-click
sound with every step they took?
Oh, not click-click, but click... click...
Not click-click, but click... click...
Every time they took a step?
That's it!
The culprit did that to pick those up.
Hey. When you searched the shop,
did you check the bathroom?
Of course.
What about the water tank?
We glanced inside, but we didn't see
anything that looked like jewelry.
Sera-chan?
Conan-kun?
H-Hey...
I see.
So that's why the culprit
was swinging the hose.
They couldn't leave this at the crime scene.
And if they're still coming
here, that means...
They haven't been able to retrieve it yet.
Their million yen treasure.
The Next Day
Welcome!
Thanks for coming!
No customers today, huh?
There was a group in here until a minute ago.
Really?
Yo!
We're back, Boss.
Hey.
You're here with the kid today, Mari-chan?
My name's Masumi.
Boss, could I place an order?
Sure thing.
Could I get one order each of pot
stickers, shumai, spring rolls,
and a small rice?
What?
You're not having ramen today, either?
Are you sick of it?
Oh, no. It's not like that.
He used to be all about the
Judge of the Afterlife ramen.
Really?
But if that's the case,
why did you sit there?
Huh?
There's not much soy sauce.
It'll run out soon.
Don't you eat pot stickers, shumai,
and spring rolls with soy sauce?
You were using a lot yesterday, too.
And you used a different soy sauce
container when yours ran out.
Uh, well...
And there was nobody else
here until we arrived.
So why did you sit at a seat
that had so little soy sauce?
Why?
Um...
Just because he's ordering
dishes that require soy sauce,
doesn't mean he'd check how much soy
sauce is left at each seat beforehand.
It's just a coincidence
that you sat there, right?
Y-Yeah.
They're not popsicles.
There's no prize at the bottom
of a soy sauce container.
WINNER
Right?
Boss, could I get a large
Judge of the Afterlife ramen,
pot stickers, and fried rice?
H-Hold on, Sato...
Satoko-san, if you eat
that much, you'll get fat.
I'll be fine, Taka... o-kun.
I'm planning on getting a
lot of exercise tonight.
B-By the way, have you heard?
There was a murder in this
neighborhood last week.
What?!
I had no idea!
A woman who returned home
to get something she forgot
and ran into a thief.
The thief pushed her as he tried to escape.
She hit her head on the stairs
in the entryway and died.
But the thief didn't leave right away.
He kept swinging around
a two meter long hose.
Creepy, right?
Seriously? What is that?
I'm so scared!
Hey, did that hose the
culprit was swinging around
have anything stuck to the end of it?
Yeah.
According to the police,
there were signs that packing tape had
been attached to one end of the hose.
Something may have been stuck to it.
What was it?
If the object taped to the end of the
hose were a breathable piece of cloth,
and he swung the hose around above his head,
it would've functioned as a vacuum cleaner.
The centrifugal force forces
the air inside the hose out,
and an amount equal to the air forced
out is sucked in through the other end.
I saw it performed in an
experiment on TV the other day.
Maybe the culprit saw it, too.
Really?
But what could he have used
for the breathable fabric?
Who knows?
Apparently the hose
belonged to the homeowner,
so it must've either been
something at the house,
or something the culprit had with them.
But the texture of a handkerchief would
be too fine to serve as a filter.
Is there some kind of cloth
that allows air through but
doesn't have large holes?
Maybe it was a mask.
You can breathe through a mask,
but it doesn't let dust through.
Hey, that's right.
Oh, right.
Speaking of masks,
didn't you have one the day of the incident?
I-I had a bit of a cold that day.
Really?
But what did he need to vacuum
up before running away?
Oh, that's right.
The policewoman who told
me about the case
said a guy who passed by the
culprit heard a weird noise.
A noise?
Yeah.
Every time the culprit took a step,
he made a click... click sound.
Click... click?
Maybe something was stuck
to one of his shoes.
Maybe he accidentally stepped
on something hard and sharp
that got stuck to the sole of his shoe.
But what did he step on?
It was more important than fleeing the scene.
Maybe it was glasses.
The lenses would break
if you stepped on them.
That must be it!
The culprit must've dropped his
glasses and stepped on them
when he got into a fight with the woman.
That's why he collected the
shards of the broken lenses
using the hose vacuum before running away.
The type and prescription of a lens
can be determined from the smallest piece.
The police would've known who bought it.
Wow, the police are so amazing!
Bo—
Boss!
I was wearing my glasses that day, right?!
Huh?
Yeah, you were.
But didn't you have
a glasses case with you?
S-So, what?
Conan-kun, do you have a glasses case on you?
No.
I always wear mine, so I don't need one.
The only people who carry cases are ones who
have separate pairs for near and far sight,
or have just recently bought a new pair.
New glasses are always
strong and make you dizzy,
so some people carry around an old pair
until they get used to the new ones.
Oh, yeah.
Come to think of it, what
happened to your new glasses?
What?
Wh-What new glasses?
Weren't you wearing them
the day the lady who was killed
tried to pick a fight with you?
W-Was I?
That's odd, though.
The police even investigated
the bathroom drain.
Why didn't they find the broken lenses?
What?
Really?
They even performed a body
check on the three suspects,
but none of them had it on them.
I'm sure the police will find
it if we tell them about this.
You know,
because Japan's police force
is so exceptionally talented.
You're right, Satoko-san.
Crap! Crap!
I need to get it before the police find it!
Huh?
It's gone!
It's not here!
S-Someone's in here.
I said someone's in—
What?
Are these the lens shards you're looking for?
Sorry, but we found them half a day ago.
I'm sure you thought about flushing them,
but if the police searched the
drain, you would've been screwed.
So you hid them at the
bottom of the water tank,
along with the other parts of your glasses.
Lenses are hard to see underwater
unless you look really closely.
And if your new glasses were frameless,
all you had to hide in the water
were the arms and bridge of the glasses.
It was likely the police would assume
they were part of the
toilet and overlook them.
And at a glance, they wouldn't
look like the stolen jewelry.
You probably retrieved the arms and bridge
the day after the murder.
But an examination of the
lenses revealed the truth.
A month ago,
you bought these from an optician.
So what?
That doesn't prove I killed that woman!
Oh,
we already found the earrings you
hid in the soy sauce container.
What?
You probably hid them there
before Yumi and Naeko arrived at the shop.
But you've been coming here every day
because you lost track of which
container they were in, right?
That's why you kept ordering
dishes that used soy sauce.
And the fingerprints on the
earrings we found matched yours.
We just got the warrant for your arrest,
so we barged into the bathroom
to place you under arrest.
Y-You're cops?
Did you forget?
We've met before.
MPD Section One Violent Crimes
Division Three, Sato Miwako!
And Takagi Wataru of the same department.
We were told to wait outside the shop
until the warrant arrived.
But we couldn't let you take a hostage,
and hole up inside the shop.
But since you'd seen us before,
you may have tried to run
if we entered the shop.
So we put on disguises and put on an act,
with the help of Conan-kun and the others.
It seemed like they were
having a lot of fun, though.
And you're the ones who told us
about the truth behind this case.
I-It wasn't me.
It was actually Sera-no-neechan who...
Huh?
Hey, where's Sera-no-neechan?
Oh, she just left.
She said she had something to do.
What?
Mari-chan left?
I forgot to give her her handkerchief again.
Her handkerchief?
Yeah.
She forgot it here when
she came the other day.
Oh, right.
Could you return this to her?
Yeah, sure.
I didn't mean to kill her.
I just wanted to scare her.
Yeah, yeah.
Tell it to the police.
Sheesh.
Apparently, he left scratches on the safe
in the victim's house, too.
He didn't want to make
it obvious that the thief
who stole the earrings heard
about them at this shop.
In any case,
we should get to the station
to record his statement.
And there's still the matter
of tonight's exercise.
If you want a workout,
why don't you go to the gym?
What?
I... I think I'll do that.
Idiot.
Look.
It's embroidered right
here on the handkerchief.
It says "Mari."
No, this isn't Mari.
It's Mary.
Then this handkerchief
belongs not to Sera Masumi,
but to the girl in the photo with her.
Huh?
Why did I assume that?
It's possible that Mary is
Sera Masumi's real name.
Which means I've met her and
heard that name somewhere before.
But where?
Episode Preview
Wh-What is that?
A nice old couple ran the shop.
Apparently the person who died on the
bridge was wearing brown shoes, too.
An insurance salesman came that afternoon.
That's strange. The person who
came down this path was...
That's right.
The dirt from the shrine out back.
The Mysterious Boy
The next episode of Conan
is "The Mysterious Boy!"
Toy Engine
Next Conan's hint!
A toy engine!
He loves soccer.
Don't miss the next episode.
And wears glasses.
And is always going potty.
He's not mysterious at all.