Kometo Bridge
The river dries up during this season.
What a filthy bridge.
The railing's completely black.
So what did you want to discuss?
There's something I want to show you
on the other side of the bridge.
Sheesh.
Fine, then.
I want to go to the shopping
area near the station.
Sorry.
It won't take long.
Huh?
What's wrong, old man?
Hey, look!
What is that?
Wh-What is that?!
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
An incident begins with a glowing toy.
A chance meeting leads to a miracle.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Mysterious Boy
“The Mysterious Boy!”
Are you guys going to look
for UFOs again tonight?
Of course!
We've already gone twice.
And came up empty-handed both times.
That's why we're sure it'll show up tonight.
Right?
UFOs, huh?
Conan-kun, you don't believe in them?
There have been three sightings
since the month started!
Three!
And they were all at the
riverbed near Kometo Bridge.
Some glowing gold thing flew
over the riverbed really fast.
That's right.
Some people even saw aliens on the riverbed.
As detectives, we can't just
ignore these sightings.
Investigating aliens isn't a detective's job.
In any case, we're going tonight.
Yeah!
Look.
Nagai Toys's curtains are open.
Maybe he's opening his store back up.
It won't open.
This shop closed down a long time ago.
I came here a few times.
A nice old couple ran the shop.
But there was never much that I wanted.
All they had were old toys.
Hey, what are you doing?
Let's go.
Okay.
Hey!
Your hands are covered in ice cream!
Sorry, sorry.
Jeez, now I'm all sticky.
Even kids still care about this place, huh?
Oshiro Tsutomu (30)
Kuromaru Finance Employee
That kid with the glasses was
staring at this toy engine.
Hey, stop!
Don't touch that!
Don't surprise me like that.
You made me drop it.
Nagai Tokujiro (72)
Manager of Nagai Toys
Just leave that old thing.
My wife treasured this engine.
In any case, you should sell
this place for the money.
I can't wait any longer.
Fine.
I'll do as you say.
Really?
Yes, but in exchange,
will you at least leave
some incense in the altar?
I don't have time for that shit.
Really?
Fine, then.
I know.
Take this with you.
You said you like liquor.
Are you sure?
Isn't that high quality scotch?
I bought it when I went
to England with my wife.
And I've stopped drinking.
Thanks.
Man, that's good.
Anyway, I'll be back once I
get the paperwork together.
See you later.
Sheesh. That brat...
What?
Are you going out, too?
We need to talk.
Do you mind?
Talk?
Sure, I guess.
The river dries up during this season.
What a filthy bridge.
The railing's completely black.
So what did you want to discuss?
There's something I want to show you
on the other side of the bridge.
Sheesh.
Fine, then.
I want to go to the shopping
area near the station.
Sorry.
It won't take long.
This way!
That was definitely the UFO.
It came from over the bridge
and landed over there.
Are you sure?
I didn't see anything.
Me, neither.
The light disappeared around here.
Okay.
Let's look for it!
Yeah!
I bet it's near the wall.
The wall?
It's a UFO.
What's this?
This is...
What's this doing here?
Hey, Edogawa-kun!
Stay back!
And, Haibara, call the police.
Got it.
The victim is Oshiro Tsutomu, thirty years old.
He worked for Kuromaru Finance in Haido-cho.
He was a debt collector for
a black market lender, huh?
Yes, most likely.
According to security cameras in the
shopping center, he left the station after four,
and walked past the shopping
center heading directly this way.
He probably came here to collect on a debt.
I see.
Judging from the circumstances,
it's likely he got drunk
and fell off this bridge.
But just to be sure, go check
with Kuromaru Finance tomorrow.
Got it.
So you kids came here to see the UFO?
Yeah.
Did you hear any suspicious sounds
or see any suspicious figures?
Good work, everyone.
It's likely that this was an accident.
Once we're finished with
the general inspection—
Hey, Inspector.
What?
There's a coupon for half off
at a ramen shop in this man's wallet.
Shinobiya Ramen
What about it?
He must've been desperate to eat
at Shinobiya Ramen if he
printed out a coupon for it.
That's odd, though.
This bridge doesn't lead
to Shinobiya Ramen near
the station shopping center.
He probably meant to go another day.
No, the coupon expires today.
Effective Through August 13
Which means he probably
meant to stop by after work.
Then it doesn't make sense
that he came this way.
So if he was finished with work,
he wouldn't have come this way.
And if he wasn't, then he
wouldn't have been drinking.
This is...
Who is it?
What are you doing here at this hour?
I live around here.
I forgot my house key, and I can't get in.
Where are your parents?
They're out.
Can I stay here until they come back?
Here?
Sorry, but—
Apparently someone died at Kometo Bridge.
A person?
That explains the sirens I heard.
Apparently it's a murder.
This is becoming a dangerous area.
Fine.
You can come in.
You can wait in here for a little while.
Thanks!
What are you doing?
Come in.
These “Flashing Boomerangs”
brings back memories.
You hardly see them anymore, though.
Is it broken?
Yeah.
I had it out on a shelf, but it fell.
You mean that shelf?
That's right.
My hand slipped when I tried to
pick it up, and I dropped it.
Hm...
Mister, do you live alone?
Yeah, my wife passed away last year.
She'd been in the hospital for a
long time with a difficult disease.
And you've been alone since then?
Yeah.
Did anyone visit you today?
No, nobody came.
You've been here the whole time?
Yeah, I was here all day today.
Hm...
What are you doing, son?
Do your shoulders hurt?
From about six months ago.
They hurt pretty badly when
I try to lift my arms.
But how did you know?
The bottom half of this
cabinet has been cleaned,
but the top is covered in dust.
I thought you might have
trouble raising your arms.
You're right.
It's hard cleaning the top.
Then you couldn't have
picked up the toy engine.
What?
That shelf is pretty high up.
How did you get the toy engine when
your shoulders are hurting you?
I dropped it because I
pushed myself too hard.
Why did you do that?
No reason.
Being here alone just brought
back some old memories.
But someone must've visited you today.
How do you know that?
I'm not lying.
Because there's shoe polish on the floor.
Is something wrong?
Look at the floor over there.
See those brown marks?
That's shoe polish, right?
Apparently the person who died on the
bridge was wearing brown shoes, too.
An insurance salesman came this afternoon.
The shoe polish probably belongs to him.
I had him leave immediately since I
wasn't interested in his insurance.
That's why I'd forgotten.
These marks were made when
someone put these shoes on.
That means he took off his
shoes and came inside, right?
Why did you let him in when you
weren't interested in his insurance?
Son, your parents have
probably come home by now.
Mister, smell my hand.
Son, that's enough!
Please!
Doesn't it smell like strawberries?
Yeah, it does.
This evening my friend touched
the door of this building
with his strawberry ice cream covered hand.
I just touched it when I
tried to open the door,
so I smell like strawberries.
Really?
I'll clean it in the morning.
This same smell was on the
hand of the man who died.
He came here today, didn't he?
Wh-What are you trying to say, son?
It sounds like you think I'm
involved in the case somehow.
But aren't you?
Aren't you the one who killed him?
Wh-What are you saying?
If you're right,
that means you're alone with a murderer.
Doesn't that scare you?
No,
because I don't think
you're actually a bad man.
No matter what you say,
I haven't killed anyone.
Besides, didn't he accidentally
fall from the bridge?
You threw this off the bridge,
and while the dead man was
distracted, you pushed him off.
I don't think a toy boomerang
would fly that well.
You experimented numerous
times at the riverbed,
to see how the boomerang would
shine and how it would fly.
The people who saw that
started saying it was a UFO.
A UFO?
My friends were talking about it, too.
That's ridiculous.
Besides, why would I go
through all that trouble
just to push someone off a bridge?
The man who died was young and fit,
so you couldn't overpower him.
Besides, your shoulders hurt,
so you can't lift your arms.
You had to lift his legs while
he was distracted by something.
How do you know I lifted his legs?
His pants didn't have any grime
from the railing on them.
But his palms were pitch black with dirt.
That proves he was holding the
railing and leaning out over it.
But that doesn't prove I did it.
I would never do anything as
violent as killing a person.
There aren't any shops that sell
these boomerangs these days.
But there are plenty here.
And then there's the strawberry ice cream...
It's just a coincidence.
I don't know anything about it.
Then how did you know he fell off the bridge?
I only said a man died near it.
It's natural to think they fell
if a person died at a bridge!
He drank too much scotch
and accidentally fell!
That's obviously—
How did you know the victim
was drinking scotch?
Not beer or ordinary whiskey,
but scotch.
I just...
had a feeling.
It's not working.
Looks like it's missing some parts.
It's probably a small gear.
Did you try looking for it?
Of course.
Think back on the moment the toy engine fell.
Didn't the gear fall into a shoe?
The police don't think it was
an accidental death, either.
They'll find out that the dead man
came here before long.
On top of that, if they find
the gear in his shoe...
My wife was in the hospital
a long time for her sickness.
It was expensive.
I ended up borrowing money
from some shady lenders
to pay her medical bills.
The man who fell from the
bridge was a debt collector.
He was terrible to me.
But I didn't mind, no matter
what he did to me.
After all, it was all for my wife.
But he
went to my wife in the hospital
and demanded repayment.
My wife became despondent, and
her condition suddenly worsened.
Her last words were “I'm sorry.”
I remember you now.
I thought we'd met before.
Yes, you're the boy who came to my store.
Back then...
Who dropped this?
I-I don't know.
He's the one who dropped the engine.
I-It wasn't me!
You shouldn't make up stories!
It's not a story.
See the footprints on that stool?
The culprit stood on that so
they could pick up the engine.
Those are the footprints
of a boy's athletic shoes.
So we can eliminate the girls.
The remaining three boys are
all wearing athletic shoes.
But the dirt on the stool
is damp and viscous.
This isn't from the schoolyard, but...
That's right!
The dirt from the shrine out back.
The dirt on your shoes is dry.
It's probably from school.
So you couldn't have done it, either.
You're tall.
You wouldn't have needed the
stool to get the engine.
Which leaves only you.
Hey, wait!
Why aren't you going after him?
I don't have to.
He'll come back.
What?
I trust that boy.
But the engine is broken.
If something's broken,
you just have to fix it.
I'm sorry!
My late wife used to talk
about that day all the time.
No, that's not possible.
You haven't changed at
all since ten years ago.
What on earth...?
If he goes to the police now,
he can still turn himself in.
You went awfully easy on
the culprit this time.
Yeah.
I understand.
Takagi-kun, go to Nagai-san's
store immediately.
Yes, sir.
Sato-kun, look into Kuromaru Finance.
If they're actually giving out dubious loans,
I want you to investigate them thoroughly.
Got it.
Nagai-san,
come with me to the station.
Yes, sir.
Maybe I shouldn't ask, but
why did you turn yourself in?
A mysterious boy appeared.
A mysterious boy?
Yes,
a mysterious boy who hadn't changed
at all since ten years ago.
He...
He may have been sent by my wife in heaven.
Episode Preview
Hey, Conan-kun.
Doesn't this forest seem like there
would actually be zombies out there?
Th-This is the magical sword
that turns zombies to ash
at the slightest touch.
Harawaki-san?
Let's just leave already!
A Cottage Surrounded By Zombies
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is “A Cottage
Surrounded By Zombies, Part One!”
Zombie Blade
Next Conan's hint!
A zombie blade!
Ran, you can be such an airhead.
Don't miss the next episode.
What? How?
You can practically count on it.