Hongo,
I'm finished...
Don't be ridiculous.
It's nearly dawn.
Then the rescue team will arrive.
You don't need to comfort me.
I can't move the leg they bit.
H-Hongo, you should run.
I can't do that.
Look out the window.
You can't see outside
because of all the zombies.
The odds you'll make it through there
while carrying an injured
man are practically zero.
But on your own,
you'll be able to survive using
the Zombie Blade you wield.
Hongo, you've got to keep on living.
Live so you can avenge me...
H-Hey,
don't you think Hayato-san is acting weird?
Hang in there, Hayato-san!
I'll drag you home if I have to!
Shut up and watch.
Stand up, Hayato-san!
I told you so!
Hayato-san?
No.
She needs to run.
No, no, no, no, no.
Hayato-san?
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
Ran can't stand horror movies.
But the filming location is even scarier.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
A Cottage Surrounded By Zombies
(Part One)
"A Cottage Surrounded
By Zombies, Part One!"
Hey, come on.
I took you out for a drive
since you seemed bored,
even though it's summer break,
and you're yawning?
It's your fault for renting that scary DVD.
Thanks to you, I couldn't
sleep until morning.
I couldn't help it.
It was a low budget, C-movie horror.
But they wouldn't play it on TV
even though Yoko-chan was in it.
Anyway, is your stomach okay?
You kept saying you were hungry earlier.
Yeah.
I'm fine now.
You shouldn't snack between meals.
The doctor said you have
too much visceral fat.
Yeah, yeah.
Anyway, where are we headed?
You'll find out when we get there!
W-Wait, isn't this
the cottage from the zombie
movie we watched last night?
Yeah.
We're pilgrims visiting a holy place.
Haven't you heard
of fans visiting locations
used in movies and TV shows?
Yeah, but usually they visit
places from memorable—
This is the front door where
Yoko-chan coughed up blood!
That's the window Yoko-chan
kicked a zombie out of!
Look at all these treasures!
Hey, Conan-kun.
Doesn't this forest seem like there
could actually be zombies out there?
We'll be fine.
There aren't any zombies.
Apparently there are.
I said there's no way—
I-It's you!
Hattori-kun and Kazuha-chan!
What are you doing here?
They're obviously here
on a pilgrimage like me.
No, idiot.
It's true that we're here
on related business, though.
What do you mean?
Some idiot couple came here
on their own pilgrimage.
After checking out the cottage,
they started their car to go home.
But something suddenly jumped out in
front of the car, and they ran it over.
They thought it was an animal
and got out of the car to check.
But when they opened the door,
they smelled rotting flesh.
And when they went to look under
the car, it crawled out...
A zombie in tattered clothes
with a broken neck!
What happened to the couple after that?
They fled in their car and told
their friend Otaki-han about it.
Let's leave.
And then we heard about the story.
Let's leave!
Though it was probably
just some idiot's prank.
Let's leave.
Let's just leave already!
What's wrong with you?
We just got here.
Besides, Zombie Blade:
Dinner Party of the Dead,
the movie we watched last
night, has a cult following.
Rumor is they're making a sequel,
so they might use this cottage again.
I'm not sure they'll be
able to make it though.
Oh, there will be a sequel.
What?
After all, we're here to shoot the trailer.
Um...
Who are you?
Naito Tetsuto (38)
Film Director
I'm Naito Tetsuto, director of Zombie Blade.
If you're here to shoot the trailer,
does that mean you've got a ton of
crew packed into the back of your car?
Yeah.
The lead actress, too?
Of course.
She's our lead actress, Ria-chan.
I-It's not Yoko-chan? But it's a sequel.
Yeah.
I've known Yoko-chan since her debut,
so she appeared in the first one
for the sake of our friendship.
Kawabata Ria (29)
Actress
What's this old man's problem?
Does he think I'm not good
enough to star in the movie?
Of course I don't.
Hey, hey, isn't that Kawabata Ria?
You mean that woman who's in
all those suspense thrillers?
Yoko-chan wanted to appear in the film,
Harawaki Takashi (30)
Producer
but her agency wouldn't
give us the green light.
So I convinced my friend
to star in this C-movie.
You keep calling it a C-movie,
but you're going to film it properly, right?
Don't worry.
Since we're old friends,
I'll make sure it looks good.
Ejiri Kyoko (30)
Cameraman
Especially the scene in which you're bitten
by a zombie and become one yourself.
There's no scene like that, Kyoko.
Oh, really?
This movie is about Okino Yoko-san's character,
Hongo Yoko's cousin Kazami Reina,
Baisho Orie (29)
Lighting Crew
inheriting the Zombie Blade from
her and exterminating zombies.
Wasn't it in the script?
There's no way Ria would become a zombie.
B-But I like bad endings, too.
Ninomiya Masahachi (29)
Sound Crew
No, no.
This isn't a school festival movie.
We can't keep changing the story.
B-But he...
Yeah.
He'd probably want
a crazy story about a protagonist
who becomes a zombie and butchers
friend and foe alike in a total bloodbath.
But there's no point in wishing for it.
He's gone, and the script is finished.
I even came up with the subtitle this morning,
and put it in an envelope like I always do.
I'll be announcing it later, so
you can look forward to that.
Who is he?
He's the president of
our college horror club.
We're all former members of the
club aside from the director.
Let's get inside and start filming.
Yeah.
U-Um, excuse me...
W-Would it be all right if I went inside?
Dad.
I'm sorry, but you can't watch us work.
W-We can't have any noise in the background.
Oh, I don't want to watch.
I-I need to use the restroom.
What's wrong? You look like a zombie.
Did you eat something weird?
But we had the same thing for breakfast.
And we're fine, right?
Come to think of it,
didn't you go into the forest on
the way here to go to the bathroom?
You must've gotten bit by
some kind of weird bug then.
N-Nothing bit me.
I was a little hungry,
so I had a bite of these
delicious mushrooms.
That's a tsukiyotake.
Apparently they taste good,
but they're poisonous.
What?
We're going to be filming,
so try not to make too much noise.
Okay.
Is he really going to be okay?
Yeah, if he rests for a while.
It's rare for anyone to die
from eating tsukiyotake.
We could take him to the hospital
on the motorcycle we rode here,
but I doubt he'd be able to hold
onto me until we got there.
If you're worried,
why don't we ask the crew to give
him a ride to the hospital later?
Maybe you're right.
Ran-chan, come here!
They said we could watch
them film if we're quiet.
Want to watch them work?
What? But...
Let's go.
There's no point in us staying here.
Dad, we'll be back.
Get some rest, okay?
Th-This is the magical sword that turns
zombies to ash at the slightest touch.
The Zombie Blade!
What?
What is this feeling?
Something's entering my body.
Cut!
Th-There wasn't any noise.
And the sword was glowing nicely, too.
The video was perfect, too.
Good.
That was super intense!
I know! It was amazing!
I can't wait to see how it turns out.
I-I'll probably pass on watching it.
The rest of our scenes take place after dark,
so why don't we have an early dinner?
Yeah, you're right.
Ninomiya-kun, will you get
our food from the car?
O-Okay.
Anyway, where did Harawaki-kun go?
It's weird.
Normally he sticks around
to complain about the shoot.
Do you want us to go look for him?
He's somewhere around the cottage, right?
Yeah, thanks.
When you're around, I feel
like I'm in college again.
Really?
It would be perfect if
the president were here.
I know.
Well, the president's brother
is here filming instead.
I'm sure he's happy up there.
Hey, where are you?
Everyone's eating dinner!
Harawaki-san!
Sheesh.
Could he be sleeping in one of the rooms?
Oh, well.
I guess we'll have to check all of them.
Yeah.
Harawaki-sa...
H-Hey, mister!
Are you okay?
Damn it.
He's not breathing.
He's holding something.
It's a cell phone.
A-And check this out.
It's recording?
What? Harawaki-kun is dead?
H-He was poisoned?
Yeah.
It was hydrocyanic acid.
His mouth smelled like almonds.
And under the desk were a plastic bottle
and jar labeled potassium cyanide.
A body's jaw stiffens first,
but his was still soft.
He had death spots, too,
but they hadn't merged yet.
Which means it's been between
thirty to sixty minutes since he died.
H-How do you know that?
Who are you?
I'm Hattori Heiji.
In Kansai, I'm fairly well-known as
the High School Detective of the West.
H-High school detective?
Of the West? Does that mean there's
a High School Detective of the East?
Of course.
This kid standing in front of you...
H-Hey!
...knows high school student
Kudo Shinichi real well.
Ran-chan knows Kudo-kun better than him.
Right?
Y-Yeah.
Is it possible someone
made him take the poison?
No.
Apparently he took it himself.
There's a video.
A video?
Yeah.
Harawaki-san died with his phone in his hand.
It captured him drinking
the poison and collapsing.
That's a pretty low angle.
Yeah.
Apparently he propped up the phone on
the floor with a box of cigarettes.
The timer was set to automatically
start recording after a while.
See?
He's putting the poison in the water bottle.
Then he chugs it down.
He starts writhing in pain,
and drops the bottle of
poison and plastic bottle.
And after staggering backwards,
he loses balance in front
of the phone on the floor.
I'm not sure why,
but then he reaches out for the
phone that's recording him.
He knocks it down, and it cuts to black.
After this, the video's black for a while.
After about 50 minutes, you can
hear our voices in the background.
Which means the estimated time of death
I gave earlier was more or less right.
H-Hey, mister!
Are you okay?
You're right.
I hear your voice.
See?
Damn it.
He's not breathing.
What?
Was that you, Conan-kun?
It kind of sounded like Shinichi.
Uh-oh!
He was copying me.
Since we're always getting
involved in cases together,
he picked up my mannerisms
without realizing it.
This kid really seems to look up to me.
Yeah.
I want to be a detective like Heiji-niichan.
You two really are as close as brothers.
Yeah.
Hattori, nice follow up.
Thanks for saving me.
Kudo.
You owe me.
He still hasn't forgotten about the
recording of his confession to Kazuha-chan.
But why would he record this video?
I don't know yet,
but it's almost definitely a suicide.
There was some creepy note
that sounded like a
suicide note on his phone.
C-Creepy?
Note?
"To my old friend Naito Joji.
Though this poison
will stop the beating of
my heart and I will die,
my soul will remain in my body
and gain an infinite amount of time.
Then, just like the events of this film,
Funeral Procession of the Dead,
I shall invite the living in
this house to join our world."
Fu...
Funeral Procession of the Dead?
It was written on the paper
inside the envelope in
Harawaki-san's pants pocket.
It must've been the subtitle of the movie.
He said he was going to announce it later.
Did Harawaki-san always choose the subtitles?
Yeah.
He said it was his job as the producer.
He'd always choose it himself,
seal it in a white envelope,
and reveal it in front of the crew.
Once Ninomiya-kun accidentally
opened an envelope.
Harawaki-kun was furious and went through
the trouble of changing the subtitle.
Then Harawaki-san probably
wrote the note on his phone.
The paper's too thick to see through.
And there weren't any signs that the
envelope had been ripped or wet.
Anyway, I'm more interested in the Naito
Joji he mentioned at the beginning.
Who is he?
We told you about him before
we entered the cottage.
He was the president of
our college horror club.
He was also my younger brother.
His death was a strange one.
It's possible that it
influenced Harawaki-kun.
How'd he die?
I-It happened eight years ago.
We were staying here to film a horror
movie for our school festival.
But our director and club
president suddenly announced...
Naito Joji
Horror Club President
A mystery!
Why don't we make this a mystery
instead of a horror film?
If it's not going to be that impressive
anyway since it's an amateur film,
we might as well surprise
our audience with a mystery.
There you go again with your crazy ideas.
There isn't much time until the festival.
A-And we have to return the equipment
we borrowed from your brother.
Aren't you the one who suggested
we shoot a zombie movie?
I'm not saying there won't be any zombies.
The twist will be that the
real murderer isn't a zombie,
but a living person.
If you don't think we can do it,
I'll vanish from this room.
Like a corpse that's returned
to life as a zombie.
The president always had crazy ideas,
but they often made sense
once he explained them.
Everyone went along with his idea.
If he was so convinced he could
do it, we wanted to see him do it.
I see.
So what happened?
He told us to wait ten minutes,
so Ninomiya-kun and I
kept watch at the window.
Harawaki-kun, Kyoko, and I
stood in front of the door.
When we entered the room after
ten minutes, he really was gone!
There wasn't a trace of him left!
Did you really look for him?
Of course we did!
We looked under the bed and in the dresser.
We even moved the dresser
to see if there was a secret passageway
leading to the next room behind it.
We thought he might've escaped
through the window
while Ria and Ninomiya-kun were
coming around the cottage.
S-So we searched the forest,
but we couldn't find him anywhere.
We called his name until we were
parched, and we were thirsty for beer.
So we ditched the president
and went into town to drink.
We took Harawaki-kun's car.
Then Ria caught a cold and
was down for three days.
On the day of the fourth morning,
when we returned to the cottage...
He was there in the room,
his emaciated body sitting on the floor.
His head was turned slightly as though he
was saying, "You finally found me."
Episode Preview
Why?
It's got to be around here somewhere.
Th-They vanished.
Just like the president eight years ago,
they turned into a zombie
and vanished from the room!
That's impossible.
The dead don't come back to life.
Th-The body's missing...
Th-There are zombies around the house.
A Cottage Surrounded By Zombies
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "A Cottage
Surrounded By Zombies, Part Two!"
Audition
Next Conan's hint!
An audition!
Don't miss the next episode.
Apparently lots of zombies
are in the next episode.
How exciting.
Yeah, right!