We came to visit the shooting
location of a zombie movie.
Hattori and Kazuha were also
there to investigate rumors
that actual zombies had appeared there.
On top of that,
the crew shooting the sequel to
the zombie movie also arrived.
But during filming, the producer
Harawaki Takashi-san died.
Due to the video of him
drinking poison and something
that appeared to be a
suicide note on his phone,
we thought it was a suicide, but...
Anyway, I'm more interested in the Naito
Joji he mentioned at the beginning.
Who is he?
He was the president of
our college horror club.
He was also my younger brother.
Naito Tetsuto (38)
Film Director
His death was a strange one.
It's possible that it
influenced Harawaki-kun.
How'd he die?
Why don't we make this a mystery
instead of a horror film?
Aren't you the one who suggested
we shoot a zombie movie?
I'm not saying there won't be any zombies.
The twist will be that the
real murderer isn't a zombie,
but a living person.
Naito Joji
Horror Club President
If you don't think we can do
it, I'll vanish from this room.
Like a corpse that's returned
to life as a zombie.
He told us to wait ten minutes,
so Ninomiya-kun and I
kept watch at the window.
When we entered the
room after ten minutes,
Baisho Orie (29)
Lighting Crew
he really was gone!
There wasn't a trace of him left!
We thought he might've
escaped through the window
while Ria and Ninomiya-kun were
coming around the cottage.
S-So we searched the forest, but
we couldn't find him anywhere.
Ejiri Kyoko (30)
Cameraman
We called his name until we were parched,
and we were thirsty for beer.
So we ditched the president
and went into town to drink.
Then Ria caught a cold and
was down for three days.
On the day of the fourth morning,
when we returned to the cottage...
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
The president appears
to have become a zombie.
They start closing in on
the mysterious mansion.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
A Cottage Surrounded By Zombies
(Part Two)
"A Cottage Surrounded
By Zombies, Part Two!"
So?
How long had it been since your brother died?
The police said it had been
about twelve hours.
The strange thing is
there were marks on my brother's fingers,
indicating he'd scratched something
hard enough for his nails to come off.
But there were no scratches
anywhere in the room.
Don't tell me one of you killed Joji-san,
and carried his body there.
O-Of course not!
Before we found the body, we'd all gone
to Ria's apartment to take care of her!
You're right.
Although I had a bunch of rare
horror movie DVDs at my apartment,
Kawabata Ria (29)
Actress
so all you really did was drink and party.
Harawaki-kun was the only
one of us could drive,
but he was blind drunk for three days.
W-Wait a minute!
Only Harawaki-san can drive?
Yeah.
This isn't good.
Someone's dead, but we
can't even call the police.
What?
Why not?
We can take our motorcycle to the police.
I know,
but the bike's nearly out of gas.
You're kidding.
You didn't realize we were out of gas?
Can't we call the police
on our cell phones, then?
There's no service here.
What?
Then we'll have to wait for
Ran-chan's dad to get better.
Yeah.
Anyway, what happened to the movie?
We never finished it.
The video we took was lost, too.
If we knew where it went,
it might actually solve the mystery
behind Harawaki-kun's suicide.
What mystery?
Kyoko, do you know something?
I can't tell you yet.
I'm waiting until the police arrive.
I could be wrong, though.
Hey, Ran-chan.
Want to go to the bathroom together?
O-Okay.
I was actually about to
suggest the same thing.
I wish they'd stop telling
scary stories already.
I feel like we really will see a zombie.
D-Don't say that.
H-Hey, Kazuha-chan.
I-I feel like there's something behind us.
Y-Yeah, right.
A z-zo...
Zombie?
D-Dad?
Oh, it's just your dad.
Don't scare us like that.
Th-There are zombies around the house.
Z-Zombies?
That's impossible.
Are you sure your fever isn't
making you hallucinate?
You should rest if you're sick.
Hey, mister. Still not feeling better?
We'll never solve this case unless you drive.
Heiji, don't be so unreasonable.
He ate a poisonous mushroom.
M-More importantly, look outside...
No, Dad. You can't go outside yet.
He'll have to rest a while longer.
Looks like we're going to
have to stay here tonight.
What?
But we haven't had dinner yet.
I'm starving.
Apparently there's a convenience store
about a three hour hike down the mountain.
Really?
Maybe we can use the phone there to
call the police and an ambulance.
They shopped there all the time
while shooting the movie
for their school festival.
Really?
Anyway, what a strange story.
I can't believe all the
members of the horror club
are making movies now.
Weren't you listening?
Director Naito's younger brother died then.
That's why the director invited
them to work with him.
He asked if they wanted to finish the
movie his brother wanted to make.
Apparently he found the script
for the movie at his house.
Oh, you mean that horror-turned-mystery film?
No, no.
Apparently they upgraded
the script they wrote
before turning it into a mystery.
It turned out to be a bigger
hit than they expected.
When he decided to make a sequel,
the director got them back together again.
The zombie movie trailer they
came to shoot this time
is supposed to be a teaser for the sequel.
I'm a little scared to hike down the
mountain to the convenience store, though.
It seems like there are zombies out there.
Don't worry.
There's no such thing as zombies.
Z-Zombies...
Th-There are zombies outside...
Are you stupid?
Open you eyes and take a good look!
There aren't any zombies—
Wh-Who the hell are they?!
What's that horde of zombies doing out there?
They've surrounded the cottage!
You two take the old man upstairs!
But, Heiji...
Don't worry.
I won't let a single one of them through.
Okay.
You guys should hurry up and go upstairs!
Damn it!
This is all we've got for weapons!
A boom mic?
That's right!
Inside the box...
H-Hey, Hattori!
Crap! They broke through the window!
Anyone who attacks me is my enemy.
Come and get me if you want to die.
Dad, hang in there.
W-We need to get him inside the room.
No way.
Oh, no.
The body's in here.
Damn it!
Just how many are there?
Th-Thanks, Kudo!
There's no end to them.
Yeah, I know.
Usually hordes like these will back
down if you kill their leader.
That's him.
Hey, big guy!
Are you their leader?
What?
I-I killed him!
K-Kudo, what are we going to do?
More importantly, look.
Even though you took off his
head, he's still moving.
What?
I thought they were a gang
pretending to be zombies.
But if they really are monsters,
we'll have to send them all to hell.
W-Wait...
What?
You've got it all wrong.
I just fixed this head, too.
And now you've ruined it!
Y-You're auditioning to be extras?
Yeah.
You all are?
Well, yeah.
They said we could be in the
Zombie Blade sequel if we passed.
Come to think of it,
another director asked fans
to do their own makeup
and audition to cut costs.
You mean that Halloween party on the boat.
It was hard work.
We pitched tents in the forest and
helped each other with our makeup.
We waited until eight when the
audition started while bugs bit us.
I've been camped out here for three days!
When I went to practice on a couple who
came to visit the filming location,
they ran over my fake head with
their car and broke it.
It took me two days to fix it,
and now look at what you've done.
So this guy was the zombie
that attacked the couple.
So who set up this audition?
The producer Harawaki-san.
The man who committed suicide?
He uploaded the announcement to his blog.
"I'm holding an audition for
extras, so gather all zombies!"
There was an announcement on a hidden
website only core fans know about.
He told us not to tell anyone since he
wanted to surprise the director and crew.
Harawaki-san was supposed to
come out and say it was a prank.
What's going on?
Hey, Hattori.
A man with this kind of surprise planned
wouldn't kill himself, would he?
Yeah.
That means that suicide was actually...
Sounds like the extras got in
through the second story window.
What a pain in the butt.
Kazuha, they're not zombies.
H-Heiji...
K-Kyoko-san is bleeding from her neck.
She won't respond when we talk to her.
She's not moving at all.
What?!
Kyoko?!
Hang in there!
Kyoko!
Move! Don't touch her!
It's too late. She's dead.
Her carotid artery's been cut.
Ran-neechan, ask the zombies
downstairs to call the police.
Th-The zombies?
Some of them probably drove here.
O-Okay. Zombies...
What was the situation
upstairs when you found her?
W-We were all in different rooms.
But we decided it'd be
better to stick together.
When we came to this room
to look for Kyoko-kun...
We found her like this.
Is this cell phone on the chair Kyoko-san's?
Y-Yeah.
Just like Harawaki-san's,
this one is recording.
What?
D-Does that mean the culprit
was recorded on it?
The first person to enter
the frame is Kyoko-san.
Looks like someone's chasing her.
That person's in the frame now.
No! Stay back!
H-He bit her neck.
We can't tell who it is from behind.
Come on, face this way.
That's it, just like that...
What?
N-No way.
Was that Harawaki-kun?
Impossible!
D-Didn't he kill himself?
H-Heiji?
That's impossible!
The dead don't come back to life!
Th-The body's missing...
No way.
When Ran-chan and I came in earlier,
the sheet was still over it.
Really?
Yeah.
What in the world...
...is going on?
What? Harawaki-kun's body disappeared?
Yeah, as you can see.
All that's in the room is the
sheet that was covering the body,
the top Kyoko-san was wearing
before she was murdered,
and a box cutter with blood on it.
Th-That box cutter...
I think that's the one
that was in the toolbox.
Why is there blood on it?
The culprit must've used it
to cut Kyoko-san's throat.
What?
Wasn't Kyoko bitten on the neck?
No.
In the video it looked like she was bitten,
but she was actually cut with a knife.
You can tell by looking
at the cut on her artery.
The question is why did the
culprit prop up Kyoko-san's phone
on the chair and record that video?
Ninomiya Masahachi (29)
Sound Crew
Wasn't it Harawaki-kun?
H-He came back as a zombie and wanted
to film himself murdering Kyoko-san.
You idiot, the dead don't come back to life.
There must be some trick behind the video.
T-Trick?
Yeah, and there's another one, too.
Hey, you guys.
Did anyone come out of this window
or drop anything out of it?
What?
We've been here since about an hour ago.
But no one opened the window.
Hey, Hattori.
Isn't there a window at the end of
the hallway in front of this room?
Yeah.
According to the zombie extras
who climbed up to the window
and were looking inside,
they don't remember who
went in which rooms,
but they didn't see anyone carrying a body.
Looks like no one exited
through this window, either.
Which means Harawaki-san's body...
Yeah.
Someone hid it inside this room.
Let's split up and search the room.
We'll start with this wardrobe.
I-I'll help, too.
You're right.
We'll have to move the wardrobe
to see if there's a hidden door behind it.
Kid, could you look under the bed?
Yeah.
It's a fixed bed.
You're right.
There could be a hidden
passageway under the bed.
What's wrong, Orie?
Nothing.
Why?
Why can't we find the body anywhere?
Only Harawaki-kun's jacket
was inside the wardrobe.
Th-There doesn't seem to be a secret
door behind the wardrobe, either.
There wasn't anything under the bed.
Or inside the mattress.
That's impossible.
It's got to be around here somewhere.
H-He vanished.
Just like the president eight years ago,
he turned into a zombie
and escaped from the room!
W-Wait a minute.
You and Ninomiya-kun don't know,
since you were outside watching the window!
But eight years ago, Harawaki-kun and
Kyoko and I searched this room, too!
What?
Then this room...
Yeah, that's right!
The president disappeared from
and was found dead four
days later in this room!
Who was the first one to find the body?
Kyoko and Ria.
They said they'd search the second floor.
After a while, we heard Ria scream.
When we got there, Ria's legs had given out,
and Kyoko was standing
dumbfounded behind her.
You can't blame me for that.
The corpse of a man who disappeared
had reappeared in front of me.
S-Speaking of disappearances,
the hand truck went missing then, too.
The hand truck?
Yeah.
Our 60 x 30 centimeter hand truck
we used to move equipment went missing.
Now that you mention it, I let my brother
borrow a bunch of stuff to shoot his movie,
but that's the only thing
that didn't come back.
Someone suggested
that maybe the culprit used the hand truck
to move the president's body into the room.
B-But the hand truck had been missing
since before the president disappeared.
Eight years ago, a man suddenly disappeared.
Then his corpse appeared in the same room.
This time a body disappeared,
and someone else was murdered
by the man we thought was dead.
There must be...
...something going on with this room.
Episode Preview
Now that I, demon hunter Yamamura, am here,
everything will be okay.
What are you doing?
The body's on the second floor.
Conan-kun, did you figure
out who did it, too?
N-No.
I was just helping Heiji-niichan.
But isn't the culprit Harawaki-kun?
Yeah!
The moment he attacked
Kyoko was captured on film!
The proof is right there.
A Cottage Surrounded By Zombies
(Part Three)
The next episode of Conan is "A Cottage
Surrounded By Zombies, Part Three!"
Toilet Paper
Next Conan's hint!
Toilet paper!
Don't miss the next episode.
The Gunma Prefectural Police
will be arriving next episode.
That's Inspector Yamamura.
Uh, oh.
We'd better solve this soon.