We came to the filming
location of a zombie movie,
where we met the crew shooting the sequel.
But during filming,
the producer Harawaki Takashi-san died.
On top of that,
during a commotion caused by
an audition for zombie extras,
cameraman Ejiri Kyoko-san died as well.
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
Inspector Yamamura tries to stir things up.
But the Heiji and Conan duo
solve the surprising mystery.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
A Cottage Surrounded By Zombies
(Part Three)
"A Cottage Surrounded
By Zombies, Part Three!"
E-E-Excuse me...
Th-The zombies brought some officers
from the Gunma police force...
Ran-chan?
Th-The Gunma police?
Which means...
Could it be?
Those of you troubled by
zombies, thank you for waiting.
Now that I, demon hunter
Yamamura, am here,
everything will be...
...okay?
Th-There are z-z-zombies everywhere?!
Begone, evil spirits!
Hey.
Huh?
What are you doing?
The body's on the second floor.
Y-You boys?
I see, I see.
You're saying this is what happened?
After finishing filming the movie trailer,
the two of you went upstairs
to get Harawaki-san for lunch.
But he was collapsed in the
room next door to this one,
and on the phone he was holding was
a video of him taking the poison,
and something that seemed
to be a suicide note.
Later, you were surprised by the
zombies Harawaki-san invited.
You directed the crew to flee upstairs,
and while you were fighting
zombies downstairs,
for some reason Ejiri Kyoko-san
was killed by having her neck cut.
Yeah, that's right.
Furthermore, there's a video
of her neck being cut,
and the culprit is Harawaki-san who
is supposed to have committed suicide.
Since Harawaki-san suddenly
disappeared from the room
where he committed suicide,
h-he...
He must have turned into a
zombie and killed Kyoko-san!
How scary! So scary!
I knew he'd say that.
In some ways, this is
exactly what I expected.
If that's the case, where
did Harawaki-san go?
He must've blended into the
zombie horde and escaped.
That's why he invited so many zombies.
Wow.
It actually makes sense.
Otherwise he'd never have
been able to take this video!
Wasn't it recording until you stopped it?
Yeah.
Even if he tried to trick
the victim into filming it,
she never would've agreed to being
bitten and killed by a zombie!
Besides, isn't Kyoko-san a
cameraman and not an actor?
Apparently she was an actor
in the zombie movie they shot
during college eight years ago.
But they probably would've
checked any footage they shot.
They'd know if they saw it, right?
Wh-What?
No one's seen the footage
you took eight years ago?
Is that true?
Yeah.
Kawabata Ria (29)
Actress
The president said he'd show us the
footage he edited together later.
That's why Kyoko the
cameraman complained
that he wouldn't let her check the video
Baisho Orie (29)
Lighting Crew
for any parts she wanted to reshoot.
Naito Tetsuto (38)
Film Director
My brother was probably
excited to see your reactions,
since you'd be his first audience.
So?
What roles did Harawaki-san
and Kyoko-san play?
Um, I think it was...
Harawaki-kun becomes a zombie
and tries to attack Kyoko.
But because they're exes,
he doesn't attack her.
Didn't the president throw that out since
he said a zombie movie
doesn't need romance?
Now that you mention it,
Harawaki-kun said he wanted to fight
back instead of just becoming a zombie.
That's the first time I've heard that.
So no one really remembers what happened.
Hey,
is the footage from that
movie really missing?
Yeah.
That's what Kyoko said.
B-But Harawaki-kun told me
he had it on his tablet.
Ninomiya Masahachi (29)
Sound Crew
Did he carry that around with him?
Yeah, he has a mini tablet.
He always kept it in his jacket pocket.
Let's see.
This is it.
Crap.
The data's been erased.
Oh, but I have the pictures we
took while filming the movie.
See?
Hey, this T-shirt Kyoko-san is wearing...
This is the T-shirt
with the letter E on it
that Kyoko wore back then.
She had a bunch of them in different
colors since her name was Ejiri.
Speaking of clothes, Kyoko-san took
off her top before being killed.
Do you know why?
It was a little damp, right?
Who knows?
Maybe she decided to change
since it got sweaty.
Now that you mention it, during
our bathroom break while filming,
she said she couldn't wait to change
out of her clothes and take a bath.
That was about an hour before we
went looking for Harawaki-san.
Oh, right.
I went to the bathroom
during that break, too,
but something weird happened.
Weird how?
Ran-chan went earlier and
told me to be careful
since there was only one spare
roll of toilet paper left,
but I didn't see a single one.
But when I just went to the
bathroom, the spare roll was back.
Th-That's kind of creepy.
Well, I more or less know...
...how that was used.
What?
You know, too, Conan-kun?
Oh, no.
I was just copying Heiji-niichan.
There doesn't seem to be
a secret door in the room.
And all you can do with
a roll of toilet paper
is turn a zombie into a mummy.
Hey, wait!
Huh?
The prayer beads that fell
into the upper drawer
came out of the bottom drawer.
Why?
I see.
So this is what it means...
...to miss something right under your nose.
By the way, I hadn't asked yet.
Did you two ride a motorcycle
here all the way from Osaka?
No,
we took the bullet train to
Tokyo and rented a bike there.
We heard the cottage was
deep in the mountains, so...
So you forced him to bring you with him?
Heiji's the one who invited me.
He said there was something
important he wanted to discuss.
Something important?
What?
You know who did it, so you're
going to solve the mystery?
Yeah, me and this kid.
Conan-kun, did you figure
out who did it, too?
N-No.
I'm just helping Heiji-niichan.
Right.
Well, I guess the Sleeping
Kogoro's not up to it.
After all, those poisonous mushrooms
have already put him to sleep.
I'm so funny!
What's his deal?
But didn't Harawaki-kun do it?
Yeah.
There's even a video of him attacking Kyoko.
A-And one of Harawaki-kun
committing suicide by poison.
How do you explain the videos?
That's all video you shot eight years ago
at this cottage for the movie.
What?
The culprit played the video
on Harawaki-san's mini tablet
and set the phone to record it.
Then they knocked the phone down,
so the lens would face the
floor or the seat of the chair
at the blackout and keep recording.
But did we shoot a scene of
Harawaki-kun drinking poison?
I'm not sure.
Harawaki-san said he didn't
want to just become a zombie.
He wanted to resist his fate.
So he probably secretly filmed
the scene with the president.
One of him committing suicide by poison.
And didn't the first script have the
protagonist cutting down her friends
who became zombies one after
another with a magical sword?
Y-Yeah.
Then they must've shot a scene of
Harawaki-san biting Kyoko-san
and turning her into a zombie.
The culprit used that to their advantage.
But even if you say this is an old video...
The backgrounds are the same
since they were shot here.
The proof is in the video.
What?
Harawaki-san had a beard before he died,
but there's none in the video.
His pants are a slightly
different color, too.
And Kyoko-san was wearing lipstick,
but she's not in the video.
She was wearing the hair she tied
back like she did in college, too.
Speaking of college,
Kyoko-san is wearing the
same T-shirt in the video
as the one from the picture
you showed us earlier.
Here it is.
It's hard to see because
her hand is in the way,
but if you enlarge it,
you can see the letter E.
Y-You're right.
Kyoko-san's body was wearing
a plain white T-shirt.
It's proof that they were
killed by the same person.
B-But what about Harawaki-kun's suicide note?
The "Dinner Party of the Dead"
in Harawaki-kun's suicide note
was the movie subtitle he thought
of that was in the sealed envelope.
You're the one who said only
he could've written it.
We didn't realize then
that the culprit had used this
to see inside the envelope.
T-Toilet paper?
How?
It's easy.
You just set it on top of the
envelope and look through the hole.
Want to see?
O-Okay...
You're right.
I can just barely see through the envelope.
But why?
Because of the reflected light.
You can't see through the white envelope
because of the reflected light.
So when you block out just enough,
you can see through the paper.
So when the toilet paper went
missing during the break...
Yeah.
The culprit used the break to poison
Harawaki-san, look inside the envelope,
and write the suicide note on his phone.
B-But then where is Harawaki-kun's body?
It's right here in this room.
What?
Inside the wardrobe.
Wh-What are you talking about?
There's only a jacket inside,
and the drawers are empty.
Then watch closely.
First...
If you pull out both drawers
and take out the board between them,
it should be inside.
Harawaki-san's body on a hand truck.
No way.
It's like a magic trick.
The trick is in the board and
top drawer of the wardrobe.
Take a look.
There's a space carved out
that would fit a human body.
Using this,
you could hide a person inside the wardrobe.
S-So that's why the prayer
beads in the top drawer
came out of the bottom drawer?
Yeah.
They fell through the hole
into the bottom drawer.
It's what you call—
Missing what's right under your nose!
They say it's hardest to notice the
things that are closest to you.
Right, Heiji-niichan?
Y-Yeah...
He said what I was going to say.
He's always stealing my thunder.
You didn't notice that the first
time you opened the drawer?
I thought it was a little heavy,
but the body is on a hand truck.
And the middle board was distributing
his weight evenly, so I didn't notice.
But even if it was on the hand truck,
shouldn't the body have come
out when you opened the drawer?
Take a look.
There's no board at the
back of either drawer.
You can keep what's inside in place
by setting the middle board in place.
Even if you opened the drawers,
this board would keep the
body from coming out.
But we didn't have time to put
that kind of trick together.
No, no.
This wasn't made by the culprit.
Your brother set this up eight years ago.
What?
Joji did?
S-So when the president
vanished from the room...
Yeah.
He was hiding inside the
wardrobe using this setup.
I'm certain that Joji-san
hid inside the wardrobe.
The fact that Joji-san's body was
grasping its knees when it was found
proves that he became stuck inside
the wardrobe and starved to death.
So my brother died because he couldn't
get out of the wardrobe on his own?
No.
He should've been able to get out by himself
by pushing out the drawers
and removing the board.
Th-Then why?
Because he couldn't push the drawer open.
W-Wait a minute.
Are you saying that
because we moved the wardrobe
to look for the president eight years ago,
he couldn't push out the drawer and...
And if Harawaki-kun and
Kyoko-san were killed, then...
Does that mean it was
the president's brother?
Wait, I...
Well, that's part of the reason he died.
But that's not the problem.
After being trapped inside the
wardrobe and starving to death,
why was Joji-san sitting on the floor
when you came to look
for him four days later?
Wh-Why?
There was someone who knew Joji-san
was hiding inside the wardrobe.
What?
Right?
Actress Kawabata Ria-san.
You're the one who killed
Harawaki-san and Kyoko-san, too.
First you went to Harawaki-san's room
during the bathroom break and got
him to drink the poisoned water.
Then you wrote a suicide note,
including the subtitle you read
using the toilet paper on his phone,
played the eight year old video
on Harawaki-san's tablet,
and recorded it with his cell phone
You placed the phone in the
hand of Harawaki-san's body
with the image blacked out,
and returned to filming.
If you'd stopped there,
Harawaki-san's death might have
been treated as a suicide,
but Kyoko-san realized
the trick you had used.
If we knew where the video went,
it might actually solve the mystery
behind Harawaki-kun's suicide.
You had no choice.
So when you fled to the second
floor during the zombie scare,
you spilled water or something
on Kyoko-san's top
to force her to change into a white T-shirt.
Then you cut her throat with a
box cutter near the wall
to resemble the video taken eight years ago.
Then you recorded the eight year
old video on Kyoko-san's phone,
and hid Harawaki-san's body in the wardrobe
so we'd think he became a zombie and
killed Kyoko-san using the same trick
Joji-san told you about eight years ago.
Somewhere on your clothes,
I'm sure we'd find the blood that got
on you when you killed Kyoko-san.
B-But anyone could've used that trick.
Remember what Ria-san said?
When I tried to search the wardrobe,
she told me to look under the bed.
Isn't that because you were
worried about my height?
I might have found the body
hidden inside the wardrobe.
And there was something Orie-san said, too.
Eight years ago when Ria-san
and Kyoko-san went upstairs
to look for Joji-san, they heard
Ria-san scream after a while.
When they ran into the room,
Kyoko-san was standing behind
Ria-san, whose legs had given out.
That's how Heiji-niichan knew.
Since this room is at the top of the stairs,
one of you would have searched it first.
It was strange that it took so
long for you to hear a scream.
If Kyoko-san was standing behind Ria-san,
then Ria-san was probably the
one who removed the body
from the wardrobe and
pretended to be surprised.
Well, I was genuinely surprised.
I thought the president would have gotten out
of the wardrobe and be
snoring away on the bed,
but he was still inside.
I quickly got him out of the wardrobe
and screamed after setting him on the floor
as though I'd just found him.
B-But wasn't it an accident?
Y-Yeah.
You were sick with a cold.
But Harawaki-kun didn't see it that way.
When we came to check out
the cottage for the shoot,
he found the messages the
president had written in blood
inside the wardrobe that
I had forgotten to erase.
It's true.
It's full of messages like "curse you."
I'm shocked, too.
I poisoned Harawaki-kun
because he threatened
to out me as a murderer unless
I appeared in his movie.
I even killed Kyoko when she nearly
figured out the trick I used.
I'm supposed to be a warrior
who defeats zombies.
But I'm the one whose heart rotted away
and became a zombie.
Is that the sound of
Hattori-kun's motorcycle?
Yeah.
A road service technician just
arrived to put gas in their tank.
I'm going to see them off, then.
Don't!
What?
Heiji-niichan said they had
something important to discuss.
Really?
Something important, huh?
Heiji, what is it?
Isn't there something important
you wanted to talk about?
Kazuha, I've been thinking
this for a while now.
But the truth is...
Huh?
Isn't the audition today?
That was yesterday, idiot.
It's already over.
Guys, the audition's already over.
What?
Seriously?
So, what were you going to say?
You should hold your skirt down
so people can't see your panties.
What? Wait...
H-Heiji?
This isn't the place.
Well, I repaid the favor.
Episode Preview
If you're going to shoot someone, shoot me.
Don't die!
Mister!
The Great Detective's Weakness
The next episode of Conan is "The
Great Detective's Weakness!"
Emergency Staircase
Next Conan's hint!
An emergency staircase!
Don't miss the next episode.
Dad, you've got too many weaknesses.
Heiji, am I your weakness?
Absolutely not.