Wait!
Stop!
S-Stay away!
You're not getting away!
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
Kogoro-no-occhan has many weaknesses,
but he must overcome them!
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Great Detective's Weakness
"The Great Detective's Weakness!"
Metropolitan Police Department
What?
The gun disappeared?
Wh-What do you mean, Inspector?
When we arrested the suspect,
he didn't have a gun, much less a knife.
B-But...
Yes. We're certain he robbed
a bank and fired a gun.
It's also a fact that when
you determined his location,
he fired at you and ran,
which means...
He must've either hid it or
thrown it away somewhere.
It's strange.
They didn't find a gun when
they searched the area
where he was arrested, either, right?
C-Conan-kun!
Ran-san.
I was worried about you, Dad.
This is just a scratch.
Ow, ow!
Jeez...
Ow...
Mori Detective Agency
Because he had that experience when
he already had a fear of heights,
he's in a mild state of shock.
Well, the doctor said he'll be back to normal
if he stays in and rests for a while.
Damn it...
It's already been two days since then.
I'm the great detective Mori Kogoro.
This is pathetic.
Huh?
What?
Dad, didn't the doctor
say you shouldn't drink?
Shut up.
I know.
In Front of Toto Detention Facility
Sakaki Taizo (43)
Forward Trading Group
Representative
Bail was expensive.
If you're innocent, the
courthouse is the real scam.
Just kidding.
Defendant Sakaki Taizo has
just been released on bail.
He will later stand trial
for fraud charges that...
What?
That's...
H-He's been shot!
Sakaki has been shot!
What?
No way!
Damn it.
That gun was...
Hello?
Oh, Mori-kun.
Sorry, but I need to head to the crime scene.
What?
The suspect used that gun?
Beika Northern Hospital
Forensic Investigation Laboratory
It's a match!
That's right.
It's definitely the same gun.
Yes.
Sakaki-sama
It's a serious wound that will
take a full month to heal.
But since it was only a .22 caliber gun,
he'll survive.
Are you sure you're okay, Mister?
Ran-neechan was worried about you.
As long as I don't go
anywhere high, I'm fine.
And this is my case.
I'll get that gun back with my own two hands.
That's fine, but...
S-Stay away!
Did the robber holding the gun
and the man who was shot have
anything to do with each other?
What? Of course not.
The gun ended up in the current
suspect's hands by total coincidence.
It probably happened then.
Was there anyone there?
Did you see anyone suspicious
while you were chasing the robber?
I came back to the crime
scene so I could remember...
Now that you mention it...
Wait!
Excuse me!
You're not getting away!
Could she have taken the gun?
Do you remember her face?
What about her clothes or possessions?
I think she had a tote bag
and a convenience store bag!
Mister, look.
You know her?
Really?
She's probably one of our regulars.
What's her name?
I don't know that much.
But she always comes out
of that apartment building.
Mister, look.
This license plate.
It's the suspect's motorcycle.
Does that mean they're in room 403?
All right! I found you.
Shouldn't you call Inspector Megure?
I know.
And what are you doing here, anyway?
It's too dangerous. You should go home.
Inspector, this is Mori.
I'm here because I'm worried about you!
And you only just now noticed?
Hey, I told you to go home
since it's too dangerous.
Forget about that.
Hurry up.
Where's room 403?
Y-You!
Wait!
Mister!
This smell...
Th-This is...
Th-The suspect's...
Damn it!
We've identified the suspect.
Onda Izumi, twenty-five years old.
She's a clerk at a nearby printing company.
Unbelievably, she was once a candidate
for the Olympic shooting team.
Onda Izumi (25)
Office Clerk
Her motive was her father
whose factory went bankrupt
Onda Machines
after he invested a large sum of
money in the Sakaki Group's futures.
He killed himself six months ago.
Her mother later fell ill and
joined her father in death.
Also...
Sakaki Group
Sakaki Taizo
Shibasaki Kohei
Kadota Rina
Wh-What?!
She has other targets?!
Sakaki Group
A-Are we there?
Yeah.
Are you okay, mister?
Executive Room
Let go of me!
Let go!
I said let go!
You must be Shibasaki-san and Kadota-san.
Shibasaki Kohei (35)
Trader
You're Sakaki's right-hand men,
Kadota Rina (32)
Analyst
and will soon be arrested
on fraud charges as well.
Wh-Who are you?
Where do you think you are?
Sorry for showing up unannounced.
Did anyone ask you about
your schedules today?
Our secretary just came to ask about that.
Someone from the media probably called.
Was it a man or a woman?
I believe they said it was
a young woman's voice.
You want to be our bodyguard since
someone's trying to kill us?
Can't you tell?
That won't be necessary.
Ow!
Mori-san, Conan-kun.
Are you okay?
Ouch...
Hey, wait! You...
Are you okay, mister?
Damn it...
Takagi, Chiba!
Where's the suspect?
O-Our APBs haven't found her yet.
More importantly, you should rest, Mori-san.
We'll secure the area.
If the suspect shows up,
we won't let her escape.
What's this?
Something just now didn't make sense...
But what is it?
It's been two hours, huh?
What is the suspect doing?
She should just come already.
Why didn't she come after these two first?
What?
The suspect acquired the gun
two days before Sakaki posted bail.
The police didn't know she was
also trying to kill these two then.
She wanted to pick off
the major target first.
Wait a minute.
He hadn't been released on bail yet.
That is odd.
In the first place, she hasn't
even finished him off yet.
Her warning shot was accurate,
but she missed her target.
She was riding a motorcycle then.
Not even an Olympic candidate
could've seen that coming.
It was a serious but non-fatal injury.
Would she really let the unexpected
remain the unexpected?
That's it.
In other words, the suspect asked
about their schedules to mislead us.
Yeah, I think you're right.
While we're distracted, she's going
to finish off her primary target.
The still living Sakaki.
Emergency Drill Today
Sakaki-sama
Wh-Where is Sakaki-san?
We should buy now.
We'll definitely sell soon.
You...
I see.
So it was you.
As long as you're around, nothing will start,
and nothing will end.
It's not coming back down.
Mister!
What?
Stairs
Seriously?
What floor are we on?
Mister, are you okay?
Of course.
This is nothing.
I'm going on ahead, then.
Wait, kid!
It's too dangerous!
We should go together!
Damn it.
Don't look.
I won't look.
Mister, we can't get out this way!
What?
You should've said so sooner.
Emergency Exit
That's...
You idiot.
I'd never go anywhere alone.
This is self-defense!
Go to hell!
Don't underestimate me.
Just because it's high...
Even if I'm scared...
I'm the great detective...
Mori Kogoro!
Mister!
You did it, old man.
Don't shoot!
Don't shoot.
Move!
If you don't, you'll...
Give up, Izumi-san.
D-Don't be stupid! Stop!
If I can't even avenge them,
I should kill my spineless self.
I finally understand why you
didn't try to kill those two.
You had doubts.
U-Uh-oh.
Hello, Inspector.
I need a favor.
Please hurry.
Once this guy had been arrested,
you had given up on your revenge, hadn't you?
Call it a detective's hunch, but Izumi-san,
you were in the middle of shopping then.
You had overcome your rage and sadness,
and were returning to your normal life.
Am I wrong?
But at the bottom of your
heart, you still had doubts.
That's why you picked up the gun
the robber happened to drop.
But you still had doubts.
You didn't try to attack the other two.
But two days later, when you learned
Sakaki was to be released on bail,
your desire for revenge was reignited.
But why would you try to kill yourself?
Spineless? You're wrong.
Izumi-san, are you sure you didn't have some
kind of personal relationship with this man?
I need you to search the premises again.
I found it.
Huh?
Takagi?
Th-This is...
You really are a great detective.
You're right.
They trusted him because he
was dating their daughter.
But my father...
My mother...
The only thing I can't do is forgive myself!
But without a gun...
If I'd secured it then...
It may have been a coincidence,
but I'm responsible for
letting you pick it up.
So if you're going to
shoot someone, shoot me.
Don't die!
Old man!
Thank you.
But it's too late.
Stop!
Mister!
Emergency Drill Today
They made it in time.
Later, Kisaki-sensei agreed
to represent Izumi-san.
New evidence of the fraud
group's crimes was found,
Two Employees Arrested Simultaneously
and the investigation was reopened.
Sakaki Arrested Again
Mori Detective Agency
All right!
I'm all better!
Ouch...
I'm not better yet.
You've just had too much to drink.
Oh, Dad.
Episode Preview
It's room 901, right?
Yeah, on the top floor.
Hey, you snuck into the car, didn't you?
Die!
I-I did it...
It's Takarada-san.
Yeah, it serves him right.
The Man Who Died Twice
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Man Who Died Twice, Part One!"
Announcement Letter
Next Conan's hint!
An announcement letter!
Next time I'll really shine!
Don't miss the next episode.
Why?
Because Double-Oh-Kogoro only lives twice.
I don't get it.