It's room 901, right?
Yeah, on the top floor.
Hey, you snuck into the car, didn't you?
Sorry.
It's fine, son.
All children should have such energy.
Be careful, okay?
Okay!
Wait, you brat!
Looks like it's down that way.
You always do this.
This isn't a game, you know.
Die!
I-I did it...
Wh-Who are you?!
That's Takarada-san.
Yeah, it serves him right.
Mister, we should call an ambulance.
We're too late.
It's been two hours
since he was strangled to death.
Strangled?
What?
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
The mysterious case of a man murdered twice.
Somebody must be lying somewhere.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Man Who Died Twice
(Part One)
“The Man Who Died Twice, Part One!”
Takarada Yoichi?
Takarada Yoichi (48)
Moneylender
That notoriously unscrupulous moneylender?
According to his secretary
Shinkai Haruyuki-san,
Takarada was renting this room
so he could write a novel.
Shinkai Haruyuki (27)
Takarada's Secretary
Now that you mention it, I heard he
self-published books in his spare time.
Doers are Winners
Swallow It Whole
Prey
And Takarada-san had come to
this room today to write, right?
Prey
Yes.
He'd been in here since
this morning by himself.
I didn't know he was such an evil man.
You'd been hired to come work for him, right?
Even though we'd never met before,
he suddenly called before noon.
He had received a murder threat in the mail.
He wanted me to come at three to discuss it.
But when I came for our appointment...
The threat had already been carried out.
This seems to be that letter.
It was on the table.
I will kill the monstrous
Takarada Yoichi.
Grudge.
Hatred.
Murder!!
He's preyed on countless people.
One of his victims must have sought revenge.
When the letter arrived at the mansion
this morning, that's what I thought, too.
I'd like to see them try.
I didn't want to allow
his victim to become a killer.
So...
while the president was napping...
Die!
But I was too late.
We'll be asking you about the
damage you did to the body later.
Right now, the murder is
the more pressing matter.
Do you have any idea who did it?
He had too many victims who hated him.
But is one of them really the murderer?
What do you mean?
Well...
Inspector Megure.
Did you figure something out?
Yes.
After knocking the victim unconscious
by striking him on the back of
the head with a blunt object,
they strangled him with some
kind of rope-like object.
We believe he died roughly two
hours before the body was found.
That would be around 1 PM.
Inspector.
This is the building administrator.
He says he saw a suspicious
woman right around that time.
What?
Tomii Kinsaku (58)
Building Administrator
After lunch, I came to this
floor while doing my rounds.
Just then,
a blonde I didn't recognize came
walking away from this room.
That was around one.
Inspector.
Do you recognize this woman?
Her sunglasses are covering her face.
But that's not necessarily a woman.
They could've be trying to look like one.
Since there's only footage of her leaving,
she must've snuck in
through the rear entrance
and exited through the front
because she'd been seen.
Did the president not lock his door?
Now that you mention it, he had
a habit of using the chain lock.
If he was so worried about the
letter that he called a detective,
he wouldn't have let any strange
people into his room, right?
We haven't forgotten that
it could be someone he knew.
Got it.
His family have finished
identifying the body.
His wife and younger brother, right?
Let's go meet them.
Takarada Mika (36)
Takarada's Wife
How am I going to go on living by myself?
Damn it.
Takarada Koji (42)
Takarada's Younger Brother
Who on earth would kill my dear brother?
Ma'am, where were you around
1 PM this afternoon?
You think I did it?
No, this is just a formality.
Of course they suspect you.
You'll be inheriting his fortune
and the insurance money.
You're the one who resented Takarada!
Where were you around 1 PM?
I was at home organizing the
storehouse like Takarada asked.
I see.
What about you, Koji-san?
I was wandering around Shinjuku.
Can anyone verify that?
That's a no, then.
Excuse me...
The wife is telling the truth.
What?
I was in the study until I left the mansion,
just after 2 PM.
Around 1 PM, she was in the storehouse.
Shinkai...
Thank you. I'm so glad to have you around.
Not at all.
I see.
So that leaves...
Hey, wait.
Don't you think it's weird
to assume family did it?
Excuse me, but could we continue
this discussion at home?
Very well.
Let's head there.
I'll join you!
Sure.
Takagi-kun, could you
investigate the other case?
Got it.
If only he'd noticed the president was dead.
He wouldn't have committed his crime.
MPD Beika Station
Atoning?
Yes.
Naturally, I was aware of President
Takarada's unscrupulous practices.
But I assumed
his victims were fools for allowing
themselves to be preyed upon.
But the other day,
one of them took their entire family with them
and committed suicide!
Their child wasn't even one year old yet.
For the first time,
I blamed myself for helping the president.
Then this morning, the letter arrived.
I thought whoever had sent it
must've been a victim like the
one who killed their own child.
So I...
You didn't want them to commit a crime.
But why did you decide to
kill Takarada yourself?
As long as he was around,
more victims would've been born!
I had to kill him myself.
I thought it would be a way
to atone for helping him!
But I was too late.
They had already sullied their own hands.
But the killer isn't necessarily
one of Takarada's victims.
Detective, do you really think
someone in his family did it?
I can't say yet.
I hated my brother?
That's not true, Inspector.
But earlier, Mika-san...
Koji-san has made a living deceiving people.
Two years ago, after failing
in one of his attempts,
he came crying to Takarada to
bail him out of the situation,
but he refused.
He was forced to go into hiding.
So he resented him for that.
But three days ago, he asked
us to take him in for a while.
And today, Takarada was murdered.
What are you talking about?
Is this because I suspected you earlier?
I'm just telling them the truth!
You're making it sound like I
came home to kill my brother!
Detective, I just happened to come home.
One of his victims must've killed him.
In any case, there are plenty of them.
Kinoshita Kyoko (40)
Takarada Family Housekeeper
Yes.
It seems it's true that a
lot of people hated him.
Then he must've received a
lot of threatening letters.
He did, and...
And?
Huh?
What's strange?
Takarada-san received threatening
letters all the time.
His housekeeper said he was even
attacked with a knife once.
But it didn't bother him at all.
So why did he decide
to ask you about it this time?
He even laughed it off
in front of everyone else
before calling you, right?
Maybe he had a special reason for it.
That's it!
Takarada knew who was trying to kill him.
That's why he laughed it off so
they would let their guard down.
Then he was going to hire me
to investigate and expose them.
Oh, right!
What?
Which means...
The killer is not only one of his own,
but also one of the three people
who were there at the time.
But mister, of those three people...
Since Shinkai-kun stabbed the body
without realizing Takarada had
already been strangled, he's out.
And if his wife Mika-san has an alibi...
Then that leaves...
H-Hey, wait.
Yes, hello?
Yes.
Got it.
They found fingerprints on the letter.
Yours, Takarada Koji-san.
Y-You must be joking.
Kyoko-san, come here.
Yes? Did you call me?
Call my lawyer Watari-sensei
and have him come here.
Tell him we need to discuss the inheritance.
And tell Beika Health I need
to discuss the insurance claim.
Hurry.
Y-Yes, ma'am.
It's only natural.
Now that we know this man
did it, the case is settled.
Actually, we're not certain it's him yet.
I've been waiting for this moment to come.
Now that it's over,
I can finally say I only married
Takarada for his money.
Since he was such an evil man, I was
hoping he would die sooner, though.
Thank you, Koji-san.
I feel dizzy.
What's wrong with this woman?
In any case, Koji-san, you
sent Takarada-san that letter
to make the murder seem like the work
of someone who resented him,
and then killed him to get revenge
for the events of two years ago.
I didn't do it.
I didn't write that letter.
But your fingerprints are on it.
Strange, isn't it?
How can he be so composed?
I see.
Got it.
Let me know if there are any developments.
Um, Detective?
Is Koji-san the suspect now?
Yeah, though he seems to be denying it.
Detective, he didn't do it!
He has an alibi!
What?
W-W-Wait, wh-what do you mean?
When Koji-san came to the mansion,
the president told me to make sure
he didn't need to be bailed out again.
So when Koji-san secretly went out today,
I followed him.
Koji-san seemed to be waiting
for someone on the roof
of an apartment building at
a hero show for families.
I watched him the whole
time, but no one came.
I thought he had been stood up, so I left.
That was between just before 1:00 and 1:30.
But you said you were at the mansion then.
Because the police suspected his wife.
I lied in order to protect her.
What? You lied?
But now that Koji-san is being accused,
I have to tell the truth.
The housekeeper should be able to
verify the wife's story, anyway.
I'm sorry for lying!
N-No way...
Inspector, we were able to verify his story.
The rooftop must've been
crowded with families, too.
Got it.
So that secretary was following me?
So he was so composed
because he knew he was being followed.
Shinkai-san was actually able
to verify Koji-san's alibi,
and not Mika-san's.
The tables have turned.
Now I have someone to back up my alibi,
and you don't.
Not a single one.
I'm sorry.
Kinoshita-san,
you were out at the hospital all afternoon?
Yes.
I'm so sorry.
It's fine.
I don't need someone to back up my story.
Huh?
But if Koji-san didn't do it,
then why are his fingerprints on the letter?
It must've been a trick.
They used a piece of paper that
had his fingerprints on them.
So the real killer could make
it look like he'd done it.
I have no idea who you're talking about.
Killing my brother wouldn't
benefit me in any way.
But you'd finally get his fortune.
Yeah, but I wouldn't go through
the trouble of killing him for it.
The doctor told me.
The doctor?
What did he tell you?
Thank you.
It's true.
Takarada had terminal cancer
and only six months to live.
Which means...
I just needed to wait six months
before I'd get his fortune
and insurance money.
What kind of idiot would do something
stupid to risk losing it all?
This must be her last card, but...
Thank you for your help.
Hey, is that...?
So after you came back
from relieving yourself,
and this wig and these sunglasses were here?
Yeah.
It was stuffed into my things.
Maybe they thought it was
a garbage collection site,
and were trying to dispose of their disguise.
Yeah, that must be it.
Excuse me, but we'd like to borrow this.
Sure, just give them back later.
Takarada Mika-san, the
hair sample you gave us
matched the hair we took
from the wig that was found.
What?
Th-That's impossible.
I don't know anything about that wig.
There must've been some reason
you couldn't wait six months.
Maybe, but that wig had
been thrown away, right?
There are much more certain
ways of getting rid of something,
if that's what they wanted to do.
You...
You've been waiting for your chance
to kill my brother, haven't you?
And then a convenient scapegoat
like me showed up.
Man, that was scary.
You almost got away with framing me.
I was here at home when Takarada was killed!
You have to believe me, Officer!
Let's talk at the station.
Please come with us.
That settles that. Let's go home.
But, mister...
I need to use the bathroom first.
It wasn't me!
The woman who had remained married
to Takarada for his money
planned to murder her husband when Koji-san,
the perfect scapegoat, showed up.
Using a sheet of paper with
Koji-san's fingerprints on it,
she wrote and sent a threatening letter.
Then she visited the rented
room and strangled Takarada.
She fled while wearing
the disguise she prepared
in case anyone saw her and
disposed of it when she was done.
That should be the story, but
it all seems too careless.
Huh?
Is that Koji-san?
Yeah, you're the only one I
can ask about legal stuff.
If a wife murders her husband, she
can't inherit his fortune, right?
In that case, the money would...
Oh, no.
The head of the household
only has one younger brother.
Could it be?
Killing my brother wouldn't
benefit me in any way.
But if he sets up his brother's
wife and his killer,
he can keep all the money to himself.
That means...
Kyoko
Afternoon Hospital
So Koji-san knew you were
going to the hospital today?
Yes.
Not just Koji-san, but everyone knew.
I didn't want to inconvenience anyone,
so I wrote my appointment on the calendar.
So he knew
that she wouldn't have anyone
to verify her alibi today.
What?
What are you doing here?
This is your fault!
If you'd just kept up the lie
and backed up my story!
No...
What a disgusting woman.
She won't get off that easily.
If he tricked the police...
No, all of us, then...
I won't let him get what he wants.
Episode Preview
If they killed Takarada and made
it look like his wife did it...
That's what they were doing there.
Mori-san truly is a great detective.
We made a mistake from the very start.
We assumed someone in his family did it.
B-But, Mori-san...
That doesn't prove they killed him.
The Man Who Died Twice
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is “The
Man Who Died Twice, Part Two!”
Calendar
Next Conan's hint!
A calendar!
Don't miss the next episode.
The killer is a mystery, too.
What?
Two death!