The old man went to meet a client who had
received a murder threat in the mail.
When he got there,
his client Takarada Yoichi
was being stabbed by his
secretary Shinkai Haruyuki-san.
However, Takarada had actually
been strangled to death,
two hours earlier by someone else.
Shinkai-san was arrested
for mutilating a corpse.
Shinkai Haruyuki (27)
Takarada's Secretary
Takarada's younger brother, Koji-san,
fell under suspicion when his
fingerprints were found on the letter.
Takarada Koji (42)
Takarada's Younger Brother
But the suspicions disappeared
with Shinkai's testimony,
and his wife Mika-san became
the new prime suspect.
Takarada Mika (36)
Takarada's Wife
When the wig that was
evidence in the crime was found,
her guilt became all but certain.
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
Look closely at the three suspects.
One of them is telling a big fat lie.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of
an adult, his name is Detective Conan!
The Man Who Died Twice
(Part Two)
"The Man Who Died Twice, Part Two!"
Mori Detective Agency
She still hasn't admitted it?
She did seem like a nasty woman.
The inspector must be having a tough time.
If someone killed Takarada and
made it look like his wife did it,
then she would lose the right to his fortune,
and his brother Koji-san
would inherit everything.
That must've been what he was going for.
But the question is Shinkai's testimony.
Was he forced to perjure himself?
What are you mumbling about?
What?
Nothing. Just talking to myself.
Hello?
Um, I'd like to talk to
you about Shinkai Haruyuki,
who was arrested yesterday.
Oh. Come in.
My name is Teshima Hisashi.
I see.
You work at a printing plant.
So what did you want to
discuss about Shinkai-san?
Teshima Hisashi (28)
Shinkai's Childhood Friend
Shinkai and I have been friends since
we grew up in the same foster home.
So if there's anything I can do
to lighten his sentence, I want to do it.
I heard you witnessed his crime, so...
So you came to see me.
Yes.
I promise you that Shinkai isn't a bad guy.
He was abandoned by a
horrifyingly selfish mother.
I feel sorry for him.
A selfish mother?
Stay out of this, kid!
Teshima-san, I understand how you feel.
But you should be discussing
this with a lawyer.
This doesn't fall under a detective's domain.
A lawyer, huh?
Yes.
I'm sure they'll be able to help you.
I understand.
Sorry to have bothered you.
Not at all. I'm sorry I couldn't help you.
Excuse me.
Hey, Mister. I'm going out for a bit.
Hey, kid!
What's wrong with that kid?
And he left his book out.
What did you want to confirm with me?
Around one yesterday when
Takarada-san was murdered,
you were at a department
store in Shinjuku, right?
Yeah.
What do you want to know?
Apparently Shinkai-san is
saying you threatened him
into perjuring himself to back up your alibi.
That bastard!
Why'd he have to lie about that?
Is he lying?
Tell the detective who sent you here
that there's no point in suspecting me.
I've got other people to back up
my alibi besides the secretary.
What?
Yesterday I was invited out over the phone
by a man I don't recognize.
He said he had a sweet get-rich-quick scheme.
Ultimately, he stood me up,
but while I was waiting for him...
Hey, you! I found you, Koji!
Crap!
Wait, damn it!
Give me back my money, Koji!
It was some guy named Yaginuma
who I'd previously conned.
The reason I was so composed
when the police suspected me
was because I just had to call
in Yaginuma as my witness.
Knowing that he'd beat me
half to death if I did.
It seems he wasn't lying.
Isn't that what you call
fishing in troubled waters?
And I didn't send you here.
Listen up.
Takarada Yoichi was
murdered by his wife Mika.
And she had a man call Koji on the phone
to draw him out of the house
so he wouldn't have an alibi.
But, Mister...
If that's true, then don't you
think her plan was too careless?
How?
If she wanted to eliminate his alibi,
she would've sent him somewhere deserted.
Because she didn't, he has a
witness named Yaginuma-san.
And because the blonde wig was
thrown away so offhandedly,
it was found by the police.
Oh, shut up.
It just means Mika was stupid.
What?
Are you sure you want to
write her off as stupid?
It's not possible for
Mika-san to have done it.
Which means...
That's it.
That's why that had to be found.
Huh?
But that means...
They found fingerprints on the letter.
Yours, Takarada Koji-san.
Those should be Mika-san's fingerprints.
Wait a minute.
It's only natural.
Now that we know this man
did it, the case is settled.
Which means...
But if that's true, then
why did they do that?
Is that why they did it?
But that would mean it was
planned from the start.
That kid is up to something again.
Mori Detective Agency
Got it.
No, I was just curious.
Excuse me.
I knew it.
That's why...
Hey, four-eyes!
What kind of ridiculous epiphany
did you have this time?
If you pretend to be me
again, you'll pay for it!
But no matter what kind of
background that person has...
He's famous...
For happily wearing the gaudiest
clothes he can get his hands on.
So if he found a blonde wig...
Yeah, he'd definitely wear it.
He'd be overjoyed.
So that's what it was doing there.
Mori-san truly is a great detective.
He's right. I did receive a
phone call from a tenant.
Tomii Kinsaku (58)
Building Administrator
They didn't leave their name, though.
They said a suspicious
figure headed upstairs.
When I went to check it out,
I ran into the blonde woman.
So it wasn't a coincidence after all.
All that leaves it the conclusive evidence.
Come to think of it, when we got here...
What's going on, Inspector?
I could ask you the same thing.
You're the one who asked me
to bring these three here.
What?
But, Inspector, you said you figured
out the truth behind the case.
Now then, everyone.
It's time to discuss the
events of this case in full.
We made a mistake from the very start.
By assuming someone in his family did it,
we immediately eliminated the true culprit.
Eliminated the true culprit?
Yes.
The person who murdered Takarada Yoichi
is Shinkai Haruyuki-san.
Shinkai-san did it?
Mori-san...
If he strangled Takarada to death,
then what need was there for him
to stab him two hours later?
And in the first place...
I have an alibi for the time
when the president was murdered.
Shinkai-san did testify that
he planned to murder Takarada
since more victims would be created
as long as he lived, but...
That's not why he murdered Takarada.
Shinkai-san, as Takarada's secretary,
you knew Mika-san remained
married to him just for his money.
Where on earth is this coming from?
Takarada probably told you himself
that he had only six months to live.
In other words, in six months
Mika-san would inherit the fortune
and insurance money she longed for.
But you couldn't allow that.
That's when you came up with the idea
of murdering Takarada and
framing Mika-san as the killer.
Then Mika-san would lose the
right to Takarada's fortune
and the insurance money.
In other words, you didn't murder
Takarada-san to kill him.
You did it to frame Mika-san as his murderer.
Wh-What?
You're not making any sense.
You seem determined to paint
me as the true culprit,
but you're contradicting yourself.
If I wanted to frame his wife,
I should've put her fingerprints
on the threatening letter.
But it's mine that are on it.
He's right.
It is contradictory.
When Koji, the perfect
pawn, came to the mansion,
you put your plan into action.
Why aren't you responding
to my counterargument?
You created a threatening letter
with Koji's fingerprints on it and mailed it.
I already told you, that's contradictory!
And the letter arrived yesterday.
I'd like to see them try.
Later, you urged Takarada
to come to this room alone.
And you told Mika-san that
the president asked her
to organize the storehouse.
Ma'am, you were asked by Takarada
to organize the storehouse, correct?
Yes, but not directly.
I conveyed a message from the president.
You planned this so she would
have no one to back up her alibi.
But the housekeeper was at the mansion.
You knew she would be out.
Kyoko
Afternoon - Hospital
Yes.
Not just Koji-san, but everyone knew.
I didn't want to inconvenience anyone,
so I wrote my appointment on the calendar.
I may have heard about it, but I forgot.
Then you called me pretending to be Takarada.
Since I'd never met him before,
I wouldn't recognize his voice.
There's no proof that I called you.
You also pretended to be
an imaginary person
and invited Koji out of the house.
That was you?
There's no proof that was me, either.
At one, you came to this apartment.
I followed Koji-san to Shinjuku.
The place was crowded with families
there to see the hero show.
If you followed him there,
then perhaps you can tell us about
the commotion that occurred.
There's no way you didn't see it
if you were there.
Hey, you! I found you, Koji!
Crap!
Wait, damn it!
You could've learned about the
hero show before that day.
You could also naturally assume the
place would be crowded with families,
even if you weren't there.
You're accusing me because
you have proof, right?
Yesterday at one,
you avoided the security cameras,
and entered this building
through the rear entrance.
You gained access to his room by
pretending you had urgent business.
Then you strangled Takarada.
You left the letter you
had brought in the room,
disguised yourself as a blonde woman,
called the building administrator
under the guise of a tenant,
let him witness you,
planted one of Mika-san's hairs on the wig,
and stuffed it into the belongings of a man
famous for dressing up so it
would be found by investigators.
Then you returned to this room,
and waited for me to arrive at three.
Looks like it's down that way.
You always do this.
This isn't a game, you know.
And at just the right moment...
Die!
You called me so I would
witness that decisive moment,
since I have the absolute
trust of the police.
No one would attempt to kill a man
he's already murdered.
You hid behind that preconception.
I thought the president was alive.
He seemed to be napping when I arrived,
so I took that opportunity to stab him.
After being arrested for mutilating a body,
you fabricated plausible sounding lies
while you waited for your
schemes to come into effect.
So that was all made up?
And just as you had planned,
Koji fell under suspicion due to
his fingerprints on the letter.
I told you, that doesn't make sense!
That's precisely what made me suspect you.
Thinking the case had been solved
with Koji as the murderer,
Mika-san became ecstatic.
I've been waiting for this moment to come.
Thank you, Koji-san.
She no longer had to wait six months.
But before she knew it,
the situation changed.
The tables have turned.
Now I have someone to back up my alibi,
and you don't.
Mika-san had no one to back up her alibi,
and when material evidence was discovered...
Th-That's impossible.
I don't know anything about that wig.
I was here at home when Takarada was killed!
You have to believe me, Officer!
In other words,
the killer deliberately wrote a letter
with Koji's fingerprints on it,
so Mika-san would taste a moment of ecstasy
before suddenly being thrown into despair.
No!
It was a reversal filled
with hatred for Mika-san.
And of course, it began when you
reversed your alibi testimony.
That's when I began suspecting
you were the killer,
Shinkai-san!
This is all too forced.
Show me the evidence, Mori-san!
Everything you've said is
nothing more than hypothesis!
Since you're so careful,
there's likely no physical evidence.
Hey, Mori-kun.
So you admit it's all fantasy.
But you were too careful.
What do you mean?
The tenant living across from
this room saw you yesterday.
What?
It happened around 2:30.
Because it was more than an hour before
the time reported in the paper,
they thought it was unrelated to the case.
In other words, even though you were
supposed to have come here at 2:30,
you stabbed Takarada at three.
Which doesn't support your
story of stabbing Takarada,
because he appeared to be napping
when you arrived.
B-But Mori-san...
That doesn't prove he killed him.
You're right.
No, it's over.
It was supposed to be perfect.
But exposing even a single
flaw means I've lost.
Of course I was careful, Mori-san.
Even though we agreed to meet at three,
you could've arrived earlier.
So I quickly returned here and watched
from the window so I would
be ready whenever you came.
If I timed it wrong,
I wouldn't have been able to
hide behind your preconceptions.
Which means, Shinkai-san...
Yes.
Everything Mori-san said is true.
Everything.
Why?
Why were you willing to
kill Takarada to frame me?!
It shouldn't matter to you whether or not
I get his fortune or insurance money!
Yeah.
Why, Shinkai?!
Because he saw his own mother in you.
I heard from Teshima-san.
So the selfish mother he mentioned...
I loved my father.
He had a weak constitution,
but he was intelligent and kind.
But my mother shunned my father.
She refused to divorce him, though.
Eventually my father died.
The second she got the insurance money,
she disappeared with another man as
though she'd been waiting for him to die!
And abandoned her ten year old son!
But I never...
I know!
I know, but watching you...
Apparently, the killer mutilated
the body to camouflage the murder.
I solved another case
without knowing it again.
You must be a god.
A god?
I see.
So I'm a god!
Yeah, it's a miracle you haven't noticed yet.
Episode Preview
The three of us should start a band!
Who's going to sing the vocals?
What?
Sorry I'm tone deaf.
Hagie! Hagie!
Have we met before?
No.
I believe today's the first time we've met.
The Unfriendly Girls Band
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Unfriendly Girls Band Part One!"
Security Camera
Next Conan's hint!
A security camera!
Ran-neechan and her friends
are starting a band.
Don't miss the next episode.
A joke band?
No, a high school girl band.