Poirot
A band!
We should start a high school girl band!
What?
Where did that come from?
The high school girl band I saw in
a movie last night was super cute!
Really?
And?
Sonoko-neechan, what instrument
are you going to play?
The drums, of course.
The drummer in the band looked like me.
She was so cool.
I see.
Then I would play...
Ran, since you have long black hair,
you'll play the bass.
What?
The band's bassist had the same kind of hair.
B-But I've never played the bass before.
Ran-neechan, you're better at piano, right?
Want me to play the bass?
My brother's friend taught
me a long time ago.
Then Sera-chan will play the bass.
Ran, can you play keyboard?
Sure...
But where are we going to perform?
Tada!
Beika City Countdown Talent Show
Looking For Performers
We'll perform at the end of
year talent show in Beika City,
and walk off with the title!
But won't our band need a guitarist?
Yeah, but there doesn't seem to be anyone
in our class who can play the guitar.
Azusa-san.
Could you wipe down this table?
Sure.
Our guitarist!
What?
The high school girl band
had a girl named Azusa
who was good at guitar!
B-But I've never even touched a guitar.
And I'm not a high school girl.
No one will be able to tell
if you put on a uniform.
Besides, you have a pretty loli face.
L-Loli face?
That movie sure had a
negative influence on her.
B-But isn't playing the guitar hard?
You'll be fine.
With a little practice, you'll
be able to play in no time.
Strum, strum.
You play it, then.
What?
You can borrow my guitar.
Oh, but...
We'll hook it up to our portable amp.
You can play right away.
Here.
A-Actually...
I thought that with a little practice,
you could play in no time.
So why don't you show us
that right here, miss?
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
What will Sonoko-neechan do?
But expectations are high for the
high school girl trio's band.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Unfriendly Girls Band
(Part One)
"The Unfriendly Girls Band, Part One!"
Um, in the movie I think they
did this with their fingers...
What's this? You can't even play.
You've got some nerve to say those things
when you can't even play, little girl.
Sonoko...
Let me see that.
Wow.
He's so good.
With some practice, even these
girls can learn to play that.
Right?
Y-Yeah.
You're right.
Sonoko-san, you should watch your big mouth.
Okay.
Thank you.
Hey, Amuro-san.
You should join our band.
What?
We could have a high school girl
plus handsome man band, right?
I'm not so sure.
I don't like to draw attention to myself.
Well, he is a Public Safety officer
infiltrating the Black Organization.
I can help you practice, though.
Would you like to go to a rental studio
and practice a little right now?
Great idea.
Let's do it.
Hey, you.
Have we met before?
No.
I believe today's the first time we've met.
What? No way!
All the rooms are full?
One should open up in about an hour.
What should we do?
Should we come back later?
But we came all the way here.
We can afford to wait an hour.
They have a break room in the basement.
Basement Studio
Break Room
If we rent instruments,
you can at least learn the feel of
a song through chords and tones.
Really?
You can play the bass, too?
Yes,
although I can't guarantee I'm
better than your brother's friend.
By the way, Sonoko,
can you play the drums?
Of course!
I'm great at Drum Master.
A video game?
Sera-chan, that's amazing.
Way to go.
All I did was play a scale.
That's all my brother's friend taught me.
Really?
Do you remember what the man who
taught you bass looked like?
More or less.
But how did you know my
brother's friend was a man?
Just a hunch.
Come on!
At this rate, we won't make it in time.
Kibune Someka (25)
Guitar
We only have a week until the concert.
Tadako, your bass is offbeat,
and I can't hear you at all.
Fuekawa Tadako (24)
Bass (Vocals)
Sorry.
I had too much to drink yesterday.
Rumi, your keyboard was off in places.
You didn't cut your fingernails, did you?
Kogure Rumi (24)
Keyboard
S-Sorry. I haven't been playing lately.
And, Hagie, your drums felt
more sluggish than usual.
Yamaji Hagie (25)
Drums (Leader)
Sorry. I'm just so tired.
Get it together, girls.
But, Someka, your guitar was too fast.
You seemed irritated.
Because we're running out of time.
And you haven't noticed that
your button's nearly fallen off.
What?
On your left breast pocket.
In any case, we'll resume
once we've cooled our heads.
Until then, I'm going to
take a nap in the studio.
I should be better after a ten minute nap.
Sheesh.
We only have two more hours in the studio.
What should I do about my nails?
Want to use my nail cutters?
Thanks. I'll cut them in the bathroom later.
Someka, want me to sew your button back on?
I brought my sewing kit.
Tadako, you're like a mom.
You're so good at sewing.
I'm not as good as Akane at knitting, though.
She made the knit hat Hagie's wearing.
That's right.
This is a tribute concert for Akane,
so we have to make it a success.
But Hagie's taking a nap.
Does she really get it?
Uh, oh!
I forgot my sewing kit in the studio.
I'll go wake Hagie while
sewing your button on.
Let me take your jacket.
Sure.
But I'll wake Hagie.
I need to replace my broken
guitar string, anyway.
There was a part of the
song I wanted to change.
But if Hagie's sleeping in
the studio, I guess I can't.
I can't write music unless
I can play my keyboard.
Tuning makes noise, too.
Well, we still have time.
There's no need to rush.
You're right.
Now that we've decided you'll be playing
Okino Yoko-san's "Dandelion,"
who's going to sing the vocals?
What?
S-Sonoko, right?
I can't multi-task.
Sera-chan, can you sing?
I'll pass.
What about your boyfriend, Shinichi-kun?
What?
I bet he can play the guitar, too.
Sh-Shinichi can play the violin,
but I don't know about the guitar.
And his singing...
His singing?
He sings like Conan-kun.
Right?
Sorry, I'm tone deaf.
Aren't those screams from the
girl band we saw just now?
It came from the studio upstairs.
Where did that scream come from?!
F-From the studio back there!
Is she dead?!
What?
Hagie!
You must be joking.
Yoshikawa lines on her neck.
She was strangled.
S-Strangled?
Who would strangle Hagie?
I think we'll know right away.
What?
Look.
We can view the footage from the
security camera on the ceiling.
Hey, what is this?
Half of the image is black.
And the drums are blocked entirely.
That might be the back of a phone.
We were filming ourselves practicing.
We stuck a selfie stick to a mic.
I see.
Under these circumstances...
...even if someone did something
next to the victim...
...there's no way for us to know what it was.
I see.
Because of the cell phone on a selfie stick
you attached to a mic stand
to record your performance,
the security camera's image is cut in half,
obscuring the area around the drums,
and preventing us from
knowing who killed her.
Is that right?
Y-Yes.
By the way, who put this here?
I-It was me.
I wasn't trying to block the security camera.
I just put it where I was told to.
Right?
Yeah.
While watching the image on the phone,
we told her to move it more to the left.
Or farther back.
Although in the end I think we decided
where to put it when Hagie said,
"There's fine. Let's start practicing."
Did you not get in trouble
with the studio staff
for blocking the security camera?
We were warned at first.
But we're regulars,
so they started letting us off the hook.
But why?
Normally one wall of a studio
is covered in mirrors.
The camera would've captured
the crime in the reflection.
So why did you close the curtains?
That was Hagie, too.
She said she wanted to focus on playing.
That it would be enough to watch
the video we recorded later.
Which means this situation
was just waiting to happen.
Yes.
The culprit must've been
expecting this situation
so they could use it in their crime.
If I can offer a detective's
perspective, that is.
In any case, we should probably
question the three girls,
while watching the security camera footage.
Apparently, the three of them came to this
studio one at a time to wake Hagie-san.
It's the café detective,
the high school girl detective,
and the boy who thinks he's a detective again.
This city sure has a lot of detectives.
Tell me if this sounds right.
While the four of you were
taking a break in the basement,
Hagie-san said she was going to take
a nap and returned to the studio.
One at a time, you went to wake her,
but she remained asleep.
Since she'd been sleeping
for more than thirty minutes,
you finally decided to go wake her together.
But when you got there,
she had been murdered.
Y-Yes.
Who went to wake Hagie-san first?
I-It was me.
I called out to her a few times,
but there was no answer.
She was still asleep by the time
I finished reattaching the button,
so I went back to the break room
where Someka and Rumi were waiting.
A button?
When I agreed to sew the button on
Someka's jacket that was coming off,
I realized I forgot my
sewing kit in the studio.
This must be it.
When Tadako-san entered the room.
Half her body is hidden,
but you can tell she's sewing
something onto the jacket.
You were there for more than ten minutes.
Does it really take that
long to sew a button?
When I looked more closely, I
realized her cuffs were frayed, too.
You're right. The cuff's been fixed.
Who went to wake her next?
Me.
My guitar's out for maintenance,
so I borrowed one from the studio.
But one of the strings broke during practice.
I thought I'd try waking her
while I replaced the string.
The broken string is the reason
the four of us stopped practice,
and went to take a break.
If you rented the guitar from the studio,
couldn't you have asked their
staff to replace the string?
I wanted to replace the
string and tune it myself.
This is Someka-san, right?
This is you replacing the string
and tuning the guitar.
Yeah, that's right.
But doesn't tuning make noise?
And you're standing pretty
close to the drums.
I was making noise on
purpose so she'd wake up.
I wanted to start practicing again.
How did Hagie-san seem then?
She was sleeping with her
face on the high tom-tom
and covering it with her arm.
Hagie always slept like that.
So if she was already dead by that point...
...you wouldn't have known.
Are you trying to say I killed
her when I went first?
We're just speaking hypothetically.
Rumi-san, were you the
last one to go wake her?
Yes.
During practice, there was actually a
section of the song I wanted to change.
I thought I could wake her
while working on the song.
You'll see if you look at the sheet
music that was in the studio.
Let's see.
There does seem to be a
section that was rewritten.
You made this section uptempo, right?
Yeah.
This is way better.
I don't get it.
Although with Hagie dead,
we might not get to perform
that song anymore.
She's in the video.
But, Rumi-san, you're moving the keyboard.
I moved away from the drums
so I wouldn't wake Hagie.
I wanted Hagie to hear the song
once I finished fixing it,
so I played as quietly as possible.
I called to her when I finished,
but she didn't answer.
It looks like you were in the
studio for about ten minutes, too.
Well, we're going to look for the
string used to strangle Hagie-san.
After undergoing a body search,
I'd like the three of you to wait
in the break room in the basement.
What?
You can't find the murder weapon?
Did you search the entire area?
Yes, from the studio to the drains.
The estimated time of death
is when the three of them
went to the studio to wake the victim.
According to the store's security
cameras at the entrance,
the three of them haven't gone outside.
And if a body search didn't
produce the weapon,
then it must be around here somewhere.
Search harder.
Yes, sir.
Did something happen?
There's a police car parked outside.
Is it a case?
Well, um...
What's wrong, Sera-chan?
Do you think they did it?
Oh, no.
When I see people carrying
guitar cases on their backs,
I'm reminded of four years ago,
when I saw Shu-nii standing
on the opposite side
of the train platform with
a guitar on his back.
Shu-nii?
Does that mean she's
actually Akai-san's sister?
I was surprised.
I thought he was in America.
And I'd never seen him play
any instruments before.
I was on my way back from
the movies with my friends,
but I ran to the other platform and
got onto the same train as Shu-nii.
I really wanted to hear him play the guitar.
Really?
What happened next?
He found me on the station platform
after changing trains a few times.
He got mad at me and told me to go home,
but when I told him I didn't have any
money and didn't know how to get home,
he told me to wait there
while he bought me a ticket
and left me on the platform.
Since I was in middle school,
I actually did have money,
and I knew how to get home.
But I thought Shu-nii must
still see me as a little kid.
Did you wait like he told you to?
Yeah. I wanted to cry.
But the guy with Shu-nii said...
Hey, you.
Do you like music?
Then he took his bass out of its case
and taught me how to play a scale.
Really?
So the person who taught you to
play the bass you mentioned...
It was him?
Yeah, although it was only
for about ten minutes.
Maybe he was your brother's bandmate.
I don't know about that.
He had his bass in a soft case.
But even after he took it out,
it retained its shape and stood straight up.
It's possible that the bass was camouflage
for something hard he had in the bag.
A rifle.
And? And?
Did he tell you his name?
No.
But another man who came to the platform
called him Scotch.
Scotch?
W-Was he a foreigner?
He was obviously Japanese,
so maybe it was a nickname.
But the man who called him
that was wearing a hat low over his eyes,
so I didn't see his face clearly.
But I have a feeling
he looked like you, Amuro-san.
You have the wrong person.
Anyway, instead of talking about the past,
why don't we solve the
case that's happening right now?
You're a detective, too, right?
Yeah, you're right.
Episode Preview
Like they said, it looks like we'll have
to investigate the other bands' members.
Come to think of it,
I want to see the practice video
you said you filmed in the studio.
Sure.
I turned it off while we weren't practicing,
so we don't have video
of the culprit, though.
See?
I see.
So that's how it is.
The Unfriendly Girls Band
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Unfriendly Girls Band (Part 2)!"
Knit Hat
Next Conan's hint.
A knit hat!
You're a little young for scotch.
Don't miss the next episode.
How about bourbon?
That's okay.
You must be joking.