Detective Conan Episode 387 "The
Unfriendly Girls Band (Part 2)"
While hanging out at Poirot after school,
Sonoko suggested to Ran and Sera
that they form a girls band.
Amuro-san and I tagged along
to a rental studio so they could practice.
But a girls band member
we met at the studio...
Is she dead?!
What? Hagie!
You must be joking.
Hagie! Hagie!
Nothing was caught on the security camera,
and the police couldn't
find the murder weapon.
Meanwhile, Sera seemed to find
something about Amuro-san suspicious.
And? And?
Did he tell you his name?
No, he didn't,
but another man who came to the platform
called him Scotch.
But the man who called him that
was wearing a hat low over his eyes,
so I didn't see his face clearly.
But I have a feeling
he looked like you, Amuro-san.
You have the wrong person.
Anyway, instead of talking about the past,
why don't we solve the
case that's happening now?
You're a detective, too, right?
Yeah, you're right.
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
I'm curious about Bourbon and Scotch.
But finding the missing
murder weapon comes first.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Unfriendly Girls Band
(Part Two)
"The Unfriendly Girls Band, Part Two!"
What?
You want to search us again?
You just searched us thoroughly.
We just want to be sure.
Y-You still haven't found the murder weapon?
Kogure Rumi (24)
Keyboard
And you think one of us is hiding it.
Fuekawa Tadako (24)
Bass (Vocals)
Don't tell me you think we swallowed it.
Kibune Someka (25)
Guitar
If that's the case, x-ray us
or do whatever else you want.
We're open to anything
if it'll clear our names.
Anyway, have you examined
the other bands yet?
No, not yet.
Hagie fought with other bands all the time.
They may have resented her.
The other day, with a
band we performed with...
You girls are still in a band?
But your vocalist's dead.
You're making this girl with the
freckles sing instead, right?
Poor girl.
Well, your vocalist did kill
herself after ruining her voice.
Can't be helped.
Um, who is this vocalist
who committed suicide?
Shuto Akane.
Shuto Akane
She had a beautiful voice.
Hey, anyone outside the studio could've seen
that half the security
camera's image was cut off
by looking at the monitor
at the reception desk, right?
Yes.
If they knew the girls had
a habit of doing that,
they may have been able to find
the studio they were renting.
Then someone could've used that
situation to sneak into the studio,
strangle the victim, and
leave with the weapon.
Like they said,
it looks like we'll have to investigate
the other bands' members.
But we let a few groups leave since
we had our eyes on these girls.
Call them back here immediately.
Yes, sir!
Hey, guys.
Which of you first suggested
that you form a band?
It was Hagie.
We were classmates in college.
She said she found a great vocalist,
so we started a band with Akane.
Akane could play the guitar, bass,
and keyboard in addition to singing.
She taught us all kinds of things.
But she couldn't do anything feminine.
Hagie taught her how to cook,
and I taught her about makeup and fashion.
I tried teaching Akane sewing and embroidery,
but she didn't stick with it for very long.
The only thing she kept doing was
knitting, which Rumi taught her.
Yeah,
but the rest of you ended
up being better than me.
Come to think of it,
I want to see the practice video
you said you filmed in the studio.
Sure.
I turned it off while we weren't practicing,
so we don't have video
of the culprit, though.
See?
Huh?
I thought you turned that in to the police.
The detective returned it to me
because it didn't seem to have
anything to do with the case.
And it's our last performance with Hagie.
Why was the video shot vertically?
Wouldn't the band fit into the shot
better if you shot it horizontally?
Our feet would be cut off
if we shot it horizontally,
so we decided to do it vertically, right?
Yeah.
And it's interesting how it's
different from a TV screen.
I see.
So that's how it is.
Seriously?
You still haven't found the weapon?
No, sir.
The victim Yamaji Hagie-san
was strangled using a rope
or string-like weapon.
She even had Yoshikawa lines
on her neck that indicate
she struggled while
she was being strangled.
In other words,
there must be a weapon with Yamaji-san's
blood on it somewhere in this studio,
so why haven't you found it yet?!
We investigated all the
strings in the studio,
but none of them produced a luminol reaction.
Now that you mention it,
didn't the victim's bandmate Kibune
Someka-san change one of her guitar strings?
Her guitar was the first thing we
examined, but we didn't find anything.
Could the culprit have cut the string
up and flushed it down the toilet?
We thought of that, too.
We also examined the scissors
in Fuekawa Tadako-san's sewing kit,
and Kogure Rumi-san's nail clippers,
but we didn't find anything.
If they used them to cut a bloodied string,
there would've been a reaction.
Then someone in a different band
must've strangled Yamaji-san
and left with the weapon.
If that's true,
then they've probably already
disposed of the weapon.
If forensics could find the culprit's skin
under the fingernails of Yamaji-san's body,
that would point us in the right direction.
But she was strangled from behind.
It's unlikely that she scratched the culprit.
Were you able to call back all
the band members we let go?
We couldn't get in touch with a
couple of them, so not all of them.
That won't be necessary.
After all, the culprit hasn't
left the building yet.
What?
Th-They haven't left?
Then the culprit...
Yes.
That means one of the
three remaining members
of Yamaji-san's band did it.
What?
I-Is that true?
Let's head to the basement break room,
where the three of them are waiting.
What?
One of us murdered Hagie?
You're still going on about that?
It's not us that's saying it.
It's these three who are helping
us with the investigation.
Sheesh.
I don't care if you think you're detectives.
But none of us have the string-like weapon.
There's no reason to suspect us.
If you think we threw it away somewhere,
you should be able to find
it somewhere in the studio.
Did you find it?
N-No, not yet.
Then we must be innocent!
Why don't you let us go already?
But...
There's no way they'll find it.
After all,
the weapon has already been
transported outside the studio.
Wh-What are you talking about?
None of us set one foot outside the studio!
How could we have taken the weapon outside?
Because... you're not the
ones who took it outside.
It was the police.
What?
Because... you're not the
ones who took it outside.
It was the police.
What?
The police took the victim's
belongings to the station,
where they're being examined, right?
Y-Yeah.
But there weren't any
strings in her possessions.
What if that string had been
knitted into something else
and was shaped differently?
What?
Y-You mean...
Yeah. The knit hat Hagie-san was wearing.
The weapon is a piece of
yarn knitted into that hat.
Th-They knitted the yarn into the hat?!
The culprit brought
a piece of yarn the same color
as Hagie-san's hat with them.
After strangling her with the yarn,
they removed the decoration
on the top of the hat,
knitted the weapon into the yarn,
replaced the decoration,
and put it on her head.
Since they folded up a
larger section of the hat,
no one really noticed.
B-But don't you use two pointed sticks
called knitting needles to knit?
None of them had anything like that.
There were some.
Next to the woman who died.
What?
Th-There were?
On top of the snare drum
to the left of the victim
there were drumsticks.
Couldn't you knit with those?
Y-You're right.
It wouldn't be impossible.
The three of them entered the studio
for about ten minutes to wake Hagie-san.
Tadako-san repaired the button that
was falling off Someka-san's jacket.
I-I fixed her frayed sleeve, too.
Someka-san was replacing
her broken guitar string.
I told you I tuned it, too.
And Rumi-san was fixing the
song you were working on.
Yes, while playing the keyboard.
None of them had time to knit anything.
There was one person
who could've prepared
for that beforehand.
You could've prepared
what you did beforehand,
Kogure Rumi-san.
What?
Th-That's it!
Someka-san's button coming off
and the guitar string
breaking were coincidences.
Not only that, but the guitar was one
they rented from the studio today.
She couldn't have
manipulated the guitar string
so it would be more likely
to break beforehand.
But if she fixed the song beforehand at home,
then all she had to do at the crime scene
was rewrite was she had decided on.
I see.
And unlike the others,
Rumi-san's back was to the camera.
She could've pretended to play the
keyboard while she was knitting.
I see.
Apparently you were good enough
at knitting to teach the others.
B-But I can knit, too.
And she couldn't have done that
without covering half the security camera.
Right, Rumi?
Y-Yes.
We attached a phone on a
selfie stick to a mic stand.
It was a coincidence
that it ended up in front
of the security camera.
The three of us decided where to put it
by looking at the video
and offering our opinions.
Or are you saying we worked together
to put it in front of the security camera?
We figured out that trick
after seeing the video of
you performing together.
What?
I saw that video, too, but
I didn't notice anything.
May we see it again?
Y-Yes.
What about this helped you figure it out?
Look at where they four of them are standing.
Where they're standing?
The position of the drums is
already set and can't be changed.
And the two playing the guitar and bass
will stay in frame no matter how they move.
So the position of the phone
being used to shoot the video
depends on the keyboard
in the top left corner.
In other words, Rumi-san could
control where the phone would be set
depending on the location of her keyboard.
What?
It would even be possible to control it
so it would be covering half
the security camera image.
If she was too close the drums,
the phone would have to be positioned closer,
preventing her from blocking the camera.
If she was too far away,
the phone would also move away,
and the phone would disappear
from the camera's frame.
After blocking half the
security camera's image,
you pretended to go wake Hagie-san,
and strangled her with the yarn.
You used her drumsticks to
knit the yarn into her hat,
all while pretending to fix the song.
Then you put the hat back on her head,
and returned to the break room
like nothing had happened.
Am I wrong?
B-But unless she knew Hagie-san
would sleep on the drums...
Someka-san, didn't you mention
that Hagie-san always slept like that?
If she always did, by mixing sleeping
pills into Hagie-san's drink,
then she could've predicted that Hagie-san
would return to the studio
alone to nap against her drums.
I'm sure you'll find a plastic bottle
with traces of sleeping pills on it if you
search the garbage cans in the studio.
Search them.
Yes, sir!
And tell forensics to examine
the victim's knit hat.
Got it.
Kogure Rumi-san, could you
come with us to the station?
Rumi...
B-But what about the scissors?
Without scissors,
I couldn't have removed the
pom-pom on top of her knit hat.
You used nail clippers.
What?
You knew Tadako-san would lend you
hers if you let your nails grow out.
Th-That's just your imagination!
There's no proof that I did it!
It's obvious.
What?
After all, you borrowed her nail clippers.
But you didn't trim your nails.
It means you knew you wouldn't
be practicing anymore today.
You wouldn't need to cut your nails.
And from the yarn in Hagie-san's knit hat,
I'm sure they'll find her blood
and your fingerprints.
Modern forensic investigators
can even collect fingerprints
from the fluffy surface of a tennis ball.
You're not making any sense!
Rumi would never use that
knit hat as a murder weapon!
Yeah!
After all, Rumi and Akane were the closest
in the band, and she knit that hat!
That's right.
I used that hat because Akane had knit it.
I wanted her to taste Akane's bitterness.
What?
You know how Akane ruined her voice, right?
Wh-When Hagie was drunk, she told her...
...that she wanted her voice to be deeper.
That's right.
She took her seriously
and gargled with liquor,
and pressed a cushion against
her face and screamed
to achieve a huskier voice.
But Hagie...
What's wrong with your voice?
It was better before.
Well, nothing we can do now. Tadako,
you'll have to sing at our next concert.
Akane, don't sing!
That's what she said.
It was too much!
She didn't understand how Akane felt!
Several days later,
Akane jumped in front of
a car and killed herself.
So I avenged Akane.
It wasn't a suicide.
It was an accident.
It was suicide!
Otherwise, she never would've
ignored the traffic light!
You're wrong, Rumi.
It was a boy who ignored the
light and jumped into traffic.
Akane was hit by a car
while trying to save him.
What?
Y-You're lying!
You must be lying!
After all,
Hagie said at the funeral
that it was her fault Akane died.
Probably because Akane did
what Hagie told her to do.
Did what she told her to do?
She said, "Don't speak
until your voice recovers."
"You'll get your beautiful
voice back in no time."
"I'm sorry for saying something
so stupid when I was drunk."
The people who witnessed the accident
said she jumped into traffic to save
the boy instead of calling out to him.
You didn't know
because you were bedridden
from the shock of Akane's death.
N-No!
What am I going to do?
Hagie...
No! No!
The murderer's screams of regret
rang throughout the studio,
until her voice became hoarse.
No way.
The keyboardist did it?
Yeah.
But I'm impressed, Sera-chan.
You solved another case.
You think so?
With Amuro-san and Conan-kun's help,
a case like this is a piece of cake.
Well done, high school detective.
I'm only a detective because of
my brother's influence, though.
You mean your smart brother you mentioned
during the Red Woman case?
No, that's my middle brother.
I was influenced by my oldest brother.
I thought your oldest brother was dead.
Was he a cop who died in the line of duty?
Yeah, but he wasn't a Japanese cop.
He was an agent of America's FBI.
Really?
Apparently he had a hard
time getting his green card.
That's why your brother was in America.
Yeah.
Hey, what's your brother's name?
It's Akai Shuichi.
Cool, right?
I knew it.
But you saw your brother on a
station platform in Japan, right?
Yeah, that's why I was so surprised.
Then maybe the guy who taught you
how to play the bass was an FBI agent, too.
Yeah, right.
He was probably a friend my brother
met while he was on vacation.
No, he
was an MPD Public Safety undercover officer.
A man your brother, Akai Shuichi,
killed.
Episode Preview
There are hot air balloons everywhere.
Watch out! They're going to crash!
It may have been an accident,
but a person is dead.
You could be held accountable.
Wh-What?
This is...
Could it be?
Mystery in a Hot Air Balloon
The next episode of Conan is
"Mystery in a Hot Air Balloon"
Hat
Next Conan's hint!
A hat.
Akai Shuichi is an amazing brother.
Don't miss the next episode.
I know all about that.