Suzuki Balloon Festival
First Prize 10 Million Yen
There are hot air balloons everywhere.
I know. They're so pretty.
This is the nation's biggest
hot air balloon rally.
The first place winner will
receive a 10 million yen prize.
That's amazing.
Event Headquarters
Reception
Hasegawa-san!
Miss, thank you for coming
all the way out here.
I brought a friend this year.
That's okay, right?
Yes, that's fine.
Hasegawa Ayato (45)
I'm Hasegawa of the event
management committee.
We'll take all the guests we can get.
Hey, how high can a hot air balloon fly?
It depends on the size of the balloon.
But the larger ones have climbed
over 10 thousand meters in the air.
They can easily fly above Mt. Fuji.
Really? I'd like to ride one!
I'm going to be riding one to
record the event on video.
Would you like to ride with me?
Yeah!
You guys should ride with me.
But we'd be bothering him.
Yeah.
You're actually just scared, aren't you?
Hot air balloons are safe.
You'll be totally fine.
They're as large as a seven story
building and full of light air.
It takes more than a tiny hole
to make them fall out of the sky.
See?
Did you hear what the event manager said?
Mizuguchi-san, is something wrong?
I just came to register another person.
Mizuguchi Shingo (37)
I want to show my wife the view from above.
I'd been turning down his
invitations until now.
Mizuguchi Arisa (33)
But I thought I'd try riding one this time.
See?
If you miss this chance, you're
not likely to get one again.
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
Giant and colorful hot air balloons.
But something unexpected
occurs while riding one.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Mystery in a Hot Air Balloon
"Mystery in a Hot Air Balloon!"
I'm not actually very interested
in hot air balloons.
What? Why'd you agree to ride, then?
He wanted me to accept the champion's cup,
since he was so confident he'd win.
And he said he'd buy me a
necklace with the prize money.
So I agreed.
Because he flies hot air
balloons on his meager salary,
he hardly buys me any accessories.
What's going on?
What are you doing?
Don't do it! Stop!
There's no way you'd beat me!
Okuda Akihiro (35)
What did you say?
I'm the champion!
So what?!
What?
Darling.
What are you doing? Stop!
Stop!
Arisa. But he—
What are you talking about?
You're the one who started it!
I thought hot air ballooning...
...was a more laid-back activity.
Looks like it isn't.
Mizuguchi-san said he was the champion.
That's right.
He's been the reigning
champion two years in a row.
He's a very passionate man.
Last night he was here working on his balloon
after the rest of us had
gone back to the hotel.
Look.
The blue balloon all the way
over there is Mizuguchi-san's.
Please get ready to start.
I-It's amazing!
It's so pretty...
Wow, look!
The people are getting smaller.
You're right.
Everyone else is leaving us behind.
Do we not have to go after them?
You're right.
Looks like the wind is stronger up above.
I'll man the burner, so you
take the camera, Conan-kun.
Okay.
Huh?
Is something wrong?
No, it's nothing.
Everyone's going so fast.
Isn't it dangerous for them
to be flying so close?
Today's task is called a "race to area."
Participants score points not just for
dropping the marker on the target,
but also for speed.
So everyone's trying to reach the
finish line as quickly as possible.
Isn't that dangerous?
Where?
The blue balloon in the lead.
There are two people riding.
Isn't that Mizuguchi-san?
Watch out! They're going to crash!
He opened the deflation port!
He's trying to run towards the ground.
They're falling.
Yeah, but hot air balloons fall slowly.
The people riding should be okay.
Conan-kun.
Arisa...
How could this happen?
Hasegawa-san, call the police.
G-Got it.
I see.
It sounds like this was an accident.
Detective Kaneko (35)
Ibaraki Prefectural Police
Where is the man piloting the
hot air balloon that hit them?
Okuda-san is still in the race.
He should be arriving at
the finish line around now.
It may have been an accident,
but I'd like to know the particular
circumstances that caused the woman to fall.
I'm Kaneko of the Ibaraki Prefectural Police.
You're Mizuguchi Shingo-san, correct?
I'm sorry to have to ask
during such a difficult time,
but could you describe what
happened when your wife fell?
A hot air balloon crashed into ours
and tore a hole in the envelope.
The envelope?
It's the balloon part on
top of the hot air balloon.
I see.
And then?
Because he crashed into us,
and the hole opened on
the side of the balloon,
the basket shook.
I told her to hold on tight,
but Arisa...
Sir, we're finished.
Can we transport the body now?
Yeah.
Arisa?
Where are you taking Arisa?
We may need to perform an autopsy.
We're taking her to a university hospital.
Please don't perform an autopsy on her!
How could you hurt her body even more?
She's already been hurt enough.
We know she died from the fall.
But until the coroner examines
her, we can't be sure.
Arisa!
Please take me with you.
Sure.
You should probably get your
injuries looked at, too.
I felt so bad for them, I couldn't watch.
I can't believe he did this at our event.
It may have been an accident,
but Okuda won't get away with this.
Huh?
Arisa-san's hat?
That's blood.
Come to think of it, Mizuguchi-san
had a cut on his face.
Plastic?
Is that part of the balloon?
Conan-kun!
Sonoko says she's going to the finish line.
I'll be right there.
She's dead?
Really?
That's why the police are here.
You really didn't know?
It's true!
I led the pack all the way here.
I don't know what happened
to the guys in back.
So you acknowledge you crashed
into Mizuguchi-san's balloon?
Yeah, but it was a race.
Everyone was trying to get to the
finish line as quickly as possible.
This kind of thing happens
all the time in races.
It may have been an accident,
but a person is dead.
You could be held accountable.
Wh-What?
Mister, you were fighting with Mizuguchi-san
before the race, weren't you?
What?
What? Is that true?
What are you talking about, kid?
There's no way you'd beat me!
What did you say?
I'm the champion!
I-It was his fault.
He said I was way too
inexperienced to beat him.
So you got angry and deliberately
ran into his balloon?
I said it wasn't on purpose!
And part of your basket is broken.
Some of the wickerwork is sticking out.
He's right.
You tried to poke a hole
in Mizuguchi-san's balloon
so he would drop out of the race.
This isn't an accident!
It's a murder!
And Okuda-san, you're the one who did it.
What?
D-Don't be ridiculous!
None of the cane was sticking out
while I was working on
my balloon yesterday!
A-And if he hadn't lowered his altitude,
our balloons would've just
bumped into each other!
He's right.
During the incident...
Mizuguchi-san opened the deflation
port and reduced his altitude.
Why?
Ran-neechan, you said "huh"
while we were flying, right?
Did you notice something strange?
Oh, that?
It looked like only one person was
riding in Mizuguchi-san's balloon.
But when I looked later,
there were two people there.
Arisa-san must have been
crouching in the basket.
Hey, Hasegawa-san.
Can I see your camera?
Sure.
Thanks.
This is...
Could it be?
In any case, Okuda-san,
you'll be coming to the station with us.
Wait a minute. I won today.
At least wait until after the award ceremony.
That's all forensics has to report.
Good work.
Let me know if anything else comes up.
Yes, sir.
Mizuguchi-san.
Are you all right?
Yes.
I'm sorry for causing so
much trouble at your event.
It's not your fault, Mizuguchi-san.
Yeah.
Okuda-san, after meeting with the judges,
we've decided to revoke your victory
for obstructing another competitor.
What? Obstructing?
I was just doing everything I could to win!
You've got to meet with the judges again!
No matter how many times we discuss
it, the result will be the same.
You heard him. Okuda-san, will
you come to the station now?
B-But...
Sonoko, what's wrong?
Could you wait a minute, Detective?
Don't take him away yet.
Why?
Because you should be arresting someone else.
Who are you talking about?
The poor victim's husband.
Right, Mizuguchi Shingo-san?
Wh-What are you talking about?
Hasegawa-san said last night
you were the last one here
working on his balloon.
Mizuguchi
Okuda
That's when you damaged the
basket on Okuda-san's balloon
so the cane would stick out.
Then you provoked Okuda-san
before the race
so he would run into you.
If he hadn't, you probably meant
to run into him yourself.
Why would I do that?
When Ran looked inside
your balloon in the air,
she said she only saw one person.
But the next time she
looked, she saw two people.
Of course she did.
Two of us were in the balloon.
You're right.
There were two of you.
But the person we saw wasn't Arisa-san.
Arisa-san was sitting in the basket.
When I examined your
balloon on the riverbank,
you had a bag containing the rope used
to lead the balloon when you land.
But the bag containing another
important item was missing.
And there was blood on
the inside of the basket.
At first I thought it got there
when you injured yourself.
But the blood was probably
your wife Arisa-san's.
Forensics did say the blood
belonged to the victim.
In other words, Arisa-san was already injured
while riding in the balloon.
When Okuda-san's balloon ran into yours,
you had your arm around Arisa-san's body.
I was doing my best to protect
her in the unsteady basket!
No, you weren't.
Watch out! They're going to crash!
After opening the deflation port
and lowering your altitude,
you were desperately holding down Arisa-san
so she wouldn't fly out of the basket.
Because that wasn't Arisa-san.
It was a light inflatable doll.
When you landed, in order
to destroy the evidence,
you burned the doll along with the balloon.
If you don't stop,
I'll sue you for defamation!
It was an accident!
And if it wasn't an accident,
then it was Okuda's fault!
You don't know when to give up, do you?
Now onto the main issue.
After reducing your altitude and
hiding your basket from view,
you...
...threw the unconscious Arisa-san's
body from the basket.
You murdered Arisa-san who trusted you.
She's lying!
She's making it all up!
Where's the proof?
Now, please.
Look at the burns on the balloon.
If you look closely,
there's some plastic stuck to the
balloon shaped like a doll's hands.
And then there's this.
It was found about 300 meters
from the starting point.
There's a fire extinguisher inside the bag.
It might match the wound on Arisa-san's head.
I didn't have a choice.
The stocks I bought with money
borrowed from my clients crashed.
If I didn't return it soon, they were
going to audit me next month.
So you were blinded by your
wife's life insurance money.
It's infuriating how stupid you are.
You murdered someone just for the money.
You should think about what you've
done from inside a prison cell,
you good-for-nothing.
Mizuguchi-san,
please come with us to the station.
Way to go, Detective Queen.
That was really cool.
R-Really?
Why don't your detective skills
apply to anything else?
I don't need your concern.
And when you're explaining your reasoning,
why do you fall asleep like my dad?
Y-You're right!
If it's genetic, then you're
the one who should be sleeping.
It's not genetic.
Both of them are just sleeping,
not solving mysteries.
Episode Preview
It's the voice of the tengu.
It's so pretty.
Why was it shaking?
Probably because of the wind, but...
The voice of the tengu.
You Can Hear the Tengu's Voice
The next episode of Conan is
"You Can Hear the Tengu's Voice!"
Wind
Next Conan's hint!
The wind!
Don't miss the next episode.
You can count on me to solve all cases!
I guess I went too far this time.
Sonoko is turning into a tengu.