That's in the opposite direction.
Jeez, what are we going to do?
We could head back, but
the sun's about to set.
Is there someplace nearby where
we could spend the night?
Shimomura Shozo (62)
Local Historian
There's a guest house at
the bottom of the mountain.
Let's stay there!
Thank you very much.
No need to thank me.
Wh-What was that sound?
The voice of the tengu.
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
Everyone heard the eerie moan.
The secret of the tengu marks
the start of a new case.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
You Can Hear the Tengu's Voice
"You Can Hear the Tengu's Voice!"
It's so pretty.
Where's the money coming from?!
What are you talking about?
Imazu Shigeo (51)
Building Contractor
I'm talking about the money
not listed on the statement!
There's no such money.
Mayama Shoji (44)
Mayor
If you don't stop making things up,
I'll sue you for slander, Imazu.
I'd like to see you try!
What a loser.
Man, the water was great!
I know.
I'm hungry.
Hey, that's him.
Thank you for earlier.
Oh, no problem.
Ah, Sensei. In here.
Got it.
Shimomura-sensei
Publishing Party
He's an author, huh?
Sensei, do you have anything
you'd like to say?
Tengu Inn
9:50, huh?
There's still an hour before the bus comes.
Dad, Conan-kun.
Apparently there's a cave nearby.
Do you want to go check it out?
I guess. We don't have anything else to do.
Kokushu Historical Site
Welcome to the Tengu Cave
It's a good thing the guest house was
willing to hold onto our bags for us.
Yeah.
Hey, isn't that it?
Let's see. What does it say?
What's this?
Oh, excuse me.
I-It's fine.
What was he doing back there?
It's closed.
What?
Oh, I'm sorry!
Let me open that for you.
Visiting Hours
10 AM to 5 PM
Hirai Yasutaro (29)
Tourism Department Employee
This place opens at ten.
Come in.
Good.
Huh?
What's wrong?
The mask is missing.
Is this video of the inside?
Yes.
The passages are narrow, so it's for
people unable to go deep inside the cave.
Look, Conan-kun.
There's a shrine in the middle of the cliff.
It's called the Tengu's Shrine, and—
Huh?
What is that?
H-He's hanging from his neck...
What?
It's an emergency!
He fell!
Let's head inside! Quickly!
Watch your heads.
Ow!
Are you okay, Dad?
Ow...
This certainly is a narrow passage.
We're out.
It's over there.
Th-The mayor!
There's no pulse.
He's dead.
Ran, call the police.
Okay.
There's no service here.
We'll have to return to the guest house.
Got it.
This is probably what happened.
The mayor strung a rope on the
shrine and hung himself,
but unable to withstand the weight, it broke.
That place is really high
off the ground, though.
What's this?
It's scaffolding.
You used to be able to go
right up under the shrine.
But it's been disassembled.
It was here when I came yesterday morning.
I wonder who took it apart?
Can you get up there without the scaffolding?
Oof.
This won't work.
It's impossible to climb.
There's a trick to it.
Shimomura-sensei.
We meet again.
But even if there is a trick, this cliff...
Wh-What is this?
It's the mayor.
He's dead.
Speaking of this cliff, Hirai-kun,
you boys used to climb up to the
shrine all the time, didn't you?
Yes, and you'd always scold us for it.
What kind of sensei are you?
He's a teacher at a school.
A principal.
Since he retired two years ago,
he's been continuing his life's
work of researching the tengu.
Is the book you published
about the tengu, too?
My former students paid for it.
On top of that, they threw
me a party last night.
I'm grateful for their support.
Were the mayor and Imazu-san
your students, too?
That's right.
They were in different years, though.
There it is again.
What is the tengu's voice actually?
Who knows?
M-Mayama...
Who are you?
He's Imazu-san.
Until he lost to Mayama-san in
the recent mayoral election,
he was the mayor.
I see.
Imazu-san, could I ask you a few questions?
Who are you?
Mori Kogoro the detective.
How long were you in front of the cave?
Since 8:30, I think.
Did you see Mayama-san arrive?
Yeah.
Mayama came around nine.
Was he alone?
Yeah.
Maybe I should tell you what I
was doing in front of the cave.
Please.
It started last night.
B-Blackmail?
How much do you want?
Fine.
Where do you want to meet?
Tomorrow at 9 AM at the Tengu's Cave.
Got it.
This is just my speculation,
but I think he was being blackmailed over off
the books money he received in the election.
So I was waiting in front of the cave...
But he never came out.
While I was wondering what
to do, I ran into you guys.
Did anyone else enter the
cave during that time?
Nope.
Hey, Imazu-san.
What?
You work for a building contractor, right?
Are you the one who disassembled
the scaffolding?
Yeah.
When did you do that?
Yesterday afternoon.
Mayama called to tell me to do it.
That's odd.
If he meant to hang himself in the cave,
it would've been easier to
leave the scaffolding up.
Why did he do it the day
after it was taken down?
I don't think it was planned.
It was probably a spontaneous death.
No, it must've been planned.
He had to get the rope to hang himself with.
This must be what happened.
At 9 AM, without realizing
you were watching him,
Mayama-san entered the cave alone.
He locked the door from the inside,
and stole the tengu mask from the office.
Then he scaled the cliff,
tied the rope around the shrine post,
and hung himself.
What about the person blackmailing him?
Does that mean they never came?
They came,
but when they realized Imazu-san
was out front, they probably left.
I see.
Now we just have to find a motive.
Does anyone have any ideas?
Huh?
What else is there?
Death spots?
This doesn't make sense.
If he hanged himself, they
should appear on his legs.
Which means...
This wasn't a suicide.
When did the killer enter and leave the cave?
There's no guarantee Imazu-san
is telling the truth,
and it's possible he just missed it.
But it's true that the door
was locked when we arrived.
I guess I'll try climbing it.
Okay.
Hey, Conan! That's dangerous!
I'll be fine.
Five minutes, huh?
There is where we met
Shimomura-san yesterday.
So that's why we heard the tengu's voice.
He probably thought he couldn't
escape his blackmailer.
That's the kind of man he was.
When things started to go south, he'd run.
You're right.
No, you're wrong.
His conscience was troubled.
The Kurama tengu is a symbol
of chasing out evil.
Maybe that was the message he was trying
to convey by wearing the tengu mask.
It's a good thing his body was swinging.
If it had fallen straight down,
it would've suffered a lot of damage.
What?
Why was it swinging?
Probably because of the wind, but...
C-Can we fit through this narrow space?
You sure can. Watch your head.
I believe the call
from the blackmailer and
the publishing party
triggered this event.
I see.
I found it!
This means the case is solved—
Dad.
That's what I'd like to say,
but we'd just be playing
into the killer's hands.
What?
Please examine the victim's back.
You'll find death spots there.
Y-You're right.
Death spots appear on the legs
in the case of a hanging.
They appear on the back when the victim
is lying face up on the ground.
So he was hanged after being
killed while lying on his back?
That's impossible.
How could someone have carried
a body all the way up there?
You're right.
And there'd be no benefit
to doing it, either.
Hirai-san.
Yes?
Try to recall
what you saw on the monitor then.
I saw
the mayor hanging from the post.
How was he hanging?
He was swinging.
Since he was swinging,
the body didn't fall onto the scaffolding.
We'd better thank the wind, then.
Was it the wind?
The spring was visible in the
foreground of the monitor.
The spring was flowing like it is right now.
Maybe it was because it was just
after he had hung himself.
If he struggled, his body would swing.
Based on the death spots,
it couldn't have been immediately afterwards.
Then why was he swinging?
He made his body swing.
What?
He made his own body swing?
That's impossible.
Not the body.
What we saw on the monitor
was the killer pretending to be the body.
Wh-What?
At 9 AM,
Mayama-san followed the
instructions he received
from the blackmailer the previous
night and came to the cave.
The killer was waiting for him inside.
They're also the one who locked the door.
It was so they'd be free to commit
their crime for an entire hour,
until Hirai-san came at
10 AM to unlock the door.
They led Mayama-san deeper into the cave.
Then they strangled Mayama-san with
the rope they prepared beforehand.
Next the killer put on Mayama-san's jacket
and pants and the tengu mask.
They wore the mask simply to hide their face.
The killer climbed the cliff to the shrine,
tied the rope they used to
strangle Mayama-san to the post,
and broke it, causing it to fall.
Next they tied a separate
piece of rope to their body
like a harness and dangled from the post.
They probably tied the rope so it
would come undone if they let go.
By swinging their body, they were
able to jump to the nearby ledge.
The ledge they fell onto
isn't visible on the monitor.
Please examine the ledge.
You'll find pieces of the
victim's jacket there.
We found it.
Then they replaced Mayama-san's
jacket and pants
on his body and placed the
tengu mask on his face.
Isn't it all too convenient?
When did he run?
How did the killer know you would come?
The voice of the tengu.
T-Tengus don't exist.
It's actually the sound of the wind.
It occurs when the door to the
cave is opened and closed.
You can also just barely hear human voices.
This is narrow.
How are we going to get the body out of here?
The killer hid when they heard our voices.
I see.
So who did it?
We can eliminate Hirai-san.
He witnessed the body falling with us.
Then...
Hey, it wasn't me!
It wasn't me, either.
The killer must've climbed
the cliff to escape.
Yeah.
We should search the mountains immediately!
There's actually something
odd about the tengu's voice.
We first heard the tengu's voice
after Ran left this place.
Got it.
In other words,
the first voice we heard
was the sound of Ran opening the door.
First Voice
The second voice occurred just
before Imazu-san appeared.
In other words, when
Imazu-san opened the door.
Second Voice
No one entered or exited between them.
Shimomura-san, when did you enter the cave?
When?
Right after you.
I guess that would be right after
the first voice you mentioned.
Then you should've passed Ran.
Don't tell me you didn't.
After all, look at how
narrow that passage is.
M-Maybe it was a little later.
You must've missed it.
You're still playing innocent?
I'm not playing at anything.
Yesterday you had that cloth
hanging around your shoulders,
but today it's wrapped around your neck.
Is it because you're hiding
a scratch underneath it
from when you scraped yourself
on the uneven rocks?
This is ridiculous!
I got this while hiking around the mountains.
You could easily explain a single scrape.
But can you explain scrapes
on your shins and thighs?
Inspector, please examine Mayama-san's body.
His clothes are torn, but
his body is unscratched.
You're right.
Is the rope you used when
you fell inside your backpack?
Yes.
But, Sensei, why?
It happened a few days ago.
While hiking around the mountains,
I ran into a surveyor.
When I asked why he was surveying,
he said it it was to turn this mountain
into a landfill for industrial waste.
What?
Mayama-kun had received undocumented
contributions to his campaign
from industry workers on that condition.
I couldn't allow it.
He was willing to destroy
the town's valuable cultural
property for his own benefit.
I had to do it to stop him.
For the town's sake,
I had to become the tengu,
and bring the hammer of
righteousness down on him.
I pretended to be a blackmailer
and called Mayama-kun to the cave.
I didn't think he would come otherwise.
I was surprised to see the
scaffolding had been taken down,
but I didn't lose my cool.
It would've been simpler if I'd made
it look like Mayama-kun's body
fell onto the scaffolding,
but I couldn't do it.
Hirai-kun witnessed the fall at
10 AM, just as I had planned.
I meant to escape while he called the police.
But I wasn't expecting him to bring the
great detective Mori Kogoro with him.
It would've been the same even if I hadn't.
Imazu-san was waiting outside.
You're right.
That was some sharp detective
work, if I say so myself.
He's really turning into a tengu.
All his bragging might
actually make his nose grow.
Episode Preview
We already ate since you came back so late.
Apparently they arrested the killer
of the murder that happened
the day before yesterday.
She's a pretty woman.
What? Roll up my pants?
It is you.
The Last Gift
The next episode of Conan is "The Last Gift!"
Watch
Next Conan's hint!
A watch!
Don't miss the next episode.
Another pretty lady is in the next episode.
Let me handle it!
He's got a lewd look on his face again.