Mori Detective Agency
Good morning, Dad.
According to police, the
victim Katsui Masaru
We already started eating
since you woke up so late.
Apparently they arrested
the killer in the murder
had been demanding money
from suspect Hirose Junko,
that happened the day before yesterday.
and unable to withstand his demands
any further, resorted to murder.
The other day?
The suspect appears to
have admitted to her crime,
Oh, you mean the one in Tonkoro City?
and is currently being
held at Tonkoro Station,
This woman...
Huh?
where she is being questioned.
What?
Tonkoro City Murder
Suspect Arrested
Suspect
Hirose Junko (25)
We are waiting for updates on this case.
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
When the old man sees a
beautiful suspect on TV,
he makes an unexpected move.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Last Gift
"The Last Gift!"
MPD Tonkoro Station
What's did you want to discuss
that's so important, Mori-kun?
First, could you tell me the
sequence of events of the case?
It started yesterday on Saturday morning.
The body of Katsui Masaru,
thought to be killed the night before,
was found behind a park in Tonkoro City.
Katsui Masaru (30)
Because he was a serial blackmailer,
we believed the suspect
was one of his victims.
As we were questioning
our list of suspects...
Hirose Junko (25)
Office Worker
Last night, Katsui came to visit,
and demanded money from me again.
I couldn't take it anymore.
We arrested her because
she had motive and seemed
to admit she had done it.
And you're sure Katsui was murdered
around 8 PM on Friday night?
His watch was stopped at that time.
We believe it broke when he was killed.
And he was caught on security cameras
at Tonkoro Station around 7:20 PM.
If he met with the murderer
and was killed after that...
If the time this watch is stopped
at is the time of the murder,
then she didn't kill him.
Wh-What?
Around 8 PM that night,
she was in Beika City.
It's still only eight?
Thank god it's Friday!
One more bar!
Huh?
She's a pretty woman.
Are you all right?
Ouch...
Miss?
It was impossible for her to have done it.
It takes almost an hour
to drive from Beika City
to the crime scene.
Inspector.
What?
Roll up my pants?
Just for our reference,
could you roll up your left pant leg?
It is you.
I happened to see you around 8 PM
on Friday night in Beika City.
What is the meaning of this, Hirose-san?
He's right.
I was going to a restaurant in Beika City.
But I ended up not going since my leg hurt.
More importantly, why did you
lie about killing Katsui?
Because I...
thought the killer must have been like me.
If they were being blackmailed by Katsui,
then I was willing to
take the blame for them.
In any case, you have an alibi.
But giving false testimony is an
interference of public duties.
We'll let it go this time.
We're also at fault for being
too hasty in making an arrest.
That's great news.
Thank you.
No problem.
Mori Detective Agency
So she was acquitted and released.
Thanks to me, her savior.
Hirose Junko-san seems like
a strange person, though.
Why would she take responsibility
for a murder she didn't commit?
What?
She had motive, right?
But she has someone to verify her alibi.
Maybe the actual time
of the murder was different.
Maybe the killer adjusted the time
on his watch after killing him.
Hirose Junko-san admitted to the crime.
If she was going to do that,
there would've been no need to hide
the actual time of the murder.
That's true, but...
Wait, kid!
She's definitely innocent.
But it doesn't make sense.
I'm going to investigate.
We may be able to figure
out why Hirose-san
pretended to be the murderer.
In that case, you should look into
her connections to Beika City.
When I saw her,
she didn't have the expression of someone
on their way to eat, drink, and be merry.
We need to know why she
really came to Beika City.
I see.
Hirose-san was lying.
Yeah, but I still don't think she's guilty.
I see.
You're trying to prove Conan-kun wrong.
And I thought it would be the
best way to find the true killer.
This is it.
This is where they found
Katsui Masaru's body.
Here?
But this place...
I'm surprised they found a body
in such a well-concealed area.
An anonymous woman called the police.
I see.
But what was that woman doing here?
How should I know that?
We're assuming the victim
was killed around 8 PM
because his watch was
stopped at that time, right?
Yeah.
We're certain Katsui arrived
at Tonkoro Station around 7:20.
That matches the time of death
determined by the autopsy,
which was between 7 PM and 9 PM.
Between seven and nine?
Then if she had hurried
back to Tonkoro City
after being spotted in Beika City around
eight, she would've arrived around nine.
Hirose-san could just barely have done it,
and made it seem as though
he'd been killed at eight.
Then she would've fabricated
an alibi for that time.
Like another witness who
happened to see her.
Yeah, but...
Is there any evidence that
points to the true killer?
There isn't any.
Katsui bought two packs of
cigarettes at the station,
but one was left untouched in his pocket.
So he was a heavy smoker.
In any case, there's no evidence.
But if it's just barely possible
that she could've done it—
Give it up already, kid.
Soba and Udon
Her man lives in Beika City?
More accurately, he's her ex-boyfriend.
His name is Matsubayashi Atsuro-san.
Apparently he recently got
engaged to the daughter
of an executive at his company.
So he dumped Hirose Junko-san.
But she has no other
connections to Beika City.
Maybe she was actually
visiting him the other night.
So she does
have someone besides
you to verify her alibi.
Around 8 PM.
You're saying that's him?
What are you talking about?
Fabricating an alibi.
If you assume she used him...
Then wouldn't she have told the
police about Matsubayashi-san
when the police suspected her?
Yeah.
Yeah, but...
I figured out
why Hirose-san pretended
to be the murderer!
That night, Hirose-san went
to see Matsubayashi-san.
She went to get rid of old
mementos still left there.
But she couldn't tell the police.
She couldn't tell them?
Yeah, she couldn't tell them.
So why not?
If she did,
the police would've tried to confirm
her story with Matsubayashi-san.
Then his fiancée might find out
he let his ex-girlfriend into his home.
His fiancée would think
he was up to something.
She might even call off the engagement.
And his fiancée is the daughter
of an executive at his company.
Matsubayashi-san would lose his job.
Hirose-san hid the truth
because she didn't want to put
Matsubayashi-san through that.
Even if it meant being convicted
of a crime she didn't commit,
she wanted to protect
Matsubayashi-san's happiness.
But he left her for another woman.
But she still wanted to do it.
Hirose-san still loves Matsubayashi-san.
Pretending to be the murderer
was Hirose-san's last gift
to Matsubayashi-san.
Yeah, but Ran-neechan...
Interesting.
Your theory that she tried to use
her ex to fabricate her alibi.
And Ran's theory that she still loved him.
If we meet this Matsubayashi guy,
we'll know right away which of you is right.
Matsubayashi Atsuro (28)
Office Worker
What?
Did Junko come here?
Yeah, two nights ago.
Of course not.
We broke up.
But, Matsubayashi-san...
You're bothering me!
Don't come back again!
Based on that reaction, we know for
sure that Hirose-san came to visit him.
But if that's the kind of man he is,
that doesn't support either of your theories.
Yeah.
I can't imagine her wanting
to be convicted of a crime
she didn't commit for him.
And I doubt he would've agreed
to verify Hirose-san's alibi,
even if she asked.
In other words, she couldn't have
used him to fabricate an alibi.
I guess I was wrong to suspect Hirose-san.
You finally admit it?
Either way, he's a selfish gold digger.
But Hirose-san
still loved and trusted him despite it.
Wait a minute.
Could it be?
Hey, mister.
How did Hirose-san react
when you went to confirm her alibi?
She was surprised,
perplexed,
thoughtful,
and then happy.
So what?
Nothing.
Just checking.
If that's true, then there
must be some trace of it.
Excuse me.
Is Hirose-san moving?
Oguchi Hamako (52)
Landlady
Yes, because of the awful
things she went through,
like being suspected by the police.
Really?
This is garbage, right?
I'll put it out for you.
Thank you. How considerate.
Since it was Friday night,
it probably hasn't been collected yet.
Found it.
What could you possibly want now?
Why did you ask me to come here?
We have no idea, either.
Thanks for waiting.
Why did you gather all of us here, Mori-kun?
What?
Inspector, you called me.
Mori-san, we examined this
thing Conan-kun brought us.
You were exactly right.
But what does this mean?
What is that?
I didn't—
Did you run out of patience,
Hirose Junko-san?
What?
Katsui Masaru was using something
to continue to blackmail you.
And your boyfriend Matsubayashi-san
ran after an executive's daughter
so he could marry into money.
What? Stay out of my business!
When Katsui Masaru demanded
money from you again,
you decided to remove the
obnoxious blackmailer
from this world.
It's impossible to run from murder.
But you made up your mind.
If you could use a murder
for another purpose,
then you were willing to be arrested.
So you put your plan into action.
B-But, Mori-san...
You're the one who said she was innocent.
You verified my alibi.
Just after seven on the
night of the incident,
you visited Matsubayashi-san in Beika City.
What do you want now?
You're getting married, right?
Then we have to erase all traces of me.
Hey, wait!
You can't do that!
While you were using an excuse to
get into Matsubayashi-san's home,
Katsui Masaru was arriving in Tonkoro City
at your invitation.
At eight, after you left
Matsubayashi-san's home
and were hurrying back to Tonkoro City,
I happened to see you.
Then you led Katsui Masaru
to the crime scene,
and murdered him around nine.
You set his watch to eight and
broke it, stopping the watch.
The next morning,
you made an anonymous call
to the police so they would find the body.
When they came to question you,
you confessed to the crime.
Everything was complete.
Last night, Katsui came to visit,
and demanded money from me again.
I couldn't take it anymore.
If the suspect denied committing the crime,
the police would've suspected
you of manipulating the watch.
But because you confessed,
no one suspected you.
You're right.
But if she meant to confess to the crime,
why did she bother with fabricating an alibi?
Matsubayashi-san.
You learned through the news
that Hirose-san was arrested
for murder, didn't you?
And that the time of the crime
was 8 PM on Friday night.
In other words,
even though you were the one person who
knew Hirose-san couldn't have done it,
you didn't come forward.
I was just thinking about doing it.
You're lying!
You would never give up
the golden ticket you got your hands on!
Your other goal for killing Katsui
was to make Matsubayashi-san feel
as though he allowed an
innocent woman to fall.
Since Hirose-san is a first-time offender,
considering her motive,
she would've gotten out in a
relatively short amount of time.
And then...
How could you let me fall
when I was innocent?
How could you let me fall?
Honey, who is that?
What does she mean by "fall?"
The reason you made us believe the
murder was committed at eight
was so you could send Matsubayashi-san,
the selfish man who dumped
you, one last gift.
One full of hate.
Your only miscalculation
was the appearance
of a second person who
could verify your alibi.
That was why you were surprised.
Then perplexed,
then thoughtful.
You were considering how
to handle my testimony.
Then you happily latched onto it.
Though you'd be unable to get
your revenge on Matsubayashi-san,
you could avoid becoming a murder suspect.
This is all speculation.
I haven't seen Katsui in years.
Where were you that night between 7:20,
when Katsui arrived in Tonkoro City,
and nine when he was murdered?
Because you wanted us to believe
he was killed at eight,
you couldn't let Katsui be seen by anyone.
And the safest place to hide him
was in your home.
She's late.
Detective Takagi, please
explain the situation.
Inside this plastic bag
were ten cigarette butts
and a box containing ten unsmoked cigarettes.
Katsui's fingerprints were
found on all of them.
And we found Hirose Junko-san's
fingerprints on this bag.
In other words, Katsui
was waiting in your home
for you to return.
So he could be killed by me.
And I meant to use his murder to take revenge
for the betrayal at the hands
of the man I loved and trusted.
You're right.
Hirose Junko-san, could
you come with us, please?
What a stupid woman.
Should you be laughing, Matsubayashi-san?
When the details of Hirose-san's
crime are reported,
what will your fiancée and
her father think of you?
Mori Detective Agency
Suspect Hirose Junko-san has
been arrested once again,
and confessed to her crime.
You were right, Conan-kun.
It was just a coincidence.
That's right.
His idea just happened to be right.
The difference between his reasoning
and mine is night and day.
Chalk and cheese.
Totally different.
Totally different! Totally different!
Jeez, this old man...
Episode Preview
Are you hurt?
Tsutsumi?
Hey, where did they find the will?
The ambulance crew
found it in Tsutsumi-san's jacket pocket.
The Rainy Bus Stop
The next episode of Conan
is "The Rainy Bus Stop!"
Umbrella
Next Conan's hint!
An umbrella!
What? I can't take a bath when
I got soaked in the rain?
Don't miss the next episode.
That's not what that means.