Damn it.
This is why I hate rainy days.
You should've stayed home, then.
You idiot.
Since Ran's out, this is my chance.
How could I not go out drinking?
But Ran-neechan made dinner
for us before she left.
Don't blame me if she gets mad at you later.
You say that, but you came with me.
Won't it be easier to make an
excuse later if I come with you?
So? What do you want to eat?
Well...
What was that?
Mister, that sound...
Yeah.
It could be an accident.
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
A car's lights illuminate the crime scene.
A simple accident takes a surprising turn.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Rainy Bus Stop
"The Rainy Bus Stop!"
Hey, you! Are you okay?
How is he?
He's just unconscious.
But what is he doing in
the middle of the road?
Mister, over there!
What is it?
What?
It's no use.
He's dead.
Kid, call the police.
It looks like that won't be necessary.
Huh?
Car parked on the Chuo Line...
Inspector?
Mori-san?
What are you two doing here?
We were on our way back
from working on a case
when we saw a suspicious
car parked on the Chuo Line.
Mori-kun, what are you doing here?
Well, actually...
I happened to be walking around
the area when I heard a crash.
By the time I ran over,
it was already like this.
Looks like there aren't any security cameras.
Yeah.
And given the rain and darkness,
I doubt we'll be able to find any witnesses.
Which means we'll have to
ask him what happened.
Is he all right?
He'll live.
An ambulance should be here soon.
So we'll have to wait for
him to regain consciousness.
Who's the victim?
Yes, sir.
His wallet and cell phone were in his pocket.
Tsutsumi Naohiro (31)
His ID card indicates he's Tsutsumi
Naohiro-san, 31 years old.
The cause of death was most
likely a brain contusion
caused by a blow to the head.
He seems to have been drinking.
He was probably drunk
and jumped into traffic.
But we can't assume it was an accident yet.
Huh?
Ow!
All you ever do is get in
the way at crime scenes.
You stay here and behave yourself.
My head...
C-Can I help you?
You don't remember anything?
Remember?
I was driving in my car, and...
That's right. I...
What happened to the person I hit?
I-Is he all right?
Unfortunately...
N-No.
Are you all right?
Are you hurt?
I-I'm fine.
Just to be sure, you should
get checked out later.
The ambulance will be here soon.
Okay.
How is he doing?
He cut the inside of his mouth,
but he seems to have no other injuries.
So if we wanted to inspect
the scene with him...
There should be no problem.
In that case, could you
come this way, please?
Yes.
Let's start with your name.
Kikuchi Toshiaki (31)
It's Kikuchi Toshiaki.
Where do you work?
I'm unemployed right now.
I see.
All right, then.
T-Tsutsumi?
Tsutsumi!
Tsutsumi.
It really is you.
Why did this happen?
Why?
You knew him?
Yes.
I can't believe I hit you.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
Was the victim a friend of yours?
He was a former coworker.
Former?
Tsutsumi and I were both
recently laid off.
We started around the same time
and were relatively good friends.
We were laughing about
leaving the company
around the same time, too.
I see.
This must be hard for you,
but could you describe in detail
what happened during the accident?
Yes.
After eating dinner at a friend's restaurant,
I was driving home.
I noticed someone with an
umbrella jumped into the street,
and slammed on the brakes.
But because of the rain and darkness...
I know it's just an excuse, though.
You said you were on your
way home after dinner,
but you didn't have
anything to drink, did you?
Of course not.
I haven't had a drop to drink.
That umbrella...
This umbrella is the victim's.
Mister, what are you doing?
Oh, it's you.
I came to get my umbrella.
I can't stay under the detective's forever.
Inspector, the ambulance
crew found something.
Looks like they found something.
Seems that way.
What's going on?
We found Tsutsumi's suicide note.
Life is too hard. I'm at my limit.
That can't be.
He wouldn't have written a suicide note.
In other words, this wasn't an accident.
It was a suicide.
Hey, where did they find the note?
The ambulance crew
found it in Tsutsumi-san's jacket pocket.
Kikuchi-san,
do you have any idea why he
may have wanted to kill himself?
He was fired from his job.
At first he was trying to find a new one,
but it wasn't going well.
Maybe I'll win the lottery.
More importantly, how's the job hunt going?
What?
Nobody would hire me now.
Don't say that, Tsutsumi.
Man, you're killing my buzz
with your depressing questions.
Damn it.
Hey, Kikuchi.
Lend me some money.
Didn't the company give you some money?
I already spent all of it.
Jeez.
Just give me something.
Hey!
I'm borrowing one of these.
What are you going to do now?
Who knows?
If I run out of options,
maybe I'll kill myself.
Kill yourself? Are you serious?
I'm just kidding.
Later.
I see.
So he'd been fired from his
job and had money troubles.
I can't believe he was so
depressed he killed himself.
If only he'd talked to me about it.
Hey, Detective Takagi.
There's something on the back.
You're right.
Looks like a piece of string.
Is that...?
What did I tell you?
Don't get carried away.
Ow!
Go sit over there.
The rain's coming down harder now.
We should get out of the rain.
You're right.
Well, there's nothing particularly
suspicious about this case.
It was probably a suicide.
What will I be charged with?
Well,
that'll depend on the traffic
division's investigation,
so I can't say for sure.
But I doubt it'll be worse
than forward inattention
and professional negligence
resulting in death.
I see.
He's wrong.
This wasn't a suicide.
Damn it.
I still don't have any decisive evidence.
Damn it, I'm soaked.
This coat isn't waterproof at all.
That's it!
It must be here somewhere.
Found it!
The traffic division sure
is taking their time.
According to the ambulance crew,
there was a multi-car crash
at Beika Ohashi Bridge.
Today's was sudden...
Mori-kun, has it come to you already?
Is it your usual thing?
Yeah, I figured it out.
This was a premeditated murder
carried out by Kikuchi-san.
But you were just calling it a suicide.
Indeed.
I was fooled by Kikuchi-san's
brilliant acting.
Don't be ridiculous.
Kikuchi-san, there are several
problems with your testimony.
Conan, show the inspector.
Here, Inspector!
I found this near the car.
It was probably Tsutsumi-san's umbrella.
It looks like an ordinary umbrella.
Kikuchi-san said a person carrying
an umbrella jumped into the street.
Huh?
But the umbrella was closed.
Maybe the umbrella closed when he
was struck during the accident.
That umbrella is what's known
as an automatic umbrella.
It opens at the push of a button,
but to close it
the runner must be
slid down the umbrella.
As you can see, unless you're
deliberately closing it,
that umbrella can't be closed.
So when did Tsutsumi-san close his umbrella?
It's hard to imagine he closed
it himself after he was hit.
Which means...
You're right.
I misremembered the accident.
Tsutsumi's umbrella was never open.
That's right.
I'm sure of it.
Oh, you misremembered, did you?
It's true.
My memories were confused
because of the accident.
By my deduction,
Tsutsumi-san closed his umbrella
so he could get into your car.
Am I wrong?
What do you mean?
When I arrived at the scene,
the car's dome lights were on.
Hey, you!
Are you okay?
When you returned to your
car to get your umbrella,
you closed the passenger side
door, turning off the dome lights.
In other words,
someone opened the passenger
side door at some point.
And for some reason,
the door was left half open.
Kikuchi-san,
why did you reach over the passenger seat
to get an umbrella in the back seat?
B-Because...
Are you sure you weren't
trying to hide the truth
because you believed the dome
lights would be evidence
that you tried to get
Tsutsumi-san into your car?
N-No.
Kikuchi-san, you called Tsutsumi-san
to this deserted street,
devoid of any security cameras.
When he arrived,
you urged him to get into your car.
After closing his umbrella so he
could get into the passenger seat,
the moment he touched the door,
you suddenly drove in reverse.
He must have received the abrasions
on his right-hand fingers then.
After momentarily stopping,
you suddenly drove toward
the dumbfounded Tsutsumi-san.
Wait.
Why did he have to back up first?
To build up the speed necessary
to kill a person by striking them with a car.
The side view mirror bent
forward on the passenger side
is proof that the car reversed.
The mirror must have hit Tsutsumi-san's
body while he was reversing.
After hitting Tsutsumi-san,
you exited the car with the suicide
note you prepared in your hand.
Then you hid it in
Tsutsumi-san's jacket pocket,
returned to your car,
and pretended to be unconscious.
That's the full story.
I-It certainly does make sense.
But do you have proof?
That's not enough to definitively
say I'm a murderer, right?
He's right.
With all the circumstantial evidence,
it's impossible to pin the
murder on Kikuchi-san.
There is proof.
Look at the note found
on Tsutsumi-san's body.
What is it?
Look closely at the paper.
Don't you think it's too clean?
If Tsutsumi-san had been struck
with the note in his pocket,
the paper should be more crumpled.
Now that you mention it, you're right.
Next, the note is wet in an unnatural way.
You're right.
Some sections aren't wet.
What does this mean?
It means the note was made water resistant.
Why would that be necessary for a note?
It wasn't the note itself.
It's more likely that because it was kept alongside something water resistant,
the water repellent was transferred onto it.
Detective Takagi,
could you search the dashboard
in Kikuchi-san's car?
Got it.
I found something!
It's car wax and a towel he
probably used to wipe it.
Kikuchi-san,
you waxed your car today, didn't you?
The fact that only your right sleeve
is repelling the rain proves it.
If the blue fibers on the note
match the fibers of the towel,
we'll know for sure if you hid the note
in Tsutsumi-san's pocket.
You were probably hoping the rain
would wash away the evidence,
but it ended up working against you.
When he was laid off,
he told our superior all kinds of stories,
and got me caught up in it.
What?
Tsutsumi!
Why did you tell those lies?!
Because of you, I...
I didn't have a reason.
I just wanted to bring
someone down with me.
You ruined my life just for that?!
Well, now that we've both been fired,
let's be friends.
Right, buddy?
My life was thrown out of
whack because of his whim.
I couldn't forgive him!
Now we can finally eat dinner.
Yeah.
It's raining again.
Huh? Where's my umbrella?
Huh?
Oh, right!
I left it at the bus stop!
I'll hurry back and...
What a classic case of "danger
past, God forgotten."
Episode Preview
If you hadn't tagged along,
this would've been the best drive ever.
Ran-neechan asked me to come.
I'm glad you seem to be over it.
All thanks to you, Mori-san.
This is where I wanted to take you.
An amusement park?
Then what was their motive?
Turning Point on a Driving Date
The next episode of Conan is
"Turning Point on a Driving Date!"
Ferris Wheel
Next Conan's hint!
A Ferris wheel!
You're going on a date with
the beautiful woman who solved a case?
Don't miss the next episode.
I'll be there, too.
Damn you, Ran.