This is the perfect place for a drive!
Nakanishi Kei
Resort Inn Employee
The locals are proud of this place.
It's an impressive two-lane road, too.
You chose the perfect day for your visit.
If you hadn't tagged along, this
would've been the best drive ever.
Ran-neechan asked me to come.
She asked me to make sure
you didn't cut loose too much.
I'm just having Nakanishi
Kei-san show me around.
Are you sure?
Inside the car — fun conversation
Lunch — warm up to each other
Amusement park? — build excitement!
Sunset at the beach — passionate conversation
You brat! Give that back!
You stole this, didn't you?
You dropped it on the ground.
What's a "passionate conversation," anyway?
You drew a heart next to it.
It's, well...
That's hilarious.
What?
I'm glad you seem to be over it.
All thanks to you, Mori-san.
You were unusually helpful
for once during her case.
It was the very first time.
Hey, you idiot!
Mister, the light's green.
Oh, whoops.
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
I'm the third wheel on a three-person drive.
Where will the cheerful conversation lead us?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Turning Point on a Driving Date
"Turning Point on a Driving Date!"
It was six months ago, right?
Yeah.
When I went to Haido-kitamachi for work,
I happened to come across it.
A woman named Kirisaki Remi was
found hanging in her own apartment.
Kirisaki Remi (30)
Kei's Neighbor
Fukurai Kiyomi (58)
Apartment Landlady
She moved in three months ago.
She'd been mentioning all the time
since then that she wanted to die.
She said the same thing to me several times.
On top of the landlady and
Nakanishi Kei-san's testimony,
Will
I'm tired of living, so I'm
going to the other world
Kirisaki Remi
they found a note left by the woman.
It was clearly a suicide.
The signature even matched the lease she
signed when she moved into the apartment.
But concerning her neighbor's
death, Kei-san said...
It's my fault.
I couldn't prevent her suicide.
Don't blame yourself.
But...
She's the one who made the final
decision to commit suicide.
It's not your fault.
Mori-san's words saved me.
So I sent him a thank you letter.
Right now I'm helping out at the resort
inn operated by my uncle and his wife.
It's a great place with
mountains and beaches.
If you're ever in the area,
I hope you'll stop by.
So that's why you shamelessly showed up here.
Shamelessly?
Whoops.
What's going on? There
wasn't any traffic before.
But, Kei-san, why did Kirisaki-san's
suicide bother you so much?
You were just neighbors, right?
Yes, but...
The two of them were good friends.
How did you know that?
About a week later, I
returned to the apartment.
I wanted to see how you were doing.
But you'd already moved by then.
I had been planning to move
since before the incident.
Yeah, the landlady told me.
That's when she told me about the fire, too.
So that's how you knew.
The fire?
There was a small fire near the apartment.
Fire, fire!
There's a fire!
Kirisaki
Fire!
Where's the fire?
Huh?
She was surprised to see you
come out of Kirisaki-san's room.
While I was visiting,
Kirisaki-san left when she realized
she had forgotten something.
And you ended up holding down the fort.
Since they were used to coming and going
from each other's rooms, it's no surprise.
It's only natural you were shocked
by Kirisaki-san's suicide.
Whoops!
Watch where you're going, idiot!
What's that look for?
Bleh to you!
Come on. Kids don't even do that these days.
But why did Kirisaki Remi-san
want to kill herself?
I asked her, too, but...
The day after the article on her
suicide appeared in the paper,
a man visited the apartment.
You're sure it was her, right?
Y-Yes.
Kamatari Eiji (32)
Financial Company Employee
So this is where that debt-avoiding
woman fled to this time?
In other words, she killed
herself because she was tired
of running from debt collectors all the time.
Really?
Thanks to you, I finally learned the truth.
He's just conveying the landlady's story.
I know even more.
Since two years ago, she'd
been using a fake names.
Hayashi Mayuko, Wada Miyuki, Inuyama Kaori.
She'd been using all kinds of names!
And even though that brassy woman
wouldn't pay off her debts,
she'd play pachinko all the time!
She'd been using fake names
since two years earlier?
Then why did she use her real
name to rent that apartment?
Don't ask me.
And mister, "brassy" doesn't
match the description
given by Kei-san and the landlady.
It was definitely Kirisaki Remi.
The relatives the police called confirmed
it was her and took the body.
Then it couldn't have been a stand-in.
What an interesting boy.
He's just a cheeky brat.
Huh?
Oh, there's a police checkpoint?
Sorry to bother you while you're in a hurry.
Yamazumi Tan (35)
Police Officer
There was a robbery in the city.
Oh!
The culprit was a mustachioed well-built man,
who fled in a white sedan!
That fits perfectly.
You'll get out of the car without
any resistance, won't you?
N-No, wait! I'm...
Hello?
What? He abandoned the car?
You hear that?
I'm God's gift to detectives, Mori Kogoro!
The famous detective?
S-Sorry!
Looks like we got away.
Don't say it like that!
You two make a good duo.
Looks like a two hour wait.
I'll see what I can do.
I know the owner.
We can eat somewhere else.
You're that guy from earlier.
Wh-Whoa!
Bleh!
Huh?
That's all he wanted to do?
All that trouble just
for that? What an idiot.
Ouch...
That was some drive.
You were mistaken for a
robber, and even the sky...
It's because we were talking
about that apartment.
Huh?
The place is cursed.
The apartment is cursed?
Normally, you rent an apartment
through a real estate agent.
But Kirisaki Remi asked
the landlady directly.
"Do you have any open rooms?"
She was drawn to that apartment.
"If you're going to kill
yourself, do it here."
It was just a coincidence.
Kei-san fell victim to it, too.
She came back here six months ago,
but she had planned to
return after three months.
But just before she was supposed to move...
My uncle is postponing the opening
of his resort inn by three months.
You wouldn't have a job
if you went home now.
It's fine if you want to stay
here for three more months.
Oh, someone new is moving in
next door to you tomorrow.
Really? I hope they're a nice person.
Just after her plans changed,
Kirisaki Remi moved in and killed
herself three months later.
In other words, if things had gone
according to her original plan,
she could've avoided the pain
of her neighbor's suicide.
The apartment stopped Kei-san to inflict
that painful experience on her.
What are you talking about?
What? Oh, nothing.
How did it go?
We're good to go.
I explained someone important
to me is visiting from Tokyo.
Important?
That was good.
Thanks for the food.
Anyway, Mori-san,
this is where I wanted to take you next.
An amusement park? That sounds fun.
And I recommend this attraction.
I'll go get some tea.
Why do they have to have this
thing way out in the boonies?
This really is turning
into the best drive ever.
Dream Realized After 10 Years of Planning
"Ten years ago we planned to
open on our silver anniversary."
This is the resort inn Kei-san works at.
Huh? But didn't she just say...?
What's going on?
It was so sunny until a minute ago.
It's just a passing shower.
I hope you're right.
It really did pass.
The view is wonderful after rain, too.
I wish it had kept raining.
What was Kirisaki Remi-san like?
That again?
I told you, she was a brassy woman.
That's not what I meant.
I mean her appearance.
She had long permed hair.
How about glasses?
No, she didn't wear them.
Was she fat?
She was on the thin side.
Thinner than you?
About the same, I think.
Was she taller than you? Shorter?
I think we were about the same height, too.
But why?
I know.
Why are you asking now?
That's it, Mori-san.
Whoa!
Yikes, it's huge.
I'm sure of it.
That suicide was...
That brat stole her from me.
Kei-san, do you have a boyfriend?
I used to.
But he died three years ago
of an illness.
Being in Tokyo reminded me of him,
so I decided to come back here.
We're finally alone together...
Are you sure we should've
left Conan-kun alone?
It couldn't be helped.
It's a two-person boat.
Amusement park? — build excitement!
Build excitement! Build excitement!
Are you okay?
Oh, I'm totally fine.
Probably, anyway.
Then what was her motive?
The next stop is my number
one recommendation.
The bluffs at Shikabanezaki.
It's nearly time.
Sunset at the beach — passionate conversation
We've got to finish the day on the beach.
There had to be something
big to make her go that far.
They must've caught him.
Looks like it.
Sorry again for the trouble we caused,
but we managed to catch him.
I thought the culprit had a mustache.
I disguised myself with a fake mustache.
Don't brag about it!
Hmph.
Well-built.
No matter how much you disguise yourself,
there's no disguising your build.
Well, yeah.
Huh? What?
In any case, let's head to the
finish line at Shikabanezaki.
Yeah.
This beauty is enough to cleanse your soul.
It sure is.
There's no room for evil thoughts here.
Thank you for today.
No, thank you.
Damn it. There's no time to think anymore.
He's the driver.
In that case...
Let's go back to Tokyo.
I can't leave now!
All these mysteries are ruining my mood.
Huh?
What mysteries?
Kirisaki Remi-san moved in next door
just after you delayed your plans
to come back here by three months, right?
And she didn't find the place
through a real estate agent.
She asked the landlady directly.
And she'd been using fake
names for two years,
so why did she rent the
apartment under her real name?
Since she left a writing sample on the lease,
they knew she had written
the suicide note, too.
So, what?
Yeah.
Since her relatives confirmed
the identity of the body,
we know it was Kirisaki Remi-san,
but the descriptions of her don't match.
Since Kei-san came out of
Kirisaki-san's room during the fire,
we know Kei-san was coming and
going from Kirisaki-san's room.
But with the exception of
their hairstyles and glasses,
they had really similar builds, right?
So, what?
I don't see what's so strange about that.
The strangest thing is
why you delayed your plans to
come back here by three months.
Her uncle delayed his plans
to open the resort inn, so—
But look.
Huh?
It's an article about Kei-san's uncle.
It says they planned ten years ago to open
on the day of their silver
anniversary, and they did just that.
So the opening wasn't delayed.
Which means Kei-san
delayed her return here
by three months for her own reasons, right?
And during those three months...
Could it be?
But when you think of it that
way, then everything is...
Hello?
Yes, until the fire,
I had no idea Nakanishi-san
and Kirisaki-san were friends.
After all, I had never
seen them together before.
It's true.
The woman who hanged herself in the room
next to yours was definitely
Kirisaki Remi-san.
But she never...
No.
Nobody ever lived in that room.
You saw through my lies.
But why did you do it?
A grudge from three years ago.
I had a fiancé.
His name was Ogawa Natsuyuki.
When I visited his apartment that
day, he was collapsed on the floor.
I quickly called an ambulance, but...
Because of an illegally parked car,
the ambulance couldn't
make it to his apartment.
Ogawa Natsuyuki (29)
Kei's Boyfriend
Kei...
Kei.
I'm here. I'm right here!
He died before we reached the hospital.
I heard it was too late by the
time the ambulance arrived.
But I still thought he may have been
saved if that car hadn't been there.
But it seriously sucks.
Yeah, they never answered their phone.
I had to say something to the car's owner.
But she said...
He was just never meant to
live long in the first place.
Idiot!
And that was Kirisaki Remi-san.
She mocked you and your fiancé.
Three years later, you saw
Kirisaki-san somewhere.
It was three days before I
was going to move back here.
Anzai
She used fake names because she
was engaged in some shady business.
She was a nasty woman.
You knew then that you couldn't
leave Tokyo like that.
First you had to get revenge
for three years earlier.
Yes.
That's when you thought the best way
to get away with murder was
to make it look like a suicide.
So you delayed your return here
and became Kirisaki Remi-san.
What?
Isn't that room empty?
You rented the room next to yours.
Oh, someone new is moving in
next door to you tomorrow.
Really? I hope they're a nice person.
Within one apartment, you played both
Nakanishi Kei and Kirisaki Remi.
I want to die.
Don't say that, Kirisaki-san.
You began dropping hints so they
would think it's a suicide.
When the fire happened, you probably...
Fire, fire!
There's a fire!
Kirisaki
Fire!
Where's the fire?!
What?
...had removed your disguise and were
about to return to your room.
After three months of planning,
you approached Kirisaki Remi-san.
You're using a fake name, but
you're Kirisaki Remi-san, right?
Who are you?
There's something I'd like to discuss.
You created an excuse to secretly bring
her to the neighboring apartment.
You made it look like a suicide
and left a suicide note.
You probably called the
landlord of the apartment
she lived in and asked them
to dispose of her belongings,
since she'd suddenly decided to move.
You're right.
Will you take me to the police, Mori-san?
Yes.
The sun has set completely.
It may have set today,
but it will rise tomorrow.
Haido Police Station
Huh? Hey, whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
I just brought in a suspect!
Hey, wait!
Wait! I-I'm helping the police!
Hey!
I knew it would end like this.
Episode Preview
Wow, it's amazing.
What is it, Professor?
Something good's happening after this, right?
It's almost Christmas, so I thought we could
use this 10 thousand yen gift certificate...
Wh-What was that scream?
It came from the stairs.
The Detectives in a Grove
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Detectives in a Grove, Part One!
Christmas Present
Next Conan's hint!
A Christmas present!
Don't miss the next episode.
Mister, do you have a fear of needles?
Why?
Because that's a no parking point.
Hey, you little brat!