What?
Meal tickets?
Did you win them in a lottery again?
Wow!
You're so lucky, Professor.
I thought we could go to
the high-class restaurant
on the top floor of the
Beika Department Store.
All right!
Don't celebrate yet.
You've got another good
thing waiting for you.
What?
What is it?
Tell us.
It's a secret.
What?
No way!
Don't be so mean!
If Sera is Akai-san's sister,
then why did she return
to Japan from America?
To confirm his death since she heard he
was dead? Is that why she approached me?
Because I have ties to the FBI?
Then she should be investigating me more.
Which means that middle school girl
Sera's hiding in her hotel room
must have something to do with it.
Her name is probably Mary.
A girl who looks a lot like Sera who calls
herself "The Sister From Another Domain."
No...
More than Sera, she looks like...
What is it?
Lost in thought?
Yeah, sort of.
Why do you have bags under your eyes?
Last night I found a cockroach
just before going to bed.
It took until four in
morning to get rid of it.
R-Really?
The professor went to
sleep before me, though.
Well? What were you thinking about?
Oh, nothing.
I was just wondering what kind of
lunch a high-class restaurant serves.
Oh, really?
You're rather carefree, aren't you?
Sorry.
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
There's a lot to think about.
But lunch comes first until there's a case.
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Detectives in a Grove
(Part One)
"The Detectives in a Grove, Part One!"
Wow! It's amazing!
The department store is
decked out for Christmas!
Wow!
It's kind of exciting!
Hey, it's Santa Claus!
He's handing out balloons!
Let's go get some.
Yeah!
Merry Christmas.
Thanks.
Thank you!
Hey, the elevator is over there.
It sure is crowded since
Christmas is coming up.
Ai-chan, look.
They're doing people's makeup over there.
Oh, yeah.
They're doing makeup demonstration sales.
This mascara is nice.
It's perfect for a Christmas date.
You're right.
Mascara...
That looks fun.
Hey, the professor is calling us.
You're too young for that stuff anyway.
What? You can't do it?
What, then?
Are you saying we're not customers?
We could do your mother's makeup.
h-Hey, Ai-kun.
Just do something quick for her.
Her mother will get here soon.
Uh, okay.
Have a seat, please.
Okay.
H-How do I look?
Do we look different?
Y-Yeah.
It's...
Beautiful.
Yeah, it certainly is different.
Um, where's your mother?
She died right after I was born.
What?
Now let's go to lunch, Yoshida-san.
Okay.
H-Hey, wait!
Are you guys going to the
restaurant looking like that?
Hey!
They didn't even buy anything.
I'm stuffed.
I couldn't eat another bite.
The portions were just the right size, too.
Yeah.
Well, the six of us did share
three adult-sized meals.
They washed off their makeup.
What is it, Professor?
Something good's happening after this, right?
What is it?
I actually won a gift certificate
to this department store,
in addition to the meal tickets.
Whoa.
Seriously?
Wow.
It's almost Christmas, so I thought we could
use this ten thousand yen gift
certificate to buy presents for you.
Huh? Where did they go?
Over there.
I've always wanted a telescope.
I want a baseball glove and bat.
I want a big stuffed animal.
Well, actually...
What I won was a ten thousand yen...
Maybe I'll go check out the
new Fusae brand clutches.
Ai-kun, you, too?
Did you call for me, sir?
Are you the chef here?
Yes, sir. I'm the head chef here.
Hosogoe Ujiyasu (47)
Head Chef
Is there a problem with the food?
Actually, my husband is insisting
the secret ingredient in this soup is miso.
Yes, it's Haccho miso.
I'm impressed that you noticed.
See? I was right.
That's amazing.
Chef.
We received another
call from that customer.
Ah, the one with the weird voice?
They said they're here at
the department store today,
and want to speak with you in person.
We can't let them start a commotion
here in the restaurant.
Tell them we'll talk in the stairway
next to the restaurant in thirty minutes.
Yes, Chef.
I guess we should look for those kids.
There's no need for that.
I've been receiving tons
of messages telling us
to come right away because
they found what they wanted.
They all sent pictures, too.
Let's see.
Genta's on the seventh floor where
the sporting goods store is.
Mitsuhiko's on the fifth floor
where the camera store is.
Ayumi-chan's on the fourth
floor where the toy store is.
And Haibara's on the first floor where
the bags and brand-name products are.
Everyone's expecting me
to buy them something.
What's wrong, Shinichi?
Nothing. I was just thinking
it's been thirty minutes.
What was that scream?
It came from the stairs.
Let me through!
Isn't he the chef of the
restaurant we were just at?
Are you okay? Hang in there.
The culprit... ran downstairs...
Professor, call an ambulance and the police.
Got it.
Guys, can you hear me?
Someone was just stabbed at the
tenth floor restaurant area.
The culprit is currently
fleeing down the stairs.
If you're near the stairs,
check to see if anyone's running down them.
Haibara, explain the situation to
the department store reception desk
and tell them to stop any customers
who are short of breath from leaving.
Got it.
The rest of you just look at the culprit.
Remember their face, clothes, and
distinguishing characteristics.
Got it? They tried to kill someone.
There's no telling what they'll
do if they think you know.
Whatever you do, don't try anything!
Got it!
So, at Conan-kun's direction,
these three are the ones
who were caught at the
exit in a hurry to leave.
All three of you seem rather sweaty.
I-I was looking for a bathroom.
Kamaya Takashi (26)
Part-time Worker
The bathrooms on every floor were full.
I was stopped while trying to
go to a nearby convenience store,
so I could use their bathroom.
What about you?
I was looking for my wallet.
Shikama Mitsuko (38)
Housewife
I thought I might've left it somewhere,
so I've been running around all
the shops I stopped at today.
Did you find your wallet?
What? Yes.
When I took a closer look,
I found it inside my bag.
What about you?
I had Thai food at the restaurant area here.
I'm a chef, so I was here
to study the flavors.
Miyadai Masaru (52)
Chef
The sautéed vegetables I had
were particularly spicy.
I couldn't stop sweating,
so I was hurrying home to take a shower.
All three of them do have
a reason for being a hurry.
That leaves the testimony of the three kids
who say they saw the culprit.
Don't worry.
They didn't see their face,
but they say the remember the culprit's
distinguishing characteristics.
Right?
Yeah.
We sure did.
We got a good look.
They were pretty small.
They had the number 2 on their
clothes, which were gray.
It was the same color as
what Haibara's wearing.
You're wrong.
What?
They were on the larger side, and
they were wearing dark gray clothes.
They had a masculine run, too.
No, they were small!
They probably just looked
big because you're so small!
No, I'm sure of it.
It was a large man.
I thought it was a woman.
They were wearing gray clothes
so light they were almost white.
They were average height, just a
little taller than the professor.
Wait a minute...
I said they were small!
This is a problem.
They were definitely big.
All their stories are totally different.
No, it was a woman.
It was definitely a small
person wearing gray clothes.
No, it was a large man
wearing dark gray clothes.
It was a woman a little taller than the
professor wearing light gray clothes.
Um, to summarize what you told us...
The culprit who stabbed Hosogoe-san
around these stairs on the
tenth floor restaurant area...
According to Genta-kun, who
was on the seventh floor,
was a smaller person with the
number 2 on their clothes,
which were a gray color
similar to Ai-chan's clothes.
Yeah.
According to Mitsuhiko-kun,
who was on the fifth floor,
it was a large person with a masculine run,
wearing dark gray clothes.
That's right.
And according to Ayumi-chan,
who was on the fourth floor,
it was a woman slightly taller than Agasa-san,
wearing light gray clothes.
Yeah.
But all three of the people
who were stopped
from leaving the department
store are wearing gray.
Yes, although the shades are different.
Kamaya-san, you're wearing a gray
similar to Ai-chan's clothes,
like Genta-kun described.
Y-You can't be serious.
I seriously was just looking
for an empty bathroom stall.
What's this?
You seem to have injured the
fingers on your right hand.
Oh, I sprained it.
I was in a hurry and hit the bathroom door.
A-Anyway, the other two kids
said it was a darker and lighter gray.
And that fat kid said they had
the number 2 on their clothes,
but mine...
Beika
Look. It's only got Chinese characters on it.
You're right.
Then the person wearing light
gray like Ayumi-chan described...
W-Wait a minute.
Didn't I tell you?
I was running around the shops I visited
today while looking for my wallet.
But the wallet was in your bag, right?
Why were you in such a hurry to leave?
I was in a hurry because I remembered the
TV drama I missed was airing a rerun tonight.
Do you have a cold?
Yes. It was getting better.
But I got cold after running
around and sweating.
It might be coming back.
There's no number 2 on your clothes either.
The brooch on your chest
does resemble a number.
Not a 2, but a 6.
Miyadai-san, that leaves you,
who's wearing dark gray clothes
like Mitsuhiko-kun described.
Wait a minute.
I wasn't lying when I said I was sweating
because of the spicy food
I ate, and was in a hurry
to leave so I could go
home and take a shower.
I actually came here
because I heard rumors
that the Thai restaurant here
serves a soup that tastes like ours.
Did you come to make a complaint, then?
Well, yeah.
I tried it but didn't think
it tasted that similar,
so I left without saying anything.
I see.
By the way, there seems to be something
written on the back of your jacket.
Yes, but it's not a number.
The Tokyo Spirits, huh?
Um, you seem to be fidgeting with your feet.
I have athlete's foot.
I'd like to get home soon so
I can put some medicine on it.
Then there's the reason why Ayumi-kun
thought the culprit was a woman.
Why did you think that?
Well...
I just thought they were a woman.
You...
You just did?
Inspector Megure!
We just learned the victim Hosogoe-san
has connections to those three.
What?
Kamaya-san worked at a
restaurant where the victim
was the head chef until two years ago.
But his attitude during work
was bad, so he was fired.
Shikama-san lives in the
apartment next to the victim's.
Apparently, they frequently got in arguments
because her dog barked too loudly.
And three years ago,
Miyadai-san created a commotion
when he claimed the victim
ripped off his food.
The local police had to show up.
I see.
It sounds like we'll need to question
the three of you more thoroughly.
Before you do,
could you ask the three of
them if they have gloves?
Gloves?
Yeah.
The culprit's fingerprints
weren't on the weapon, right?
If the culprit used gloves and
the victim's blood got on them,
I would've thrown them away if I'd done it.
Well?
I have some.
So do I.
It is cold out.
There doesn't seem to
be blood on any of them.
According to the coroner,
the victim was bleeding because he
tried to remove the knife himself.
It's possible the culprit
didn't get much blood on him.
I see.
How is the victim doing?
He's out of surgery,
but he's still not awake.
In any case,
we'll be questioning the three
of you in a separate room.
Us, too.
You can't.
This is the police's job.
What?
Seriously?
Why won't they let us
watch the investigation?
It's not surprising considering
your random descriptions.
They weren't random.
I saw it.
We're not lying.
Now, now, now.
Genta, are you sure the culprit you saw
was small, had a number
2 on their clothes,
and was wearing clothes the
same color as Haibara's?
Yeah.
Then how come you couldn't
see the culprit's face?
B-Because I was in the sporting goods area
where some basketball players
taking the stairs got in the way.
Basketball players?
Oh, them?
That was the Haido High basketball team.
Their new uniforms were
just completed today,
so the entire team came to pick them up.
I see.
They're all so tall, they looked like adults.
But when they got their uniforms,
they happily put them on over their clothes.
They were excitedly talking like kids
about how they'd wear them home today.
Do you know what the uniforms looked like?
Yeah, I sure do.
I took a picture of them to commemorate it.
See?
They're the same gray as the
clothes Ai-kun is wearing.
Yeah.
Yeah, the culprit was wearing
the same gray color.
They quickly passed in front
of the basketball players
heading for the stairs and went down.
Could the basketball players
have seen the culprit, too?
Maybe not.
What?
I shouted at them to move,
so they were all looking at me.
But basketball uniforms have
numbers on them, right?
Then maybe you mistook someone
on the basketball team wearing
number 2 for the culprit.
I didn't make a mistake!
He was the only one running!
But if there were numbers everywhere...
No, Genta definitely saw the number 2.
There's no number 1, 2, or 3 in basketball.
See?
What? Why not?
Basketball refs use their fingers to
identify players who violate the rules.
But they also use their fingers to indicate
one point for free throws, two for regular shots,
and three for three pointers.
Because it's confusing, the
International Basketball Federation
decided not to use numbers 1 through 3.
Really?
But none of those three
were wearing the number 2.
Yeah, that's the thing.
If only you'd taken pictures of the culprit.
Then you should've said so.
Huh?
Genta, your hands are full
with a bat and glove.
Who took this picture?
The basketball players I mentioned earlier.
I see.
Looks like Mitsuhiko and
Haibara took selfies.
Ayumi-chan, you didn't take
yours yourself, did you?
Nope.
A nice lady working at the
toy store took it for me.
When I told her I got a message
from you saying the culprit
who stabbed someone was
coming down the stairs,
she showed me where they were.
Then that employee...
...may have also...
...seen the culprit.
In any case, let's go to the toy store.
Yeah.
Hey, the elevator is on the other side.
It's busy. The stairs will be faster.
Episode Preview
So who's the culprit?
The culprit slipped between
these mannequins and signs.
How's this?
Ai-chan, the button on your clothes.
But I saw a 2.
What's wrong? Is there something on my face?
The Detectives in a Grove
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Detectives in a Grove, Part Two!"
Mannequin
Next Conan's hint!
A mannequin!
The next episode is on Christmas Eve.
Don't miss the next episode.
Merry Christmas!
These presents are killing me.