With the meal tickets Professor
Agasa won in a lottery,
we came to a high class
restaurant on the top floor
of the Beika Department Store.
However, the restaurant's
chef was gravely injured
when he was stabbed in
the stomach by someone.
I immediately contacted the Detective Boys,
who were scattered throughout
the department store,
and instructed them to look
for the culprit, but...
That leaves the testimony of the three
kids who say they saw the culprit.
Don't worry.
They didn't see their face,
but they say they remember the culprit's
distinguishing characteristics.
They were pretty small.
They had the number 2 on their
clothes, which were gray.
It was the same color as
what Haibara's wearing.
You're wrong.
What?
They were on the larger side,
and they were wearing dark gray clothes.
They had a masculine run, too.
I thought it was a woman.
They were wearing gray clothes
so light they were almost white.
They were average height, just a
little taller than the professor.
Wait a minute...
I said they were small!
This is a problem.
They were definitely big.
All their stories are totally different.
No, it was a woman.
A canvas stained black with crime.
With brilliant detective
skills, its color is changed!
First, Merry Christmas!
Will we be able to solve the mystery
of the inconsistent testimonies?
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Detectives in a Grove
(Part Two)
"The Detectives in a Grove, Part Two!"
Hey, Conan!
Wait!
What?
What's wrong, Mitsuhiko?
When I saw the culprit,
these mannequins were near
the fifth floor stairs.
I just remembered I saw
the culprit slip between
the mannequins as they
headed down the stairs!
Mister, were those really on the fifth floor?
Yeah, about ten of them.
We're holding a children's uniform
fair in the sporting goods area,
so we're moving the mannequins
to the seventh floor
from the fifth floor storage room.
The fifth floor used to be a toy store
that sold children's clothes, too.
Really?
I moved four or five spare signs
up to the seventh floor, too,
so I'm exhausted.
Even though the service
elevator is being inspected,
the floor manager told me to hurry.
That's right.
I couldn't see the culprit from the neck up
because the signs were blocking my view.
Then can't we determine the
culprit's approximate height
by looking at the signs?
But there were tall ones and short ones,
and I don't remember which sign it was.
Were the mannequins the same as that one?
Yes, although they were all kind of white.
Were the signs white, too?
Yes.
It looked like something had been
pasted to the front at one point,
but it was torn off.
In any case, let's hurry to the
toy store on the fourth floor.
That employee could be our
most reliable witness.
Y-Yeah.
Sorry.
You're talking about when I took
this girl to the stairs, right?
I was running, so my contacts
slipped out of place.
I only saw a fuzzy image.
I-I see. That's too bad.
Do you remember anything that happened then?
Even something indistinct could help.
Well...
The girl and I waited behind the wall
near the stairs for the
culprit to come down.
When they first appeared,
they were back lit by the window
and appeared as a silhouette.
I doubt she saw them clearly either.
But it looked like the culprit stopped
in front of the window for a little bit.
Th-They stopped?
Right?
Yeah.
It looked like they were removing something
stuck to the bottom of their left shoe.
What was it?
I'm not sure.
Maybe it was chewing gum.
I don't know.
Even if it were chewing gum,
they probably already
threw it away somewhere.
The culprit came down the
stairs after that, right?
Did you see their face?
No.
I tried, but a bunch of
middle or high school boys
came up the stairs.
The culprit ran past as they did,
so I didn't get a good look.
Huh?
How did you know they were
middle or high school students?
They were all wearing the same clothes.
The same clothes?
Yeah.
Now that you mention it,
a group of high school students on
a school trip came to buy souvenirs.
They reminded me of the high
school cheerleader I liked.
In my case, even flirty students
would cover up with stand-up collars,
and look like straight-laced cheerleaders.
Hidden but seen?
Then those students must've
seen the culprit, too.
Do you know which high school they were from?
I'm not sure.
A few of them were here until a moment ago.
Damn it.
If we knew what school they attended,
we might've known who the culprit was.
It's all right.
I don't think that's necessary anymore.
Right, Detective?
Yeah, I solved the mystery.
I know why your testimonies
were all different.
And who the culprit is.
Inspector, we found it.
You did?
Yes, sir.
We found the helium gas can the
culprit used to change their voice
when they called the victim's
restaurant in the shrubbery
next to a phone booth
near the department store.
Then after calling the
restaurant on the tenth floor
of the department store
using the payphone,
they hurried to the stairs
next to the restaurant,
stabbed Hosogoe-san when he came
to deal with the complaint,
and fled down the stairs.
Yes, sir.
Forensics is examining the
phone booth and can right now.
But since the culprit's fingerprints
weren't on the knife,
we're not expecting to
find them there either.
Which means we'll have to wait until
the victim regains consciousness.
It's okay.
We know who did it based on their testimony.
What?
Right, Professor?
Y-Yeah.
But, Conan-kun...
The suspects who attempted
to flee the department store
are the small Shikama Mitsuko-san
who is wearing light gray clothes,
and has a brooch resembling
the number 6 on her chest.
Shikama Mitsuko (38)
Housewife
The large Miyadai Masaru-san
wearing a dark gray jacket,
with the Tokyo Spirits logo
printed on the back.
Miyadai Masaru (52)
Chef
And the medium sized Kamaya Takashi-san,
wearing a neither light nor dark gray jacket,
Kamaya Takashi (26)
Part-time Worker
with the characters for Beika on the back.
But your testimonies were
all over the place.
Nobody was a perfect match.
Want to try it, then?
Try it?
Yeah.
Then you'll realize their
inconsistent testimonies
all point to the same person.
We'll start at the seventh floor
stairs where the sporting goods are.
Genta, you saw the culprit running
down the stairs here, right?
Yeah.
Hey.
Uh, who are they?
The basketball players that were
with Genta when he saw the culprit.
We called them and asked them to come.
I see.
Genta, could you describe
the culprit you saw again?
Got it.
They were on the smaller
side, wearing clothes
the same gray as Haibara, and had
the number 2 on their clothes.
Detective Chiba, could you go
stand by the basketball players?
S-Sure.
Detective Chiba is a little
chubby and average height,
slightly taller than the professor.
Ch-Chubby?
See?
When he's surrounded by the
tall basketball players,
doesn't he look small?
You're right.
The impression you have of an object
is influenced by the size of
the objects surrounding it.
Even if they're the same size,
they look like different sizes.
I see.
Next...
Detective Chiba, could you hold Haibara
and hide behind the basketball players?
O-Okay.
Excuse me.
Hide him a little more.
The buttons on Ai-chan's clothes
look like the number three.
You're right.
If you hid both sides of her buttons,
it would look like the number 8.
The basketball uniforms and
Haibara's clothes are both gray,
and the area is full of numbers,
which is why it looks that way.
But I saw the number 2.
So who's the culprit?
We need to go to the next floor to find out.
Next are the fifth floor stairs by the
camera shop where Mitsuhiko saw the culprit.
Is this right?
Yes, this is more or less how it was.
This time the area's full
of mannequin children.
There are a lot of signs, too.
The culprit slipped between
these mannequins and signs.
We asked a department store
employee to put them back
where they were when
Mitsuhiko saw the culprit.
I see.
Mitsuhiko, what did the
culprit you saw look like?
They were a rather large person wearing
dark gray clothes with a masculine run.
Detective Chiba, could you
stand next to the mannequins?
Since this is the opposite
of the last scenario,
I know I look like a larger person when
I'm standing in the middle of them.
Okay.
Haibara, could you stand in front
of the short sign over there?
Yeah, yeah.
How's this?
Hey, Haibara's clothes...
They look darker than before.
You're right.
The mannequins and signs
are a bright white color,
so Haibara's clothes look darker.
Just like the sizes of objects, colors are
also influenced by their surrounding colors.
Contrast of Value
This is called "contrast of value."
Right, Professor Agasa?
Y-Yeah.
I see.
So the clothes Mitsuhiko-kun saw
might've been a darker gray.
Yeah.
So, who's the culprit?
Let's head to the next floor.
Sheesh.
Finally there's Ayumi-chan.
She saw the culprit on the fourth
floor stairs where the toy store is.
After receiving my message,
an employee brought you here,
where you waited for the culprit
to come down the stairs, right?
Yeah.
What did they look like?
At first I only saw a black person shape
because of the light from that window,
but I had a feeling they were a woman.
Then they came down the stairs,
so I know they were wearing
light gray clothes
and of average height just a
little taller than the professor.
Around Chiba-kun's height, then.
Sorry we're late.
How can we help with the investigation?
What?
Could you stand around this girl?
Me again?
Hey, Haibara's clothes this time...
They look like a lighter gray than before.
I see it.
Opposite to the previous scenario,
colors look lighter when they're
surrounded by a dark black.
Really?
When Ayumi-chan saw the culprit,
they were running past a group of students
wearing their uniforms, so I asked
the basketball players for help.
I told them we're looking for
the person who stabbed someone,
and to tell their male friends
wearing uniforms to come here.
So, who's the culprit?
If you exclude from the testimony
that their size was influenced
by their surroundings,
the number 2 that was mistakenly seen
because of the colors and numbers,
and the uncertain testimony claiming
the culprit just seemed like a woman
That means the culprit was an average
height person slightly taller
than the professor wearing
clothes the same gray
as Haibara's with a masculine run, right?
There's only one person like that.
Th-That's it.
The culprit is...
Give me a break.
Why are you accusing me based on
the vague testimony of those kids?
There are three certain
facts among their testimony.
The culprit was slightly
taller than the professor,
wore the same gray as Ai-kun,
and had a masculine run.
Kamaya Takashi-san, you're the only person
who matches the description.
B-But there's no number 2 on my clothes,
and I'm not a woman.
Didn't these kids say that?
Kids?
Huh?
Mister, there's something on
the bottom of your left foot.
It's just gum.
I stepped on it somewhere
in the department store.
Hey, there's no gum on my shoe.
He's doing the same thing the culprit did.
What?
That's right.
When something's stuck to
the bottom of his left foot,
normally a man brings his foot out in front
of him and removes it with his right hand.
Unlike women, men's hips don't
bend outward very easily.
But you couldn't use your right hand
because of your sprained finger.
That's why you raised
your left foot behind you,
and forced yourself to remove
it with your left hand.
Ayumi-chan saw your back lit
silhouette doing that,
and intuitively thought you were a woman.
Th-That woman would do the same thing.
Try putting that backpack on your back, then.
Then we'll see the number
that identifies the culprit.
You can't do it?
Fine.
How's this?
It's a 2!
This is the 2 I saw!
Seriously?
I see.
Half of the "flower" character in Beika
was covered by the backpack
and looked like a 2.
In other words, your testimonies
were all accurate.
Yeah!
Will you come with us to the station?
W-Wait a minute.
There's still no proof that I did it.
Inspector Megure!
We found saliva on the intake
of the helium gas can.
And?
If we can collect DNA from the saliva,
we'll know who it belongs to.
Which means if that DNA is yours,
you'll be able to provide a
plausible explanation, won't you?
For why you were changing
your voice at a payphone
near this department store and who
and why you were calling them.
I thought he'd know who I was
if I didn't change my voice.
Even though I quit my job two years ago,
that chef still remembered my face.
So you stabbed him because you were fired?
I-I wouldn't stab someone over being fired!
The other day, I invited my girlfriend
to eat at that restaurant.
I didn't tell her I worked
there until two years ago.
I can't believe you knew of such
a high class place, Takashi.
Despite how I look, I'm actually a gourmand.
I watched him cook while I worked there.
Since I dyed my hair black
and shaved my beard,
I called the chef over thinking
he wouldn't recognize me.
The secret ingredient in this
marinade is honey, isn't it?
You can't fool my tongue.
But the chef...
No, it's a bit of jam.
What kind of jam is an
industry secret, though.
What?
But you used to...
Yes, previously I used honey to
tone down the sourness, but...
Huh? Are you our former
employee Kamaya-kun?
What? No, I...
I was worried I was a little hard on you.
You were crying when you quit.
A-Actually, I...
Because of him, my girlfriend
became disenchanted with me,
and dumped me.
I'd finally gotten back together with her,
but because of that chef...
Because of him...
But I didn't mean to kill him.
I just wanted to scare him by
threatening him with a knife!
He's not dead.
The hospital just called to say
that he's regained consciousness.
What?
Apparently Chef Hosogoe asked us
not to release the culprit's name
until he turned himself in
because they used to eat and work together.
He's practically telling
them who did it himself.
What a total misunderstanding.
I'm so appalled, I'm not even angry.
So, Professor.
Isn't it time...
...to give us...
...our Christmas presents?!
Oh, you remembered.
Of course!
I haven't given up on a new
Fusae brand clutch either.
Haibara, you've taken that joke far enough.
Huh?
What?
What's wrong?
Is there something on my face?
Yeah, there is.
There's something black under your eye.
No way.
It's mascara.
Jeez.
I thought I got all of
it off in the bathroom.
Haibara...
That face...
Episode Preview
What in the world happened?
What am I doing here?
I see.
And you noticed this morning?
No signal?
Safe cracking?
D-Dry ice?
Am I inside a coffin?
Conan Cornered in the Darkness
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is
"Conan Cornered in the Darkness, Part One!"
Two Tone Shoes
Next Conan's hint!
Two tone shoes!
It's been another year!
Don't miss the next episode.
Thank you!
We hope you have...
...a happy new year!
It's a promise.