Happy New Year!
Thanks to our viewers,
today "Detective Conan" is entering
its 22nd year of broadcasting.
No fair, Conan!
Let us say hello to the viewers, too!
Last year, you and Ebizo-san wished
them a Happy New Year yourselves!
Well, either way...
Shouldn't we do it together?
Fine.
Once again...
Happy New Year!
We hope you'll continue
supporting Detective Conan...
...and the Detective Boys in 2017!
Thank you very much!
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
Conan is charging forward again this year!
But where is he? In trouble!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
What in the world happened?
What am I doing here?
Conan Cornered in the Darkness
(Part One)
"Conan Cornered in the Darkness, Part One!"
I see.
It's clearly been broken into.
Asada Law Firm
And you noticed this morning?
Asada Kimihiko (55)
Lawyer
Yes.
But I was working here all last night.
It must've been broken into
when I went home to take
a nap for a couple hours.
I see.
So, what was inside the safe?
It couldn't have been money,
since you called me instead of the police.
Impressive, Mori-san.
No, it wasn't money.
It was a will.
I see.
I know who did it.
What?
But... I don't want to get
the police involved.
I see...
All right.
My eyes have gotten used to the darkness.
Am I...
inside a box?
What am I doing here, though?
My phone!
It's here.
My phone's by my feet.
Almost there...
Conan-kun's not answering.
He's not answering his phone, either.
Maybe he went to eat by himself.
I'm hungry.
He's not you, Genta-kun.
But the sale has already started.
What should we do?
Don't hang up...
Don't hang up, guys.
Damn it!
What's the meaning of this?
Why don't you want to get the police
involved when you know who did it?
Because... I'd like to avoid a scandal.
For the late chairman's sake, too.
The late chairman...
You mean the leader of the Karahashi Group,
for whom you worked as a legal
advisor, Karahashi Gotaro.
I believe he passed away three
days ago due to an illness.
Yes.
And after today's funeral,
the contents of his will
were going to be announced.
But it was stolen.
Does that mean
the contents of the will were
unfavorable for the thief?
It was ten days before he passed away.
The chairman summoned me to the
hospital where he was staying.
He wanted to rewrite his will.
I see.
We got the new one!
Conan-kun's still not here?
I'd feel bad for him if he
couldn't buy a copy of the game.
Yeah.
He'll be fine.
There were still plenty
of copies on the shelves.
I can't take it anymore!
I'm going to get something to eat!
That's it. It was those guys.
This morning I headed out with them, and...
I need to remember from the beginning.
Good morning, Conan-kun!
Morning.
This morning, we met up to buy
copies of a new game today.
On our way there, I...
What was previously written in the will?
Since his wife passed away ten years ago,
Karahashi Group
he planned to give 50% of his fortune
to his eldest son Karahashi Kozo,
Kozo
and split the remainder
between his eldest daughter
Mitsuyo and second son Eisuke.
Mitsuyo
Eisuke
What did he want to change?
Well, actually, the chairman had a secretary
who worked for him for fifty years.
He was going to give his
entire fortune to her.
Interesting.
Were he and that woman...?
Yes.
She and the chairman were close.
To put it plainly...
They were lovers.
Yes. Though...
She's currently experiencing health issues
and is being treated at a
hospital in her hometown.
I see.
And then... Yeah, that's right.
When we got there...
Hurry up, hurry up.
Is that...?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
If we don't hurry, the sale will start soon.
Let's get this over with so we can eat.
You guys go on ahead.
Conan-kun!
Where are you going?
What's wrong with him?
I knew it.
Huh? Conan's still not here?
No.
No...
He probably went to get lunch by himself.
There are still two more hours before noon.
Seriously, though, what happened to him?
I'm worried. Let's have Ai-chan look into it.
Edogawa-kun?
Got it.
I'll track his phone's GPS.
No signal?
In that case...
Uh-oh.
His spare glasses are with the
professor for maintenance.
Mori
Hello, this is the Mori Detective Agency.
Oh, Ai-chan.
What? Conan-kun?
He hasn't come back yet.
He's not with you?
No, I'm not interested in modern games.
Tell Edogawa-kun to call
me if you hear from him.
Huh? What do you mean?
Wait, Ai-chan!
Yeah, that's right.
I remember now!
Safe cracking?
I-I'm being transported somewhere.
But where...?
What's this smell?
Is that... incense?
D-Dry ice?
Am I inside a coffin?
Did they bury me?
Ai-chan!
You came!
Since he's not answering his
phone, I don't have a choice.
But we might want to contact the police.
But all the Detective Boys are here now.
Let's try looking for him
ourselves for a little bit.
And Conan might've just gone
to get lunch by himself.
Where did you part ways with him?
This way!
Is this a draft?
Which means I haven't been buried.
Then...
Isn't anyone there?
It's no use.
Then...
I'll try that.
A little more...
Just a little more...
This was the place, Ai-chan.
That's right.
This is where Conan-kun suddenly
told us to go on ahead.
There weren't any eel or hamburger vendors.
Just so you know.
But he might've seen or found something.
Like what?
We're going to search for it.
We'll split up and search this side
and the other side of the
street, little by little.
The Detective Boys are on the case!
Yeah!
I'm hungry...
Come on. Let's go, Genta-kun.
Karahashi Gotaro Funeral
M-Mori Kogoro?
Karahashi Kozo (38)
Eldest Son of the
Karahashi Family
You mean the famous detective?
Considering the circumstances and
the fact that we're short on time,
I insisted he take the case.
As he said,
I'm the detective Mori Kogoro.
It's nice to meet you.
A detective?
Karahashi Mitsuyo (32)
Eldest Daughter of
the Karahashi Family
What's the meaning of this?
You make it seem like one
of us stole the will.
Don't play dumb.
Karahashi Eisuke (28)
Second Son of the
Karahashi Family
Of course one of us
is the thief.
So, who did it?
You already know, don't you, Detective?
Well, actually, I was going
to figure that out now...
Wh-Why are you looking
at me like that, Eisuke?!
You're the one playing dumb!
I don't know what you're talking about.
Don't be ridiculous!
You want to fight, asshole?
Please stop, you two.
This isn't the place for this.
Idiots.
Kozo-niisan, you were the most angry
about the will being rewritten.
What did you say?
Mitsuyo, you were furious
over the original will.
You thought your share wasn't large enough.
Yeah.
And so was Eisuke.
Not as angry as you two.
What did you say?
What do you want?
M-Mori-san...
Please calm down, everyone.
Your father's funeral is starting soon.
Anyway, I'd like to hear
about the details later,
but there is one thing
I'd like to make clear.
Where were all of you this morning?
And do you have any way to prove it?
You're already looking into
our alibis, huh? Interesting.
You're unbelievable.
Are you happy you're being
treated like a criminal?
That's how he's always been.
Who are you going to start with, Detective?
Ahem.
We'll start with the eldest
son, Kozo-san, was it?
Would you be able to tell me
where you were this morning?
I was at home at that hour, of course.
Oh, right.
His phone call woke me up this morning.
Is that true?
Can't a detective like you get the police
or phone company to look into it?
Early this morning I received a
phone call from him at my house.
Your house?
Not your cell phone?
Yeah, but I don't know where he called from.
I called from my house.
I was woken up by a call from my sister.
I see.
So you called using your home phone, too?
I don't know where she called from, though.
She was complaining that she didn't
like the program for the funeral.
I called my brother since I couldn't stand
it, but she butted in while on hold.
Just because you're the oldest,
you took control of everything.
With your program, I doubt Papa
will be able to rest in peace.
What did you say?
And before you ask, I called
from my house phone, too.
You, too?
I only use my cell phone
while I'm out of the house.
Why don't you look into it, Detective?
I see.
I know.
If there are nails, I could
hook the rope onto one and...
Damn it. I can't see.
That's it.
Come on.
Come here.
They're all so confident.
What do you think, Mori-san?
Naturally I'll be confirming
their stories later,
but most likely...
Did he buy our alibis?
Who knows? You can't be sure.
Yeah.
One of us could've hired someone to do it.
Then I'm safe.
I can't afford that, unlike you.
Oh, really?
You'd be able to pay them once
you got your inheritance.
So would you.
All right!
It's broken...
Then...
Well? Did you find him?
Eel
That looks good...
He's not in here!
Where did Conan-kun go?
Maybe we should tell the police.
Wait.
All right.
A car?
Based on the way the sound
echoed, I must be inside.
No, in an underground parking lot.
W-Wait!
Wait!
W-Wait! Don't go!
Hey!
Damn...
Damn!
Fixing the lock?
He was called early this morning
by a resident of the building.
Is that was Conan-kun saw?
Maybe there's a really
good restaurant inside.
I guess not.
Maybe it was a thief.
It doesn't seem like they told him,
but it's conceivable.
Maybe we should call the police.
Ai-chan?
Oh, it's you, Dad.
What? A funeral?
Now?
Conan-kun!
Where in the world are you?!
Don't shout.
I don't know where I am, either.
Apparently I haven't been buried, though.
What does that mean?
Judging by the size, I must
really be inside a coffin.
Someone placed a board over stacks of
cardboard, creating a false bottom.
I'm in the small space underneath.
What? Which means...
Is there someone above me?
What?
What is this?
What's wrong?
Damn it...
I can't reach.
What are you guys doing?
We followed the alleyway you entered
to the rear entrance of a building.
That's it! That's the place!
There was a burglary happening
inside that building, and...
I-It's moving?
Then I must be inside a car, too.
A car carrying a coffin?
Is this a hearse?
Episode Preview
This is a false bottom coffin.
And someone's body is above me.
What?
Where's Conan-kun?
We found him.
Really?
He's inside a hearse right now.
A-A hearse?
Wh-What?!
Conan's inside the coffin?
And you're saying the will is inside, too?
Conan Cornered in the Darkness
(Part Two)
"Conan Cornered in the Darkness, Part Two!"
Hearse
Next Conan's hint!
A hearse!
That was awful. I was in the
dark for thirty whole minutes.
Don't miss the next episode.
Every night comes to an end.
Shut up.