When I woke up,
I was in darkness.
While on my way to buy a new game
with Ayumi, Genta, and Mitsuhiko,
I saw someone breaking into a safe.
But I was attacked and
trapped inside a coffin.
Meanwhile, Kogoro-no-occhan was hired
to find the stolen will of Karahashi Gotaro,
chairman of a corporate group,
who died three days earlier,
and the thief who stole it.
Just when I finally got in touch with
the Detective Boys using my badge,
the darkness I was trapped
inside began to move.
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
Trapped inside a dark coffin,
he can't see a way to escape.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Conan Cornered in the Darkness (Part Two)
"Conan Cornered in the Darkness, Part Two!"
What's wrong, Edogawa-kun?
Edogawa-kun!
It's a car.
This coffin is inside a car.
I'm inside a hearse.
A hearse?!
Yeah.
I smelled incense and felt
the chill of dry ice, too.
There's no mistaking it.
This is a false bottom coffin.
And someone's body is above me.
What?!
L-Let's look for him right away!
If he's in a hearse,
we'll find him in no time!
Yeah!
I'm not so sure.
What?
These days
most hearses are ordinary sedans
instead of old-fashioned hearses.
It won't be that easy to find him.
We should call the police.
Wait, Haibara!
They need more information.
There's a good chance that
place was a funeral home, so...
Got it.
I'll look into it.
Beika City Crematoriums
Let's split up and look for him.
If a funeral just ended someplace...
I see.
Conan-kun might be inside
the hearse that just left.
B-But if that's true, then
he's headed towards...
That's right.
Probably a crematorium.
A-A crematorium?
Is Conan-kun going to be incinerated?
That's why we need to hurry.
It's no use.
This one's a miss.
So was this one.
Guys!
Ran-oneesan.
Sorry.
Could you wait here for a minute?
I was so worried.
Where's Conan-kun?
We found him.
Really?
He's inside a hearse right now.
A-A hearse?
Asada Law Office
Huh? This place...
A will?
Will
What?
He hired the Sleeping Kogoro?
The lawyer Asada?
Yeah.
He came here early this morning.
Could it be related to the
robbery Conan-kun described?
Seems like it.
But he just called
to say he might be attending
the funeral with Asada-sensei.
He asked me to bring his
mourning clothes just in case.
A funeral?
Is this the place?
Yeah, this funeral home.
Huh? What?
What's wrong, guys?
Ran-oneesan, hurry!
Hurry!
We'll leave you behind!
Wh-What?!
Conan's inside the coffin?
And you're saying the will is inside, too?
R-Really?
That's what Conan-kun said.
He said it's inside a
small paulownia wood box.
Asada Kimihiko (55)
Lawyer
That's it!
That's definitely it.
We did it!
Dad, what about the funeral?
It just finished.
The hearse and his family
left for the crematorium.
What did you say?
We knew it!
No...
You've got to be joking.
Conan-kun.
Excuse me.
Y-You mean the culprit
means to incinerate the body and the will?
Without the will,
his fortune will be divided
evenly among his children.
Then who's the culprit?
What are you talking about, Dad?!
More importantly, Conan-kun
is about to be incinerated!
I know.
Apparently, that's the only hearse
that left the funeral home today.
I had them call the crematorium.
The hearse should be
getting there anytime now,
but it hasn't arrived yet.
What?
What does that mean?
Where are you right now, Edogawa-kun?
Where am I?
I wish I knew.
We stopped again.
Again?
Yeah.
We've been stopping and moving slowly,
at about one minute intervals.
Maybe they're late because
they're stopping by places
where the deceased had connections.
Karahashi Industries
From big businesses to small workshops,
the chairman was a popular man.
Connections?
Like branches and business
partners of the Karahashi Group?
Yes.
Check that out immediately.
I'll head directly to the crematorium.
If that's what they're doing,
we can easily beat them there.
Hello, Inspector.
Conan-kun.
Please let us make it.
Go faster, Mister.
Beika Funeral Hall
We did it.
We made it!
But something seems weird.
This is Mori.
This is Asada.
Mori-san, the chairman's hearse stopped
at one of our branches.
However, because of the bad weekend traffic,
they've decided to cancel
the rest of the visits
and head directly to the crematorium.
What?
They should be arriving soon.
Take a look at this.
The Karahashi family cremation
will be held in the annex.
Beika Funeral Hall
The annex?
That must be it.
Beika Funeral Hall Annex
What?!
W-Wait!
Wait!
Conan!
Conan-kun!
S-Stop the cremation?
Karahashi Mitsuyo (32)
Eldest Daughter of
the Karahashi Family
Karahashi Kozo (38)
Eldest Son of the
Karahashi Family
Karahashi Eisuke (28)
Second Son of the
Karahashi Family
What are you talking about?
That detective doesn't have a clue.
Conan-kun is inside!
There's a child inside that coffin.
Looks like you know what we're talking about.
Impossible!
Of course not!
Yeah, there's no way!
Then will you let us open the coffin?
I've been waiting for you, Inspector.
We're with Section One of the
Metropolitan Police Department.
This is a potential kidnapping.
Takagi, Chiba.
Yes, sir!
Even if you're the police, you can't do that!
Is there a problem?
Oh, no. Not really.
Is Conan-kun under the body?
Excuse us.
He's not here!
What?
In fact,
this coffin doesn't have a false bottom.
What?
No way.
What's going on, Mori-kun?
But that shouldn't be.
Hey, what's going on?
Don't ask us.
Isn't this a problem?
You'd better take responsibility for this.
W-We'll handle that another time.
Edogawa-kun?
Where are you, Edogawa-kun?
Is the signal not getting through?
Where did he go?
Conan-kun.
Haibara?
Haibara!
Damn it.
Where are we going?
What a piece of junk.
I've wasted a lot of time.
That's it.
Which means this might be...
Haibara, can you hear me?
Wh-What?
There's another hearse?
Yeah, that's what Conan-kun said.
It was probably parked in the funeral
home's underground parking lot.
Huh? Where did those kids go?
Inspector!
Takagi.
Yes, sir.
Hello? Is this the funeral home?
Hold it.
Where are you going?
Chiba.
Yes, sir.
You'll be staying here until
we figure out what's going on.
Inspector, there really is a second hearse.
Really?
It's an old-fashioned hearse they sent
to be scrapped this morning.
It was parked in the underground parking lot.
I knew it!
Where are they taking it?
The person who arranged
it isn't working today.
You don't know?
Hello, Ai-chan?
Where did you...?
What?
You're chasing down Conan-kun's hearse?
What?!
I see.
This one's scrap, huh?
We just turned right.
Then left.
Then straight.
And another left.
Turn right, then left.
Go straight, then left again.
You heard him.
We're counting on you.
I see. The incense, dry ice, and
cardboard in the box was garbage, too.
You weren't trapped inside a coffin.
And the stopping and going we thought
was them making stops was...
The engine of the piece of junk hearse.
It was just a coincidence.
And there was a reason for this.
I'm starting to see what's going on.
There were multiple culprits there.
I see.
That's why...
What?
But they have alibis.
They probably...
In Call
And during that time...
They met at the crime scene.
Safe cracking?
Yeah, that's definitely it.
We stopped.
It's a crosswalk.
After leaving the funeral home,
they went through a tunnel.
Then right, left, left.
After that, they hit a crosswalk.
There's a lot of those.
We're moving.
We're at a train crossing now.
A train crossing?
A train crossing...
This must be it!
I know where they're going!
Yes!
All right. Now I can untie myself.
We stopped again.
No, he turned off the engine.
Which means this place is...
They're headed for the Kuriniji Scrapyard!
Hurry!
Huh?
All right.
Conan-kun!
Where are you?!
Over there!
N-No...
Conan-kun!
Conan...
S-Stop!
Stop the press machine!
Stop the machine!
W-We were too late?
N-No way. No way!
I-Impossible.
Impossible!
N-No...
No!
No...
No, Conan-kun!
Conan...
I'll buy you ten eel bowls
if you'll come back to life!
I can't eat that much.
Genta.
C-Conan!
Conan-kun!
That was close.
Now.
Now's my only chance.
Where's the will?!
W-Was it crushed with the hearse?
Huh?
I don't believe it.
Where's Conan-kun?
Where, where, where's the will?
They found the will?
Really?
Wait.
The Sleeping Kogoro?
Conan.
Here.
Here it is.
Thank you.
This is definitely it.
This is the newest version of
the will the chairman rewrote.
What a shame, Eisuke-san.
What?
You stepped on some gum, didn't you?
Gum?
The smell
and stickiness is all over my phone.
Th-That's...
Kozo-san and Mitsuyo-san,
you were there, too.
You counted on us to assume that
siblings who hated each other
wouldn't verify each other's alibis
using a classic trick.
Wh-What about proof?
That's right.
Where's the evidence?
Inspector.
Please inspect the will for fingerprints.
If I'm correct, in addition
to the deceased's,
Asada-sensei's, and Conan-kun's,
you'll find their fingerprints as well.
Is that true?
Since they planned to dispose
of or rewrite the will,
they touched it with their bare hands.
They wanted to confirm its
contents as soon as possible.
Am I wrong?
The three of you likely
colluded on the condition
that the fortune be split evenly
or be rewritten in your favor.
You hid the will in an unused
hearse along with Conan-kun,
who you planned to eventually release,
without realizing it was
being scrapped today.
It's our father's fault!
You can't be serious.
I can't believe he's leaving
his fortune to his secretary...
No, his lover!
You can't expect us to allow that!
You put a child's...
Conan-kun's life in danger over that?!
You're the ones who have
done something unforgivable!
Ran...
Asada later informed the old
man that while his fortune
was given to the secretary,
she donated all the money
to a charity organization.
That must have been awful, Conan-kun.
Being trapped inside a dark, cramped place.
Can you go to the bathroom
by yourself at night?
Want me to come with you?
Y-You don't need to do that, Ran-neechan.
No need to be shy.
I'm not!
You can depend on me.
You can't be serious.
No way!
I'm a high school student.
Episode Preview
You want me to find an alien?
Yeah!
I saw it with my own two eyes.
An Unidentified Flying Object.
A UFO?
This area's closed to the public!
Mori-san?
And? What's he saying?
He says an alien flew down in a UFO
and killed Nakatsu-san
while floating in midair.
Chiba's UFO Case
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is
"Chiba's UFO Case, Part One!"
Concrete
Next Conan's hint!
Concrete!
Don't miss the next episode.
Detective Chiba's the
star of the next episode!
That chubby Chiba, huh?
What?