Yumi-san!
Yumi-san, wait!
Ch-Chiba-kun?!
I just checked with the traffic department.
They said you were patrolling
Haido City on October 4th.
October 4th?
Oh, right.
That weirdly hot day.
Did you see anything
while you were on patrol?
Like what?
Are you still investigating that weird case?
Well, yeah...
Only the victim and that man
were at the scene, right?
Go bring him in and get a
confession out of him.
I can't just do that.
Chiba Kazunobu.
He has an exceptionally
strong sense of justice.
He's my childhood friend,
and my first love.
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
Here's another fretful couple.
Will this strange case
bring them closer together?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Chiba's UFO Case
(Part One)
"Chiba's UFO Case, Part One!"
Chiba Kazunobu.
So, did you see anything?
He has an exceptionally
strong sense of justice.
No, nothing suspicious.
He's my childhood friend,
and my first love.
I'm going home.
There's a show I want to watch.
You can't cross!
What?
The signal's red.
Who cares?
There aren't any cars.
And nobody's watching.
I'm watching.
And you're watching, too.
If you go easy on yourself
and break the rules once,
it can turn into a habit.
And habits aren't easy to fix.
Don't you understand that?
His only faults are that he's
a little too strict about rules,
and still hasn't remembered me.
How about you?
What?
You were riding with Yumi-san, right?
Do you remember seeing
anything strange that day?
I know it was three days ago,
but if you think about it, you
could still remember something.
Jeez.
You're the one who needs to remember!
What?
Oh, uh...
What kind of strange things?
Well, for example...
An alien?
What?
An a-alien?
Of course you didn't see one.
I'll ask someone else.
He's so dense.
Anyway, did Chiba-kun gain weight again?
Y-You think so?
He does look a little rounder.
He's more than round.
He's obese.
He'll die young.
I wouldn't want him for a boyfriend.
I know what you mean.
Even if he were the last man in the universe,
I wouldn't be with Chiba-kun.
Hey!
Quit chatting and go on patrol!
Yes, ma'am!
H-Hey, you're making a scary face.
Coming.
Oh, hello, Manager.
A package arrived for you.
I accepted it for you.
Thank you.
Be careful when you open it, though.
There was something strange
written in the sender field.
"Your biggest fan in the universe?"
An alien?
You want me to find an alien?
Yeah!
Me, the great detective Mori Kogoro?
It's written right here on your website.
Wada Hina (17)
Haido High School
Second-Year
"We travel to the edge of the
universe to find missing persons
at the Mori Detective Agency."
It's supposed to mean
that I'll work that hard.
She's not asking you to
go into space to find it.
Right, Hina-chan?
Yeah.
I saw it with my own two eyes.
An unidentified flying object.
An unidentified flying object?
A UFO?
Wh-What was it shaped like?
It was a long, skinny cylinder.
A cigar-shaped UFO?
You saw it near Haido Park, right?
Yeah, while jogging with my club.
Are you sure it wasn't a blimp?
Their shapes are similar.
Similar...
Come to think of it, the
Sister From Another Domain
that Sera's hiding in her hotel
room looked a lot like Haibara.
If they're related,
then that would mean Sera's brother Akai-san
and Haibara are related, too.
Wait, wait.
Haibara's sister Miyano Akemi
and Akai-san used to be...
Conan-kun.
What are you doing, Conan-kun?
Aren't you coming?
Where are we going?
To the place where Hina-chan saw the UFO.
Yoko-chan played an extraterrestrial
investigator on TV the other day,
so Dad's really into UFOs right now.
Really?
Hina-neechan's in the karate club, too?
So that's why you know each other even
though you attend different schools.
That's right.
We usually run into each other at the
semi-finals of karate tournaments.
I've never beaten Ran-chan, though.
No wonder I thought I recognized her.
Anyway, I saw the UFO
during our summer training camp.
I told the other club members and my friends,
but they didn't believe me.
That's when I remembered Ran-chan's
dad is the Sleeping Kogoro.
If there was a UFO,
then there must be an alien,
so I sent Ran-chan an e-mail
to ask for help finding it.
What are you going to do if
there really is an alien?
I'll ask it why it came to Earth,
and about the planet it's from,
and if I can ride its UFO.
I have so many questions I want to ask it.
But it could be a terrifying alien.
Of course.
Then we'll have a conversation with our fists.
That's why I practice karate.
Uh, really?
This is it.
I saw the UFO flying between these two trees.
It entered Haido Park,
so I rushed up the stairs
and looked for it,
but I didn't find anything.
Since I was jogging, I didn't have my phone,
so I couldn't take a picture.
But if you were jogging as
part of your training camp,
someone else must've seen it.
W-Well, actually...
I was so eager to "overthrow Ranmaru"
that I made my muscles sore,
so I was running slower than everyone else.
R-Ranmaru?
Oh, you know. Mori Ran sounds
a lot like Mori Ranmaru,
so I started calling you that.
Like, "Overthrow Nobunaga's sycophant!"
R-Really?
Wait, isn't this...?
How is Natsuko?
She dented her skull.
She made it through surgery,
but she's still unconscious.
I see...
How did you know she was a teacher?
Oh.
There were a bunch of answer sheets
inside her bag.
Wait, Conan-kun?
What are you doing here?
W-We were just on a drive together.
Were those answer sheets blank
without anything written on them?
Huh?
Actually, they were all filled in and graded.
I don't think she was attacked here, then.
What?
These are the stairs Jodie-sensei's friend,
Shibuya-sensei, was pushed down, right?
What? Really?
Th-That's what Jodie-sensei told me.
Oh, right.
Ran didn't know.
Shibuya-sensei is a teacher
at Haido Elementary School.
She walks through this park on her way home,
so the school must be nearby.
I see.
You could've mistaken a flying
grade school science experiment
for a UFO.
I don't think that's possible.
The school was on summer vacation.
And it came flying from the
direction of my high school.
Although aside from our
karate club using the gym,
nobody was there.
Haido High School, huh?
I've always wanted to go there.
We can go, but I'm not sure
we'll be able to get inside.
Why not?
At the start of October,
there was a murder on school grounds where
some remodeling work was being done.
Since we're on winter break now,
the school's been strict
about who they let in,
including us students.
Wow, you're right.
There's a police car parked
in front of the rear gate.
Ran-chan! Over here!
The lock here's broken.
The gate opens.
See?
Are you sure we should be going inside?
Looks like this is the scene of the murder.
Come to think of it, I saw
something on the news.
They found a body covered in
concrete inside a high school.
The news didn't mention
the high school's name.
I can't believe it was Haido High.
But wait...
Next to the body was another man
covered in concrete saying things
that didn't make any sense.
I thought he had done it,
and the case was solved.
Hey, what are you doing?
This area's closed to the public!
Mori-san?
Detective Chiba?
What are you doing?
I was helping an adorable client
and ended up here.
I-In any case, unauthorized personnel
can't...
Are you unwell?
Oh, no.
I just parked my police car farther away.
Why?
There was a thick file
inside a package I received the other day.
It described at great length how
obesity can lead to hyperglycemia,
high cholesterol,
and high blood pressure,
and increases the risk of diabetes,
coronary infarction, and strokes.
After that were various dieting methods,
so I've been putting those into practice.
Are you sure that's not part of a
con to sell you useless supplements?
No, it didn't seem like they
were trying to sell anything.
And the sender's handwriting seemed familiar.
Anyway, tell us about the case, Chiba-chan.
I'm always helping you guys solve cases.
Jeez.
The victim was magazine
editor Nakatsu Kyogo-san,
forty-two years old.
He was lying face down with his
face pressed into the concrete.
Nakatsu Kyogo (42)
Magazine Editor
The cause of death was suffocation.
Lying next to him face up in the concrete
Kuchiki Yusuke (38)
Unemployed
was the unemployed Kuchiki Yusuke-san,
thirty-eight years old.
He frequently submitted photos
to the UFO magazine
Nakatsu-san worked for.
Six months ago,
witnesses saw them arguing
at the editorial office,
so he definitely had motive.
Then he must've killed him by pressing
the victim's face into the concrete.
The victim didn't inhale any concrete.
He definitely fell into the
concrete after being killed.
And we know the victim was
strangled not with a string,
but with a bag covering his head.
But we can't find the weapon.
It was probably blown away in the wind,
or stuffed with rocks and thrown far away.
There was hardly any wind
the day of the murder,
and a bag containing rocks
can only be thrown so far.
It would be easy to find.
And?
What's he saying?
That he's not the one who killed Nakatsu-san.
He says an alien flew down in a UFO,
killed Nakatsu-san while floating midair,
and flew away in its UFO.
An alien?
See? Aliens do exist.
Y-Yeah...
No, it wasn't an alien.
This was a murder committed by a human.
Do you actually believe his story
of an alien coming down from a UFO,
murdering a person while floating midair,
and flying away in its UFO?
I don't want to believe it.
But the victim, Nakatsu Kyogo-san,
was definitely suffocated
using a bag covering his head,
before falling into the concrete.
And Kuchiki Yusuke-san who was collapsed
in the concrete next
to him didn't have a bag,
and we still haven't found one nearby.
Considering the circumstances,
Kuchiki-san's alien story is
starting to sound plausible.
Couldn't he have suffocated
him somewhere else,
before bringing the body here
and throwing it in the concrete?
I don't think so.
What?
Look at the footsteps they
left in the concrete.
They both walked on their own legs.
There's no trace of a body being dragged.
Then the culprit carried
the body on his back.
After laying him down in the concrete,
he got back out, changed his shoes,
and reentered the concrete.
Then he put the first pair of shoes
on the victim's feet
and lay down in the concrete next to him.
If that were true,
then the footsteps he made
while carrying the body should be deeper.
But they're all about the same depth.
And all the footsteps are
pointing the same way,
so I doubt he left before
the concrete hardened.
Th-Then maybe he got up
after the concrete hardened,
left the concrete to dispose
of the bag somewhere else,
and came back to lie down in the same place.
There would be no point in coming back.
Besides, when the construction workers
came back to check on the concrete,
they said the concrete
had hardened completely,
and getting them unstuck was a hassle.
Then maybe the alien did it.
I don't think that's it either.
What?
The victim was face down in the concrete,
and the man with him was face up, right?
Yeah.
He said there was a bright light
and he lost consciousness.
Then this imprint must belong
to the man next to the victim.
You can see the shape of his butt.
It looks like he was wearing
his hood when he fell.
So?
Wasn't he wearing his
hood because it was cold?
But didn't we hear about this case
on the news on October 4th?
Yeah, there was a festival
in Haido City that day.
Oh, right.
That weirdly warm day.
He was wearing his hood when it was hot out?
That's it.
He fell knowing the concrete would harden.
If he hadn't worn his hood,
his hair would've gotten
stuck in the concrete,
making it difficult to remove.
Then the guy who was with
the victim must've done it.
He could've had an accomplice with him.
He didn't have an accomplice.
Besides the front and rear gates,
this school can only be entered
through this gate with the broken lock.
Look.
We checked the security camera footage
taken from that camera
attached to that street light.
On that day,
it only recorded the two of them entering.
So it didn't record the murder?
No, the angle's not right for that.
But shortly after the two of them entered,
something strange appeared on the screen.
Something strange?
What?
A large, skinny shadow crossed
from the top to the bottom of the frame.
It headed past that fence towards Haido Park.
Maybe it was the UFO I saw.
What?
You saw it, too?
Yeah, a cigar-shaped UFO.
I saw it during summer break, though.
Oh, man!
Aliens really do exist!
But that alien could be a murderer.
We'll make him amend his
ways using our fists.
I-I'm not sure he would.
The man who was with the
victim probably did it,
but there may be some
mysterious element involved.
By the way, why was this concrete poured?
Apparently they were planning
to place a sculpture
to celebrate the 50th anniversary
of the founding of Haido High.
Construction was supposed to be
finished during summer break,
but it was delayed until fall for some reason.
The victim was lying face
down in the concrete
and suffocated to death.
The man next to him was lying
face up and wearing his hood.
He's saying an alien flew down in a UFO,
murdered the victim while floating midair,
and flew away in a UFO.
And the security camera
captured a large skinny shape
Episode Preview
What is it? Did you find the alien?
Not yet.
I was just wondering what color
the cigar-shaped UFO you saw was.
It was black.
It was a little shiny,
but it was solid black.
Head to his place immediately
and ask him what's going on!
Chiba-kun has changed, hasn't he?
Did he lose weight?
Chiba's UFO Case
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is
"Chiba's UFO Case, Part Two!"
Garbage Bag
Next Conan's hint!
A garbage bag!
Don't miss the next episode.
When you're up against an alien...
A case this tough would make anyone shrink.
He actually shrank.