The body of magazine editor
Nakatsu Kyogo-san
was found pressed face-first into
concrete on Haido High School grounds.
Nakatsu Kyogo (42)
Magazine Editor
The suspect is Kuchiki Yusuke-san,
Kuchiki Yusuke (38)
Unemployed
who was found face-up in the
concrete next to Nakatsu-san.
However, Kuchiki-san is claiming
an alien descended in a UFO,
murdered Nakatsu-san
while floating in midair,
and flew away in its UFO.
See?
Aliens do exist.
Y-Yeah...
No, it wasn't an alien.
This was a murder committed by a human.
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
A strange case that involves a UFO.
The diet cop closes in on the truth.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Chiba's UFO Case
(Part Two)
"Chiba's UFO Case, Part Two!"
Chiba-kun, what's going on?
What do you mean?
I'm talking about the concrete murder
that happened on October 4th.
Everyone's talking about it online right now.
They're saying the murder
was committed by an alien,
and the police are hiding
the existence of aliens.
The article contained a lot of information
we hadn't made public yet and says
it came from a famous detective.
Oh, that must be Mori-san.
I ran into him at the
crime scene the other day.
Then head to his place immediately
and ask him what's going on!
Y-Yes, sir!
Sheesh.
Chiba-kun has changed, hasn't he?
He hasn't changed a bit.
He still seems to be obsessed
with anime and manga.
I meant his build.
Y-You think so?
Chiba-kun.
I heard you got in trouble.
For leaking secret information.
You shouldn't do that.
You have to be careful
when talking to Mori-san.
But you two talk to him all the time.
I always tell him not to tell anyone.
You shouldn't boast about that.
You can't blame me for
wanting Mori-san's help.
I wasn't making any progress no
matter how many people I questioned.
Come to think of it, Yumi told me something.
If you want to know what
happened three months ago,
you should've come three months ago.
I couldn't help it.
The man we found at the crime
scene suddenly changed his story.
At first he said he lost consciousness
when he was bathed in a bright light.
But now he's saying the murderer
was an alien who flew away in a UFO.
I'm exhausted from being
made to canvas the area
around the crime scene every day.
You do look a little haggard.
Have you lost weight?
About ten kilos.
The dieting methods in the package I
received have been really effective.
Since I'm losing a little bit every day,
I look forward to getting on the scale.
I should try the memory diet
and eating order diet next.
Maybe I'll send him the eight hour diet, too.
Mori Detective Agency
Sorry.
I told my drinking buddies about
it half-jokingly the other day.
Sheesh.
Tell them to take down
that blog post right way.
But is it true that the man
at the crime scene recently
and suddenly started
claiming it was an alien?
Yeah, he said he suddenly
remembered after three months.
Naturally, that's a secret, too.
But that man keeps a blog, so I took at look.
He's casually written about getting arrested
for trespassing in a person's yard
while trying to get a photo of a UFO,
and being stopped for speeding
while chasing after a UFO in his car.
He said it's the police's
fault the UFO got away,
and that maybe they're deliberately
blocking him so information about aliens
won't get out to the public.
R-Really?
Isn't this guy a UFO fanatic?
I would've expected him to brag on his blog
about seeing an alien fly down
in a UFO to commit a murder\
before telling the police about it.
Y-You're right.
If he wanted to insist it wasn't
him, he would've written about it.
Anyway, did anyone else see the UFO?
Didn't it fly towards Haido Park?
Yes,
but everyone was at the
Haido Festival that day.
Hardly anyone was in the park.
Then what about the summer break
when Ran's friend saw the UFO?
Since a grade school teacher
was pushed down the stairs at
Haido Park before summer break,
everyone had been avoiding
the park out of fear.
People started returning to the
park after security cameras
were placed at the end of August, though.
Why don't we try going
to that man's house now?
N-Now?
If the Great Detective Kogoro solves
the case after talking to him,
it might get you off the hook.
Kuchiki-san.
Kuchiki Yusuke-san?
Yes, what is it?
I'm Chiba with the MPD.
Could we come inside to
talk to you for a minute?
W-Wait a minute.
I-It's a little messy.
Okay, please come in.
Excuse the intrusion.
I don't have any tea to offer you.
Don't worry about it.
Did he really clean?
Please don't touch anything.
And who's this kid?
Wow!
There are lots of photos of UFOs.
Who the hell are you?
Oh, he's just a kid I'm taking
care of who likes UFOs.
What?
Wait...
Hey!
What are you...?
Plastic Bag (Black)
70L 10 Count
Let's Conduct
Experiments
Science is Fun
You little brat!
Sorry about that.
He's a naughty little kid.
You wait outside.
Conan-kun?
What?
You want me to tell you Hina-chan's number?
Yeah, I had a question for her.
Hold on.
Hina-chan's right here.
What? Why?
Our karate clubs had a joint
practice session today.
We just finished.
I'll put her on.
Hina-chan, Conan-kun called for you.
He said he wanted to talk to you.
Oh, that smart kid?
Wada Hina (17)
Haido High School
Second-Year
What is it?
Did you find the alien?
Not yet.
I was just wondering what color
the cigar-shaped UFO you saw was.
It was black.
It was a little shiny, but it was solid black.
Got it.
Thanks.
Hey, wait.
I see.
So that's how it is.
That's why
he didn't blog about seeing a UFO.
So no one would identify his
unidentified flying object.
Coming.
Sorry I'm late.
It was just the right distance,
so I jogged here from home.
Um...
Who are you?
I'm Chiba from the MPD.
Try not to forget.
Detective Chiba, we've been waiting for you.
That's right.
Conan-kun asked me to come.
You solved the concrete
murder case, didn't you?
What?
Remember that thing we made last night?
It was the trick the culprit used.
Oh, right.
You mean that long skinny bag we made
by taping black plastic bags together?
So that wasn't your science homework.
In any case, let's get everyone
together and test it out.
After all,
there isn't a cloud in the sky today.
What do you want?
We already talked in my
apartment the other day.
So you're still insisting it was an alien
and not you?
It had to be.
Nakatsu-kun was found in the concrete,
having been suffocated with a bag, right?
I may have been collapsed
in the concrete next to him,
but I didn't have a bag on me.
There weren't any footprints
leaving the concrete either.
And there wasn't much wind that day,
so the bag couldn't have been blown away.
Couldn't you have walked
backwards out of the concrete,
while retracing the steps you took in?
You idiot,
then those footprints would be deeper.
What were you doing inside
our school's grounds,
when you're not even a student, anyway?
Hina-chan.
I saw a UFO around here the day before.
So I brought Nakatsu-san since
he's the editor of a UFO magazine.
You can see the whole area
from the roof of the school.
Who is that girl, anyway?
She says she saw
a cigar-shaped UFO
flying over Haido Park
over summer break, too.
See!
It does exist.
I must've seen the same one.
I was blinded by a bright light as it left,
and lost consciousness.
Was that UFO
this color?
N-No,
the one I saw was more gray.
But you can make this thing
fly through the sky like a UFO.
And suffocate someone, of course.
What are you talking about?
Even if you covered them with this giant bag,
you couldn't kill someone.
Then try putting it on.
See?
Even if you hold the opening
shut, you can still breathe.
Detective Chiba,
could you try tightening the bag from behind?
L-Like this?
That's it.
Better too big than too small.
You could suffocate someone like this.
I can't breathe!
D-Dad...
B-But I wasn't carrying that giant bag
in the security camera footage.
Y-Yeah.
You probably hid it in the shrubbery.
Even if I did,
nobody found a huge bag at the crime scene.
Yeah, because it flew away like a UFO
after you filled the bag with air.
A-Air?
How?
It seems like you could inflate it
by running around with the bag open.
There weren't any footprints
like that in the concrete.
Try waving it in a sideways
figure eight motion.
Like this?
Wow!
It's...
...filling with air!
Once it's inflated,
you'll be ready to go
after tying the bag shut.
O-Okay.
See?
You can inflate the bag that
way without running around.
You're right.
But if you wave the bag around like that,
your footprints would be deeper there.
That's right.
All these footprints are
about the same depth.
He really is just a kid.
You could hide the footprints if a
giant monster stepped on them, though.
A monster?
Th-That's it.
He fell on top of those deep footprints.
The imprint of his body hid them.
But that giant air-filled bag
wasn't found at the crime scene.
It probably would've blown in a strong wind,
but there wasn't any blowing that day.
Don't worry.
Once enough time passes,
the black bag will become a UFO.
What?
It's just an inflated bag.
No matter how long we wait,
it won't...
It's floating!
Wow.
That's it.
The UFO I saw was like that, too.
It's called a solar balloon.
When the air inside the bag is
heated by the sun and inflates,
the density of the air inside
decreases, so it floats.
The bag is black so it
gets hotter in the sun,
and it's long and thin,
so the air heats up quicker
all the way through.
I saw it on an experiment program on TV.
Really?
I see.
In other words, you took the following steps:
Knowing concrete would be poured
on this section of Haido High grounds,
you called Nakatsu-san here.
You covered his head from behind,
using the skinny black plastic bag
you hid in the shrubbery beforehand.
Then you suffocated him inside the concrete,
and pressed his dead body into the concrete.
You filled the bag with air using the method
we just demonstrated and tied it off,
fell onto the deep footprints you left,
and raised the bag above you.
Then you waited
for the sun to heat the air
inside the bag so it would float away.
As expected, the construction
crew found you
when they came to check on the concrete.
Then the long skinny shadow on
the security camera footage...
It was the shadow of the solar
balloon he used to commit his crime.
What about the UFO I
saw during summer break?
It was probably him testing
to see if the black bag would actually float.
Y-You've been talking like
I'm the one who did it,
but do you have any proof?
Do you have any proof that I
released the floating black bag?
I'd been holding back until now,
but if this is how the police
are going to treat me,
I'll post it all over the internet.
That the murderer was an alien,
and the police are trying to hide it.
The proof's probably caught
in the trees at Haido Park.
What?
You were able to collect
the bag you tested with,
but security cameras were installed in
the park at the end of summer break.
I see.
He originally planned to say it was an alien
after collecting the bag.
But since he couldn't retrieve
the bag because of the cameras,
he couldn't say it anymore.
If you weren't careful,
the police might gather eyewitness
accounts of a flying black bag,
and the bag would be found
stuck in a tree inside the park.
Since there weren't any
accounts after three months,
you went with your original plan,
and started saying an alien in a UFO did it.
Once the bag is found,
Nakatsu-san's saliva and the culprit's
fingerprints will be on it.
There's no proof more decisive than that.
What an idiot, though.
I can't believe you were willing
to get stuck in concrete
to make it look like an alien did it.
I-I just did what he wanted.
Nakatsu looked at the UFO photos
I worked so hard to take and said...
This one's no good. It's out of focus.
And it's too small to tell what it is.
Bring me some more impactful photos.
I don't care if you have to use tricks.
It's not like UFOs exist anyway.
He said that even though he's
the editor of a UFO magazine!
Then you should've put him to shame
by sticking to your guns and
taken better photos of real UFOs.
But you tried to get away with murder
by framing the aliens you believe in.
You're the one that looks like
an unidentified alien to me.
Kuchiki Yusuke,
let's go.
Detective Chiba's so cool.
Kyogoku-senpai would've kicked his butt.
Oh, right.
Kyogoku-san was in the
Haido High karate club.
Yeah.
He's studying abroad right now,
but apparently some rich girl
has been following him around.
Anyway, I'm surprised you
figured out the trick he used.
There were science books, black plastic bags,
and tape stuffed in a
cupboard at his apartment.
But how did you know he
was hiding them there?
His hands.
When he let us in after
cleaning up his apartment,
his right hand was paler
than the rest of him.
That's how I knew he'd been
raising his right hand
above his heart to hide
something important.
But I'm sure you noticed, too.
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, of course.
Of course I noticed.
Chiba-kun, I heard the news.
They say you caught the alien.
Really?
No,
I arrested a suspect who tried
to pin his crime on an alien.
Although I have Conan-kun
to thank for most of it.
Chiba's gotten a little handsome.
Not just a little.
He's pretty hot.
So he hadn't been trying until now.
I know.
He's like the protagonist of a police drama.
Maybe I'll go for him.
No, me first.
What?
Several Days Later
Chiba-kun.
You're back to normal.
R-Really?
I was sent a bunch of early
Valentine's Day chocolate.
They were so good, I
couldn't stop eating them.
You shouldn't overeat.
A police officer needs to be fit.
The same goes for you, sir.
You're right.
He's rebounded completely.
I'd never go for Chiba-kun.
No way.
Okay!
Episode Preview
It's gone!
Was there anything written on the envelope?
Oh, you mean the envelope containing
the marriage registration.
You've finally arrived, Chacha.
Marriage Registration
Haneda Shukichi
Did you look inside the envelope?
I'll win all seven crowns,
and wait for Yumi-tan's response.
The Marriage Registration's Password
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The Marriage
Registration's Password, Part One!"
Air Conditioning
Next Conan's hint!
Air conditioning!
This episode featured Kazunobu.
Don't miss the next episode.
The next one features Chukichi.
It's so hard.
Yeah, for them.