I'm stuffed.
That Italian place was good.
Yeah, but you might've had too much to eat.
Who cares?
Can't I cut loose on my day off?
Besides, I've been feeling annoyed lately.
By the way, that envelope
from your boyfriend
that you mentioned at the restaurant...
My ex-boyfriend.
He forced me to take it a few years ago.
Sorry I'm late.
You're late.
This is for you.
Huh?
What is this?
H-Hey, wait.
Please don't open it until I get all seven.
B-But what's in it?
I'll let you know once I do.
Promise me.
And that's what he said.
Apparently he has all seven now,
but our days off never match up,
so I've had enough.
But inside the envelope there might be...
...a marriage registration.
What?
Yeah, right.
It's pretty common.
His name is already written in,
and you just have to write
yours if you say yes.
I don't know what his seven are,
but he told you to hold onto it, right?
W-Well, yeah.
What's he like, anyway?
What does he do?
He won't tell me.
Our next story is concerning shogi.
He said he would once he got all seven.
The fierce championship match
between Master Haneda Shukichi
Apparently he's some kind
of master of something.
It's probably fishing or
games or storytelling.
and Master Katsumata Susumu continues.
Storytelling?
After going 3-3,
the match is now entering its seventh round.
Hey, it's Master Taiko.
Everyone wants him in their commercials
and quiz shows these days.
Yesterday the first day ended with
Master Katsumata Susumu in the lead,
M-Master?
and they began playing
again this morning at nine.
You mean of shogi?
Yeah.
Everyone's watching to see if
Master Haneda will become
the second man ever to hold
onto all seven crowns.
Yumi, is your boyfriend...
Can he keep all seven titles?!
...Master Taiko?!
A-Apparently.
Then his seven
must be the seven major shogi titles.
R-Really?
Why didn't you open the envelope?
Didn't he tell you to open
it once he got all seven?
I was going to open it in front
of him the next time we met
and tear it to pieces if
it was something stupid.
And? Where's the envelope?
I feel like I saw it the other day.
Oh, right.
I used it to bookmark a
page in a fashion magazine.
Where's the magazine?
It was an old one,
so I threw it out with
the others this morning.
Then let's go get it immediately.
We might still make it in time.
No, it's fine.
What?
I hadn't even thought about marriage yet.
Besides, I don't want him to
think I changed my attitude
just because he's a shogi master.
If you say so.
It's a shame, though.
Holding all seven titles should earn him
at least a hundred million yen a year.
What?
Seriously?
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
A marriage registration in the trash?
There's no way this'll be easy to find!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Marriage Registration's Password
(Part One)
"The Marriage Registration's
Password, Part One!"
You can't be serious!
It's gone!
My hundred million yen!
That's why she's disappointed, huh?
Why don't you tell him what happened,
and have him write up a
new marriage registration?
I can't do that.
Chukichi can be weirdly stubborn.
When we went on a date the other day,
I jokingly asked if he could give me
a spare envelope in case I lost it.
No, there's only one of
it in the entire world.
There's no such thing as a spare.
He wouldn't give me one.
Wait.
The garbage truck is probably still
out driving around town, right?
We might be able to stop it if we chase after
it with the sirens on the patrol car sounding.
That's an abuse of police authority.
Huh?
It's Detective Sato and the patrol lady.
What are you doing?
Are you on a case?
Ugh, kids.
Yeah,
Yumi threw out something
important with the garbage.
M-Miwako...
Really?
You must be stupid.
You shouldn't have thrown it
away if it was so important.
It was a mistake.
You accidentally put it in a garbage bag?
It was stuck inside a fashion magazine.
I bundled it up with some other
magazines and threw it out.
But apparently they don't
collect recyclables today.
What?
You're as negligent as ever.
You're one to talk.
But if that bundle of magazines isn't here,
then the building manager might
be keeping them somewhere else.
What?
If he identified it as your garbage,
it might be in front of your apartment.
It's here!
Recycling is
on Tuesdays!!
Great.
You've got a responsible building manager.
He even left a note telling you
that recycling is on Tuesday.
I'm pretty sure I left it in here...
I'm surprised the manager knew
it was Yumi-san's garbage.
If he's been working here for a while,
he probably knows which
magazines his residents buy.
Yumi-san's probably the only one who gets
a mix of fashion and mahjong magazines.
It's not here!
I can't find it anywhere!
By the way, what are you looking for?
A hundred million yen!
What?!
Yumi left an important envelope
inside a fashion magazine as a bookmark.
Oh, you mean an envelope containing
a marriage registration.
Y-Yeah, probably.
Even the kids figured it out.
Was there anything written on the envelope?
The word "seal" was written
along the opening on the back,
Seal
Haneda Shukichi
and his name was written on the font.
Then some woman may have picked it up,
written her own name in the wife field,
and submitted it to the ward office.
No way.
I wouldn't hesitate, too, if it
meant marrying Master Taiko.
What?!
I'm joking.
In any case, let's go talk to the manager.
He may be holding onto it if it's important.
Yes?
Excuse me.
It's Miyamoto from room 308.
I have a question about the garbage.
Give me a minute.
Hachitsuka Koroku (68)
Building Manager
You've finally arrived, Chacha.
Chacha?
I told you to stop calling me that.
It's annoying.
Yumi, what's Chacha?
I don't know.
When Chukichi came here before to hang out,
we ran into the manager.
He started calling me Chacha after that.
You're no different from that evil
woman who stole Taiko's spine.
I get it.
Mister, do you like shogi?
Yeah, I thought I was as
good as a professional.
But he taught me a lesson.
Ten years ago, I heard a middle
school aged pro was coming
to an event being held
at a department store.
I thought I'd beat that kid good.
Instead, I suffered a thorough
defeat at his hands.
I fell in love with his style.
I'm a huge fan of Master Taiko now.
Each time he won a title, I was as
pleased as though I'd won it myself.
I was living a carefree life.
Until this Chacha arrested me, anyway.
Arrested him?
Yeah, this old man used to be a pickpocket.
A pickpocket?
I caught him trying to steal
my wallet on the train,
and sent him to jail.
But he said he couldn't find a job
once he finished his sentence,
so I helped him get a job
managing the building here.
R-Really?
More importantly,
where's the envelope that was stuck in
the magazines I put out this morning?
Oh, you mean this?
Did you look inside the envelope?
Marriage Registration
Haneda Shukichi
Why do you care?
You threw it out with the trash.
You old fart...
That's good news, though.
It really was a marriage registration form.
Give me back my registration form.
Now where did I put it?
What?
I thought I put it in my bedroom,
but I've been so forgetful lately.
Move!
I'm going to look for it.
Hey, wait. It's not on the
desk or in any of the drawers.
That's strange.
I'm sure it's in this room.
I'm sure he'll give it back
to you once we find it.
F-Fine.
You don't have that much time.
What?
He wrote that his profession
Shogi Master (Seven Crowns)
was "shogi master, seven crowns" on the form.
He must've written that with great
resolution and determination.
I-I know that.
But Master Taiko is currently
struggling in the championship match.
It's probably because of
the registration form.
He mentioned in a magazine interview
that he couldn't think about shogi right now,
since he still hasn't received a response
from the person dearest to him.
That's right.
If Taiko loses the championship match,
this marriage registration with
seven crowns written on it
will become invalid.
What?
Th-Then call him right now to
tell him you want to get married.
What?
There's no point.
Masters don't keep their phones
on them during a match.
What?
The only time you'd be able to see him
is during his lunch break.
If you appear holding the
marriage registration,
he'd defeat all enemies with
the strength of a million men.
There's about an hour left before lunch.
You know where the registration
form is, don't you?
Where is it?!
Where did you hide it?!
Then show me your resolve.
M-My resolve?
The resolve to stand by Master Taiko's side
no matter what happens!
If you're desperate enough,
you should be able to
find an envelope or two!
M-My resolve?
The resolve to stand by Master Taiko's side
no matter what happens!
If you're desperate enough,
you should be able to
find an envelope or two!
Hey, isn't this it?
What?
It says to enter the eight digit password.
It even says it has to
be entered by Yodogimi.
Who's Yodogimi?
Taiko Hideyoshi's wife, also known as Chacha.
But what's the password?
Won't we get it right eventually if we
just enter a bunch of random numbers?
We can't.
Only Yumi-san is allowed
to enter the password,
and it says no mistakes are allowed.
Password
Enter the 8 digit password
Only Yodogimi may enter the password
No mistakes allowed
Apparently it locks up if
you get it wrong even once.
Then what are we supposed to do?
It's simple.
If we find the eight digit number
hidden somewhere in this room,
and Yumi-san enters it into this computer,
we'll know where the envelope is.
Isn't that right, mister?
Y-Yeah.
Now that we know what to do,
let's split up and look for it.
Yeah!
Let's look, too.
O-Okay.
Genta-kun, don't flip over the garbage can.
But we don't know where it's hidden.
Huh? There was a weird piece
of paper in the trash.
Wait a minute.
What is this?
I don't get it.
But it seems like what's written
on that paper is some kind of code,
and we'll find an eight digit number
once we solve it.
Sheesh. How am I supposed to solve this?
You'll probably be fine.
That code looks a lot
like the Dancing Man code
from Sherlock Holmes.
The Sherlock looking at the
photo he took of the code
has probably already solved...
Conan-kun, not even you can solve it?
S-Seriously?
Is it that hard?
Y-Yeah.
What is this?
Are they numbers or letters?
Or are they symbols?
Damn it. I don't have a clue.
Hey, some of them look like numbers
if you cover part of them.
See?
If you hide this part, this looks like a one.
Y-You're right.
But what are we supposed to hide them with?
I know.
It's shogi pieces.
If we put shogi pieces in the
right places on top of the paper,
we might find an eight digit number.
You're right.
The shogi board conspicuously placed in
the middle of the room is suspicious, too.
It does seem like a hint.
Okay!
Now that that's settled,
let's solve this code together.
Yeah!
She's won them over completely.
Yumi-tan...
Why hasn't she responded yet?
D-Does she not want to marry me?
No, no.
Even if that were the case,
she would still let me know.
Oh, whoops.
I need to focus on this match right now.
Maybe she hasn't opened the envelope yet.
Could she really have thrown it away?
That seems more likely for Yumi-tan.
Master Haneda.
Huh?
You seem rather worried.
Why don't we take an early lunch?
I don't mind.
No, let's keep playing.
That's right.
I'll win all seven crowns and
wait for Yumi-tan's response.
That's the play I chose.
Stick to the plan!
It's not that they don't look like numbers,
but it doesn't seem right.
I don't know which number
to start with either.
Maybe this isn't the way to solve the code.
Maybe the code can't be solved
with only that sheet of paper.
What do you mean?
Maybe there's a second code sheet
that creates an eight digit
number when you overlap them.
Or maybe it reveals a sentence
that's a clue to the code.
So we should look for
the second sheet, right?
Y-Yeah, probably.
Okay, men! Let's search the room again!
Yeah!
She's like a general and her servants.
Searching for something reminds
me of that time, though.
Huh? What time?
When we went bamboo shoot hunting.
Bamboo shoots?
When I went to hang out
at Chukichi's apartment,
Stick To the Plan
he was panicking because he
couldn't find an important fan,
so I found it for him.
How is that bamboo shoot hunting?
Fans are made from bamboo.
And the fan was stuck in a pen holder.
Only the tip was visible.
So I told Chukichi he couldn't find it
because he was looking for a fan.
If you imagine you're looking for something
that's mostly hidden, it's easier to find.
All you can see of bamboo shoots are the tip,
since most of it's hidden in the dirt.
Really?
"Thoughts are like bamboo shoots.
Most of them are buried in the dirt."
It expresses the importance of
looking at what's on the inside,
instead of being caught up in appearances.
And it's a saying left by the extraordinary
shogi master Sakata Sankichi.
Did she say that because she knows?
I'm the one who stuck the
fan I found on his desk
in the pen holder while he
was in the bathroom, though.
So it was just a coincidence.
But why do you call him Chukichi,
when his name is Haneda Shukichi?
He has weird eating habits.
When we started dating,
he always ate cheese because it
wouldn't make his hands dirty.
And since mice like cheese...
That's right.
I couldn't stand to watch it,
so I made him eat an exceptionally
delicious shortcake.
Chukichi couldn't stop eating it.
Now that you mention it,
shogi players eat a lot of
sweet desserts while they play.
It's supposed to help them think.
M-Master Taiko did start winning titles
after he began eating
shortcake during his matches.
This could be just another
coincidence, but...
This woman...
It is really true?
Is there really another sheet?
Then show me your resolve.
M-My resolve?
The resolve to stand by Master Taiko's side,
no matter what happens!
Even if Yumi-san demonstrates her resolve,
there's nothing we can do if
we can't complete the code.
In other words, the second should
be as easy to find as the first.
So why can't we find it?
Damn it. What's going on here?
Episode Preview
What disappears when you make a photocopy?
Oh, right.
Men don't like to go back on their word.
Don't let anyone beat you until then,
you balding mouse!
I-I thought she was Chacha,
but could she be...?
The Marriage Registration's Password
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The Marriage
Registration's Password, Part Two!"
Origami
Next Conan's hint!
Origami!
A mean old man.
Don't miss the next episode.
And a tough code.
We'll never find the registration form.