Traffic cop Yumi-san
threw away an envelope she
received from Master Haneda
with the trash.
Fortunately, the building manager
had retrieved it for her, but...
More importantly, where's the envelope
that was stuck in the magazines
I put out this morning?
Oh, you mean this?
Did you look inside the envelope?!
Marriage Registration
Haneda Shukichi
Why do you care?
You threw it out with the trash.
You old fart...
That's good news, though.
It really was a marriage registration form.
Give me back my registration form.
Hachitsuka Koroku (68)
Building Manager
He wrote that his profession
Shogi Master (Seven Crowns)
was "shogi master, seven crowns" on the form.
He must've written that with great
resolution and determination.
I-I know that.
But Master Taiko is currently struggling
in the championship match.
If Taiko loses the championship match,
this marriage registration with
seven crowns written on it
will become invalid.
You know where the registration
form is, don't you?
Where is it?!
Where did you hide it?!
Then show me your resolve.
M-My resolve?
The resolve to stand by Master Taiko's side,
no matter what happens!
Hey, isn't this it?
What?
It says to enter the eight digit password.
It even says it has to
be entered by Yodogimi.
Then what are we supposed to do?
It's simple.
If we find the eight digit number
hidden somewhere in this room,
and Yumi-san enters it into this computer,
we'll know where the envelope is.
Isn't that right, mister?
Y-Yeah.
Now that we know what to do,
let's split up and look for it.
Yeah!
But after searching the whole room,
all we found was a single sheet of paper
with mysterious symbols written on it.
What is this?
Are they numbers or letters?
Or are they symbols?
Damn it. I don't have a clue.
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
The code is too difficult to solve.
Where will their feelings
for each other end up?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Marriage Registration's
Password (Part Two)
"The Marriage Registration's
Password, Part Two!"
Oh, right.
Miike told me you drove one
of the MPD's patrol cars
all the way to Yamanashi.
Yeah.
Chukichi said he was going to
be late to some kind of match.
Anyway, you're amazing, Haneda-san.
You had an important match today,
but you skipped it for Yumi-san.
What match?
My master qualification
match was actually today.
Master qualification match?
Where and when is that?
I need to arrive at the Tokiwa
Hotel in Yamanashi by three,
but there's only ninety minutes left.
Chukichi, don't underestimate
what this car can do.
Hey, you!
You in front!
Move over and get out of the way!
Quit wasting time and move!
Y-Yumi-tan, you should stop.
Now that I think about it, it
might've been a shogi match.
Have you heard of the Tokiwa Hotel?
No.
The Tokiwa Hotel in Yamanashi
is where Master Taiko claimed
his seventh crown by playing
his master qualification match.
I heard he barely made it in time,
but I had no idea he rode a patrol car there.
Anyway, we made it to the hotel,
but Chukichi was panicking
because he lost the photo of me
that he kept as a good luck charm.
So I sent him off with a kiss.
You know, since his name's Shu-kissy.
I-I thought she was Chacha,
but could she be...?
Look, look!
All right!
How many squares do I move forward?
Isn't it ten thousand?
The game would be over if she moved that far.
These guys got tired of searching,
and are playing Parcheesi
with shogi pieces now.
I guess it can't be helped since we searched
everywhere and still couldn't find it.
Which means this really is
the only code sheet, right?
Anyway, don't you think it's cold in here?
You're right.
Hey, mister.
Could you turn on the heat?
I wish I could,
but the cooling and heating unit has
been broken since yesterday.
It doesn't work.
Sorry, but you'll have to endure the cold.
What?
When we first entered the room,
it was a little warm.
The heat must have been on.
So why is he trying to hide that?
Hey.
Did you even come up with this code?
Yeah, I did.
Why don't you think so?
Because this isn't the original.
It's a photocopy.
What? Really?
Crap.
I took a picture of it right away,
so I didn't examine the
actual paper very closely.
I'm saying you probably copied a code
somebody else wrote down somewhere.
I guarantee you I wrote that code.
I only copied it because I felt like it.
No...
It doesn't look like there's
a copy machine here.
He would've had
to walk ten minutes to the closest
convenience store to copy it.
And copy paper is rectangular.
It took even more extra work
to cut it into a square.
He didn't photocopy it on a whim.
There was a reason he had to copy it.
But what could it be?
Because he wanted to hide a sketch?
To hide marks left by whiteout?
Or...
If you made the code,
at least give us a hint.
Even without a hint,
if you're prepared to marry Master Taiko,
you should be able to solve the code quickly.
If you're prepared to be a
true married couple, that is.
A married couple?
Another one.
I'm so close to the goal.
You were doing well earlier.
Well, life has its ups and downs.
Ups and downs?
Wait a minute.
That code was in the trash can, wasn't it?
Then if we fold that paper into that shape...
Give me that.
Hey.
Conan-kun?
Did you figure something out?
Yeah, right.
He's just playing around.
But when it comes to this kid...
See?
Look.
Does it look like he's solving a code to you?
Y-You're right.
It looks like the origami
I used to fold as a kid.
That's amazing.
It spells something.
Yumi, enter the eight digit password.
Okay.
Let's see...
Yeah, but...
Those aren't numbers.
It's katakana.
It's okay.
Most adults could decipher an
eight digit code from that.
Yeah.
What?
And the code I just showed
you isn't the only one.
There's a pair.
H-Hey, Miwako.
This is it, right?
P-Probably...
Okay, then. I'm going to
click the enter button.
Wait!
L-Let's check online just to be sure.
What?
If you get it wrong even once,
we'll never know where the envelope
containing the marriage registration is.
Y-You're right.
Wow! Ai-chan was right!
Yumi-san entered an eight digit
number without hesitating.
But the code was written in katakana.
Why did those characters appear
when you folded the code sheet?
You didn't get any hints.
We did get hints.
What?
The fact that he went out of his
way to copy the code sheet,
and that the sheet was in
the trash can were hints.
Copied?
What would have been obvious
if he hadn't made a copy?
Like a sketch or whiteout?
Take this sheet I just folded.
What disappears when you make a copy?
Oh, right.
It's the creases.
That's right.
The creases?
Really?
Yeah.
If there were creases on the paper,
we would've known right
away how to fold the sheet.
But how were we supposed to know
how to fold it without them?
That's why the sheet was
inside the trash can.
What?
Was he trying to throw it away?
No.
There's an old expression.
"A crane in a junk heap."
It refers to someone exceptionally talented
or beautiful mixed in with a
group of unexceptional people.
Really?
That's right.
A junk heap is a place where
you dispose of your garbage.
Since this code was in the trash can,
it means we should fold the
code sheet into a crane.
If you fold it into a crane
with the code facing up...
See? As you can see...
It spells the words "root" and "five."
What's root five?
Root 5
The number you square to get five
is called the square root
of five or root five.
Most middle and high school students
are made to memorize the first eight digits.
E-Eight whole digits?
I can't remember that many.
It's okay.
There's a rhyme to help you remember.
There is?
For root five,
the rhyme is "a parrot
cries at the base of Mt. Fuji,"
or 2.2360679.
So if we enter that eight digit number...
Yeah, that's right.
Okay, here we go.
Password
Enter the other
eight digit number
"E-Enter the other eight digit number?"
You mean root five isn't the only password?
It's okay.
We just have to fold another
crane out of the code sheet.
What?
The old man gave us a hint when
he mentioned married couples.
Start by folding it back to this shape
with the small overlapping squares.
Fold like part like so.
Then you just have to fold a crane again.
It should reveal a different
word like root five.
It's not katakana this time.
There's a strange picture on the back, too.
The symbol on top of the circle
is the square root symbol,
so I think we need to figure out
what number goes inside the circle.
But our only hint is this strange drawing.
Maybe it's a nine.
Why do you think that?
If the circle on top is the moon,
and the thing underneath is a sake cup,
then it could signify moon viewing, right?
Oh, right.
You probably mean to say moon
viewings are held during September,
so the number inside the circle is nine.
But the square root of nine is three.
It's not eight digits.
Really?
That's not it?
My dad always says he wants to enjoy
a drink while gazing at the moon.
A drink?
I see.
That's it.
Shall we begin the post-match discussion?
What?
Sonant marks?
These two dots on the upper
right side of the cup
are sonant marks?
Yeah.
What are sonant marks?
They're marks that change
the sound of a character.
Huh.
The "ge" sound in your name
comes from adding sonant
marks to the character "ke."
Oh, those things.
But how does that help you determine
the number that goes inside the circle?
Try counting up from one.
How do you count fingers?
Ippon, nihon, sanbon, yonhon...
One finger, two fingers,
three fingers, four fingers...
How about mice?
Ippiki, nihiki, sanbiki, yonhiki...
One mouse, two mice, three mice, four mice...
How about beverages?
Ippai, nihai, sanbai, yonhai...
One cup, two cups, three cups, four cups...
You've figured it out by now, right?
When counting objects, which
number uses sonant marks?
It's three!
Bingo!
Apparently you're supposed
to enter root three.
What?
Root three is "treat me like
you'd treat anyone else,"
so it's 17320508.
"Treat me like you'd treat anyone else."
Okay!
H-Hey, what is this?
The screen just switched to
showing what's being captured
by the camera on top of the computer!
Where's the envelope?!
Look closely.
Look closely?
The envelope's in my coat pocket.
All right!
I see.
When Yumi ran into you in the entryway,
you used your pickpocketing skills
to hide the envelope in Yumi's breast pocket.
That's why he turned off the heat.
It was so she wouldn't remove her coat.
Chukichi's marriage registration is mine.
The championship match is taking
place at the Jinya Inn in Kanagawa.
They break for lunch until 1:30, so...
I can make it in time if
I rush there in a taxi.
Yeah.
Huh?
Someone's calling.
Shukichi
It's Chukichi.
Hello?
Chukichi?
I thought you couldn't
use your phone right now.
It's all right.
All right?
The match is already over.
O-Over?
You can throw away the envelope.
It's meaningless now.
What?
What do you mean, throw away the envelope?
Oh, no!
They're reporting online that
Master Taiko lost the match!
What?!
Let's see.
"Evidently troubled by something else,
Master Taiko made one poor play after
another and lost before lunch."
Apparently it's true.
But, Chukichi...
Stick to the plan.
It was the motto of my brother-in-law,
the respectable shogi player Haneda Koji.
Haneda Koji?
I'm sorry, Yumi-san.
Men don't like to go back on their word.
Oh, really?
What?
Yumi-tan.
I don't know
what you put inside this envelope,
but if you've got something to say to me,
say it to my face!
If you ever get your seven
or eight whatevers
and become a champion again,
I'll hear what you have to say.
So...
Don't let anyone beat you until then,
you balding mouse!
I-I won't!
Yumi, that was awesome!
I thought she was Chacha,
but she was Nene after all.
I can see she wears the
pants in their relationship.
Don't you mean Nobunaga?
What? No way.
The championship match is
only played once a year?
Yeah.
The soonest you'll be able to
accept Master Taiko's proposal
will be one year from now.
What?
Seriously?
I thought they played it every month or so.
And while Master Taiko
has six crowns right now,
if he loses another title like he did today,
he'll have to start over from there.
Who knows when your wedding will be?
I don't care how many crowns he has.
I'm going to call him to tell him to
sign a new registration form right away.
Don't do that.
Not after showing off like that.
If they love each other, they should
just get married right away.
Yeah.
I'm sure it's more complicated for adults.
Do you know what happened to Haneda Koji?
Yeah.
He was a genius shogi player
who was the closest to
winning all seven titles,
but he left for America to
play in a chess tournament.
While he was there,
he got involved in some kind of
incident and passed away, right?
Since his name was also Haneda,
I thought they might be related.
But I had no idea he was Master
Taiko's brother-in-law.
What about him?
I've seen that name before.
What?
It was two names below
yours on the list of people
who were administered APTX 4869.
Kudo Shinichi – Missing
Haneda Koji - Deceased
Episode Preview
Conan-kun!
No one else is here.
Come join me over here.
You idiot, you're there.
Are you all right?
Th-The red ogre?
The red ogre?
The Descent Into Hell Tour of Love
(Beppu Chapter)
The next episode of Conan is
"The Descent Into Hell Tour
of Love, Beppu Chapter!"
Airport Shuttle
Ready, and...
Next Conan's hint!
An airport shuttle!
Takagi-kun, did you really get time off?
Don't miss the next episode.
Yeah, no problem.
Liar.