The old man invited me and Ran
to the Beppu hot springs in Oita.
The Lake of Blood Hell and
the Ogre's Mountain Hell.
You can't visit the Beppu hot springs
without visiting all the hells.
Visiting the hells, huh?
Sounds fun.
There is one thing bothering me, though.
For some reason the old man
who invited us on this trip
isn't saying anything.
Oh, excuse me.
Go ahead.
Huh?
That voice...
Thank you.
Not at all.
Taka—
I'm not here.
You can't see me.
What was that?
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
Detective Takagi and the old
man are behaving strangely.
Fraught with foreboding, they head to Kyushu.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Descent Into Hell Tour of Love
(Beppu Chapter)
"The Descent Into Hell Tour
of Love, Beppu Chapter!"
Beppu Station
Long ago,
because the sources of the spring
were so terrifyingly unapproachable,
they were called hells.
Stove Hell
The Stove Hell, where a red ogre
can be seen on top of the stove.
Huh?
Amazing.
Wow.
It's so big, and the
water's a beautiful color.
I can't see anything...
Ocean Hell
The Ocean Hell, said to have been formed
by an eruption of Mt. Tsurumitake.
The Stone Monk Hell, where
boiling bubbles of mud
Stone Monk Hell
come bubbling up.
Mountain Hell
The Mountain Hell, where hippos
and flamingos are kept.
How scary!
How cute.
Ogre's Mountain Hell
The Mountain Ogre Hell, also
known as the Alligator Hell.
White Lake Hell
The White Lake Hell, where
Amazonian piranhas can be seen.
Waterspout Hell
The Waterspout Hell, where hot
water erupts from the ground.
Lake of Blood Hell
The Lake of Blood Hell,
where even the steam is red.
Walking through the eight hells
is the centerpiece of any visit to Beppu.
I'm taking the picture!
Okay!
Did you get it?
Yeah, want to see it?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
What is that?
That person has a huge bag.
That man...
Huh?
Come to think of it, where's Dad?
It's hard to find any clues
based on this photo alone.
Dad!
Whoa!
What are you doing by yourself?
Oh, uh...
I'm not doing anything.
Hot!
Hot, hot, hot!
What is this?
You idiot, g-give that back!
Dad, who is this person?
Who are they?
She's, uh...
Mister, I think you should tell us the truth.
Huh?
Oh, yeah.
The truth is the president
of the famous Nakadai Electric company
came to my office yesterday.
Mori Detective Agency
Your daughter has gone missing?
Yes, my daughter's name is Manami.
Nakadai Hidetora (58)
President of
Nakadai Electric
Early this morning she left a note
I'm going on a trip.
Don't worry about me.
Manami
saying she was going on
a trip and disappeared.
That's concerning.
Do you have any idea where she went?
I found this photo in my daughter's room.
Welcome to hell?
Hosogai Yozo (40)
Nakadai's Secretary
It's a ticket to the hell tour
at Beppu in Oita prefecture.
Beppu?
My daughter just recently became engaged.
She's marrying Ehara Kenichiro-kun,
Ehara Kenichiro (35)
Manami's Fiancé
the president of an IT company.
As soon as they announced their engagement,
she received that photo
from a man named Hiroyuki.
Hiroyuki?
He's a man she used to date.
I had no idea, but according
to my secretary Hosogai,
they met when she went to Beppu
to celebrate her graduation.
He's a local Japanese paper craftsman.
He wrote her several times
even after they broke up.
I think he may be using more intimate
and private photos to threaten her.
If that's true,
then he's a totally vulgar man.
My daughter probably feared
that I or her fiancé
would learn about it, and
went to see Hiroyuki alone.
That would be dangerous.
She could get caught up in
some kind of criminal activity.
What?
But if the police get involved,
this could turn into a scandal.
It would affect our company's reputation.
I don't care about the company's reputation!
I'm just worried
it could hurt Miss Manami, too.
I understand.
Allow me, Mori Kogoro, to
handle your daughter's case.
So I casually arranged
this fake family vacation.
Casually, my butt.
If you'd told us from the beginning,
we could've helped you.
Anyway, these Paradise Buns are good.
When did you get those?
While we were at the Ocean Hell.
You're appalling.
Oh, they really are good.
Right?
Yufuin Station
Yunotsubo Road
I can't believe we're openly
going on a date together.
It's like a dream.
Anyway, Takagi-kun,
I'm surprised you got time off.
What?
Aren't you handling the armed robbery case?
I thought it hadn't been solved yet.
W-Well, since I'd been stuck
doing stakeouts for so long,
Inspector Megure told me to take a vacation.
Really?
Uh... Oh!
There's something over here
that I wanted to show you.
What?
How wonderful!
Isn't it?
A-Apparently the church next
door is available for weddings.
What?
Yufuin Stained Glass Museum
Weddings?
Yes.
Okay, she's showing interest.
If things go well...
We can make some memories together.
It's beautiful.
Conan-kun, the view's better from over here!
No one else is here.
Come join me.
You idiot, you're there.
Anyway, kid,
why'd you want to stay at this inn?
This inn's shuttle was in Manami-san's photo.
Way to go, Conan-kun.
Not even Dad noticed that.
You idiot!
The great detective Mori Kogoro noticed!
What? Really?
O-Of course I did.
It seems my father hired a detective.
He's looking for me.
I don't know what you're planning,
but it's over.
Just give up.
The water sure was nice.
The outdoor bath was huge.
Huh?
What's wrong?
Didn't the woman who just passed
by look like Manami-san?
What?
Are you all right?
The red ogre...
The red ogre?
Wait!
What?
You found my daughter?
Yes.
After I told her that her
father was worried about her,
she promised to return with us tomorrow.
I see.
I'm still worried about her,
so perhaps I could go there.
Sir, you have meetings
tomorrow and the day after.
I don't care about the meetings!
I'll be taking the first
train over in the morning.
Look after her until then.
Understood.
Why?
There aren't any footsteps anywhere.
Where did those cuts come from?
Hayami Hiroyuki?
Nakadai Manami (22)
President Nakadai's Daughter
He's my ex-boyfriend.
We were seeing each other
until six months ago.
Did your ex send you this photo?
Yes.
I had just gotten engaged.
I was scared, so I called Hiroyuki.
He asked me to come to Beppu right away.
In other words,
he threatened you using a photo.
There are even more intimate
photos of you and Hiroyuki,
and he wanted you to buy them from him.
What intimate photos?
For example, uh...
Of you kissing.
Dad, you can't ask that. It's rude.
Is it possible the ogre we saw
last night was Hiroyuki-san?
I'm not sure.
In any case,
I wanted to keep Hiroyuki a secret
from my dad and fiancé.
Your fiancé Ehara Kenichiro-san
is a company president
who makes two billion a year, right?
On top of that, he's a fashion icon.
It's amazing.
Do you have any photos of Hiroyuki-san?
I do.
They're from six months ago, though.
Here.
Hayami Hiroyuki (31)
Japanese Paper Artist
He's not the man in the sunglasses.
The mist is so romantic.
This is my chance!
I should ask her to get
married in that church.
S-Sato-san, u-u-um...
What?
This is Sato.
Who could be calling right now?
Inspector Megure?
What?
You found the car used in the armed robbery?
It's at the parking lot
of the Oita Marine Palace
Aquarium Umitamago, right?
Oita?
What?
Takagi-kun is home sick with a cold?
Got it.
I can handle it myself.
I'll head to Oita immediately.
S-Sorry.
I wanted to take time off together.
Don't bother making excuses!
I'm sorry!
If you're a real cop,
you can make up for it by working.
Let's go.
Y-Yes, ma'am.
Oita Station
We've been waiting for you, sir.
Good work, Mori-san.
This is Manami's fiancé Ehara-kun.
I'm Ehara.
I joined the president since I was worried
about Manami-san as well.
Does Ehara-san know about Hiroyuki-san?
I told him everything,
but he said he was willing
to accept her past.
I see.
So, where's Manami?
She's changing in her room.
She should be coming out soon.
Welcome to hell.
She's taking a long time, though.
I'll go check on her.
Manami-san!
I'm opening the door.
Dad, come quickly!
Manami-san is...
Why was the room ransacked like this?
Dad, the emergency exit is open!
These tire tracks are fresh.
They look brand new.
Mori-san, where's Manami?
Someone may have taken her away.
Taken her away?
Hello?
Is this President Nakadai?
Wh-Who are you?
I have your daughter Manami.
What?
If you want her returned unharmed,
get me 100 million yen in cash.
100 million?
If you contact the police,
your daughter is dead.
Okay.
I'll do as you say, so please
return my daughter unharmed.
I'll call again in an hour.
Is the culprit Hiroyuki?
I think it's likely.
Something's not right.
There's something behind this kidnapping.
We're Sato and Takagi from the MPD.
We appreciate your cooperation.
Thank you for coming.
Oita Prefectural Police
It doesn't look abandoned.
The culprit could be nearby.
Nearby.
It's possible the culprit
will try to attack us.
Allow me to transport the ransom money.
Ran-neechan, you have a highlighter, right?
Yeah, but why?
Hey, kid.
What are you doing?
This is Nakadai.
Did you get the money?
Yes.
Put the money in Manami's yellow bag
and come to the Takasakiyama Zoo.
The Takasakiyama Zoo?
Have Ehara Kenichiro transport the money.
Ehara-kun?
Get here within thirty minutes.
Wh-Why did he say my name?
If the culprit is Hiroyuki-san,
then it would make sense for him
to know the name of Manami-san's fiancé.
He's not planning to harm me, is he?
It's all right.
I'll be with you.
Ehara-kun, Manami's life is on the line.
Please do as the culprit says.
All right.
Oita Marine Palace Aquarium Umitamago
Welcome to the Oita Marine
Palace Aquarium Umitamago.
Takagi-kun, I don't see anyone who
looks like the culprit over here.
Neither do I.
The Takasakiyama Zoo is on
the other side of the road.
I'm going to go check it out.
Takasakiyama Zoo
Apparently they have 1,500 wild monkeys.
Really?
It's supposed to be good luck if a
monkey walks between your legs.
Wow, that's a lot of monkeys.
I-I don't think I'll be able to find him here.
H-Hey!
Hey, wait!
This is it.
What's going on?
Hey! Give that back!
Hey, Takagi.
What?
M-Mori-san?
I'm in the middle of investigating
a kidnapping case.
Stay out of my way.
I'm here investigating an armed robbery.
An armed robbery?
Mori-san!
I can't handle all this responsibility.
What are you talking about?
Manami-san's life depends on this.
What should we do?
Hello?
Leave the bag on top of Monkey Rock.
Monkey Rock?
Monkey Rock is a rock that
looks like a monkey in profile
that brings happiness to
couples who view it together.
It's that way!
There it is.
Is this safe to climb?
Shut up.
We don't have time for that right now.
Where is the culprit coming from?
Now we just have to wait for him to show up.
Wait!
Damn it.
Conan!
Conan-kun!
Episode Preview
Takagi-kun, where are you?
Sato-san, don't do anything
until I get there.
I'm arresting you for armed robbery.
Hey, where's the culprit's car?
We can't see it anymore.
Sato-san, I'm on my way!
The Descent Into Hell Tour of Love
(Oita Chapter)
The next episode of Conan is "The Descent
Into Hell Tour of Love, Oita Chapter!"
Shoes
Ready, and...
Next Conan's hint!
Shoes!
Don't miss the next episode.
We're finally...
...alone together.
I'm here, too.