Detective Conan Episode 852 "The Descent
Into Hell Tour of Love (Oita Chapter)"
Ran and I were invited by the old man
to come to the Beppu hot springs in Oita.
However, the old man's true aim
was to find Nakadai Manami-san,
the missing daughter of a company president.
Nakadai Manami (22)
President Nakadai's Daughter
Fortunately, we were able to find Manami-san,
but when her father President Nakadai,
his secretary Hosogai, and
her fiancé Ehara arrived,
Ehara Kenichiro (35)
Manami's Fiancé
the unthinkable occurred.
Hello?
Nakadai Hidetora (58)
President of Nakadai Electric
Is this President Nakadai?
Wh-Who are you?
I have your daughter Manami.
What?!
If you want her returned unharmed,
get me 100 million yen in cash.
Damn it!
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
Armed robbery is followed by a
kidnapping at the hot springs.
Where will Conan's deduction lead him?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Descent Into Hell Tour of Love
(Oita Chapter)
"The Descent Into Hell Tour
of Love, Oita Chapter!"
This way!
Conan-kun, are you okay?
Y-Yeah...
Ouch.
Mori-san, what kidnapping
are you talking about?
Manami-san, the daughter of
Nakadai Electric's president,
was kidnapped.
What?
It was a Nakadai Electric's vehicle that
was attacked in the armed robbery, too.
What?
It happened three weeks ago.
The culprit seemed to know
there was cash in the car.
Nakadai Electric
But the sudden impact warped the car
so the hatchback couldn't be opened.
Fortunately, the 100 million yen was safe.
The kidnappers ransom's
was 100 million yen, too,
and he also went after Nakadai Electric.
It's hard to imagine it's a coincidence.
It must be the same men behind both crimes.
Hello?
Takagi-kun, where are you?
It's an emergency.
A kidnapping has occurred over here.
A kidnapping?
The daughter of Nakadai Electric's
president was kidnapped,
and the kidnapper just ran
off with the ransom money.
Wait.
What?
The culprit showed up.
The culprit showed up?!
Sato-san, don't do anything
until I get there!
Sato-san?
Don't move.
I'm Sato of the MPD.
I'm arresting you for armed robbery.
Stop resisting!
You're the one who should stop resisting.
Huh?
Could this be...?
Damn it!
What is he planning to do to my Sato-san?!
There he is!
After him!
Are you involved in the kidnapping, too?
Shut up and drive.
Damn it.
I won't let them get away.
Hey, where's the culprit's car?
We can't see it anymore.
They're north-northwest.
Conan-kun?
Mister, turn left at this signal.
Why are you telling me what to do?
When the drone carried me away,
Damn it!
I stuck a transmitter on
the bottom of the bag.
It's Takagi's rental car.
Sato-san, I'm on my way.
Where are we going?
To hell.
What?
The Ocean Hell.
Hiroyuki and I will split the 100
million 50 million each there.
Hiroyuki?
Who's Hiroyuki?
I don't know.
I've never met him.
What?
He found me on an illegal site.
Apparently he has a grudge
against Nakadai Electric.
A grudge?
He was laid off after they brought in
drones for deliveries and security.
So were you.
You worked at Nakadai Electric, didn't you?
Shut up!
Turn right here!
Way to go, Sato-san.
Her driving technique is
as incredible as ever.
What are you doing?
The culprit's getting away!
He's not getting away!
Head towards the torii.
Walk faster.
Quit wasting time.
Is that you, Hiroyuki?
Conan-kun?
Stay out of my way, kid.
Your plan ends here, mister.
You should give yourself up.
What?
Sato-san!
Takagi-kun, stay away.
Crap.
Damn it.
I'll send you all to hell!
It's an emergency! Look over here!
I can't see anything.
Sato-san, run!
Takagi-kun, get him.
Yes, ma'am.
The culprit is Ogikubo Ryuji.
Ogikubo Ryuji (45)
He was formerly an employee
at Nakadai Electric.
Hey, where's Manami?!
Where is she?!
I don't know.
Ask Hiroyuki.
Hiroyuki?
Hiroyuki...
Hosogai Yozo (40)
Nakadai's Secretary
Is something wrong?
N-No.
We need to find the bag
with the ransom money.
These two cases...
Could it be?
I found it.
I-It's gone!
The ransom money is gone!
What?
I see.
So that's how it is.
What's going on?
Where is Manami and the ransom money?!
I-I don't know.
Manami-san is probably with Hiroyuki.
With Hiroyuki?
When Manami-san came to Beppu,
she left a note, right?
Which means she probably left a
note in her room at the inn, too.
A note?
What are you talking about?
How could she have left a
note when she was kidnapped?
Hiroyuki probably told this man
to throw away a note if he found one.
Yeah, that's right.
Since the girl left a note,
Dad, I'm sorry. Please
just wait one more day.
Manami
I balled it up and put it in my left pocket.
What?
Is it in this pocket?
You're right.
In other words, Manami-san wasn't kidnapped.
She wasn't kidnapped?
Hiroyuki, can I take off the blindfold now?
Go ahead.
Hiroyuki, did you make this?
I did.
I call it "Manami."
Why didn't you tell me?
The photo I sent you was an invitation.
Hayami Hiroyuki (31)
Japanese Paper Artist
This was supposed to be for an exhibition.
But when I saw the news
that you were engaged,
I knew you wouldn't come unless I did this.
I've been waiting for you this whole time.
You're the one who abandoned me.
I tried sending you letters plenty of times,
but you never responded.
Letters?
I never got those.
I knew it.
Hiroyuki.
Naturally, it's my fault.
Because I was so absorbed in my work,
those six months passed
in the blink of an eye.
But I was determined to finish
in time for our anniversary.
Our anniversary?
We met a year ago today.
You remembered.
Yeah.
Oita Prefectural Police
We're going to escort
Ogikubo to the Oita police.
Thank you for your help.
Hello?
Manami?
What?
Oita Prefectural Art Museum
Dad!
Manami!
I'm glad you're all right.
I thought you had been kidnapped.
Kidnapped?
What do you mean, Dad?
Mori-san, could you explain?
Very well.
The culprit behind this case
attempted to steal 100 million yen
from a cash transport
vehicle three weeks ago.
However, because of the accident
he was unable to steal the money.
Isn't that right, Hosogai-san?
Y-Yes, I believe so.
The culprit used Hiroyuki-san's name
to convince Ogikubo Ryuji to join him.
First he had him attack the
transport vehicle, but he failed.
Next he made up the fake
kidnapping of Manami-san,
and attempted to steal the ransom money.
That's it, old man.
Your reasoning is surprisingly
on point today.
By the way, Hosogai-san,
did Manami-san ever discuss
her concerns with you
since her father was so busy?
Did she ever talk to you about Hiroyuki-san?
Yes, I did listen to her concerns.
Are you sure you didn't
want to marry Manami-san
and become the president's successor?
What are you saying, old man?!
So you plotted to use Hiroyuki-san's
name to incite a kidnapping,
break off her engagement to Ehara-san,
and destroy her relationship
with the real Hiroyuki-san—
That's enough joking around.
Both of these cases were the work of Ogikubo,
who carried out the crimes,
and a man named Hiroyuki
who was working with him.
This Hiroyuki knew which inn Manami-san
would be staying at,
and sent his accomplice Ogikubo there.
He instructed him to watch Manami-san's room
and send him information.
Try to understand, Hiroyuki.
I don't want to make my father worry.
What?
He was watching my room?
That's right.
Using a drone.
A drone?
The drone he used was equipped
with a camera and mic.
Then what I saw outside my room last night...
They were the two red lights
and the "horns" formed by
their reflection of the drone.
Because the sound of the
waterfall is so loud there,
it covers the drone's engine noise.
With the pine branches surrounding it,
its silhouette looked exactly like an ogre.
Isn't that right, Conan?
Yeah.
That's why there weren't any
footprints left outside the window.
And there were marks left on the pine tree
by the drone's propeller.
Ogikubo, who was staying at
the same inn as Manami-san,
received instructions from Hiroyuki
to take the note she left
and ransack the room,
as though she had been kidnapped.
If she'd been taken by force,
she wouldn't have put on her new shoes.
However, in the room
was the empty box of a
pair of brand new shoes.
Wasn't that because her
fiancé Ehara-kun was coming?
Manami-san couldn't have
known Ehara-san was coming.
You put on the new shoes
because you were meeting
the real Hiroyuki-san, didn't you?
Yes.
Manami-san,
you're engaged to Ehara-san.
I only agreed to it because you interfered
with my relationship with Hiroyuki.
You must've known I always loved him
because I told you about it.
Is this true, Hosogai?
What?
I-I just...
That's right.
The man who used Ogikubo
and called himself Hiroyuki
as he manipulated us from beyond the steam...
A man very familiar with Manami-san
and Hiroyuki-san's relationship.
A man capable of predicting
Manami-san's actions,
and a man who knew
the route of the 100 million
yen transport three weeks ago.
That's right.
It's you,
Nakadai Electric secretary
Hosogai Yozo-san!
I-Impossible.
Why would I want 100 million yen?
Since you planned to split
the money with Ogikubo,
don't you mean 50 million?
How did you plan to use 50 million yen?
Was it to hide the company
money you embezzled?
Hosogai, is this true?
I-I...
I'm sorry!
I couldn't help myself...
What did you do with the ransom money?
I don't know!
I really don't know!
It wasn't Hosogai-san who
stole the 100 million yen.
There's someone who tried
to use this incident to
swipe the 100 million.
What?
That person is
Ehara-san!
D-Don't be ridiculous!
Why would I steal 100 million
when I make two billion a year?!
Ehara-san,
your business has been
doing worse, hasn't it?
I heard you rushed your
engagement to Manami-san
because you were after
Nakadai-san's wealth.
How rude.
What proof do you have?
For example,
a fashionable man like you was
on his way to meet his fiancée.
So why were you dressed
in clothes you already
wore in a men's magazine?
And you weren't wearing your several
million yen watch today either.
Are you sure you didn't sell it
because you're short on cash?
Don't be absurd.
My clothes and watch don't make me a thief.
That's not all.
While you were waiting in the rest
area with the ransom money...
W-Wait!
There was quite the commotion.
This is it.
You switched out
the stacks of bills for magazines.
Only you could've done it.
If we search underneath the
shelves at the rest area,
I'm sure we'll find the money.
What proof do you have that I did it?
If you've got any, show me!
The proof is right there.
Conan, you marked the bills
with a highlighter, didn't you?
Yeah.
If anyone touched that money,
it would've left highlighter on their hands.
Hiroyuki-kun.
Yes.
This is a wonderful sculpture.
With the new light bulbs we developed,
it would shine even more beautifully.
Why don't you give them a shot?
Thank you!
Dad!
I'm so glad.
That's great.
Yeah.
Huh?
Hell Steam Workshop Kannawa
Is it ready yet?
Put them in here.
Oita's hell steam is the best.
Dad, don't drink too much.
Anyway, I'm surprised you two
were on a secret vacation here.
Please don't tell the inspector.
Since you arrested the culprit,
the inspector will probably forgive you.
Even if he does,
I won't.
I'm not letting you get away
with faking an illness to take time off work.
Now that's a truly hellish!
Just kidding!
A beer after a solved case
sure does taste great.
Right?
No Alcohol Allowed
Non-alcoholic Beer
I'm the one who solved it.
Right?
Episode Preview
Come to think of it,
I thought I heard something fall
when I picked up the shoehorn.
I'm sure you can put it
back together with glue.
We'll have to ask your kindergarten teacher
to make you a new one.
It's done.
Make me one, too.
What?
That's a cherry blossom, isn't it?
Memories From Sakura Class
(Ran GIRL)
The next episode of Conan is "Memories
From Sakura Class, Ran GIRL!"
Nameplate
Next Conan's hint.
A nameplate!
Sakura class, huh?
Don't miss the next episode.
That brings back memories.
Yeah, it sure does.
Why would it for you, Conan-kun?
Uh, oh.