This way!
If it's nothing special, I'm going
to make you buy me something.
There's nothing wrong with
a detour once in a while.
Yeah.
This is it.
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
We were willing to take a detour
to see the beautiful cherry
blossoms and Ran's memories.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Memories From Sakura Class
(Ran GIRL)
"Memories From Sakura Class, Ran GIRL!"
They're beautiful.
The cherry blossoms are in full bloom.
Yeah.
Conan-kun was right.
This was the right way to go.
Good job, kid.
I thought they were pretty when I walked
through here with my friends yesterday.
Looking at cherry blossoms reminds me
of when I met Shinichi.
I doubt Shinichi knows,
but back then...
I hated him.
What?
13 Years Ago
Hey, honey...
I left Ran's name tag here.
Do know where it went?
It's on the kitchen table.
That's the Tulip Class one
she used until last year.
Starting today, I'm in Sakura Class.
Oh, right!
I was going to pin it on her when
we went to preschool today,
so I left it on the shoe cupboard.
Have you seen it?
Come to think of it,
I thought I heard something fall
when I picked up the shoehorn.
Sakura Class
Mori Ran
Crap. I stepped on it.
You're kidding.
It's in pieces.
Sorry.
I'm sure you can put it
back together with glue.
I don't think that'll be enough to fix this.
W-Well, today's my first day at headquarters.
Hey, wait.
Sheesh...
We'll have to ask your preschool
teacher to make you a new one.
What will I do until then?
It's okay.
I'll make you a new name tag.
Could you get the colored
paper and cardboard?
Yeah.
Give up.
She's not coming back.
No.
Not that!
What do you want me to do, then?
Reset everything.
It'll go better this time.
There are no time constraints
to starting over.
I was moved, Kudo-sensei.
Thank you.
Book Publishing Signing
Especially by the words of the
wandering woman detective at the end.
"There are no time constraints
to starting over."
It was like she was talking to me.
It gave me goosebumps.
You're that girl from Hokkaido
who came to the last
signing event, aren't you?
You remembered me.
Thank you.
Has the late snow that was just falling
turned to rain yet?
Oh, no.
This is just an old habit.
I see.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry for taking up so much of your time.
Thank you.
Hello?
Oh, Yukiko.
What?
Shinichi's preschool name tag?
Yeah, the cherry blossom shaped one.
It's made of plastic.
Shin-chan's starting at a
new preschool today.
I wrote his name on it and left it
on the desk in the study last night.
Have you seen it?
No.
I hurriedly stuffed the pen and glasses case
that were on the desk in my
pocket when I left, though.
Sakura Class
Kudo Shinichi
This must be it.
I knew it!
You took it with you.
It's because you left it on the study desk.
But the perfect pen was right here.
I'll stop by when I take
Shin-chan to preschool.
Wait for me.
Don't forget to wear a hat
and glasses when you come.
You'll cause a commotion
if people know it's you.
Okay!
Shin-chan, let's go.
Shinichi?
Where are you?
Beika Preschool
Huh?
Ran-chan, what happened to your badge?
My mom made it for me.
My other one broke.
It looks just like ours!
There's a safety pin on the back,
so I can put it on and take it off.
See?
You're right.
Your mom's a genius.
Here.
What is this?
It's just paper.
Lame.
Anyone wearing this isn't one of us.
Yeah, yeah.
You're an outsider.
Hey, give that back.
No way.
Give it back!
Sonoko-chan?
Sonoko-chan!
Come on.
Shake hands.
There.
Now you've made up.
Efune Ronsuke (39)
Preschool Teacher
Ran-chan, your new name tag
should be ready by next week.
Can you wait until then?
Yeah.
Sorry, Ran-chan.
I tried to get it back,
but now it's all wrinkled.
That's okay.
I watched my mom make it.
First you fold it in half,
then you fold it in half again.
Then you open it up,
fold the top part down along
the creases in the middle,
and unfold it.
Next you fold this part in along
the creases in the middle,
unfold it, and then...
And then...
You can do it.
You're almost there.
You're almost finished.
Then you draw a line here
and cut along the line.
It's done.
Make me one, too.
What?
It's a cherry blossom, right?
Am I wrong?
That's right.
But how did you know?
How?
Are you making fun of me?
Look at the badges on top of the
folded clothes by everyone's head.
Everyone in this row has cherry blossoms.
Everyone in the next row has tulips.
But how is that enough to know
I'm making a cherry blossom?
Because you're the only one
without a badge on their clothes.
Besides,
the fold you used makes ten
equally sized sections out
of square origami paper.
Since you're cutting it into this shape,
it'll be a cherry blossom when you unfold it.
That's how I knew
you lost your cherry blossom badge
and were crying while
making a new one, crybaby.
You're amazing!
It's like you're psychic.
You idiot, I'm not psychic.
And I'm not a crybaby.
But you were crying.
No, I wasn't.
Were, too.
No, I wasn't!
Shin-chan, there you are.
Don't disappear while I'm filling
out admissions paperwork.
Mom...
What happened to your name tag?
You were wearing it a minute ago.
I lost it.
You can't be serious.
We went all the way to the signing to get it.
Is she a lady spy?
I was going to have her make a
cherry blossom badge for me.
Oh, you...
Are you Eri-chan's daughter Ran-chan?
Y-Yeah.
So we're attending the same preschool.
Uh, ma'am?
If you can't find it,
we can get you a new name tag,
along with Ran-chan's by next week.
Oh, really?
If you want a cherry blossom,
you can have this one.
O-Okay.
I'll write your name for you.
What's your name?
Huh?
Oh.
Kudo Shinichi, Sakura Class.
Kudo...
Shinichi...
Th-Thanks.
Here.
It's done.
Sakura Class
Kudo Shinichi
You can keep it, so promise me, Shinichi-kun.
I'm not a crybaby,
so don't call me a crybaby again.
"Don't call me a crybaby again!"
Isn't that what you shouted
while glaring at him?
Really?
Because he was acting like an adult,
even though he was just another kid.
When I thought that
he might think all other kids are idiots,
I wanted to say something to him.
I was actually crying because
the badge my mom made for me
was ruined.
So she was crying.
Besides, I didn't understand the real reason
Shinichi had me make a
cherry blossom for him.
I was angry.
The real reason?
Yes.
That cherry blossom was actually...
Shut them, open them.
Clap your hands and shut them.
Open them and clap your hands...
What are you looking at?
Huh?
What do you mean?
You've been staring at her this whole time.
What?
That's not true.
Okay, everyone.
That's enough singing.
Let's get ready to go for a walk.
Okay!
Are you stupid?
Efune-sensei was watching
everyone because he's the teacher.
Really?
Yeah, and everyone's watching Efune-sensei.
Efune-sensei is popular.
Lots of kids want to marry Efune-sensei
when they grow up.
Really?
Do you like him, too?
Why would I tell you, Shinichi-kun?
Are you dumb?
Really?
What?
Sorry.
You think he doesn't like me?
Forget him.
He keeps saying weird stuff.
Wait.
Does everyone know what to do?
While walking in a crosswalk,
hold your hand in the air.
Okay.
Come on. Shinichi-kun, raise your hand.
Hooray!
Beika Children's Park
You just got to slide.
So did you.
Stop fighting.
Hey, now.
No fighting.
Friends should get along.
Got it?
Okay...
Ran-chan, do you want to slide?
Yeah.
Sorry, kids.
Could you let Ran-chan through?
Hooray!
Shinichi-kun, come slide with me.
It's fun.
Hey, Shinichi-kun.
Sensei, slide with us.
What?
I don't think I can.
Okay, everyone.
It's time for your afternoon nap.
Lay your futons
out in a line according to your class.
Oh, sorry, Shinichi-kun.
This is Ran-chan's spot.
Sorry, Shinichi-kun.
Don't you think that's weird?
What?
Why is she the only one
with a designated spot?
Oh, because...
Besides the futons, you've done
three other suspicious things.
Why do you always hold her hand
when we walk to the park?
And on the slide,
even though there were kids waiting in line,
you let her slide first.
In the first place,
that park's farther away than
the one we've been going to.
There are two extra crosswalks,
so it's more dangerous.
Why did you change the park we go to?
Efune-sensei?
You're planning to win her over
so you can do something bad, aren't you?
Confess!
What's so funny?!
Sorry, sorry.
I hold Ran-chan's hand while we go for walks
because she once got separated from the group,
and ended up in Haido City
on the other side of town.
I let her slide first
because she's a nice girl
who lets everyone go before her,
so there have been times when
she didn't get to slide.
And the reason Ran-chan's spot is here
is because it's closest to the bathroom.
Bathroom
One time she didn't make it in time
because she was sleeping
far away from the bathroom.
What?
You wet yourself because you didn't
make it to the bathroom in time?
D-Don't say that so loud!
You idiot!
Idiot.
Also, I'll tell you why we switched parks
when we go on a walk tomorrow,
little detective.
The Next Day
Okay, everyone.
Raise your hand when you're
walking in a crosswalk.
Okay!
What's wrong, Ran-chan?
You seem down.
Is it because of those mean
things that kid said yesterday?
No.
My mom got mad at me last night.
She said I shouldn't be mean to my friends.
What?
I haven't been mean to anyone, have I?
No.
If anything, I think you're
the one being bullied.
Okay, everyone. Be careful.
Hurry up and tell me.
Why did you decide to come to this park?
Because walking farther
will help build your strength,
and you'll have an easier time
remembering traffic rules
if we cross more crosswalks.
And the biggest reason I chose this park
is her.
Her?
See the hospital next to the park
behind the cherry trees?
There's a woman in that
hospital looking this way.
She's actually
my wife.
What?
Your wife?
You mean you're married?
Yeah.
She's always been sickly,
so she's been in the hospital for a while.
Next month she's moving to a hospital
in the mountains where the air is better.
But all the people who
live there are elderly.
There aren't any children like you.
So I thought I'd show her
you guys until she moved.
After all, she loves children.
So honestly,
it was just me being selfish.
That's okay!
Why don't we wave to her?
Yeah!
Let's wave.
No way.
I'm not listening to someone
wearing a weird badge.
Yeah, yeah.
After all, you're an outsider.
You're wrong.
What?
Can't you see?
My badge is made
of paper just like hers.
Then you're an outsider, too.
But if there's two of us, then we're friends.
And if we're friends,
then we're not outsiders!
Oh, right.
He was watching.
Anyone wearing this isn't one of us.
Yeah, yeah.
You're an outsider.
He was watching me then.
That's why he actually...
Make me one, too.
It's a cherry blossom, right?
What happened to your name tag?
I lost it.
My badge is made of paper just like hers.
If we're friends, then we're not outsiders!
And
you'll never beat me.
Remember that.
Shinichi, wave to the teacher's wife.
Sh-Shinichi?
What about honorifics?
You can call me by my name, too.
On the back of cherry blossom petals,
I made a new childhood friend.
Episode Preview
There's definitely something wrong with him.
Wrong how?
He's probably planning to win
her over and do something bad.
Oh, really?
Shin-chan, are you sure you're not jealous
because that teacher's giving
Ran-chan all his attention?
A-Are you stupid? It's not like that!
Memories From Sakura Class
(Shinichi BOY)
The next episode of Conan is "Memories
From Sakura Class, Shinichi BOY!"
Colored Paper
Next Conan's hint!
Colored paper!
Shin-chan, you were so cute back then.
Don't miss the next episode.
You're still small and cute.
Shut up.