What? No way!
So Shinichi-kun acted like he solved
the mystery of the cherry blossom badge
through reasoning when he
actually just saw what happened?
Maybe.
Back then, I thought he was amazing.
I wish I could take that back.
He just wanted to impress a girl.
Besides,
it sounds like he wanted to
protect you from your bullies.
You idiot.
All I saw through the window
then was a girl who was upset
because she had something taken from her,
and the word "outsider."
It was the first time
in my life that I experienced
solving a heart-pounding mystery.
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
Ran and I met in Sakura Class.
Hiding in the shadows was
an adults' conspiracy.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Memories From Sakura Class
(Shinichi BOY)
"Memories From Sakura Class, Shinichi BOY!"
I'll stop by when I take
Shin-chan to preschool.
Wait for me.
Don't forget to wear a hat
and glasses when you come.
You'll cause a commotion
if people know it's you.
Okay!
Shin-chan, let's go.
Shinichi?
Where are you?
If one simply knocks out
all the central inferences,
and presents one's audience with the
starting-point and the conclusion,
Sherlock Holmes Series
The Adventure of
the Dancing Men
one may produce a startling, though
possibly a meretricious, effect.
I found you!
What are you doing?
I'm still in the middle of reading this book!
I told you we're going to
your new preschool today.
I don't need to go there!
Besides, you'll have to
wear glasses like Yusaku
if you read in the dark.
I-I'll never wear glasses.
It's Fujimine Yukiko!
Wh-What?
That's odd. I'm wearing a hat and glasses.
Yeah, ones that scream that you're an actress.
Here's the cherry blossom name tag.
Now stop stealing the spotlight at my event.
Got it.
Shin-chan, put this on your
chest so we can get out of here.
Yeah, I know.
Sakura Class
Kudo Shinichi
Beika Preschool
The last thing I'd like
to ask about is allergies.
Efune Ronsuke (39)
Preschool Teacher
Is there anything we shouldn't
feed Shinichi-kun?
Like eggs, noodles, or cheese?
No, not in particular.
He doesn't like raisins.
He hates them.
Let's see.
Where's the library?
Seriously? There's no library.
Oh, they're just sleeping in rows.
I thought it was a morgue like the one
I saw in that movie the other day.
This row is Apple Class.
The next row is Tulip Class.
And the top row
is Sakura Class.
Good children, good children.
She's the one who had
something taken from her.
Since her clothes are the
only ones missing a badge,
she must've had her badge taken from her.
But what's she making?
Wait a minute.
I've seen that fold before.
That's the fold Dad used to make stars
to decorate the Christmas tree.
Dad made stars by making
a straight diagonal cut,
so the curved cut she's making would make...
A cherry blossom!
That must be it!
Since she had her badge
taken from her earlier,
she's making a new one out of paper.
Damn it.
I want to ask her if I'm right.
Holmes said if one simply knocks
out all the central inferences,
and presents one's audience with the
starting-point and the conclusion,
one may produce a startling,
though possibly a meretricious effect.
Will she be surprised?
Will she be impressed?
No...
Anyone wearing this isn't one of us.
What was taken from her
wasn't a plastic badge.
It's done!
Make me one, too.
What?
It's a cherry blossom, right?
Why does she look so puzzled?
A-Am I...?
Am I wrong?
That's right.
But how did you know?
I was right!
How?
Are you making fun of me?
Now if I clearly explain
to her why I thought that,
she should be surprised.
That's how I knew
you lost your cherry blossom badge,
and were crying while
making a new one, crybaby.
Okay, how's that?
Will she be surprised like Watson?
Is she impressed?
Th-They're all surprised.
This is amazing!
Holmes is amazing!
You're amazing!
It's like you're psychic.
You idiot, I'm not psychic.
Then this girl must be surprised, too.
What?
She's mad?
And I'm not a crybaby.
What?
But you were crying.
No, I wasn't.
Were, too.
No, I wasn't!
She has tears in her eyes right now.
Shin-chan, there you are.
Don't disappear while I'm filling
out admissions paperwork.
Mom...
What happened to your name tag?
You were wearing it a minute ago.
I lost it.
I need to make sure she
doesn't find the name tag
that I'm hiding in my pocket.
What's wrong with him?
Who's he looking at?
It's this girl.
But why?
Uh, ma'am?
If you can't find it,
we can get you a new name tag,
along with Ran-chan's by next week.
Oh, really?
If you want a cherry blossom,
you can have this one.
Okay...
I'll write your name for you.
What's your name?
Huh?
Oh.
Kudo Shinichi, Sakura Class.
Kudo...
Shinichi...
Th-Thanks.
Here.
It's done.
Sakura Class
Kudo Shinichi
You can keep it, so promise me, Shinichi-kun.
I'm not a crybaby,
so don't call me a crybaby again.
Now, now.
Don't fight.
And Shinichi-kun, you shouldn't
call people crybabies.
Who are you?
I'm Efune Ronsuke.
I'm your teacher.
Nice to meet you.
Yeah, nice to meet you.
There's definitely something wrong with him!
Definitely!
You mean Efune-sensei from preschool?
Yeah.
Wrong how?
He has a designated spot for her
to sleep during nap time.
When we go for walks,
he holds her hand the whole time.
At the park we went to on our walk,
he let her skip the line on the slide.
He calls her name loudly, too.
He's probably planning to win her over
and do something bad.
Really?
So who's the girl?
Huh?
Oh, u-um...
A-A girl named Ran.
Oh, really?
Shin-chan, are you sure you're not jealous
because that teacher's giving
Ran-chan all his attention?
A-Are you stupid?!
It's not like that!
It's not like that at all!
It is a problem if he's
playing favorites, though.
Did you ask your teacher why?
Yeah.
Ran sleeps closest to the
bathroom because one time
while she was sleeping far away
from it, she didn't make it in time.
He holds her hand on walks
because she has a really
poor sense of direction
and once got separated from the
group and ended up somewhere crazy.
And he let her slide first
because she lets everyone go before her.
So he has a reason for everything.
Come to think of it,
didn't you say your walking route changed
and you started going to a new park?
Y-Yeah.
He said he'd tell me why
tomorrow when we go for a walk.
I see.
But aren't you just being jealous?
I told you, that's not it!
He definitely looks at her
with the eyes of a bad guy!
I won't let him beat me.
Hey.
Shinichi, does Ran-chan sleep
longer than the other kids?
Yeah.
She always sleeps soundly
until she's the last one up.
Yu-chan, do you have an idea?
I have a fan who shares the name
Efune with Shinichi's teacher.
Shinichi-kun has a quick mind and
sometimes comes into conflict
with the other children,
but he should settle down
as he gets accustomed
to the preschool.
Let's wait and see
how he does.
Efune Ronsuke
She's from Hokkaido, though.
The Next Day
What's wrong, Ran-chan?
You seem down.
My mom got mad at me last night.
She said I shouldn't be mean to my friends.
What?
I haven't been mean to anyone, have I?
No.
If anything, I think you're
the one being bullied.
Okay, everyone. Be careful.
Beika Children's Park
And the biggest reason I chose this park
is her.
She's actually
my wife.
What?
Your wife?
You mean you're married?
Two Days Later
What?
A black van?
Yeah.
It's been parked outside the rear
exit of the preschool for a while.
Should we report it to the police?
Maybe.
We might want to write down its license
plate number just in case, too.
Wh-Why don't I go check it out?
Efune-sensei.
Could you do that, please?
Be careful.
Give up.
She's not coming back.
No.
Not that!
What do you want me to do, then?
Reset everything.
It'll go better this time.
No.
There are no time constraints
to starting over.
Let's not do this!
Let's not have this conversation in the rain.
Come sit in the passenger seat.
Wh-Who are you?
A simple novelist who's been
gaining popularity recently.
A novelist?
Where is he?
This is my brother-in-law's van.
Oh, my detective friend
who was staking out
the place arrested him
when he tried to break in through
the preschool's bathroom window.
He's being questioned by
the police right now.
Under suspicion of breaking and entering,
and attempted kidnapping of a young girl.
Your brother-in-law was attempting
to kidnap a girl named Mori Ran.
Each day you held her hand
so your brother-in-law
would know which child to kidnap.
You called her name loudly
and raised her to the top
of the slide near the hospital window
so your wife could get a good look at her,
and confirm that she was
the child she wanted.
And you had her sleep
next to the bathroom
so she'd be closest when your
brother-in-law broke into the bathroom.
Didn't the accident you
mentioned as the reason
why she slept near the bathroom happen
because you'd been slipping her sedatives
so she'd be easier to kidnap?
Children become confused when given sedatives,
and sometimes do things they don't want to.
You did all of this to make it seem
as though you were favoring her
so the other children would resent
and begin bullying her.
By writing in her correspondence notebook
that she was bullying other children,
you made her parents unfairly lecture her,
so you'd become the only
person she could depend on.
In other words,
you were attempting to win her over
so you'd be able to happily live
together even after you kidnapped her.
Just like my son suspected.
Y-Your son?
Yes.
You actually meant to spend
more time winning her over,
but you had to rush your plan since
my son nearly discovered you.
But I imagine my son
has locked the bathroom
window after you left,
per my instructions,
Bathroom
and is standing in front of
the bathroom door right now
in order to protect her.
My wife suffers from neurosis,
so my brother-in-law and I were forced to
Because your daughter ran away from home?
H-How do you know that?
Your wife likely broke down
after your daughter ran away from home,
and wanted to raise a child
again from preschool age,
when your daughter was cutest.
Yes.
On top of attempting suicide several times,
she became anorexic.
I couldn't just watch my
wife waste away day by day.
Could we leave my wife out of this?
No, your wife should've turned herself
into the police by now with your daughter.
M-My daughter?
I have a fan named Efune.
She had an umbrella with her,
even though she was from Hokkaido.
She said it was an old habit.
Most Hokkaido residents don't
use umbrellas in the snow,
which means it was likely she grew
up somewhere outside Hokkaido.
Not only that, but she said the last line
of the female detective in the novel
I wrote felt like it was written for her.
Kudo Yusaku
The Missing Body
It's when the detective finds a
runaway who faked their suicide,
and tells them there are no time
constraints to starting over,
in order to convince them
to return to their parents.
Since that line left an impression on her,
I thought she might be a runaway as well.
If you want to see your daughter,
turn yourself in before my friends
who are waiting nearby lose their patience.
The next day,
the preschool children were surprised
to learn Efune-sensei had quit.
Most of the kids who liked him cried.
Hey, listen.
You can cry when you feel like it, Ran.
I won't call you a crybaby anymore.
"You can cry when you feel like it?"
What a thing to say for a four year old.
Yeah.
I didn't have a choice!
She really didn't like
being called a crybaby.
Does that mean he's been in
love with you since then?
Yeah, right.
His first crush has got
to be his actress mom.
Yeah.
I doubt Ran knows,
but since the day we met...
What's your name?
K-Kudo Shinichi, Sakura Class.
Kudo...
Shinichi...
Th-Thanks.
Here.
It's done.
I've been head over heels
for that smile.
I didn't think she hated
me that much, though.
Episode Preview
Makoto-san is so cool.
Yeah, yeah.
Why don't you wear that belt?
I'm getting old.
It's time for me to give up
my black belt and retire.
Th-The belt is gone.
Kyogoku-kun, did you...?
Mystery of the Missing Black Belt
The next episode of Conan is "Mystery
of the Missing Black Belt!"
Karate Gi
Next Conan's hint!
Karate Gi.
Don't miss the next episode.
Next week's episode features a
black belt. Hattori's dark-skinned.
But our movie is crimson.
It opens next Saturday.