Stop!
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
Before tackling the Scarlet Case,
we head to a karate dojo with Sonoko.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Mystery of the Missing Black Belt
"Mystery of the Missing Black Belt!"
I'm impressed.
Makoto-san is so cool!
Yeah, yeah.
Why are you so indifferent?
They're doing us a big
favor by letting us watch.
Try to look a little happier.
You're the one who forced me to come.
I wanted to go to USJ with everyone else.
We came all the way to Osaka.
You should've brought Ran-neechan
with you to watch karate.
Ran has to watch the kids.
Besides, if Ran came,
she and Makoto-san would end
up talking about karate.
I didn't want to come alone,
so you were my only option.
Osu!
Thanks for having us!
Hiroki, your karate gi...
My old one was falling apart,
so my parents bought me a new one.
Kids' practice is starting now.
Makoto-san is their guest.
Who's the old man standing over there?
Takami Tatsuhito (70)
Tenshin Style Karate
Eighth Master
He's the eighth master of Tenshin style karate,
Takami Tatsuhito-sensei.
Really?
What's his relationship with Kyogoku-san?
I-I think they've known
each other for a long time.
While I was in grade school,
I once stopped making progress
with my karate training.
When I came to Osaka on a family trip,
I happened to meet Takami-sensei.
I practiced with him one time.
During that practice session, I...
Win without fighting.
Consider the meaning of these words.
I am who I am now because of that lesson.
Win without fighting?
What does that mean?
Doesn't it mean
you shouldn't strike the first blow?
Everyone interprets it differently.
There's no one right answer.
The children's practice is starting.
Take your time.
Okay!
Are you all right, Sonoko-san?
I'm fine.
I had a touch of a cold, but I'm over it now.
Anyway, that sparring you
did earlier was so cool!
Th-Thank you.
Let's begin practice.
Osu!
I'm always surprised by
the growth of children.
One, two, three, four!
Over there is Kadota Hiroki.
Five, six, seven, eight!
Kadota Hiroki (10)
His body was stiff, and he
had trouble with stretches.
One, two, three, four!
Five, six, seven, eight!
Now I hardly recognize him.
He's become somewhat of a leader recently.
He's dependable.
Next to him is Kawaguchi Katsuto.
I'm excited for his future.
His body is large, but he's timid.
He had trouble displaying his
abilities in demonstrations.
Kawaguchi Katsuto (10)
Now he's passed the shodan
test and wears a black belt.
Ah, yes.
There's also Obashi Norio.
He was a weak runner and became
exhausted before the run was over,
Obashi Norio (10)
but now he completes them easily.
Isn't that because you're a good teacher?
I'm not so sure.
Thank you for coming today.
You're a hero to the children, Kyogoku-kun.
This will be a good memory for them.
Sensei, my stomach hurts.
Would it be all right if
I skipped practice today?
Of course.
Anyway, are you all right?
Do you need someone to take you home?
No, I can make it by myself.
I should get better with some rest.
Let's begin practicing the fundamentals!
Sensei, what is that?
It's a display of the medals and
trophies I've won in various matches.
I told them not to,
but my students insisted.
What's that on top?
It's the belt the master of this
dojo has worn for generations.
It's a symbol of the blood
and sweat of our seniors.
I've been practicing hard,
so as not to bring shame upon the belt.
What's the belt you're wearing now?
An ordinary belt you'd find anywhere.
But aren't you the master of the dojo?
Why don't you wear that belt?
Sorry.
I should be getting back to practice.
What's gotten into him?
Since Takami-sensei became the master,
a lot of people quit over
his intense practices.
On top of that, he doesn't charge
the children for practice.
What?
You mean it's free?
Let's go running!
Osu!
Kyogoku-kun, we need to talk.
Yes, sir.
Takami-san.
Kajiyoshi Ginji (42)
Kajiyoshi-san.
Could I get your signature today?
Sorry.
Could you wait a little longer?
What are you talking about?
I'm here because you said you wanted
to sell this place as soon as possible.
I'm prepared to buy it
for a reasonable amount.
I have guests right now.
Whatever.
I'll be back.
Who are those guys?
I think they're black market loan sharks.
What?
If he can't pay,
they're going to take this place instead.
They could make a lot of
money selling the land.
Sensei, are you serious
about selling this place?
I'm getting old.
It's time for me to give up
my black belt and retire.
But...
Unfortunately,
there's still no one worthy
to take over the Tenshin dojo.
That's why I thought to
close it down instead.
But as far as I can tell, you're still...
I don't have the strength I once had.
The strength to wear that black belt.
Excuse me.
Takami-sensei, what's going to happen
to those kids once this place is gone?
I'm planning to ask another
dojo to take them in.
Didn't they come here because
they looked up to you?
You're being irresponsible!
Kyogoku-kun, what did you do?
Th-The belt is gone.
Kyogoku-kun, did you...?
If it were me...
What would you do?
Makoto-san, is it true?
Explain yourself.
I'd like you to reconsider closing the dojo.
What?
I'm sorry.
The decision's already been made.
Then I challenge you.
If I win, keep the dojo open.
If you win,
I'll return the belt.
Are you sure we can't reach a compromise?
Yes.
Fine.
I accept.
Sensei!
Makoto-san, don't do this!
Please!
What are we going to do?
I can't believe this is happening.
Hey.
Makoto-san, stop!
You're scaring the children!
Makoto-san!
What?
Oh, crap.
Sonoko-san?
Makoto-san didn't do it.
He's just protecting the person who did.
What?
Who has the keys to the display room?
Only me.
There's another exit.
The window in the wall.
Not even a child could
fit through that window.
There's a drainpipe.
You could use it to climb up to the window.
The drainpipe is falling apart.
It's useless.
Only Kyogoku-kun could've stolen the belt.
If you're so sure, why don't you search him?
He doesn't have it.
He could've hidden it somewhere.
Surprised by the sound of
Makoto-san breaking the lock,
we ran to the dojo.
There was no time for
Makoto-san to hide the belt.
Sensei?
She's right.
Do you know where the belt is?
Yes.
Where is it?
Kadota Hiroki-kun, Kawaguchi Katsuto-kun,
and the absent Obashi Norio-kun.
They know where it is.
Wh-What did you say?
You've been planning to
steal Takami-sensei's belt
for a while now, haven't you?
Is this true?
Why?
That's odd, though.
I was out running with the children.
They were with us the whole time.
Do you always run along the same course?
Yeah.
There's a park about five minutes from here.
We do a head count there before
running along the river.
We cross the third bridge and run
back along the opposite side,
do another head count at the park,
and come back here.
How do you explain that?
You say they were all there,
but you didn't check each
of their faces, did you?
Well?
N-No, I didn't check their faces.
They swapped places when you
first did a head count at the park.
Hiroki-kun and Obashi Norio-kun,
who had gone home earlier.
Norio-kun pretended to be
Hiroki-kun and ran with you.
What?
After leaving the park alone,
Hiroki-kun returned to the dojo.
He snuck around the back
to avoid being spotted,
climbed the wall,
took the belt from the display
case through the window,
and left.
That's ridiculous.
It's impossible for a child to
climb that wall without a rope.
It's possible using the drainpipe.
But the drainpipe's falling apart.
What if it were a small, flexible child?
Hiroki, is this true?
Did you take the belt?
He could just barely reach the belt
by putting his body through the
window and stretching his arms.
But his collar got caught
on the edge of the window.
The frayed collar on
Hiroki-kun's new karate gi
proves it.
Hiroki-kun took the belt to the park,
and waited for the others
to return from their run.
But where's the belt?
There's nowhere to hide it.
Kawaguchi Katsuto-kun.
Could you take off your belt?
Th-This is...
They didn't just switch people
at the park after the run.
They also switched belts.
Katsuto-kun was able to wear a black belt
because he just passed his shodan test.
Norio!
Why?
Why would you do this?
We wanted you to keep the dojo open.
We heard you talking on the phone.
You said you were going to close the dojo
because you lost your passion for karate.
We wanted to keep practicing here.
We wanted you to teach us more.
You said now that you
had the belt you wanted,
you had no regrets.
We thought you'd want to keep training
if the belt disappeared.
B-Boys...
Please don't quit!
Please keep the dojo open!
Please!
Makoto-san, you understood
how the children felt.
That's why you knew immediately
who did it when you noticed
the belt was missing.
The boys put their plan into motion
because they didn't want you to quit.
It took them a long time.
A long time?
That's right.
In order to climb the wall to the window,
Hiroki-kun had to make
his stiff body flexible.
Only the small Hiroki-kun could
climb the deteriorated drainpipe,
and fit through the window.
Katsuto-kun worked hard to pass his shodan
test so he could wear a black belt.
Only the large Katsuto-kun
could wear an adult-sized belt.
And Norio-kun worked to
get better at running.
He had to keep up with the others,
while pretending to be Hiroki-kun.
Boys...
You guys having a meeting?
I'm here to collect your
signature, just like we agreed.
Take off your shoes.
What?
This is a dojo.
You can't wear your shoes in here.
Who are you?
Mind your own business.
Kajiyoshi-san.
I'm sorry,
but could we forget
about what we discussed?
It seems I was wrong.
I thought I'd already done everything,
but I still have a lot to learn.
I need training.
These children taught me that.
These children—
and I—
still need this place.
All right!
Don't be ridiculous!
You expect me to just accept that now?
What's going on?!
Either return all the
money you owe immediately,
or vacate this property.
It's one or the other.
What, you wanna fight?
Fine.
Get him!
Don't get ahead of yourself!
Why don't you leave for today?
Win without fighting.
I'm still a long way away from that.
Now let's begin practice.
I'm glad a lawyer agreed
to help Takami-sensei.
I had someone look into Kajiyoshi's company,
and it was totally shady.
It was a corrupt moneylender.
Since the police will be
investigating them soon,
I doubt he'll have to pay back his loan.
Sonoko-san, thank you.
Thanks to you, the dojo will stay open.
Don't worry about that.
Makoto-san, you were as cool as ever.
I'm so glad I came to watch.
Sonoko-san, are you all right?
You have a bit of a fever.
Excuse me!
I'm fine.
Maybe your cold is coming back.
Take this.
Thanks, Makoto-san.
Are you okay?
Sonoko, your face is red.
I'm fine.
I'll be okay.
Makoto-san and I are going to have some fun.
What's going on?
You can't be serious.
Come with us, miss.
Wh-Wh-What is this?!
Did you do this, Makoto-san?
I'm sorry.
I called them.
You shouldn't underestimate a cold.
Colds lead to all kinds of illnesses.
You need rest to get better.
Let go of me!
I'm going to USJ with Makoto-san!
They're gone.
Let me out!
I'm going to USJ!
Sonoko would thank Kyogoku-san later.
Later we got caught up
in a major case involving
a TV station.
Episode Preview
That came from downstairs.
This is...
There's blood on it.
I think we can assume it was
used to commit the crime.
Detective Chiba, where did you find this?
In this apartment's dump site.
What?
The Socialite Couple's Secret
The next episode of Conan is
"The Socialite Couple's Secret!"
Closet
Next Conan's hint!
A closet!
Let me out!
Don't miss the next episode.
Do you not like being with me?
What? No, I don't mind.