Lost!
Nyan-chan (Male)
Responds when meowed at
*Reward*
Oh, Nyan-chan.
You've lost so much weight.
Thank you so much.
No problem.
Sheesh.
Why does a famous detective like
myself have to look for lost cats?
It's not so bad.
Besides, you earned a lot in rewards.
Yeah, I guess.
Let's use that money to
get something good to eat.
Ah. So, that's why you
tagged along, isn't it?
It's past noon.
Let's go to a family restaurant.
Let's go someplace better.
Yeah, when I'm by myself.
Cheapskate.
Did you say something?
No, nothing.
That came from downstairs.
Yeah.
Is something wrong?
Th-The apartment's been ransacked,
and there's blood on the floor.
Have you gone inside?
We were too scared to.
Got it.
All right. You all stay here.
I'll go check things out.
It's no use.
He's dead.
Excuse me, but could you call the police?
Huh?
Where did the other woman go?
Saki!
Wait!
Saki, open your eyes!
Miss, stand back.
She's gone.
No...
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
Two victims within the first two minutes.
The trick behind the case defies imagination.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Socialite Couple's Secret
"The Socialite Couple's Secret!"
I see.
You thought something seemed
wrong from the entryway.
Just as you were about to call
the police, he came running up.
Yes, that's right.
The kid and I entered the
apartment to check things out,
and found a dead man in the living room.
Then you found the dead woman in
the bedroom and called the police.
Yes, that's right.
Why did all of you come to this apartment?
I came because they asked me to
unlock the door to this apartment.
Hayashi Yoshie (62)
Apartment Manager
See?
I was hired asked to pick up a package,
Hori Maiko (28)
Saki's Friend
Matsuda Takumi (23)
Deliveryman
so I came to get it.
I had plans to go shopping with Saki.
She didn't show up on time,
so I came to get her.
I see.
Inspector Megure.
Ah, good work.
How did it go?
All the neighbors are out,
so we haven't been able to collect
any useful eyewitness information.
But we did discover that all the cash
cards and valuables are missing.
Based on the ransacked state of the room,
it's likely this was a robbery.
Who were the victims?
Maehara Seiichi (32)
Day Trader
The man in the living room was
Maehara Seiichi-san, thirty-two years old.
He was a day trader who invested in stocks.
He was stabbed multiple times
in the chest with a sharp blade.
We believe he died of blood loss.
He seems to have made a lot
of money from stocks recently,
and transferred several million
yen into his bank account.
We've already confirmed this
information with his brokerage firm.
Was the culprit after that money?
Probably.
What about the woman in the bedroom?
Maehara Saki (29)
Seiichi's Wife
She was Seiichi-san's wife,
Maehara Saki-san, twenty-nine years old.
She was a housewife.
We believe she was smothered to death.
When did they die?
We believe Seiichi-san died around 11:00 AM,
and his wife Saki-san died around 12:30 PM.
Inspector Megure!
The building's security cameras
captured a suspicious figure,
thought to be the culprit, entering and
exiting the building around 11:00 AM.
What?
These are photos of the individual.
We can't see their face under that disguise.
Does anyone recognize this person?
No.
I see.
There's also something else
that caught my attention.
The camera in the emergency
staircase was broken.
The emergency staircase?
Yes.
That was broken two days ago.
It was a nasty prank.
I see.
But since that person entering and exiting
the building was caught on camera,
the incidents are likely unrelated.
In any case, it's almost
certain that this person
was involved in the murder
of the Maehara couple.
Call for an emergency deployment,
and do everything you can to find them.
Yes, sir.
There you are.
We're leaving.
Already?
All that's left is for the
police to find the culprit,
and arrest him.
There's no need for a detective here.
Okay...
Inspector, we'll be leaving now.
Thanks for your help.
Inspector Megure.
What is it?
Forensics found this.
Th-This is...
There's blood on it.
I think we can assume it was
used to commit the crime.
Detective Chiba, where did you find this?
In this apartment's dumpster.
What?
You're lying!
I refuse to believe that!
Now, now. Calm down.
According to detectives canvassing the area,
they were able to confirm that the
clothes worn during the murder
were purchased by Saki-san
at a nearby hardware store.
No...
That's hard to believe.
Saki would never something like that!
I understand how you feel,
but the hairs collected from inside
the knit hat matched Saki-san's.
In other words, it was all a sham.
A premeditated murder,
using the security cameras carried
out by the late Saki-san.
This explains why the camera in the
emergency staircase was broken.
What do you mean?
After disguising herself as the
robber and leaving the building,
she threw away the evidence
in the dumpster.
In order to return to the apartment,
she needed a path unmonitored
by security cameras.
Then how was she suffocated?
There wasn't anything
particularly strange about it.
She probably intended to
pretend to be a victim,
but accidentally killed herself.
She bound her own arms and
legs and entered the closet,
but the clothes were so heavy
she became unable to breathe.
So it was an unfortunate accident.
Although the truly unfortunate one
is the man killed by his wife.
Saki, this can't be true...
You were called here by her,
so you would discover the crime.
Me?
No...
Saki!
Saki, open your eyes!
Here again?
We're really leaving this time.
We missed lunch.
I'm starving.
His expensive suits are
going to get wrinkled.
People can put all the effort
they want into their appearances,
but their true selves can always
be found someplace hidden.
Hey, quit messing around the crime scene!
Could it be?
Inspector Megure.
Inspector, according to forensics,
Maehara Saki-san's fingerprints were found
on the bands used to bind her.
Any other fingerprints?
Not on the bands.
Hori Maiko-san's fingerprints
were found on the tape, though.
They probably got there
when she tried to take off
the tape when she found her.
I'm sorry.
I was so upset.
It's clear now that she tied herself up.
No way...
Uh, could I leave now?
I still have other deliveries to make.
I have work to do, too.
Since we've determined the identity
of the culprit, that should be fine.
In that case...
Mori-san?
Wh-What's gotten into you?
Wait.
This case hasn't been solved yet.
What are you talking about? The case—
It's strange.
What is?
Detective Chiba found the weapon
used in this case in the
apartment's dumpster.
Would a culprit throw away
such damning evidence in a
place so easily discovered?
She probably thought it would
be collected right away.
It's Saturday.
The garbage won't be collected
until next Monday.
The weapon would've been
left in the dumpster
for two whole days.
Yes.
I see.
That's when it occurred
to me that she may have
meant to store it there temporarily,
and throw it away elsewhere later.
But it was found before she could
move it, and her crime was exposed.
The natural conclusion
to that line of reasoning
is that she had an accomplice.
What?
Mori-kun, what do you mean?
She must have wanted to destroy
the evidence as soon as possible.
However, in her scenario,
she was trapped in the closet.
If she was spotted disposing of
the evidence someplace far away,
it would've contradicted her scenario.
You're right.
That's why she needed an accomplice
to dispose of the evidence for her.
I see.
But, Mori-san,
the evidence was found in the
apartment's dumpster.
That's right.
There was probably some trouble
between Saki-san and her accomplice.
That's why the evidence remained there.
Which means...
Saki-san was murdered by her accomplice.
Look at the tape that was
covering Saki-san's mouth.
There are several lipstick marks on it.
It's because Saki-san struggled when her
accomplice put the tape on her mouth.
If she had put it on herself,
there would've only been one mark.
You're right.
Yeah.
Furthermore, look closely at the closet.
I don't see anything
particularly out of place.
There are too many clothes relative
to the volume of the closet.
The expensive suits would've
become wrinkled, ruining them.
I see.
That's not all.
There are even items such as t-shirts
that would normally be kept in drawers.
But doesn't that vary from
household to household?
Some people keep their t-shirts on hangers.
I... do.
You can tell from looking at the t-shirts and
other clothes that they're dirty and creased.
Clothes previously worn or stored
in the chest of drawers
were crammed onto the rack.
You're right, Mori-san.
These clothes have been worn more than once.
I also smell cigarettes.
This must have been one
of the folded clothes.
In order words, her accomplice camouflaged
the crime scene to make
it look like an accident.
Who was her accomplice?
Maiko-san,
why did you ignore my commands
to stop and run to Saki-san?
What?
I was worried about Saki.
Is that true?
Yes.
Are you sure it wasn't because you had
to be the first to discover her body?
What?
Mori-kun, what do you mean?
In order to disguise the
reason your fingerprints
were on a piece of evidence,
you had to be the first discoverer.
Am I wrong?
Ah, the fingerprints on the tape!
Oh.
That.
That's just a wild accusation.
I really was worried about Saki.
You still refuse to admit it?
Could you show us the
contents of your bag, then?
What?
Why do you need to see inside my bag?
Saki-san must've hidden
her valuables somewhere.
However, as you can tell from
the fact that the evidence
was discarded in the dumpster,
she couldn't have hidden them far.
Since the police haven't found them yet,
it's likely that her accomplice
took them with them.
Could you show us what's inside your bag?
This is...
Maiko-chan, why?
I took the emergency staircase
to Saki's apartment.
You're late!
All you have to do is keep doing as I say.
Are you scared?
There's no turning back now.
You basically killed my husband.
No!
That's what it means to be an accomplice.
The evidence is in the dumpster.
Get rid of it.
I knew the deliveryman was coming soon,
so I hurried out of the apartment.
I didn't have time to move the
evidence from the dumpster.
Even if it were discovered, we
would think Saki-san did it.
That's what you believed.
Yes.
She said she'd share the insurance money,
but more than anything, Saki had
helped me since high school.
But I was afraid.
I thought I'd have to do as she
said for the rest of my life.
I wanted to break her spell over me.
Mister, should you be eating so much?
You idiot!
I missed lunch.
Besides, if you're worried about the money...
Huh?
It's gone!
What's wrong?
I think I dropped the envelope
with the reward money somewhere.
What?
What am I going to do?
It's time to search for
an envelope next, mister.
I wanted that reward...
Episode Preview
A murder motivated by hatred...
Why did you come here?
He's horrifyingly crude.
Everyone in the neighborhood had motive.
What?
Nonsense?
So this was a kind of ABC Murder.
The Shifting Mystery of Beika City
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The Shifting
Mystery of Beika City, Part One!"
Okay, Conan-kun. Go ahead.
The ABC Murders
Next Conan's hint! Huh?
The ABC Murders!
Do you have something to say?
Don't miss the next episode.
Let's see "Crimson" before the sun rus-sets.
Who are you, the professor?