The victim is Amagi Tatsuya-san, a
resident of a nearby apartment building.
Fukuda Tameo-san, who discovered the body,
Fukuda Tameo (33)
Office Worker
found it when he happened
to pass through this area.
Th-That's right.
I was shocked and called the police.
Based on the body's condition,
we believe he was killed
around 9 PM last night.
He seems to have been stabbed in the torso
several times by a sharp awl-like object.
Since the wallet full of
money was left on the body,
and due to the relentless nature
of the murder, it's likely...
Amagi Tatsuya (24)
...a murder motivated by hatred.
Conan-kun!
I saw some police cars
and followed them here.
What kind of hatred would drive a
person to do something like this?
Mori-kun!
I saw some police cars.
You're unbelievable.
Anyway...
Inspector.
The victim Amagi-san seems to have
been disliked by his neighbors.
Looks that way.
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
The rubberneckers respond in a curious way.
A chain reaction of cases
starts in the neighborhood.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Shifting Mystery of Beika City
(Part One)
"The Shifting Mystery of
Beika City, Part One!"
Amagi Tatsuya-san, who was living off
his inheritance from his parents,
moved to this town about three months ago.
He rode his motorcycle at all hours.
Its deafening roar bothered all the residents
of this quiet neighborhood.
They should've asked him to keep it down.
We tried, but...
Excuse me.
What?
Do you need something?
Oh, well...
Why did all of you come to see me?!
Ouch...
You're pathetic.
Why did you even come here?
He was horrifyingly crude.
In other words, the victim Amagi
Tatsuya-san was a massive nuisance.
And including you, Fukuda Tameo-san,
who discovered the body...
Everyone in the neighborhood
had motive to kill him.
Why do they think we killed him?
It's no surprise he was killed.
It was divine retribution.
We're the victims here.
We wouldn't kill someone over that.
We asked the neighborhood
association president,
Bando-san, to make him stop.
Are you referring to Bando Hikoichi-san?
Yes.
You know him?
Yeah, we found Bando-san's
medical examination card
next to the body.
Maybe neighborhood association
president Bando Hikoichi-san
invited Amagi Tatsuya-san out last night
so he could tell him to stop, but...
Amagi-san wouldn't listen so,
he stabbed him in a rage.
Let's visit Bando-san next.
The local authorities can handle things here.
Yes, sir.
You can count on us.
Hey, mister.
Don't you think it's too sloppy to leave
personally identifying
evidence at a crime scene?
Let's go see the face of that sloppy man.
He got what was coming.
Amagi got what was coming to him.
Bando Hikoichi (35)
Neighborhood
Association President
Bando-san!
Are you all right?!
It's no use.
He's dead.
Judging by his condition,
he must've died last night.
He poisoned himself with
alcohol and pesticides.
This is blood, isn't it?
Yeah.
It's probably the weapon used
to kill Amagi Tatsuya-san.
So it ends with the murderer's suicide.
Does this mean our suspect's dead?
No.
But...
Get forensics down here.
Yes, sir.
Bando Hikoichi-san seems to have
been a pleasant but unreliable man.
He was forced into becoming the
neighborhood association president.
Apparently more than half the neighborhood's
property belongs to the Bando family.
So he couldn't refuse.
But if the residents were pestering him,
he couldn't have avoided
talking to Amagi-san.
Of course he couldn't!
Ezaki Hiro (20)
College Student
We were paying dues to the
neighborhood association.
Apparently that woman, Ezaki Hiro-san,
was pestering him the most.
She seems like a strong-willed person.
Since he was so unreliable,
he may have brought the awl
with him for self-defense.
What'd you want to talk about?
Um...
Huh?
Spit it out!
What did you want to discuss?
And the panicked Bando-san
ended up stabbing him.
But believing he couldn't escape his crime...
He killed himself.
That's one painful case closed.
Don't rush to conclusions.
Well, that works out.
That useless man
finally did something useful
for the neighborhood.
How convenient that he
stabbed that awful nuisance.
I don't think that's what
happened, detectives.
Bando-san couldn't have committed a crime.
Really?
If that's not what happened, then...
Bando-san wasn't that worried
about Amagi-san either.
He was laughing just yesterday.
Could you tell us more, uh...?
My name is Kanemitsu Toyoko.
You can't cross that line.
Kanemitsu Toyoko (68)
Café Manager
Then why don't we go to my place to talk?
There's no need for us to go anywhere.
Yeah.
You're the great detective
Mori-san, aren't you?
You should come with us.
I run a small café just over there.
Really? In that case...
Seriously?
Here you are.
Thank you.
When did Bando-san stop by yesterday?
Gamo Koyuki (23)
Waitress
I think it was past noon.
That's right.
He came with his friend Chino Yosuke-sensei,
who teaches Japanese
history at Haido College.
I had it appraised.
This one's not worth much either.
That's a shame, Bando-san.
I wasn't expecting much.
Didn't you spend days examining the
contents of the storehouse, Chino-sensei?
Chino Yosuke (35)
College Professor
Yeah, I was hoping we'd
find something valuable.
But the storehouse was full
of old worthless junk.
Is it possible for such a historic old
mansion not to have any treasures?
I know.
But Chino's an expert.
Yup, not a single treasure.
I shouldn't be laughing.
The neighborhood association has been
pestering me about that nuisance.
You still haven't gone to talk to him?
That's not something I'm good at.
I'm waiting for the right moment.
That was yesterday afternoon?
So it's hard to imagine Bando-san
went to talk to Amagi-san last night.
You're right.
It's hard to imagine he did.
Bu...
But...
Did Bando Hikoichi-san really kill himself?
There was something strange about
the lock on his front door.
It was unlocked when we arrived.
Normally you'd lock it if
you meant to kill yourself.
So no one can interfere.
I don't know...
...what's going on anymore.
This is Megure.
Yeah. Got it.
It's forensics.
He was indeed poisoned with pesticide,
but it was mixed into the
alcohol in the bottle.
If he killed himself, he would've
poured it into a glass.
Putting in the bottle would've diluted it.
Sounds like a murder disguised as a suicide.
But that means...
The culprit must be absent-minded.
The method they used is easily discovered,
and they didn't even lock the front door.
If Bando-san didn't commit suicide,
then what about Amagi-san's murder?
I told you, Bando-san didn't do it.
After all, I heard Amagi-san was
stabbed to death with an awl.
What?
That's impossible, since...
Bando-san had a fear of needles.
What?
He couldn't stand pointed objects.
He would start shaking if he just saw one.
Does that mean someone like
that can't use an awl?
This must all be the work
of the real culprit X.
That is what it means.
X probably murdered Amagi Tatsuya-san.
In order to make it look like
Bando Hikoichi-san did it,
he murdered Bando-san and
made it look like a suicide.
Yes.
So these kinds of things really do happen.
I read about a few of them in those.
Kanemitsu-san, do you enjoy mysteries?
She even has professional journals.
But they're not new, and
there's only one volume each.
She probably only bought them when
her favorite authors were featured.
In any case, the question is who X is.
Our chief told me to bring
this to you, Inspector.
It was found under the
sofa at the crime scene.
The housekeeper showed up, so
we had her confirm what it was.
That doesn't belong to
the master of the house.
Hayama Eiko (55)
Housekeeper
He doesn't smoke.
Besides, this wasn't under
the sofa when I went
home yesterday evening.
If that housekeeper is right,
then it must've been left by
someone who visited after dusk.
It's possible that it belongs to the culprit.
Isn't that lighter...?
Remember?
That's Chino-sensei's.
Chino-san and Bando-san met
at this café, didn't they?
Yes. I saw him using it then.
This is starting to smell fishy, Inspector.
It would mean he visited him again after
dusk when they met during the afternoon.
Where's the housekeeper?
We're having her stay at the house.
Excuse us.
Do the police think Chino-sensei did it?
Surely not.
This lighter wasn't there?
No.
As I was leaving yesterday,
I dropped some change.
It fell all the back back there.
Good.
It's all here.
I would've noticed it if it was there.
So it was dropped after dusk.
Thank you for staying.
Not at all.
Do you really think Chino-sensei did it?
Since his belongings were
found at the crime scene,
that makes him a suspect.
And friends bring each other liquor.
He could've made him drink, too.
What a nonsensical duo.
What?
Nonsense?
The culprit killed Amagi-san,
and tried to make it look
like Bando-san did it, right?
But Chino-sensei doesn't
live in this neighborhood,
so it wasn't as though
Amagi-san was bothering him.
In other words, Chino-sensei had
no motive to kill Amagi-san.
Not currently.
Chino Yosuke-san has no motive.
No motive to kill Amagi Tatsuya-san.
With no motive, it doesn't make sense.
I got it!
It's the other way around!
The other way around?
Bando Hikoichi-san was the person
Chino wanted to eliminate!
What?
To avoid the police's suspicion,
he decided to make it look like a suicide.
But a suicide needs motive.
So Chino used the fact that the
neighborhood association
was pestering him to
talk to Amagi Tatsuya-san.
He killed Amagi-san.
By making it look like Bando-san had done it,
he created a motive for suicide.
If you assume Bando-san was killed only
to make Amagi-san's death
look like a suicide...
Then it's no wonder we can't find a motive.
But why would Chino-sensei kill Bando-san?
Well...
That's it.
You're missing the most fundamental aspect.
Looks like we're back at square one.
That's why I said you're full of nonsense.
What did he stand to gain
from killing his friend?
It would be a different story
if he had some kind of treasure.
Treasure?
That's it!
There was one!
While examining the storehouse, Chino
found an unbelievable treasure.
He killed Bando-san so he
could steal it from him.
But they said they didn't find any treasure.
Chino lied. Kanemitsu-san,
you said it yourself.
Is it possible for such
a historic old mansion
not to have any treasures?
When you think of it that
way, it does make sense.
It's not impossible.
If Bando-san really did have a treasure.
The case is really settled this time.
So this was a kind of ABC Murder.
It's a coincidence, but their names...
Their initials are A, B, and C.
Was it Agatha Christie who
wrote the ABC Murders?
Where the victims are murdered in order.
Are you saying Chino-san might
have already been killed?!
You can't be serious!
I'm sure that's not possible.
Right?
I am kind of curious.
It seems I'm the one who
was speaking nonsense.
I'm Chino.
He's all right.
Yeah.
Conan-kun, you again?!
The old man asked me to come check on him.
Could we ask you a few questions about
Amagi-san and Bando-san's murders?
What?!
Bando was murdered?!
Your suspicions are groundless.
I never even met Amagi.
The last time I saw Bando was
at the café that afternoon.
I never went to his home.
But we found this.
It's mine, but I lost it somewhere.
In any case, there really wasn't a single
treasure worth stealing in that storehouse.
You'll see if you examine it for yourselves.
It's possible you already stole the object
while you were examining the contents.
You were worried Bando-san would
notice, so you killed him.
Impossible.
You seem determined to make me the murderer.
I was at home yesterday!
Was anyone with you?
I was alone.
I was judging submissions.
What submissions?
For the New Writer of the Year award.
Sometimes I'm asked to judge
submissions for a mystery magazine.
I was the president of the
mystery club during college,
so I'm contacted by various
mystery magazines.
So you're into mysteries.
In other words, you have no
one to verify your alibi!
I-I'm not strapped for cash.
There's no need for me to steal.
You can tell us more at the station.
W-Wait!
Listen to me!
Hey, w-wait!
Inspector, you think it's
strange, too, don't you?
It's hard to imagine someone who
likes mysteries making basic mistakes,
like putting poison in a bottle or
leaving the front door unlocked, right?
And he must know of all kinds
of ways to fabricate an alibi,
but he didn't make a single attempt.
Which means Chino-san isn't X.
He could've been set up.
That's impossible.
Mister!
Mori-kun!
I came to get a look at Chino Yosuke-san.
What did you mean by impossible?
If someone else killed
Amagi-san and Bando-san,
and tried to pin their murders on Chino-san,
then they would've killed Chino-san, too.
They would've made that
death look like a suicide.
Everything would've made sense that way.
It is strange that a murderer
who killed two people
didn't do anything to Chino-san.
Now that you mention it...
The fact that he's alive is definitive
proof that Chino Yosuke did it.
It does make sense.
Yeah, but...
It seems I was overthinking things.
Let's go.
All that's left is for the police
to investigate and arrest him.
Could it be?
Hey.
Were you waiting long?
Uh... no.
Did anyone see you?
Of course not. Let's go.
Okay.
Pathetic.
X deliberately didn't kill Chino-san.
What?
The customers there at that time were...
Fukuda-san and his family and
Ezaki Hiro-san and her friends.
What?
The man who first discovered
Amagi-san's body and the woman
who was most aggressively
pestering Bando-san were there.
Which means X is...
Episode Preview
I know Bando had a fear of needles
and couldn't have used an awl.
Does Fukuda-san work nights?
It would've been tough for him to do it.
Why are you sniffing around?!
I'll see you later.
Hey!
Wait, you brat!
Do you recognize the name Dorosue Yamiyo?
The Shifting Mystery of Beika City
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The Shifting
Mystery of Beika City, Part Two!"
Mystery Magazines
Next Conan's hint!
Mystery magazines!
Don't miss the next episode.
What do you have to say today?
If we watch "Crimson," can we get some candy?
No way.