Amagi Tatsuya-san, a man alienated from
his entire neighborhood, was murdered.
Amagi Tatsuya (24)
The initial suspect, neighborhood association
president Bando Hikoichi-san, was also murdered.
Bando Hikoichi (35)
Neighborhood
Association President
Kanemitsu Toyoko (68)
Café Manager
The testimony of Kanemitsu Toyoko-san,
the owner of a nearby café,
and Detectives Takagi and Chiba's
reasoning cast suspicion
on college professor
Chiba Yosuke-san, but...
Inspector, you think it's
strange, too, don't you?
It's hard to imagine someone
who likes mysteries
making basic mistakes, like
putting poison in a bottle
or leaving the front door unlocked, right?
Which means Chino-san isn't X.
He could've been set up.
What?
The customers there at that time were...
Gamo Koyuki (23)
Waitress
Fukuda-san and his family, and
Ezaki Hiro-san and her friends.
What?
The man who first discovered Amagi-san's body
and the woman who was most aggressively
pestering Bando-san were there.
Which means X is...
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
Who is trying to kill who?
An unexpected culprit is
found in an unexpected place.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Shifting Mystery of Beika City
(Part Two)
"The Shifting Mystery of
Beika City, Part Two!"
What?
Chino-sensei?
I heard he sometimes judges
submissions for New Writer awards.
For mysteries, right?
He's in the middle of judging some right now.
That's what he said yesterday
at this café, right?
Yeah.
It sounds like a lot of work.
I can't focus during the day.
Chino Yosuke (35)
College Professor
I'm going to lock myself in my
study and stay up all night again.
X probably chose to act at night
because they overhead that.
But why'd you want to know about that?
Kogoro-no-ojisan told me
to ask, so I don't know.
Both of them could've done it.
Their motive is still unclear,
but it's likely either
Fukuda-san or Ezaki-san is X.
In any case, I need to confirm
their alibis for last night.
I'll start with the man
who discovered the body...
He got what was coming.
Fukuda Tameo (33)
Office Worker
Amagi got what was coming to him.
Fukuda Tameo-san.
Metropolitan Police Department
Beika City Station
If I killed this Amagi fellow,
and wanted to frame Bando,
I wouldn't have used an awl!
I know Bando had a fear of needles
and couldn't have used an awl!
W-Well...
You did it deliberately!
That's right.
If you were ever exposed,
you planned to escape by saying
you'd never have chosen an awl
for a weapon because you knew
Bando-san had a fear of needles.
Like you just did, Chino-sensei.
I see.
You were trying to outsmart us.
What?
If you go by that logic,
there's no end to it.
We're doing awesomely this time.
I'm scaring myself.
It just keeps coming.
Hey, mister.
Does Fukuda-san work nights?
Yeah...
It would've been tough for him to do it.
Which means it must be the other one.
That useless man
Ezaki Hiro (20)
College Student
finally did something useful
for the neighborhood.
How convenient that he
stabbed that awful nuisance.
Ezaki Hiro-san, who pestered neighborhood
association president Bando-san
more than anyone else to make Amagi-san stop.
Ezaki
Really?
Ezaki Hiro-san's a student at Haido College?
Thank you!
Chino-san is a professor at Haido College.
There's a connection between them.
Ezaki-san must've run into trouble with Chino-san
through the college, and out of spite...
Hey!
Why are you investigating me?
Why are you sniffing around?!
Bye!
Hey!
Wait, you brat!
Is there some reason she doesn't
want to be investigated?
What are you going to do with those?
I'm taking them home.
But you just brought them here this morning.
I'm done using them.
Done using them?
I'm going to drop these off since
we don't have any customers.
They're important.
See you later.
Important?
But they're not new,
and there's only one volume each.
She probably only bought them when
her favorite authors were featured.
Who is Kanemitsu Toyoko-san's
favorite author?
The copy of "Mystery World" she
had was last year's May issue.
There's nothing that stands out.
"Labyrinths" was this year's January issue.
Huh?
This author...
Their name was in "Mystery World," too.
Monthly Magazine Labyrinths January
New Author Award Submissions
Title
The Melting Weapon
Author
Dorosue Yamiyo
This is definitely it. Dorosue Yamiyo.
They're the common author found
in the books on the bookshelf.
Hello?
Yes, this is Detective Mori.
I have a bit of a random question.
Monthly Magazine Labyrinths - Magazine Search
It's a confusing story.
The trick is insane, and their criminal
profile is totally unrealistic.
Ichimura Zetto (32)
Editor
They hate arguments so much,
they casually commit murders one
after another to avoid them.
No one like that could possibly exist.
New Author Award Submission
This is terrible!! Absolutely not!!
Chiba
It would be terrifying if they did.
Kogoro-no-ojisan wanted
me to ask you a question.
Do you recognize the name Dorosue Yamiyo?
Dorosue Yamiyo?
They're the author of a ridiculous
story "The Melting Weapon."
So you do recognize the name.
He told me this case doesn't end with ABC.
It's an ABCD case that
includes Dorosue Yamiyo-san.
Chino-san, do you remember
anything about that story?
I knew it.
It's all coming together now.
Really?
You like mysteries, too?
Yeah!
I thought we could discuss the case
together since we both like mysteries.
Is that why you wanted to see me?
Fine.
Let's go.
Conan-kun, right?
Don't you think it's too late, though?
Didn't Chino-sensei do it?
No.
I think the real culprit is X,
and they framed Chino-san.
But that's not enough.
Since X killed Amagi-san and Bando-san,
it doesn't make sense that
they didn't kill Chino-sensei.
Maybe they deliberately didn't kill him.
What do you mean?
X really hated Chino-san.
They thought it would be a waste
to quickly kill him like
Amagi-san and Bando-san.
They wanted him to suffer
a fate worse than death.
So they decided to frame him?
Yeah.
When you think of it that way, it
explains why they didn't kill him.
I see.
What you're saying makes sense, Conan-kun.
Now it's my turn.
Who is X?
There are two points to consider.
Yeah.
Since X tried to frame Chino-san...
It had to be someone who knew Chino-sensei
would have no one to verify
his alibi for yesterday.
They also had to be able to
steal Chino-sensei's lighter.
That's right.
Oh, my. Now that's a problem.
That would mean the customers
who were at my café yesterday
are the most suspicious.
I asked the waitress Koyuki-san
who was at the café yesterday.
Of the people there, Fukuda-san
is particularly suspect.
Fukuda-san was being bothered by Amagi-san.
Perhaps he resented Bando-san
for not doing anything,
despite being the neighborhood
association president.
That's sufficient motive.
But Bando-san couldn't have
committed the murders at night.
You're right.
Fukuda-san works nights.
Right.
Which means the next
suspicious character is...
Ezaki Hiro-san?
Apparently she's a student at Haido College.
She may have had problems with Chino-san.
But it may not be her either.
But if Fukuda-san couldn't have done it...
In the first place, we can't narrow it
down to only Fukuda-san and Ezaki-san.
It's possible Fukuda-san's wife or
Ezaki Hiro-san's friends did it.
It's possible.
It also might not have even been a customer.
You don't think Koyuki-chan...
I see.
It's possible.
But the true identity of the person
who killed Amagi-san and Bando-san,
and tried to frame Chino-san
for the murders is...
The true identity of X is...
Could it be?
Oh, my.
If it isn't the woman from the café.
Oh, Ezaki-san.
I was just on my way to your café.
Are you open?
Yes, Koyuki-chan is watching the store.
Oh, but isn't he...?
Oh, crap.
Uh, don't tell Ruriko.
Hey, are we going to be okay?
It's fine.
She's tight-lipped.
Let's go.
She doesn't seem to be involved in the case.
She seems to have some nasty secrets.
If Ezaki-san is innocent,
that narrows down the
identity of X quite a bit.
X killed Amagi Tatsuya-san
and Bando Hikoichi-san,
and is trying to frame Chino
Yosuke-san for the murders.
But they faced a fundamental
problem in framing Chino-san.
Chino-san had no reason
to kill Amagi-san or Bando-san.
It's not possible to frame
Chino-san without a motive.
But when X learned
Chino-san examined the contents of
the storehouse at Bando-san's mansion,
they realized they could use that.
Furthermore, yesterday...
I can't focus during the day.
I'm going to lock myself in my
study and stay up all night again.
They waited for an opportunity
to swap Chino-san's lighter
for a similar one and took his.
Since Chino-san would have
no one to verify his alibi,
they decided to act that night.
First they called Amagi-san to the park.
Huh?
Who are you?
And then killed him.
Then...
They killed Bando-san.
They placed the pesticide bottle
and awl used to kill Amagi-san on the table,
left behind Chino-san's lighter
they got that afternoon,
took Bando-san's examination card,
and left it near Amagi-san's body.
Then they waited for Amagi-san's
body to be discovered.
Naturally, the police suspected
Bando-san when they found his card.
I don't think that's what
happened, detectives.
Bando-san couldn't have committed a crime.
They appeared before the police
as a well-informed source.
Isn't that lighter...?
Remember?
That's Chino-sensei's.
They directed them towards Chino-san.
What a nonsensical duo.
What?
Nonsense?
They provoked the detectives into following
the scenario they had concocted...
That's it!
There was one!
And led them into believing
there was indeed a treasure
in Bando-san's storehouse,
and Chino-san murdered the both
of them in order to steal it.
In other words,
X couldn't forgive neighborhood
nuisance Amagi-san,
or negligent neighborhood association
president Bando-san either.
Even if they did something wrong,
it doesn't justify taking their lives.
I think your reasoning makes sense,
but even if it is true,
you still haven't solved the mystery.
Why would X hate Chino-san?
X left us a hint to solve that mystery.
Rather than hiding it,
showing the evidence necessary
to solve the mystery
is the ironclad rule of mysteries.
That's why X took us to the café.
Then they showed us the books
that were the key to solving the mystery.
The mystery books X brought from home.
Inside those books was the
clue to solving the mystery.
What clue?
Dorosue Yamiyo.
This author's name was in
all the books X showed us.
Dorosue Yamiyo
Unfortunately, it seems the police
didn't notice the clue left by X.
I nearly missed it, too.
All of Dorosue Yamiyo's works were
rejected in the first round of judgment,
so I called the publisher
because I was curious.
That led me to discover another common point.
The man responsible for judging
all those submissions was...
...Chino Yosuke.
That's right.
The true culprit in this case...
is a person who despised Chino-san
and plotted to frame him.
Dorosue Yamiyo.
After confirming my suspicions
with Chino-san himself,
I figured it all out.
The person who killed Amagi-san and Bando-san,
and tried to frame Chino-san
for the murders...
The identity of Dorosue Yamiyo...
Kanemitsu Toyoko-san.
It's you, isn't it?
Chino-san called your works...
That's right.
Right in front of me.
Come to think of it,
one of the works I'm reviewing
right now is incredible.
It's called "The Melting Weapon,"
but it's truly awful.
That bad, huh?
Everything about it is awful.
Ma'am, listen to this.
He was harshly critical.
And then...
The content was bad enough,
but the pen name Dorosue
Yamiyo is awful, too.
I question the character of
anyone capable of writing that.
He even mocked my character and rejected me.
That's why
I murdered neighborhood nuisance Amagi,
killed the useless Bando,
and plotted to frame Chino for my crimes.
I didn't particularly dislike those two.
I killed them because it fit perfectly
into my plan to frame Chino.
But, Conan-kun...
I'm impressed that you were
able to solve the mystery.
There's no evidence, so it's
all just my conjecture.
What are you talking about?
Once you solve the mystery, it's over.
A pure mystery doesn't need something
as filthy as evidence.
Toyoko-san, the ABC Murders you mentioned
were a hint, too.
Agatha Christie's story involved
not just A, B, and C, but also D.
It was a hint that we should
also consider a D in this case.
You really do like mysteries.
But you crossed the line.
You turned the mystery you
came up with into a weapon.
No matter how much you like mysteries,
or how good the mystery is,
you can never cross the line.
You left us hints to solve
the mystery, but those...
It was my nature and sin.
I'm sorry.
What do you want, kid?
Why'd you tell me to come here?
She wants you to accompany her.
What?
Where?
I don't like physical evidence,
but I thought the police would want some,
so I have some prepared.
It's a receipt from a hardware store.
It's from when I bought the
awl I used on Amagi-san
and the pesticide I used on Bando-san.
What?!
You...
You know where you're going, don't you?
What?!
Kanemitsu Toyoko-san killed both of them...
And tried to frame Chino?
All because he made fun of a story she wrote?
I don't enjoy speaking harshly to seniors,
but killing a person is...
I know how sinful it is.
It's why I'm here.
So what's "The Melting Weapon" about?
Well, it's a locked room murder.
The culprit slips a slug covered in poison
through the door of a bedroom
locked from the inside.
The moment the victim who's
sleeping inside touches the slug,
the poison seeps through their
skin, and they suffocate to death.
Meanwhile, the salt in the
sweat the victim produces
as they writhe to death melts away the slug.
And that's the locked room murder.
How does the slug conveniently
make its way to the victim?
And why doesn't being coated
in poison kill the slug?
Unfortunately, there's no explanation.
What?
Seriously?
That's too much of a mystery for me.
But it's fun if you think of it
as a blank for the reader to fill.
How would you explain it?
A blank?
Blank...
Episode Preview
That's enough!
Huh?
Each time we increase the power,
it's coated with kerosene.
I had a nightmare.
What?
Could we ask you a few questions
about the late Yamakura-san?
Yeah!
The Dark Mountain Route
The next episode of Conan is
"The Dark Mountain Route!"
Research Balloon
Next Conan's hint, boing!
A research balloon!
What do you have today?
Don't miss the next episode.
The characters for love and song
together make "love letter."
Oh, Sato-san.
That's actually pretty decent.