Camping, camping!
We're going camping!
Wow!
She's climbing up that cliff.
There's a river on this side.
Someone's kayaking down it.
They're so pretty.
Wait.
It's a rare mountain plant.
Don't pick it.
Okay!
Let's hurry up and go.
Aren't you going to take a panoramic shot
of the city for your science project?
Now let's go.
Okay.
Mount Kumomaru
Cottage Entrance
That's enough!
Huh? It's those guys from earlier.
Why do you always act like this?
You show up late and demand we cook for you!
Oh, shut up. Who cares?
Yamakura Takemi (26)
Mountain Climber
Eiko-san said she'd cook for me.
Ikeguchi Eiko (23)
Mountain Climber
Yeah, I said I would.
That's irrelevant.
Takemi, you always do this.
Hayashida Taro (28)
Mountain Climber
Calm down, Ashizuka-san.
Ashizuka Tokunori (33)
Mountain Climber
No, I'm going to let her have it.
She's always inconveniencing
the group with her selfishness.
You're right.
That's why Motoki-san is dead, too.
You're wrong.
It was an accident.
I'm not so sure.
You think what happened three
years ago is my fault, don't you?!
An accident? Three years ago?
Wait, Takemi-san.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have said anything.
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
It was supposed to be a feel-good hiking
trip but misfortune strikes an arguing group.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Dark Mountain Route
"The Dark Mountain Route!"
Apparently she's sleeping at the
bottom of this cliff tonight.
It seemed like they really hated each other.
I'm sure they have their reasons.
Sorry, guys.
I'm sorry you had to see that.
Hey, what's the accident that
happened three years ago?
What? Oh, well...
We were part of the same club.
Three years ago, one of our
members had an accident.
Takemi ran off by herself.
When Motoki went after her, he
fell from the top of the cliff.
Motoki was my childhood friend.
We'd climbed several mountains together.
We were going to keep climbing, too.
But because of Takemi—
Damn it.
So we get together every year
to commemorate his death.
Huh?
What's that sound?
Could it be?
Helium
That's a research balloon, right?
Yeah.
I'm sending it up to the stratosphere
to collect meteorological data.
Hayashida-san, you're a
weather station employee.
That's right.
For the next ten days, I'm going to
be sending up my balloon every day.
I brought enough for the job.
Something smells weird.
Yeah.
Each time we increase the power,
it's coated with kerosene.
Done.
Wow!
Couldn't you use one of
those to fly to the peak?
That's impossible.
A single balloon can only carry
five or six kilograms at most.
There!
He moves so much in his sleep.
She's still not here.
I'm going to call her.
Forget her.
But...
Sorry.
Did we wake you?
No.
This must be when Motoki-san died.
Hello, Takemi-san?
Don't wake me.
I was sleeping.
I know.
I'll offer a silent prayer, too.
Huh? Where's Hayashida-san?
He said he was going to a nearby
mountain to collect data.
Ayumi-chan, what's wrong?
I had a nightmare.
What?
Really? Just look at you.
I'll cast a sleeping spell on you.
We're leaving as soon as we finish breakfast.
To the peak!
What's wrong, Genta?
Th-That.
Takemi-san's on the ground!
Conan-kun!
5:05.
Campsite Entrance
Over there!
5:45.
Takemi!
She's dead.
It can't be...
Hey, look at this.
That's her hiking compass.
Yeah.
Takemi-san!
How did this happen?
Is that a drone?
Yeah.
We're using it to search the mountains.
Way to go, MPD.
Are the three of you
the late Yamakura
Takemi-san's acquaintances?
Yes.
We found a backpack
in the forest three kilometers
from the crime scene.
We'd like you to confirm if
it belonged to Yamakura-san.
A backpack in the woods?
That's definitely it. It's Takemi-san's.
I see.
Inside were the knife we believe is the
murder weapon and an empty wallet.
The killer must've abandoned it.
Then the killer fled down the mountain
after killing Takemi-san at the bottom.
Well, actually...
According to the mountain guard,
he's been in the cottage at the entrance
to the foot of the
mountain since about 4 AM,
but no one suspicious left the mountain.
What do you mean?
Someone may have left the bag in the forest
to make it look as though
an outsider killed her.
Which means one of us did it.
Wait.
We couldn't have killed her.
Why not?
Takemi was alive until 3 AM.
You were there, too.
Yeah.
That's when Eiko-san called her on her phone.
That's right.
The body was found around 5 AM.
Cottage
Campsite
In other words, the crime was
committed during those two hours.
But no matter how much you hurry,
it takes about forty to fifty minutes to
take the path down to the crime scene.
That's about how long it took when we went.
Killing Takemi-san and leaving the bag
in the forest
three kilometers away would
add another thirty to forty minutes.
Since the return trip is uphill,
it took more than sixty minutes.
All together, that's over 120 minutes.
It couldn't have been done within two hours.
And they were sleeping
in the cottage with us.
Eiko-san was sleeping with me.
See?
Eiko and I couldn't have done it.
But, Hayashida, you...
I was surveying on another mountain!
I see.
Could we ask you a few questions
about the late Yamakura-san?
Did they really not do it?
It wasn't Eiko-san.
She definitely didn't do it.
But you saw the four of them fighting.
Shall we investigate?
What?
Yeah!
If one of them is the killer,
that means they snuck out of the cottage,
went to the crime scene and forest,
and returned within two hours.
However, that's not actually possible.
But what if they climbed?
Climbed?
Yes.
Instead of taking the mountain path,
if they climbed straight
up and down the cliff,
they could've done it within two hours.
Eiko-san was climbing yesterday.
No, that cliff is fifty meters tall.
Even an experienced climber
would take an hour one way.
So it doesn't work.
Then they used the river.
The river?
Yeah.
Ashizuka-san was kayaking, right?
If he rode down the rapids in
the river next to this field...
It does snake down to the crime scene, but...
That would get him there,
but how would he return?
He couldn't have kayaked up the river,
and he'd need time to bring it back.
So it doesn't work.
I know. They used the sky!
The balloon.
The balloon?
Yeah.
He flew through the air like a bird to
reach the crime scene and the forest.
North
Cottage
Campsite
Wind
South
Since the wind is blowing south to north,
a balloon would get you there.
But a single balloon can barely
carry five or six kilograms.
Approx.
A person couldn't have used them to fly.
That's why he inflated all of them.
What do you think, Conan?
Hayashida-san said he had
enough balloons for ten days.
He has nine left now.
It would still be difficult even
if he used all his balloons.
So it doesn't work.
This is a difficult problem.
I can't think of anything.
It's dislodged.
Helium
Mud?
This is it.
Rope marks?
Conan-kun.
What's wrong?
Oh...
Huh?
What's this?
Wait, Edogawa-kun.
That fluff...
Hey!
There's something going on at the cottage!
What?
Is this a balloon?
Yes.
We found it using the drone.
It was past the forest
where we found the bag.
It got caught on a tree branch and tore.
A balloon, huh?
That's it.
I knew you did it.
You think I killed her?
That's right.
You used this to transport the bag.
Transport a bag using a balloon?
At 3 AM, you said you were going surveying,
and took the balloon you hid down the cliff.
Then you killed Takemi.
Then you tied the balloon to her
bag and took it to the forest.
You could've made the trip within two hours.
Unfortunately for you,
it got caught on a tree.
Wait.
I was surveying during that time.
Survey Log
I have logs.
You could've made them up.
Besides, wasn't the red
compass at the crime scene
the memento you got from Motoki?
You saw it at the crime scene, didn't you?
Why didn't you say anything?
I didn't want anyone to think I'd done it.
Liar!
You're just pretending not to know!
You're the one who killed her!
Inspector.
We found this in Hayashida-san's bag.
What is this?
It's surveying equipment
for attaching to balloons.
But I always keep it with me.
There's blood on it.
It could be the victim's.
No! I didn't do it!
So one of them is the killer.
Balloons... Kerosene... Wool...
There's something bothering you, isn't there?
Could it be?
Detective Takagi.
Stop it there.
I knew it.
So that's how it is.
No, I didn't do it!
It wasn't me!
Wait a minute, Inspector.
Hey, Shinichi.
Is something wrong, Agasa-san?
There are a few things I'm wondering about.
Hayashida-san, did you wipe your
hands and body thoroughly yesterday?
What?
Yes, I did.
That's why you don't smell of kerosene.
Kerosene?
Yes.
It's used to increase the
strength of rubber balloons.
If anyone used the balloons,
the smell would remain on them.
Couldn't he have wiped his hands
immediately after committing the crime?
Even if Hayashida-san did it,
he barely had two hours.
Did he have that kind of time?
You mean someone else is the killer?
That is what that would mean.
There's something I'd like all of you to see.
This.
This plank is designed to come off.
There's something else.
Detective Takagi,
could you search the shed
behind me for balloons?
Got it.
There's three left.
Hayashida-san, how many balloons
are supposed to be there?
Nine.
So six are missing.
The killer used those balloons.
What?
Agasa-san, what are you talking about?
The killer left the cottage before 3 AM
when everyone had fallen asleep,
and prepared six of the balloons.
But inflating them makes a lot of noise.
That's why they had to move
away from the cottage.
I found evidence of their activities.
After 3 AM, they offered a
silent prayer to Motoki-san,
waited for the others to fall
back asleep, left the cottage,
retrieved the six balloons they had prepared,
and leaped from the top of the cliff.
They jumped?
So they did fly.
That's impossible.
Only six balloons aren't
enough for a person to fly.
You're right.
But that's the key to this trick.
They won't make a person fly,
but it's enough to reduce their falling speed,
like a bird spreading
their wings to decelerate.
They reduced their speed by landing
on the rocks partway down the cliff
before jumping the rest of the way down.
They reached the crime
scene quickly this way.
That's ridiculous.
They couldn't have done that.
Look at this.
It's a photo of the rocks
in the middle of the cliff.
There are some strange footprints
pointing towards the edge.
Wait.
With only six balloons,
it would've had to have been
someone extremely light to...
That's right.
Ikuguchi Eiko-san, you killed her.
I killed her?
You're wrong!
It wasn't her!
No.
After reaching the bottom of the cliff,
you released five of the six balloons.
The balloons floated north
on the wind to the lake,
where no one would find them.
You deflated the remaining balloon, cut it,
and kept it with you.
You killed Takemi-san, left Motoki-san's
compass at the crime scene,
and headed north with
Takemi-san's bag and wallet.
At the forest three kilometers
away, you left the bag,
and beyond that you left
the deflated balloon.
Once you returned,
you put the surveying equipment with
Takemi-san's blood in Hayashida-san's bag.
You're wrong.
You're wrong. I didn't do it!
Miss, you smell like kerosene.
What?
Now that I think about it,
there was meaning behind all of your actions.
Meaning?
Yeah.
You caused that fight and called her phone,
so Takemi-san would head
to the bottom of the cliff
and you could confirm
she was alive at 3 AM.
Don't be stupid.
I was sleeping with Ayumi-chan
when she was killed.
You planned that, too.
You wanted Yoshida-san to verify your alibi.
Really?
No.
I've had enough!
I didn't kill her, and I
didn't go to the forest!
We found this, too.
It's a species of horse thistle.
Around here, it only grows in that forest.
It was on Yoshida-san's pants.
It probably came from you while
you were sleeping together.
See? You did go to the forest.
After going to the forest,
you came to right below here.
All you had to do was return.
But using the mountain path
might leave more evidence.
That's why you began climbing
back up this cliff.
But you were in such a hurry, you
made a mistake at the very end.
This is blood.
Hey!
Yes, sir.
Excuse me.
This mark must have been
left by the balloons' rope.
Eiko, why did you kill her?
Motoki-san and I were secretly dating.
I couldn't forgive Takemi-san for
forcing him into that accident.
You spent three years planning her murder,
and learning to use balloons for that?
But why would you frame Hayashida?
Hayashida-san, you knew about us!
You were always jealous!
That's why you didn't tell Motoki-san he
was heading towards a dangerous cliff!
Mount Kumomaru
Peak
Okay, let's take a commemorative photo first.
Is everyone ready?
Yeah!
Mitsuhiko, it's on you.
What?
But I want to be in the
picture with Haibara-san.
Sorry, Ayumi-chan.
I want to be in the photo, too.
Please, Conan-kun.
Me?
Fine, then.
Detective Takagi.
This is to reward you for your help.
Say "cheese!"
Episode Preview
It's dangerous to walk alone at night.
Hey, Mister.
There's a weird smell mixed
in with the smell of alcohol.
He smells kind of like peppers.
Anyway, this wall sure
is glossy like a mirror.
That's because it has a UV coating.
The Security System's Pitfall
The next episode of Conan is
"The Security System's Pitfall!"
Thief
Next Conan's hint!
A thief!
Don't miss the next episode.
It's already mid-May.
Don't forget to go see "Crimson."
Got it!