You can rest assured, Junko-san.
I, Mori Kogoro,
will catch the thief who
broke into your home.
I hope you're right.
Miyoshi Junko (26)
Client
Thank you, Mori-san.
The jewelry shop by the station
was robbed the other day.
I'm so scared.
In that case, Junko-san, perhaps I
should stay at your house tonight.
That's all right.
My boyfriend's supposed to come over.
Your boyfriend, huh?
That's a relief.
So I was hoping you could catch
the thief as soon as possible.
Gladly!
Rejected.
Ow!
There was a bug on your head.
Did he hear that?
Thank you so much for walking me home.
No problem.
It's dangerous to walk alone at night.
What was that?
It sounded like it came from
the apartment parking lot.
Is something wrong?
O-Over there...
M-Mori-san, what in the world happened?
Junko-san, stay back.
And call the police.
O-Okay.
Kitagami-san?
What?
You knew him?
Y-Yes. He lived next door.
Mori-san, is Kitagami-san...?
Judging by his condition, he's probably dead.
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
While discussing theft prevention, a
neighbor experiences a strange fall.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Security System's Pitfall
"The Security System's Pitfall!"
Kitagami Naotsugu (32)
Office Worker
The deceased is Kitagami
Naotsugu-san, thirty-two years old.
He was an office worker who lived in
room 704 of this apartment building.
The cause of death was most likely
a cerebral contusion caused
by a strong blow to the head.
Due to the numerous scratches
on the front of the body,
he likely...
He likely fell by accident.
M-Mori-san?
The body stinks of alcohol.
After getting drunk, he probably slipped
and fell from his apartment's balcony.
Hey, mister.
There's a weird smell mixed
in with the smell of alcohol.
Kind of like peppers.
You just stay with Junko-san.
Okay.
By the way, who's the woman
who was with you?
Oh, no.
There's nothing suspicious
about our relationship.
Nobody said anything like that.
She's a victim of the burglaries that have
been occurring in this neighborhood lately.
When I came to this apartment
to discuss the matter,
I happened upon this incident.
Coincidentally, she lives in the room
next door to the victim Kitagami-san.
I see.
Inspector, we should head
up to the victim's room.
You're right.
Call the apartment manager.
Yes, sir.
Chiba-kun!
We're heading up to the victim's room!
Got it.
This is it.
He had his own security cameras, huh?
And he hired a security company, too.
Seems like he was a watchful person.
Yes.
Huh?
What is it?
The door's unlocked.
What?
It looks like he just forgot
to lock his front door.
Home
The security system's off,
and his house key is hanging right here.
Inspector, the victim seems
to have been drinking.
Quite a bit, too.
Inspector Megure.
What?
There's a bottle on the balcony, too.
Looks like I was right.
But why did the victim
come out on the balcony?
He was probably drunk
and trying to cool down.
Then he lost his balance
when he tripped on the bottle,
fell over the railing,
and plunged straight down
toward the ground.
I see.
Takagi-kun, Chiba-kun.
Split up and question the
neighbors just in case.
Yes, sir!
Thank you for your help.
Sawada
Yes?
Excuse me, but I'm with the police.
Could I ask you a few questions?
Give me a minute.
Sorry to bother you when you're so busy.
Sawada Ryosuke (30)
It's awfully noisy in the parking lot.
Did something happen?
Did you know Kitagami
Naotsugu-san in room 704?
Yeah, I'd seen him around.
Kitagami-san was found
dead in the parking lot.
What?!
Seriously?!
Do you know anything about that?
I was at home all day,
but I didn't notice anything in particular.
I see.
Hey, was your apartment burglarized?
What?! C-Conan-kun?!
Wh-Who's the kid?
What?
Oh, well...
There are scratches around your keyhole,
so I thought you might have been.
What? Really?
You're right.
It's probably just some mischief.
I didn't have anything taken from me.
Could you check again?
If you notice anything suspicious...
In that case, could you
let us see your balcony?
Could we see your balcony?
Did you find anything?
No, not in particular.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Conan-kun, let's go.
What's wrong?
I need to use the bathroom.
I've been holding it for a while.
What?
I'm sorry, but could we borrow your bathroom?
Go ahead. It's located...
That's okay. I can find it myself.
Conan-kun, we're here.
Oh, sorry. I was thinking.
Inspector Megure, I'm back.
D-Did something happen?
We know who did it.
What? Who did it?
I thought it was an accident.
We're not talking about that.
Apparently, this necklace
belongs to Miyoshi-san.
My boyfriend bought it for me overseas.
That's definitely it.
Uh, what about it?
We found that necklace in this room.
What? Then...
That's right.
The thief behind the string of burglaries
in the neighborhood
was the resident of this room who
got drunk and fell from his balcony,
Kitagami Naotsugu.
How did your questioning go, Takagi-kun?
I didn't find any particularly
useful information.
I see.
Then he probably got drunk,
and accidentally fell like Mori-kun said.
That's it! So that's how it is!
This wasn't just an accident.
I'll have Section Three
contact you immediately
regarding the stolen goods and burglary.
Okay.
Thank you.
Excuse us.
Anyway, that was an unexpected conclusion.
I can't believe the man who
fell happened to be the thief.
I know.
The question is how do I prove that?
Mori-kun, what are you doing?
Oh, I just...
While looking at myself
reflected on the wall,
I became concerned with my appearance.
Anyway, this wall sure
is glossy like a mirror.
That's because it has a UV coating.
Since it's quick-drying and glossy,
it's often used in elevators.
Huh...
Huh?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
The detective badge that was
in my pocket is missing.
I must have dropped it.
Do you have any idea where
you might've dropped it?
Well...
Oh!
It's probably in Sawada-san's room.
Can I go get it?
Of course.
Huh?
What's wrong? Go look for it already.
Mister, you're not coming with me?
Why would I go with you?
I feel helpless going alone.
What?
Aren't you always running around by yourself?
Why don't you go with him, Mori-kun?
Sheesh.
Let's get this over with.
Thanks, mister!
Sawada
Sorry about this.
I don't mind,
but please leave once you
find what you're looking for.
Of course.
Hey, did you find it?
Not yet.
That's weird.
Sheesh...
Is it really—
I found it.
Now that you've found it, let's go.
Okay!
Please do.
Sorry for the intrusion.
What?
What kind of joke is this?
Hey! Why are you lounging around?
What?
Coming!
You're that detective from earlier, and...
Excuse us.
Hello.
Mori-san told us to come here.
Great timing.
Can't you do something about him?
Mori-kun, what are you doing
in this man's apartment?
Excuse me.
I was so tired of waiting, I fell asleep.
Well? Why did you call us here?
I find it odd that Kitagami-san,
a man who employed extensive
anti-theft measures,
forgot to lock his front door.
But everyone forgets to
lock their door sometimes.
But he was a thief.
There was proof of it in his room.
Do you believe he'd be that careless?
There was something strange
about the body, too.
The body?
Detective Takagi, how do you
dress when you drink at home?
How do I dress?
Do you wear a suit and necktie?
Yeah, right.
Oh.
That's right.
Kitagami-san's body was dressed
in a suit and necktie,
even though he was supposedly
drinking at home.
But, Mori-kun,
it's possible the bottles in his apartment
had been left out for a while and
Kitagami-san had been out drinking.
That's not possible.
What?
There were still bubbles in the glass of beer
in Kitagami-san's room.
Doesn't that mean it was poured
shortly before we entered the room?
You're right. It is strange.
But what's stranger is the fact that
you're lounging around in this room.
What are you trying to do?
Solve the case, of course.
The case in which Sawada Ryosuke-san,
this room's resident, murdered Kitagami-san.
What?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Mori-kun, what do you mean?
Kitagami-san got drunk, tripped on a bottle,
and fell from his apartment's balcony.
Yeah, that's what you said.
There were scratches on the body.
But there were no corresponding
scratches on his balcony.
Didn't he just get scratched
on the ground when he fell?
Detective Takagi, look at the
balcony of this apartment.
You should find scratches.
Got it.
Mori-san, I found it!
Brand new scratch marks!
Sawada-san, after killing Kitagami-san,
you attempted to throw him from the balcony.
However, throwing a person
over the balcony is hard work.
So in order to throw him over the edge,
you lifted him onto the railing.
That's when Kitagami-san's belt
buckle scratched the railing.
Naturally, Kitagami-san's belt
buckle was scratched, too.
Then you raised his legs and slowly
lowered him from the balcony.
That's when the entire front
of his body was scratched.
I can't believe how rude you are.
You barged into my apartment, and
now you're accusing me of murder?
Didn't Kitagami fall from his own balcony?
He could've scraped against my
balcony while he was falling.
Why would I kill him, anyway?
We never even had a proper conversation.
Motive, huh?
Well, Mori-kun?
Kitagami-san was a thief.
And there were signs of lock picking
on the keyhole of this apartment.
What? You mean...
That's right.
He entered this room to burgle it,
and ran into you when you came home.
So he ran into the victim as he was
burgling his apartment and killed him?
Yes.
But, Mori-san, why didn't Sawada-san
report it to the police or run?
What if there was a reason he couldn't?
Couldn't?
Why wouldn't he be able to?
I think I know why.
What?
When I borrowed the bathroom here,
there was a big bag stuffed
into the bathroom cabinet.
You brat!
Now, now.
Takagi-kun, bring that bag here.
Yes, sir!
You don't mind, do you?
Inspector Megure.
I found the bag, just like Conan-kun said.
What's inside?
What?
This is...
Sawada-san, I apologize,
but you don't look like
you could afford to buy
so many expensive jewels.
Where did you get them?
Well?
He's right.
I stole those jewels!
So Kitagami found the jewels when
he broke into the apartment,
and you killed him to silence him.
No!
I-I was panicked when he found
the jewels, but we made a deal.
A deal?
He found the jewels, so I gave him one.
In exchange, we agreed to forget
about the burglary and jewel robbery.
Then he left without a fuss.
I don't know anything about his fall!
I've had enough of your delusions.
Mori-kun, you have proof
to back up your reasoning, don't you?
Of course.
In addition to the jewels,
there's tear gas inside the bag.
He must have used it during the robbery.
Kitagami-san's eyelids were red
and swollen not from drinking,
but because he was sprayed with tear gas.
Th-That's not evidence.
Mori-san.
I borrowed what you requested from forensics.
Perfect timing.
Conan, give me a hand.
Okay!
Detective Takagi, could I see that?
S-Sure.
This type of spray spreads in a mist.
So when you use it inside a room,
some of it gets on the user, too.
But the liquid's transparent and hard to see.
That's okay.
Tear gas contains UV paint
so the person who used it
can be tracked down even
if they wash their clothes.
Detective Chiba, could
you turn off the lights?
Okay.
Detective Chiba, illuminate
my hands and Conan's clothes
with the black light.
See?
I see.
Which means...
If Sawada-san's sleeves glow
like Conan's clothes...
Excuse me.
Well?
Will you still make excuses?
He said he changed his mind.
He suddenly demanded all the jewels.
He was being aggressive,
so without thinking, I used
the tear gas in the bag.
While he was writhing
around in unbearable pain,
he tripped on the table and hit
his head on the edge of the shelf.
He barged into my apartment
and killed himself!
How is that my fault?!
When I realized he lived directly above me,
I thought it wouldn't seem unnatural
if I threw him over the balcony.
Since he had his key on him,
I went to his apartment...
And you camouflaged his death.
You idiot!
Not only did you commit robbery,
but you also threw Kitagami-san from a balcony
in a childish attempt
to hide what you'd done!
That's a serious crime!
D-Damn it...
Damn it!
How long are you going to
keep sleeping, Mori-kun?
We're leaving.
Where am I?
My eyes burn!
My eyes hurt!
There's something on my hands!
Your reasoning was impressive,
but now you've disgraced yourself.
More like "dis-faced."
Episode Preview
Haneda Koji.
Shards of glass?
There's a pattern and letters on it.
It probably spelled "PUT ON MASCARA."
So, what?
Are you saying I did it?
Would it be all right
if I accompanied you to the crime scene?
Just Like a 17 Year Old Crime Scene
Part One
The next episode of Conan is "Just Like
a 17 Year Old Crime Scene, Part One!"
Scissors
Next Conan's hint!
Scissors!
A 17-year-old Sato-san?
Don't miss the next episode.
What's going on?
Just a misunderstanding.