Haneda Koji.
Seventeen years ago, the four-crowned shogi
master took his crowns and went to America
to participate in a chess tournament,
which he played as a hobby.
Mysterious Death
of Shogi Genius
But the night before the tournament,
someone attacked and killed him in
the hotel room where he was staying.
The room was ransacked,
and Haneda seemed to have
resisted his killer,
but the actual cause of his death is unclear.
The cause of death of Amanda Hughes,
a wealthy American woman killed
on the same day in another room of
the same hotel, is also unknown.
Because Amanda was a fan of
Haneda and interacted with him,
and the bodyguard who was accompanying
her vanished after that day,
the bodyguard Amanda called "Asaka"
has been sought after as the prime suspect
in the case, but he's still missing.
Furthermore, the identity of
"Asaka" is shrouded in mystery.
None of Amanda's family or friends
know how she came to hire him.
Hey, wouldn't you know who Asaka is?
Who knows?
I've never heard of him.
But if Haneda Koji's cause
of death is unknown,
and he's on the list of persons
administered APTX 4869,
then it's likely Asaka is a
member of the Organization.
Don't you think it's weird, though?
If Haneda Koji was killed seventeen years ago,
Kudo Shinichi Missing
Haneda Koji Dead
why is his name two rows below mine?
Whoever kept the list didn't list the
victims in the order they were killed.
Maybe they were grouped according
to their blood types.
And if that drug was around
seventeen years ago, then...
How old are you?
How rude.
I told you, I'm eighteen.
It was probably the drug my parents made.
All I did was scrape together the data
that survived the fire and recreated it.
Survived the fire?
My parents' lab caught fire.
The two of them burned to
death along with their data.
The Organization told me it
was an unfortunate accident.
What they were actually having me make
was a different drug, though.
But...
Why would they kill a Japanese shogi player?
He probably just happened to witness them
killing that wealthy woman
who was getting in their way.
Apparently Amanda had clout
with the FBI and CIA.
And it's true that Amanda
visited Haneda Koji's room.
Apparently Amanda's fingerprints were
on the doorknob, sofa, teacup, plate,
and fork in Haneda's room.
Maybe they ordered tea and cake through
room service for afternoon tea.
Looks like the dishes were smashed
when the room was ransacked, though.
Yeah.
Shards of plates and cups with
"Juke," the hotel's name,
on them were scattered all over the room.
There's some glass mixed
in with the utensils.
Was it a mirror?
And there are letters on it, too.
PTON?
It probably spelled "PUT ON MASCARA."
Right around that time,
there was a cosmetics company
selling mirrors along with mascara.
It was a huge hit.
They contained the words "PUT ON MASCARA."
My sister inherited one of
those mirrors from our mother.
But what would that mirror be
doing in Haneda Koji's room?
The wealthy woman who was
murdered was over 80 years old.
Maybe Haneda Koji got
it from his mother, too.
As a shogi player, he probably
minded his own appearance.
Anyway, I'm more interested in
the room that was left ransacked.
The Organization never would've done this.
They always leave things as
though nothing had happened.
That's what the murdered
woman's room looked like.
It says the sink in the bathroom
was left running, too.
Anyway, I'm impressed you were
able to find this information.
Someone regularly uploads it to the internet.
They don't seem to care that it gets deleted.
It's as though someone's asking
for the mystery to be solved.
But how do you know he resisted?
There are defensive wounds
on Haneda Koji's arms
from being punched or kicked.
In his right hand were marks left
by him holding the small scissors
that came with the room.
He was holding scissors?
What about the scissors?
Actually, there was a murder
in Okuho City this morning.
The victim died holding
some scissors I invented,
so Inspector Megure asked me to come
to the crime scene this afternoon
to explain how they work.
You mean those stupid scissors that
say "snip" when you close them.
You managed to sell those?
Ahem!
Everyone says the sound
is excellently pleasant.
Would it be all right if I accompanied you
to the crime scene?
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
A case involving APTX and a hotel.
With scissors in hand,
danger is fast approaching.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Just Like a 17 Year Old Crime Scene
(Part One)
"Just Like a 17 Year Old
Crime Scene, Part One!"
S-Subaru-san.
Why?
I seem to have made too
much meat and potatoes.
I came to share.
That's not what I meant.
Why do you want to go to a crime scene?
There's something about that
case that interests me.
Then let's head over there.
Yeah.
Oh, you don't need to come.
What?
You can stay home alone, can't you?
Fine.
You want me to stay here by myself so
I can eat this poorly-made food, right?
Is it that bad?
The vegetables in the cream stew you shared
with us the other day were completely raw.
It felt like you'd been listening
in on our conversation,
and hurriedly brought over
the food you were making
so you could get involved in the case.
Yeah, right.
I'm just not a good cook.
In that case, I'd appreciate it if you
could recook the food while we're gone.
I'm pretty sure I used the right
ingredients and seasoning.
Look after the girl.
I'm counting on you, Camel.
Yes, sir.
Hiyama
Agasa-san, we've been waiting for you.
You didn't come alone?
Well, actually...
I was actually involved in the
development of those scissors.
Will we be in the way?
W-Well, if that's the case...
Are those scissors that
amazing of an invention?
So the crime scene's in the annex.
The victim had been spending most
of his time in the annex lately
because he felt the main house was insecure.
Those two are strangely well-built.
Are they bodyguards?
Ah, Agasa-san.
Thank you for coming all the way out here.
You're welcome.
The body's still here.
Allow me to explain the situation.
The victim was the president
of a real estate company,
and owner of the house, Hiyama
Kunihisa-san, sixty-one years old.
Hiyama Kunihisa (61)
Real Estate Company President
He was bludgeoned to death
with a blunt object.
He was attacked in another room of the annex,
and fled into the changing
room of the bathroom,
but the culprit broke through
the door and finished him off.
The victim was holding these scissors
with your logo on them.
What do they do?
Oh, they—
Wait.
You'll hurt yourself if you're not careful.
Shards of glass?
There's a pattern and letters on it.
Looks like it matches the cup on the counter.
Can we assume the victim
threw this cup at his killer
when he entered the room?
What?
Yes.
Then the victim attempted to defend
himself with these scissors,
invented by Professor Agasa,
that he used to trim his mustache?
P-Probably.
Then don't you think it's strange?
Wh-What's strange?
The mop behind the victim.
What?
The mop?
The long-handled mop would be far better
for defending oneself against
a killer with a blunt object,
so why did he choose the scissors?
Y-You're right.
Wait, who are you?
I forgot to introduce myself.
I'm Professor Agasa's
assistant, Okiya Subaru.
Okiya-san?
I came here today to help
explain the scissors.
Oh, right.
Apparently these scissors make
a sound when they're closed,
but can they record noises?
They're not nearly that useful.
Sorry.
I thought he was holding them because
he recorded the killer's voice.
But there's blood on the shards
of glass near the entrance.
The culprit must've stepped on them.
C-Conan-kun, you can't come in here!
Won't we know the identity of the killer
if we compare this blood with the blood
of the people who came to the house?
Actually, that blood...
What?
It belongs to the person
who discovered the body?
Not the killer?
Yes.
His name is Senba Kazunori-san.
He ran a candy shop in this neighborhood,
but his son and wife sold the property
to President Hiyama without his approval,
so he came by this morning to complain.
Then didn't he do it?
That's not possible.
Not possible?
As you can see,
there are iron bars on all of
the windows of the annex.
Those two bodyguards were
at the only entrance,
and they were frisking everyone who entered.
They would've known immediately if
someone was carrying a blunt weapon.
They were even using a metal detector.
Is it not possible they used something
that was already in the annex as a weapon?
No.
President Hiyama had a lot of enemies
because of his dishonest business practices.
To avoid being attacked by his visitors,
the only thing that could serve
as a weapon was that mop.
Nothing else was kept in the annex.
Naturally, we didn't find blood on the mop.
Was the old man already dead when he entered?
Yeah.
After being frisked,
Senba-san entered the annex and called
out to him, but there was no answer.
The bathroom door was
open, so he went to look.
He saw President Hiyama on the
floor and bleeding from the head.
When he ran to the body, he stepped
on a shard of glass near the door.
Then he returned to the entrance and
told the bodyguards what happened.
Huh.
Where is he right now?
He's being treated by a police
officer in the main house.
Please excuse me if I'm wrong,
but was the sink in the
changing room left running?
Yeah, it was.
How did you know?
I knew it.
Hey, Akai-san.
Is there something going on with this case?
You must have noticed, too.
It's very similar to the murder of
Haneda Kenji seventeen years ago.
The case that inspired me to join...
the FBI.
It inspired you to join the FBI?
Akai-san, you were involved in the
Haneda Koji case seventeen years ago?
No, it was my father who
was directly involved.
Th-Then was your dad an
FBI investigator, too?
No, he wasn't in the FBI.
But if I'm going to tell you about my father,
I wish you'd tell me your identity.
Not until after everything's been resolved.
I see.
I have a feeling he already knows, though.
Hey, what in the world is going on?
Senba Kazunori (50)
Former Candy Store Owner
I thought you were going to let me leave
once they were finished treating my cut.
W-We still have questions for you.
Is that him?
Yeah.
That's Senba Kazunori-san, the
man who discovered the body.
Ah, the man who injured himself stepping on
a piece of a broken cup at the crime scene.
Yeah.
Excuse me, but did you step on
the glass with your right foot?
What?
It looked like you were favoring
your right leg as you walked.
No, I hurt my left foot today.
My right leg is feeling the aftereffects
of when I broke it in a
traffic accident last month.
I ended up in the hospital
until last week because of it.
Wait, who are you? A cop?
No, he helped develop the scissors
the victim Hiyama-san was holding.
Would you be willing to recreate the
circumstances under which you found the body?
I have a few questions.
Hmph.
Why would I do that when
you're not even a cop?
Hey, about those scissors.
They have another special feature.
If you performed a certain
action near the body,
that feature may have been activated.
Right, Professor?
Y-Yeah.
Wh-What action?
We can't tell you yet.
In any case, why don't you do what
you did when you found the body?
What?
Did those scissors have that kind of feature?
First I was frisked
by these bodyguards at the annex entrance.
Then I opened the door and went inside.
I waited a while, but he didn't come out,
so I entered the annex and called
out to him, but he didn't answer.
Then...
I noticed the door to the
bathroom changing room was open.
When I looked inside, I saw this.
What's going on?
The scissors' special feature
may have been activated,
so he's recreating the steps
he took when he found the body.
Then you saw Hiyama-san
bleeding from the head
and lying on the ground,
so you ran to him, right?
Y-Yeah.
Even though there were clearly
pieces of a cup all over the floor?
W-Well, when I looked inside,
the door was only cracked open.
S-So I didn't notice the shards.
Then I punctured my foot
when I ran to the body.
That's weird, though.
What?
If the door was mostly closed,
then when you opened it to enter the room,
most of the shards should have been
pushed to the other side of the door.
And if the culprit closed the door,
then there should be more
shards closer to the entrance.
Y-You're right.
I made a mistake.
Th-The door was wide open.
I was distracted by the body
and didn't look at the floor.
Really?
So what?
Are you saying that I did it?
Look closely.
If I hit someone hard enough to make
them bleed, I'd have blood on me.
But there isn't any blood on my clothes.
Huh?
Mister, the bottom buttons on your
shirt are in the wrong holes.
What?
And the back isn't tucked into your pants.
Your necktie is tied neatly,
but the rest of you is a mess.
I-It's just a coincidence.
I-In any case, I didn't have a blunt
object that could serve as the weapon!
That proves I didn't do it!
I've had enough. I'm leaving.
You can't leave yet.
Wait! Wait a minute!
Please, Senba-san!
We're finished taking photos.
Let's collect the pieces of the cup.
Yeah.
Did Senba-san step on the glass barefooted?
No, he was wearing slippers.
See?
I see.
So that's how it is.
Uh, do those slippers
have anything to do with the
feature of Agasa-san's scissors?
This broken cup is the same as
the one on the counter, right?
Yeah.
Apparently the Fusae Brand collaborated
with a tableware maker to make those cups.
Fusae-san did?
So what does the cup have
to do with the scissors?
Excuse me. Body coming through.
A sweet...
...smell.
I smelled a strange smell
coming from the body.
Oh, right.
There was some kind of honey-like
paste in the wound on the body.
Honey?
Does the honey have anything
to do with the scissors?
If it doesn't, then could you
please leave the crime scene?
Are you listening?
The scissors the victim was holding.
The broken cup on the floor.
The smell of honey on the body.
The running sink.
How did the culprit kill Hiyama-san?
Episode Preview
If Senba-san isn't the culprit
because he didn't have a weapon,
then how did the culprit...?
Looks like you found the
weapon you were looking for.
You figured out the trick the culprit used?
Yes, we did.
Yeah.
I bought the capsule toy,
honey, colored ball,
and large marble you asked for.
Just Like a 17 Year Old Crime Scene
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Just Like
a 17 Year Old Crime Scene, Part Two!"
Colored Ball
Next Conan's hint!
A colored ball!
Don't miss the next episode.
The evidence is sweet honey.
But meat and potatoes...
...shouldn't be too sweet.