Because the murder victim was holding
scissors invented by Professor Agasa,
Hiyama
Okiya Subaru-san and I accompanied
the professor to the crime scene.
Was the sink in the changing
room left running?
Yeah, it was.
How did you know?
Hey, Akai-san.
Is there something going on with this case?
You must have noticed, too.
It's very similar
to the murder of Haneda Koji
seventeen years ago.
And when the body passed by us as it
was being transported to the morgue...
A sweet...
...smell.
There was some kind of honey-like paste
in the wound on the body.
The scissors the victim was holding.
The broken cup on the floor.
The smell of honey on the body.
The running sink.
How did the culprit kill Hiyama-san?
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
Scissors, a cup, and sweet honey.
A variety of evidence ties it all together.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Just Like a 17 Year Old Crime Scene
(Part Two)
"Just Like a 17 Year Old
Crime Scene, Part Two!"
What a strange case.
Hiyama Kunihisa (61)
Real Estate Company President
The victim was murdered while
holding a pair of scissors.
There's honey in the wound on the body.
On top of that, the sink was left running.
Even if Senba-san isn't the culprit
because he didn't have a weapon,
how did the culprit sneak into the annex
when there are metal bars in the windows?
No.
What?
The culprit...
...is him.
Senba Kazunori (50)
Former Candy Store Owner
It's Senba-san.
What?
R-Really?
Yes.
We even know how he killed him.
But we still haven't found the weapon.
Hey!
You guys searched Senba-san, right?
Oh.
Yeah.
Did Senba-san have anything
unusual on him then?
Anything unusual, huh?
Come to think of it,
he had a plastic bag containing a
little figurine about this small.
And a little catalog of the
series the figurine belonged to.
He said it was a prize from his candy shop,
and that he was going to
give it to his grandchild.
Although that store has
apparently closed down.
Anything else?
Besides that he had a wallet,
handkerchief, and keys.
Come to think of it, one of
those colored balls I used
to buy at the neighborhood candy shop
as a kid came flying over the wall.
A—
A colored ball?
Yeah.
Just before Senba-san arrived,
there was a yellow one about this size.
We turned it over to the police.
There's a park on the other side of the wall,
so some kids were probably playing baseball.
They never came to retrieve it, though.
Do you remember where that ball came from?
Yeah.
We heard something strike the roof,
so I headed to the back of the annex.
I think it was around here.
Did both of you leave the entryway then?
No, I came by myself.
Was there anything besides the colored ball?
No, just the one ball.
Hey, there aren't bars in this little window.
Where does it lead?
The bathroom.
The one across the hallway
from the changing room.
Huh.
Not even a kid could fit
through a window that small.
That's why there aren't any bars on it.
The slippers he wore when
he stepped on the glass.
The honey in the wound.
The colored ball that struck the roof.
The figurine inside a
plastic bag and catalog.
The small bathroom window.
Come to think of it...
The sound we heard was pretty
loud for a colored ball.
It sounded like "clang-clang."
C-Could it be?
Was the weapon inside?
Professor!
Is something wrong?
Oh, no, I-I just...
It's nothing serious,
but l-look.
A-Ants.
The ants have formed a line.
I was surprised when I saw them.
But, Professor, you have tons
of insect encyclopedias.
I know, but...
It's easy to think of them as cute little
insects when they're inside photos,
but seeing them move around
in person is a bit rough.
It's different if they're inside?
Hey, kid.
Come here.
Looks like we found the weapon
we've been looking for.
What?
You figured out the culprit's
identity and the trick he used?
Is that true, Agasa-san?
No, it's these two who figured it out.
Yes, we did.
Yeah.
We determined the method Senba-san used
to bring a blunt weapon into the annex.
What?
Wait a minute. I already told you.
I was frisked when I entered the annex.
Hey, you.
I didn't have a blunt object then, did I?
What?
No.
But you had a figurine inside a plastic bag,
and a little catalog of that
figurine's product series, right?
S-So what?
Then you should've had one of those, too,
so why didn't you?
What are you talking about?
A round plastic capsule.
The objects you had on you were
the contents of a capsule toy.
Apparently the catalog wasn't inside
the plastic bag with the figurine.
Oh, that?
I threw it away since it
was getting in the way.
Conan-kun.
I bought the capsule toy,
honey, colored ball,
and large marble you asked for.
But did the culprit really use these?
Yeah.
Start by opening the capsule.
Use the tap holding the halves together
to cover the holes in the capsule.
Then put the marble inside the capsule,
pour the honey over it,
and close the capsule again.
There. All done.
All done? What does that mean?
Could you throw this capsule and the
colored ball on the roof of the bathroom?
What? You want me to throw them?
Yeah.
Got it.
Make sure you throw them on the roof.
Okay.
There.
Huh?
The colored ball came down, but
the capsule's still up there.
Detective Takagi, keep watching over there.
Okay.
Now let's head inside the annex.
Yeah.
Could you remind me what you did after
being frisked and entering the annex?
I-I told you.
I waited for Hiyama to come meet me,
but he never showed up, so I went inside.
No, when Hiyama-san met you, you told him...
What?
"I'd like to use your bathroom."
Th-The bathroom?
Yes.
Of course, not to perform
a biological function,
but to collect the murder weapon.
What?
In any case, let's go to the bathroom.
It should be arriving soon.
Arriving?
You'll see.
In the bathroom across from the changing room
where Hiyama-san was murdered...
If you open this small window...
near the bottom of the wall...
See?
Th-That's...
The capsule Takagi-kun threw on the roof.
What's that capsule doing outside the window?
Did you hand it to him, Takagi-kun?
No, I didn't do anything.
Then how?
Inspector Megure, weren't you watching?
The colored ball rolled off the sloped roof,
but even if you tilt this capsule...
See?
The marble gets stuck in the honey,
and it doesn't roll very well.
I-I see.
So unlike the colored ball
that fell right away,
the capsule rolled slowly.
Once it entered the gutter,
it slowly rolled along.
Then it fell to the bottom
the same way rainwater would
and came out the end of the gutter.
Gutters are slanted slightly towards the edge
so rainwater flows through them better.
I-Is that what happened, Takagi-kun?
Yes, sir.
It came rolling out after a while.
By the way, Senba-san threw the colored ball,
along with the capsule,
from outside the fence
to disguise the sound.
Since the bodyguard mistook the colored
ball as the source of the sound,
he left the area immediately.
But is this marble really
enough to kill someone?
What was inside the capsule was a
heavy iron ball rather than a marble.
If you put that ball inside
a sock and made a blackjack,
it would dramatically increase its lethality.
The honey around the wound
on the murdered Hiyama-san's head proves it.
Right, Senba-san?
What...
What about the blood?
If I hit him hard enough to kill him,
I'd have blood on me.
But there's no blood on any of my clothes.
You probably got naked inside the bathroom
so the blood wouldn't get on you.
It seems like you dressed
yourself in a hurry.
You washed off the blood
that got on your body
in the bathroom next to the
changing room, didn't you?
You could've dried yourself off
using toilet paper and flushed it.
Right, Professor?
Y-Yeah...
Normally you vigorously solve the mystery,
but you're awfully quiet today.
I-I thought I'd let the
young'uns handle this case.
That's right.
After retrieving the iron
ball from the bathroom,
Senba-san put the ball
inside a sock, undressed,
and called Hiyama-san to the bathroom...
Claiming, "the toilet won't stop
flushing" or something similar.
Then Hiyama-san was struck
by Senba-san with the sock
containing the iron ball.
He fled into the changing
room opposite the bathroom,
but the door was broken down.
He threw a cup to resist his attacker,
to no avail before being
finished off by Senba-san.
Senba-san meant to wash off the blood
and honey-stained sock along with his body,
but if he wore slippers over a wet sock,
that slipper would be unnaturally wet.
So he deliberately injured himself
by stepping on the shards
of the cup Hiyama-san threw at him,
and used it as an excuse
to take off the sock.
After hastily dressing yourself,
you went to the entryway
and told the bodyguards
Hiyama-san was murdered in the changing room.
While they left their post to investigate,
you hid the weapon beneath the main house.
Forensics has already found the
capsule containing the iron ball
that was swarming with ants,
and even though you stepped on the
shard of glass with your heel,
there was blood all the
way inside the slipper
because it's Hiyama-san's blood.
Naturally, it should be on your body, too.
You can't erase traces
of blood from your body
just by washing it once with water.
Yeah.
I'm sure it's all over me.
When I washed myself off in the bathroom,
the tiles were red with his blood.
Did you kill him because he bought your land?
Yeah.
He talked my son and his wife into
it while I was in the hospital.
But the accident that put me in the hospital
was something Hiyama put
his underlings up to.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
When I asked him about
it before I killed him,
he promised to pay my hospital
bills if I spared him.
My family ran that candy shop
since my grandfather's generation.
I was shocked to find it gone once
I returned from the hospital.
The shop had been smashed to pieces,
and a giant iron ball
was swinging in the air.
So I smashed his head open
with my own iron ball,
but in the end, I'm just a
man who runs a candy shop.
I couldn't fool you.
Especially not a kid.
What about those scissors
the victim was holding?
Ah, that was Hiyama-san's dying message.
A dying message?
The letters on the shards
of glass on the floor
were F, U, A, and R.
The shard stuck in the slipper read D.
If you rearrange the letters left
after removing FUARD from FUSAE BRAND,
you get SENBA.
I see.
B-But it's hard to imagine he was able
to precisely cut out those
little letters with scissors
while the door of the changing
room was about to be broken down.
Th-That's it.
The chemomechanical effect.
Ch-Chemomechanical?
Yeah.
If you try to cut glass
with scissors, it shatters.
But if the glass is submerged in water,
the water molecules permeate
the glass, which weakens it.
It allows you to cut it.
D-Does that really happen
when you put glass in water?
Could you show us?
Even though it's like cutting glass,
it does still shoot off small
shards, so it's very dangerous.
And I don't want to cut
one of Fusae-san's cups.
Then why didn't he leave
the letters spelling SENBA?
That would've been easier to understand.
Because it would've been too easy.
If the culprit realized the letters
spelled his own name at a glance,
he would've hidden them.
Y-You're right.
That's probably why he
threw the cup at Senba-san
when he came through the door after
cutting the letters out of it.
That way he would think the glass
broke when it hit the wall.
He wouldn't realize the letters that were
removed from the glass were more important.
It would be impossible...
...for the culprit to tell instantaneously.
I see, I see.
The scissors in his hand
and the running water
were a hint pointing
to that whatever effect,
and the shards containing
the letters spelling SENBA
were washed down the drain.
I see, I see.
Hey, wait.
G-Guys? Conan-kun?
Sheesh!
H-Hey.
Are you sure you want to leave, Shinichi?
Aren't they interviewing
the suspect after this?
Your laptop!
Professor, your laptop is in your car, right?
Yeah.
Are you all right, Shinichi?
I found it.
And where did Akai-san go?
Why'd you suddenly want to meet, Shu?
Take my tablet out of the glove box.
What?
I found it.
The documents on Haneda Koji's
case haven't been deleted yet.
The letters left in the mirror
were PTON.
The letters originally written on
the mirror were PUT ON MASCARA.
If you remove PTON,
that leaves UMASCARA.
There are a lot of As.
Is it a Japanese person's name?
Since "CA" and "KA" can be
pronounced the same way,
what comes to mind is...
ASACA.
The suspect Asaka.
If you remove ASACA from UMASCARA,
that leaves UMR.
And if you rearrange those...
RUM.
Episode Preview
Spirit detective Hotta Gaito?
What?
He's going to solve the mystery
of Haneda Koji's murder?
Someone just ran from the balcony.
H-Haneda...
Koji.
What's wrong, Detective Takagi?
Something got stuck to my hand
when I hit the table earlier.
Is this salt?
The Spirit Detective's Murder
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Spirit Detective's Murder, Part One!"
Wine Glass
Next Conan's hint!
A wine glass!
Don't miss the next episode.
Rum.
The man with one false eye.
And the Organization's number two.