Detective Conan Episode 863 "The
Spirit Detective's Murder (Part One)"
Rum.
I was right.
The person who vanished after killing
Haneda Koji seventeen years ago...
...was the bodyguard Asaka.
And the identity of Asaka...
...is the number two man of the
Black Organization, Rum.
Even if that's the dying message
he left before he was murdered,
I can't find any other information.
Is Asaka their family name
or given name, anyway?
If it's their family name, then
I can't even tell their gender.
And what drug was Haneda Koji given?
Apparently it was made by Haibara's parents.
But Haibara said she wasn't trying...
...to make a poison when
she recreated the drug.
Besides, Gin mentioned something
when I was given that drug.
We'll use this.
This drug was recently developed
by the Organization.
They won't be able to find any
traces of poison in the body.
It allows you to commit the perfect crime.
Although this prototype hasn't
been tested on humans yet.
Which means I was given the
the drug recreated by Haibara,
and I was its first test subject.
I'm home.
What? An interview?
With another detective?
Spirit detective Hotta Gaito?
Yeah, I remember a shady detective
who used to go by that name.
In any case, I need to
gather more information.
But the case's site was taken down, and
it hasn't been reuploaded for a while.
What? He's going to solve the
mystery of Haneda Koji's murder?
What?
Wasn't the Haneda Koji murder...
...an unsolved case of some guy...
...who was murdered in America
seventeen years ago?
What?
He's going to summon the
spirit of Haneda Koji?!
I don't have time for that kind of idiocy!
What?
This time it's just a short segment
on a late night TV show,
but if it's well-received, it'll
be switched to prime time?
And my name will be in the title?
And the MC will be Okino Yoko-chan?
Mori Kogoro's
Solve the Cold Case!!
There's a planning meeting tomorrow
morning at a hotel restaurant?
Okay, okay!
So, how much does it pay?
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
The information on Rum is eerily effective.
What will the spirit detective reveal?
Always determining the one truth...
...with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Spirit Detective's Murder
(Part One)
"The Spirit Detective's Murder, Part One!"
Why'd you have to come with me?
Ran-neechan's been gone since yesterday
night because of her karate training camp.
And it's not fair that you're the
only one who gets to eat at a hotel.
Apparently the TV station's paying for it,
but don't order anything too expensive.
Besides, I want to meet
the spirit detective, too.
Hotta Gaito
Spirit Detective
That detective Hotta
Gaito summons the spirits...
...of dead people and says
things only people close...
...to the deceased would've known, right?
Yeah.
Apparently he found the skeleton of a
person who went missing in the mountains.
It was a coincidence.
The bones ended up belonging to someone else.
Besides, Hotta knew all that information
because he investigated cases beforehand.
It got out that he paid people to create
false witness reports of the missing person.
After the media destroyed
him, he disappeared.
Anyway, I'm surprised he
was able to return to TV.
And even if he does have a new scam,
the Sleeping Kogoro will expose it.
That's right.
If he's summoning the spirit
of a man who died so long ago,
it's likely he got a hold of information related
to the case that hasn't been made public yet.
I'll do whatever it takes
to get that information.
And expose the identity of Rum.
Mori-san!
Thank you for waiting.
Sorry for asking you to come so early.
Kokuri Sanpei (35)
Toto TV Director
It's fine.
Ah, you must be Conan-kun.
Nice to meet you.
I know about you.
You're the Kid Killer, right?
You think we could get a
comment from you, too?
Sure.
Let's eat while we discuss the show.
First, we need to go the room
where Hotta-san is staying.
What?
Apparently he wants you to
see him summon a spirit.
All right.
Let's head there.
Anyway, you were right to
bring Conan-kun with you.
What?
Even if him summoning a spirit
does seem a little fake,
we'll still be able to get a
shot of him looking surprised.
I see.
I can't imagine this kid
being surprised by that.
Huh? That's weird.
He should be in his room.
When I emailed him this morning to
confirm the time of our meeting,
he said he was seeing someone
else before our meeting.
Maybe he's still at their room.
Huh? Hotta-san emailed me an hour ago.
What?!
They're going to kill me. Help.
"Th-They're going to kill me. Help?"
Seriously?
I-In any case, I'll have a
bellhop come unlock the door.
You stay here so nobody leaves the room.
S-Sure.
This better not be some kind of performance.
What's taking him so long?
What is that director doing?
Oh, they're here.
Sorry. It took a while
to explain the situation.
Hotta-sama?
Hotta-sama, are you there?
You don't need to bother
with that. Open the door.
A-All right.
In that case...
Hey, wait!
My phone's ringing.
Hello, Hotta-san?
Is that you, Hotta-san?
I'm sorry.
It was a wrong number.
I'm opening the door.
Okay.
Hotta-sama?
What was that sound?
It sounded like something breaking.
Wineglasses and plates.
Looks like someone was drinking
wine until a moment ago.
That person dropped the plates and
glasses in surprise when we came in,
stepped in the spilled wine,
and ran into that room.
Someone just ran from the balcony!
But we're on the fourth floor.
No, I know I saw someone.
They must've crossed the balcony
into the room next door.
They left their wine-stained
slippers behind, too.
That must be it.
Hey, bellhop.
Y-Yes, sir.
Is there someone staying
in the room next door?
You mean room 403?
A young high school-aged man has
been staying there since last week.
What?
Some kid has been living by
themselves in a hotel for a week?
More importantly, what's that sound?
It's the sound of the remodeling
construction going on downstairs.
Since it's loud and makes
the rooms shake a little,
the rooms in this area are discounted.
Huh.
So, where's Hotta Gaito?
Probably in bed.
There's a slight bump.
But judging by the fact that
he hasn't moved an inch,
he's probably already...
Damn it. Who would do something so awful?
Hotta-san?
Hotta-san!
Stop!
Don't touch the body.
Right.
I'll go back to the front
desk and call the police.
No, you stay here with Kokuri-san...
...and call the police from here.
If the killer returns through that window,
one man may not be enough to stop them.
S-Stop them?
M-Mori-san, where are you going?
I'm going to the room next door.
That kid living in the room next
door may have been killed already.
Damn it. No one's answering.
The killer must've gotten to them.
Who is it?
What's with all the noise?
Y-You...
Huh? You're the guy from
the detective agency.
S-Sera...neechan?
Hey, Conan-kun's with you.
More importantly, did anyone enter your room?
No.
Are you sure?
It's true.
I'm the only one in here.
I see, I see.
Have I got this right?
The room next door to this one is room 402.
You went there with TV director Kokuri...
...to meet with the spirit detective.
The moment you opened the door,
you heard the sound of wine glasses...
...and plates falling and breaking.
When you ran into the room, you saw footprints
left by someone who stepped in the wine.
Those footprints led into the bedroom, so
when you opened the door and went inside,
the window was open, and you saw
someone running from the balcony.
That balcony is connected to the
balcony of my room, room 403.
You thought that person might have leapt...
...over the railing and fled into my room.
While you were looking around,
you noticed a slight lump
in the bed in the bedroom.
And when you pulled off the covers...
Is that right?
Yeah.
That's why we were wondering if
anyone suspicious came to your room.
It's just me.
But the wine-stained slippers were left at the
edge of the balcony of the room next door.
Since we're on the fourth floor,
your room was the only
place they could've gone.
In any case, let me search your room.
They could have sneaked in
and be hiding somewhere.
I told you, there's no one here.
Anyway, do you know who did it?
Apparently he met someone
before he was meeting me.
They probably did it.
It's probably someone involved
in that seventeen year old case.
Hotta Gaito said he was going to
summon the spirit of Haneda Koji,
who was murdered in that case.
H-Haneda...
...Koji.
And?
Did that detective tell you
anything about the case?
N-No. I hadn't met him yet.
What? Do you know something about Haneda?
Y-Yeah. He was a professional
shogi player, right?
If you want to be involved in this
case, let me search your room.
The police will be doing it
anyway when they get here.
Fine.
I left my underwear out, so give me a minute.
Sheesh.
How long does it take to
put away some underwear?
Excuse me.
I just heard from the front desk.
We received a complaint about a car parked
in a strange spot in the parking lot.
Is it either of yours?
Oh, that's my car.
Sorry. The parking lot was full.
I forgot that I was going to re-park it later.
I-I'll move it right away.
Thanks for waiting.
Hey, wa-
If you needed to hide yourself in a hurry...
The perfect place would be the balcony.
But there's no one here.
Anyway, since the wine-stained slippers
were on the balcony next door,
they must have jumped to this one.
This is the fourth floor.
They couldn't have jumped down.
Huh? There's a car parked
directly below the balcony.
What's it doing there?
Kokuri-san?
Oh, that must be the car he just mentioned.
It's a convertible.
He's got a nice car.
That's odd, though.
The parking lot's pretty empty.
Why'd he park it there?
I should take some pictures just in case.
I should take one of under the balcony, too.
Conan-kun.
Kogoro-san's calling you.
He's finished searching the room.
Oh, okay.
Sorry to have bothered you.
See? I was right.
Doesn't he have good instincts?
More importantly, solve this
case as soon as possible.
If the police search this room,
they'll find out about me.
You need to solve it before
they hear about the information...
...concerning Haneda Koji's
murder and come here.
Y-Yeah.
A bow tie?
I understand the events leading
up to the discovery of the body.
But it's hard to believe someone
hurried out of the room,
since you heard the sounds of wine glasses
and plates breaking when you opened the door.
There was construction taking place
on the floor below at that time.
The room was shaking slightly, wasn't it?
Y-Yes.
Construction starts every day at 9 AM.
You entered this room right
around 9 AM, didn't you?
Yes.
Then couldn't the vibrations from the
work have caused the glasses and plates...
...to fall if they were positioned
just on the edge of the table?
Why don't we try it by putting our
phones on the edge of the table?
Y-You're right.
Is everyone ready?
Here we go.
Huh?
Half of them fell, but the other
half are still on the table.
That's it.
Even if the table shakes, there's no telling
which way they'll shift, so they don't all fall.
I see.
Even if the utensils were placed on the edge,
the odds that they would fall
on the floor were 50-50.
It's not very useful for a trick.
You're right.
And there's no guarantee construction
would start at exactly 9 AM.
Actually, construction was
scheduled to start at 9 AM.
It's falling behind schedule, so the hotel has
been pressuring the construction company to hurry.
But there's still no guarantee
it would start at exactly 9 AM.
Actually, we once received
a complaint from a guest...
...that construction started a minute early,
so the construction crew's clocks are set
to match the hotel's down to the second.
I see.
But it's still a coincidence that
we opened the door at exactly 9 AM.
Besides, we opened the door
then because Kokuri-san...
...was delayed while calling the bellhop.
What's taking him so long?
What is that director doing?
They're here.
Sorry. It took a while
to explain the situation.
And Kokuri-san went to get the bellhop...
...because he noticed the email from Hotta-san.
Huh? Hotta-san emailed me an hour ago.
What?
They're going to kill me. Help.
"Th-They're going to kill me. Help?"
Seriously?
I-In any case, I'll have a
bellhop come unlock the door.
You stay here so nobody leaves the room.
S-Sure.
And the email Kokuri-san
noticed was sent an hour ago.
If he'd noticed right away,
we would've entered the room a lot sooner.
There wouldn't have been time for a trick.
Exactly.
So the killer fled from the room when they
noticed us enter and dropped the utensils then.
What's wrong, Detective Takagi?
Something got stuck to my hand
when I hit the table earlier.
Is this salt?
Salt?
That's it.
If they used salt, then that explains
what the inspector said earlier.
And all the coincidences
the old man listed...
Really?
You got salt on the base
of your pinkie finger...
...when you hit the table directly above
where the glasses and plates had fallen.
Really?
Hey.
It kind of sounds like you're explaining
the details of the situation to someone.
I-I'm not doing that.
I'm the type of person who organizes their
thoughts by asking themselves questions.
You didn't know?
Really?
I had no idea.
Episode Preview
Mori-kun, are you sure you saw
someone run from that window?
Yes. I saw it with my own two eyes.
How is it, Conan-kun?
It's a little sticky.
So you found signs something
was stuck above the window.
What is this?!
Wh-What's wrong?
Did you find something?
The Spirit Detective's Murder
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is
"The Spirit Detective's Murder, Part Two!"
Salt
Next Conan's hint!
Salt!
Mister, are you doing exercises?
Don't miss the next episode.
I'm doing somer-salts.
Talk about being salty.