Kogoro-no-occhan and I came to a hotel
to meet spirit detective Hotta Gaito.
However, we found the man
we were supposed to meet
murdered in a hotel room.
Not only that, but in the room next door...
Who is it?
What's with all the noise?
Y-You...
Huh?
You're the guy from the detective agency.
S-Sera... no-neechan?
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
Is Sera the only one living next door?
The case turns a deeper shade of black.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Spirit Detective's Murder
(Part Two)
"The Spirit Detective's Murder, Part Two!"
By the way,
did Hotta-san order this wine
while staying in this room?
Yes.
He said he was meeting someone,
so I brought snacks and wine for two.
I see.
Do you have any idea who he was meeting?
No idea.
It sure is hot in here.
You're right.
It's chilly today, but not cold
enough to turn on the heat.
If the killer were trying to
disguise the time of death,
they would've turned up the heat
in the bedroom where the body is,
but it's cold in here because
the windows were left open.
Mori-kun, are you sure you saw
someone run from that window?
Yes. I saw it with my own two eyes.
Someone just ran from the balcony.
Come to think of it, there was a gust
of wind when we opened the door.
Wind?
That's probably because I
had the front door open.
Kokuri Sanpei (35)
Toto TV Director
If someone came running out of the room,
I thought I'd capture it on camera.
Why didn't you close it?
They would've escaped.
But they'd attack me if they couldn't escape.
I-I suppose.
Maybe the wind blew the glasses to the floor.
But the glasses fell when
the front door was opened,
before the bedroom door was opened.
Hey, Conan-kun.
Right.
Was that bellhop here
when you found the body?
Yeah.
At first it was just me,
Kogoro-no-ojisan, and Kokuri-san,
but nobody answered when
we rang the doorbell.
Huh? That's weird.
He should be in his room.
Then Kokuri-san noticed he received
an e-mail from Hotta-san
an hour earlier, and when he saw it...
What?
"Th-They're going to kill me. Help?"
Then he went to get a bellhop
to unlock the door for us.
Really?
Was the bellhop able to unlock it right away?
No.
When he was about to unlock it...
Hey, wait!
My phone's ringing.
Hello, Hotta-san?
Is that you, Hotta-san?
I'm sorry.
It was a wrong number.
I'm opening the door.
Okay.
Then when we opened the door...
Well?
Was that a clear enough explanation
for your mystery person?
What?
Who are you talking about?
More importantly, I want to see
what's above the balcony window.
S-Sure...
There.
How is it, Conan-kun?
It's a little sticky.
As though something was stuck here.
I see.
So you found signs something
was stuck above the window.
Hey, you!
What are you doing over there?
Get off the balcony.
Maybe something was stuck to the window,
and set to blow away when
the door was opened.
Air flows away from hot and towards cold.
But I don't think the wind would've
been enough to unstick something.
Even if it did, the object that was
blown away should be around somewhere.
You're right.
But either way,
Kokuri-san probably did it.
Inspector Megure, we'll be leaving now.
Good work.
Whoa!
What is this?
Wh-What's wrong?
Did you find something?
Oh, no.
When I went to use the bathroom,
the toilet lid opened on
its own and surprised me.
Why's he using the bathroom at a crime scene?
A lot of modern toilets do that.
Really?
Yeah.
They have a sensor that opens the lid
automatically when a person approaches.
There's a sensor, and it opens automatically?
Sensor... automatically...
Sensor...
Let's head there.
Huh? Hotta-san emailed me an hour ago.
What?
"Th-They're going to kill me. Help?"
Sorry. It took a while
to explain the situation.
Hey, wait!
My phone's ringing.
It was a wrong number.
Hotta-sama?
Someone just ran from the balcony.
There's a car parked
directly below the balcony.
What's it doing there?
I see.
So that's how it is.
Hey, Sera-no-neechan.
What? Deliver what?
Damn it.
I don't have a choice.
Hey, mister.
There's something I want to show you.
What do you want to show me?
Just come with me.
Sheesh.
Now that forensics is finished,
there's nothing left to see.
Okay.
The Sleeping Kogoro's ready to go.
This'll be a little sketchy
since Sera's here.
Now I just have to use my
bow tie-shaped voice changer
to produce the old man's voice and...
Wait, what?
Crap.
My voice changer's missing.
I dropped my bow tie-shaped
voice changer somewhere.
The Sleeping Kogoro can't
solve the case without it.
I already put him to sleep, too.
Mori-kun?
Th-That pose. Does this mean...?
You solved the case.
Uh, Mori-san?
Is he actually asleep?
M-Maybe he's just thinking.
Why does it have to be so confusing?
Sera should be able to solve this case.
Yeah. Yeah, I got it.
But she doesn't know about Kokuri-san's car.
Conan-kun.
Want some help?
You're in trouble, right?
I-I'm not in trouble.
How about you, Kogoro-san?
Do you need help?
Hey, answer me.
You look like you're actually asleep.
H-Hey, wait.
Sleep is a biological function
of the periodically repeated
loss of consciousness.
In other words, it's practically impossible
for a person to speak while sleeping.
The old man's voice...
A smartphone behind his neck?
Naturally, sleep talking is an exception.
Where did that come from?
The words I'm speaking now must sound like
nonsensical sleep talking to you.
But since they are the words of the detective
who has solved this ridiculous
case, I ask that you listen.
You really did solve the case.
That's it.
She must be using my voice changer
from behind the curtains.
But you're speaking differently than usual.
Damn it.
Don't get in the way.
I prefer to be brief,
so I'll start at the end.
The man who murdered spirit detective Hotta,
and made it seem as though
the killer fled the scene
when we arrived, is TV director Kokuri.
B-But you said the wine glasses and plates
fell when you opened the front door,
so you followed their wine-soaked footsteps,
and saw someone running
from the balcony when you
opened the bedroom door.
There was construction taking place
on the floor below when it happened,
so the room was shaking slightly,
but the odds the utensils
would've fallen were 50-50,
so it couldn't have been used as a trick.
No, it was 100%.
It was impossible for them not to fall.
I-Impossible?
Excuse me.
Yes?
I brought a wine glass, a bottle
of wine, a plate, and salt.
Detective Mori said he needed
them for the investigation.
What?
First, set the plate on
the very edge of the table.
Then pour a large amount of salt next to
the plate towards the center of the table.
Okay.
I poured the salt.
Then put the wine glass on top of the salt
so it's leaning towards the plate.
Put the wine glass...leaning...
I put the wine glass on the—
Once the glass is on the
table, blow the salt away.
Just weakly enough that
the glass doesn't fall.
That's amazing.
It's still standing.
That's right.
The glass is being held up
by just a few grains of salt.
Finally, place the bottle against the
base of the glass and shake the table.
The glass becomes unbalanced,
and the bottle blocks its fall,
forcing it to fall towards the plate.
The glass and plate fall
on the floor together.
If you place broken plates and
glasses under the table beforehand,
the falling objects will break and
make a noise when they strike them.
What was that sound?
It sounded like something breaking.
By spilling wine on the floor
and creating wine-stained footprints
leading to the bedroom,
you made it appear as though the
killer ran into the bedroom.
Furthermore, you created a
difference in temperature
between this room and the
bedroom by turning on the heat,
so when the bedroom door was opened,
a breeze would blow through,
scattering the small piles
of salt left on the table.
You feared your trick would be discovered
if the police found piles of salt
with indentations left by
the bottoms of the glasses.
Th-That's it!
He used that breeze to blow
away whatever was stuck
to the window to make it
look like someone ran away.
Wind
Are you an idiot?
Think about it.
Wind alone wouldn't be
enough to blow away
an object stuck to the window.
Even if it did come off,
are you saying the object disappeared
without being seen by anyone?
How did he do it, then?
There was fishing line attached to the door.
It was attached in a way that would
come undone when I opened it.
He attached a piece of fabric
the same color as the curtains
to the bedroom window and ran
the fishing line to the door.
He taped it in place on the
balcony side of the window.
Then he attached a weight to the other end
of the fishing line and hung
it from the balcony railing.
When the door was opened and
the fishing line came undone,
the weight dragged the fabric down.
It's a stupid trick for making
people believe they saw
someone run across the balcony.
But wouldn't someone have
found the fallen fabric?
Masumi.
Masumi?
I doubt you saw it,
but Kokuri parked his car
directly below the balcony.
His convertible car.
The switch for opening and closing
the roof can be attached
to the keys upon request.
If the keys were attached
to the weight hanging
from the balcony with
the button taped down,
then the car's roof would have
closed when the fabric fell,
leaving only a car parked
in a strange location.
Additionally, this trick only works if
I entered the room at exactly 9 AM,
when construction began.
That's why he set his phone to
go off one minute before nine.
Hey, wait!
My phone's ringing.
Hello, Hotta-san?
Is that you, Hotta-san?
I'm sorry.
It was a wrong number.
It allowed him
to control the moment the bellhop
unlocked the door using the master key.
If the victim's request for
help was sent an hour earlier,
then he most likely murdered him then, too.
In a country where earthquakes
are so frequent,
that salt trick can't
be left alone for hours.
Which means they should still be in his car.
Both the weight and fabric
he used in his trick,
as well as the weapon he used to murder Hotta
and clothes covered in his blood.
Yes.
The bloodstained clothes are
still in the trunk of my car.
Along with the knife I used
to inflict retribution
on the man who made a show
out of my sister's body.
Your sister's body?
Several years ago, my sister
committed suicide in the mountains.
In her note she said she
was going to hang herself
because she couldn't bear her broken heart.
No matter how much we searched for
her, we couldn't find the body.
But...
During a TV show, Hotta Gaito
said he sensed the death
of someone other than the missing
person on that mountain.
They discovered my sister's body in the dirt.
Do you understand?
Even though he found the
hanging body of my sister,
he buried it without telling the police!
All so he could make people believe
in his supernatural abilities!
S-So I... I...
Damn it.
She went back to their room.
You can tell us the rest at the station.
Not yet.
I have to tell her.
I need to visit my sister's grave,
and tell her I got the man
who disgraced her death.
H-Hey!
What?
Hey!
Crap. He went next door.
Wh-Who are you?!
Damn it.
Move!
I-Is he dead?
No, they struck his vitals
and knocked him unconscious
during the seconds it
took for me to run here.
They're as quick as a secret service agent.
Whoever did this must have been...
Mom!
What?
Uh, nothing.
A-Are you okay, Conan-kun?
Y-Yeah.
Mom?
Way to go, Mom.
It took you no time at all to learn
how to use Conan-kun's bow tie device.
Yeah, there were marks on the dials.
He must've used that detective's voice often.
Anyway, I'm surprised he can
produce all kinds of voices
with such a simple device.
I could imagine using it
in all sorts of situations.
How exciting.
Y-Yeah.
You don't look that excited.
Well?
Did you figure out what
information Hotta acquired?
Oh, yeah.
Kokuri mentioned something
before he was escorted away.
Someone saw the missing bodyguard
Asaka holding that hand mirror.
Apparently Kokuri learned Asaka was a woman.
He planned to summon the spirit
of Haneda Koji and scream,
"A woman! A woman's going to kill me!"
That's all?
Ridiculous.
Anyway, pack your things.
We're moving.
What? Already?
I was just thinking how lucky we are that
Conan-kun knows where we're staying.
All sorts of monsters lurk in the dark.
Keep your guard up around Edogawa Conan.
He's nothing like the boy
we met ten years ago.
Okay.
Asaka was a bodyguard and a woman.
If she's Rum, the number two
person of the Black Organization,
then does that mean Haibara's
description of a feminine man
actually refers to a woman who's
strong on the inside like a man?
If she was working as a
bodyguard seventeen years ago,
then she should be pretty old by now.
But if they returned to middle school
age by taking the same drug I was given,
then the most suspicious person
is this girl Sera called "Mom."
Who is she?
By the way, bro, apparently Hotta Gaito,
the man investigating the
Haneda Koji murder case, died.
I don't care about Rum's
seventeen year old mistakes.
I'm more interested in the Sleeping Kogoro.
I heard he was involved in
this morning's case, too.
All sorts of monsters lurk in the dark.
And if he's a monster,
then we'd better finish him
off while he's still asleep.
Episode Preview
Call the police!
What? You let them get away?
You idiot! Don't bother coming!
The missus...
What?
What kind of party is this?
Which one of those three murdered Naoko-san?
That's it.
The Foul-Mouthed Myna Bird
The next episode of Conan is
"The Foul-Mouthed Myna Bird!"
Potted Plant
Next Conan's hint!
A potted plant!
By the way, bro...
Don't miss the next episode.
What?
Nothing.
Huh?