Conan-kun, here it comes!
Kokubo Naoko
Nice pass, Mitsuhiko!
Over here!
Genta!
Got it!
Ow.
Call the police!
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
A foul-mouthed myna bird lets
slip something unexpected.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Foul-Mouthed Myna Bird
"The Foul-Mouthed Myna Bird!"
Did the victim have a pet bird?
Yes. Apparently it's a myna bird.
Judging by the state of this bird cage...
And since that window is open...
It escaped.
Hello?
Is this Kokubo-san's house?
I'm calling from the Midoridai
Station police box.
We have your myna bird, Nine.
Nine
I see.
So your name is Nine.
You're a giant idiot.
What?!
I'm Mori Kogoro!
Why are you getting mad at a bird?
What? Kokubo-san was murdered?
Moron, fool, twit, bonehead.
He's gone.
Ah, Mori-kun. You caught the myna bird?
We were just looking for it.
Could you bring the bird here?
What? You let it get away?
You idiot! Don't bother coming!
Even the inspector called me an idiot.
Ouch.
Is something wrong?
He sprained his ankle while drinking.
We were on our way to the hospital today.
I told you, I don't need to
go to the hospital—ouch.
Come on.
Thank you.
Apparently that man is Kokubo-san's nephew.
She was always getting mad
at him for asking for money.
I can't believe the old
woman who smiled no matter
how much noise we made is dead.
Kokubo Mamoru (30)
Victim's Nephew
So that man who visited the
victim discovered the body?
Yes, sir. The victim lived here with
her live-in maid, Yahagi Emi-san.
Where's the maid?
According to a neighbor,
around this time the maid would go
shopping and the victim would take a nap.
Every day, from exactly 1PM to 2PM.
But it's already past two.
How was the victim's relationship
with Yahagi Emi-san?
No one had anything particularly bad to say.
But Yahagi Emi-san's medical
bills were piling up
because her mother has
been sick for a long time,
and she was asking for a raise.
There aren't any signs of a break-in.
The side entrance's semi-automatic
lock was locked.
There are two keys.
The victim and Yahagi Emi-san each had one.
It's apparently difficult to duplicate.
So the culprit could only
have used the main entrance.
Is her nephew Kokubo Mamoru-san a student?
No. He learning how to write children's books.
So he's still unemployed.
When did he find her?
13:55.
What? That's rather accurate.
Is that was he said?
No, the children saw him.
Children? Are they reliable, then?
We are!
What?
You shouldn't underestimate kids!
As you can see, Inspector...
Good grief.
Nine escaped.
You know about the myna bird, too?
Yes.
The mischievous Nine was famous.
Uh, oh. It's probably my
fault that the window is open.
Uh, oh.
Sorry!
I see. The myna bird escaped through there.
We were playing in the park
across in front of the house.
Apparently no one entered or
left after Yahagi Emi-san.
Yeah.
Yahagi Emi (18)
Kokubo Family Maid
Oh, no!
The missus...?
You found an abandoned child and
were looking for its mother?
Yes, asleep in their stroller.
Did you find the mother?
Two girls passing by helped me look for her.
Apparently she went to get her hat
that was blown away by the wind.
So you're late because you
were watching the stroller?
I was worried the missus would scold me.
I certainly wasn't expecting this.
The question is whether or not
your story can be verified.
What?
You're the only person besides the victim
who has a key to the side entrance.
You could've secretly returned to the house and
killed her and gone back to shopping afterwards.
It wasn't me!
What's the name of the
woman with the stroller?
I-I didn't ask.
What about the girls?
I-I don't know.
You didn't get their names?
I would tell you if I knew!
Inspector Megure!
It's Kogoro-no-ojisan.
Conan-kun.
What are you kids doing here?
Sayama-san?!
Well, hello. This is
quite the mess, isn't it?
The missus was furious that
you sold her a forgery.
Who are you?
A used book seller named Sayama-san.
Sayama Yotaro (60)
Used Book Seller
We met at the hospital.
Don't push yourself too hard.
I'll write you a prescription
for the medicine right away.
Doctor.
What is it, Sayama-san?
Isn't there anything you
can do so I can drive?
I can't work like this.
That's impossible.
It'll take three more days.
I see...
Midoridai Hospital
Hey, was that him?
That was a crow, not a myna bird.
Myna bird?
That bird that flies around with a
red piece of yarn trailing behind it?
Oh, I just thought you meant
Kokubo-san's myna bird.
What is it?
I see.
Of course you haven't heard.
What?
I brought him because he
seemed to know the victim.
Despite what he says, he just wants
to stick his nose in the case.
But it looks like he was
right to bring the old man.
What?
The missus collected rare old books.
But the book she bought
from Sayama-san was...
I-It fooled me, too.
I meant to tell her the truth right away.
But you still haven't
returned her money, right?
I overheard her before I went out.
Ma'am, shall I move the flowerpot
in the backyard to the kitchen?
Kokubo Naoko (70)
Picture Book Author
You can do it later.
I'm sick of your excuses, Sayama-san.
It's already ten past.
Find the money and pay me back immediately!
Poor man.
I can't raise money with this kind of injury.
I don't need your excuses.
Does this mean you can't return the money?
You're just as angry as
your mistress, Emi-chan.
Don't call me that!
Inspector! I have a report from forensics.
Got it.
They found strangulation
marks on the victim's neck.
The weapon was the white stole the
victim had wrapped around her neck.
The time of death was between 12:55 to 13:55.
No, the actual murder occurred
between 13:35 and 13:55.
I'm going to the bathroom.
Come back right away.
Okay.
Excuse me.
What room is this?
My aunt's office.
She wrote children's books.
A long time ago, anyway.
Kokubo Naoko's books are here.
I see.
I knew I recognized that name.
I believe she stopped
writing after a scandal.
I see. Thank you.
Sayama-san was seen speaking
over his cell phone
at Midoridai Station at 12:55.
That matches Yahagi-san's story.
How far is it to the station from here?
Since he doesn't seem to have taken a taxi,
it's about a forty-five minute walk.
Excuse me.
Yes?
What?
What kind of party is this?
You're those girls.
Oh, you work here?
That's right.
Oh? You have Nine with you.
Since he's famous, we
recognized him right away.
Thank you.
The children can back up
Kokubo Mamoru-san's story,
but what about Sayama Yotaro-san?
We have the victim's call history.
Their call lasted from 12:55 to 13:35.
That's a long conversation.
And he went to the hospital after that.
Is it possible for him to have done it?
The hospital is about halfway
between here and the station.
Midoridai
Station
Sayama Witnessed
Kogoro's Testimony
Estimated
Time of Death
Hospital
Kokubo House
If Sayama-san headed to the hospital
after making a call at the station,
minutes
and going to Kokubo Naoko-san's
house to murder her,
that wouldn't match the time of death
or Mori-san's testimony.
The answer is clear.
Yahagi Emi-san is the only person
who has no one to verify her alibi.
Looks like we won't need the
Sleeping Kogoro this time.
They all have alibis?
I'll testify anytime!
Is that inconvenient for you?
Why don't you hang yourself with noodles?
Go hit your head on some tofu.
What? How rude.
Why does Nine insult everyone?
He was quiet earlier.
He's smart and likes people,
but I can't believe he
was only taught insults.
Maybe it's the missus' influence.
After being betrayed by someone she trusted,
she couldn't trust anyone anymore.
She said all compliments were lies,
and only insults were accurate.
Ah, you mean when Kokubo-san
plagiarized her mentor.
But according to insiders,
it was the other way around.
It wasn't the missus who
committed plagiarism.
Her mentor had writer's block.
But the media sided with the major writer,
and wouldn't listen to the missus.
People are blind.
It happens all the time.
Which one of them killed Naoko-san?
That's why my aunt told me to stop writing.
But, Mamoru-san,
the missus always said you'd be successful.
What?
I see.
Huh? That flowerpot...
Mamoru-san, did you bring this inside?
No, it wasn't me.
I see.
How much trouble did the
old woman have walking?
I think she said she could
barely use a wheelchair.
I can't stand the stench. It stinks.
Who stinks? You mean the culprit?
How could he possibly know?
He's just a bird.
I want eel.
What?
I'm hungry.
He copied me.
By the way, what's the band for?
The missus put it on him this morning so he'd
be easily identifiable if he escaped again.
It certainly is eye-catching.
Sayama-san called him the
myna bird with the red yarn.
Hey, is there anything smelly in the house?
There's all kinds of pickles.
My aunt liked them.
But I don't smell anything.
They're kept in the basement.
Where's that?
They're down here.
Is there something down there?
I can't stand the stench.
It stinks.
I knew it. So that's how it is.
How rude!
It doesn't look like he'll be falling asleep.
Excuse me.
Inspector! It's Mori-san!
Ah, I've been waiting for this.
Sorry to keep you all waiting.
This was a truly difficult case.
After all, all three of
the suspects have alibis.
However, there's one person
whose alibi doesn't hold up.
Their alibi doesn't hold up?
Wh-Who is it?
The owner of Sayama's Books.
Sayama Yotaro-san.
Wh-What are you talking about?
You verified my alibi.
Let me ask you something.
Apparently you saw a myna bird
with red yarn trailing behind him.
So, what?
Nine left the yarn and his
leg band at the police box.
When did you see a myna bird with red yarn?
Oh, right. That's amazing, Dad.
I-I saw a myna bird with red yarn
on the way to the hospital!
I see.
I'm impressed you were able to recognize that
it was yarn and not red string.
By the way, apparently the victim
attached the yarn to Nine this morning.
I-I just misspoke.
But, Mori-san,
Sayama-san was seen at
Midoridai Station at 12:55.
It would have been impossible for
him to meet you at the hospital
after speaking on the phone until 13:35
and killing Naoko-san here.
What if Sayama-san kept walking
after answering the victim's
call at the station?
The victim told him to come
to her home immediately.
He simply followed her instructions.
I see.
He could've arrived at the house
by the time the call ended.
But he couldn't have
used the main entrance based
on the children's testimony.
How on earth did he get in?
The side entrance.
What?
I thought it was locked.
The victim Kokubo Naoko-san
opened it herself.
What?!
The flowerpot proves it.
That's why that flowerpot was there.
After being summoned to the side entrance,
the victim instructed him to bring in
the flowerpot by the rear entrance.
I see.
Committing the crime and
leaving afterwards was simple.
Since the lock is semi-automatic, it locks
after pushing a button and exiting.
Sayama-san.
B-But look at me!
I can't use my dominant hand!
Right?! I couldn't have done it!
Mori-san, you heard what the doctor said!
Yes,
that was your last excuse.
Let me ask you something.
Sayama-san, you're the one that
said this room stinks, aren't you?
The clever Nine even
remembered how you said it.
What could possibly have smelled so bad?
Conan, are you there?
I'm here.
Okay. I'll try it.
There.
It's done.
This allowed you to strangle
her with only one hand.
She was crazy.
Returning the money wasn't
enough to forgive me.
Post an apology at my store.
Send an apology to the newspaper.
Go into the basement and stir the pickles.
I couldn't take it anymore.
You can tell us all about it at the station.
She wrote such beautiful stories, too.
I can't believe she had such
a terrifying side to her.
It just goes to show women
are different on the inside.
Conan-kun...
Whoops.
Ouch.
Episode Preview
Traitors...
...will be punished.
What a surprise to see you
here, Okiya Subaru-san.
The Traitor's Stage
(Part 1)
The next episode of Conan is
"The Traitor's Stage, Part One!"
Rope
Next Conan's hint!
Rope!
Don't miss the next episode.
Myna bird!
Traitor!
That's called parroting.