Sorry, Furuya.
They figured out I'm a cop.
My only escape...
...is to the underworld.
See you later,
Zero.
Traitors...
will be punished.
Right?
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
The truth behind Akai and
Scotch's relationship.
The drama surrounding the
Organization continues.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Traitor's Stage
(Part One)
"The Traitor's Stage, Part One!"
Bourbon? Bourbon?
Hey, Bourbon.
What?
Don't give me that.
You were supposed to turn right
at the last intersection.
Sorry. I was thinking.
Oh? That isn't like you.
Does that mean you weren't
listening to what I was saying?
I was listening.
I have to investigate it before it becomes
public and destroy it if necessary, right?
Your target is a big one.
If you have trouble getting to him, I
could have an acquaintance disguise you.
Don't worry about it.
I know how to get to close to him.
Jeez!
Why do a couple of high school
girls have to clean the house
of a mystery nut while he's gone?
It's not so bad once in a while, Sonoko.
Sorry.
Thanks for your help.
This place is too large
for me to clean by myself.
It's fine. I love cleaning.
Sonoko.
By the way, her name's
Sera Masumi-san, right?
She didn't come with you.
We invited Sera-chan.
But she said she was too busy
since she's moving hotels again.
I see.
I wish I could live in a hotel.
Really?
For an heiress living in a luxurious mansion,
every day is like living in a hotel.
Have you seen anyone strange around Sera-san?
For example, a person constantly
observing their surroundings
and skilled in quickly neutralizing
any threats named Asaka.
Though I doubt they're using that name.
They're not Asaka, but there is someone.
What? Really?
It's you, Ran.
What?
You're my personal bodyguard,
who neutralizes all threats to me.
Listen...
Jeez.
Oh, right. Speaking of Asaka,
the title of the new song
rock musician Hado Rokumichi
Hado Rokumichi (39)
Musician
is going to release is "ASACA."
Apparently he finally wrote lyrics to a
song he composed seventeen years ago,
and is going to perform
it at his next concert.
Seventeen years ago?
It's an unusual title, though.
Unusual how?
It was written in the English alphabet
when it was announced online,
"ASACA"
Performed for the first time in April's concert!
Hado Rokumichi's first song in five years
but the "CA" in ASACA was
spelled "CA" instead of "KA."
Not "KA"...
...but "CA?"
Why? Why is it "CA" instead of "KA?"
Wh-Who knows?
There must be some reason for it.
Do you have any idea?
If you're so curious, why
don't you ask him yourself?
What?
We're going to watch Hado
Rokumichi rehearse soon.
I'll take you with me.
Really?
Would it be all right if I
joined you at this rehearsal?
What? You, too?
I'm a huge Hado Rokumichi fan.
Sure, glad to have you!
By the way, when was the
title announced online?
Just last week.
Since it's his first song in five
years, it was a popular news story.
Yeah, that's right.
Which means...
...it's too late.
The organization...
...has already seen it.
What?
We can't watch the rehearsal?!
Seriously?!
I'm sorry.
He actually hasn't finished the
lyrics to his new song yet.
He asked to be left alone for
two hours so he could write,
Enjo Kanae (40)
Hado's Manager
while looking out at the empty seats.
Does this kind of thing happen often?
Sometimes.
Let him be.
Fuse Okuyasu (58)
Record Company President
Apparently this is going
to be his last concert.
H-He's huge!
His last concert?
The rumors about Hado-san retiring are true?
Yes. I tried to stop him,
but he's going to tell his fans at
the end of tomorrow's concert.
Does that mean you've reached an agreement?
Retiring before his contract
expires is unthinkable.
Especially when you were yelling
about taking him to court
Kajiya Hirokazu (51)
Magazine Reporter
and charging him an exorbitant
penalty for breaking the contract.
Who are you? How did you get in?
Through the front entrance, of course.
I bought one of the staff's
jackets and used it to get in.
Anyway, pretty manager,
have you settled things with him, too?
What do you mean?
Rumor is the ASACA of the
title of Hado's new song
is also the name of his new girlfriend.
I heard that you, his longtime mistress,
were furious and fought with
Hado over releasing the song.
Who told you that?!
Well, I heard that your chief
editor was furious with you
because someone beat you to reporting that
Hado was putting his music career on hold.
You'd been following Hado for fifteen
years, so what were you doing?
That's why I pretended to be
a staff member to get in here.
I wanted to make an explosive
comeback before Hado quits.
You there!
Y-Yes, ma'am!
This man isn't allowed
in here. Throw him out.
What?
H-Hey, I paid money to get in here!
At least let me interview him!
Be quiet.
Hey! Hey! What are you doing? Hey!
Let go of me!
Hey! Hey!
Should we leave, too?
Yeah. We have school tomorrow.
What? We're leaving?
Sorry, but that might be for the best.
There's no telling when
the rehearsal will start.
Right.
But shouldn't we watch the rehearsal if
this is going to be his last concert?
Subaru-san, sorry.
But we're just not that big of fans.
What? Then who suggested we come?
Me.
When I told them at Poirot that
I was a huge fan of Hado-san,
she arranged to have me come see a rehearsal.
Sonoko-san's Suzuki
Conglomerate happens to be
financing his record company.
Azusa-san, you came, too?
You didn't seem that interested at Poirot.
I kept it hidden at the store,
but I'm a huge fan, too.
I followed Amuro-san here
after my shift ended.
I was surprised.
She stopped me as I was
entering the building.
The staff let us in after
we explained the situation.
Speaking of surprises, what
a surprise to see you here,
Okiya Subaru-san.
It was good to see you the other day.
Do you remember me?
Yes. You're...
the deliveryman, aren't you?
What?
Uh, yeah.
Well, you three fans enjoy the show!
Come on. Conan-kun, we're leaving.
What? H-Hey, wait.
Hey, Azusa-neechan!
You like Hado-san because
he's a good guitarist, right?
You were really good at playing the guitar.
Yeah, of course.
What? Azusa-san, didn't you say
you've never touched a guitar?
Yeah, when we invited you to
join our band the other day.
Oh, right.
I was just too embarrassed to
join a high school girl band.
I knew it.
She's Vermouth.
Which means I need to get Subaru-san
out of here as soon as possible.
Hado's best song is "Bloody
Comet," don't you think?
I prefer "Snowy Fallen Angel."
They're having a friendly chat.
Hey, Subaru-san.
This isn't good.
We have to get away from here.
They say nothing ventured, nothing gained.
But it takes courage to retreat, too.
We're here for the fire inspection.
We'll be checking the facilities.
Hey, you.
Wait. You can't go inside yet.
H-Hado-san...
Wait, Conan-kun.
Don't, angel.
Don't go inside.
You don't belong on this bloody stage.
A-Angel?
Oh, yeah, because you're innocent.
So she's an angel?
In any case, let's let them handle the case.
The most perceptive man of
the Organization, Bourbon.
The high school detective transformed
into a child by a drug, Kudo Shinichi.
And one other...
Who is he?
Were there multiple killers?
If this was done by one person, they
must have been incredibly strong.
Don't you agree, Okiya-san?
When we met the other day,
I noticed you had exceptional
deductive skills.
I'm just a grad student who enjoys mysteries.
There's a hole as though something
was pressed into the rope.
There's a folding chair, rope, and
toolbox on the edge of the stage.
Judging by the cut on the end of the rope,
it's what was leftover after hanging him.
But what's it doing here?
Huh? What's this string?
Is it kite string?
It leads to the seats.
What's going on?
On the other end there's...
...a baseball?
What's the overview of the case?
O-Oh, right.
The deceased is musician Hado
Rokumichi-san, thirty-nine years old.
He was going to perform
a concert here tomorrow.
I see. What's the time of death?
Based on the dilation of his pupils,
he's probably been dead for
about an hour or two.
According to his manager,
Hado had been in here for
around two hours writing lyrics.
And during that time someone
entered the auditorium,
hanged the victim by his
neck, and killed him.
They probably passed a
rope over the metal bars
used to hang spotlights,
and lifted him using the machine
for moving the heavy curtains.
I don't think that's possible.
The room with the curtain
controls was locked.
When the murder took place, the staff
who had the key were out to lunch.
Then did they lift him
without using the machine?
Yes. Probably with several people.
Without pulleys attached
to the bar above the stage,
it would've been impossible alone.
Another point of interest is the
folding chair, leftover rope,
and toolbox left at the edge of the stage.
There's also a strange hole in the rope
near the knot in the rope
attached to the seats.
And there was a baseball with kite string
attached to it in the middle of them.
C-Conan-kun, you're here, too?
In any case, we should question the staff.
Anyway, I can't believe how often
we run into various detectives.
Yeah, although Conan-kun deserves
an award for his perfect attendance.
According to the staff,
during Hado-san's estimated time
of death between 4:30 to 5:30,
the only persons who weren't seen for
a while were Fuse-san and Enjo-san.
What?
Wait a minute.
I told you, I've had an upset
stomach since this morning.
I was just in the bathroom.
I was running around the concert hall
issuing instructions to the staff.
Additionally, the body was discovered
by the firefighters who came
to perform an inspection.
Detective, shouldn't he be
considered suspicious as well?
Let me go!
Hado was killed, right?!
Yeah, I'm sure.
I bought a jacket from the staff
and entered the auditorium
before 5:30. It was around 5:20.
If you think I'm lying, ask the
guy who sold me his jacket.
That's odd, then.
Enjo-san was missing between 4:30 to 4:50,
and Fuse-san was missing
between 5:00 to 5:15.
So it wasn't possible for any
of them to have worked together.
Hey.
Did any of you play baseball?
Hey, Conan-kun.
Why are you asking them that now?
I played rugby through college.
I played a little tennis in middle school.
I was a phantom member of the hiking club.
Hado played baseball through high school.
Apparently, he was an outfielder
with a strong throwing arm.
Why do you ask?
We found a baseball at the crime scene.
It's probably the ball Hado received
Good luck
becoming a musician
from his team when he
graduated high school.
He always had it on him.
Of course his ex knows all about him.
You dated Hado from around that time
until he started getting popular, right?
And then, that company president fell
in love with this beautiful manager
but ended up being rejected.
That was years ago.
Who cares?
Who knows what kind of warped emotions
are behind your twisted
relationships and Hado's death?
By the way, do you know where
Hado-san's cell phone is?
We couldn't find it in the
green room or with his things.
Hado always kept his cell
phone in his breast pocket.
His cell phone in his breast pocket...
His cell phone...
Cell phone...
Cell... phone...
Hey, Scotch!
Damn it!
Don't bother listening for a pulse.
He's dead.
I shot him through the heart.
Rye, you bastard!
Didn't you hear?
He was working for the Japanese police.
The real shame is
I shot the cell phone he
had in his breast pocket.
Now we'll never know who he was.
It's like I killed a ghost.
It's creepy.
Amuro-san. Amuro-san?
Amuro Toru-san?
Yes?
Could you write your name and
"I'm sorry" in this notebook?
Why?
You weren't listening?
We found this paper in
Hado-san's breast pocket.
I'm sorry
We're having everyone in the auditorium
write it so we can perform a handwriting analysis.
Oh, in that case...
Conan-kun, what's Azusa-san's family name?
Enomoto. Why?
Thanks.
Azusa-san, could you write yours as well?
Okay!
Vermouth...
She knows I've seen through her
disguise, but she's still so brazen.
She knows I won't say anything
to keep Ran and Sonoko
from getting involved.
Angel...
Where have I heard that nickname before?
Thank you.
Enjo-san, could we get yours next?
I'm surprised you knew
Azusa-san's family name.
If you'd told me beforehand, I could've
provided more detailed information.
Why did you suddenly disguise
yourself as Azusa-san?
I can handle investigating the lyrics
of a not-yet-performed song myself.
I felt uneasy when I heard
you were coming with them.
I wasn't sure you'd keep your promise to me.
You mean making sure no harm comes to them?
Anyway, who is he?
He's a Toto University grad
student named Okiya Subaru.
He lives next door to
an inventor named Agasa.
Thank you.
You're left-handed?
Yes.
Is there a problem?
No.
When we met the other day, you removed
your mask with your right hand.
I thought you were right-handed.
Is that right?
Don't worry about it.
The man I hate
enough to kill
just happens to be a lefty.
Episode Preview
Give up, Scotch.
That's right.
It was then...
You're the one who made him do it.
Akai...
Shuichi.
The Traitor's Stage
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is
"The Traitor's Stage, Part 2!"
Folding Chair
Next Conan's hint!
A folding chair!
Don't miss the next episode.
I haven't seen you since the Ferris wheel.
That was a thrilling experience.
For me, too.