We came to watch Hado Rokumichi's
concert rehearsal...
at which he was set to perform "ASACA,"
a song written seventeen years ago,
but...
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
In the shadow of the case happening on the
stage lurk Amuro, Okiya, and Vermouth!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Traitor's Stage
(Part Two)
"The Traitor's Stage, Part Two!"
What? The victim wrote the
note on the paper himself?
Y-Yes, sir.
According to forensics,
the paper came from the notebook
the victim used to write lyrics.
The handwriting matched the lyrics written
on the other pages of the notebook.
Which means it's likely the
victim felt indebted to someone,
and that became their reason to kill him.
Any ideas?
I don't know about indebted, but he
may have had an inferiority complex.
Enjo Kanae (40)
Hado's Manager
Hado often said he had
to work hard to keep up
with other handsome musicians
since he had an off-putting face.
I see.
I told him not to worry about it.
Fuse Okuyasu (58)
Record Company President
I said the way he seemed difficult
to approach was part of his charm.
Come to think of it, Hado-san
changed his image recently.
Yeah, he seemed softer than before.
Changed how?
Just his overall impression.
Maybe his face?
That reminds me, there were
rumors Hado got plastic surgery.
Although I think that was around the
time he graduated from high school.
Kajiya Hirokazu (51)
Magazine Reporter
I told you before, that's all nonsense!
We didn't have any money back then.
We worked every day for
a shipping company
to make enough money
for him to be a musician.
But Hado dumped you after
you worked so hard together,
and married another woman.
I think that was sixteen years ago.
And the song "ASACA" he was
set to announce at this concert
was composed seventeen years ago.
There must be some reason he left it
without lyrics for seventeen years.
Right, pretty little manager?
Hey, that's enough.
President, you must know something, too.
I heard Hado asked you
after his previous concert,
"Why didn't you say anything
for seventeen years?"
And after your argument,
Hado suddenly announced he'd be
releasing his new song "ASACA."
There must be something going on.
Is this true?
Hado started working with my record
company seventeen years ago.
I jokingly told him the real
reason I had him debut with us
was because I'd fallen in love with Enjo-san,
and wanted to court her.
He said he'd quit if that were true.
I see.
But that doesn't sound like a
motive to murder Hado-san.
Then I'm leaving.
Hey, wait!
Isn't it impossible for anyone
to have committed this crime?
You can't. It's impossible.
Give up, Scotch.
His right hand was covered in blood,
except for the tip of his thumb
and the back of his hand.
That means he put his thumb on the trigger
and shot himself.
You're the one who gave him
your gun and made him do it,
Akai Shuichi.
He would've had plenty of options
besides killing himself.
Hey.
Huh?
You've been glaring at him. What's going on?
Nothing.
I don't particularly care, but
could you solve this soon?
It's dangerous for me to stay
here very long while in disguise.
Of course.
Hey, let go.
I need to get back to the office and
write an article about this case!
We need to check the
contents of your bag first!
You guys never give up.
I told you to let me go!
Whoa!
Ouch...
Oh, the evidence...
We'll help.
Thank you.
Hado-san's driver license.
He certainly seems unapproachable.
After viewing the images on the
camera that was in your bag,
it looks like you were secretly taking photos
of Hado-san as he entered the concert hall,
but he discovered you and tried
to take away your camera.
Is that right?
Yeah.
What did he say then?
He just said to stop taking pictures.
Also, Inspector...
One of the band members scheduled
to perform with Hado-san
at tomorrow's concert was just
arrested by narcotics agents.
What?
For possession of stimulants.
Hey, mister.
What is it, kid?
Did you find a... on the ground?
Azusa-neechan said she lost one.
Lost...
...one?
No, we didn't find anything
like that on the stage.
Then was anything missing?
Like wire or gloves.
The staff said both of those
were missing from the tool box
at the edge of the stage.
Did the staff leave that folding
chair next to the tool box?
No, they kept it farther offstage.
Hey, leave that stuff where it is.
Apparently the concert is canceled.
Seriously?
I just untied this, and
now I have to retie it?
Did you inspect the folding chair, too?
Not for prints yet.
But he's taking it back along with
the mic stand for further inspection.
Excuse me.
Could you show me the bottom of the seat?
What?
Sure, just for a second.
Thank you.
I knew it.
So that's how it is.
This got kind of crazy.
Uh, are you done?
Yeah.
Excuse me. Coming through.
Excuse me. Out of the way, please.
Move.
Move, please.
That's right.
The suspicious woman who tried to
kidnap Conan-kun and Ai-chan said...
Move away from the brunette,
if you don't want to die!
Hurry up!
Move it, Angel!
That's what she called me.
By why would Azusa-san
call me by the same name?
Y-You know how the killer
lifted the victim's body?
Is it true?
Yes, probably.
We passed the rope over the spotlight bar
and tied the other end to Takagi-kun,
but is one person really strong
enough to lift him out of the chair?
Of course.
First you create a loop with the rope hanging
from the bar while standing
next to the stage.
Wrap the bottom loop around
the top loop two times.
While twisting the lower loop,
pass the section hanging
down through the loop.
Hook the resulting large loop
onto the armrest of the seat
about two meters below, like this.
Next, pass the end of the rope
without the loops under the armrest.
Create the same loops as before
and pass the rope through.
Now hook the large loop and rope
on the armrest of a chair
about four meters away.
Create a third loop and
pass the rope through,
and this time, hook the
large loop onto a chair
about eight meters away.
Now all you have to do is return
to the third set of small loops
you created and pull on the leftover rope.
Sonoko-san, you seem like
the weakest person here.
Could you pull on this?
What? Me?
Sure.
I doubt I'll be able to lift him, though.
What? How?
What's going on?
It's the principle of pulleys, right?
Yes.
The small loops created along
the rope function as pulleys.
Force
Each set of loops doubles,
quadruples, and octuples
the strength at which the rope pulls.
Since we're using rope rather than pulleys,
the strength isn't actually
octupled due to friction,
but if you use a light
and slippery enough rope,
even Sonoko-san can lift Detective Takagi.
In other words, the culprit used
not the strength of several people,
but lifted Hado-san alone.
Furthermore, this is
known as a shipping knot.
Shipping workers use this
knot to secure cargo.
Which means the most likely suspect
who lifted Hado-san's body
is his manager who worked
for a shipping company
when she was younger.
What?
Enjo Kanae-san, it's you.
I can see how she lifted him, but how
did she tie the rope to the seats?
That's simple.
First, after lifting the victim,
she temporarily secured the
rope by tying it to a nearby seat.
Then she wrapped a wire around the
rope leading upwards around here.
Once the rope coming from the
ceiling is secured using the wire,
the remaining rope can be untied
and reattached to the seat,
and the wire can be removed.
The best part of the shipping knot
is that it can be untied easily
since it doesn't actually create any knots,
but if it's done using a brand new rope,
then it leaves behind telltale marks.
That's why after retying
the rope to the seat,
you cut the end using the
box cutter in the tool box,
and left it coiled next to the tool
box at the edge of the stage, right,
Enjo-san?
You can't assume she did it just because
she used to work for a shipping company.
It's the size of her feet.
H-Her feet?
Shipping workers coil rope
by wrapping it like this.
The inner loop is approximately
the size of the person's foot,
since the space between the elbow and the
wrist is about the size of their foot.
Since the rope found at the crime scene was
in loops about the size of Ran-neechan's feet,
we thought the rope might have been
coiled by the smaller manager.
I see.
So after seventeen years,
the manager's feelings for
Hado turned into hate.
Hey, you shouldn't say that.
We're still not sure that she did it.
Contact lenses.
As his manager, you must've noticed
Hado-san was wearing contact lenses
to make his irises look larger.
Y-Yes.
I noticed after looking at
Hado-san's driver license
and comparing it to the images
the magazine reporter took today.
One of the lenses is stuck to your back.
What?
Th-This is...
Do you mind?
Go ahead.
I see.
While you were lifting his body,
one of them fell onto your clothes.
That's enough evidence for me.
You can tell us the rest at the station.
W-Wait a minute. Did you really do it?
After supporting him for seventeen
years, why did you have to kill him?
Answer me.
She can't answer that question.
After all, she didn't kill him.
What?
What do you mean?
Where do you think we found
the other circle lens?
It was under the folding chair
left at the edge of the stage.
In other words, that chair had fallen
under his feet after he was hanging.
There's also the baseball
tied to the kite string.
It was used to pass the rope over the
bar by tying the other end to the rope,
throwing the ball so that
the kite string would pass
over the bar on the ceiling,
and pulling on the string.
I don't mean to be rude,
but I doubt Enjo-san would have been able to
throw the ball high enough to clear the bar.
Although Hado-san, known for his strong arm on
his high school baseball team, is another story.
I'm sorry
Then there's the note found
in Hado-san's breast pocket.
You know where this is going, don't you?
He killed himself?
That's right.
He hung himself,
and she disguised it to look
like a murder after finding him.
Why did you try to hide his suicide?
Something must've happened seventeen years ago.
Were you worried about what
we discussed the other day?
What do you mean?
Seventeen years ago,
she was pregnant with Hado's child.
Fuse-san!
Saying it was for their unborn child,
the freshly debuted Hado locked himself
in his studio and wrote music.
He stayed up so many nights
in a row, I thought he'd die.
When she came to stop him, she
collapsed in front of the studio
and miscarried.
At the hospital, she asked
me not to tell Hado about it.
I see.
Since "ASACA" was the song he
wrote for that unborn child,
he held onto it for seventeen years,
unable to write the lyrics.
When he learned what happened,
he felt responsible and attempted to write
lyrics for the child and release the song.
But unable to write,
he left the message "sorry"
and chose to die instead.
But why was it necessary to
make it look like murder?
I didn't want his family
to know he killed himself
over his ex's baby.
So I took his phone with the
message "goodbye" in his outbox
out of his pocket
and raised him up...
What an idiot to make a woman
cry even after his death.
Please don't put this in your article!
I followed Hado for years.
I crawled along the ground day
after day looking for a story.
And now the story I've found is also
the biggest scandal in Hado's career.
Please. Please don't.
I like to think I understood
Hado better than anyone.
Even if you didn't ask me not
to, I wouldn't write about this.
Such an overly sentimental story
doesn't suit a rock and roller.
We still don't know why the "CA" in "ASACA"...
was spelled the way it is.
Oh, I asked Hado about it before.
Since he heard about the pregnancy at
a morning café after an all-nighter,
if it was a girl, he wanted
to call her "Asaca,"
taking the "ca" from "café."
Really? Sounds good to me.
But if you were good enough friends
for him to tell you that story,
why did you turn on him and
push him towards retirement?
Did you know about his
band member who was just
arrested for possession?
I-I don't know anything about that.
You already heard about that?
The story's already online.
I'm impressed.
I'm impressed, Scotch.
You took my gun while pretending
to be thrown by me.
I won't beg for my life,
but before you shoot me, don't you
want to hear what I have to say?
I didn't draw your gun to shoot you.
I see.
I drew it to do this!
You can't.
It's not possible to pull
the trigger of a revolver
when someone's holding the cylinder.
Don't kill yourself, Scotch.
You're not meant to die here.
What?
I'm Akai Shuichi, an agent of the FBI.
Like you, I'm a dog trying
to sink my teeth into them.
Now let go of the gun and listen to me.
Helping you escape will be easy.
O-Okay.
I see.
He took my gun so he could destroy this.
This cellphone that likely contained
data on his family and friends.
Traitors will be punished.
Right?
I have a strong urge to
fold down your turtleneck,
but I'll restrain myself for now.
See you...
another time.
Excuse me, Azusa-san.
What?
You're not Azusa-san, are you?
You're that woman...
who called me Angel before, aren't you?
I told you, Ran-chan.
Don't come any closer to our side.
After all, you're my treasure.
Yes,
one of only two in this world.
Episode Preview
Wow!
It's so awesome!
Where am I supposed to put these books?
The store's already packed
with books we can't sell.
Finding a used book is a once
in a lifetime experience.
Someday these will pass into the
hands of the people looking for them.
Wh-What is this?
The Whistling Bookstore
The next episode of Conan is
"The Whistling Bookstore!"
Group Photo
Next Conan's hint!
A group photo!
Don't miss the next episode.
The Angel and the Silver Bullet.
They're a curious pair.