Beika City Used Book Sale
There.
Yujiro-ojisan, you bought so many books.
Yeah. I found some real treasures today.
Tamaki Yujiro (65)
Owner of Tamaki's
Used Bookstore
There.
Well, I'm off.
Thanks for the help.
No problem. It's only natural.
Let us handle it.
You're so dependable.
Tamaki's Used Bookstore
Are you all right?
They're heavy, so don't overdo it.
Despite how I look, I'm pretty strong.
And it'll go faster if we all help.
There.
Don't push yourself too hard.
O-Okay. Thanks, Conan-kun.
We're finally finished.
Thank you, everyone.
As a reward, you can each have one
book of your choice from the store.
Really?
Yes.
All right!
You're not going to get one?
Are you sure it's okay?
You know, for the store to give out books.
Children shouldn't worry about that.
Just choose whatever you'd like.
Okay.
Even heaven is watching the
labyrinths of the world!
Full throttle reasoning skills
penetrate all mysteries!
The train whistle in the park brings a case to
a used bookstore that smells nostalgic.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Whistling Bookstore
"The Whistling Bookstore!"
No way.
Sherlock Holmes...
A first edition?!
I didn't notice this before.
It's so expensive.
I couldn't possibly ask him for this.
Dad, that's enough.
Where are we supposed to put these books?
The store's already packed
with books we can't sell.
Finding a used book is a once
in a lifetime experience.
Someday these will pass into the
hands of the people looking for them.
You know this isn't a warehouse, right?
Besides, we need money to run a business.
You understand that, don't you?
Yes, I know.
Unbelievable.
When did you guys...?
Conan-kun?
The rest of you are here, too.
Tamaki Ichiro (35)
Yujiro's Son
Did you come to buy something?
What?
Uh, yeah.
No!
Since we helped move the books,
we each get a book for free.
Genta-kun!
What? Wasn't that the agreement?
Dad, is this true?!
Yes.
How generous of you when
the business is struggling.
Hey, Ichiro-san.
What is it?
Did you just come back from work?
You're wearing an apron.
No, I just came back for my wallet.
Uh, oh.
I'd better hurry.
Ichiro, sorry for the trouble.
If you're sorry, shut down the shop.
I...
That vague attitude of yours is so annoying!
Watch out!
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Looks like this bookshelf rotted.
You and this store are
at the end of their rope.
You should've realized that by now.
We finished picking them up.
Thank you.
Looks like they're closed today.
Yeah.
Hey, let's go to the park.
O-Okay.
Wow!
It's so awesome!
We come to Tamaki's Used
Bookstore pretty frequently,
but I never knew this park was here.
I just learned about it recently, too.
And this park has a secret.
What is it?
This steam engine moves!
What?
But there's no track.
Not like that.
The wheels move in place.
Huh. So, when does it run?
Twice a day at 11 and 3.
There's still some time.
Then let's play soccer until then.
Conan-kun, here we go.
Nice pass.
There.
Nice catch.
Ayumi-chan, here we go.
Sorry, Ayumi-chan.
It's nearly time.
I'm excited.
Mitsuhiko, where'd you get that?
I borrowed it from my father.
I thought I'd take a picture
of the steam engine running.
Can you use that crazy thing?
Leave it to me.
Hey.
What are you kids doing?
We're waiting for the steam engine to run.
Really?
What are you doing?
I'm working the evening shift
today, so I was out for a walk.
A leaf?
That was intense.
Yeah.
The store!
What?
Wh-What is this?
Dad?!
Thank you.
Will he be okay?
His life's not in any danger.
I'm sure he'll be fine.
That's good.
How did this happen?
The clock is stopped at three.
That's exactly when we were
watching the steam engine.
That's why we didn't hear
the shelves falling.
Judging by the situation,
the shelf on the end fell,
and the rest fell one by one like dominoes.
They were badly rotted.
I guess it was an accident waiting to happen.
What's this?
Come on, kids.
It's dangerous. Get out of the store.
But...
Go home.
Okay...
Oh, you came to see me?
Yeah. Are you okay?
Yes. It's just a minor concussion,
so I'll be able to leave soon.
That's good news.
It's really unfortunate
those bookshelves collapsed.
I suppose,
but I'm just glad they
didn't injure a customer.
I probably had it coming.
What?
I wasn't supposed to be
in the bookstore then.
I went out to buy more books,
but I realized I forgot my wallet on the way.
When I went back to get it, this happened.
I see.
If I'd closed down the
shop like Ichiro said...
What? You're going to close the store?
I did think it was about time,
but I just couldn't go through with it.
The accident was unfortunate,
but it's a good opportunity.
It's probably the right thing to do.
Ai-chan?
That store is badly deteriorated.
They'd probably have to
start from the foundation
if they wanted to restore it,
which would cost millions.
I doubt they have that kind of money.
Ai-chan's right.
What's going to happen to the books?
Sadly, we'll have to auction them.
Then the books will find their
way to people who want them.
Oh, I know.
Would you like to see our photos?
We took lots of pictures of the steam engine.
Really?
I'd like to see them, then.
These are nice photos.
This one's the best.
I agree.
Let me see that!
What's wrong?
Thank you.
I heard you visited my dad in the hospital.
Yeah. He has a minor concussion,
so he'll be out soon.
Yeah.
But he said he's closing down the store.
You don't seem too happy.
What?
I thought you wanted him to close it.
Well, yeah.
Ichiro.
Michiko.
I guess this is my girlfriend.
What do you mean, you guess?
Yoshikawa Michiko (27)
Ichiro's Girlfriend
I'm Yoshikawa Michiko.
Nice to meet you.
Okay.
What are you kids doing?
They were visiting my dad.
They came to tell me how he's doing.
Your dad's in the hospital?
Yeah, he was injured in an accident.
Is he okay?
The old man's fine.
Really? That's good.
You're his girlfriend?
That's right.
We've been dating for five years.
What? That long?
What do you like about Ichiro-san?
My, you're precocious.
Probably how nice he is.
And how much he cares for his father.
It didn't look that way to me.
They were arguing in the bookstore.
He's just awkward,
especially around his dad.
Thanks for waiting.
It's good.
When you're finished working, we should talk.
Sorry. I can't tonight.
You're seeing your father in the hospital.
I'll go with you.
Sorry. There's a lot of preparations
to be made and paperwork to fill out.
Can we meet tomorrow?
Fine. Call me once everything is settled.
Work hard.
Don't worry about the store.
I'll wait as long as it takes.
Tell your father I can't wait to see him.
Sure.
Bye.
What did she mean about the store?
Michiko and I are planning
to open a café together.
I'm working here to earn
money for the café and train.
Really? Yujiro-san will
miss having you around.
If only he'd close the bookstore before
I'm not around to look after him.
You said the same thing before.
Is there a reason you want
him to close the bookstore?
Running a bookstore is hard work.
It's too much for an old man.
I was worried about letting my dad
work alone in a run down bookstore.
The accident was unfortunate, but things
turned out exactly the way you wanted.
Now you can relax.
Ai-chan, you shouldn't have said that.
Oh, really?
I'm sorry.
You shouldn't go in there. It's dangerous.
Conan-kun? And...
Ichiro-san, what are you doing here?
I dropped something when I
came here this afternoon.
I'm here looking for it.
Without a flashlight?
Anyway, what are you kids doing here?
It's dark out. You should go home.
You're the one who caused
the accident, aren't you?
What?
This incident could only
have happened deliberately.
Conan-kun, what are you talking about?
Think about it.
There weren't any books
in the shelf on the end.
In other words, it was the lightest.
You think that bookshelf could've
pushed over a shelf full of books?
You're right.
They were all badly deteriorated.
I don't think it's strange that the
slightest bump caused an accident.
Besides, when the shelves fell, I was...
You were with us.
This is the photo that was taken at exactly
three when the steam engine began running.
Judging by the broken clock in the bookstore,
the accident happened at exactly three, too.
See?
So I couldn't have pushed
the shelves over then.
Maybe not directly, but it's
possible using a trick.
A trick? What trick?
Look closely at the photo.
It looks like an ordinary group photo to me.
These photos were taken using burst mode.
Let's replay the series.
Pay attention to the butterfly
at the edge of the frame.
Don't you think the butterfly's
movements are strange?
It's weird that it's not flapping its wings,
but later it suddenly jumps up into the air.
I think the butterfly was
stopped on an invisible thread
and was thrown upwards by the shock.
Ichiro-san, you connected
the steam engine's wheels
and the bookshelves with thread, didn't you?
Once the steam engine's wheels
started moving at three...
The bookshelves fell one after another.
After most of the thread
was wound up by the wheel,
the thread broke, throwing
the butterfly in the air.
The reason you had a leaf stuck
to you when you came to see us
was because you were in the brush
tying the string to the shelves.
You're wrong.
Then show us what you're
hiding behind your back.
If I'm right,
then what you're holding is evidence
that you planned this accident.
Am I wrong?
There's no way a man who was so nice
us to us would do something bad.
Right?
It's burned and damaged in a few places.
It should match the marks on the bookshelves.
You don't have to say any more. I did it.
You're lying!
Ichiro-san would never
try to kill Yujiro-san!
Mitsuhiko, he wasn't trying to kill him.
Remember what Yujiro-san said?
He happened to go back to the
store to get his wallet.
You're right.
Ichiro-san was only trying
to break the shelves,
but unfortunately Yujiro-san
got caught up in it.
It was really stupid of me.
Why'd you do it, then?
I didn't want my father to
push himself so hard anymore.
No matter what I said, he wouldn't listen.
I thought he'd stop working
if the shop were gone.
Later, Ichiro-san admitted his own guilt,
and turned himself in to the police.
Three Months Later
This is where Tamaki's Used
Bookstore used to be, right?
Yes, it should be.
Welcome.
Oh, you're those kids.
Here you go.
Yujiro-san!
Thank you for your help.
Mister.
Long time, no see.
You finally opened your café.
Yeah.
We agreed that this was
the best for the three of us.
It's a wonderful café.
Don't you agree, Ai-chan?
It's not bad.
What?
Thank you.
Ichiro-san was detained
by the police for a while,
but when Yujiro-san learned how
he felt, he didn't press charges.
The case against Ichiro-san was dropped.
Oh, right.
These are for you.
I didn't get the chance
to give them to you then.
No way!
Are you sure?!
Yes.
All right!
I want that one.
Me, too.
What? Didn't you guys get your own books?
What?
I want that one!
Hey, wait!
No way! Absolutely not!
Play nice.
I said no!
Let go!
Episode Preview
Where did he go?
Conan-kun went out with
Ai-chan and the other kids.
He's seriously hurt, but he's breathing.
Conan Disappears Over a Cliff
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "Conan
Disappears Over a Cliff, Part One!"
Family Photo
Next Conan's hint!
A family photo!
Don't miss the next episode.
Used books are nice.
They're cheap.
And they have flavor.
They're tasty?