Hey, now. Where do you think you're going?
N-No one said we'd be murdering anyone.
They ignored our warnings that
we'd kill them if they resisted.
They got what they deserved.
I-I'm out.
Now that's really not part of the plan.
You've broken the contract.
You're a traitor.
You'll have to be punished.
Hey, you!
What are you doing?
Hey!
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
The criminals are acting in secret!
Will the Detective Boys
come in contact with them?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Conan Disappears Over a Cliff
(Part One)
"Conan Disappears Over a Cliff, Part One!"
Victims have been reported in the case.
The serial armed robbery and
arson group known as Zorro
murdered three residents
of the home they broke into,
and seriously injured a patrol officer
reporting to the fire before they fled.
According to the other patrol officer, the
culprit fired a crossbow without warning.
Ridiculous.
This is the fourth wealthy
home they've targeted.
The MPD is doing everything it
can to arrest these criminals.
They're the opposite of the name Zorro.
They're a fiendish group of thugs.
Dad, I know it's your day off,
but don't day drink too much.
I know.
Where did he go?
That kid who always sticks
his nose in news like this?
Conan-kun went out with
Ai-chan and the other kids.
Did you forget?
Must be nice having no responsibilities.
It must be nice for you, too, Dad.
Ready, and...
Beans and honey!
Pudding!
Eel!
Did you get all that, Conan-kun?
Beans and honey, pudding, eel.
That's correct.
That's amazing.
How did you know?
It's obvious.
Let's do our favorite subjects next.
That's obvious, too.
We're almost there, kids.
Hooray!
It's so wonderful!
Staying here makes me feel like a celebrity.
I bet they serve the best eel.
I'm not sure about that.
Unfortunately, we have to cook
for ourselves here, Kojima-kun.
What? N-No way.
Anyway, your connections never
fail to impress, Professor.
I can't believe you know the
person who owns this villa.
Don't you know any eel vendors, Professor?
No.
How could you answer so quickly?
What?
What's wrong, Ayumi-chan?!
Hey, who is he?
He's alive.
He's seriously hurt, but he's breathing.
Haibara, call an ambulance.
Got it.
That was a surprise.
Who was he, and what happened to him?
Is it some kind of case?
He's probably just a thief.
Maybe he made a mistake while
breaking in and hurt himself.
It's not impossible
if he can shoot himself in
the arm with a crossbow.
A crossbow?
Wasn't yesterday's...?
Huh? Where's Conan-kun?
What? He was here until a minute ago.
He must've left this behind.
What's this?
They're probably either
usernames or passwords.
Haibara.
They're totally different.
What are you going to do with
that? Give it back to him?
I guess.
Make up some excuse to tell the others, okay?
Make something up, huh?
Misakihama Clinic
A crossbow was used in yesterday's robbery.
I thought I'd ask him about
it, but he's not awake yet.
Military boots?
What?
Now to call the police.
Inspector Megure.
Does that mean this is connected
to yesterday's case?
Damn it!
What? Conan-kun?
A suspicious man fled through the window!
Check the rear entrance!
What?
It's no use.
He escaped.
We found this in the garbage out back.
Was that injured man part
of the Zorro robbery group?
Actually, the group hires its members.
Isehara Yuji, twenty-eight years old.
Isehara Yuji (28)
Hacker
He's a skilled hacker our cyber-crimes
division was pursuing, too.
He hacks and manipulates the
target's security information.
We heard through the Kanagawa Police
that they had a likely
suspect in their custody,
so we came here.
Is that enough information?
Thank you.
I'll be able to give
Kogoro-no-ojisan a full report.
What? Isehara's missing, too?!
What?
Find them!
Yes, sir!
I see.
Thank you for contacting me, Inspector.
One of yesterday's robbers was found at
the villa where the kids are staying?
Yeah.
I don't know what happened, but he was
hiding in the yard with an injury.
Will Conan-kun be all right?
The police are there.
You don't need to worry.
That's not what I meant.
I'm glad I took a picture just in case.
Dad, how long are you going to keep drinking?
Let's go.
Huh?
There's no way Conan-kun would
just sit still after this.
He'll definitely get up
to something dangerous.
Yeah, but it's not like I've
been hired to investigate.
What are you talking about?
There's no need for the great
detective Mori Kogoro to go—
Stop complaining and stand up.
Ow, ow, ow!
We're leaving.
I'm close.
That's not fair, Conan-kun.
You should've told us if something was up.
The Detective Boys are a team.
I'm hungry.
Huh? Where did Conan go?
That's odd.
We could see him until a moment ago.
It's starting to get dark.
Will Conan-kun be okay?
You mean will we be okay?
Y-You mean...
We seem to be lost.
What? You can't be serious.
What about dinner? Dinner...
Since the sun is setting that way,
the ocean's this way.
We can still identify directions for now,
so we can get back if we need to.
Really, Ai-chan?
Impressive as always, Haibara-san!
So we can still have dinner?!
Yes, so let's go a little farther.
If I keep going this way...
Where am I?
The sun's setting over there,
and the ocean's this way, so...
Is this...?
I'm inside a cave.
A sea breeze?
So there's an exit on the other side?
Of course not.
That's impressive...
Wait, I don't have time for detours.
I'm finally back here, but
it's completely dark out.
Am I lost again?
I'll have to go back.
What's that?
Found it.
What an idiot.
What are we gonna do, Zorro-san?
Mizorogi Go (35)
Armed Robber Zorro
I knew exactly where you'd go, Isehara.
That's him.
S-Spare me.
Please spare me.
For your wife and kid?
Talk about melodramatic.
You talked, didn't you?
I-I didn't say anything!
Then I'll let you choose.
Either I'll kill your family,
or you die here.
It's up to you.
Now choose.
Who's there?
Isehara!
Over here.
Who are you?
Edogawa Conan. I'm a detective.
A-A detective?
Where did he go?
Hurry.
A kid?
Damn it.
Where did they go?!
Th-They're going to kill me.
It's okay.
They don't know where we are.
No! I don't wanna die!
This way.
Wait!
This place...
Conan!
What? Conan-kun?
Conan-kun!
One more. No, two more.
I have a bad feeling.
Could you go faster?
Dad, wake up.
S-Spare me, please.
You put us through all this
unnecessary work, traitor.
Die.
Conan-kun!
Ah, Professor Agasa.
Thank you for coming to meet us.
Did something happen to the kids?
Huh?
I-I just heard from the kids.
What?
Conan-kun is...
I-Is he...?
Ran!
Episode Preview
Conan-kun is...
It can't be true.
B-But we all saw it.
We won't let that happen!
Inspector.
What? Ai-chan's missing, too?
I came alone like you instructed.
Let's go.
Conan Disappears Over a Cliff
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Conan
Disappears Over a Cliff, Part Two!"
Password
Next Conan's hint!
A password.
Conan, are you serious?
Don't miss the next episode.
No way!
It's impossible!
We'll have to wait until next week.