We came to hang out at a villa owned
by Professor Agasa's acquaintance,
where we found an injured
man named Isehara Yuji.
Isehara was a hacker
working for a chivalrous
robber known as Zorro.
I narrowly rescued Isehara as he was
about to be killed for betraying him,
but while we were being pursued...
C-Conan!
What? Conan-kun?
Conan-kun!
Die.
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
Serial robber and arsonist Zorro.
While narrowly avoiding danger,
he'll be brought down!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Conan Disappears Over a Cliff
(Part Two)
"Conan Disappears Over a Cliff, Part Two!"
Guys!
Ran-oneesan!
Conan-kun is...
It's not true.
It can't be true.
B-But we all saw Conan fall
from up there.
You're right.
We all saw Edogawa-kun fall from the cliff.
N-No...
No!
Conan-kun...
Why? Why?
What happened, Inspector?
It's Zorro. He did this.
What did you say?
From the children's testimony,
we were able to determine
the man with Conan-kun
as they were being pursued was Isehara Yuji.
But right after they fell from the cliff,
Zorro and his men disappeared.
There must be discord among the group.
And Conan-kun got caught in the crossfire.
But what was that kid doing with Isehara?!
Don't ask me!
In any case, we'll ask the Kanagawa
Police to begin searching the ocean
first thing in the morning.
Right now!
Have them start now, Inspector!
F-Fine. Hey!
Yes, sir!
Damn it.
This can't... This can't be happening!
D-Dad...
Kanagawa Prefectural Police Misakihama Station
It's okay. He's fine.
I'm sure Conan-kun is fine.
We'll wait for him, okay?
Okay.
Yeah.
Okay?
How did it go, Inspector?
It's been three hours
since the search started,
but they still haven't found anything.
I see.
According to the local police,
the water below the cliff is deep
and the currents there are fast.
Anyone who fell there would have
been quickly washed out to sea.
They rarely find bodies there.
We're having them continue the search.
They'll call us immediately
if they find anything.
Understood.
Conan-kun's safety is important of course,
but depending on Isehara's condition,
the Zorro investigation could run aground.
We won't let that happen!
Not ever.
Inspector.
I saw him fall
from the cliff with my own eyes.
But I didn't see his body.
He came this way.
A cave?
A sea breeze?
Then at the end of the cave...
Those rocks...
Which means this is
directly below that cliff.
Wait. I said wait!
Isehara Yuji (28)
Hacker
Shut up! Stop following me!
I don't have time to play
detective with a kid.
Jeez.
You're not gonna thank me after surviving
the fall from that cliff unscathed?
S-Spare me, please.
You put us through all this
unnecessary work, traitor.
Die.
We're directly above that cave.
Which means I have to take a chance.
It's my only option.
If I consider the height of the cliff,
and try to match the timing of
the waves crashing against it...
Now!
Hurry! Swim inside!
Way ahead of you.
You're not going to turn yourself in?
Of course not.
There was a guy who did and revealed
the location of Zorro's hideout.
I heard Zorro followed him
overseas to finish him off.
Even if I turn myself in, eventually...
But you can't keep running forever.
That's why I'm thinking of a plan!
Then wouldn't it be faster to get Zorro
before he gets you?
What are you talking about?
Though you'll need help.
ZR-Stunt Co.
It's an exhibition and jewelry
sale for the nouveau riche.
Mizorogi Go (35)
Armed Robber Zorro
It's held in the same place once a month.
What's it worth?
Unlike robbing individual homes,
we'll make a fortune in one go.
We'll make at least 100 million.
How's security?
Pretty standard.
We can use Isehara's program to
disable it like we always do.
It'll be no problem at all.
Speaking of Isehara, he's an idiot.
I can't believe he ran away and
fell straight down into hell.
Naturally we'll be splitting
his share. Right, Zorro-san?
Should we rewrite the contract?
We'll do it tonight just like we planned.
Start getting ready.
What? Ai-chan's missing, too?
What's going on?
I don't know.
She was gone by the time we noticed.
Could Haibara-san have fallen victim...
...to them, too?
Unbelievable. What was she thinking?
Why do they keep running off?!
That's not important right now, Dad!
I know!
Inspector.
Start looking for her immediately.
Yes, sir!
I came alone like you instructed.
Whew.
I thought it'd be broken
after falling in the sea.
I'm glad my message got through.
More importantly, don't
you have something to say?
You're right.
Sorry. I need them to think we're
dead, or his family will be in danger.
S-Spare me.
Please spare me.
For your wife and kid?
Talk about melodramatic.
You talked, didn't you?
I-I didn't say anything!
Then I'll let you choose.
Either I'll kill your family,
or you die here.
It's up to you.
Now choose.
Well, I don't mind, but make sure
you explain it to them later.
I know.
So, did you bring what I asked for?
Yeah, yeah.
All right!
Hey, be careful with that.
I spent two months developing it.
Huh, you even have these kinds of programs?
Kids are amazing these days.
I used to be like you.
I knew it.
They've already started working
on disabling the target's security
using my program.
So one of those passwords
was for checking that.
Then the other...
We need to stop Zorro's next robbery first.
What's his target?
The Beika City Central Event Hall.
Okay, let's call the police.
Yeah.
ZR-Stunt Co.
Security Controls
Memory Controls
Communication
Controls
7th Crown Jewel Exhibition and Sale Party
Left side set.
Right side set.
Devices set.
Three, two, one, go.
Let's go.
Wh-What?
I've been waiting for you, Zorro-san.
Unfortunately, tonight's party was canceled
after we learned you were coming.
That's impossible.
We heard voices earlier.
Shut up!
You mean these voices?
So that's how it is.
Now I remember.
He's that kid. He's still alive?
Which means he is, too.
What are you talking about, kid?
We're just stuntmen.
We were called to provide
entertainment at tonight's party.
Don't bother playing dumb.
You can come in now.
I knew it.
But we saw him fall.
What's going on?
It doesn't matter!
I'll just kill him again!
Zorro, also known as Mizorogi Go.
You're under arrest for
robbery, arson, and murder.
You're going down with him!
Give yourselves up!
Let's go, Isehara.
O-Okay...
I knew it.
I'll check it out.
Megure here.
Ah, Agasa-san.
No, thank you. That was
some impressive work.
What? Is there something else?
You did well, Isehara-san.
What?
This isn't your wife or child.
You modified a photo you found
online to make them appear
to be your family so Zorro and his
men would believe you had a weakness.
You were after the money he
stole from the beginning.
After finding their bank account number,
you ran from them.
That's when...
I knew it.
They've already started working
on disabling the target's security
using my program.
What's his target?
The Beika City Central Event Hall.
Okay, let's call the police.
Yeah.
The children noticed.
That password was for remotely transferring
the money into your overseas account.
You probably assumed you'd be
released from prison before them.
Am I wrong?
I'm impressed you noticed, Agasa-san.
We had Interpol freeze the account.
You won't be able to withdraw
a cent of it, Isehara.
It's finally over.
No, not yet.
Play nice.
Conan-kun!
Uh, I... Sorry for making you worry.
I'm sorry!
Oh, right. In that case,
Episode Preview
there's somewhere I'd like to go.
The Onimaru Squad Nobuna
Gaizers have arrived!
A local hero show, huh?
So they're heroes modeled after Oda Nobunaga.
The members of Nobuna
Gaizers are over... Huh?
The Nobunaga 450 Case
The next episode of Conan
is "The Nobunaga 450 Case!"
Nobuna Gaizers
Next Conan's hint.
Nobuna Gaizers!
To make up for making us worry...
Don't miss the next episode.
A video game!
A stuffed animal!
Extra fine eel!
Uh, what?