Nobuna Gaizers
We're here!
We made it!
Oda Nobunaga
It's so shiny!
It's Nobunaga!
Wow!
2017 is the 450th anniversary
of Warring States General Oda
Nobunaga's entry into Gifu Castle.
In addition to sightseeing around the city,
we've come to see the numerous
events commemorating the event.
Minna No Mori Gifu Media Cosmos
Wasn't that interesting, Conan-kun?
Yeah, it was.
Ayumi, I didn't know you
liked this kind of thing.
Oh, a lot of girls do these days.
They're called History Buffs
or Warring States Girls.
I don't know about that,
but it was really interesting.
Let's head to the next place.
Okay.
Nobunaga 450 Project
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
A case casts a shadow over new heroes of
Warring States Era Gifu, the Nobuna Gaizers.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Nobunaga 450 Case
"The Nobunaga 450 Case!"
Juhachiro
This is where we're staying tonight.
Welcome.
Thank you!
Tobayama-san.
Ah, Agasa-san.
Kids, this my old friend
and the man who invited us,
cormorant fisherman Tobayama-san.
Hello. You must be the Detective Boys.
Tobayama Iwao (55)
Cormorant Fisherman
Nice to meet you!
Good, you're full of energy.
Wow.
It's so pretty.
Ah, Tobayama-san.
Tobayama-san!
Where should we go next?
Hey, that's the Gifu dialect.
Actually, "ikomaika" isn't the interrogative.
It means "let's go to a particular place."
I see you know everything, Mr. Detective.
Whatever.
I'm starving.
What?
Didn't you just eat three
Hida beef steaks, Genta-kun?
Oh, right.
Oh, right. In that case, there's
somewhere I'd like to go.
Huh?
Since Nobunaga took the
castle, it's been 400...
...and 50 years!
In this year for the ages,
to this land, we bring
justice and friendship!
Courage and effort!
Love and smiles!
The Origami Squad Nobuna
Gaizers have arrived!
Nobuna Gaizers!
A local hero show, huh?
No... Nobu... Naza?
What are they called?
The Nobuna Gaizers.
They're heroes modeled after Oda Nobunaga.
They're so cool.
Aren't they?!
I actually came here for this.
Local Hero Album
Seriously?
Mitsuhiko-kun, did you make this?
Yes!
By going on trips and looking online,
I've gathered data on local
heroes across the country.
There's a lot of them.
With all those heroes, the
world must be super safe.
Yeah.
Go!
Nobuna Gaizers!
That was their signature move, the
Gaizer Triple Decker Knock Down!
They're so cool!
They're amazing!
I'll help.
Me, too.
Thanks.
The Nobuna Gaizers have something for you.
Make sure you get yours.
Line up, line up.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Oh, my.
Ah.
Hooray.
Here you go.
The paper's so pretty.
This is Minowa paper, isn't it?
Ah, you know what it is?
I looked up where you've been working
before coming.
That's amazing.
I'm so glad to hear that.
We couldn't exist without you.
Thank you.
N-No, thank you! I'm overjoyed!
Thank you so much!
Origami Squad
Nobuna Gaizers
No, thank you.
See you kids later!
Bye!
That was crazy. I've never
seen Mitsuhiko like that.
Good work today.
Good work.
Good work, everyone.
Akahoshi Kengo (28)
Nobuna Gaizer Red
Aoto Teppei (26)
Nobuna Gaizer Blue
Midoriyama Koji (23)
Nobuna Gaizer Green
Kurotani Takuro (30)
Nobuna Gaizer Black
Momochi Kurumi (22)
Nobuna Gaizer Pink
We have a meeting to
discuss tomorrow's event.
Oyabu Kimifusa (45)
Event Promoter
We'll meet at the office.
Okay!
It's against the rules to see
a hero's face, Conan-kun.
Oh, right.
Let's head back to the hotel, kids.
Okay!
I definitely feel full after that.
I agree.
What? I could keep eating.
Let's stop by a convenience store
on the way back, Professor.
We need to get lunch boxes and pork buns
and sandwiches and chips and drinks.
Okay, okay.
Genta-kun, that's too much food.
Yeah.
What's wrong, Mitsuhiko-kun?
I forgot to ask them to sign my album.
This sucks.
Mitsuhiko, are you sure you
want to give up so easily?
We'll wait for you.
Yeah.
But we're going to the
convenience store after.
Thank you!
Be careful.
I will!
Excuse me.
Are the members of Nobuna Gaizers in...
Mitsuhiko's taking a while.
I'm about to starve to death.
It's quiet.
Let's try calling him.
That's Mitsuhiko-kun's.
Genta-kun
Incoming Call
No way.
What's going on?
Juhachiro
You still haven't found him?
It's been two hours.
I've told the other fishermen.
They'll call if they see or hear anything.
Thank you.
What about the police?
The professor used the old man's
name to get them to look into it.
They should be coming soon.
Huh?
You kids seem familiar...
I remember now!
We met during the world heritage
site Onizawa Village case.
Detective Matsushiro, right?
Matsushiro Tamekichi (38)
Gifu Prefectural Police
Is Mori-san not here today?
Professor Agasa came with us instead.
Professor Agasa.
I've heard about you.
You solve cases with deductive abilities
on par with Detective Mori's.
I-Is that right?
They're both me, though.
They'll hear you.
Could you give me the
details of the case again?
But Mitsuhiko's whereabouts
remained unknown, and...
The Nobuna Gaizers are missing, too?
What does this mean?
We wanted to question them too,
but we still haven't been able
to get in touch with them.
I have a bad feeling about this.
Yeah.
Gifu City History Museum
Golden Tile
Solid Gold Nobunaga Statue
(Miniature)
Solid Gold Nobunaga Statue (Miniature)
The objects that were stolen include a
miniature solid gold Oda Nobunaga statue
and a golden tile.
They also took some ancient
manuscripts with historical value.
They're all treasures of Gifu.
If we don't hurry, they'll be sold on
the black market and be sent overseas.
R-Really?
This is turning into a big deal.
Uh,
could we see the security camera footage?
Yes.
Security Office
Huh? These guys...
They're the Nobuna Gaizers.
You can't be serious!
I didn't want to believe it,
but the heroes are the thieves!
They're the worst! They
won't get away with this!
Wh-What?
You found the Nobuna Gaizers' car?
Wh-What's that?
It's a Nobunaga badge.
Is it Mitsuhiko-kun's?
Was he in this car?
Did they take him hostage?
What?
Look.
Yeah, I noticed, too.
And look at the front wheels.
Is that...?
Yeah. It's asphalt tar.
Nobuna Gaizers
Nobuna Gaizers Wanted
The Nobuna Gaizers, local heroes,
popular for cleaning up the city
and helping the elderly, are
wanted as suspects in a robbery.
The five heroes on the run may have taken
a grade school aged boy hostage—
It's my fault for saying that.
Mitsuhiko, are you sure you
want to give up so easily?
We'll wait for you.
Yeah.
But we're going to the
convenience store after.
Thank you!
Be careful.
I will!
I told him to go, too.
I didn't try to stop him either.
Me, too.
Heroes, my butt.
They're just a bunch of nuisances.
Nobuna Gaizer Red is left handed, right?
Yeah, but he was right
handed at the crime scene.
Blue and Green were switched
in their signature pose, too.
What does it mean?
C-Could it be?
They're impostors?
Yeah, that's exactly right.
Huh? What?
Are you the Nobuna Gaizers?
Hello. Everything's ready here.
We'll handle the rest.
They kidnapped the real Nobuna
Gaizers, stole their costumes,
and committed the robbery while wearing them.
How dare they.
But who would do this?
You already know, don't you?
Should we confirm your suspicions?
Yeah. Professor, call Detective Matsushiro.
Got it. It's a success.
What's a success?
You mean your evil plan?
Yes, your plan to frame the
Nobuna Gaizers for a robbery.
Hero show promoter Oyabu Kimifusa-san.
Wh-Who are you?
We're the Detective Boys!
Where's Mitsuhiko-kun?
Wh-What are you talking about?
I don't know anything.
Don't bother playing dumb. We have evidence.
Evidence?
Nobuna Gaizer Red is left handed.
Blue and Green's positions are switched, too.
You should've done more research if
you wanted to frame them, mister.
They just happened to be different.
Then there's another piece
of damning evidence.
Your ring.
What?
You should've taken it off.
Heroes don't wear rings.
You hit the security
guard at the crime scene.
Your ring tore the glove when you did.
It should match the cut on the victim, too.
We checked the costumes again
after Agasa-san called.
The costume's glove was torn.
We'll have to examine that ring thoroughly.
I didn't have a choice.
My company was going under.
I was being threatened by loan sharks.
Were the other impostors
employees of that loan company?
Y-Yeah. I was forced to help them.
I'm impressed, Agasa-san.
Oh, uh... I guess that solves it.
It's not over yet. Where's Mitsuhiko?
Where are the real Nobuna Gaizers?
Where are they?
I-I don't know.
They told me they'd handle the rest.
It's true!
What? Crap.
What does it mean, Conan-kun?
It means if we don't hurry,
they'll be silenced forever.
The heroes and Tsuburaya-kun.
What?
Find them!
F-Fire!
We're done for!
We're finished!
I don't want to die!
Don't give up!
Your fans are waiting for you!
Hey, Conan, what should we do?
Yeah. It's asphalt tar.
Wait! Stop!
Where were you working this morning?
Almost... Almost...
All right.
Is anyone there?
Help!
What should we do?
At this rate...
Over there.
We can use those.
Gifu Castle
This morning the areas
that were paved were...
...these two places.
They're practically in opposite directions.
Which one is Mitsuhiko-kun at?
That's...
It's okay.
We won't fall.
Trust us.
You can do it.
Mitsuhiko-kun.
Okay.
Hold on, Mitsuhiko.
Damn. We're out of paper.
What should we do?
Use my album.
But isn't that important to you?
Heroes were made for moments like these.
This is it. He's nearby.
This is Mitsuhiko's album.
Over there.
Mitsuhiko!
Tsuburaya-kun!
Mitsuhiko-kun!
Conan-kun, the door is locked!
Got it!
You came for me.
Thank you!
I was scared!
Thank you, Mitsuhiko-kun.
You're our hero.
Thank you.
I-I'm honored!
The remaining impostors were arrested and
the treasures of Gifu have been returned.
And the Nobuna Gaizers'
name has been cleared.
Nice job, Mitsuhiko.
You're the pride of the Detective Boys.
Why don't you cosplay as heroes?
The Detective Heroes have arrived!
I'm out.
Me, too.
Local heroes Nobuna Gaizers!
Plus one!
Episode Preview
The Black Organization
must be interested, too.
A strange duo?
And that piece of paper had
the word "nue" written on it!
Y-You mean it lives in this forest?
That monster from folktales?
Conan and Heiji's Nue Legend
(Roar Arc)
The next episode of Conan is "Conan and Heiji's Nue Legend, Roar Arc!"
Buried Treasure
Next Conan's hint!
Buried treasure!
You did well this episode.
Don't miss the next episode.
Nobuna Gaizers!
That's enough.
Plus one!