What?
It was your doppelganger?
Seriously?
So you didn't go to the concert hall that day.
N-No. Did we really look that similar?
Yes.
I was completed fooled when she
stopped me at the entrance.
I wonder who she was.
Maybe it was Kaito Kid.
He must've come to steal my heart.
Yeah, right.
It was Vermouth.
But if she bothered to investigate,
the Black Organization must be interested
in the "ASACA RUM"
cipher left by Haneda Koji
seventeen years ago, too.
I wonder what she was after, though.
It's kind of creepy.
Speaking of creepy, when I went out
shopping for ingredients earlier,
I saw a strange duo going
up to the detective agency.
A strange duo?
Were they dressed in black?
What? They were dressed
like a normal couple.
The boyfriend's skin was dark
like Amuro-san's though.
Dark?
Was it Makoto-san?
What's he doing with another woman?!
I-I wouldn't know, but they were
talking about something strange.
Something about cleaning rags.
R-Rags?
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
Rags dance in a terrifying case.
The forest where the nue's cry can
be heard is a horrifying place.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Conan and Heiji's Nue Legend
(Roar Arc)
"Conan and Heiji's Nue Legend, Roar Arc!"
Mori Detective Agency
Not cleaning rags, rags to riches.
Really?
Rags to riches, huh?
I knew it was him.
The mayor of Yadori Village sent
Heiji a letter asking him to help
unearth Tokugawa's buried treasure,
since he found a clue to its location.
We thought we'd invite your dad, too.
I'm not going.
Even if it's actually
Tokugawa's buried treasure,
most of it will end up
belonging to the state.
Really? Guess you're not going, then.
Since we have a few days off, you
should take this kid with you, Ran.
But doesn't searching for
buried treasure sound scary?
What? You should come with us, Ran-chan.
The mayor's covering all our travel expenses.
Besides, if Heiji got a letter, as
the other high school detective,
Kudo-kun might've received one, too.
Sh-Shinichi got one?
You're right.
Come to think of it,
Kudo said he was interested
in buried treasure before.
Maybe he'll be there.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Yeah, so you should come with us.
What do you think you're doing?
It's not like I can't since we
have a few days off, but...
You're not interested in
buried treasure either.
I didn't have a choice.
If she doesn't come, you can't come either.
You've got an ulterior motive, don't you?
There's nothing like that.
Anyway, Tokugawa's buried treasure
is at Mt. Akagi in Gunma.
If there's another case, that
useless inspector will show up.
Don't worry about that.
We're not going to Gunma,
we're going to Shizuoka.
Shizuoka?
Thank you for coming, Hattori Heiji-sama.
And your friends, too.
I'm looking forward to unearthing
this buried treasure.
Takekuma Densuke (58)
Yadori Village Mayor
After all, the fate of Yadori
Village depends on it.
But why did you write to Heiji-niichan?
There are other non-high
school aged detectives.
Yes, well, I also invited
historians and archaeologists,
so the budget was tight.
Forgive me, but I thought a high
school detective would come
if I paid for his transportation and food.
Hey.
You'll pay for the bullet train
I took to get here, right?
Of course.
Hey, you must be joking!
You really expect us to stay
in this run down hotel?
It doesn't look like much, but it's
sparkling clean on the inside.
I bought plenty of ingredients,
so I'll do my best to
prepare a feast for you.
You're cooking for us?
There used to be droves of tourists
who came to see Kurogane Lake.
The hotel prospered, but
since the incident...
What incident?
What happened?
Oh, actually...
A member of the team unearthing
Tokugawa's buried treasure
died in an accident while excavating.
Tanzawa Michiki (62)
Archaeologist
Hey...
Do people really think there's
buried treasure around here?
Yeah.
Shizuoka is where Tokugawa Ieyasu retired,
and Sunpu Castle once stood here.
And there's a legend.
During the war, when Ieyasu was
nearly captured by Imagawa,
an old couple hid him
here in Kurogane Forest.
After the country stabilized, he gave
them a mountain of golden coins,
Someji Yasukatsu (55)
Historian
to thank the couple and their
son for their kindness.
Really?
Is it true?
Yes. There's even a poem about it.
"In the morning and evening sun,
two thousand jars glitter
with a thousand golden coins."
It's a nursery song that's been
sung in this town for ages.
"In the morning and evening sun"
is a phrase that appears in poems
on the location of the buried
treasure from throughout the country.
Masuko Fumie (46)
Author
But if there really are two thousand
jars filled with a thousand gold coins,
it would be truly romantic.
That's two million gold coins.
It would be so wonderful if it were true.
No way.
You two cuties look like treasures
that glitter brighter than gold to me.
Hey!
Who the hell are you?
Oh, are they your girlfriends?
I asked you first!
Answer me!
I'm a documentary writer who
travels across the country
Tsurumi Hajime (22)
Documentary Writer
in search of local monster legends.
Mon...
Monsters?
What? That's got nothing
to do with buried treasure.
What? You haven't heard?
This village actually...
Whoa, a dog!
Stop that!
I-I don't like dogs...
He's cute!
Yeah.
He was brought here by the member
of the excavation team
who died in the accident.
After the accident, the locals took him in,
but since he kept escaping to come back here,
we've let him be.
The lake is just past the
trees so it's a bit dangerous,
but someone's been feeding him occasionally.
Stay Out
Danger!
That's a huge sign.
Conan-kun, it's dangerous.
You can't go in there.
Is this everyone you invited here today?
Well, yes.
Shinichi's not here, then.
I was planning to give him my answer
to what he said in London, too.
What you said over the
phone had better be true.
The view is magnificent.
Better than the view of
Big Ben in the evening?
Of course. It doesn't even compare.
You're sure, right?
I guarantee it.
Hey, Kazuha-chan.
Did Hattori-kun invite you here?
Yeah. He asked if I was busy over the break.
But now they're talking
about cave-ins and monsters.
I have a bad feeling about this.
Actually...
What you're feeling might be love.
What?
I'm stuffed.
I couldn't eat another bite.
The stew was good.
Thanks, Mister Mayor.
You're welcome.
Now to finish it off,
we put rice in the bowl
and cover it with beaten eggs.
Then you mix it with your chopsticks,
and the porridge is ready.
What? You're mixing it?
But the eggs are fluffier if
you just cover it instead.
It all tastes like egg if you
mix it. It's delicious that way.
Let's hear that monster story
you started to tell us earlier.
Ah, that story?
There was a foreigner named Charles
Abel on the excavation team
who spoke broken Japanese.
He's the one who got in the accident.
When the rest of the team
arrived, he was still alive.
He was trying to say something
from under the rocks,
so they asked him if he had found anything.
But the foreigner's throat had been
destroyed, and he couldn't speak.
Someone on the team handed
him a notebook and pen,
and the foreigner slowly and
carefully wrote three letters
from the alphabet on the page.
The team members who saw the
page were frozen in fear
because that piece of paper had
the word "nue" written on it!
Nue?
What?
N-Nue? You mean...
That monster from folk tales?
That's right.
The head of a monkey,
the body of a tanuki,
the legs of a tiger,
and the tail of a snake.
It's an ancient monster that
appears in a cloud of black smoke
with an eerie cry to bring misfortune.
Are you saying one of those was in that cave?
Yeah. I mean, what else could it be?
That's why I was invited here.
In order to tell the world about
the monster that plunged
the excavation team into the depths of fear!
What do you think you're doing, hag?
Don't gleefully recount a person's death!
Now you've ruined the porridge.
I thought your novels covered similar themes.
Indeed.
It's hard to imagine those
words coming from the woman
who described in such grotesque detail
the death of a man eaten by a monster.
Oh, would it better if I left?
Now, now, everyone. Let's try to get along.
Why don't we get a good night's sleep
and meet at the cave at the
excavation site in the morning?
Wh—
Wh-What is this weird sound?
How unusual.
Is it here?
In the forest?
"Is it here?"
What is this sound?
It's the cry...
of the nue.
Th-The cry of the nue?
Y-You mean it lives in this forest?
That monster from folk tales?
Not the monster, the bird.
It's...
...a bird?
It lives in hardwood forests in hilly areas.
The scaly thrush was once called the nue.
Since the cry of the monster that appeared
in the Tale of Heike sounded
similar to the bird's,
it was called the nue.
I didn't think the scaly thrush
lived around here, though.
How unusual.
Maybe the foreigner who died in the cave-in
saw the bird, too.
All he wrote as he was dying
was "nue" in the English alphabet.
Wh-What are you talking about?
The foreigner saw it inside a
cave at the excavation site!
It couldn't have been a bird!
It really was there!
Deep inside that cave, the legendary nue!
Yeah,
but none of the surviving
members of the excavation team
saw the nue, right?
Actually, it may not be entirely false.
Long ago, the body of a nue fell on the
western side of Hamana Lake in Shizuoka.
The regions Nueshiro, Dosaki,
Hanebira, and Ona of Mikkabi
in Hamamatsu City's North Ward
are said to have gotten their names
from the nue's head, body, wings,
and tail that fell.
It's even said that the nue's
legs fell here in Yadori Village.
Yadori Village was once written using
the characters for "night" and "bird."
Yadori (Night Bird)
Together they make the character for nue.
Nue
So this sound could be not the bird, but...
What?
Huh?
It stopped.
Hey, let's go home.
What? But we came all the way here.
And all those monster stories
were heard second-hand.
The foreigner writing the
word "nue" at his death
must be fake, too.
Oh, I actually have that piece of paper.
Y-You do?
See? It says "nue."
After the cave-in, the previous
mayor found it next to the body
when they dug the foreigner out.
It's been kept at the town
hall for sixteen years.
Along with this old hairpin they
supposedly found with the paper.
Really?
If this dog belonged to that
foreigner, he must be pretty old.
It wouldn't be strange if he
dropped dead any day now.
He was still a puppy when he had him.
What was found recently was
this notebook with a page
that perfectly matches the
torn edge of this piece of paper.
It details where and how
the team was excavating
the cave, and on the basis of what information.
If we could go to the cave
tomorrow and describe
where the buried treasure might be found,
while reading from this notebook
in front of a camera, you'd be
doing Yadori Village a huge favor.
I see. He's making a video
to revitalize his town.
So he never expected us to
find any buried treasure.
Rest well, everyone.
Did you get the beverage I requested?
I have trouble sleeping without it.
What about my sake?
And mine?
Yes, I bought all of them.
I'll bring them to your rooms later.
Someji-sama, you requested milk and whiskey.
Tanzawa-sama, you requested
Japanese sake and dried cuttlefish.
Masuko-sama, you requested
white wine and soda water.
And Tsurumi-sama, you requested
cola and potato chips, right?
Yeah. I'll drink it from the
bottle, so I don't need a glass.
Very well.
Hattori-sama, shall I bring
anything for your group?
Nah, we're fine.
Right?
Yeah.
If we drink too many fluids, we'll have to
use the bathroom in the middle of the night.
I'm not sure if I'll be able to sleep tonight.
Yeah.
You should inspect your rooms
before you go to sleep.
There was a desiccated mouse corpse
in the desk drawer of my room.
What?!
That's odd. I thought I cleaned everything.
If you're so scared, why don't
you sleep with me in my room?
You can sleep with the mice!
I agree.
A letter?
What are you doing?
If you want to open the
drawer, open it already.
B-But...
What if there's a mouse in there?
There's nothing like that in there.
There's something inside.
Looks like old notebooks.
I wonder whose they are.
Maybe someone forgot them.
Th-That's terrifying.
It's the same character
written over and over.
Wh-What is that?
Oh, the foreigner who died
was probably practicing his hiragana.
What?
Charles Abel
See? It says Charles Abel on the back.
Doesn't that mean this is the room
the dead foreigner stayed in?
It's light outside.
What's going on?
There's a fire in front of the hotel!
What?
Fire!
Run! There's a fire!
Stay Out
Danger!
Who could've done this?
I-It's the nue...
The nue came in a cloud of black smoke.
You idiot! There's no way
anything like that—
Heiji! Look...
I-It's huge...
What is this thing?
I-It's leaving!
Damn!
We can't go after it this
way because of the fire!
Mayor, fire extinguishers!
Use all the fire extinguishers
here to put out the fire!
G-Got it.
Kazuha, help them put out the fire!
Wh-What about you?
Don't ask stupid questions!
I'm going around back to find
out what that monster really is!
Conan-kun!
There are huge teeth marks on it.
Yeah.
That's weird, though.
We ran around the back...
...but we didn't pass the monster.
Could it have gone through the trees
and into the lake?
Blood?
It leads towards the lake.
That's Someji-san!
Is he unconscious?
No, he's already dead.
With scratches on his back as though
he was attacked by a wild beast.
Episode Preview
H-He's dead?
It's the nue...
That giant monster got him.
It must've been some kind of trick.
I smell kerosene in these burns, too.
Where'd that fire come from?
I don't know. It suddenly ignited.
Wh-What was that scream?
Conan and Heiji's Nue
Legend
(Scratch Arc)
The next episode of Conan is "Conan and
Heiji's Nue Legend, Scratch Arc!"
Giant Monster
Next Conan's hint!
A giant monster!
My answer to London...
Don't miss the next episode.
Am I feeling love?
They're both acting weird...