Invited by Hattori Heiji and Toyama Kazuha,
Ran and I came to Yadori
Village in Shizuoka Prefecture
to help unearth the buried
treasure of Tokugawa.
However, that night...
It's light outside.
What's going on?
There's a fire in front of the hotel!
What?
Who could've done this?
I-It's the nue...
The nue came in a cloud of black smoke.
You idiot! There's no way
anything like that—
H-Heiji! Look...
After pursuing the monster, we found...
Blood?
That's Someji-san!
Is he unconscious?
No, he's already dead.
With scratches on his back as though
he was attacked by a wild beast.
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
Is it the Nue or something else?
The giant scratches spur the mystery
of the buried treasure onward.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Conan and Heiji's Nue Legend
(Scratch Arc)
"Conan and Heiji's Nue
Legend, Scratch Arc!"
H-He's dead?
Someji-san is dead?
R-Really?
Yeah.
We found him in the trees by
the lake next to the hotel.
He was murdered, with huge
scratch marks on his back.
What?
Masuko Fumie (46)
Author
Th-They didn't look like
tiger claw marks, did they?
No, they were bigger.
There were four scratches
about ten centimeters apart.
Y-You must be joking.
This is no joke.
It's the nue.
Tsurumi Hajime (22)
Documentary Writer
That giant monster got him.
They say the nue has the legs of a tiger.
Tanzawa Michiki (62)
Archaeologist
I thought it was the jars, but
the monster really does exist.
What?
Nothing. I was talking to myself.
He thought it was...
...the jars?
So, did you call the police?
Yeah, we did.
Since we're in the mountains, they
said they couldn't make it right away.
But I don't think the police
can handle a monster like that.
Don't worry.
There's no way the monster's real.
It must've been some kind of trick.
I smell kerosene in these burns, too.
But you found giant scratches
on the body, right?
Someji-san probably fled from his attacker
after he was stabbed in the back,
but he collapsed from exhaustion,
and the culprit made a long
cut over the initial wound.
Then they added three more to make it
look like he'd been attacked by the nue.
The mayor who invited Someji-san here is
probably the only one who could've done it.
Oh, no.
Takekuma Densuke (58)
Yadori Village Mayor
The truth is I was asked to
invite everyone by a stranger.
In addition to the notebook
I showed you at dinner,
I was also sent some money and a message
stating that inviting the four of them
would rekindle the legend of the buried
treasure and revitalize the village.
Also included were four
letters addressed to them.
They were guaranteed to come if I sent them.
Remember the extra envelope
in the letters I sent to you?
Yeah.
A letter about the cave-in sixteen years ago.
You could be lying.
I'm not lying.
The letter even specified which
hotel and rooms you should stay in.
In any case...
We'll talk once the police arrive.
Until then, you'll be staying in your rooms.
And I'll take anything you have that
can make noise like your phones.
Someone may have produced that eerie cry
using some kind of device.
W-Wait a minute.
If everyone's rooms were specified
like the mayor said...
Maybe there's something in the rooms.
Our room was used by the foreigner
who died in the cave-in.
I wish someone would switch rooms with us.
Is that true?
Yes. The notebook he used to practice
hiragana was in the desk drawer.
There were other notebooks in there, too.
How interesting.
I'd be willing to swap rooms with you.
No.
I'll stay in the room.
I can't allow the women to be frightened.
Then can I move to a room on the third floor?
I don't mind, but don't set one
foot outside of your rooms.
If you do, I'll assume you're the murderer.
I see, I see.
We can see all their rooms from here.
And if the monster appears again,
we'll be able to chase it off.
Why are you here, anyway?
You should be staying in your room.
You can let us handle this.
Absolutely not. I may
have been told to do it,
but I'm the one who invited everyone here.
As the mayor, I must
ensure everyone's safety.
Whatever. As long as you're
here, why don't you tell us?
Tell you what?
Why you invited each of them.
Wasn't it written in the
letter from the stranger?
Yes.
The archaeologist Tanzawa
Michiki-san is knowledgeable
about the geology of Shizuoka,
and once examined this area in the past.
He's excavated ruins not just in
Shizuoka but all over the country.
Until a few years ago,
he was famous as a commentator
on TV programs on ruins.
Although he disappeared
completely after some pottery
he unearthed was suspected of being fake.
What about the author woman?
You mean you don't know who Masuko Fumie is?
She's famous for her mysterious
stories featuring monsters.
As an author of such books, naturally she's
knowledgeable about Japanese monsters.
When filming TV adaptations of her work,
she's had shooting locations changed
and sets repainted because
they didn't match her vision.
Apparently she graduated from art school,
so I can see why it's so important to her.
That has nothing to do with
Tokugawa's buried treasure.
Th-The letters suggested using
the nue to revitalize the town,
if the buried treasure wouldn't work.
What?
Yeah, but...
The documentary reporter isn't famous, is he?
That's right.
The murdered Someji Yasukatsu-san
was a historian knowledgeable about
Tokugawa's buried treasure, though.
The letter simply stated
that Tsurumi Hajime-san
is a fledgling reporter who travels
across the country for monster stories.
I don't know why he was invited either.
But why weren't the survivors
of the cave-in invited?
We would've been able to ask
them more about the incident.
A-Apparently, they all disappeared
after the accident.
We don't even know their names.
Then why did you invite Heiji-niichan?
The letter actually requested that I invite
the great detective Mori Kogoro-san,
but I used some of the
money to repair the hotel.
At first I thought about inviting
Kudo Shinichi-sama of Tokyo,
but I couldn't get in touch with him, so
I invited Hattori-sama of Osaka instead.
So I'm here because the old
man and you couldn't make it?
Sorry.
Your letter said I could
bring my female friends.
Was that in the letter
from the stranger, too?
Yes.
The letter said to invite Detective
Mori's daughter as well.
It would be better for the village's
promotional video to have a young girl in it.
That worked out, I guess.
Then there're the trees in front of the hotel.
Why is only the tree on the left
edge different from the others?
What?
Look. The other trees in front of
the hotel all have pointed tops,
but just one of them is different.
Who knows?
I haven't been here in a while.
What is this?
There's something that looks like
cloth on the end of this burnt stick.
Was this always in front of the hotel?
Who knows?
Hey!
Keep it down.
S-Sorry.
I was going to take a nap
before the police arrived,
but I can't sleep through
all the noise you're making!
I don't mind.
After all, I'm a talent-less reporter,
who was invited along with
all you famous people.
I won't be able to write a good
article unless I sacrifice sleep
to keep my eyes and ears open.
Besides, there's no telling
when the monster will appear.
It's that cry again.
Where's it coming from?
What?
Where'd that fire come from?
I don't know. It suddenly ignited.
It's the nue.
The monster is back!
Wh-What was that scream?
It sounded like Tanzawa-san
from the room upstairs.
That's the room we were
originally staying in.
The left end of the third floor.
Hey, wait.
You won't be able to get
in without the spare key.
Hey, Tanzawa-san! What happened?
Hey, Tanzawa-san!
Move, please.
I-I'll unlock the door.
Tanzawa-san, we're coming in.
It's no use. He's already dead.
Two red spots under his chin.
Was he bitten by a snake?
Is that the only spare key to this room?
Y-Yes.
Which means this is a locked room.
Hey, don't tell me
the nue really exists.
Thank you for waiting, everyone.
I'm Yokomizo Sango of the Shizuoka Police.
According to the call we received,
apparently you saw a giant monster.
But now that I'm here, it's all right.
I'll protect you from said monster.
Two people are already dead, though.
I'm sure it's some kind of trick,
but why don't you tell us what you
saw when you witnessed the monster?
We heard an eerie cry,
and the grass in front
of the hotel caught fire.
When we went outside, from behind the wall...
...a four-legged monster appeared.
It was so big, it reached
the second-story windows.
I see. And?
Did you see a thin string above the monster?
We didn't see anything like that.
Yeah.
I see.
Not only that, but it bit
the sign in front of it,
pulled it out of the ground,
and walked away with it.
It pulled out the sign
and walked away with it?
Was that sign about thirty centimeters tall?
This is the sign.
What?
See? There are teeth marks on it.
Th-They're rather large.
We found this sign on the
ground where the monster went.
Next to the sign was a trail
of blood leading to the lake.
When we followed it,
we found the body of the
historian Someji-san.
With scratches on his back.
S-Scratches? Like from a cat?
These are the pictures we took of the body.
See how the scratches are spaced
about ten centimeters apart?
It wasn't a cat.
Y-You're right.
We told everyone to stay in their rooms
until the police arrived.
We took their phones so they couldn't
produce any sounds, just in case.
We were keeping watch over the area
with the mayor where the monster appeared.
When we heard the cry again,
the grass we'd extinguished
earlier suddenly caught fire,
and it kept spreading and spreading.
While we were standing
in shock, we heard the dying cry
of archaeologist Tanzawa-san from
the room on the end of the third floor.
When we went to his room,
we found him poisoned to
death in a locked room.
This time with marks under his chin
as though he'd been bitten by a snake.
C-Come to think of it,
we saw the monster's tail when it left.
Yeah.
It looked like a snake, right?
Its tail was a snake?
Officer, you've heard
of the nue, haven't you?
It has the head of a monkey,
the body of a raccoon dog,
the legs of a tiger, and its tail is a snake.
Th-The nue?
It's a legendary monster that appears with
an eerie cry and a cloud of black smoke.
L-Legendary?
You haven't heard of it?
Calm down, everyone.
You make it sound as though
the monster was resurrected.
But there was once a monster known as the nue
that existed in the Kurogane Forest.
What?
There was an eyewitness report of a nue
sixteen years ago.
Y-Yes...
The foreigner on the excavation
team was caught in a cave-in
and wrote the word "nue" before he died.
I've already told them about—
See? It does exist.
The nue's been hiding in the
forest for sixteen years.
Kudo, this guy's no different
from that incompetent Gunma cop.
Yeah.
In any case, the police will protect you.
You should gather in a
single room and wait there.
I will contact my superiors to ask
if we can mobilize the self-defense force.
Seriously?!
Anyway, I thought it was going
to rain, but it hasn't yet.
What? Why?
The second time the grass caught
fire, a raindrop fell on my cheek.
I thought I heard
the sound of a carbonated
beverage being opened, too.
A carbonated beverage?
It wasn't me.
I did request white wine and soda water
so I could mix them,
but if I'd poured it from my window,
the mayor wouldn't have been
the only one who got wet.
Besides, unlike him, I have more class
than to drink on the window sill.
Sorry I'm so low-class.
I was abandoned by my
parents when I was a kid.
I wasn't raised properly.
The water wasn't mine either.
Even if I shook my cola as hard as I could,
it wouldn't have reached the mayor.
Heiji-niichan.
Huh?
Look.
There are small round white
objects all over the grass.
If this is what I think it is,
then even without matches or a lighter...
...they could've started a fire.
Which leaves the trick
behind the giant monster...
...and poisoning in the locked room.
Let's start with the locked room.
The victim Tanzawa-san moved
into the third floor room
we were originally staying in, right?
Yeah.
Based on the positions of their rooms,
Masuko-san in the room directly
below his is the most suspicious.
When Tanzawa-san was surprised by the fire
and stuck his head out of the window,
she could've thrust a long stick with
poisoned needles on the end upwards.
For some reason only one side of
the window in that room would open,
so she could've predicted
where he'd stick his head out.
But when we collected Masuko-san's phone,
we examined the room
and didn't find any sticks.
Yeah.
The only objects of interest in the room
were the two one liter bottles of soda water,
one bottle of white wine, one glass, and the
sommelier knife she requested from the mayor.
Inside Masuko-san's bag were writing
implements like ball point pens,
paper tape, a sewing set, and a notebook.
What about the documentary writer?
When Tanzawa-san moved into our room,
he moved right next door to the
third floor room on the end.
Maybe only one side of
Tanzawa-san's window opened
so it wouldn't block him from shooting
a poisoned blow dart at him.
But Tsurumi-san and Tanzawa-san's
windows were ten meters apart
with one window between them.
Plus he couldn't pierce the
bottom of his chin from the side.
And Tsurumi-san didn't have blow darts.
Yeah.
In his room we found
three 500 milliliter bottles of cola,
two bags of potato chips,
a folding knife, a selfie stick,
cigarettes and a lighter,
and the plastic model he said
he bought to pass the time.
He even bought glue.
He didn't have anything that he
could've used to poison someone.
Which leaves the mayor.
All he had was a deck brush.
What are you doing over there?
The police told you to stay inside the room.
Yeah, but we're worried about the dog.
When the nue's cry sounded earlier,
we heard him barking and
scratching at the wall.
We thought he was hungry
and wanted to get out,
so we made him dinner in the
kitchen and brought it to him.
But he won't eat.
Come to think of it, when we
first heard the nue's cry...
He was barking then, too.
But when the monster appeared...
...he wasn't barking.
I see.
So that's how it is.
And the only one who could've done it...
...was that person.
Episode Preview
We're going to summon...
...that monster again.
That can't be—
It's the nue's cry.
Heiji, where are you? Help!
Conan and Heiji's Nue Legend
(Resolution Arc)
The next episode of Conan is "Conan and
Heiji's Nue Legend, Resolution Arc!"
Plastic Bottle
Next Conan's hint!
A plastic bottle!
The nue's so scary!
Don't miss the next episode.
Where's the self-defense force?
Wait and see.
We'll extinguish the flames of this case.