Invited by Hattori Heiji and Toyama Kazuha,
Ran and I came to Yadori Village in Shizuoka
to help unearth Tokugawa's buried treasure.
But that night, the legendary
monster known as the Nue appeared,
and Someji Yasukatsu-san was murdered.
Tanzawa Michiki-san was also
murdered in his hotel room.
And...
What are you doing over there?
The police told you to stay inside the room.
Yeah, but we're worried about the dog.
When the nue's cry sounded earlier,
we heard him barking and
scratching at the wall.
Come to think of it, when we
first heard the nue's cry...
He was barking then, too.
But when the monster appeared...
He wasn't barking.
I see.
So that's how it is.
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
After solving the mystery of the
Nue, what will Heiji say to Kazuha?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Conan and Heiji's Nue Legend
(Resolution Arc)
"Conan and Heiji's Nue
Legend, Resolution Arc!"
Heiji.
We brought what you asked for.
Three sets of sheets from an
unused room, a deck brush,
a mop, and a toolbox.
Then there's a cardboard box and the
spray used to remodel the hotel.
We also borrowed a permanent marker
and sewing set from Masuko-san,
and some glue and a knife from Tsurumi-san.
Good work.
Thanks.
Oh, right.
In the desk drawer of the
room Ran and I moved into
there was an old photo.
Isn't that the excavation
team from sixteen years ago?
Yeah.
And it may be our imagination,
but the foreigner in the middle of the photo
kind of looks like Tsurumi-san.
Tsurumi Hajime (22)
Documentary Writer
You're right.
So, what are you going to
make with all this stuff?
Isn't it obvious?
We're going to summon...
...that monster again.
What?!
What is Heiji thinking?
This doesn't feel romantic at all.
Yeah.
Ow.
Hurry up, Kudo.
Otherwise the sun will rise.
Yeah, the trick's too obvious
unless it's done at night.
Huh?
Oh, yeah. You're right.
Hey, there isn't some other reason you
don't want the sun to rise yet, is there?
N-Not especially.
Sheesh.
What's wrong with you?
You woke me up while I was fast asleep.
It's only four in the morning.
But Hattori-sama asked me to gather
everyone in front of the hotel...
Takekuma Densuke (58)
Yadori Village Mayor
...because he discovered
the identity of the nue.
The identity of the nue?
Is that true?!
Come to think of it, the forensics
team and my men were sneaking around.
Masuko Fumie (46)
Author
Without telling you what they were doing?
What? Yes.
I-Isn't that...?
It's the same.
Stay Out
Danger!
It's burning just like it was
when the monster appeared.
Th-There's even a sign there.
Wh-Wh-What is this eerie sound?
Th-This is it.
It's the nue's cry.
Heiji, where are you?! Help!
I'm right here.
What? Where's here?
Right here.
What?
I'm right here.
H-Heiji, you...g-grew?
No, dummy. Come over here
and take a closer look.
B-But standing in front of you...
Th-There's a black monster...
Oh, this isn't a monster.
Take a look.
It's an ordinary dog wearing a bear skin.
What?
I found this skin in the back of a closet.
Look. There's even a snake
tail attached to it.
In any case, come over here.
Then you'll understand.
Come over there?
T-Try not to step on us.
Huh?
What?
No way. What is this?
What's going on?
We sewed some sheets together,
drew some windows on them
in extreme perspective,
and hung it from the window.
For the parts sticking out, we stuck
pieces of cardboard to the sheets
and spray painted them the
same color as the wall.
And since that tree's in the
way, you can't see the building.
When there's smoke in the air, you
can't see the trees behind us.
On top of that, in the darkness of
night, it's no wonder we were fooled.
Officers, you can put out the fire now.
Thanks.
So the forensics team and my men
were secretly helping him
put together this trick.
The finishing touch is this sign.
They trained the dog to
carry away this little sign
when he heard the nue's cry,
and left the real sign with giant teeth marks
next to Someji-san's body,
so it'd look like a giant
monster killed Someji-san
and disappeared, leaving the sign behind.
Remember how this dog barked
when he heard the nue's cry?
He was barking because he wanted
to go to the sign, but couldn't.
The nue's cry could have
been produced the first
or second time using a
cell phone or something...
But we heard its cry when
Tanzawa-san was poisoned, too.
Hadn't you taken everything we
could've used to make any sound then?
How did they create that cry?
It's this sound, right?
If you fill a wineglass with water
and trace the edge of the
glass with a moist finger...
I've seen that on TV before.
In other words,
the only person who could've
hung the cloth painted
with windows from that
spot and made that sound
is the person staying in that room
on the second floor who asked
for wine to be sent to their room.
It was you,
Masuko Fumie-san.
As an art school graduate,
you'd be able to draw realistic
looking windows on the cloth.
And when we chased the monster
around the back of the hotel,
since this area was burning,
you could've erased the evidence
by setting the cloth on fire.
We did find its burnt remains, though.
But when did she paint
those windows on the cloth?
She probably painted them beforehand
and hid it in this room.
Beforehand?
Someone was coming here occasionally
to feed the dog, right?
It was probably Masuko-san.
She had to train the dog to pull
the sign out of the ground, too.
Masuko-san may have planted this tree
for the sake of this trick, too.
B-But the second time the grass
caught fire, she was in her room.
How did she start the fire?
Using metallic sodium.
What? Metallic sodium?
If you wrap it in something flammable
like paper or grass and pour water on it,
it becomes extremely hot and catches fire.
When we put out the first
fire, Masuko-san had a bucket.
If she had the sodium in the bucket,
she could have faked putting out the fire and
strewn it over the grass in front of the hotel.
B-But how did she pour water on it?
You said it yourself, Mr. Mayor.
When the grass caught fire,
you heard the sound of a carbonated
beverage being opened.
She opened a hole in the wine cork
and stuck a ball point pen
tube emptied of ink in it.
Then she wrapped tape around the cork
so it would fit perfectly
in the soda water bottle.
By shaking the bottle, she was able
to shoot water at a distant target.
Hah, shoot water at a distant target?
That can't be—
What?
See?
You're right.
Wow.
I was able to make the
same thing using the spare
bottle of soda water and
wine cork the mayor bought.
And I used the same tape
and pen Masuko-san had.
Furthermore, if you point the bottle
upwards and release your finger...
See? It easily reaches the window above.
The window above?
Then Tanzawa-san was poisoned using...
That's right.
By attaching a two-pronged
poison dart to the cork
and shaking the bottle while holding
it in place with her finger,
she was able to poison Tanzawa-san
by releasing her finger
when he stuck his head out the window.
And by attaching a string to the poison
dart, she was able to quickly retrieve it.
In other words, here's what you did.
After hanging the cloth painted with
windows from your second story room,
you invited Someji-san outside with a
letter or something and murdered him.
You cut claw marks into his back,
left the sign with large
teeth marks next to the body,
switched the real sign
out for the little one,
poured kerosene over the grass in front
of the hotel, and set it on fire.
When everyone came outside,
you used your phone to produce the nue's cry,
calling this dog wearing the bear skin,
who took the sign just like you trained him,
went around the back of the
hotel, and headed back inside.
While pretending to put out the fire, you
scattered metallic sodium in front of the hotel
and sprayed water on it
without spraying it on us,
while we were keeping watch outside,
to ignite the metallic sodium.
When Tanzawa-san stuck his head out
of his window to look at the fire,
you poisoned him using the dart.
The first man was killed by a
tiger, and the second by a snake.
You made it seem as though both of
them had been killed by the nue.
You no doubt threw the knife you
used to kill Someji-san in the lake,
but if forensics hasn't found the
dart you used to kill Tanzawa-san,
it's probably still inside
the pens you have on you.
You could've made a two-pronged dart
by tying sewing needles to a toothpick.
You're lucky the needles
struck Tanzawa-san's chin.
It wasn't luck.
What?
It was 100%.
I practiced countless
times so I could hit him,
no matter where he stuck his head out.
Y-You admit to killing them?
B-But why them?
Because they let him die.
Member of the excavation
team and my husband,
Charles Abel.
W-Were they on the excavation team, too?
Yes.
When the cave-in occurred,
they left my husband behind
and fled even though he was still alive.
But they couldn't have helped it.
He wrote the name of a
monster on a piece of paper.
It's not nue.
It's "tetsuno" (metal), isn't it?
What?
Charles was trying to write
that he found a metal hairpin,
but as a foreigner he'd
never seen one before.
After writing the word "metal,"
he meant to show the team the hairpin
and the piece of paper
to ask them what it was.
Since he wrote the word slowly
using a permanent marker,
the ink bled through,
making the team think he
wrote "n-u-e" instead.
I see.
You used that misunderstanding
to bring them here.
You wrote in your letter that Charles
may have found metal jars instead.
Metal jars?
Did you forget?
"In the morning and evening sun, two thousand
jars glitter with a thousand golden coins"
is how the nursery song goes.
A jar containing a thousand golden
coins would make a fine treasure.
And the two of them came,
drawn by that possibility,
without realizing they'd be murdered.
Yes.
I planned to forgive them
if they didn't come,
but they shamelessly came like
the miserable wretches they are.
You invited a detective so
he'd testify that the monster
actually exists and a young woman
so she'd be frightened when
she found the creepy notebook
the foreigner used to practice his hiragana.
You predicted that Tanzawa-san
would offer to trade rooms
with the girl when she became frightened.
A room containing Charles' possessions
may have held some clue to the metal jars.
Th-Then why'd she invite me
when I had nothing to do with any of this?
Probably because Masuko-san's your mother.
What?
She wanted her son to watch
as she avenged his father.
The dog probably likes you
because he sees his dead owner in you.
I-Is this true?
You idiot. Of course not.
I invited you for fun
after reading one of your awful articles.
So you'd better write a
better one this time.
About the idiot woman who got
a taste of her own medicine
when she tried to use a monster legend.
It's just like the legend.
What?
According to one theory,
the nue was the mother of Minamoto Yorimasa,
who transformed into the beast
so her son could slay it.
Huh?
Is that you, Ran-san and Conan-kun?
Uh, yes.
There was a major case.
Where's Mori-san?
Where are you? Where are you, Mori-san?
He's not here.
You just noticed?
Hey, Conan-kun.
Huh?
Have you seen Kazuha-chan?
She headed towards Kurogane
Lake with Heiji-niichan.
But I think you should
leave them alone for now.
"Watch how I do things."
He said something like that.
What?
Why did you bring me here, Heiji?
If you're planning to show me another
weird monster, give me a break.
No, idiot.
I'll only say it once, so listen closely.
Listen, Kazuha.
Okay.
The morning sun turned the
surface of the lake gold.
That's it. That's what it means.
Huh? What?
"In the morning and evening sun,
two thousand jars glitter with
a thousand golden coins."
The name Kurogane refers to the metal jars.
In other words, the lake
itself is a metal jar.
When the light from the rising and setting
sun strikes the lake, it turns gold,
and the waves look like coins
scattered across the surface.
Really?
But that's not what I came to talk about.
Huh?
I didn't realize it until the
incident at the Ebisu Bridge,
but it seems I...
have...
Evacuate the civilians to a safe area!
Huh?
Wh-Wh-What?
Operation Capture the Nue begins now!
Th-The self-defense force?
Th-They actually came!
If they did come, I guess it
would be the Hamamatsu ADSF.
S-So, what were you going to say?
You were right.
I was just going to say that gruel does
taste better when you mix the egg into it.
Right?
Gruel always tastes better when you mix it.
Ran-chan!
What did Hattori-kun say?
Heiji says it tastes better
when you mix the egg in.
What?
I told you so!
Author Masuko Fumie Arrested For Murder
High School Detective Hattori
Heiji Finds The Truth!
Huh. Looks like you're
making quite the splash.
My future...
husband.
Ooka Momoji (17)
Kyoto Senshin High School
Second-Year
Episode Preview
Oh, no. What should we do?
Could something bad be happening again?
The Buddha is warning the living
that misfortune is coming.
It's nothing for a detective
to involve himself in.
What?
"The Mysterious Prophetic Buddha!"
The next episode of Conan is "The
Mysterious Prophetic Buddha!"
Tanuki
Next Conan's hint!
A tanuki!
Can I say it now?
Don't miss the next episode!
Yeah, go ahead.
Gruel can be such a cruel joke.