[OP]
Why don't you show me
Fukuhara Yuka (26)
Head Priest's Daughter
Fukuhara Masako (53)
Head Priest's Wife
this mysterious Buddha?
Okay.
It's in here.
It's the eleven-faced
Kannon inside this shrine.
And you're saying it turns to the side
or turns around entirely
without anyone touching it?
Yes.
That certainly is mysterious if it's true.
It's true.
And whenever it turns, something
bad always happens afterwards.
I see.
In any case, I'll take a look.
Thank you.
Oh, no. What should we do?
Could something bad be happening again?
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
A Buddha that turns around on
its own causes a strange case.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Mysterious Prophetic Buddha
"The Mysterious Prophetic Buddha!"
It looks like an ordinary Buddha.
You have nothing to worry about.
Even if something does happen,
I'll be here this time.
I don't even want to see your face!
Get out!
Every day you go gallivanting
around instead of working.
Fukuhara Eizen (23)
Head Priest's Son
Fukuhara Eikyo (56)
Hoto Temple Head Priest
And this time you've committed robbery!
It's pathetic!
I just borrowed it!
And it's just the easy money you
collected from your parishioners!
Don't be so self-righteous!
If you just borrowed it, then give it back!
I just have to return it, right?
Well, I don't want to see your face either!
That fool...
I'm sorry you had to see that.
That's my father and brother.
He said he gallivants around every day.
My brother went to train at the head temple
so he could follow in our father's footsteps,
but he left after less than a month.
Since then he hasn't been
going to school or working.
Instead he hangs out with a bad bunch.
Wakuda Junko (28)
Trainee Monk
This is Junko-san who's training with us.
Junko-san, this is Detective Mori-sensei,
Ran-san, and Conan-kun.
They're visiting from Tokyo.
Hello.
I am Junko.
Thank you for coming.
Junko-san, when we looked earlier,
Kannon-sama was turned around.
I hope nothing bad happens.
Indeed.
I hate to start before the head priest.
My father will eat by himself
once he's finished praying.
Go right ahead.
Junko-san, you can cook?
It's part of my training.
Junko-san is a much better cook than I am.
He certainly is.
It's nothing to be proud of.
Oh, Dad. Dad, this is Detective
Mori-sensei from Tokyo.
He's investigating the
eleven-faced Kannon for us.
The Buddha is warning the living
that misfortune is coming.
It's nothing for a detective
to involve himself in.
You should leave.
Yuka, Junko,
your wedding will be in September.
I need to perform my evening duties.
I'll join you.
That's all right.
You can discuss the wedding with Yuka.
Ran-chan and Conan-kun, eat up.
I'm sorry.
He's not a bad person, but
he can be so stubborn.
This is excellent.
We received these from our parishioners.
Conan-kun, have some.
Thanks.
Ran-neechan, what about you?
I'll put on weight if I eat this late.
You are around that age.
I used to be like you, too.
Mom, you're not going to feed him?
We have guests today.
I'll feed him later.
Do you keep animals?
No, but you'll see if you come with me later.
I wonder what it is.
So, what's the bad news Kannon-sama
has warned you about?
Last year someone who went foraging for
wild vegetables was attacked by a bear.
Yes. They survived, though.
They said there was nothing
for it to eat since there
was still snow on the ground
when it woke up from hibernation.
Before that, just after a typhoon
passed and we thought we were safe,
a house was crushed by a landslide.
Was the Buddha turned around both times?
I'll go put out your futons.
Dad, why don't you stop
drinking and eat something?
Don't worry about it. You can watch TV.
Come to think of it,
Dad's taking a long time.
Maybe he's praying extra hard
so the two of you will be happy.
Dad!
They said we could take a bath.
Are you going to take one?
Not tonight.
I told you not to drink so much.
The head priest is still praying.
This is embarrassing.
What was that?
Stay back!
Mister.
It hasn't been long since he was stabbed.
Just a few minutes.
Ran, call an ambulance and the police.
Got it!
No signs of a struggle.
Mister, look at this.
Looks like it was moved recently.
What's this cut?
Detective Hayashi (32)
Yamanashi Police
Detective Shimokawa (48)
So you were all in the same room
after the head priest left
to perform his duties?
Yes. We were all together until
the eight o'clock bell sounded.
Someone must have broken in and killed him.
We had forensics examine
the front door and windows,
but they didn't find any signs of a break-in.
I-I see.
Well, if someone entered the room,
it is unlikely that the priest would've
quietly prayed until he was stabbed.
Huh?
There's something stuck to
that golden chandelier thing.
Ow!
You're unbelievable.
How many times do I have to tell you not
to interfere with a police investigation?
It's tape.
It was stuck to the inner
left side of the canopy.
Who are you?
What are you guys doing at my house?
Identify yourself.
I live here.
Eizen!
What's wrong? Were we robbed?
Dad is... Dad is...
What's going on?
Your father has been murdered.
Eizen-san, where have you been until now?
I was with a friend.
Anyway, who are you?
Mori Kogoro. I'm a detective.
Could you tell us your friend's name?
Why should I tell you that?
Your father scolded you this afternoon.
He demanded you return the money, and
after acknowledging that, you stormed out.
If you were unable to return the money,
you'd have motive to kill your father.
D-Don't be ridiculous!
I only borrowed 300 thousand yen!
I wouldn't murder someone
over that paltry amount!
What is your friend's name?
Sakurai Manami. She's a hostess at "Romance."
I owed money after going a few times,
so I borrowed some of the money set
aside to renovate the reception hall.
The tape was stuck to the
left side of the canopy.
What's on that side?
What was that?
Conan-kun, what's wrong?
I saw an animal run away.
Oh, it's a tanuki.
Remember what we said earlier?
My mother feeds it, so it
comes to the temple at night.
Really?
It lives in the bushes along the
path leading to the waterfall.
That was a surprise.
I know, right?
It's an automatic bell striker.
Dad and Junko-san...
Sometimes they go out to meet parishioners.
What is this?
Okay, thank you.
Bye.
I was able to confirm that Eizen-san
was at "Romance" until
about thirty minutes ago.
See? I have an alibi.
How dare you suspect me.
Mister, look at this.
I found this near the tanuki's den.
I'm busy.
Conan-kun, don't bother him.
But it's important.
Come with me.
The tanuki was being fed
every night by this bell tower.
Huh?
So, what?
This bell is equipped with
an automatic bell striker.
We heard the bell ring while
we were in the dining room.
Yeah, so?
Maybe the tanuki found this
salami here and took it to its den.
Here?
That's it. So that's how it is.
Eikyo-san's murderer killed him
without entering the temple.
Alibis are meaningless in this case.
Eizen-san, even you could have killed him.
What do you mean?
Allow me to explain.
The killer placed the salami on this
side of the chain—in other words,
in the direction the hammer
moves when the bell is struck—
and passed the string through the hole.
Then they pulled the string through
the window and into the temple.
Then they passed the
string through the canopy
and taped a knife to the end of the string.
When the automatic bell striker
pushed the hammer forward,
the string was pulled off the knife,
and the knife fell.
Then the tanuki took
the salami to its den,
erasing all trace of the trick.
This method would allow anyone to kill
Eikyo-san without even being here.
That makes everyone who was at the temple
and Eizen-san a suspect.
Yes, he's right.
But...
But, Junko-san, the person
who killed Eikyo-san...
is you!
How do you know that?
Only someone who frequently
entered the temple
to prepare scriptures and
offerings could have done this.
I did it!
I did it exactly as Mori-san described.
Damn it! Why'd you kill my dad?
I'm actually engaged to someone else.
But the priest wanted me to marry Yuka-san.
At first I was hesitant,
but when I considered all he'd
done for me, I couldn't refuse.
The priest believed I'd given my consent
and chose a date for the wedding.
So it's my fault.
It's my fault for not turning Dad down.
I suspected Junko-san's feelings.
But I didn't want to upset my father.
You should've told him no!
Even if he got mad at you, you could've left!
I didn't mean to kill him.
I just wanted to scare him
and ask to end my training
because of all the bad things
happening at the temple.
So I turned the Buddha
inside the shrine around,
and moved his table to the right
so the knife wouldn't strike him.
Hey.
Kogoro-no-ojisan asked me
to do something for him.
Detective Mori did?
He wants you to drop a knife
from the same height the tape was stuck to.
Detective Mori-san asked us to do it?
Then we have to do it.
Here we go.
I knew it.
It's impossible to kill
someone using this trick.
Mister, is this white powder left
over from dusting for prints?
No, it's not.
We examined it. It's rice powder.
Junko-san, you can tell us
the rest at the station.
Junko-san.
Are you the one who's
been turning the Buddha?
No, today was the only day I moved it.
Wait a minute.
It's true Junko-san attempted
to frighten Eikyo-san
using that trick.
But he's not the one who killed him.
What?
In fact, it's impossible to
kill someone using that method.
Even if the knife hit him, it
would only have injured him.
So who really killed him?
His wife Masako-san.
You saw Junko-san setting
up his trick, didn't you?
You planned to frame him.
Detective, what are you talking about?
There was rice powder on
the edge of the table.
After dinner,
you and Conan were the only ones who ate
the rice cakes covered in rice powder.
If the powder had been on the table before
he started praying, he would have wiped it off.
In other words, only the killer
could have put the powder there.
That's right.
I'd had enough of him.
I didn't want to see his face anymore.
That's why I killed him!
He'd always yell when
things didn't go his way.
He'd arrogantly complain
about the smallest thing.
He treated his wife and children like slaves.
I feel better now that he's gone!
Mom...
I'm sorry I got you involved in this.
I'm more worried about you.
We never discovered the secret
behind the turning Kannon-sama.
I'm sorry we couldn't help.
Oh, I figured that out when we got here.
Huh?
What?
The Buddha only turned after heavy rain
or when there was a lot of snowmelt.
The low frequency sound waves
generated by the waterfall
when the water level increased resonated
with the air inside the shrine,
slowly turning the Buddha.
Really?
You know a lot of strange things.
I called Shinichi-niichan.
He said that's probably what it was.
He should've come here and solved
the case instead of calling.
I did, though.
Episode Preview
This is the lab.
I see.
This is my robot.
I have no idea why he made that.
Who did you find suspicious?
I'd have to say Tanizaki-san.
Ishiki-kun, shut off the gas.
Horiuchi-kun, call an ambulance.
Got it.
The Mechanical Witness
The next episode of Conan
is "The Mechanical Witness!"
Mouse
Next Conan's hint!
A mouse!
First the hint was raccoon
dog, now it's mouse.
Don't miss the next episode.
Could it be animal-related?
Pay attention to next week's hint!