Authorized
Personnel Only
Kusumi Machinery
It's so cute!
Kusumi Kyoichi (50)
President of Kusumi Machinery
Try pressing the button
on the remote control.
Okay.
Wow!
Hey, wait.
Let me see that.
Suspicious person identified.
Huh?
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
At the super high tech plant downtown,
he takes on cutting-edge technology
with his detective skills.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Mechanical Witness
"The Mechanical Witness!"
I'm sorry.
It was designed as a
self-defense robot for women.
This is the lab.
I see.
Hey.
You little rat.
He's quick.
Please don't!
Huh?
This is my robot.
Tanizaki Takeshi (45)
Employee
What? Oh, sorry.
But why would you make something like that?
Horiuchi Fumika (32)
Employee
I know.
I have no idea why he made that.
Isshiki Kazuomi (25)
Employee
Maybe he made it to scare girls.
What's your problem?
Why would you use our cutting-edge
technology to create mischievous products?
And one of such poor taste, too.
I know.
I'm sorry, sir.
I need to speak to you urgently.
That's a problem.
I'm sorry, Mori-san.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Give me a minute.
Hello?
Okay.
What? Tonight?
Tonight's not good for me.
Why don't we postpone it?
You can't?
Today's the last day they'll
be making fun of me.
You just watch.
I can't.
Isn't there something you can do?
I already told you not to get
too involved in online auctions.
I can't give you any more
advances on your pay.
Who does he think he is?
I hope this company goes under.
President's Office
Sorry for making you come with me.
They'd be on their guard if it
were just the famous Mori-san.
It's fine.
So, what do you think?
At this point, who did you find suspicious?
Tanizaki-san.
Tanizaki-kun, huh?
Before coming here, I conducted
a stakeout at Myojo Technics,
where you suspect information
is being leaked to.
I saw this.
Damn it.
I felt bad for him because he was laid off.
And this is what I get for hiring him?
I'm turning him in to the police.
He'll deny it if you do.
Then what should I do?
We'll have to catch him in the act.
It was the original components
that were stolen, yes?
That's right. I have no idea how he
got them out of the plant, though.
There's a metal detector at the entrance.
Since they're for precision instruments, they'd
break if you threw them out a window.
Even from the first floor?
There are no first floor windows here.
Direct sunlight is bad for
precision instruments.
Hey, why are you dressed like that?
They say if you want to hide a leaf,
you should hide it in the forest.
I can see the entrance and stairs from here.
But why tonight?
There's an important presentation
at the other company tomorrow.
The thefts always occur the night before.
What was that?
It was just something falling.
Well, we should get going.
Okay.
Huh?
What's wrong?
Doesn't it smell like gas?
It's a gas leak!
It won't open?
It's locked from the inside.
Mori-san?
Do you have a spare key?
A spare key?
All the rooms here lock from the inside,
so we'll have to call a locksmith.
They'll never make it in time.
What's wrong?!
Help him break the door down.
O-Okay!
Isshiki-kun, shut off the gas.
Horiuchi-kun, call an ambulance.
Got it.
The gas pipe is broken.
I'm going to shut off the main.
How is he?
Call the police.
Got it.
We've determined the victim
Tanizaki-san suffocated to death.
Suffocated? It wasn't gas poisoning?
No. There were ligature marks on his neck.
He probably resisted.
We found ligature marks on the
palms of his hands as well.
We also found a 30 meter long rope
in the shrubbery beneath the window.
We're still waiting to hear from forensics,
but we believe it's the murder weapon.
He was also bleeding from
the back of his head.
Does this mean he was murdered?
That's right.
I heard something fall before
the gas alarm sounded.
You heard it as well, didn't you?
Yes.
I heard it.
Judging by the footprints on the
floor and the broken gas pipe,
their fight must have been rather violent.
By the way, we found this among the
objects in Tanizaki-san's pockets.
Do you know what it is?
That's a new robot part
our company is developing.
He must have been stealing—
No, strictly speaking,
he was helping someone else steal it.
What do you mean?
He locked the door from the
inside so no one could enter,
and invited a non-employee
into the storeroom.
However, there was a problem,
and Tanizaki-san was murdered.
He betrayed us. He got what he deserved.
Who is this non-employee?
A man named Makita.
He works for Myojo Technics.
Check it out.
Yes, sir.
Could you tell us where you
were when the murder occurred?
I was in my office on the third floor.
I was in the lab on this floor.
I left work at my regular time,
but I realized I had forgotten
something and returned to get it.
On your way back, did you spot
any suspicious figures outside?
No, I don't think so.
Does that mean the killer
broke in from the outside?
Well, the doors were locked.
But the windows were open.
We may be able to solve this
case sooner than expected.
Impressive, Mori-kun.
I hope he's right.
That's the crime scene.
The president's office.
What's that?
This isn't an ordinary stain.
Is this...?
Come to think of it...
This is my robot.
Today's the last day they'll
be making fun of me.
You just watch.
I see.
So that's how it is.
Spare
Prototype Components
What? Makita is innocent?
According to Takagi-kun's report,
Makita-san belongs to the
general affairs department
that has nothing to do with
technological development.
Surely even the general affairs department
would've wanted the information.
On top of that, he has an alibi.
What? I'll prove his alibi is—
Huh?
Hey!
Mori-kun!
Inspector, I've solved the mystery.
Call everyone here.
What? Got it.
Mori-san.
I heard you identified the culprit.
Yes.
By culprit you mean murderer, right?
Earlier you said Tanizaki-san was
responsible for the leaked information.
That's actually not the case.
What?
Tanizaki-san was attempting
to catch the leak.
What?
Tanizaki-san's mouse robot was
actually a security device.
No way.
What?
It's a rather well made robot.
It can identify the culprit
using its sensors.
That's impossible!
An AI can't identify a culprit!
She's right. Is this a joke?
But it can.
It's you, isn't it?
Isshiki Kazuomi-san.
This is ridiculous.
Mori-san, you made it do that.
No, I didn't.
The robot's sensors responded
to something stuck to your shoe.
Huh? What's on my shoe?
The ink on your toe.
I'm back!
What's going on?
Isshiki-san, didn't you notice?
The same thing happened to you
when you snuck into the room.
I-I got this at home.
You keep the special ink these
sensors respond to at home?
Tanizaki-san designed the robot,
so the culprit couldn't
explain his way out of it.
Fine. I admit it.
I'm the one who stole the information.
Did you give the stolen information
to Makita-san of Myojo Technics?
No, it was some guy named Hiraguchi
from their R&D department.
I did it for the money.
He did it for his career.
Then why did Tanizaki-kun meet with them?
According to Makita-san, he asked about
the date of their next presentation.
He needed to know so he could
set a trap for the leak.
That's why I said we should
postpone it, but...
Damn it!
But I didn't kill him!
I did hit him when we got into a
fight, but I didn't strangle him.
It's true.
Then who did?
Probably one of those two.
What?
I was outside.
I would've seen the culprit
flee if they were an outsider.
But I didn't see anyone.
Yeah, but that doesn't mean we—
She hated Tanizaki.
I wouldn't kill him just
because I didn't like him.
Then it was the president.
You thought Tanizaki was the leak
and killed him for his betrayal.
I-I wouldn't do that.
In any case, Mori-san, tell us who did it.
Very well.
Allow me to explain the course of events.
Before leaving the office, Isshiki-san
hid the components in this room.
He chose this room because it's
not normally used by anyone.
After unlocking the windows so
he could enter from the outside,
he got a rope to hang out of the room.
What did he attach the rope to?
There's nothing on the
outside wall to tie it to.
He tied it to the gas pipe inside the room.
What?
After tying the rope around the gas pipe,
he passed the ends through the gaps
between the ventilation fan
above the water heater.
That's why he needed 30 meters of rope.
By pulling on one end
of the rope from below,
he could retrieve the rope,
allowing him to commit countless thefts
without leaving any evidence behind.
Once everything was ready,
Isshiki-san left the office.
He secretly returned and
waited beneath the window.
He waited for the right
moment to climb the wall
and entered the room through
the window he left unlocked.
Isshiki-san didn't notice the robot
because he was surprised
by something else:
Tanizaki-san was in the room.
Knowing the theft would happen tonight since
the presentation was scheduled for tomorrow,
Tanizaki-san found the hidden
components and hid in the room.
He locked the room so the
thief couldn't escape.
Then Tanizaki-san and
Isshiki-san got into a fight.
He began bleeding from his
head when he was struck.
Disturbed by this,
Isshiki-san fled from the room.
That's when the gas pipe,
that had supported the rope
so many times before broke from the strain.
Isshiki-san nearly fell.
But miraculously, he was saved.
Upon reaching the ground,
Isshiki-san reeled in the rope
and hid it in the shrubbery.
He returned to the office
because he was worried about Tanizaki-san.
That's exactly right.
I had no idea there was a
murderer in the office, though.
What trick did you use?
What was the weapon?
Huh?
Isshiki-san.
What?
Did you not wonder why you stopped falling?
Why?
Your fall was stopped because
Tanizaki-san grabbed the rope.
However, he was unable to hold your weight.
The rope became tangled
around Tanizaki-san's neck.
And he was raised off the floor.
Y-You're lying!
Unfortunately, it's true.
The footprints on the floor.
The rust on the water heater
and Tanizaki-san's back.
And more than anything, the
blood on the fan proves it.
Isshiki-san, your series of
thefts took Tanizaki-san's life.
Forgive me!
Forgive me.
Forgive me...
It's hard to believe that's a robot.
It even feels like the real thing.
What? Then what about the one on my head?
Idiot.
Who are you calling stupid?
I'm the famous detective Mori Kogoro!
Then you should've noticed.
Episode Preview
You're right. You have a bump.
I thought I could find that guy
and turn him in to the police.
Of course we'll help.
Ouch...
Damn.
What am I doing here?
You don't even remember your own name?
Not at all.
Are you a wanted robber?
A Pair of Crossing Fates
The next episode of Conan is
"A Pair of Crossing Fates!"
Next Conan's hint!
Genta
Genta!
Am I the star?
Don't miss the next episode.
Genta, you're the hint.
Then it's next Genta's hint.