Koda Yoshi (77)
Old Woman
Tch. Just a souvenir coin.
Th-Thief!
I-I'm being robbed! Someone help!
The smell stopped.
Let's see...
Move, rice ball head!
Ouch...
Huh? A bump?
You jerk!
You're not getting away! Stop!
Stop, you violent jerk!
Stop!
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
A star-crossed fate descends upon a
thief that becomes entangled with Genta.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
A Pair of Crossing Fates
"A Pair of Crossing Fates!"
You're right. You have a bump.
It looks painful.
I thought I could find that guy
and turn him in to the police.
Of course we'll help.
So, why were you walking around in Oku-Beika?
That's pretty far from Beika City.
Well...
We should find the robber
first before he gets away.
You're right.
You only saw him from behind, right?
Yeah. He was wearing a red jacket and jeans.
That's not much to go on.
Let's start by splitting
up and canvassing the area.
Wait just a minute!
"Violent man in a red jacket"
is an inconvenient name.
Let's give him our own name.
Our own name?
Does he need one?
I think Gonbei would be a good name.
After all, "The Nameless Gonbei"
is a term for an unknown man.
Gonbei, huh?
Why don't we call him "Gonta" since
he's the Gonbei who pushed Genta?
You're starting to sound like the professor.
Nice!
Impressive, Haibara-san.
That's a fantastic name.
Since he's the Gonbei who
pushed Genta, he's Gonta.
Fantastic.
That sounds like something
the professor would say.
He's not making fun of me, is he?
Probably not.
Ouch...
That's right. I fell from there.
Tch.
It's this guy's fault.
In any case, I need to get out of here.
Wait. Nobody's seen my face.
If I change my clothes...
Heave.
"I didn't do it! He must've changed
my clothes while I was unconscious!"
"You think the police would
buy an excuse like that?"
Right?
How did you guys do?
Nothing.
No one's seen him.
I got nothing.
Damn it. Where did that violent man go?
It's Gonta.
Oh, right.
Hey, kids!
What are you doing here?
Have you seen a suspicious man?
One wearing a red jacket and jeans.
Huh?
He's a robber who broke into the
home of Koda-san who lives up there.
He was a robber.
Yeah.
"He?"
Have you seen him?
Well, no. I didn't see his face.
He probably pushed Genta out of
the way while he was fleeing.
Pushed you?
Yeah.
See? I hit my head and got this bump.
So I thought I'd catch him and
turn him in to the police.
Understood.
Takagi-san, the security
cameras around the station
didn't capture our suspect.
I see.
Then he could still be around here.
Let's go.
Got it.
So he wasn't just a violent man.
Gonta's a heinous criminal.
Yeah.
We must do what we can to capture him.
What are you going to do?
Yeah!
They're getting pretty excited.
Well, it sounds like he was acting alone.
If it comes down to it, I'll use this.
Haibara-san, Conan-kun. Let's go.
O-Okay.
Ouch...
Damn. Where am I?
What am I doing here?
Who am I?
Do I have some ID or a license?
Anything?
Wh-Why do I have this?
Excuse me.
Do you know who I am?
What?
I can't remember who I am.
You don't even remember your own name?
Not at all.
A red jacket and jeans.
Are you the wanted robber?
I-I'm not a robber.
Could you answer a few questions?
No! I don't want to be arrested!
Penal Code Article 95
Obstructing Performance of Public Duty
Stop!
Huh?
It's him!
We found Gonta!
That's him!
That's Gonta!
What are you doing?
You can't just enter a man's house!
Uh, actually...
Penal Code Article 130
Trespassing
Penal Code Article 261
Damage to Property
Railway Operation Act
Entering a Restricted Area
Why would I rob someone?
I can't remember anything.
But if they catch me, I'll be thrown in jail.
My car!
Th-Thief!
I need to run.
Penal Code Article 235
Larceny
It's broken?
My bike!
Th-Thief!
I need to run!
Penal Code Article 236
Mugging
So the man pushed you and stole your bike?
Yeah.
First a car, then a bike.
He's a really bad guy.
Indeed.
If we search randomly,
we'll never get anywhere.
We might find something if we
go to the house that was robbed.
Like a clue to Gonta's identity.
Looks like something's bothering you.
The cop said Gonta seems to
be suffering from amnesia.
We may be able to solve that mystery
if we go to the crime scene.
Was the thief really alone?
That's right.
He suddenly hit me from behind.
When I came to,
he was stealing my space
museum souvenir coin.
The crime scene shows signs
that two men entered.
Genta, you only saw one guy, right?
Yeah.
The police must be confused.
Detective Takagi.
Hey.
I'm here to report to the inspector.
Huh?
The old man?
Ujihara Masuzo (68)
Financier
You know him?
Ujihara Masuzo.
He's a financier who works near the station.
Rumor is he sends bad men after people
who can't pay off their debts.
He's the very picture of an evil man.
Let's trace Gonta's steps.
After knocking the woman
unconscious, he fled the house.
He pushed me down here.
And you lost sight of him here.
Huh?
What is it?
It looks like someone fell down this hill.
I've got it.
Gonta failed to make this
turn and accidentally fell.
Then he hit his head and lost his memory.
Let's head down there.
Looks like you're right.
Huh? There are two trails.
Two men fell?
You're right!
Someone else got involved.
When Gonta rounded the corner,
he ran into someone, and they fell together.
But if that's true, then...
The person who got involved would
naturally report it to the police.
But Detective Takagi didn't
mention anything like that.
Yeah. Why didn't they report it?
That's it! He doesn't know what happened
to him because he lost his memory.
You're wrong, Conan-kun.
It wasn't the bystander who got
involved who lost his memory.
It was Gonta.
Edogawa-kun, do you mean...?
Yeah.
Come to think of it, I thought
something seemed strange.
His clothes were strangely baggy.
Hey, Genta.
Are you sure the man who
pushed you was that Gonta?
Huh? Now that you mention it...
I have a feeling he was a little bigger.
That settles it.
They switched places after falling
here by changing clothes.
In other words, the Gonta
we've been chasing...
Isn't the robber who pushed me.
But the bystander who got involved.
But he believes he's the robber
and is running from the police.
Even though he hadn't done anything wrong.
Penal Code Article 95
Obstructing Performance of Public Duty
Penal Code Article 130
Trespassing
Penal Code Article 261
Damage to Property
Railway Operation Act
Entering a Restricted Area
Penal Code Article 235
Larceny
Penal Code Article 236
Mugging
But he's been doing bad things to get away.
Let's head back to Beika City.
Beika City?
To see Ujihara, right?
Yeah.
If he sent the actual thief to rob the house,
then it explains why he
appeared at the crime scene.
To see how it went.
Or if he's been exposed as the mastermind.
It's certainly a possibility.
If we question him, we'll be
able to find the real culprit.
Ujihara Finance
Under Inspection
Who are those kids?
Sixth floor, huh?
How are we gonna investigate him?
It's that rice ball kid.
Could it be?
Conan-kun?
Detective Takagi.
What are you kids doing here?
What are you doing?
I'm here to talk to Ujihara Masuzo.
I'm going to show him this police sketch.
Actually...
U-Um, Detective Takagi...
That man is...
The elevators are closed, so...
He's not the robber.
Wait. Wait!
I was worried for nothing.
You know this man, don't you, Ujihara-san?
I don't know him.
But the moment you saw this drawing, you—
Wait. Wait a minute.
Huh?
Something's not right.
What do you mean?
This man is an innocent bystander
who got caught up in the robbery.
Caught up?
But Ujihara reacted to his police sketch.
It doesn't make sense.
Wait a minute.
Inspector Megure said...
So that's how it is!
Huh?
Yes?
I'd like to talk to you about
the robbery in Oku-Beika.
Looks like it was him.
You remember me, don't you?
You're not getting away!
Stop!
How dare you push me?!
Hello?
Takagi-san? We've captured the suspect.
Koda
This is the robber I saw.
He was wearing that red jacket and jeans.
Actually, that's not him.
It's not?
It's actually rather complicated.
Torimaru Shinya-kun.
I happened to hear about Ujihara
the moneylender yesterday.
There's a woman named Koda in Oku-Beika.
Ujihara Finance
If you're having trouble finding
the money, go make some there.
Y-You want me to rob her?
It'll be easy. She's an
old woman living alone.
I thought it sounded good,
so I broke into this house.
But the old woman was unconscious, and
the whole house had been searched.
But while I was conducting my own search...
Tch. Just a souvenir coin.
Th-Thief!
I-I'm being robbed! Someone help!
The smell stopped.
Let's see...
Move, rice ball head!
Stop!
Ouch...
That's right. I fell from there.
Tch.
It's this guy's fault.
In any case, I need to get out of here.
Wait. Nobody's seen my face.
If I change my clothes...
Heave.
I thought I'd gotten away
with it by framing him.
So I was knocked unconscious
by two different robbers?
They weren't working together,
but two men did indeed break in.
I-Inspector, does that mean he's...?
So even though I hadn't robbed anyone,
I committed one crime after
another while trying to get away?
I don't believe it!
Torimaru-san, was this the voice you
heard at Ujihara Finance yesterday?
Huh?
What am I going to do?
Y-You want me to rob her?
That's right! He's the one who
Ujihara was threatening yesterday!
Me?
What?
Conan-kun, looks like you were right.
If Ujihara hadn't put him up to it,
he wouldn't have reacted like that.
Which means...
He broke into the house with the intention of
robbing it and knocked Koda-san unconscious.
He was searching the house
when you broke in, and ran.
While he was nursing the ankle he twisted
while running, you ran into him.
So that's what happened.
That explains everything.
All that's left is to arrest
Ujihara Masuzo for incitement.
And that wraps up this robbery case.
So I was a robber after all.
Gonta-san must've felt like he
had to after being threatened.
Huh? My name's Gonta?
Oh, that's just the name we gave you.
That's it! I'm Gonta!
Gonno Taro!
Gonno Taro?
Gonno Taro
People have called me
Gonta since I was a kid.
Gonta
I remember everything now.
I was in despair after the company
I was working at shut down.
But yesterday...
Ujihara Finance
Y-You want me to rob her?
I was shocked, but...
Being a thief sounds exciting.
That's why I broke in.
I was burning with new purpose.
He's even worse than I am.
Take these two away!
Yes, sir!
Come to think of it, why were you
walking around here, Genta-kun?
Yeah, we haven't heard the
answer to that question yet.
I was... Huh?
I can't remember.
Genta-kun, could it be?
When you were pushed and hit your head...
Yeah, right.
I can't remember.
Japan's Best Eel Bowls
This Way
What was it?
What? Don't ask us.
Episode Preview
Look closely.
What was that about?
Tada.
Wait, Conan-kun.
Seriously? It's that store we were just in.
"The Blind Spot in the Changing Room
(Part One)"
The next episode of Conan is "The Blind
Spot in the Changing Room, Part One!"
Swimsuits
Next Conan's hint.
Swimsuits!
Don't miss the next episode.
Next episode features high
school girls in swimsuits.
Yeah, so?
You seem happy.
Shut up.