Waves...
Whenever I see Sera-san running away,
I always hear it in the back of my mind.
The sound of waves crashing,
as though I've had a spell cast on me.
I started to miss Japan, so I came back.
To be reunited with a magician...
Huh? A postscript?
PS
Have you already met your magician?
Well, yeah.
A magician?
I'm not the magician.
What?
You're a magician.
Listen...
Sera-chan, have we met before?
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
Including the mysterious Sera, the high
school girl trio show off their swimsuits.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Blind Spot in the Changing Room
Part One
"The Blind Spot in the
Changing Room, Part One!"
Tada!
Huh?
Wh-What do you think?
U-Uh...
It's...
It looks good.
Shinichi-kun will fall head
over heels for you, Mrs. Kudo.
I already have.
We didn't invite Shinichi to the pool.
Sonoko-kun, you're next.
Tada!
Oh...
Wow.
What do you think?
It's sexy.
Right?
But Kyogoku-san might chide
you if he saw you in that.
"Sonoko-san, a woman must
keep her hips warm."
Like that.
Ugh, I bet he'd say that.
He's a typical Japanese man.
I'm next.
Look closely.
What was that about?
Tada!
Huh?
It looks good!
It's sporty and cute.
I used to wear swimsuits like
this one when I was little.
I was kind of drawn to
the micro bikinis, but...
Maybe you shouldn't.
Y-You think?
If someone with your body
wore one of those...
You're so mean.
I should be filling out soon.
I've seen that swimsuit before.
If she was wearing a swimsuit, it
must've been at the pool or the beach.
I'm afraid.
I feel like I've been possessed.
Who are you?
One enthralled by the god of death...
You're a magician!
Next, next!
Let's try some more on!
What? We're trying more?
Huh?
How's this?
I feel like...
...I don't belong here.
Hey!
Could I go check out the toys?
Oh, sorry.
This can't be fun for you.
Uh, yeah.
You can go, but don't follow any strangers.
Okay.
We'll come get you once we buy our swimsuits.
Then we'll have lunch at a restaurant.
I bet you're hungry, kid.
Nope, I've already had my fill.
What was that memory, though?
You're a magician!
If that girl with the double tooth was Sera,
then that man in the sunglasses...
Who are you?
He looked pretty young, but was it Akai-san?
Then who are that boy and woman?
I feel like I might have met them somewhere.
But where?
You don't remember?
Huh?
It's me, Nitsuka!
I-I see...
Nitsuka, the woman who collapsed
in the changing room last week,
and was taken to the doctor!
Nitsuka Tomoyo (43)
Customer
Ni-tsu-ka!
Oh, I remember now!
Nanbu Reia (24)
Employee
You were feeling anemic
and lost consciousness.
It wasn't anemia. It was my dog allergy.
Since that woman covered in dog hair
used the changing room before me,
I had an allergic reaction
and lost consciousness.
I-I see.
So I'm asking if that woman came here today.
I'm not sure who you're talking about.
That high-handed, unpleasant
looking woman with gaudy nails.
Oh?
Could that high-handed,
unpleasant looking woman
with gaudy nails you're
complaining about be me?
Sashihara Ritsuko (41)
Customer
Nitsuka-san, was it?
If you hate dog hair so much,
why don't you hold your breath
while you use the changing room?
Right, Yamaki-san?
Don't you agree?
But, ma'am,
Yamaki Ayami (35)
Customer
an allergy to dogs can be triggered
not just be inhaling dog hair,
but also coming in contact
with fur, dander, or saliva.
Oh, really?
Then you won't be able to try any clothes on
without wearing socks and a wet suit.
Wh-Why you...
Ma'am.
You may have gone too far.
What? Are you trying to give me advice?
What?
Have you forgotten that I
agreed to take on your debts,
and even hired you to work at my company?
No, I...
Now, now. There are three changing rooms.
Why don't you agree on a way to share them?
Oh, good idea.
Hmm, Nanbu-san.
I don't recognize you. Are you new?
Oh, yes. I was just assigned
to this shop last month.
I know the owner. I'll be
sure to tell him about you.
Thank you!
That there's an eyesore at his shop
who dared to tell me what to do,
and she should be fired!
B-But...
Now show me some clothes!
I'm going to another
party overseas next week!
Come on, hurry up!
Unlike you, I don't have
all the time in the world!
I don't know what's going on,
but I'm staying out of that.
Huh?
That crazy woman's one of their customers?
Yeah.
She seems like the first person
to become a victim in a mystery.
Sera-chan, don't say things like that.
What shop was that?
A place called Shimusa on the fourth floor.
Why don't we go there now?
What?
I'd like to see this woman.
Don't. I'm in a good mood
after buying a cute swimsuit.
A swimsuit.
Hey, Sera-no-neechan.
Huh?
The first swimsuit you tried on today...
Oh, that's right.
Have you worn that swimsuit before?
I thought I recognized it.
Really?
Come to think of it, Ran was there, too...
Hey, look.
Huh?
What is it, Sonoko?
That store the kid was
talking about is nearby.
Let's check it out.
Let's not.
W-Wait, Conan-kun!
Someone's dead!
Call the police!
Someone help!
Seriously? It's that store I was just at.
W-Wait, Conan-kun!
Someone's dead!
Call the police!
Someone help!
Seriously? It's that store I was just at.
Have you called the police?
I will.
Don't let anyone out of the store.
Got it.
There are Yoshikawa lines.
Looks like she was strangled.
Her left hand is in her jacket.
Why?
She's pointing next door.
Who was in the changing room to the left?
Th-That was me.
You killed her?
Y-You can't be serious. It wasn't me.
Who was to her right?
Me. Is there a problem?
Who was the first one to find her?
That employee.
Yes. There's a dead customer
in the changing room.
She's holding something in her right hand.
Lipstick?
Come to think of it, it looked like she
wiped her lipstick off with her finger.
She put lipstick on her thumb and
grasped it before she was killed.
But why?
For what purpose?
No way.
The woman who died was the one
Conan-kun was talking about?
Yeah, the high-handed and
unpleasant looking woman.
It's Sera-chan's fault
for saying she'd be killed
first in a mystery novel.
Actually, I think it's the
kid who caused her death.
So, who's the victim?
Ah, yes, sir. Sashihara
Ritsuko-san, forty-one years old.
She was the president of a cosmetics company.
The cause of death was strangulation.
According to forensics,
the killer wrapped a rope around her neck
and lifted her onto their back.
I see.
Who found the body first?
The body was discovered by...
I-It was me.
And you are?
I'm Nanbu Reia. I work here.
Sashihara-sama hadn't come out
of the changing room for a while.
She didn't answer when I called to her,
so when I opened the curtain to look
inside, I-I found her like this.
Was anyone using the changing
rooms next to hers at the time?
I was using the left room.
Oh, I'm President Sashihara's
employee, Yamaki.
I often accompanied the president
when she went shopping.
Since I know you'll ask,
I was in the right changing room.
I'm Nitsuka Tomoyo.
I'm just an ordinary customer
who had nothing to do with that woman.
And it looked like someone had used
the right changing room
before I went in there.
Someone? You mean you didn't see their face?
No, I just saw the white sandals they
left in front of the changing room.
I saw the sandals, too.
S-So did I.
How many customers were inside
the store at the time?
About... four or five.
They left when they heard there had been a
murder since they didn't want to get involved.
That boy told me not to
let anyone leave, though.
Conan-kun, what are you doing here?
I heard the scream of the employee.
I was at the escalator next to the store.
Right, Sera-no-neechan?
Yeah.
Conan-kun had been telling us
all about how the murdered woman
and these three were
arguing before the murder.
But it's not good that
the other customers left.
Yeah. I'm curious about the customer
who left the white sandals, too.
Are there any security cameras in the store?
We do have some.
But I don't think we have
any near the changing rooms.
I see.
Which leaves the victim's hands.
Her left hand has the pointer
finger and thumb extended.
Her right hand was holding her thumb
which was stained with lipstick.
What is this?
You don't know?
It's a dying message.
A message from the dead.
Maybe, but the killer
could've left it on purpose.
Look again at the palms of her hands.
The palms of her hands?
She still has nail marks on both hands.
The killer couldn't have left those marks
if they'd closed her hands for her.
The victim clenched her
hands as hard as she could
while she was being strangled,
so she could tell us who killed her.
I see.
Which way was her left hand pointing
when the body was discovered?
It was inside the right side of her jacket,
so it was pointing left.
Left?
In other words, the woman using
the left changing room...
I-I didn't do it.
If the person I killed had
their hand inside their jacket,
I would check to see what it was doing.
I'd be worried she was holding
some kind of evidence.
Besides, the killer could've
changed the orientation of
her body after killing her.
You're right.
Hey, maybe this is some kind of number.
What?
A number? This?
The victim frequently traveled abroad, right?
She said she was going to
a party overseas next week.
Yes, every week she flew all over the world
to expand her market.
Then she must've gone to Europe often, right?
Yes.
When using fingers to count numbers,
Europeans generally count
one with their thumb,
two with their pointer finger, and
three with their middle finger.
Which means this shape is two.
It's indicating Nitsuka-san.
Y-You can't be serious!
Why would I kill a total stranger?
Oh, uh, because...
Conan-kun, is that really
what they do in Europe?
I saw on TV that they do
this in Germany and France.
But where I studied abroad,
they counted the same way we do in Japan.
Pointer finger first,
middle finger second, and ring finger third.
You went to America, right?
America and Japan are the same.
O-Oh, right.
C-Come to think of it, that hand shape
looks like something, doesn't it?
Huh?
A-A gun?
And the guns used by the
Japanese police are...
New Nambus.
That's it!
That means Nanbu-san did it.
What?
I-I didn't do it!
In other words,
the left hand by itself
can be interpreted in just about any way.
Which means the key lies in the right hand
holding her lipstick stained thumb,
but we have no idea what it means.
It's strange that no one heard
the victim scream, though.
Yeah.
Normally you'd say something
if someone entered your room
while you were changing.
In any case, we'd like
to question each of you
individually in a separate room.
Can I go with you?
What?
Wh-Why?
Remember?
Conan-kun saw them arguing with the victim.
We don't have a choice.
Conan-kun, you can come.
Then I'll come as Conan-kun's guardian.
What?
All three of them are
almost exactly the same.
Episode Preview
The question is how did the killer
get inside the changing room.
Yeah.
The killer's reflection should've
appeared in this mirror.
I see.
So that's how it is.
What's this stuff for?
We're going to make another customer.
The Blind Spot in the Changing Room
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The Blind
Spot in the Changing Room, Part Two!"
Sandals
Next Conan's hint!
Sandals!
Did you solve the mystery?
Don't miss the next episode.
Yeah, but I haven't solved yours yet.