[Eyecatch]
Dragged along by Ran, Sonoko, and
Sera so they could buy new swimsuits
to go to the pool, I arrived
at the department store.
But once there...
The victim was cosmetics company
president Sashihara Ritsuko-san.
Sashihara Ritsuko (41)
Customer
The index finger and thumb on the
body's left hand were extended,
and her own red lipstick
was on her right thumbnail.
But why?
For what purpose?
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
The shape of her fingers and red lipstick.
Sera's secret is hidden
within the mysterious case.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Blind Spot in the Changing Room
(Part Two)
"The Blind Spot in the
Changing Room, Part Two!"
What?
The order in which
Sashihara-sama, Yamaki-sama,
Nanbu Reia (24)
Employee
and Nitsuka-sama entered the changing rooms?
Yes.
I think Yamaki-sama was first.
She said she'd forgotten where
the changing rooms were,
so I showed her the way
to the front of the rooms.
Did you see the white sandals then?
I believe they were already in
front of the room on the right.
Sashihara-sama was next.
She entered the empty room in the middle.
I see.
So Nitsuka-san was last?
Yes.
She entered quite a while
after Sashihara-sama,
and was irritated that none
of the rooms were freeing up.
According to Conan-kun, Sashihara-san
said something rather harsh to you.
Y-Yes.
But a senior employee told me
she'd been told the same thing
before and not to worry about it.
The dead woman said something
that made it sound like you
met for the first time today.
I don't recognize you. Are you new?
But you actually met a week ago, right?
Yes.
She was here with Yamaki-sama when
Nitsuka-sama collapsed in the changing room.
Are the black pumps you're
wearing and those white sneakers
the only shoes you have?
Yes.
I keep the pumps in my locker,
and usually wear these sneakers to commute.
Those are really all you have?
If you think I'm lying,
you can search the store.
Nanbu-san, could you draw
the white sandals you saw?
It doesn't need to be detailed.
O-Okay.
Yes.
Yamaki Ayami (35)
Customer
Like the employee said, the white sandals
were already there when I
entered the changing room.
President Sashihara entered the
changing room next to yours later.
Did you hear any strange noises?
No, not in particular.
You're sure you didn't offer to
help her undress and enter her room?
Why would I do that?!
I'm not her servant!
But the president said
she took on your debt and hired you.
Yes. It's true that I wasn't her equal.
But you saw her clothes.
She didn't need help to remove them.
You're right.
By the way,
are those boxes you had inside
your bag a gift for someone?
Yes, for the president
of the department store.
It's one of our new products.
President Sashihara told me to have
one of the employees give it to him.
Would you like to check the contents?
It's just perfume.
Yes, later.
Also, could you draw us a
picture of the white sandals?
It doesn't have to be precise.
O-Okay.
Yes, that's right.
Nitsuka Tomoyo (43)
Customer
I collapsed in the changing
room here last week
because of the dog hair that
Sashihara woman left everywhere.
I see. You're allergic to dogs.
According to forensics,
they found substantial quantities
of dog hair in the changing room.
I see.
So?
Do you know when the owner
of the white sandals
left the changing room?
Between 2:43 PM and 2:44 PM.
I was checking every minute
to see if the room on the right was open.
Why the room on the right?
That dog-hair-covered
woman was in the middle,
and her employee was in the left room.
Her employee could have dog hair on her, too.
So you knew the victim
entered the middle room?
W-Well, yes.
What's that light brown case thing?
Oh, this?
They're folding slippers.
I'm taking a flight to China after this.
Maybe you made those slippers
look like white sandals...
What?
Look at them! They're beige!
What we saw were white sandals
shaped totally differently!
Hey, you!
Give me that paper and pen!
I'll draw what they looked like!
All three of them are
almost exactly the same.
It seems there really was a
customer wearing white sandals.
Inspector Megure.
Forensics found scissors, bits of tape,
and pieces of a straw in a garbage can
near the changing rooms.
Do you think they're connected to the case?
They still don't know who did it?
No...
The killer is probably...
That woman.
No way. You already figured it out?
Yeah.
But I still don't know how they
entered the victim's changing room
without her causing a commotion.
The victim was probably wearing a face cover.
You know,
those disposable ones so your makeup
doesn't get on the merchandise.
You can't see very well
when you're wearing one.
But they don't make you blind.
You'd be able to tell if someone entered.
Do they have those in the changing rooms?
Some stores hand them out before you enter.
A lot of stores keep them
in the rooms themselves.
It looks like a big tissue box.
I see.
So that's how it is.
This wasn't the first time.
It was the second murder.
Inspector Megure.
We checked the store's security cameras.
Many of the customers' feet weren't visible,
and we weren't able to find anyone
wearing the white sandals
the three women saw
in front of the right changing
room at the time of the murder.
Which means the customer wearing the sandals
was the killer and has already left.
Or the store employee, Nanbu Reia-san,
who discovered the body.
Or the victim's employee, Yamaki Ayami-san,
who was using the left
room before the victim
entered the middle room.
Or the woman allergic to
dogs, Nitsuka Tomoyo-san,
who entered the room on the right after
the customer wearing white sandals left.
The question is how did the killer
get inside the changing room.
Yeah.
The victim would've said something if
someone entered while she was changing.
And even if they snuck in...
The killer's reflection should've
appeared in this mirror.
Yeah, but...
If the victim was already unconscious
when the killer entered the room,
she wouldn't have been able to say anything,
and it would've been easy to strangle her.
Th-The victim was unconscious?
But how?
Using one of the face covers on the
right side of the changing room.
Men probably don't recognize them,
but female customers wear them when trying
on clothes so their makeup doesn't get on them.
Huh.
By soaking the face covers in chloroform,
the victim knocked herself out
for the killer by putting on one.
I see.
Actually, I didn't know
about face covers either.
I thought it was a giant tissue box.
So the killer had a bottle of chloroform.
It doesn't have to be a bottle.
A straw's more than enough.
A straw?
You melt one end of a
straw using a hair iron,
pour the chloroform into the open end,
and melt the open end.
To use it, you just have to cut
one end open with scissors.
I read online that it's a convenient way
to store cosmetics to reduce
your luggage while traveling.
So that's what the straw and scissors
we found near the crime scene were for.
I'll go check with forensics.
But even if the face covers
were soaked in chloroform,
the killer had to know which changing
room the victim would enter.
She'd enter the middle room
if it were the only one free.
But another customer could enter the room.
Yeah. The killer made her
first attempt last week.
And like you said,
Nitsuka-san entered the
room before the victim.
In other words, this was her
second attempt at murder.
So Nitsuka-san collapsed a week ago
not because of her dog allergy,
but because she smelled the chloroform.
But how did she leave the middle room open?
The killer could enter one room,
but how did she block the other?
By putting the white sandals
in front of the other room.
This could only have been
done by the woman
who entered the left room before
the victim entered the middle room.
Yamaki Ayami-san!
It was you!
W-Wait a minute!
I don't have any white sandals!
Besides, the sandals were there
before I entered the changing room!
Right, miss?
Huh? Y-Yes.
Conan-kun!
We bought insoles, tape, and a white ribbon.
Thanks.
What's this stuff for?
We're going to make another customer.
Another...
Customer?
First place the white ribbon against
the heel of the insole.
Cross the ribbon on the underside
of the insole and tape it.
Then cross the ribbons over the top.
Tape the ends to the
underside again and there.
You have some white sandals.
Wow.
Not bad, kid.
I'm good at arts and crafts.
Make a second one, and...
Put them in front of the changing room,
and it looks like someone's inside.
Wouldn't it be obvious since
they're so flat and heel-less?
But if you raise the heel by
placing a cell phone under them...
See? They look like sandals from above.
Amazing!
You had one, didn't you?
A present wrapped in white ribbon.
If you made the sandals beforehand
and kept them in your bag,
all that would be left after the murder
would be the tape you used to make the sandals.
You could tie the ribbon around the present,
and you could hide the insoles
inside your own shoes.
I see.
The bits of tape we found
with the straw and scissors
were from when she removed
the ribbon from the insoles.
Her fingerprints may be on the tape since
it's difficult to remove without bare hands.
Here's what you did:
After making sure the three
changing rooms were empty,
you placed the white sandals in
front of the room on the right,
told an employee you forgot
where the changing rooms were,
had her show you, and made sure she saw
the white sandals in front of the right room.
When the employee returned to the store,
you entered the middle room,
soaked a face cover in the
chloroform you had in the straw,
put it back in the box,
and entered the left room.
You watched through the curtain
for the victim to enter
and listened for the victim
to inhale the chloroform
in the face cover and collapse.
After making sure no one was around,
you entered the middle room,
wrapped the rope you brought
around the victim's neck,
and strangled her.
Then you waited for Nitsuka-san, who was
frequently checking the changing rooms,
to return to the store,
reached through the curtain to collect
the white sandals and cell phone,
listened for Nitsuka-san
to enter the right room,
returned to the left room,
removed the ribbon from the white
sandals, tied it around the present,
and put the insoles inside your own shoes.
You intended to leave the
changing room immediately,
but an employee found the
victim's body first, right?
Then what were those shapes the
victim made with her hands?
The right hand grasping her
thumb with lipstick on it was...
The national flag.
The national flag?
Yeah, the flag of China.
The victim was wearing nails
with five stars on them,
so by making the area around the stars red,
she was trying to make it
look like the Chinese flag.
B-But why China?
Chinese people count on their
fingers in an unusual way.
They count from one to ten on a single hand.
One hand?
One through five are the same as Japan,
but this is six, and this is seven.
And this is eight.
W-Wait. Isn't that...
Oh, right. This is...
Eight, for the "Ya" in Yamaki-san.
I see.
Since the victim was well-traveled,
she knew how they count in China.
Since the changing room floor
is covered in dog hair,
you'll probably find a couple strands
on the bottoms of Yamaki-san's feet.
You don't need to look for dog hair.
After all, I was the president's pet.
Her pet?
I came here to buy clothes a few
months ago with the president.
We happened to try on the same clothes.
Oh?
Are you going to wear that
to the upcoming party?
Y-Yes.
But if you planned to wear it,
I'll choose something else.
Oh, don't worry about it.
I won't be wearing this.
You wear it.
Thank you.
Sounds like a nice president.
Indeed.
The president didn't wear
those clothes herself.
She had them remade as dog clothes.
Oh my, Yamaki-san.
You and my dog are matching.
That choker looks like a collar, too.
Shall I attach a lead to it?
You're my pet for life.
I couldn't get a new job
because of the debt I owed the president.
So I killed her before she could kill me.
So I wouldn't be hers forever.
Case closed.
With me and Conan-kun on the case,
a case like that is a cinch.
Right, Conan-kun?
A-All I did was make sandals using a ribbon.
Impressive as always, high school detective.
Sonoko, you're a high school detective, too.
You called yourself the Mystery Queen.
I haven't had any epiphanies lately.
I used to feel them right
around the back of my neck.
I guess I haven't tranquilized
Sonoko in a while.
Anyway, I had no idea
they count like this in Germany and France.
Shinichi used to do that all the time.
He said he got it from his mom.
Yeah, Mom tried to act cool
by mimicking French people.
Hey, kid.
Is this how they count to three in Europe?
No. I saw on TV that even in
Europe, there are exceptions.
England is the same as Japan.
They count to three using
their pointer finger,
middle finger, and ring finger.
Huh.
I knew it. Of course.
During the Red Woman case, Sera...
That's a pretty thin bat, though...
Can you hit a ball with that?
Said something like that.
Maybe she was thinking of cricket
since that's popular in England.
Cricket bats are flatter and
thicker than baseball bats.
And according to American manners,
after cutting your food with a knife,
you switch your fork to your right hand.
You eat with your fork in your
left hand in Japan and England.
Wait a minute.
Didn't Sera say this, too?
That's how I know Conan-kun's
pretty good at football.
Americans don't call soccer "football."
Which means Sera studied in England,
not America.
But why is she lying about going to England?
Wait a minute.
England...
That's it!
I remember now!
Episode Preview
Ah, you came. I've been waiting for you.
Hey, did you guys just see something yellow?
I did. It disappeared immediately, though.
The master says there are ghosts.
So that's how it is.
The Detective Boys and the Haunted House
The next episode of Conan is "The
Detective Boys and the Haunted House!"
Greenhouse
Next Conan's hint!
A greenhouse!
Remember anything?
Don't miss the next episode.
Yeah, a beach.
When and where?
It's a secret.