Ah, you came. I've been waiting for you.
Thank you.
Yoshimoto Saburo (45)
Servant
You kids don't seem to be from around here.
We came here to go camping.
It suddenly started raining when
we went to see the lighthouse.
The roads turned into rivers.
Yoshimoto Hana (42)
Servant
Not even an umbrella would
help you in this downpour.
You can stay while it's raining, but
you have to leave once it stops.
Nothing good comes from staying here.
What does that mean?
Strange things have been happening
at this mansion lately.
It's best not to get involved.
What strange things?
I've never seen one,
but the master says there are ghosts.
What?
Don't scare the children.
Ghosts, huh?
Nobody believes in ghosts anymore.
I don't believe in them either,
but the master isn't the
type to make up stories.
According to him, it's
a yellowish white color.
Now that you know, let me have those towels.
He must be lying so we'll leave.
Yeah.
Huh?
H-Hey, did you guys just
see something yellow?
I did. It disappeared immediately, though.
A-Are there really...?
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
What was that I just saw?
I detect a case in the old mansion!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Detective Boys and the Haunted House
"The Detective Boys and the Haunted House!"
It's not letting up.
Huh? Who are you kids?
We're staying here to get out of the rain.
I see.
I'm Amemiya Hideto, the
freeloader who lives here.
Amemiya Hideto (27)
Nobuteru's Nephew
Nice to meet you.
Wow!
This place is like a science lab.
There are all kinds of machines.
I conduct scientific research at college.
I also use the annex in the yard as a lab.
Given your studies, how
do you feel about ghosts?
Oh, you heard about my uncle?
I don't believe in them, but my uncle
seems to think they actually exist.
This house is pretty old, isn't it?
Yeah.
My uncle bought it five
years ago when he retired,
but it was built fifty years ago.
Did he buy it without knowing
about the ghost rumors?
Ah, I see.
My uncle started saying there
were ghosts about two weeks ago.
They didn't appear until then?
Yeah. My aunt actually
passed away two months ago.
My uncle says she's visiting him.
She always had weak legs.
Auntie.
Oh, Hideto-san.
You're going out again to sketch?
Yes.
Otaguro Chieko (72)
Nobuteru's Wife
I'm going to submit something
to this fall's exhibition.
Auntie!
She always went there.
We don't know why she fell that day.
I feel sorry for her.
It must've been quite the
shock for your uncle.
That's why he says there are ghosts.
Thank you for letting us stay for dinner.
The rain still hasn't let up.
Don't worry about it.
This stew is delicious.
Otaguro Nobuteru (78)
Master of the House
Is it? If you like it,
you're welcome to more.
More!
You already finished?
I'm reserving my portion.
We heard your wife visits you.
She does.
But isn't she dead?
Yes, but she really does come.
She comes after dark.
Then she leaves around ten.
What does your wife look like?
She looks like a yellowish light.
But before long...
I heard Chieko's voice.
Tonight she'll tell me about the accident.
Huh?
I-I'm sorry!
What are you doing?!
I'm sorry, sir.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm returning to my room.
I'm really sorry.
I'll head back to my lab, then.
Oh, Hana-san. I broke a beaker in my room.
Could you run the vacuum later?
Yes.
It's in front of the medicine cabinet.
Very well.
Is he talking to his wife's ghost around now?
Someone could be fooling him.
But he seemed happy about meeting a ghost.
What should we do, Conan?
About what?
If he's being deceived by someone,
the Detective Boys can't ignore it.
Yeah, but Otaguro-san seems happy,
and we don't know that he's—
What are you talking about?!
You know there's no end
to cases where someone
takes advantage of an
elderly person's feelings!
Fine.
It's fine. Ghosts don't exist.
H-Hey, did you see that?
Y-Yeah.
It moved on its own!
Let's head upstairs.
Ah, Chieko.
That's Otaguro-san's voice.
You came again tonight.
Yes, I have.
That's a woman's voice.
The door opened without anyone touching it.
I'm managing.
There really was a ghost!
The wheelchair moved!
We heard a woman's voice!
And a door opened without anyone touching it!
What are you trying to say?
We saw the wife's ghost!
What?
We saw a light, too. It was yellowish.
Are you saying the master was right?
That's enough!
They're just children, but I can't
believe you're going on about ghosts.
So, what will you do?
I can lend you some umbrellas
if you're leaving.
What? What should we do?
Don't ask me.
I can't believe there's really a ghost.
Let's leave.
Mitsuhiko, go borrow some umbrellas.
No! Why do I have to go?!
Even if the ghost's real,
it's just his wife, right?
I don't think she'd hurt you.
Huh?
Conan, are you going to get umbrellas?
No, I'm checking something out.
So that's how it is.
Poison
Thank you for the juice
after serving us dinner.
Children don't need to show restraint.
Besides, we always have
tea around this hour here.
There are hot beverages if you prefer.
It's gotten colder recently.
It's fine. The juice is very good.
Genta-kun, would you have preferred eel?
Well, yeah.
Maybe someone will make some eel juice.
What?
By the way, where's the boy with the glasses?
He was around a minute ago.
Hey, you're right.
Conan-kun does this all the time.
Yeah. That's just how he is.
This house is large.
I hope he doesn't get lost.
Uncle!
Are you all right?
Saburo-san, call an ambulance.
That won't be necessary.
What?
You!
Conan!
That packed a punch.
Hana-san, what's wrong with this tea?
U-Uncle? You're all right?
It's no wonder it tastes bad.
There's salt in that tea.
Salt?
Why?
Because I swapped the contents
of the poison bottle
in Hideto-san's room with salt.
I found the bottle Hana-san took from
the cabinet and hid in the kitchen.
Poison?
You took the poison?
And meant to put it in the tea?
Hana-san was worried the
ghost would reveal the truth
behind the accident that
happened two months ago.
The truth behind the accident?
Huh?
I... I...
I didn't think she'd die!
I just wanted to annoy her.
Hana-san,
I won't ask you to return the necklaces
and brooches you've stolen.
But please don't take anymore.
Someone help!
I thought she'd have trouble getting in and
out of her wheelchair if I loosened the brakes.
That's all.
Hana-san thought the ghost
would tell Otaguro-san about it.
But there was nothing she
could do about a ghost.
So Hana-san made Otaguro-san her target.
The salt I substituted
in Otaguro-san's tea proves it.
How could you?!
I'm sorry, sir!
But she didn't need to worry about it.
There never was a ghost.
Right, Hideto-san?
But the wheelchair moved on its own.
This house was built fifty years ago.
It wouldn't be strange for there
to be damage here and there.
A breeze coming through a crack in the wall
pushed the wheelchair.
Besides, the brakes were broken.
But the door to his room opened on its own.
That door opens at the slightest vibration
because the latch is old and weak.
What about the yellow ghost
floating in the room?
Remember when we arrived?
There's a greenhouse.
It's not blocking the rain.
Hey.
Maybe we can get in through there.
Hey, kids.
Don't break anything!
That was just constructed two weeks ago!
The greenhouse was built two weeks ago.
The ghost began appearing two weeks ago.
By the way, what around this area shines?
Shines?
You mean the lighthouse?
Yeah. The ghost is the
light from the lighthouse.
The light never struck this
house directly before.
After the greenhouse was built,
the light started reflecting
off the glass windows
and illuminating the walls of this house.
The light seeping through the
walls reflected off the glass
on Otaguro-san's bookcase
and looked like a ghost.
I just called the owner of the greenhouse.
He said he closes the
windows every night at ten.
That's why the ghost disappears at ten, too.
By the way, he also leaves
the windows open
when it rains so it doesn't
get stuffy inside.
What about the glow on the
second floor when we arrived?
Hideto-san turned up right after, right?
It was probably the lights
from Hideto-san's car.
We couldn't hear the car because of the rain.
But there was a woman's
voice coming from the room.
By the way, I put the poison I swapped out
for salt in another bottle and
returned it to the cabinet.
After all, the cabinet wasn't locked.
If Hana-san unlocked the cabinet,
she would've locked it so
she wouldn't be discovered.
So I think it was unlocked to begin with.
But it's strange for an
expert like Hideto-san
to leave a cabinet containing
poison unlocked.
That was careless of me.
So, returning to the voice,
since the ghost is the
light from the lighthouse,
there must be an explanation for the voice.
Thinking that, I just
examined Otaguro-san's room.
And I found it.
A speaker, mic, and wireless
device behind the bookcase.
This is probably where your
wife's voice was coming from.
The only person in this house
who could've made this
is Hideto-san.
But if he played the wife's voice...
Was he using clips he recorded?
Hideto-san was probably
playing his own voice
modified to sound feminine.
Since Otaguro-san believed his
wife's ghost was visiting him,
he believed he'd mistake it for hers.
When Hideto-san arrived at
the scene of the accident,
he noticed the brakes were loose.
He also noticed how Hana-san began acting
since the ghost started appearing.
Hideto-san realized Hana-san
was connected to the accident.
He thought she'd act as expected
if he pressured her.
He began producing the voice
so she'd think the truth behind
the accident would be revealed.
And he deliberately broke a beaker
in front of the unlocked cabinet
and asked her to clean it
knowing what Hana-san would do.
It all went according to plan.
Hana-san took the poison and
attempted to murder Otaguro-san.
You're saying I tried to kill my uncle?!
Why would I?
This is the reason.
I found them in the trash can in your room.
Open Immediately
This is a collection letter, right?
Hideto-san, you've been borrowing
money from a bunch of places.
Your motive was money.
Drowning in debt,
you wanted Otaguro-san's wealth.
Hey, why didn't you just talk to him?
My uncle's stricter than anyone
when it comes to money.
Hideto, is everything this boy said true?
Yes. Call the police.
The moon!
It stopped raining at some point.
We were just trying to get out of the rain.
That turned into a crazy night.
I'm hungry.
What?
Mister!
Could you leave those windows
open a little longer tonight?
Huh?
Please!
Conan, what are you doing?!
Nothing!
The professor and Haibara must be worried.
Let's hurry back.
Let's have the professor come pick us up.
It'll be faster.
Episode Preview
Nice to meet you.
It's been a while, Shuichi-niisan.
Is that a popular joke in England?
You're like a child enthralled
by the god of death.
Well? Think you can do
it, Holmes' apprentice?
Yeah. Of course.
The Magician of the Waves
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Magician of the Waves, Part One!"
Beach Hut
Next Conan's hint!
A beach hut!
Don't miss the next episode.
This time, I was a ghost whisperer!
What will you be next time?
A magician, I guess.