Anyway, I had no idea they count
like this in Germany and France.
Shinichi used to do that all the time.
He said he got it from his mom.
Yeah, Mom tried to act cool
by mimicking French people.
Hey, kid.
Is this how they count to three in Europe?
No. I saw on TV that even in
Europe, there are exceptions.
England is the same as Japan.
They count to three using
their pointer finger,
middle finger, and ring finger.
Huh.
I knew it. Of course.
During the Red Woman case, Sera...
That's a pretty thin bat, though...
Can you hit a ball with that?
...said something like that.
Maybe she was thinking of cricket
since that's popular in England.
Cricket bats are flatter and
thicker than baseball bats.
And according to American manners,
after cutting your food with a knife,
you switch your fork to your right hand.
You eat with your fork in your
left hand in Japan and England.
Wait a minute.
Didn't Sera say this, too?
That's how I know Conan-kun's
pretty good at football.
Americans don't call soccer "football."
Which means Sera studied in England,
not America.
By why is she lying about going to England?
Wait a minute.
England...
I'm afraid.
I feel like I've been possessed.
England...
Who are you?
One enthralled by the god of death...
You're a magician!
That's it!
I remember now!
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
While looking into Sera's secret,
I recalled a case on the beach!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Magician of the Waves
(Part One)
"The Magician of the Waves, Part One!"
10 Years Earlier...
It's been a while.
Shuichi-niisan.
It's been seven years.
You've grown, Shukichi.
You're starting your third
year of high school now?
Yeah.
Come on, say hello.
This is your first time meeting, right?
N-Nice to meet you.
I'm Masumi.
Who's the kid?
Huh?
Have you forgotten? She's your sister.
I sent you photos.
Come to think of it,
Mom had a baby bump before
I left for America.
Unbelievable.
Anyway, where's Mary?
I thought you came here together after
she went to meet you at your hotel.
We had a bit of an argument at the hotel.
She got me with a chop.
Just look at this.
I got a few hits in, though.
She's probably icing them right now.
You're the one who needs to cool his head.
I let you study abroad because you
said you wanted to study in America,
but now you're saying you actually went to
investigate the truth behind your father's case?
And on top of that, you're joining
the FBI when you graduate.
You're like a child enthralled
by the god of death.
I already have a green
card and US citizenship.
All I need now is three
years of work experience,
and to pass the written and physical tests.
It won't be a problem.
I did struggle to get my driver's license,
since I couldn't get used to driving
on the right side of the road.
In the country we used to live in and
this place, they drive on the left.
What about your living expenses?
Do you really expect me to send money to
someone who'd say something so stupid?
Don't worry.
I found a pretty decent job.
I'll survive until I can join the FBI.
Unbelievable.
I invited you to the beach
so you'd come back home.
I hope looking at this peaceful scenery
will help you cool your head,
and remember the words my husband
before his death as he sent
us to this safe country.
"Pretend I never existed."
"I seem to have made some serious enemies."
Don't forget his message.
Mom, you're the one who's forgotten
our father's body still hasn't been found.
Why don't we get some
yakisoba at the beach hut?
Okay.
I've never met my other brother before.
Unlike Kichi-niichan,
he doesn't smile at all.
I want to see him smile.
Okay!
Boo!
Shukichi, how could you let her do that?
It's dangerous.
It's no use. He won't smile.
Sorry.
Masumi said she wanted to
get on top of the parasol.
In that case, I'll use what
my PE teacher taught me.
That didn't work either.
Then I'll use my special technique.
This gets everyone in my class laughing.
Fried Potatoes
No one can resist laughing at this.
Don't play with your food.
Huh?
No way. This didn't work either?
Hey!
What are you doing, Masumi?
Mom...
You're a girl.
You got salt from your chips
all over your upper lip.
S-Sorry...
Oh...
Is that a popular joke in England?
Huh?
You're from England, aren't you?
In Japan, we call sliced and fried potatoes
covered in salt fried potatoes.
In America, they call them french fries.
Since you called them chips,
I thought you were from England,
the land of fish and chips.
Anyway, have you seen my son?
He's a boy wearing green swim trunks.
He should be with a girl around his age.
No.
I see.
Sheesh.
Where did that kid go?
Sorry for bothering you.
It's fine.
Shin-chan, where are you?
Safe country indeed.
Even an ordinary person like her can tell
where we're from just by the way we speak.
There's no such thing as a safe country, Mom.
Don't worry.
Before the men who killed
Father discover who I am,
I'll send every last one of them to hell.
It's totally obvious.
Huh?
That you're a pierrot.
A-A clown?
I was listening to your conversation.
You travel to all kinds of countries, right?
As far as I know, the only
people who do that
are circus workers.
And when I saw your left hand,
I knew exactly what you were.
I saw that mark on the
back of your left wrist.
It's common among people
who play the accordion.
Dad said that since they press the buttons
while inflating and deflating the instrument,
the belt leaves that mark on their hand.
Clowns play the accordion during
circus shows all the time.
And there are all kinds
of clowns at the circus,
but the only one among them that
wear tear makeup are pierrots.
You still have some of that
makeup under your left eye.
You probably forgot to wipe it
off since you were in a hurry
to come to the beach, but you can't fool me.
You're a pierrot!
Am I wrong?
Huh?
He smiled.
Sorry.
I've been to three countries,
but I'm not part of a circus.
Huh? Really?
Wouldn't that make everyone who
likes to travel part of the circus?
Oh, right.
I'm impressed you noticed this
mark left by the accordion,
but I got this playing requests
for customers at a bar.
I make good money doing it.
And...
This mark under my left eye isn't make up.
It's a bruise I just got
from my violent mother.
So, who are you?
I-I'm...
I'm Kudo Shinichi!
I'm... Sherlock Holmes's apprentice!
I see.
Holmes's apprentice?
Shinichi!
There you are!
Your mom's looking for you!
Ran.
You were playing Holmes again, weren't you?
I wasn't playing.
I'm training to become a detective.
If you don't behave yourself,
you'll get in trouble.
Those guys seemed really mad.
They should be.
You brat...
I finally found you.
You'll pay for embarrassing me earlier.
That was your own fault.
You tried to leave without
paying for the yakisoba
you'd nearly finished by putting a fly in it.
If you hadn't said anything,
no one would've noticed!
Huh?
Sorry, but the kid's with me.
If you've got business with him,
you'll have to go through me.
If you don't mind having
your eyes gouged out first,
I'll listen to anything you have to say.
S-Sorry!
Wow!
What do you call that?
A finger jab.
It's a blinding technique.
It's a Jeet Kune Do technique.
Wow!
Finger jab? Jeet Kune Do?
So cool!
Sorry, kids, but could
you play with my sister?
Huh?
She seems to be looking for some friends.
Sure.
Okay!
Huh?
What?!
A-A car!
Fell into the ocean?!
Seriously?!
He struck his head on the windshield
when the car crashed into the guardrail.
He must not have been wearing his seat belt.
His neck's broken.
He's a goner.
There's a bag in the back seat.
There's a bunch of brand-name watches inside.
They still have their price tags on them.
The window on the passenger side is open.
Looks like there was
another person in the car.
He's back!
Stand back, please!
Thank you!
Will he live?
It's too late for that.
What's in the bag?
Clues to determining his identity.
Anyway, I need you to do something for me.
Remember the swimsuit shop at the beach hut?
Ask if any soaking wet customers came
to buy T-shirts, swimsuits, or sandals
after the car fell into the water.
There was another passenger in the car
who escaped and blended in with the crowd.
Well? Think you can do
it, Holmes's apprentice?
Yeah. Of course.
Here.
Thanks.
Did you come here alone with that boy?
No, we came with Shinichi's mom.
Could you ask her to call the police?
Tell them a car fell into the ocean.
Sure!
Shinichi's mom!
What about me?
What should I do?
Let me help.
Tell the man at the parking
lot to stop anyone
wearing wet clothes or
a swimsuit from leaving.
They could be working with some bad guys.
Can you do that?
Yeah.
Do you remember
who came to buy T-shirts
after the car fell into the water?
I'm not sure. There were
two or three of them.
But I don't remember their faces.
Was there anyone with soaking wet hair?
Everyone's hair is wet.
They're here to swim.
I think there were three.
Huh?
Ripples
I spent a while at this shop deciding
if I should buy this shirt.
Really?
I play shogi.
I have a good memory.
Atsuhama Beach
Bathrooms, Showers, and
Changing Rooms Available
50m Ahead
Parking Lot
500 Yen Per Visit
I see.
So a car broke through the
guardrail above that cliff
and fell into the ocean?
Yes.
And this man was the driver,
and you called the police after
pulling him from the car.
I'm the one who called,
but he's the one who pulled him from the car.
Who are you?
Just a student studying
abroad in the United States.
I returned to Japan and came
here with my family today.
Anyway, is it true that
there was another person in the car?
That's what he said.
What proof do you have?
I simply thought there was another person,
since the passenger window
was open all the way.
The driver's seat was on the right side.
If only one person were in the car,
it would be strange for only the
passenger window to be open.
The other person most
likely opened the window
before the car filled with water and
escaped, blending in with the crowd.
But couldn't they have
opened the door instead?
Not with that water pressure.
There's still air inside a car
immediately after it sinks.
They couldn't open the door
because of the water pressure.
That's why they chose
to open the window and
escape through there.
So they abandoned their friend,
and fled alone.
No.
This man wasn't wearing his seat
belt at the time of the accident.
What?
He struck his head on the windshield
when the car crashed into the guardrail.
It broke his cervical vertebrae,
killing him instantly.
It's probably safe to assume the
passenger determined he was dead
when they received no response
after calling out to him,
so they decided to escape on their own.
But why would they pretend
to be one of the crowd here?
If they were a victim of an accident,
they wouldn't need to hide.
Probably because there
was a reason they had
to conceal themselves.
Episode Preview
I see.
Hey, Mr. Pierrot!
I brought all the customers
who went shopping after the
car fell into the ocean.
It seems this man who was driving
the car that fell into the water
had someone with him.
Apparently they've blended in
with the crowd on the beach.
Case closed.
The Magician of the Waves
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Magician of the Waves, Part Two!"
Detective's Assistant
Next Conan's hint!
A detective's assistant!
Don't miss the next episode.
Conan-kun, what's your weakness?
I don't have one.
Shin-chan.
Yikes.