Grandpa Tick Tock
and the
Three Clocks
By Imai Kenichi
"Grandpa Tick Tock and the Three Clocks."
"Tick tock, tick tock."
"Grandpa Tick Tock is a clock maker."
"He finished repairing the clocks."
"But he's exhausted,
and can't deliver them to his clients."
"'In that case, I'll deliver the
clocks to your clients for you!'"
Everyone, run!
There's a bomb in here!
It's going to explode soon!
Hurry up, and run!
Please run!
I-It's a bomb!
Come on.
We've done as you asked!
Now stop the timer!
Are you listening?!
Dad...
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
The countdown won't stop.
The clues to the bombs are
hidden in a pop-up book.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Pop-up Book Bomber
(Part One)
"The Pop-up Book Bomber, Part One!"
Five Hours Earlier
Mori Detective Agency
Mori-san, delivery.
Coming!
Grandpa Tick Tock and the Three Clocks
By Imai Kenichi
What is this?
"Grandpa Tick Tock and the Three Clocks?"
And a smartphone?
Is it a picture book?
There's something wrong with it, though.
Oh, I know.
It turns into a pop-up book
once you put it together.
You're right.
This looks like a test print, though.
A proof, huh?
But why'd they send that to me?
What happened inside the closed store?
Explosion at Pachinko Parlor Sandcastle
At dawn this morning an explosion occurred...
at the Sandcastle pachinko parlor
located in Beika City, Tokyo.
Huh?
What is it?
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Look at this.
"Tick tock, tick tock."
"Deliver the first clock to
the castle made of sand."
That's a sandcastle.
The name of the pachinko
parlor that exploded is...
Now that you mention it,
they said it was Sandcastle.
It's just a coincidence.
Private Caller
Grandpa Tick Tock
Tick tock, tick tock. Boom!
Sixty minutes until the target
after the castle of sand.
Is this...?
Is it Block 8 of Haido City?
Or is it Block 3?
Where is the bomb?
Can the detective solve the mystery?
A-Are they warning us
about the next explosion?
No way!
What happens next in the picture book?!
Give me a second.
"Tick tock, tick tock."
"The destination of the
second clock is a riddle."
"At a bus stop where five
passengers are waiting,
a bus with three passengers arrives."
"Two get off at the next
stop, and one gets on."
"The next stop is the final stop."
"How many passengers are on the bus?"
What's the answer?
Let's see...
It's torn.
In other words, there's
a bomb at this location.
Hold on.
There's five people waiting,
and a bus with three passengers
arrives, so all together that's eight.
At the next stop two get off, so it's six.
And one gets on, so that makes seven.
The answer is seven people.
But the smartphone message says
it's either Block 8 or Block 3.
I know. The driver.
So all together, there are eight passengers.
The bomb is at the bus stop at Block 8.
Beika Bus
Haido City Block 8
To Haido Housing
Complex North
The great Mori Kogoro would never fall
for such a stupid trick question.
Hello, Inspector?
Wait, mister!
Huh?
It doesn't say the five people waiting
at the bus stop got on the bus.
What? Which means...
Subtracting five from eight gives you three.
Beika Bus
Haido City Block 3
To Haido Housing
Complex North
Which means it's at the bus stop at Block 3.
Yeah. I think that's it.
Really? I understand, Inspector.
Where did the messages come from?
Unfortunately, this is a burner.
Since the messages are being sent
through several servers overseas,
they're having trouble determining
where they came from.
Wait, why are you coming with me?
It's too dangerous! Go home!
Conan-kun's the one who solved the riddle.
And if Conan-kun's going, it's
only natural for me to come.
Only natural?
We'll be fine.
We'll watch from a distance.
You don't need to worry.
Yeah.
Yeah, but...
And if this really is a bomb threat,
then the subsequent pages could be...
And this must be...
Haido City Block 3
Next Stop
Haido Housing
Complex North
There's forty more minutes until the explosion.
Start searching the area immediately.
Inspector!
Ah, Mori-kun.
We've identified the suspect.
What? Really?
Hirukawa Takuji, thirty-eight years old.
After causing an explosion five
years ago, he fled overseas.
It seems he secretly returned to the country.
Hirukawa Takuji (38)
Bomber
Hirukawa's fingerprints were discovered
at this morning's bomb site.
But why did he send you a bomb threat?
How would I know?
I'm not involved with him in any way.
Yes, that's the question.
Chiba-kun.
Yes, sir.
Conan-kun, could I see that book?
Sure. Here.
Thanks.
Well?
This is it.
Three days ago he took it from us, claiming
his younger brother left it to him.
I'm sure of it.
And Hirukawa injured you then, didn't he?
Yes.
What's going on?
Imai Kenichi, the author
of this picture book,
is Hirukawa Takuji's half brother.
His brother?
Yes.
But he passed away while Hirukawa was abroad.
I see.
Oh, I hadn't introduced you yet.
This is Tomonaga-san, his
brother's editor at the time.
Everyone was sure he'd win
Tomonaga Hiroyuki (45)
Editor In Chief
the picture book new author award.
We were pushing his book.
But his brother's criminal
history was exposed online.
By Imai Kenichi
People said it wasn't appropriate
for him to write books for children.
He was forced to withdraw from the contest.
He became sick right after that.
How awful.
Rumor was a private detective
exposed his brother's criminal history.
Hirukawa told friends and acquaintances
that it was the detective
who killed his brother.
What? Is that why he sent the book to me?
I don't remember doing anything like that!
Are you sure, Mori-kun?
Of course!
It's not as though every
detective is fit to be one,
but I, Mori Kogoro, will make
sure the scoundrel pays!
No one was able to determine
who the detective was either.
Most people think it was a groundless rumor.
So he was forced to choose you,
a famous detective.
That must be what happened.
F-Forced to? His resentment's misplaced.
In fact, it's complete unjustified.
Hey, mister editor.
Huh?
Were those pages always torn
out of the picture book?
T-Torn?
That's odd. They shouldn't be.
After his death, we decided
to delay publishing the book,
but we stored the proof in a secure location.
I think the torn pages
may have contained the answers
to the riddles and questions.
I see.
Since hints pertaining to the bombs
were written on those pages,
the suspect Hirukawa tore them out.
Which means there are still other bombs?!
No way.
Yeah, it's definitely likely.
So, what did those pages say originally?
Huh?
The answers to the riddles.
Well...
People started talking about his brother
right after we printed the proof.
I was overwhelmed by dealing with
that, so I never properly read them.
I see...
We found it!
It's inside a bag in a trash can!
Since hints pertaining to the bombs were
written on those pages, the suspect
Hirukawa tore them out.
Which means there are still other bombs?!
Yeah, it's definitely likely.
We found it!
It's inside a bag in a trash can!
Takagi, Chiba. Keep passersby away.
We'll wait until the bomb squad arrives.
Yes, sir!
So the threat was real.
What does he think he's doing?
Dad, Conan-kun...
Wh-What?!
What's going on, Mori-kun?
The remaining time on the bomb
suddenly changed to twenty minutes!
Private Caller
Tick tock, tick tock.
Name, arrow, make.
Get it wrong, and kaboom!
Don't make it in time, and kaboom!
People will die because of the detective.
Run, run, Detective.
What? Run?
Detective Chiba, can I see the book?
What? Okay.
Look.
"Who won the race?"
"Tick tock, tick tock."
"Deliver the second clock to
the park at the finish line."
Damn it. Another riddle?
What's the answer?
It's torn again.
Damn!
Race... Race...
What's he talking about?
Detective Takagi, could you
draw up a list of all the parks
within a twenty minute run from here?
Th-That's it.
I found them!
The corresponding parks
are Aozora Fountain Plaza,
Flower Garden Isobe, and Kanematsu Park!
I'm stumped.
Which one are we meant to go to?
Hold on.
That's it. I've got it.
What?
Really, Dad?
Flower Garden Isobe
The kanji for the Isobe
in Flower Garden Isobe
are either "Iso and Hen" or "Iso and Bu."
Isobe
Iso Hen
Iso Bu
Iso, Bu. Isobu.
Isobu
Aesop
In other words, Aesop.
That's it. The participants of the race...
The one from Aesop's fables...
...were a hare and tortoise!
That's right.
In other words, the finish line
is at Flower Garden Isobe.
But there's more to the message!
Let's head there.
Yes, sir.
Please take me with you.
I'm partially responsible.
And I may be able to remember something.
Very well. Get in.
Conan-kun, we should go home.
Give me a second.
Detective Takagi!
Huh?
Could you show me the list again?
You mean this?
Aozora Fountain Plaza.
Flower Garden Isobe.
Kanematsu Park.
That's it.
Grandpa Tick Tock
Tick tock, tick tock.
Boom!
In 15 minutes.
People will die because of you.
Run, run, Detective!
Damn it! He won't beat me!
Flower Garden Isobe
I-I'm here. I made it.
Now it shouldn't explode.
Wh-Why hasn't it stopped?!
Tick tock, tick tock.
Boom!
In ten minutes!
You can do it!
Detective!
What?
I'm here! Stop the timer!
Are you listening?!
What's wrong, Mori-kun?
The timer won't stop!
Wh-What?
Tick tock, tick tock.
Boom!
In eight minutes.
What's wrong, Detective?
Have you given up?
You can't be serious!
I, Mori Kogoro, will never give up!
It's not here, mister!
Huh?
This park was another trick answer!
Wh-What?
Get in, Dad!
You're sure this is it?
Yeah. Look at this.
It says Kanematsu Park in English.
Remember the message before the riddle?
Tick tock, tick tock.
Name → Make
This "name, arrow, make" message?
Yeah.
The English translation for those
words are "name" and "make."
In other words, "name, arrow, make"
means to turn name into make.
Turn name into make?
Turn name into make...
That's it! It means to change the
N's into M's and M's into K's!
That's right.
So if you turn the N's into M's and
M's into K's of Kanematsu Park...
Ka-me-ka-tsu...
Turtle Wins
Turtle wins!
That's right. This must be
the finish line of the race.
All right.
Everyone, run!
There's a bomb in here!
It's going to explode soon!
Hurry up, and run!
Please run!
I-It's a bomb!
Come on.
We've done as you asked!
Now stop the timer!
Are you listening?!
Dad...
Answer me!
Mister, the rabbit and
turtle statues around you
are running towards the back of the park!
So the finish line is this way!
Conan-kun!
This must be the finish line.
Goal
Yeah.
M-Mori-san.
Conan-kun, it's too dangerous.
Takagi, Chiba, lend me a hand.
We have to open the finish line.
Yes, sir!
Stand back!
Come on, Conan-kun.
Get down!
Huh?
I-It's not...
...e-exploding?
What's going on?
All right.
We did it.
The sewage must have have
damaged the detonator.
Mori-kun.
Inspector, we did it.
Private Caller
Tick tock, tick tock.
Boom!
Well done, Detective Mori Kogoro.
But the game isn't over yet.
Wh-What?
Mori-kun, does this mean...?
Yes. The bomb threat isn't over yet.
Mori-kun, where's the next bomb?
Well, until we receive the next message...
Conan-kun, that book.
Huh?
That's it. There's more to the book.
Th-That's it.
"Tick tock, tick tock."
"Deliver the final clock
to the middle of the 7."
What's next?
It's no use. It's been torn out.
Damn it! What's the middle of
the seven supposed to mean?
The middle of the seven, huh...
That's odd, though.
Until now, the riddles have
been fairly straightforward.
But...
"Middle of the seven?"
That's too vague a clue.
What does it mean?
Episode Preview
What does the number seven remind you of?
The seven colors of the rainbow?
There are seven notes
in a musical scale, too.
What? You found the bomb?
We found all three of the bombs!
Tell us how to disarm them!
Answer me!
The Pop-up Book Bomber
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Pop-up Book Bomber, Part Two!"
Seven
Next Conan's hint!
Seven!
What does the number seven remind you of?
Don't miss the next episode.
Ultra!
Wild!
Mild?
They're products of their generations...