Detective Conan Episode 884 "The
Pop-up Book Bomber (Part Two)"
Mori Detective Agency
The unfinished pop-up book
Kogoro-no-occhan
received in the mail contained
a series of bomb threats.
It was thought to be the work of
the dead author's half-brother
with a previous conviction of manufacturing
explosives, Hirukawa Takuji.
Hirukawa Takuji (38)
Bomber
Through the old man's efforts,
the second explosion was
successfully avoided.
All right.
We did it!
Private Caller
Tick tock, tick tock.
Boom!
Well done, Detective Mori Kogoro.
But the game isn't over yet.
Wh-What?!
Grandpa Tick Tock and the Three Clocks
"Grandpa Tick Tock is a clock maker."
By Imai Kenichi
"Tick tock, tick tock."
"Deliver the final clock
to the middle of the 7."
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
The pop-up book and the final bomb.
The mystery of seven takes us
in an unexpected direction.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Pop-up Book Bomber
(Part Two)
"The Pop-up Book Bomber, Part Two!"
Deliver the final clock
to the middle of the 7.
Damn it!
What does the middle of seven mean?
Divide seven by two is 3.5.
"Nana"...
nana
Between "na" and "na?"
na
Seven!
"V?"
V
None of them seem right.
I have no idea!
Hey, you!
You really don't remember
the answer to the riddle?!
I'm sorry.
Tomonaga Hiroyuki (45)
Editor In Chief
Like I mentioned before,
publication was delayed.
I was too busy handling
the incident to read it.
But I do remember the end.
The end?
It's not a 100% happy ending.
Our company wasn't sure it was
appropriate for a children's book.
I thought the same thing after reading it.
The drawings and pop-ups
are really cute, but...
What do you mean?
Grandpa Tick Tock dies.
You learn at the end that
he's actually really sick.
But in the epilogue,
his grandson takes over his
business ten years later,
so that's kind of a relief.
That's right.
Seriously? It's not a clue
to the bomb's location.
Anyway, what's the answer to the riddle?
I don't know.
I'm sorry.
What does the number seven remind you of?
Huh?
What's expressed in sevens?
Expressed in sevens?
Oh, right. Like the seven days of the week?
Yeah.
Or the seven colors of the rainbow?
There are seven notes
in a musical scale, too.
What's the middle of those?
In a week, that would be Thursday.
In a rainbow...
I think it's green.
In a musical scale, it's fa.
But there are too many things it could be.
Yeah, but what if a bomb were to explode
at a location related to those?
I-Inspector!
Of course we can't ignore it.
Have the entire department begin
searching for the bomb immediately.
Yes, sir!
Inspector, I'd only be getting in the way
if I stayed any longer.
You're right.
Now that the investigation has established
a direction, you're free to go.
Thank you.
Oh, thank you. Excuse me.
Oh, the picture book.
Let me see that, Conan-kun.
Excuse me.
Don't you need this?
Well, that's odd.
Until now,
the riddles were limited to a single answer,
Words beginning with "green"
but this time the riddle
itself is rather broad.
5 letter words including "tree"
Words beginning with "fa"
Kinomiri Park
Midori Law Office
Midori Elementary School
Green Green Restaurant
Jupiter Research Center and Observatory
Why?
And I'm still curious about the bomb
the old man threw into the manhole.
And finding the unexploded
bomb has been put on hold
There's no time to spare!
Search everywhere it could be!
since the entire department
has been mobilized.
Huh? Could it be?
Okay, good.
Keep searching.
Hey, Inspector!
What is it, Conan-kun?
What exactly did the bomber Hirukawa do?
What did he do?
Caused explosions, of course.
He manufactured explosives,
blew up the safes
and cash transport vehicles,
and stole a lot of money.
What about it?
Nothing.
That's nothing like this crime which seems
to be motivated by resentment.
Megrez Security
Did something happen?
I'm not sure.
What? You found the bomb?
The garbage collection point at the
#3 Thursday Building in Toriya City?
We found one, too.
Green Garden
It's at the orchard in Kenbashi City.
It was inside the management
office's trash can.
Alloy
We found one at "F.A. Alloy" in Daitoma City.
It's a gilding factory known
locally as "Fa Alloy."
It was found inside a garbage can.
Three bombs at once?
Is something wrong?
I'm sorry, but a bomb
was discovered up ahead.
What? A b-bomb?
We found all three of the bombs!
Tell us how to disarm them!
Hey, answer me!
Answer me!
Wow! Were you surprised?
Wh-What? They're all fake?
Wh-What does this mean?
Damn it.
What is Hirukawa trying to do?
It's a trap.
Huh?
Like the previous riddles, the
three fake bombs are trick answers.
The real one is somewhere else.
What?
Okay, okay.
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Okay, okay.
Is something wrong?
Hello, officer?
Megrez Security
Megrez Security...
Is something wrong, Conan-kun?
The Megrez in Megrez Security
refers to this star.
That's...
A picture of Ursa Major.
The Big Dipper?
That's right.
The seven stars forming
the tail of Ursa Major
are known as the Big Dipper.
And the center star is Megrez.
So it's the middle of seven.
Yeah.
Damn it. The culprit included the answer
because he knew we
wouldn't get there in time.
Inspector Megure!
Take a look at this.
Bomb Site
Kanematsu Park
Wh-What is this?
A map of the sewer?
That's right.
Going from the manhole at Kanematsu Park
where Mori-san threw the bomb to here.
Did that bomb flow all the way here?
Almost certainly.
Carried along by the increased
water level from yesterday's rain,
the bomb most likely stopped
at the grate under here.
Forensics says it's likely the explosion
was triggered by remote and not by a timer.
S-So, what does that mean?
In other words,
he always meant to blow up
the cash transport vehicle.
Wh-What?
Looks like he's right.
He made you throw the
bomb in the manhole
so it would end up here.
Which means the first bomb
was meant to camouflage this, too.
I-I don't believe it.
What does he think he's doing?
Inspector Megure!
Wh-What?
You found Hirukawa's hideout?
We'll head there.
Inspector, we're coming with you.
Okay.
Hey, wait!
How do you know it's his hideout?
We received an anonymous tip.
Huh?
They asked us to arrest the bomber
Hirukawa Takuji since they spotted him.
Then they left an address and hung up.
I see!
So that's how it is!
Well, well.
Looks like you've recovered from your injury,
Editor Tomonaga.
It's as though you were never
injured in the first place.
Wh-What's the meaning of this?
By the way, I heard you're
going independent soon.
Will you be funding yourself using the cash
Hirukawa stole from the transport truck?
Wh-What are you talking about?
I don't know what you mean.
Didn't you see the news?
What?
Hirukawa's hideout exploded
and burned down.
Oh, I just saw that.
According to the forensics team,
even when including the bills
thought to have burned,
the remaining bills they found
in the wreckage didn't add up
to the amount that was stolen.
I was wondering where the
remaining money went.
D-Don't ask me.
And apparently the location of the
hideout came from an anonymous tip.
I see.
They said to come arrest the bomber
Hirukawa Takuji since they spotted him.
So what?
It sounded like they were
using a voice changer.
That makes it difficult to
determine whose voice it was.
What does that have to do with me?
The problem isn't the
voice, but what was said.
What was said?
That's right.
Hirukawa's name hadn't been released
to the press at that time.
The only ones who knew it was him
were the police, us, and you.
No one else could have known.
Th-That's because they remembered
when his face was shown
during his last bombings.
You did?
What?
Who, me? Wh-Why would I remember?
Mori-san, do you think I did it?
Yes, I do.
Actually, I'm sure you did.
Tomonaga-san, you were
standing behind Hirukawa
like an editor guiding a new author.
I-If you think I did it, show me the proof.
While the bombs were equipped with timers,
they were all rigged to explode by remote.
According to forensics, the radio waves
from the remotes only worked
at a range of about thirty meters.
S-So what?
So only someone at the scene with
us could have sped up the timer
on the second bomb,
or sent me messages accordingly.
Only you, Tomonaga Hiroyuki-san.
Later, you asked the inspector
if you could accompany us,
and sent me messages in
response to my actions.
Am I wrong?
You suggested to Hirukawa that
he attack the transport truck
while making it look like he
was out to avenge his brother.
You also involved and used me, Mori Kogoro,
to hide your true intentions.
And you silenced Hirukawa himself
by using the extra bomb you had him make.
Impressive, Detective.
What a truly interesting deduction.
Once I go independent, why
not write mysteries for me?
A mystery by a great detective.
That's sure to become a best seller.
But it's all just speculation.
You have no proof.
Hardcore mystery fans will
surely criticize you for that.
This isn't a mystery.
This is an actual case.
A confession from Hirukawa
would change the story.
Wh-What are you talking about?
He should be dead—
At least, that's what
they said on the news...
No, the news didn't mention
anything about that.
Neither did I.
What?
Y-You don't mean...
That's right.
Hirukawa survived.
Thanks to Mori-kun's reasoning.
I didn't understand then why a
man who'd forgotten the answer
to the riddle suddenly started talking
about the illustrations in the picture book,
but you wanted them to be the same.
You wanted the culprit's suicide
and the illustration in the book to overlap.
Realizing that, Mori-san asked us drive ahead
of the force to take Hirukawa into custody.
We passed the police cars on their way and
used the rear entrance to his hideout.
We just barely got Hirukawa out in time.
Without realizing that, as soon as
the police surrounded the hideout,
you pressed the switch on the remote control.
I'm sure Hirukawa will have
some interesting things
to say once he learns he was
used and nearly killed by you.
Wh-When did you realize it was me?
When you said the author left
that proof to his brother.
Huh?
Conan.
Here!
Look at this.
This isn't a proof. It's clearly a copy.
It doesn't make sense for a
proof to be misaligned, right?
Hirukawa naturally would
have demanded the original,
but he said he didn't have it.
In other words, you must still have it.
Which means you would've looked
through it during this case,
but you lied about reading it.
Why?
Because you were the mastermind
who planned this crime.
Finally, I have a question for you.
Why didn't you give Hirukawa the original?
Because...
Because it was a masterpiece.
I'm still an editor.
I could tell.
Even if he was family, I didn't
want to turn it over to a criminal.
And tearing out the pages
that contained the clues...
Even though it was my plan, I
couldn't bring myself to do it.
Someday I planned to publish that manuscript.
Don't!
Huh?
Please don't.
You don't have the right!
It may have been a copy,
but you used that wonderful
picture book to commit a crime.
The author must be crying in heaven.
Ran...
Grandpa Tick Tock and the Three Clocks
Six months later,
whether according to the
editor's prediction or not,
the completed picture book was published
Winner of the 34th
New Author Award
Recommended
by the staff
and won the new author award.
It was an appropriate farewell gift
Author's Note
I love writing riddles
and drawing pictures.
Picture Book Author
Imai Kenichi-san
for the author who passed
away before his time,
but that's another story.
Despite all the running I did this time,
I don't feel like I accomplished anything.
I'm just tired.
Whatever, though.
Beer tastes better after a good workout.
That's good!
You always say that.
That's that.
Episode Preview
We just happened to be in London.
Oh, yeah? I'd like to say
a line as cool as that.
Anyway, are you sure about today?
Huh?
The date.
Yeah.
After all, today is...
Friday the 13th.
Huh?
Solving Mysteries at the Poirot Café
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "Solving
Mysteries at the Poirot Café, Part One!"
Seating Locations
Next Conan's hint!
Seating locations!
Kazuha-chan's coming next time.
Don't miss the next episode.
Which means Hattori is, too.
I sense love in the air.
I sense a case.