Mori Detective Agency
This is crazy.
It's so pretty.
Isn't it?
Heiji and I are on our way
now to check out the lights.
What?
Now?
Aren't these lights at Tokyo's Kinza Block 4?
Yeah, so we thought we'd invite you.
We're here.
Huh?
What?
Y-You actually came?
Yeah. We're busy at the end of the year.
Today's the only day we were free.
And you said you weren't busy this weekend.
Uh, yeah...
I guess not.
But I just got back from grocery shopping.
I haven't made dinner yet.
Dad said he'd be home around seven,
so I need to start cooking.
Then I'll help you.
Let's whip something up and go have
dinner while we look at the lights.
What?
Come on!
Uh, okay.
Don't worry about paying for dinner.
We brought meal tickets to a café in Kinza.
You boys have fun at Poirot downstairs.
Sure.
Hey, Kudo.
Huh?
If you're planning on asking why we came...
I'm not.
I already know.
Fine, then.
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
I wish I could give Hattori my support,
but a strange customer
arrives at Café Poirot.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Solving Mysteries at the Poirot Café
(Part One)
"Solving Mysteries at the
Poirot Café, Part One!"
Mori Detective Agency
I'm surprised Hattori-kun
agreed to go to such a romantic place.
I was surprised, too.
I expected him to say something
like "don't be stupid."
Wow, it's so pretty!
Apparently they're the
lights at Kinza Block 4.
It must be crazy in person.
Wanna go, then?
What?
My mom won some tickets to a
café in Kinza in a lottery.
She said she wasn't sure what to do with
them since she didn't have time to go.
Do I sense romance in the air?
Huh?
There you go again.
You always think there's
love in the air, Ran-chan.
Huh? This meat and potatoes
doesn't taste like anything.
What?
Oh, no. We forgot to put the soy sauce in.
No way.
What are we going to do?
We've already boiled it quite a bit.
The ingredients will turn to sludge
before they absorb the flavor.
Let's make curry instead.
Y-Yeah.
Who comes all the way to Tokyo for that?
Shut up, idiot.
You went all the way to London
to tell her how you feel.
I-In my case...
What an idiot.
Huh?
You mean you can't tell?
Aren't you a detective?
A detective should be able
to deduce how I feel!
You idiot!
H-Hey! Wait, Ran!
Hey!
No! Let go!
You're a tough one.
What?
You're like a tough case.
There's all these distracting emotions.
Even if I were Holmes, it'd
still be impossible to solve.
It's impossible
to accurately read the
heart of the girl I love.
W-We just happened to be in London.
Oh, yeah? I'd like to say
a line as cool as that.
Anyway, are you sure about today?
Huh?
The date.
Yeah.
After all, today is...
Friday the 13th.
Huh?
Is that why?
There are various theories on why
it's considered an unlucky day.
The most common ones are because
Jesus Christ's last supper
was attended by 13 people,
or because the number 13
doesn't fit in the duodecimal system.
And Jesus was crucified on a Friday.
President Kennedy was also assassinated
in Dallas on a Friday, wasn't he?
But we're in Japan.
You have nothing to worry about.
The 13th day of the month
just happened to be a Friday.
Statistically speaking,
it happens twice a year.
You shouldn't worry about telling the
object of your affection how you feel.
Besides, Jesus and Kennedy
didn't die on the 13th.
But on Friday the 13th...
On the Friday of October 13th, 1307,
King Philip IV had all the Knights
Templar in France arrested.
They were unjustly tortured
and burned at the stake.
On the Friday of June 13th, 1483,
the notorious Richard III had one
of his advisors executed for treason.
Julius Caesar was also betrayed
and murdered by Brutus on Friday the 13th.
? ? ? ? (?)
Customer
Today is a very unlucky day.
Even in Japan, it should be avoided.
Oh, excuse me.
I happened to overhear your conversation
and couldn't help myself.
Wh-Who is this guy?
I didn't notice him at all.
Hey, does he come here often?
No, I think it's his first time here.
He came in right after you did.
Welcome.
Ozumi Meisuke (21)
Beika University Third-Year
Huh? They're still not here?
Fine, then.
You're with the Beika University drama
club that made a reservation, correct?
Your friends aren't here yet.
Sheesh. We're celebrating
Yui's birthday here today.
Reserved
When they show up, tell them
they can start without me.
Okay.
My stomach hasn't been feeling
well since this afternoon.
A-Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Coffee Poirot
Seriously?
Don't tell me we got here first.
Uh, no.
Ozumi-san arrived earlier.
He's in the bathroom.
Really?
Ozumi-kun didn't seem well this afternoon.
Then I have you to myself
while your boyfriend's gone.
Stop that.
Yamashita Yui (21)
Beika University Third-Year
Tengo, I'm telling you just in case,
but don't say anything about that.
Anzai Tengo (20)
Beika University Third-Year
Who knows?
I might let something slip
once I start to drink.
Sheesh. They don't serve alcohol here.
Huh? Really?
Nagatsuka-kun's still not here.
Yeah.
He's in the middle of filming
your birthday video right now.
After all, he's in love with you.
Nagatsuka-kun is? Yeah, right.
He always glares at me when I flirt with you.
He's just upset that you're flirting
with his friend's girlfriend.
Ozumi-kun and Nagatsuka-kun
went to the same high school.
You and I are just childhood friends.
We're just messing around.
Just friends, huh?
Either way, they'll find out soon enough.
What do you mean?
Nothing, my childhood friend Yui-chan.
I-I thought you were just childhood friends.
Nagatsuka Minoru (20)
Beika University Third-Year
Nagatsuka-kun.
Hey, you're late.
I got lost.
Lost?
We've been here plenty of times
before while hunting for locations.
Have we?
Last year we put on a play
based on this location.
We came here together then.
Our previous club president suggested
we build a set identical to this place.
We even measured the size of the
tables and height of the chairs.
Right, mister?
You remember, right?
I wasn't working here then.
Azusa-san, do you remember?
Yes.
I was asked about how we interact
with customers and serve dishes.
Have a seat.
Let's watch Yui's birthday video together.
You finished filming your part, right?
Yeah. I just sent it to your laptop.
Oh, yeah?
But Ozumi's not here yet.
He's in the bathroom.
Oh, we're going to make some noise.
Don't mind us.
Huh?
It's not turning on.
Is the battery dead?
Hey, miss.
Could we borrow an outlet?
Sure.
Here you go.
Thanks.
No way. A blackout?
I-I just saw a spark.
Y-Yeah, from the outlet.
Azusa-san, check the breaker.
O-Okay.
What?!
Azusa-san, hurry.
Okay.
What's all this noise about?
No way. A blackout?
I-I just saw a spark.
Y-Yeah, from the outlet.
Azusa-san, check the breaker.
Okay.
What?!
Azusa-san, hurry.
Okay.
What's all this noise about?
T-Tengo! Hang in there, Tengo!
Don't!
Don't touch him!
What?
This is a murder.
Don't carelessly damage the crime scene.
Looks like this is an attempted murder.
Azusa-san, call an ambulance and the police.
Got it.
Since he was stabbed with
such a long sashimi knife,
I thought he'd died instantly.
But there's no need to call the police.
When he was stabbed, some
blood flew onto my face.
And onto my glasses, too.
His blood must've gotten
on the culprit's hands or sleeves.
Coffee Poirot
You can't be serious.
Why isn't there blood on anyone?
You, sir. The man quietly trying to leave.
Could you show us your hands?
I wasn't trying to leave.
Th-There's no blood on him either.
Again?
Sheesh. Why does every
case have to be so hard?
Seriously, Hattori.
Are you sure you're not cursed?
Mori Detective Agency
What? Don't come to Poirot?
Why not?
We just finished making the old
man's dinner and are on our way.
There was actually a mur—
It must be crazy in person.
They're filming. They're filming for a movie.
Really? I wanna see.
You idiot! You'd better not come!
It's a super scary horror movie!
What?!
We'll meet you once we're finished here.
You guys go ahead without us.
O-Okay...
W-We're leaving without them?
They said they'd come later.
An ambulance?
Is it a hospital movie?
Let's go.
I'm excited to see the lights.
Yeah...
Coffee Poirot
I see.
Due to the thin wire wrapped around the plug
powering victim Anzai Tengo-san's laptop,
when the victim plugged it
into this extension cord,
it shorted out and caused a blackout.
And in the darkness, someone inside
the store stabbed the victim.
Yes, most likely.
But there's no blood on the hands or sleeves
of the victim's three friends
or the other customer.
There's none on Conan-kun and Hattori-kun,
who were also inside the café, or
employees Amuro-san and Azusa-san.
All of this despite the fact that Conan-kun
and Hattori-kun got blood on their faces,
and the table they were sitting
at was splattered with blood.
Did the victim always carry
this laptop with him?
Yes. He kept it in that bag on the floor.
But he left it in the club room all the time.
Anyone could've done something to it.
Yeah. He had a lot of enemies.
Enemies?
He frequently flirted with other
men's girlfriends and caused trouble.
He even flirted with my girlfriend Yui.
It's because we're childhood friends.
I told you he was just messing around.
His dad's a member of the Diet.
I heard he smoothed over a lot of
disputes for him behind the scenes.
I see.
By the way, the victim
seems to have been sitting
in this seat before the blackout occurred.
Where was everyone else sitting then?
I was sitting across from him in the booth.
I was sitting next to Anzai in that chair.
I see.
What about you, Ozumi-san?
I arrived before the others.
After setting my bag in the booth,
I was in the bathroom the whole time.
My stomach hasn't been feeling
well since this afternoon.
I see. In the bathroom.
That makes you the only one who could've
washed the blood off.
If you think I did it, you can search me!
Even if I washed it off with water,
there'd still be a something-or-other
reaction, right?
Luminol.
It's used to detect
nitrogen-containing compounds.
When mixed with hydrogen peroxide
and sprayed onto blood,
it reflects a pale light.
I doubt Ozumi-san will
produce a luminol reaction.
Before the police arrived,
I checked the security camera footage.
He came to Poirot first and
went into the bathroom.
Anzai-san and Yamashita-san arrived next.
Finally, Nagatsuka-san
arrived some time later.
The blackout occurred when they tried to
watch the birthday video on the laptop.
Until the footage cut
off due to the blackout,
the bathroom door remained
closed the whole time.
I doubt he could've known
who was sitting where.
But the bathroom has a peep hole.
Oh, this?
The glass is frosted.
You can't see what's going on in the store.
Let me see.
Y-You're right.
Hey, Kudo.
Who is that guy?
He's no ordinary café worker, is he?
Oh, he's...
Huh?
Who is he?
Oh, uh... He's a detective.
He was the old man's apprentice.
Seriously? That idiot's apprentice?
Then he's good for nothing.
Sheesh.
There's curry in the pot.
We'll be back before 9.
Ran
Seriously?
I'm exhausted from looking into an affair,
there's police cars parked outside Poirot,
and Ran's not home.
Who puts shirataki in curry, anyway?
That's pretty good, though.
Inspector.
I examined the possessions of those three.
Ozumi-san had keys, cigarettes,
a lighter, a wallet,
a phone, and a present for Yui-san,
which contained a necklace.
Yamashita Yui-san had a
handkerchief, tissues,
makeup, keys, and a wallet.
Nagatsuka-san had eye
drops, a wallet, a phone,
and a present for Yui-san containing gloves.
I searched Ozumi-san's bag as well,
but didn't find anything he
could've used to commit a crime.
I see.
Listen, detectives, you
seem to think we did it.
Couldn't it have been an outsider?
Maybe someone was waiting outside
the store for the blackout,
and came inside to stab him
with night vision goggles?
That seems unlikely.
Why do you say that?
Immediately after that man
was stabbed and screamed,
I stood in front of the entrance
so no one could get out.
Really?
That's why you were standing next
to the door when the lights came on.
Yes.
You must have pretty good night vision.
No. I just happened to
be using my phone to—
Listen to music.
I used that faint light.
Music?
Come to think of it, you
haven't told us your name yet.
My name?
I'm Wada Shinichi.
I work in medicine.
I-I see...
So I'm curious why
no one has any blood on them.
Wada Shinichi?
Episode Preview
There's no blood on anyone.
I didn't know who was sitting where either.
I thought of a trick to avoid
getting blood on yourself, but...
"From between long clouds
blown by the fall wind..."
Wh-Where did that come from?
One Hundred Poems by One Hundred Poets?
So that's how it is.
I know exactly what happened.
Solving Mysteries at the Poirot Café
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Solving
Mysteries at the Poirot Café, Part Two!"
Toilet Paper
Next Conan's hint!
Toilet paper!
A detective's apprentice and medical worker?
Don't miss the next episode.
Who are these dudes?
There sure are a lot of detectives around.