Toyama Kazuha and Hattori
Heiji came to invite us
to see the holiday lights
everyone's talking about.
While waiting for Ran and Kazuha
to finish making dinner,
Hattori and I went to kill time at Poirot,
the café below the agency.
That's when Beika University
drama club members
Ozumi Meisuke (21)
Beika University Third-Year
Ozumi Meisuke-san,
Yamashita Yui (21)
Beika University Third-Year
Yamashita Yui-san,
Anzai Tengo (20)
Beika University Third-Year
Anzai Tengo-san,
Nagatsuka Minoru (20)
Beika University Third-Year
and Nagatsuka Minoru-san arrived.
Have a seat.
Let's watch Yui's birthday video together.
You finished filming your part, right?
Yeah. I just sent it to your laptop.
Oh, yeah?
But Ozumi's not here yet.
He's in the bathroom.
Oh, we're going to make some noise.
Don't mind us.
Huh?
It's not turning on.
Is the battery dead?
Hey, miss.
Could we borrow an outlet?
Sure.
Here you go.
Thanks.
No way. A blackout?
I-I just saw a spark.
Y-Yeah, from the outlet.
Azusa-san, check the breaker.
O-Okay.
What?
Azusa-san, hurry.
Okay.
What's all this noise about?
Coffee Poirot
There's no need to call the police.
When he was stabbed, some
blood flew onto my face.
And onto my glasses, too.
His blood must've gotten on
the culprit's hands or sleeves.
You can't be serious.
Why isn't there blood on anyone?
Listen, detectives, you
seem to think we did it.
Couldn't it have been an outsider?
Maybe someone was waiting outside the store
for the blackout and came inside to
stab him with night vision goggles?
That seems unlikely.
Why do you say that?
Immediately after that man
was stabbed and screamed,
I stood in front of the entrance
so no one could get out.
Really?
That's why you were standing next
to the door when the lights came on.
Yes.
You must have pretty good night vision.
No. I just happened to
be using my phone to—
Listen to music.
I used that faint light.
Music?
Come to think of it, you
haven't told us your name yet.
My name?
I'm Wada Shinichi.
I work in medicine.
Wada Shinichi?
Curtains rise as the headliner appears!
He beautifully dances his
mystery-solving steps!
A case at the Poirot Café
is tackled by Heiji, Amuro,
and the mysterious Wada Shinichi.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Solving Mysteries at the Poirot Café
(Part Two)
"Solving Mysteries at the
Poirot Café, Part Two!"
He's got the same name as you.
Huh?
Conan-kun, isn't your name Conan?
H-He meant to say "your
favorite Shinichi-niichan."
Heiji-niichan can be unclear sometimes.
Sorry.
I-I see...
Anyway, Kudo, do you know who did it?
No, not yet.
I thought of a trick to avoid
getting blood on yourself, though.
You, too?
But the person who could've used the trick...
...couldn't have committed the crime.
Damn.
I gotta solve this quick
so we can go to Kinza.
Hey.
Yamashita Yui-san.
What is it?
You said you and Anzai-san
are just childhood friends,
but that's not true, is it?
If there's something going
on, could you tell me?
It might help us solve the case.
Sorry, but I can't say.
What? But...
It's...
a secret I have to keep to protect someone.
When I was your age, I didn't
think I had any secrets either.
R-Really?
Honestly, I have way too
many secrets at the moment.
Hey, Kudo.
You know how late the Kinza
lights are staying on?
No.
"From between long clouds
blown by the fall wind,
the moonlight shining through
is beautiful indeed."
One Hundred Poems by One Hundred Poets?
I see.
So that's how it is.
I know exactly what happened.
Hey, detectives.
Can't we go now?
I'm sorry that Anzai got stabbed,
but none of us did it.
There's no blood on anyone.
I don't think we could've stabbed anyone
in the pitch blackness of the blackout.
You'd need night vision goggles.
I was in the bathroom
since before the blackout,
so I couldn't have stabbed him.
The peep hole in the bathroom
door is made with frosted glass.
I couldn't have known who was sitting where.
"From between long clouds..."
"From between long clouds
blown by the fall wind,
the moonlight shining through
is beautiful indeed."
Wh-Where did that come from?
O-One Hundred Poems by One Hundred Poets?
It's a poem by Sakyo no Daibu Akisuke.
It means the moon seen through clouds blown
by the fall wind is super pretty.
And the culprit also saw who was
sitting where through a gap.
What are you doing?
Uh, nothing. Don't mind me.
Right?
The man who was hiding in the bathroom and
secretly watching through the peep hole...
I'm asking you, Ozumi Meisuke-san.
What?
H-Hey, Ozumi...
Is this true, Ozumi-kun?
Wh-What are you talking about?!
Didn't you hear me?!
The peep hole's made of frosted glass!
Hey, Azusa-san.
Do you have any tape?
Yes.
But what do you need this for?
My science teacher told
me that if you put tape
on the rough side of frosted
glass, it's like normal glass.
What? Really?
Try putting some tape on the
peep hole and look through it.
Okay...
You're right.
I can see through the
spot covered by the tape.
Can you see me?
You're right.
I wouldn't call it totally transparent,
but you can see who's sitting where.
B-But why?
It's difficult to see through frosted
glass because tiny scratches
on its surface reflect light,
making it appear cloudy.
By putting tape over it,
the adhesive on the tape fills
the scratches in the glass,
flattening the surface and
making it transparent.
B-But I don't have any tape on me.
There was tape on the birthday
present you got for Yui-san.
After looking through the frosted glass,
you could've put it back on the present.
E-Even if I could see the
others through the peep hole,
I couldn't have stabbed
anyone in the darkness.
So you practiced, didn't you?
You arranged chairs and tables in your room
in the same layout at this café so
you could stab someone in the dark.
If you built a set identical to
this café for your play last year,
those measurements must still be
in your drama club room somewhere.
E-Even if I knew the exact layout,
it'd still be hard to stab someone.
Yes.
From the front, their hands would get in
the way, making it difficult to stab them.
But from their blindside, as long as you knew
where they were sitting, it would be possible.
That's why you came first and
put your bag on the booth seat,
knowing your girlfriend
Yui-san would sit next to it.
I see.
If the booth seats were occupied,
the victim would be forced to sit in
either of the chairs opposite them.
B-But what about the blood?
Even if I could stab him, I
would've gotten blood on me!
You made sure you wouldn't.
Using something you found in the bathroom.
Wow, it's so pretty!
It's like Tinkerbell's gonna
show up any minute.
I know. It's like a dream world.
Hey, Kazuha-cha...
Kazuha-chan?
I'm glad it's just the two of us.
What?
If I saw this in person with Heiji,
I might've felt something crazy.
What a relief.
Seriously.
K-Kazuha!
I love you, too, Kazuha!
Heiji doesn't talk like that.
Oh, sorry!
But thanks, Ran-chan.
Sure.
Anyway, I wonder what Heiji's doing.
He's not answering his phone.
Yeah.
You're late.
Sorry, sorry.
Anyway, you shouldn't have
suddenly changed where we'd meet.
I wanted Poirot's sandwiches.
You haven't heard?
There's something crazy going on at the café.
Apparently there was a murder.
Seriously?
Yeah. Some guy was stabbed
and taken to the hospital.
T-Toilet paper?
He used toilet paper to prevent
blood from getting on himself?
Yeah.
He wrapped it around his arms like a mummy.
You idiot.
You couldn't block all the blood
just by covering your arms.
No, that's all you need.
You held the cardboard tube around the
knife against his back as you stabbed him.
By holding the tube in place
as you pulled the knife out,
you could avoid getting
any blood on yourself.
That's why you chose a long knife.
Otherwise you couldn't have
stabbed him through the tube.
A little blood's bound
to come through the tube,
but as long as you don't point the
opening towards yourself, you're okay.
Instead, those of us sitting in front
of the tube got blood all over us.
Then you returned to the bathroom and
waited for the lights to come back on,
flushed the toilet paper
wrapped around your arms,
and stuck the tube you used
back inside the toilet paper.
Then you removed the
tape from the peep hole
and stuck it back on the gift
and came out of the bathroom.
No, you may have removed the
tape before the lights came on.
By folding the end of the tape over
and making it easier to grab,
you could've removed it in the dark.
If the bathroom lights came back on
first and someone saw the peep hole,
they might have noticed that
there was something stuck to it.
Either way,
the middle of the toilet paper
was sticking out slightly.
That's a sure sign the tube was
forced inside it afterwards.
I think the police would find Anzai-san's
blood and your fingerprints on it.
Th-This can't be true, Ozumi!
Ozumi-kun, you'd never stab Tengo.
It annoyed me.
Why do you call your boyfriend "Ozumi-kun,"
when you call Anzai by his given name?
B-Because we're childhood friends.
You're not just childhood friends, are you?!
There must be some reason for it!
I-I...
See? You can't say it!
I'm sure he's your ex or something!
But I had to hurt him because you
were keeping secrets from me!
Honestly, I was scared since the
knife went deeper than I expected.
You're wrong.
They're probably
half-siblings.
Wh-What?
Yui-san, you said you were keeping
the secret to protect someone,
and that you didn't think you
had any secrets as a child.
The reason you said
"someone" instead of Tengo
is because you meant someone
related to Anzai-san,
or in this case, Anzai-san's
father the Dietman.
If it wasn't a secret when you were kids,
but became one when you grew up,
it means it would be a career
ending scandal for a Dietman.
In other words, Yui-san is
his lover's secret lovechild.
I-It's what Heiji-niichan said.
Y-Yeah, that's right.
I-Is this true?
Y-Yes.
While my parents argued over compensation,
they would leave me and
Tengo to play together.
We became close.
Y-You're lying.
I don't believe this.
You're not all pulling my leg, are you?
Incoming Call
From Public Phone
A-A phone call?
Who is it?
That hurt, damn it!
I'm gonna kill you the next time I see you!
Ouch...
Well, my behavior was
hardly worthy of praise.
I can see how you got the wrong idea.
In any case, I sent Yui's
birthday video to your phone.
Check it out.
I was going to turn up the volume
so you could hear it in the bathroom.
Later.
You'd better come visit me.
B-Birthday video?
I have an announcement to make!
Yui and I are actually half-siblings! Yeah!
Since Dad's election is coming up,
Yui said not to say anything,
but I don't care!
So take good care of my sister, Ozumi.
I mean brother.
Later!
N-No...
No...
You should've tried talking
to him before stabbing him.
Wait, I don't have time for this!
I've gotta get to Kinza Block 4!
We're not going to Kinza.
We're going to Tokyo Station.
K-Kazuha!
If we don't hurry, we'll miss our train home.
Wait, Hattori-kun!
We still need to question him about the case.
Well, I guess we can interview
the people who are still here.
Wait, what?
Wada Shinichi-san is missing.
Wada Shinichi-san?
He was here until a moment ago.
There was a strange man by that name
claiming to be a medical professional.
That may have been a fake name.
Shinichi told me once that the translations
from the Meiji Era of the Sherlock
Holmes stories were set in Japan.
Both Holmes and Watson were Japanese.
Watson was an army surgeon
named Wada Shinichi.
It's just a possibility, but...
That's right.
And since he called himself Wada Shinichi
instead of using Komuro Tairoku,
Holmes' Japanese name, does that mean
there's a Holmes-esque
individual standing behind me,
ready to feed me hints in the form of poems?
His reasoning skills lived
up to his reputation.
I was impressed.
That wasn't deduction.
You could hear the sound of something
being ripped off under the man's scream.
A sound?
Now that you mention it, I
thought I heard something.
Anyway, I'm glad
that my hint helped Heiji-kun.
Though as his future wife, it's only natural.
Your recitation of the poem melted my heart.
I'm sorry I didn't do a better job.
So, what did you think of Heiji-kun?
It's no wonder he caught your eye.
His appearance, personality, and reasoning
abilities leave nothing to be desired.
There does seem to be a
girl he's interested in,
but she's no match for you, Momiji-sama.
I, Iori, shall do everything
I can to support you.
Iori Muga (30)
Otsuka Family Butler
Episode Preview
Oh, Samizu Kichiemon, huh?
All the books in the study were donated.
I keep them here in this room.
It looks like an ordinary box to me.
Yes.
It's exactly the kind of thing that
moonlit magician-thief goes after.
A big jewel.
Kaito Kid and the Trick Box
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "Kaito
Kid and the Trick Box, Part One!"
Music Box
Next Conan's hint!
A music box!
Don't miss the next episode.
Thank you for another year!
Merry Christmas!