Happy New Year.
Word on the street is the sandwiches
that waiter at Poirot makes are pretty good.
So this year, I'll present my
meat and potatoes to the world,
sell a boatload, and make fistfuls of money.
Boatloads and fistfuls, boatloads
and fistfuls, boatloads—
Once again...
...we appreciate your continued support in 2018!
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
It's been a while! Happy New Year!
I'll be keeping you in check again this year!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kaito Kid and the Trick Box
(Part One)
"Kaito Kid and the Trick Box, Part One!"
Aha.
So this is "Mokujin,"
the trick box made by mid-19th
Century tinkerer Samizu Kichiemon.
I'm delighted you're giving me this,
in addition to all those valuable books.
I'm not giving you the box.
I want you to open it.
Tomoyose Kimika (70)
Widow
My husband, who passed away last month,
left something important
to me inside that box.
I see.
Apparently my husband
stuck the instructions
to open the box inside a book.
I'd like you to find that paper
within the books I've given to you.
I see.
So, what's inside the box?
The world's largest
moonstone, "Luna Memoria."
Yes...
It's exactly the kind of thing that
moonlit magician-thief goes after.
A big jewel.
"To Kaito Kid,"
"Tonight the world's largest
moonstone, Luna Memoria,
will be on display at the Suzuki Library."
"The jewel is inside a trick
box made by Samizu Kichiemon."
"If you want to see it, you'll either
have to open the box yourself,
or find the written instructions
in the library."
To Kaito Kid!
"General Adviser to the Suzuki
Conglomerate, Suzuki Jirokichi."
Jeez.
That old man is up to his old tricks again.
If you're going, you'd better hurry up.
You've been invited, too, right?
After all, you're the Kid Killer.
Yeah. I just got a message from Ran.
Wait, what do you mean by "too?"
I've been invited by the
general adviser as well.
Since I'm a professional tinkerer,
he's asked me to open the
box before Kid arrives.
I doubt you'd be able to open
a Samizu Kichiemon trick box.
Huh? A-Ai-kun?
Samizu Kichiemon, huh?
Sounds interesting.
Subaru-san?
I was told last time that the
vegetables weren't cooked enough.
So I came to share some of this thoroughly
stewed meat and potatoes I made.
What?
You want to go, too?
No. I'll leave this here and go.
I'm not interested in thieves.
Though I do have some interest
in those who take lives rather than things.
He's always wearing those turtlenecks.
What's his deal?
Yikes.
Maybe he gets cold easily.
Turtlenecks are just about the only thing
that cover his choker-shaped voice changer.
Kudo
Professor, what are you doing?
Sorry, sorry.
I couldn't find my license.
Suzuki Library
Ran!
You're late.
The kids are already here.
Sorry, sorry.
Dad caught a cold.
We had to stop at the hospital.
Is he okay?
I told him he didn't have to come.
It's just a head cold.
How could I not come after
he offered me front row tickets
to an Okino Yoko concert?
Will you even be helpful in your condition?
He always comes through
at the critical moment.
Yeah, right. I actually made it
easier for Kid to sneak in...
How do front row tickets sound?
I'll be there!
By inviting more people for
him to disguise himself as.
Ah.
Detective Mori, thank you for coming.
Come in and examine
the trick box for yourself.
Don't worry.
Inspector Nakamori and I have agreed that
he won't pinch any faces,
and that the police
will wait outside.
What?
The inspector's not going inside?
Then there's no point in
disguising myself as him.
In that case...
My mother said to pick...
The very best one and you are it.
I see.
So this is the trick box.
It's supposed to open when you
push or pull a certain part.
It looks like an ordinary box to me.
I'll force it open!
Don't!
Ow!
Punished
I wouldn't expect any less
from Samizu Kichiemon.
It's like a mini Iron Tanuki.
What is that thing?
It shoots out needles if
you're careless with it.
I got these when I touched it earlier.
Then why don't we put it
in a vice and cut it open?
It's just made of wood.
You mustn't.
That was made by the famous
tinkerer Samizu Kichiemon.
The box itself is worth as much
as the moonstone inside it.
But I thought moonstones
weren't that valuable.
I see them going for about ten
thousand yen online all the time.
What are you talking about?
My husband went all the way
to the source in Sri Lanka
to buy the one in the box.
Its beautiful moonlight blue
luster is a true example of—
Adularescence.
Moonstones that produce that
optical phenomenon are valuable.
Furthermore, at that size,
it may truly be as valuable as
a Samizu Kichiemon trick box.
I thought you weren't interested.
My curiosity got the better of me.
I'm surprised you got in.
When I told them I knew Professor Agasa,
they let me in without searching me.
That's how we're doing things this time.
We're turning away obvious Kid fans,
but we're letting in the general public.
We're also leaving the box on this table
without any guards posted.
Won't he run away with the box?
Don't worry.
When I push this switch,
the scale embedded in the floor activates.
If the weight removed by a person leaving
is even a gram off
from the weight added when they entered...
This happens.
How very Samizu Kichiemon-esque.
Naturally, if he quietly
opens the box and attempts
to take just the jewel inside,
the same thing will happen.
He won't be able to open it quietly.
When the box is opened,
the music box inside it
plays a beautiful melody.
I heard a music box playing
in the middle of the night,
and found my husband in the study
opening the box, admiring the contents,
and then winding the key before
putting it back together.
What song does it play?
The last time my husband opened the
box was more than a decade ago.
I can't remember.
It's a famous melody everyone knows.
I think it may have been a nursery
song or something similar.
Even if he slips through the bars
with the box and jewel,
the steel shutters installed at every exit
are programmed to shut along with the cage.
No one will be able to escape.
I see.
So she wants to open the box no matter what.
Even if it means getting help from Kaito Kid.
So, where are the written
instructions for opening the box?
After my husband closed the box,
I saw him putting a piece
of paper with a diagram
of the box with arrows and
numbers inside a book.
Later my husband found me searching
the study for that book.
Oh?
So you saw me opening the trick box.
But you won't be able to find it.
What?
Not that paper or the contents of the box.
That's what he said, so I
assume the instructions
to open the box were written on that paper.
Why did your husband hide
that jewel from you?
Who knows?
My husband was a very shy man.
What?
Oh, that is,
moonstones are said to bring about love.
Perhaps he didn't want me to see him
so carefully keeping such a stone.
Her husband was one of
my adventuring friends.
He certainly was a shy man.
When we circled the world
in our man-powered plane,
he hid behind me when the media
came to take photos of us.
So, has Kid told you he's coming?
Yes.
We just received a message reading,
"As the moonlit magician,
I swear on my title that I
will come for the moonstone."
Which means in order to
open the box before Kid,
instead of blindly fiddling with the box,
it would be faster to find the book
containing the written instructions to open it.
All the books in the study
were donated to the library.
I keep them here in this room.
Then if we split up and search for...
What?
Wait...
Seriously?
All of these?
There's about ten thousand of them.
It's worth finding, don't you think?
This is way too many...
T-Ten thousand?
This is just like the
study at Shinichi's house.
You're right...
But the instructions to open that box
are inside one of these books, right?
How are we supposed to find it?
There.
We'll have to search each one.
I wish you'd done this before we arrived.
I had my entire staff spend
a whole day searching,
but they didn't find the paper.
What?
Though since there's ten thousand books,
instead of reading each individual page,
they flipped through them
like you're doing now.
Normally if there's something
stuck between the pages,
the books should open right to it.
Is it possible your husband
hid the paper somewhere else?
No.
My husband died last month in
an unfortunate traffic accident.
He couldn't have foreseen that
and hidden the paper elsewhere.
But your husband hasn't open
the box in ten years, right?
Not that I saw.
Apparently he secretly
opened it while I was out.
When I returned,
he would always say the same thing.
Looks like you still haven't opened the box.
What?
The instructions were
still in the same place.
If you're able to find that paper,
you should be able to find
the true contents of the box.
I guess this was too much for you.
But if you insist, I'll show
you where the page is hidden.
It's a bit embarrassing, though.
Is what he'd say.
The true contents?
Does that mean there's something
inside the box besides the moonstone?
I-I'm not sure.
I've never opened it, so I have no idea.
If he said he'd tell you,
you should've asked him which book it was.
I was frustrated.
He made it sound as though I'd never find it.
Did you search for the paper after that?
Yes, while my husband was out.
In the end, I never found it.
Then maybe it's in a book
you wouldn't normally read.
You're right.
I tend not to read
murder mysteries or monster stories.
Those books are kept around there.
Then we'll start there.
Before we start searching,
why don't you go to the bathroom to take
the cough medicine we got at the hospital?
Fine.
If you're taking your medicine,
there was a vending machine in the lobby.
Yeah, yeah.
If you're going to the
bathroom, I'll join you.
Me, too.
Open the Trick Box!!
Anyone able to open the trick box made my mid-19th Century
tinkerer Samizu Kichiemon will be awarded one million yen! Each
person has only five minutes to open the box. Attempting to open the box may result in injury. Do not attempt to steal the box.
Suzuki Jirokichi
Ow!
Ow...
The trick box is a huge hit.
Ah, Conan-kun.
There you are.
You took forever in the bathroom, Professor.
My stomach hasn't been feeling well.
Maybe I caught Mori-kun's cold.
Anyway, I thought Mori-kun left
the bathroom shortly before I did.
He's taking another stab
at opening the trick box.
He should just give up.
What?!
This cage moves?!
Of course.
It uses sensors to accurately
capture any moving object.
Otherwise it'd cause major injury.
What's all this noise?
Detective Mori was just joking around.
I was just checking to make sure the
anti-theft measures were working...
Oh, my! It's wet!
Huh?
If any water got inside...
Uh, because it's a wooden box.
It can't get wet.
Right.
Huh? Where are Ran-neechan
and Sonoko-neechan?
They went to the bathroom
immediately after you did.
Then they're taking a long time.
The women's restroom was crowded.
So, have you found the paper?
Not yet.
I saw some mystery novels I hadn't
read yet and couldn't help myself.
I smell soy sauce and mirin.
Were you making meat and potatoes?
Yes.
He made some before coming here.
Perhaps he spilled some on his sleeve.
Oh, my. You cook?
Yes, some.
Meat and potatoes is my specialty.
It was my husband's favorite.
I had his mother teach me.
Subaru-san, you cook?
How surprising.
Speaking of cooking, my husband bought
countless cookbooks for me
since I loved to cook so much.
I read them so often, they were
practically falling apart.
Then we can skip cookbooks.
Huh? Sonoko, did you put on some makeup?
While we were in the bathroom.
After all, Kid-sama is coming.
I need to dress up for him.
Even if he does come,
the anti-theft mechanisms
and trick box will probably prevent him
from taking the moonstone.
Not even that pretentious
thief could manage that.
I wouldn't be so sure.
This presence...
It's him.
He's nearby.
Who?
Who is he disguised as?
Episode Preview
What?
A-A blackout?
It's Kid! Kid-sama is here!
Get those lights back on.
I've taken the contents of the box.
Kaito Kid
"I-I've taken the contents of the box."
Huh?
Looks like you've figured
it out, too, Detective.
Kaito Kid and the Trick Box
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Kaito
Kid and the Trick Box, Part Two!"
Exchange Diary
Next Conan's hint!
An exchange diary!
Don't miss the next episode.
Sorry for troubling you so early in the year.
You're just entertaining me.