Inside "Mokujin," a trick box
made by Samizu Kichiemon,
is the big jewel and Kaito
Kid's target "Luna Memoria."
And the instructions to open the box
can be found in one of ten thousand
books donated to the Suzuki Library.
It's worth finding, don't you think?
This is way too many...
Is it possible your husband
hid the page somewhere else?
No.
Tomoyose Kimika
(70) Widow
My husband died last month in
an unfortunate traffic accident.
He couldn't have foreseen that
and hidden the page elsewhere.
Then maybe it's in a book
you wouldn't normally read.
You're right.
I tend not to read
murder mysteries or monster stories.
Huh? Sonoko, did you put on some makeup?
While we were in the bathroom.
After all, Kid-sama is coming.
I need to dress up for him.
Even if he does come, the
anti-theft mechanisms
and trick box will probably prevent
him from taking the moonstone.
Not even that pretentious
thief could manage that.
I wouldn't be so sure.
This presence...
It's him.
He's nearby.
Who?
Who is he disguised as?
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
I'll see through the disguise of the thief
coming after the trick box full of memories!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kaito Kid and the Trick Box
(Part Two)
"Kaito Kid and the Trick Box, Part Two!"
Suzuki Library
The old man hasn't been coughing
since he came back from the bathroom.
Akai-san seems more interested in
his surroundings than his book.
The professor spent too long in the bathroom.
The only ones who aren't suspicious
are Jirokichi and the old woman.
With the remote for the security devices,
he'd have plenty of opportunities
to swap out the box.
And Kid wouldn't get so upset
over the box getting wet.
What about Ran and Sonoko?
Kid's disguised himself
as them before, hasn't he?
What's wrong?
There's a book up there
that I'm interested in,
but I can't reach it.
I could probably get it if I used a ladder,
but they're both being used.
I'll hold your chair for you.
Thanks.
I'll use their heights to identify them.
Since they're both about
as tall as the professor...
Huh?
I can almost see her underwear...
No, wait. It could be Kid disguised as her.
But these thighs are definitely...
What a nice view.
Oh, uh...
You may look like a child, but you're
a dirty old man on the inside.
Pervert.
It's no use. I can't reach it.
I was just observing her to
see if it was Kid in disguise.
We'll have to wait for one
of the ladders to open up.
So you're a huge pervert.
Yeah, sorry I'm such a pervert!
Anyway, can't you sense his presence, too?
Who knows? I don't feel anything.
Aside from him, couldn't he be anybody?
He's the only one who's been
in this room the whole time.
No.
It's possible he's been disguised as Okiya
Subaru all along and snuck in that way.
Damn it.
Everyone's starting to look suspicious...
Here. Isn't this the book you wanted?
Thanks!
What's this?
"13 Conditions For Dating a Detective?"
Don't look!
I'm not sure if it will help,
but embarrassingly enough,
my husband and I kept an exchange
diary when we were students.
Exchange Diary
It was a very strange diary.
Strange how?
We agreed that my husband
would write on the left,
and I would write on the right.
But I couldn't fit all the day's events
or how I felt about my
husband on a single page.
So I'd fill three whole pages
so my husband could write on the left.
But my husband only ever
wrote a few sentences.
Maybe he just wasn't much of a writer.
That's what I though at the time.
But just after we got married,
I found the exchange diary
on my husband's desk.
As I was reading the awkward
writing of my younger self
with feelings of embarrassment
and nostalgia,
I suddenly came across two full pages
of my husband's writing
that I didn't recognize
from our days as students.
My husband took it from
me immediately after that.
You can't read that. It's secret.
I haven't seen the exchange diary since.
I wonder what that was.
Perhaps it's related to the
piece of paper we can't find.
Maybe the pages were glued together.
Your husband may have been eating
rice balls while reading that page.
A grain of rice could've
fallen between the pages.
My husband was a very shy man.
I had his mother teach me.
If any water got inside...
It was a very strange diary.
If you're able to find that paper,
you should be able to find
the true contents of the box.
Ah, that face.
Looks like you've figured
it out, too, Detective.
Both where that paper is and
the true contents of the box.
What?
You figured out where the written
instructions to open the box are?
Yeah.
And why we haven't been able to find it.
Conan-kun, what do you mean?
You're not just making things up, are you?
Could I borrow a notebook and pen?
Will these work?
Thanks.
First, we'll tear out a single page.
And tear that page in half again.
On the front and back of the
torn page, we'll draw a circle.
There. Now study it carefully
and remember what it looks like.
Okay.
It's just a circle, right?
Once you've memorized it, can you
put it back inside the notebook?
Here.
Thanks.
Abracadabra.
I command this paper to disappear!
Here.
Now you can't find it.
Don't be ridiculous!
By flipping through it,
it should instantly...
Huh?
This can't be possible.
It must be in here somewhere.
Huh?
I-It disappeared?
Wow!
You didn't secretly take it out, did you?
I wouldn't do that.
After all...
See? It's still in here.
No way!
How?
The trick is in the edge of the page.
See how the bottom edge of the page
is slightly torn where the paper is?
Let me see that.
That makes it so it doesn't
get caught on your finger
when you flip through it
so you skip over that page.
You're right.
If you flip through the pages
while holding them from the top,
you'll find the paper.
You're right.
It's like a magic trick.
I tore the edge of the page while
you were all looking at the paper.
The old woman's husband probably used
the same trick in the exchange
diary she mentioned.
Her husband was a shy man,
so he made it so the pages
he wrote on would be skipped over.
The old woman was able to find
them because she was carefully
turning each page while reading
the sections she wrote.
But, boy,
unless we know which of these ten
thousand books uses the same trick...
I figured that out, too.
What?
Even if you make the
instructions hard to find,
you'd eventually find them if you turned
each page like the old woman did.
Yes.
But your husband said you'd
never find them, right?
Y-Yes.
So it's between some pages you'd never turn.
But Subaru-san and Ai-chan
examined the mystery novels
and monster stories the old
woman didn't like, right?
The old woman already searched those.
She doesn't have to read
them to look for the paper.
Then which book is it?
Quit putting on airs and tell us!
It's a book with pages
she'd never need to turn.
There was no point in her reading them
because she'd learned
something even better
than what was written on those pages.
It's the...
Meat and Potatoes
meat and potatoes
recipe in a cookbook, isn't it?
Ding, ding, ding!
I see. She learned the recipe
from her mother-in-law.
Since her husband loved those flavors,
there was no need for her to read it.
And if it were between the
pages of any other recipe,
even if he used the trick
you described earlier,
she would've found it by searching
the pages written in the index.
Where are the cookbooks?
I believe they're over on that shelf.
But there are dozens of cookbooks.
A few dozen out of ten thousand.
And we're only searching the
meat and potato recipes.
If we all search for it, it
should take only a few minutes.
Meat and Potatoes
Huh?
What?
A blackout?
It's Kid! Kid-sama is here!
The lights went out.
Inspector, should we go in?
Don't panic!
We agreed not to enter this time
until we've received the signal.
So keep all the exits covered instead.
Don't let a single ant out!
Yes, sir!
You let Kid mess with the wiring
because you wouldn't let the cops in.
Don't worry.
Even if he does come,
he won't be able to open the
trick box in the darkness.
A music box.
Isn't this "My Grandfather's Clock?"
Didn't she say the box plays
music when it's opened?
That was the sound of the cage falling!
What are you doing?
Get those lights back on.
Hey, what's going on?
Is the trick box safe?
He didn't take it.
Huh?
I've taken the contents of the box.
Kaito Kid
"I-I've taken the contents of the box."
"Kaito Kid."
Th-That's impossible!
Are you saying he opened
Samizu Kichiemon's trick box
in the darkness in such
a short amount of time?
I knew he could do it!
He got us this time.
Looks like we're not needed anymore.
Can we leave now?
No!
Huh?
The security shutters linked
to the cage are closed.
He should still be inside.
I'll find him, even if it means pulling
the faces of everyone in here.
Please don't.
Huh?
Remember what I said?
I'd allow you to display the
trick box here on the condition
that you not to do anything boorish
to the guests at the library.
But, ma'am,
the moonstone your husband left you...
He can have the moonstone
for opening the box.
Japanese Cooking
What I really wanted
was the other thing inside the box.
While searching the books
according to what that boy said,
I found the piece of paper in this cookbook.
Let us open the box and see what's inside.
But he may have taken the other object.
Don't worry.
I'm the only one left in this world
who sees any value in it.
Ouch...
What's wrong, Professor?
It's my stomach again.
Then go to the bathroom.
I-I will...
Hey.
Huh?
You still haven't opened the box, have you?
What?
Conan-kun, I'm using the toilet.
Using the toilet?
You haven't taken off your pants.
Oh, um, I was just about to do my business.
Anyway, the professor doesn't call me
"Conan-kun" when we're alone together.
Yikes.
Those band-aids on your right hand.
The professor had one on the second
joint of his pointer finger,
not the tip.
Besides, the professor's as tall as Ran.
How did you easily pick out the book that Ran
couldn't reach while standing on
her tip toes on top of a chair?
Probably because you were using the
thickness of the professor's legs
to bend your knees and
make yourself look shorter,
but straightened them to get the book.
Right?
Kaito Kid.
How did you know I hadn't opened the box yet?
The American Henry Work wrote
"My Grandfather's Clock" in 1876.
But it didn't get to Japan until 1940.
A mid-19th Century tinkerer
wouldn't have known the song.
You played it on your phone, didn't you?
Ding, ding, ding!
Are you sure you don't need
to check out that moonstone?
I thought you were looking
for a special jewel.
Actually, I once stole that moonstone back
after a thief stole it
from that woman's husband.
Watch where you're going!
Oh, excuse me.
Isn't this yours?
Y-Yes, but why?
Be careful. You were just pickpocketed.
This moonstone looks expensive.
Is it a gift?
Yes, for my wife.
You could say it's her reward.
I want to keep it next to our diary.
After all, moonstones are
a symbol of pure love.
Exchange Diary
Congratulations!
You finally found it!
So it's just the exchange diary.
I see.
So you've already checked it out.
I only came here to accept his challenge.
I'll be leaving now.
Huh? It won't open.
Before you leave,
I'd like you to return those
photos you took of me.
I can't let those get out.
Come to think of it, he had some
kind of device on his neck.
Another blackout?
Bastard. He left his phone and ran.
Mori Detective Agency
Trick Box Strategy!!
Kaito Kid Still Missing
General Advisor Suzuki Jirokichi (72)
Ticket
Okino Yoko
Yoko Okino Live Project "HASHAGE LIVE"
Thanks for the food.
It's good!
This is...
Kudo
...pretty good.
The Suzuki Library is still closed
as the search for Kaito Kid
enters its twelfth hour.
As opening time nears,
the search team appears
increasingly exhausted.
They're hoping to arrest Kaito
Kid as soon as possible.
Inspector Nakamori.
There's nowhere else left to search.
Perhaps he's already escaped.
That's impossible.
Find him!
Just give up already.
Episode Preview
This is Wakasa-sensei. She'll be my
assistant homeroom teacher starting today.
Nice...
Nice to meet you!
You don't usually have assistants
start this late in the year.
Sorry for making you help
me during your lunch break.
Wow, it really is in shambles.
Don't touch that.
The New Teacher's Skeleton Case
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The New
Teacher's Skeleton Case, Part One!"
Gym Closet
Next Conan's hint!
The gym closet!
Don't miss the next episode.
We won't be seeing each other for a while.
Take good care of your girlfriend.
You, too.