Class 1-B was assigned
assistant homeroom teacher
Wakasa Rumi out of season.
Wakasa Rumi (37)
Class 1-B Assistant Homeroom Teacher
We went to the old storage
shed to look for lime
at the request of said clumsy
and fearful teacher, but...
Heave ho...
Ayumi-chan!
You picked up a schedule
in the storage shed, right?
Yeah, I still have it.
See?
Did you figure something out, Conan-kun?
I see. So that's how it is.
Now that I take a closer look,
there's something wrong with
this schedule, isn't there?
Surely not even upperclassmen
have seven class periods in grade school.
Then what is this chart?
Since it was in the storage shed
where we found the skeleton holding the code,
this is probably...
Probably?
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
A basement, a skeleton,
and a code on a string.
Keep your eyes on Wakasa-sensei!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The New Teacher's Skeleton Case
(Part Two)
"The New Teacher's Skeleton Case, Part Two!"
It's probably what?
It's probably the key to the code.
The key...
...to the code?
What's that?
A hint to help us read the code.
Huh?
Look closely at the code.
The characters on the right
side are the days of the week.
Every day of the week is represented.
You're right.
Oh, but the "water" for Wednesday is missing.
Oh, that's the water radical.
River, lake, swim.
River - Lake - Swim
A lot of characters that incorporate
the water radical are related to water.
Really?
Then what are the characters on the left?
They're parts of characters
for school subjects.
Language is "ware."
Math is "nobun."
Social studies is "kai."
Science is "sato."
Art is "ko."
Physical education is "hon."
Homeroom is "shita."
So knowing that,
we can fill in the forty-nine spaces on this
seven by seven grid with Chinese characters.
And if you apply the Japanese alphabet
to them starting at the top left...
You get this chart.
Wow!
It seems like we should be able to read
it when we wrap it around a pen now.
I'll read out the code, so you
guys check it against the key.
Understood!
The first character is the
earth radical and nobun.
Um...
It's the earth radical and nobun, so...
Su!
Next is the water radical and ko.
That's ma!
Next is the fire radical and ko.
Ho.
It's sumaho (smartphone)!
Sumaho
Looks like it really is a key.
Yeah.
What's next?
Tree radical and ko.
Me!
Water radical and ware.
U!
Sumahomeu...
Soneareta...
Ebuemua...
What does that mean?
Is it some kind of incantation?
Damn it.
I was so sure this was it.
Thanks for waiting, everyone.
We're finished with classes for the day.
We'll play dodge ball in our next PE class.
All right!
Okay, everyone.
Let's clean up and go home.
Okay!
Even if you apply the
Japanese alphabet vertically
instead of horizontally to the key,
you still get "yuteshiriso,
utsuawoko, movunimua."
Maybe it's not the Japanese
alphabet but the English alphabet.
The English alphabet has twenty-six characters.
Most of the forty-nine spaces would be leftover.
I suppose you're right.
The other things that's bothering me
are these X's drawn here
and there on the chart.
What do they mean?
I'm disappointed, though.
We couldn't crack the code.
Yeah.
Who cares?
I doubt there's any point
in cracking the code
we found in the hand of a thief who
died in an accident ten years ago.
Yeah, but...
That was quick.
Huh?
There's already a story online about the
skeleton we found in the storage shed.
They even included a photo of
the headband with the code.
Skeleton Found At Grade School
Mysterious Code →
Seriously?
Seriously.
They're calling it a "mysterious code."
Um, children...
Oh, Wakasa-sensei.
The teacher of another class asked me
to get some lime for their
science class tomorrow.
I see...
I-I saw three line markers
next to the skeleton in the storage shed.
There's probably lime inside those.
So?
So, um, if you don't mind...
Yeah, yeah.
You want us to come with you
because you're scared, right?
Well, yes.
Sorry for making you come with me again.
Wakasa-sensei, you really are a scaredy cat.
Well, there was a skeleton
in there until recently.
In any case, let's get the lime
and leave before it gets dark.
This room has been ransacked.
It was tidy earlier, right?
Could forensics have left this
mess while investigating?
No, they weren't investigating.
It's more like they were
searching for something.
Could someone have come
after the police left?
B-But why?
Hey, Mitsuhiko.
What time was that news story posted?
Huh? Um...
Two hours ago.
Two hours ago?
That's plenty of time to come here
after seeing the code online.
Wait. You don't think...
Yeah.
The guy who wrote that code
may have died ten years ago,
but the purpose of the code still lives.
Then we have to solve the code!
Let's check the basement where
we found the skeleton first.
The person who searched the storage
shed could be hiding down there.
What?
Sensei, can you open this trapdoor?
But what if someone jumps out?
It's okay.
I'll put them to sleep
using my tranquilizer gun.
Tranquilizer?
I'm opening it.
Okay.
Here goes.
The basement hasn't been ransacked.
So they haven't been down here to search yet.
Or they noticed us coming.
And ran away.
Well, they wouldn't be able to run if
we discovered them in the basement.
Maybe they're planning to return
once the students and teachers leave
and it's dark outside to resume
their search for something.
So? What is this "something?"
We'll have to crack the code to find out.
Damn.
I know I can solve it if I figure
out what those three X's mean.
Normally you'd think it's the
redundant "iue" characters in "waiueo,"
but then the X's should be in the third
through fifth squares on the bottom row.
What do those X's mean?
Conan-kun, let's carry the lime out.
Huh? Oh, sure.
Today was the worst.
I want to go home, have
a drink, and go to sleep.
Wakasa-sensei, you drink?
Yes, I do.
My favorite is whiskey.
One glass, and I can sleep with
an Ebisu-like smile on my face.
Whiskey... Ebisu...
That's it!
This code isn't in modern alphabetical order.
Then the three phrases of the code are...
That code really is connected
to that ten year old case.
Hey, Conan.
What are you doing?
Can't find the lime?
I'm hungry now.
Who's there?!
What's wrong, Ai-chan?
I thought I saw someone watching
us from behind the entrance door.
Maybe it was my imagination.
No, maybe not.
If I'm right, after the police collected
that skeleton from the basement and left,
someone ransacked this storage
shed in search of something.
The ones who murdered the
wealthy man ten years ago,
and stole 200 million yen worth
of gold ingots.
That very same group of thieves.
What?
Does that mean you cracked the code?
Yeah, because of what
Wakasa-sensei said earlier.
Huh? Wh-What I said?
Ebisu and whiskey.
Long ago, those words were written...
Like this.
What are those characters?
There are weird characters mixed in.
They're no longer used, but they're
characters from the Iroha poem.
The katakana "a" with a
line under it is "ye."
Ye
The character that looks like
the "i" in "ido" is "wi."
Wi
So if you apply the Iroha characters
to the code instead of the modern alphabet...
You get this.
I see.
The obsolete "ye" and "wi" characters
correspond to the spaces marked with X,
and the last X is a leftover space.
Yeah, and if you read the
code using this chart...
You get "Wakemaeha, youishita. Sugunikoi!
(Your shares, are ready. Come immediately!)"
Is that...?
Yes.
That skeleton belonged to the
boss of the thieves who met here.
He exchanged the ingots for cash
and had their shares ready.
And ten years later, after seeing the
news story and realizing their boss
Skeleton Found At Grade School
Mysterious Code →
prepared their shares before
his accidental death,
they came here to look for it thinking the
cash could still be inside this storage shed.
I found heaps of cash in the lime inside
the line markers in the basement.
No way!
But couldn't he have emailed them?
If they'd been emailed,
that would have led the police to
the money if they were arrested.
I see.
In any case, we should tell the police.
We may not want to tell
them about the money yet.
Why not?
If the police act, the thieves
won't come back here.
So we'll round them up first.
Sherlock Holmes Series
The Adventure of the Dancing Men
by Conan Doyle
Just like Holmes did in
the Dancing Men story.
Wow, the sun's already setting.
You're right.
We couldn't find any lime.
All we found was a code written
on some finish line tape.
But the writing looks pretty fresh.
As though someone just wrote it.
Yeah.
Yeah, but we can't read it anyway.
Just throw it away.
You're right.
I'm so hungry!
Anyway, I'm excited for tonight's
episode of Kamen Yaiba!
Yeah. The mysterious Lady
Yaiba's going to be in it!
Wow, I'm so excited.
Right, Haibara-san?
Sheesh.
I told you guys not to come.
Yeah, but...
It's not fair for you to come alone!
We're all part of the Detective Boys!
But the guys coming are—
But this is kind of fun,
like a test of courage.
Yeah.
Even Wakasa-sensei came...
If it becomes necessary, I'll protect you.
Thank you.
I'm surprise the police sent anyone on
the basis of such uncertain information.
Well, actually...
I think your track record convinced them.
Hmm.
I only came because I thought
Kobayashi-sensei would be here.
Well, Conan-kun?
Huh?
What did you write in code?
Oh.
"I'll be waiting in the
basement at midnight today."
"Let's meet for the first
time in ten years," I think.
They'll think their boss is
still alive when they read that.
Where are you, boss?
How could you?
We haven't heard from you in ten years.
We thought you ran off with the money.
Come to think of it, the code said
he'd be waiting in the basement.
Hey, answer me.
You're down there, aren't you?
A flashlight?
What's that doing there?
Hey, you down there?
Boss?
Quit hiding and come on out.
Hold it right there.
I'm Shiratori Ninzaburo with the
Metropolitan Police Department Section One.
You're coming down to the station with
me for a ten year old robbery and murder.
Then that code...
It was a trap?
That's right!
Conan-kun wrote that code!
And you fell for it!
Wait!
There were four thieves,
and their boss is dead!
That should leave three!
If there's only two in the basement, then...
Inspector Shiratori!
Brats...
How dare you underestimate me?
Did you find the money?
Yeah.
It's stuffed inside the line markers.
Let's see.
How's this?
Oh, wow! You can't beat this!
It's too bad the boss died, though.
It just means there's more for us.
We should thank him.
You're right.
Okay, boys and girls.
Why don't you head down into
the basement one by one?
The kids first.
Come on, hurry up.
What's wrong?
Take them out with your tranquilizer
or ball like you always do.
I'm not sure I can hit them
with a dart in the dark.
And I should hold onto my ball launching belt,
for when we get trapped inside here.
Is Inspector Shiratori okay?
Yeah. He just suffered a
concussion and is unconscious.
Okay.
You're last, teacher.
O-Okay.
Have fun teaching your last
class in the basement.
Wakasa-sensei!
Ouch...
Hey, what are you doing?
Sensei! Wakasa-sensei!
It won't open!
Hey!
Get up and—
H-He's unconscious...
Huh?
Are you ready?
What?
To move onto the next world.
H-Hey, Conan.
I don't hear anything anymore.
Damn.
Okay, let's open the door.
Okay.
Ready, and...
No, stop!
Stay back!
Sensei!
No!
Wakasa-sensei!
Huh?
Are you okay?
Y-Yes.
Where are the thieves?
Huh? Come to think of it...
They've been knocked out.
Sensei, you're amazing!
Did you beat all three of them yourself?
I-I was just wildly swinging the rake around.
Lucky me.
The Next Day
I heard the news, Wakasa-sensei!
You took a group of children to catch
some thieves in the middle of the night!
I'm sorry.
But there was a police officer there.
I thought we'd be okay.
Th-Then why?
Huh?
Why didn't you invite me?!
I'm the adviser for the Detective Boys!
Huh?
You're upset about that?
Y-You are?
And the police officer who
came was Shiratori-san!
You should've told me...
N-Not that it matters it was Shiratori-san!
Takagi-san or Chiba-san or Sato-san
or anyone else would have...
Oh, that's not what I mean by anyone!
I mean...
I-In any case, I'm the adviser
for the Detective Boys!
Episode Preview
"I'll be waiting in front of the large
fox at the Yuda Hot Springs Station."
"Kurataya Komakichi."
You're the great detective Mori Kogoro-san.
Haginyan!
I'm Washiyama of the Yamaguchikita Station.
I'm Tsurumi.
What?
Why am I being arrested?
The Meiji Restoration Mystery Tour
(Yamaguchi Arc)
The next episode of Conan is "The Meiji
Restoration Mystery Tour, Yamaguchi Arc!"
Letter
Next Conan's hint!
A letter!
I would've bent over backwards to go!
Don't miss the next episode.
Then why don't we talk now?
Kobayashi-sensei, it's time for class.
Oh...