[ED]
Kogoro-no-occhan received a
letter from a mysterious person
named Kurataya Komakichi saying he
wanted to give him a family treasure.
Ran and I decided to accompany
him to Yamaguchi Prefecture.
"I'll be waiting in front of the large fox
at the Yuda Hot Springs Station at 3 PM."
"Kurataya Komakichi," huh?
This must be a rather substantial treasure!
Dad, keep your voice down!
Huh?
Oh, sorry for all the noise.
Sheesh.
JR Shin-Yamaguchi Station
We're here, Yamaguchi!
We still have plenty of time until 3 PM.
Then let's do some sightseeing.
Yamaguchi has lots to see,
like historic landmarks from the
late Edo and restoration periods,
and Sites of Japan's Meiji
Industrial Revolution.
Oh, sorry.
You were just so beautiful,
I couldn't help myself.
Are you Mori Kogoro-san?
Huh?
You're the great detective Mori Kogoro-san.
It's an honor to run into you here.
Why, thank you.
Oh, I'm...
Natsume Asuka. I'm with
the Yamaguchi News Site.
Natsume Asuka (28)
News Site Reporter
Yamaguchi News Site?
We report local news stories online.
Have you come to Yamaguchi
to investigate a case?
Well, actually...
Dad!
Didn't the letter demand strict secrecy?
Oh, right.
I'm just here sightseeing.
My daughter Ran and this
kid insisted I bring them.
Sightseeing?
In that case, let me show you around.
What? Are you sure?
Yes.
I appreciate it.
This'll be a fun trip.
He can never resist a beautiful woman.
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
A beautiful reporter and
the treasure of Yamaguchi.
There's no way this can end well.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Meiji Restoration Mystery Tour
(Yamaguchi Arc)
"The Meiji Restoration Mystery
Tour, Yamaguchi Arc!"
Kozan Park
During the Muromachi period,
Yamaguchi was even more
prosperous than Kyoto.
It's also known as "Nishinokyo,"
or the Kyoto of the West.
A five-story pagoda.
That's the Rurikoji Temple five-story pagoda,
Rurikoji Five-story Pagoda
one of Japan's three greatest pagodas,
along with the ones at Horyuji and Daigoji.
It lights up at night.
It's a beautiful sight.
It certainly is beautiful.
Hey.
Chinryutei
This is the relocated and
reconstructed Chinryutei,
the detached cottage of the Abe family,
a late Edo period business magnate.
In this room, men like Saigo
Takamori and Kido Takayoshi
held secret meetings regarding
the Satcho Alliance.
I see.
In this tiny room?
Standing in this room makes you feel
like a patriot of the Meiji Restoration.
Mori-san.
What are your plans for this evening?
I'm supposed to meet someone
named Kurataya Komakichi.
Kurataya Komakichi?!
Dad!
Oh, whoops.
Excuse me. Could you wait here, please?
Huh? Sure.
What's gotten into her?
She must've remembered
she had something to do.
Asuka-san's taking a long time.
Yeah.
She's back.
Mori Kogoro-san, right?
That's me. Who are you?
I'm Washiyama of the Yamaguchikita Station.
Washiyama Nobuto (46)
Yamaguchikita
Station Lieutenant
Tsurumi Hiroshi (27)
Yamaguchikita
Station Sergeant
I'm Tsurumi.
The police?
We have a few questions for you.
Could you come down to the station with us?
Huh?
Hey! What are you doing?
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Mister!
Dad!
He's running!
Mori Kogoro, you're not getting away!
You're under arrest!
What?!
Yamaguchikita Station
I don't understand!
Why am I being arrested?
Don't just stand there! Explain yourselves!
I'm Chief Inspector Takajo.
Takajo Tetsuya (38)
Yamaguchikita Station
Chief Inspector
You will be investigated.
What am I being arrested for?
Interference of public duties.
You tried to flee the scene.
I wasn't trying to run!
I heard you're receiving a family
treasure from Kurataya Komakichi.
Huh?
Kurataya Komakichi is the suspect in an
armed robbery that occurred a year ago.
Armed robbery?
Using the name Kurataya Komakichi,
a shipping agent of Hagi
famous during the Edo period,
he entered Japanese-style
café "Takarada" with a gun,
shot the manager, and stole millions
of yen worth of Kiecho coins.
Kurata Komakichi's family treasure
refers to those coins he stole.
In other words, you're
working with Komakichi.
You can't be serious!
I was just told to come here by letter!
I see.
Let's see this letter.
You just wait.
I'll show you right now.
Huh?
What's wrong?
A detective must respect his
clients' confidentiality.
If you want to see it, bring me a warrant.
Search him!
Hey, stop! Don't touch me!
What should we do, Conan-kun?
Stop!
If we don't do something, they'll
think he's working with a robber.
Sir, he doesn't have it!
We should have Inspector Megure
contact the Yamaguchi police.
Wait, officers!
Asuka-san.
I'm sorry, Mori-san.
I'm the one who reported you to the police.
What?
I was worried you'd get
caught up in the case.
I wanted the police to
protect you from Komakichi.
So that's what happened.
We're sorry, Mori-san.
As long as you understand.
Everyone makes mistakes some—
Hey, wait!
If you arrested me,
you must not be making much progress
on the robbery investigation.
So, what?
Relax.
Why don't I, the great Mori Kogoro, assist you?
Just because I'm a great detective,
there's no need to be shy.
There he goes again.
What can a mere detective do?
A mere detective?
Investigating the robbery
is the police's job.
It's not something an incompetent
detective should involve himself in.
Have some of Yamaguchi's famous kawarasoba,
and go back to Tokyo.
That half-wit cop.
Don't underestimate the
great detective Mori Kogoro.
JR Yuda Hot Springs Station
The letter said he'd be waiting in
front of this statue at three, right?
We missed our chance to discover
the identity of Kurataya Komakichi.
Too bad.
I'm sorry.
It's my fault for reporting it.
It's not your fault, Asuka-san.
It's the fault of that half-wit Takajo.
Anyway, where did the
letter from Komakichi go?
Oh, that?
I have it.
See?
When did you get this?!
It seemed important, so I
thought I should hold onto it.
Hot Springs
Fox's Footprint
But did the robber Komakichi
really write that letter?
Huh?
Don't you think it's weird for a
robber to ask you to come here?
Fox's Footprint
You're right.
What was his plan?
You'd probably have to ask
Komakichi for the answer.
Right, Asuka-san?
Huh?
You're Kurataya Komakichi, aren't you?
What? Don't be stupid.
How could Asuka-san be the robber?
That's not what I meant.
Asuka-san sent you the letter
under the name Kurataya Komakichi.
Hey, kid!
You're talking nonsense!
But you only said the name
Kurataya Komakichi to Asuka-san.
But Inspector Takajo knew about him
giving you his family treasure.
Since I had the letter the whole time,
Inspector Takajo couldn't
have known about that.
Which means he must have heard it
from Asuka-san when she reported you.
I'm sorry!
Huh?
Conan-kun is right.
Asuka-san, what is the meaning of this?
Someone's actually been arrested
for the robbery that happened a year ago.
An accomplice?
No.
A metalworking researcher
named Fukuhara Yuichi-san.
Metalworking?
Yes.
He received a request by email from someone
calling themselves Kurataya Komakichi.
Fukuhara Yuichi (32)
Metalworking Researcher
He asked him to recreate a
weapon of the Choshu Domain,
to commemorate the Hagi Reverberating
Furnace becoming a world heritage site.
Naturally, as a work of art to appreciate
without any firing capabilities.
However, just before being completed,
it was stolen from the factory.
And modified so it could fire bullets.
Yes.
Then Fukuhara-san did nothing wrong.
No.
Ultimately they decided what he did was no
different from illegally manufacturing a gun.
He received a one year sentence.
Just before Fukuhara-san received the email,
I did a story on his factory in Hagi
and posted it on my news site.
The culprit must have seen that and
asked Fukuhara-san to create the gun.
So I'm responsible, too.
I see.
But you should've been honest from the start.
Maybe...
Asuka-san knows who the culprit is.
Isn't that why you quietly
invited the old man to Yamaguchi,
so the culprit wouldn't find out
and got him involved in the case?
Is this true?
The culprit is a cold-blooded man
who has no problem shooting people.
If he learns I asked a
detective to investigate,
he may try to kill me.
I'm so afraid.
I understand the situation.
Asuka-san, the rest is a detective's job.
Mori-san...
Thank you!
No need to thank me.
This is a detective's destiny.
The case called me here.
I know!
Asuka-san, let's announce on your
news site that I've taken the case.
Then he won't have any reason to kill you.
B-But you...
Don't worry.
Let the great Mori Kogoro handle it!
So you're the famous Mori Kogoro-san.
Asuka-san filled me in.
I heard you're going to solve
that case from a year ago.
You can count on me.
I've solved several cases
the police couldn't handle.
Now then, Takarada-san.
The coins were stolen from the storehouse
on the second floor, correct?
Yes.
Do you remember the culprit's face?
They were dressed so strangely,
that made a stronger impression.
Strange how?
I know.
They were captured on my webcam.
Your webcam?
Yes.
I installed a few in my garage
in place of security cameras
to prevent anyone from
messing with my car.
This is him.
A school uniform and white sash?
That certainly is a bit
eye-catching for a robber.
Huh? I've seen this outfit before.
Ran-neechan.
Can I see your guidebook?
Sure.
Here.
Thanks.
Found it.
Ah, Fujiki-san. Welcome.
You're Mori Kogoro-san?
Yes. Who are you?
Fujiki, a lawyer.
Fujiki Yosuke (45)
Lawyer
I've been responsible for managing
the family's assets since previous owner.
Fujiki-san, did something happen today?
I found a news story online claiming that
a detective named Mori Kogoro
would be investigating the case.
This is it.
Kurataya Komakichi, I hope
you're quaking in your boots!
How embarrassing.
Mori-san, could you stay out of this?
Stay out of this?
The previous owner willed that the artworks
and knickknacks kept in the storehouse
on the second floor should be
donated to local institutions.
Our work was stopped due to the case,
but everything must be removed
from the storehouse by next week.
I see.
So that's why there was
a truck parked outside.
Yes.
The construction happening
next door is so loud.
I can hardly run the business from
ten in the morning until evening.
I'd like the case to be solved soon, too.
Takarada-san,
even if the case is solved, you
may not get your coins back.
What?
Keicho coins have a nearly 90% gold content.
If melted down into gold bars,
they could be sold.
Fujiki-san, you seem to
know a lot about gold.
My job involves managing assets.
Mori-san, this is for your own good.
The culprit has a gun.
If you want to live, you
should withdraw immediately.
Are you threatening me?
No. It's just a warning.
Goodbye.
He's suspicious.
Hey, mister.
I think there could be a clue
to solving the case in Hagi.
Hagi
Hagi?
Inspector Takajo said Kurataya Komakichi
was the name of someone who lived
in Hagi during the Edo period.
And Asuka-san said the factory of
Fukuhara-san who made the gun is also—
Ow!
Keep your mouth shut!
The case happened here in Yamaguchi City!
Then can Ran-neechan and I go to Hagi?
No!
Why not?
It takes an hour by bus.
As long as we're here,
I'd like to visit Hagi.
It's too dangerous for you to go alone!
We'll be fine.
Asuka-san said she's working in Hagi today.
What? Asuka-san is?
Hagi: Meirin Academy
Hey, kid! Where's Asuka-san?
Asuka-san's collecting information
at Shoin Shrine right now,
Shoin Shrine
so we came here first.
We wouldn't want to bother
her while she's working.
Uh huh...
By the way, kid, what are you looking for?
Huh? Oh, you know...
There it is!
Haginyan!
What's with the costume?
It's Haginyan, the mascot
of the city of Hagi.
Really?
Ran-neechan, take a picture
of me with Haginyan.
Sure.
Sheesh. He's still a little kid.
Anyway, that mascot sure
is dressed strangely.
Dressed strangely...
Strangely...
Hey, Haginyan!
Why are you dressed like that?
What are you dressed as?
Kiheitai Haginyan
The Kiheitai!
That's it.
The culprit was dressed as Takasugi Shinsaku,
the man who formed the Kiheitai.
But why?
How should I know?
But dressing as a local hero to
commit a robbery is disgraceful.
Hey, kid. Where's Asuka-san now?
She's broadcasting from Kido
Takayoshi's former residence.
It's within walking distance.
Kido Takayoshi's
Former Residence
Along with Saigo Takamori
and Okubo Toshimichi,
Kido Takayoshi was one of three great
nobles of the Meiji Restoration.
He lived here for twenty years
before moving to Edo.
Hey, Ran.
We should probably call Asuka-san soon.
Yeah.
Hello?
Asuka-san, it's Takarada.
I'm calling you by video call.
Oh, sorry.
Hello.
How's your day going?
Fujiki just came rushing to the shop.
He must be flustered since he heard the great
detective Mori-san is investigating the case.
So it was him.
Damn it. We're lost.
It should be around here.
Are you looking for someplace?
We're trying to get to Kido Takayoshi's
former residence, but we're lost.
Oh, that's nearby.
I could take you there in my rickshaw.
Ah, nice.
I'll test its comfort first.
Ah.
What a nice view.
Ran-neechan, get down!
Hey, don't touch that!
Hey, what are you—
Hide inside the rickshaw!
What happened?
Are you okay, Ran?
Yeah.
Is Kurataya Komakichi trying to kill
Looks like he ran.
the old man?
Episode Preview
With a gun? Are you all right?
Kurataya Komakichi...
What's wrong, Asuka-san?
Mori Kogoro
In Call
Answer me, Asuka-san!
Asuka-san!
He has a gun.
Whatever you do, don't follow me.
The Meiji Restoration Mystery Tour
(Hagi Arc)
The next episode of Conan is "The Meiji
Restoration Mystery Tour, Hagi Arc!"
Truck
Next Conan's hint!
A truck!
Don't miss the next episode.
Yamaguchi is known for?
Sweet rice jelly!
And Hagi?
Bean cakes!
Really?