[Eyecatch]
The old man received a letter from
someone named Kurataya Komakichi
saying he'd like to give
him his family treasure,
so Ran and I accompanied him
to Yamaguchi Prefecture.
Washiyama Nobuto (46)
Yamaguchikita
Station Lieutenant
Tsurumi Hiroshi (27)
Yamaguchikita
Station Sergeant
However, the old man was mistaken for the
accomplice of a robber and was arrested.
Takajo Tetsuya (38)
Yamaguchikita
Station Chief Inspector
It turned out Kurataya Komakichi
was the name of a robber
who stole millions of
yen worth of gold coins.
Fortunately, news site
reporter Natsume Asuka-san
Natsume Asuka (28)
News Site Reporter
was able to get him released.
Unbelievably enough, Asuka-san was the one
who sent the old man the letter
using the name Kurataya Komakichi.
She intended to hire the old man to
secretly investigate the robbery.
Fujiki Yosuke (45)
Lawyer
So in search of clues,
we left Yamaguchi City for Hagi, but...
What a nice view.
Ran-neechan, get down!
Hey, don't touch that!
Hey, what are you—
Hide inside the rickshaw!
What happened?
Are you okay, Ran?
Yeah.
Is Kurataya Komakichi trying to kill
Looks like he ran.
the old man?
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
Fearsome bullets are being
aimed at the old man!
Where will the Restoration's
treasure take us?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Meiji Restoration Mystery Tour
(Hagi Arc)
"The Meiji Restoration
Mystery Tour, Hagi Arc!"
Wait, Dad?
Damn it.
We shouldn't be wasting time here.
Where are you going?
We haven't been questioned yet.
I appeared on Asuka-san's news site
to soothe her over-anxious nerves.
Instead I provoked the culprit.
You mean...
Yeah. Asuka-san could be in danger, too.
Ran-neechan, we need to notify
Asuka-san immediately.
Yeah.
Hello, Asuka-san?
I can't come to the phone right now.
It's no use.
It went to her messages.
We need to get to Asuka-san quickly.
Yeah.
Y-You...
Where are you going?
Someone's trying to kill you.
So, what?
We can guarantee your safety.
We'll protect you.
I don't need your protection.
Let's go, Ran.
Damn it. You...
Stay there.
Dad, what should we do about Asuka-san?
We'll wait for an opportunity to—
Inspector Takajo!
Got it. I'll let headquarters know.
You boys watch—
Damn it. That incompetent detective...
Why are you just standing there?
Hurry up and find them!
Yes, sir!
Hagi Reverberating Furnace
This is the Hagi Reverberating Furnace
of Japan's Meiji Industrial Revolution
that was made a world heritage site.
A reverberating furnace
is a metal melting furnace
for refining cannonballs.
The young members of
the Choshu Domain
poured their hearts into
constructing this reverberating
furnace themselves.
But ultimately, their passion
failed to achieve results.
Years later, you can still feel
the passion of the young patriots
who never stopped working
towards their dream.
This is Natsume.
Asuka-san, are you all right?!
What? Oh, Mori-san.
I'm fine.
Good.
Did something happen?
Someone shot at me with a gun earlier.
With a gun?! Are you all right?
Yes. Fortunately, I'm fine.
It must have been Kurataya Komakichi.
Kurataya Komakichi...
Asuka-san, you could be in danger, too.
You're at the reverberating
furnace right now, right?
Yes.
I'm at the parking lot at
the bottom of the steps.
Got it.
I'll be right there, so don't move.
Understood. Please hurr—
What's wrong?
Asuka-san?
Are you all right, Asuka-san?!
Answer me, Asuka-san!
Mori Kogoro
In Call
Asuka-san!
Where are you?
If you're here, answer us!
Asuka-san!
This is...
Asuka-san's phone.
Takarada-san
Incoming call
A video call from Takarada-san?
Huh? Where's Asuka-san?
Takarada-san.
Asuka-san has been kidnapped.
What?
We heard she was at the parking
lot at the reverberating furnace.
But when we got here,
we only found her phone.
Mori-san.
It may have been the lawyer Fujiki.
Fujiki?
Asuka-san believed Kurataya
Komakichi's true identity is Fujiki.
Even if that's true, where
could he have taken her?
I don't know.
But I heard Fujiki asked Asuka-san
to meet him at Shizuki Park several times.
Shizuki Park?
Yes.
Hagi Castle Shizuki Park
It's the park where Hagi Castle is.
There are moats and stone walls.
He could be hiding the coins he stole there.
You think he took Asuka-san there?
I'll head there now,
but it takes about an hour
by car to get to Hagi.
Got it.
We'll head there first.
Why, though?
The old man was shot at with
a gun, but Asuka-san wasn't.
Maybe he only shot at the
old man to scare him.
Does that mean he kidnapped Asuka-san
so he could actually kill her?
But where did he take her?
Someplace he could kill her
without anyone noticing...
Keicho coins have a nearly 90% gold content.
If melted down into gold bars,
they could be sold.
Is he going to...?
Ran-neechan, let me see Asuka-san's phone!
Huh?
I'm going to examine the videos she
previously uploaded to her news site.
Found it.
I consider the Hagi Reverberating
Furnace a power spot.
A power spot?
The Choshu Domain attempted to construct
the reverberating furnace
without any plans.
I come here often during
my walks to feel the power
of those men who faced such difficulties.
Oh, right.
Your foundry is nearby.
Fukuhara Yuichi (32)
Metalworking Researcher
Yes.
Driver, stop the car!
What are you doing, kid?
You guys go to Shizuki Park.
There's something I want to check out.
Hey!
What are you going to check out?
Shit! Get down!
Huh?
It's the cops!
That was close.
It's like we've done something wrong.
We can't help it.
They want to...
We can guarantee your safety.
We'll protect you.
Wait a minute. Hagi should be
outside their jurisdiction.
So why did they respond to the shooting?
Is that half-wit Kurataya Komakichi?
Where is it?
Where is the foundry?
There it is!
I hope I make it in time!
Conan-kun!
Uh, oh! I need to stop the conveyor belt!
That's it!
Conan-kun, hurry!
Stop the belt!
Go!
I made it in time...
You wait here.
Huh?
He has a gun.
Whatever you do, don't follow me.
Dad...
Conan-kun, where are you?
Ran-neechan, I found Asuka-san.
Really? Is she okay?
Yeah. Where's Kogoro-no-ojisan?
He just headed into Shizuki Park alone.
Fujiki.
That's that half-wit.
So they really are...
Dad!
Don't move, you incompetent detective.
Takajo.
I knew it was you.
Dad!
Don't move.
Huh?
Hey.
Damn. He got away.
I thought you were aiming for me.
Why would I shoot you?
Someone was trying to shoot
you from these bushes.
What?
He dropped this in his panic.
Which means the culprit is...
Hello?
Hey, kid!
Where and what are you—
Huh? What?!
I'm sorry I'm late, Mori-san.
I've been waiting for you, Takarada-san.
It really does take over
an hour from Yamaguchi.
Yes.
Anyway, were you able to find Asuka-san?
Takarada Akihiko (45)
Japanese-style Café Owner
Huh?
Wh-What are the police and
Fujiki doing with you?
Wh-What's going on?
Takarada-san.
Huh?
Did you know Fujiki had become
Fukuhara Yuichi-san's lawyer?
What?
Apparently Fukuhara-san believes
you may be Kurataya Komakichi.
What? Who, me?
You expressed disapproval
of your father's will.
The will stated that all the
artworks and knickknacks
in the storehouse should be
donated to local institutions.
So you wanted at least
the coins for yourself.
After all, if you melted them
down, you could sell them.
Wait a minute.
Do you have any proof it was me?
There is no evidence.
But weren't you beginning to notice
that Asuka-san suspected you?
So you kidnapped her and
attempted to silence her.
Officer, don't tell me you believe them.
I was shot in the arm by the robber.
You were,
but the bullet barely
scratched your left arm.
It's possible you shot yourself so
you could pretend to be a victim.
Wh-What are you talking about?
You don't even have proof.
There is proof.
Huh?
You tried to kill me twice.
What are you talking about?
About an hour and a half
ago, you shot at me once.
Then again an hour ago.
I have an alibi.
I just got here.
I was in Yamaguchi City until then.
I called you from my garage.
Was that actually the garage at your home?
There was a flashy sports car behind you.
Anyone would assume it was your garage.
I don't understand.
The culprit Kurataya Komakichi
deliberately appeared
on your webcam dressed
as a Kiheitai soldier.
A memorable outfit diminishes your
impression of the actual culprit.
Did you not employ the same
technique to make us believe
you were in your garage by having a
flashy sports car in the background?
If it wasn't my garage, where was I?
Ran.
Okay.
Conan-kun, are you ready?
Yeah. I'm ready anytime.
You're facing him now.
Hello, Takarada-san.
You said the construction
next to your shop is noisy
from morning until night,
but when you called us earlier,
we didn't hear any construction sounds.
That's how I knew you
weren't inside your garage,
but inside a truck.
You pretended you were
calling us from your garage,
but you've actually been here in Hagi
calling us from inside this truck.
Huh? Where's Asuka-san?
Takarada-san.
Asuka-san has been kidnapped.
What?
And you brought Asuka-san
here when you kidnapped her.
Takarada-san.
You really are the robber Kurataya Komakichi!
Damn it!
He's not getting away!
Damn!
Yuichi-san.
Asuka-san.
Welcome back.
I'm back.
What's going on?
I thought Asuka-san and Fukuhara-san
were just acquaintances.
Too bad, mister.
Shut up.
Anyway, I'm glad he was released
after exactly one year.
Asuka-san probably wanted to find the
culprit before his sentence was up.
That's right.
Fukuhara-san said he'd find
the culprit himself once he got out.
Asuka-san didn't want him
to do anything dangerous.
And you knew about Asuka-san's
plan from the beginning.
You finally figured it out,
you incompetent detective?
What was that, you half-wit?
I'm the one who told Asuka-san
to get you involved.
What?
I told her this case could only be
solved by Japan's greatest detective,
the great Mori Kogoro.
Why not celebrate
by eating some of Yamaguchi's
famous kawarasoba?
A delicious meal should
satisfy your empty stomach.
I can't be satisfied by food.
There's lots of good local sake, too.
Well, then I guess I can
let you off the hook.
A half-wit police officer and
an incompetent detective, huh?
They make a good team.
Episode Preview
Wow.
Isn't it wonderful, Conan-kun?
It really is.
This is kind of like what
happened to that ship.
You mean the Mystery of the Mary Celeste?
The Mystery of the Mary Celeste?
Curse
Did they walk into the lake
like the five passengers?
The Mystery of the Michelin
Starred Restaurant
The next episode of Conan is "The Mystery
of the Michelin Starred Restaurant!"
Mary Celeste
Next Conan's hint!
The Mary Celeste!
Don't miss the next episode.
I want to eat at a Michelin
starred restaurant!
Starred? The suspect could be there.
He's right?