Wow.
Isn't it wonderful, Conan-kun?
It really is!
Guess we're not the only ones here...
Shinjuku
Huh?
I thought there were other people here.
They're probably not in the bathroom
all together, are they?
This is kind of like
what happened to that ship.
You mean the Mystery of the Mary Celeste?
Oh, yeah! That's the one!
The Mystery of the Mary Celeste?
Yeah.
It's a famous unsolved case
from the 19th Century.
If I remember right, a crew of ten
people disappeared into thin air,
and then the boat was found adrift.
There was hot soup and silverware left out,
making you thinking they were still eating.
The situation is similar.
What was that?
Kuchiishi-san!
Kuchiishi Eigo (28)
Chef
You're Kuchiishi-san the chef, right?
Y-Yes...
Get it together! Can you
tell me what happened?
Dad...
Curse
Ran, get an ambulance and call the police!
Got it!
Look, mister!
Footprints?
Curse
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
The word "Curse" and five sets of footprints.
What happened during this meal?!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Mystery of the Michelin
Starred Restaurant
"The Mystery of the Michelin
Starred Restaurant!"
Thankfully, that head wound isn't very severe.
Can we ask you a few
questions, Kuchiishi-san?
Sure.
Now, there were five guests
at that table? You're certain?
Right.
They made their reservations a week ago.
It was a group from a company
called Onda Trading.
I see.
Inspector!
It's about the identities
of the missing group.
Sitting where those glasses are...
That was Kano Kozo, forty years old.
Kano Kozo (40)
Employee at Onda Trading
We confirmed his ID from his driver's
license, which was left behind.
We confirmed the guy next to him
from the employee ID in his jacket,
which was still on the chair.
Iketani Kazuki (28)
Onda Trading Employee
Iketani Kazuki-san, twenty-eight years old.
Next to him was a floral handkerchief
and a bag containing an employee ID
Ekuni Mitsuyo (38)
Onda Trading Employee
for Ekuni Mitsuyo-san, aged thirty-eight.
The seat with the ash tray next to
her belonged to Sahara Takuro-san,
thirty-five years old.
Sahara Takuro (35)
Onda Trading Employee
We gathered that from the cigarettes
and employee ID in his coat pocket.
The last one we put together from
the smart phone that was left behind.
Manaka Kaori (25)
Onda Trading Employee
Manaka Kaori-san, twenty-five years old.
Onda Trading
Director and President
Onda Teruaki
Employees
Kano Kazuki
Sahara Takuro   Iketani Kazuki
Ekuni Mitsuyo   Manaka Kaori
They all work at Onda Trading.
The company homepage confirms as much.
Kuchiishi-san, can you
confirm they're who you saw?
Onda Trading...
Where have I heard that?
Yes, that's definitely them.
We haven't been able to
contact President Onda,
so we had local police check
on his home to be safe.
Hey, Detective Takagi...
When we came in, there was
a picture on the phone...
Those are the same people, right?
Yeah, that's right.
I don't know how close they were,
but apparently the five of them
would go out a lot together,
because there were pictures of them
partying in various locations.
I bet they planned on taking one here, too...
So, all five of them came here?
Right.
They came in about an hour ago, in a car.
That'd be twenty minutes before we showed up.
Wait, back then...
What happened next?
They made a toast,
and I went into the kitchen
to continue cooking.
I served the appetizers and soups.
And then after about fifteen minutes,
I was struck from out of nowhere.
You didn't see who hit you, then?
Right.
It certainly sounds like someone from that
group was the one to strike you...
Ei
Isn't this...?
A mis-written receipt?
Hey, Kuchiishi-san...
This is that cake called tiramisu, right?
That's right.
Everyone else was eating dinner.
How come one had cake?
You get people like that sometimes,
who want to start with dessert.
I bet the lady who sat
here sure loved sweets.
That might be the case.
That should be obvious!
Quit screwing with the crime scene.
Sorry!
In that case, get out of the—
One more thing!
Did someone break their glass
when they did the toast?
I... don't think so.
I would've noticed if they did,
not to mention having to clean up.
That's what I thought...
The trash can in the kitchen was empty, too.
One other thing, the car outside—
That's enough out of you!
Ow!
You can't just run around
on your own, you know?
Sorry...
Let's wait out here together.
Okay...
Isn't that...?
What did you say?!
Understood!
Inspector!
It's about Onda Trading...
Three years ago,
the company was under suspicion
for smuggling industrial metals,
and there was an investigation.
But one of the other managers left a note
claiming they were responsible for all of it,
and committed suicide.
Huh, hell of a case.
Then the five employees from this
incident might've been involved?
Also,
the manager who killed himself
was named Kuchiishi Keigo.
What?!
That's the same family name as the chef!
Inspector Megure!
Look what's on Kuchiishi-san's blog!
Curse
"What happened to my customers?"
What?
Sir, you really shouldn't
do this sort of thing...
Kuchiishi-san is gone!
Where'd he go?
Is that...
Curse
Kuchiishi-san!
Don't tell me...
Did he walk into the lake,
like the five customers?
Th-That's impossible!
Takagi, Chiba!
I want this lake checked out ASAP!
We can't afford to wait until dawn!
Yes, sir!
I figured as much.
Is it really okay that I'm the
only one not searching the lake?
It's okay!
Inspector Megure told me
that Detective Chiba
was going to check out the
lake with the local police.
Still...
Did Mori-san really tell
us to look around here?
Yep!
Curse            Curse
See?
Look close...
D-Don't do that, Conan-kun!
You can't just grab evidence!
Lake
Restaurant
Warehouse
See?
That's a map!
Yep!
If the lake is over here,
then this is the restaurant.
And our goal is here!
We're almost there.
Ei
Isn't this...?
Yep. Just like that chef, Eigo-san.
Maybe it's like his signature?
So this is a warehouse
that Kuchiishi-san owns.
Did you hear that?!
Open it up, Detective Takagi!
Got it!
These people...
The five missing guests.
They're not wearing their shoes...
Then does that mean those footprints were...?
Yep. Kuchiishi-san put them down.
This was all his doing.
Kogoro-no-ojisan said that even
that wound on his head
was part of the plan.
What?
But why?
And where has he gone?
He said that these people should know.
Safe Lock Box
Onda Teruaki (45)
President of Onda Trading
It's been a while, Mr. President!
Since my dad's funeral...
Y-You—
Then you really are Kuchiishi's son!
My old man was weak.
He let you people push him around...
No, manipulate him into committing
suicide, and taking the fall!
But that's not gonna work with me!
That's enough!
Great timing! Get him off of me!
You're Onda Teruaki, president
of Onda Trading, correct?
I'm Megure, with the Metro PD's Division 1.
P-Police?
I've been waiting for you, Mori-san.
If you're here now, that means
you've solved the mystery, right?
Huh?
Wh-Wh-Wh-What was it again?
Come on, now!
We're only here because you told us
where to rescue the missing five people,
and question them about this location.
Rescue?
Yes.
We rescued them from where
they were being held,
took them into custody,
and are currently questioning
them about the situation.
So, Mori-kun, what's this mystery?
W-Well, to be honest...
I have no idea...
Huh?!
Is this...?
Finally!
The Sleeping Kogoro!
Pardon me.
Now, to dissect this puzzle.
It had a few similarities
with a famous unsolved case,
but as to the clues for unraveling it...
Conan!
Here!
Well, you see,
the first thing I thought
was weird was the tiramisu.
The tiramisu?
Yeah.
It was the dessert at the seat with the
lady who had the flowery handkerchief!
It was dinnertime when
everybody went missing,
but one person had tiramisu instead.
And the chef said it was because
some people like having dessert first, but...
I realized it was a mistake!
What mistake?
The answer has to do with the pictures
that were found on the cell phone.
In the pictures of past parties, there
was always one person having dessert...
But it wasn't Ekuni-san,
rather Iketani-san, a man.
What?
Not only that,
but when you always have the same group,
you might have a seating
pattern that tends to pop up.
And this time, the pictures
indicated that was the case.
But for whatever reason, that
wasn't what happened tonight.
The usual seating pattern
had different people's things in place.
I'm not sure I follow...
What was the point of it all?
It was all to make Mori
Kogoro notice something...
The truth behind this case!
Wh-What?!
When you combined the two of them,
it shows a route to the warehouse where
the kidnapped people were being held.
These "curse" notes were
another part of the puzzle.
At first I thought the five of them
were captured at the restaurant,
then moved to the warehouse,
where they were locked up.
Is that not the case?
No.
If that were the case, the five of them
would've been sitting in the same positions as usual,
leaving their own belongings in those seats.
And there was one other thing:
a jacket stained with wine,
with a broken piece of glass that
had no explanation at the time.
There was no sign of a broken glass or a
bottle in the restaurant's garbage, either.
Which would mean...
Inspector Megure, think back.
They began eating twenty minutes
before we arrived at the restaurant.
But the hood of the car that was parked
outside was still giving off heat,
like it had only recently been parked.
And that warehouse had a table, with chairs,
along with a broken wine glass and bottle.
I see! Then you're saying...
They were originally lured
out to that warehouse,
where they were kept locked up.
President Onda, you've all been
partying in a variety of locations,
haven't you?
The pictures in the phone included
restaurants, the roofs of skyscrapers,
the summits of mountains, beaches,
and even deserted islands.
Using your name as bait would've been enough
to lure them to a warehouse
with little trouble,
and get them to start
toasting among themselves.
Warehouse? What are you talking about?
Okay, thanks, Detective Takagi.
It's just like Kogoro-no-ojisan deducted.
The wine from the warehouse
and the wine on the jacket in
the restaurant are the same,
and it had tranquilizers in it.
There was also an e-mail from that
president guy asking them all to show up.
I-I don't recall ever sending that e-mail!
That's because it was
Kuchiishi-san who sent it.
Once they were unconscious,
he took their shoes,
along with jackets and other belongings,
and returned to the restaurant
in the car they arrived with.
He then placed their things at the table,
as if they had been there all
along, and served up the food.
After that, he made the foot prints leading
to the lake through the back door
to make it look like they
had drowned themselves,
placed the "curse" note,
and then hurt himself while
waiting for us to arrive.
By the way, those notes
were actually a message
to President Onda using your
father's name, weren't they?
Using his father's name?
His father's name is Kuchiishi Keigo.
If you take the "kuchi" kanji from
Kuchiishi and the "ani" from Keigo...
It makes "curse."
Might it have been a signature
your father used in the past?
Because you use one that's similar.
Ei
In other words, the son of
Kuchiishi Keigo-san, Eigo-san,
planned to avenge his father
by killing off a group of employees.
Or, intended to make it look like that.
But the truth was, he was luring President
Onda into a trap by making him cautious.
That was his true goal!
Wh-What?
The people who were kidnapped
knew where we would go
because they recognized the
man who had confined them.
And after thinking about what
their president would do next...
They told me where to find you both.
Those are the secret books for your company.
They prove that Eigo-san's late
father was innocent, don't they?
It was two weeks ago.
I learned completely by accident
that my father had been framed.
Man, if those books ever see the light
of day, this company is done for.
Shh! You're too loud.
And for the record, I am not
going down with this ship!
Yeah. I'm don't want to
end up like him, either.
Not like poor old Kuchiishi.
They likely had no idea
they were in the restaurant
of the man they had helped frame,
Kuchiishi Keigo.
I wanted revenge!
Against all of them!
But then, Mori-san made his reservation.
It felt like a sign telling me to wait.
So, I reconsidered...
And realized my father can't rest
until I expose their crimes,
that I can't redeem him without doing that.
And that if I was the ace detective
that my reputation suggests,
I'd be able to figure out the
case from the clues he left,
find this location,
and expose their crime.
You're amazing.
Thank you so much.
The next day, the secret
books were evidence enough
President of Onda Trading
And Five Employees Arrested!
to get President Onda and the
complicit five employees arrested,
and Chef Kuchiishi's father,
Keigo-san, was cleared of all charges.
Rakujo Mito Ramen
Thanks for the food!
Gotta say, it's a real shame.
That was a Michelin-starred restaurant;
those are hard to get reservations for.
Maybe Cucina Eigo will
open up again someday...
I hope so.
But the ramen here was good, too!
My tummy's full!
Of course!
Rakujo Mito Ramen
Hara Kuchii!
If we can't eat from the Cucina,
then we can at least eat at the kitchen!
You get it?!
We hope you enjoyed the show.
Episode Preview
Huh?
Didn't Pirate Spirit from race 9 win?
Seriously?!
That was the dark horse! This
pays out a hundred-fold!
One Million Yen
O-One million yen?!
All right, tonight we're having
sushi for dinner, sushi!
Who stole my one million yen ticket?!
The Tokyo-Style Detective Show Next Door
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The Tokyo-Style
Detective Show Next Door, Part One!"
Iroha Sushi
Next Conan's hint!
Iroha Sushi!
We're having sushi next time?
Don't miss the next episode.
Not if I don't win at the races!
But what if he wins?