Mori Detective Agency
Out of the fourth corner, #7
Darkest Nightmare is in the lead!
All right!
Behind him is #4 Kid the Sunflower!
Come on, come on, come on!
Will Nightmare stay ahead?
Or will Kid catch up?
Will it be Nightmare or Kid?
Nightmare is closing in! So is Kid!
It's Darkest Nightmare!
No! I lost again!
#7 Darkest Nightmare wins!
So, how much did you bet on this race?
In second is #2 Kid the Sunflower!
Huh?
N-Not much.
How much?
A thousand each on four or
five races in the second half.
And you lost all of that?
Y-Yes.
Fine. No allowance for you this month.
Hey, the G1 race is next week!
Damn it!
Today's just not my lucky day.
What do you mean?
It was sunny when I left
for the betting booth,
but it started raining
the second I got there.
When I went to buy cigarettes after getting
my tickets, my usual ones were sold out.
Sold Out
Not only that, someone ran into me,
and all the change fell out of my wallet.
To top it all off, my
wallet fell into a puddle.
The tickets in my wallet
got soaking wet, too.
Yamanaka 11 Race
Tansho
4 Kid the Sunflower
Well, they're losing tickets,
so it's not like it matters.
Anyway, what do you want for dinner?
I'm in a bad mood, so let's celebrate with—
Next up are the results
from races nine through 12.
We can't afford to celebrate!
Placing first in race nine, the Yamanaka
Special, was #8 Pirate's Spirit.
What?
Sheesh.
Huh?
What is it?
Didn't Pirate's Spirit from race 9 win?
In second was #11 Zero Enforcer.
What?
In third was #6 Raven Chaser.
Yamanaka 9 Race
Tansho
8 Pirate's Spirit
Tansho tickets for #8 win 10500 yen.
Umaren tickets for #8 and #11 win 20100 yen.
Seriously?!
That was the dark horse!
This pays out a hundred-fold!
Umatan tickets for #8 followed
by #11 win 50800 yen.
How much is it?
Well, he bought it for ten thousand, so...
Sanrenpuku tickets for #6,
#8, and #11 win 25400 yen.
One Million Yen
O-One million yen?!
I knew I could do it!
All right!
But he only bet a thousand
on the other tickets.
Why did he bet ten thousand on just that one?
Maybe when he dropped his wallet,
he picked up someone else's
ticket and put it in his wallet?
I could've accidentally added another digit.
Besides, even if I did pick up a ticket
and put it in my wallet,
the buyer's name isn't written on the ticket.
It's their fault for dropping it.
All right, tonight we're having
sushi for dinner, sushi!
We're heading to Beika Irohazushi next door!
Today is a great day.
I thought you weren't lucky today.
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
A ten thousand yen ticket
yields an easy payout!
But I smell a case at Irohazushi!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Tokyo-Style Detective Show Next Door
(Part One)
"The Tokyo-Style Detective
Show Next Door, Part One!"
There.
Welcome.
Huh?
We're the only customers.
Don't make it sound like business is slow.
Just imagine you've reserved the
restaurant for yourselves, sir.
One beer and three extra specials.
Make one without wasabi for the kid.
You got it.
One beer and three extra
specials, one without wasabi.
Dad.
I can't believe you ordered extra specials.
Don't worry.
We've got this.
You're misappropriating a lost ticket.
Shut up.
Anyway, sir, you're a curious person.
I can't believe you bet all
that money on Pirate's Spirit.
Huh?
H-How did you know?
You didn't see me pick it up, did you?
Pick it up? What are you talking about?
I just used my detective skills.
Detective skills?
My neighbor Mori Kogoro loves horse racing.
The boss said you only come
here when you win at the races.
And I heard you normally only
order regulars or specials,
but today you ordered the extra special.
You must've won big.
The radio said they were only selling dark
horse payout tickets for Pirate's Spirit today,
so I thought that had to be it.
Well?
How are my detective skills, Sleeping Kogoro?
Huh? Uh, they're all right.
Anyway, I don't recognize you.
Are you new?
Yeah.
Wakita Kanenori (56)
Cook
I'm Wakita Kanenori, a cook.
I'm not the type of guy to
settle down in one place.
I eventually ended up here.
I'm what you'd call a drifter.
I see.
I'd rather be in the kitchen,
but it's too dangerous for me
to use a knife with one eye.
The boss told me to handle customers
until my left eye gets better.
Come to think of it, Rum...
Lose?
Come to think of it, that's
what they all said.
That he was missing one.
He?
Rum.
He injured an eye in some kind of accident.
Either his right or left
eye is an artificial eye.
Hey, mister.
Huh?
What happened to your left eye?
Oh, it's a real mess.
Wanna see?
No, thank you.
Anyway, tell me about
the cases you've solved.
I've loved mysteries
since I was a little kid.
Since I heard you live next door to this
place, I've been dying to meet you.
In that case...
Irohazushi
I see, I see.
So she used the footage
from an old home video
to make it seem like the dead man
had come back to life as a zombie.
Now that's an incredible case.
Isn't it?
Another beer.
Oh, sorry. I didn't notice.
Dad, Hattori-kun solved that case.
I helped.
I'm the one who found the zombie first.
You were bedridden after eating
some poisonous mushrooms.
Anyway, sushi doesn't taste
right without wasabi.
Here's your beer.
Welcome!
What'll it be, sir?
Harashima Tsunetaka (25)
Customer
I'll have the nigiri special,
some chawanmushi...
And a cola.
C-Cola?
What was that, old man?
Nothing.
And extra ginger, please.
You got it.
Kids these days drink cola with their sushi?
Apparently they go together
surprisingly well.
R-Really?
Hey.
What is it?
Where's your bathroom?
The bathroom's back there.
Thank you.
What'll it be, sir?
The regular nigiri and an oolong tea.
Munechika Tameshige (42)
Customer
Also, do you have the limited availability
seasonal grilled fish today?
Yeah. We've got horse mackerel today.
Then I'll have one of those, too.
You got it.
You have grilled fish?
Apparently we added it to the menu recently.
We can't make it selling sushi alone.
What a tough world.
Come to think of it, they have anmitsu, too.
No way. I want some.
Sheesh.
What's with this rain?
Welcome!
What'll it be, miss?
The regular.
And what would that be?
You know, the regular.
Huh? Where's the regular guy?
He got hurt in a traffic accident.
Oh, really?
Ashino Natsume (33)
Customer
In that case, I'd like a
highball and seafood chirashi.
Extra sea urchin, salmon roe, and wasabi.
You got it.
Thanks for the food.
Check, please!
Sure thing.
That anmitsu was good.
Yeah.
Seriously?
They were complaining before we got here.
Kogoro-san, come back and tell
me more interesting stories.
I'll take your bill out of my
wages and give you a discount.
Thanks.
If you take me to a crime scene,
I'll give you something extra special.
Well, I doubt any crimes
will be happening here.
Hijirisawa Suzuyo (47)
Customer?
Who stole my pouch?!
I know the thief is in here.
H-Hey, you. What are you talking about?
What's your problem?
Hey, you!
You can't just come in here and
start picking fights with our—
Where's the bathroom?
Th-The bathroom's back there.
Hey, you! If you wanted to use the
bathroom, you should've said so!
I found it!
Found what?
It's not here!
Who threw my pouch in the trash can?
What's going on?
It was just stolen from me on the train.
This pouch I had in my bag.
I see.
But how'd you know it'd be here?
My wallet and phone were in this pouch.
I hurried home and used the GPS on my
spare phone to find it in this shop.
But none of your customers have a
bag they could have put my pouch in.
So I thought they hid it in the bathroom.
I see.
So, when was it stolen?
About an hour ago.
That's shortly before Kogoro-san
and his family arrived.
And since none of the customers
who arrived after him have left...
They might still be inside this store...
The thief who stole your pouch on the train.
How are you going to find them, though?
If they're smart, they'll have wiped
their fingerprints off the pouch.
Don't worry.
I put this on the thief.
A band-aid?
My hand slipped while I was peeling
and apple and I cut my finger.
It was bad enough that I
bled through the band-aid.
I grabbed the right sleeve of the thief
who stole my pouch with this
hand, so it should still be on them.
The sleeve of someone in
here should be stained
with my red blood that seeped
through the band-aid.
Fine.
Here.
No one has blood on their sleeve.
No way. It can't be.
That's not possible.
Just how much was stolen?
None of the money in my wallet was stolen.
Then who cares?
But the ticket I had with my cash is missing!
My dark horse payout ticket
worth a million yen!
What?
A-A dark horse payout ticket
worth a million yen?
And the wallet it was inside was stolen?
Yeah.
I was on the way to get dinner with a friend.
I was listening to the
race results on the radio.
No way. I won.
Won what?
My dark horse payout ticket.
It's a million yen.
What?!
All right!
Then you're paying for dinner tonight.
Sure. I'll buy you whatever you want.
In that case,
you're taking me someplace really expensive.
Go ahead.
How do you feel about French cuisine?
Hey!
What are you doing?
It was stolen from me in the blink of an eye.
You didn't see the thief's face?
I didn't have time for that.
I was doing my best to keep
them from stealing my pouch.
But couldn't your friend have seen them?
My friend is really nearsighted.
On top of that, she had her
glasses pushed up on her forehead
so she could read the
small print on her phone.
But I got a firm grip on
the thief's white sleeve
with this finger that's
bleeding through the band-aid.
It must be on them.
On the sleeve of someone in this store!
But there wasn't any
blood on anyone's sleeve.
Let me get a better look at
the rest of your sleeve, too.
It seems a little damp.
Yeah.
It got wet when I washed
my hands in the bathroom.
Maybe you washed it off in the bathroom.
Don't be ridiculous!
You can't wash blood out with water!
Then show me your sleeve.
All right. My sleeve is wet, too.
Like him, it got wet when I
washed my hands in the bathroom.
My sleeve's wet, but it's
not from the bathroom.
It got wet in the rain.
It was coming down pretty
hard until a minute ago.
I did go to the bathroom once, though.
Hey, Dad.
Huh?
Maybe the ticket you picked
up belongs to that woman.
You idiot.
There's no way.
It was stolen about an hour ago.
I was watching the races
in my office around then.
But the TV broadcast of the races
ended about 50 minutes ago.
Since you were out buying tickets,
you only saw the last race.
An little over an hour ago, you
would've been near the ticket booth.
I-I guess you could say that.
Maybe the thief was in a
rush to redeem the ticket,
ran into you, and dropped it.
I-I guess you could say that.
And you picked it up and
put it in your wallet.
M-Maybe you...
You can't be serious, idiots!
Come to think of it, Kogoro-san, didn't
you have a winning dark horse ticket?
Yikes!
What's with the reaction?
Oh, no. I mean to say, uh...
Blood! Yeah, blood!
Blood?
If you cut yourself deep enough that
you bled through your band-aid,
then your blood must be on the ticket, too.
There wasn't any blood on
the ticket in my wallet.
Of course there isn't.
I made sure to use my uninjured
right hand when touching my ticket.
O-Of course.
Hey, Kogoro-san.
Why don't we make this a contest?
A contest?
Let's see which of us can
find the thief first.
B-But there wasn't any
blood on anyone's sleeve.
Doesn't that make this an unsolvable case?
Dad!
Wh-What's your problem?
I was joking.
I don't have time for this.
I'll leave my money here.
I'm leaving.
Hey, you! You're running away?
What was that?
I finished eating, so I'm leaving.
Is there some reason you have to leave?
Huh? Well, yeah.
Th-There's a show on TV that I can't miss.
A TV show?
I'd understand wanting to
watch a sporting event live,
but these days don't people record TV shows
they're that excited about?
It's hard to imagine a young man
casually ordering the special
at a sushi restaurant doesn't
have a DVD or Blu-ray recorder.
Yeah, it's set to record.
Sheesh. Bring me some ginger, then.
I'll stay.
Right away, sir.
Excuse me, but I'd like to leave soon, too.
Why?
I'm meeting my wife's parents
for a drink tonight.
They've been calling to tell me to hurry up.
They haven't stopped calling.
Honey, what are you doing?
I-I told you.
I got involved in an incident
at a sushi restaurant.
What kind of incident?
Hey!
I've taken your husband's phone.
What? Who are you?
I'm Wakita, an employee at Beika Irohazushi.
A drunk tried to pick a
fight with your husband.
He tripped, and his clothes
got soaked in the rain.
We're drying his clothes at
the restaurant right now.
Then could you tell him
we'll be waiting for him
at Arsene at the Beika Center building?
Sure.
We'll send him on his way as
soon as his clothes are dry.
You should be good for a while.
I-I see...
But Arsene is a classy restaurant.
Why aren't you having dinner there?
My wife's parents are very strict.
I'm too nervous to eat around them,
so I thought I'd eat here.
Family can be complicated.
I don't mind playing along
with this charade for a while.
But I'm leaving before eight.
There's a painting I want
to buy in an online auction,
and it closes tonight at ten.
I'm the highest bid right now,
but it's a popular painting.
If I'm not careful, someone
else will outbid me.
Huh? Miss, you seem like a regular.
You don't live near here?
I live nearby. It's a 30 minute walk.
Then you could easily make it
in time if you left by nine.
My computer's on the fritz,
so I use my phone to bid in auctions.
But it's running out of battery,
so I need to charge it.
In that case, it can't be helped.
Oh, and could I get some more wasabi?
I got less than normal today.
And another highball.
In that case, I'd like
some more grated radish.
I ran out.
And if possible, another oolong tea.
Then I'll take some more cola and ginger.
It's on the house, right?
S-Sure thing.
That's odd, though.
It's strange that that woman's
blood wasn't on anyone's sleeve.
But why did the thief leave the
stolen pouch in the bathroom?
A professional thief would've taken the money
and left the incriminating
wallet in a nearby trashcan.
So why did they bring it into Irohazushi?
Episode Preview
Add... and erase?
The person who has either
a million yen in cash
or the stolen dark horse
ticket on them is the thief.
The thief's already a
carp on a cutting board.
All that's left is for me to name
them and for them to confess.
The Tokyo-Style Detective Show Next Door
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is " The Tokyo-Style
Detective Show Next Door, Part Two!"
Wasabi, Pickled Ginger,
and Grated Radish
Next Conan's hint!
Wasabi, pickled ginger, and grated radish!
It's your fault for picking up that ticket.
Don't miss the next episode!
So I got caught up in a case, too?
Conan-kun, that's always happening to you.
Wow.