While the old man was
watching the horse races
on TV and checking his payout tickets,
we found a dark horse payout
ticket he didn't recall buying.
Maybe when he dropped his wallet,
he picked up someone else's
ticket and put it in his wallet?
I could've accidentally added another digit.
All right, tonight we're having
sushi for dinner, sushi!
We're heading to Beika Irohazushi next door!
So the elated old man dragged
us to Beika Irohazushi,
the restaurant next to the detective agency,
where we met an unfamiliar employee.
Anyway, I don't recognize you.
Are you new?
Yeah.
I'm Wakita Kanenori, a cook.
I'm not the type of guy to
settle down in one place.
I eventually ended up here.
I'm what you'd call a drifter.
I see.
As we finished eating and
were settling our bill,
a woman ran into the restaurant, claiming her
pouch had been stolen from her on a full train.
Using the GPS on the phone in her pouch,
she tracked it down to Irohazushi.
Based on the timing, apparently someone
in the restaurant was the thief.
Furthermore...
Hijirisawa Suzuyo (47)
Victim of Theft
Just how much was stolen?
None of the money in my wallet was stolen.
Then who cares?
But the ticket I had with my cash is missing!
My dark horse payout ticket
worth a million yen!
What?
Hey, Dad.
Huh?
Maybe the ticket you picked
up belongs to that woman.
You idiot.
There's no way.
It was stolen about an hour ago.
I was watching the races
in my office around then.
But the TV broadcast of the races
ended about 50 minutes ago.
Since you were out buying tickets,
you only saw the last race.
An little over an hour ago, you
would've been near the ticket booth.
I-I guess you could say that.
Maybe the thief was in a
rush to redeem the ticket,
ran into you, and dropped it.
I-I guess you could say that.
And you picked it up and
put it in your wallet.
M-Maybe you...
You can't be serious, idiots!
Come to think of it, Kogoro-san, didn't
you have a winning dark horse ticket?
Yikes!
Why don't we make this a contest?
A contest?
Let's see which of us can
find the thief first.
B-But there wasn't any
blood on anyone's sleeve.
Doesn't that make this an unsolvable case?
Dad!
Wh-What's your problem?
I was joking.
That's odd, though.
It's strange that that woman's
blood wasn't on anyone's sleeve.
But why did the thief leave the
stolen pouch in the bathroom?
A professional thief
would've taken the money
and left the incriminating
wallet in a nearby trashcan.
So why did they bring it into Irohazushi?
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
A chef and the old man
have a detective showdown!
Who hid the dark horse payout ticket?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Tokyo-Style Detective Show Next Door
(Part Two)
"The Tokyo-Style Detective
Show Next Door, Part Two!"
Beika Irohazushi
Since the stolen pouch was
left in this bathroom,
is there some significance
specific to Irohazushi?
Or would any sushi restaurant have worked?
It's that young man's first
time at this restaurant.
Harashima Tsunetaka (25)
Customer
I'll have the nigiri special,
some chawanmushi...
And a cola.
Hey.
What is it?
Where's your bathroom?
The bathroom's back there.
Thank you.
The man sitting next to him
seems to have been here before.
The regular nigiri and an oolong tea.
Munechika Tameshige (42)
Customer
Also, do you have the limited availability
seasonal grilled fish today, too?
And that woman seems to be a regular.
What'll it be, miss?
The usual.
And what would that be?
You know, the usual.
Huh? Where's the regular guy?
He got hurt in a traffic accident.
Ashino Natsume (33)
Customer
Oh, really?
In that case, I'd like a
highball and seafood chirashi.
Extra sea urchin, salmon roe, and wasabi.
You got it.
Hey.
Waiter, I've been wondering...
What is it?
Why won't this guy show me his sleeves?!
Who, me?
Yeah, you.
Aren't you a suspect, too?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
I can't listen to this!
That's enough nonsense out of you!
The great Mori Kogoro would
never stoop to stealing!
Come on, sir. Show her.
Prove you're innocent.
Stains on your sleeve?
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
I-I just happened to spill some
soy sauce on myself earlier.
Take a closer look.
It's more soy sauce colored
than blood colored, right?
And see?
He's telling the truth.
It even smells like soy sauce.
But it sounds like he's making excuses.
No, seriously. It's true.
Because he's not totally innocent.
Enough!
Just confess already!
Who did it?!
Who stole my pouch on the train?!
I didn't even take the train today.
I walked here.
I-I took the bus.
I don't like full trains.
I took a taxi.
It's just the base fare
from my office to here.
Then I don't have a choice.
It was careless of me to celebrate my
dark horse payout ticket on the train.
I was willing to forgive
you if you came clean.
But now I'll have to go through the police.
And I'm sure you'd prefer
to get the police involved
so you can erase all doubt, right?
Involved... and erase?
That's it! I forgot!
The police will only have
to search your belongings.
After all,
the person who has either
a million yen in cash
or the stolen dark horse
ticket on them is the thief.
Actually, there's no need to call the police.
The thief's already a
carp on a cutting board.
All that's left is for me to name
them and for them to confess.
N-Name the thief?
You mean you know who did it?
I sure do.
I know who stole your pouch on the train,
brazenly came to eat
sushi at this restaurant,
and hid that pouch in the bathroom.
Then you must have figured that out, too.
Figured what out?
When my pouch was stolen,
I grabbed the thief's sleeve
with my finger wrapped in
a bloodstained band-aid.
But for some reason that blood
wasn't on anyone's sleeve.
Of course.
The thief passed through this restaurant's
shop curtains to erase that blood.
But I'm sure Kogoro-san has
already figured that out.
Huh?
Let's leave the mystery
solving to the professionals.
Let's see one of your detective shows.
I-I have no idea what you're talking about.
Seriously? So the Sleeping
Kogoro's nothing special.
What?
I learned a lot about food
while working as a chef.
Miss.
Yes?
Do you know why they put
ginger in ginger fried pork?
Um...
It's not because it's
called ginger fried pork.
B-Because it tastes better?
That's not the only reason.
Ginger breaks down proteins.
They put it in to soften the meat.
And protein is found in blood, too.
It's difficult to wash
bloodstains out of clothes
because the proteins in
them stick to the fibers.
If you wash bloodstained
clothes with ginger juice,
the stains will come right out.
Really? I'll try it next time.
Wait. Doesn't that mean...?
That's right.
We serve thinly sliced ginger
pickled in sweet vinegar.
So the man who ordered a
mountain of pickled ginger...
That makes you the thief.
When you went to the bathroom to hide
the pouch hidden in your jacket,
didn't you pour the juice from the pickled
ginger on your sleeve to wash out the stain?
H-Hold on!
I seriously didn't steal anything!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Don't play dumb!
Didn't you say you wanted to leave because
there's a show you want to watch?
Y-Yeah.
Kogoro-san and his family came after
the horse races ended just after four.
This woman barged in here
about an hour later at five.
You said you wanted to leave after
the argument about the theft,
so that would've been around 5:30.
If you walked here, it probably takes
you less than thirty minutes to get home.
The only shows on around that
time are cartoons and kids shows.
I-I wanted... to see a kid's show...
Kamen Yaiba!
The enemy boss's adviser is supposed
to be on today's episode!
Huh? Kamen...?
Yaiba?
And you're so into it, you
don't want to miss it?
This Kamen Whatever show?
Yeah, you got a problem with that?
Besides, I don't know exactly how it works,
but wouldn't my sleeve be the color of pickled
ginger if I poured its juice on my sleeve?
Though I'm sure the color would come
out if I washed it right after this.
Y-You're right.
Then go ahead and search my belongings.
I don't have a million yen or
a dark horse payout ticket.
Come on! You guys show them, too!
Then we'll know who the thief is.
Right, mister?
Oh, but...
You, too, old lady!
How rude!
I'm not that old!
Who cares? Just show them what you've got!
If you don't have the
ticket, you're innocent!
E-Excuse me!
I know who has the dark horse payout ticket!
Huh?
Beika Irohazushi
Hey, you.
Is that true?
Well, actually...
Dad, let me see your wallet.
Wait, Ran!
My dad ran into someone at the ticket booth.
He accidentally put a ticket that
was on the ground in his wallet.
Sheesh.
So...
I'm sorry!
You're hopeless.
Yamanaka 9 Race
Win
8 Pirate's Spirit
What is this?
This is a win ticket.
Huh?
What?
I bet five thousand on a quinella
ticket for first and second place.
Yamanaka 9 Race
Quinella
N8-11
Its payout is two-hundredfold,
so it's worth a million yen.
You shouldn't mislead people like that.
S-Sorry...
This is stupid.
I'm leaving.
Hey, you.
We're not finished—
Let me through.
Then I'm leaving, too.
Huh?
M-Me, too.
Hey!
Move.
Wait!
You're running away?
Calm down, everyone.
I guess I don't have a choice.
The dark horse payout ticket
was a quinella ticket...
Hold it right there!
D-Dad?
Since you said you like mysteries,
I thought I'd see what you could do.
But you still have a lot of
learn, detective drifter.
Huh?
Ginger does contain protease,
an enzyme that breaks down proteins.
But ginger isn't the only
thing they're found in.
It's also found in radishes.
If you wrap grated ginger in a handkerchief,
gently pat the front and
back of a bloodstain,
and then place a tissue over it,
the blood will transfer to the tissue.
Repeat the process three or four times,
and the bloodstain disappears completely.
And unlike pickled ginger,
it doesn't leave any color.
Isn't that what you did inside the bathroom?
Hey!
The man who ordered the grilled fish,
which always comes with grated radish,
I'm talking to you!
But maybe he happened to see it on the
menu and wanted some grilled fish.
It's a dish sushi restaurants rarely serve.
No, when he ordered...
Also, do you have the limited availability
seasonal grilled fish today, too?
He asked about the food.
It proves he's been here before
and knows you serve grilled fish.
And only an amateur
would bring a stolen pouch all the way here.
One who never imagined the victim would
use their phone's GPS to
track him all the way here.
Who stole my pouch?!
I know the thief is in here.
So why did you come here to remove
the bloodstain on your sleeve?
You could've returned home and taken
off your shirt or thrown it away.
Wh-Why?
Because he had something to do after this
that didn't allow him to have
a bloodstain on his sleeve.
That young man with the TV
show he doesn't want to miss
and the woman who wants to go home
to participate in online auctions...
would have no problem with a
bloodstain on their sleeve.
But not so for that
bespectacled man on his way
to meet someone for drinks
at an expensive restaurant.
On top of that, he's meeting his in-laws,
who are so strict he's too
nervous to eat around them.
Who knows what they'd say if he
showed up with blood on his sleeve?
B-But that doesn't prove I'm the thief.
No, you've already confessed that you are.
I-I haven't admitted to anything!
You said you came by bus.
Why didn't you take the train?
I said I don't like full trains.
Surely there are empty trains.
B-But she was riding in a full... train...
How do you know the train
she was in was full?
B-Because...
Because you were on that train, too.
Right?
I don't get it.
Why would a rich guy like
you on his way to drinks
at an expensive restaurant steal?
It's my wife's parents who are rich.
My wife wanted for nothing
growing up with them.
Her spending habits haven't changed,
and I can't afford it on my salary.
My savings have been
drained, and I'm in debt.
While I was wondering
if I should borrow money
from her parents that I'm about to see,
I heard her.
No way. I won.
Won what?
My dark horse payout ticket.
It's a million yen.
What?!
All right!
So I acted without thinking
out of desperation.
Then you're paying for dinner tonight.
I gave in to temptation.
I'm sorry!
E-Excuse me...
Is it all right if I answer?
It's probably my wife.
Sure, go ahead.
Thank you.
Hello, honey?
The restaurant we're at has
a vintage Romanée-Conti.
Can I treat my parents?
No.
What?
We can't afford it!
Have a beer and come home!
Oh, also, I need to go see the police now.
I won't be going to the restaurant.
Th-The police?
Wait! What do you mean, the po—
Maybe I should've said that from the start.
I know I just stole from someone else,
but I feel like a weight's
been lifted off my shoulders.
I've actually never bought
a payout ticket before.
I had no idea where or how
to exchange it for cash.
Thirty minutes later, the police
arrived at the restaurant.
Munechika-san was taken away with
the slightly cheerful expression
of a man who's just finished a meal.
I underestimated you, Sleeping Kogoro!
D-Dad?
Huh?
Please make me your apprentice.
Apprentice?
I'll give you a discount on your sushi.
In that case, sure!
He's got another apprentice.
Later...
Beika City Fifth Street Police Box
Do I really have to turn it in?
No one's going to claim it.
Yes!
But no one's going to claim it.
But—
Yes!
The old man turned over his dark
horse payout ticket to a police box.
You've gotta turn in lost items.
Episode Preview
General, the tiger is afraid
of me and won't come out!
Huh?!
The folding screen!
Let's tie him up and put him on display!
Yeah, I'll be waiting.
The Woman With White Hands
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Woman With White Hands, Part One!"
Next Conan's hint!
Wakasa
Wakasa-sensei's House
Wakasa-sensei's house!
Don't miss the next episode.
My dark horse payout ticket!
Instead of betting on horses,
make some money doing your job.
Nice one, Ran-neechan.