[Eyecatch]
Move your base of operations overseas?
Banno
Does this mean you're finally making
a serious effort to win a major title?
Yeah, since I won my first domestic
tournament the other day.
Banno Teigo (32)
Professional Golfer
I'm going to base myself in the United
States and work for three or four years.
Iyama Kurumi (29)
Model
I've already found a house there.
Really?
So...
I need to move out of here by next month.
Could you return the spare key I gave you?
Oh, is that why you invited me
here so early in the morning?
We hadn't seen each other in a while.
I thought you were breaking up with me.
I was nervous.
So, when are you leaving Japan?
My passport is expired.
I'll need to renew it.
Well, actually...
There's no ticket for you.
Huh?
I've thought about it,
and I'd like to reset everything
and start with a blank slate.
So you and I are over.
You owe me 100 million yen in damages.
1-100 million?!
You can afford it, can't you?
It seems like you've been making
money off your photo collections.
W-Wait a minute.
If I give you that much, I won't
be able to go on tour anymore.
You know my father's a lawyer, don't you?
He'll take everything you
have, so prepare yourself.
Calm down, Kurumi.
Why don't we talk about it here tonight?
I'll cook dinner for you like I used to.
Fine.
But I have work at nine tonight.
Then how about 6:30 PM?
I'll make sure you can eat right away.
Just so you know, you can't
distract me with a meal.
In any case, let's talk over dinner.
Also, if you're going to cook,
make my favorite paella.
Although you'll probably
keep making it for me.
No.
This will be our last supper.
Did you say something?
No, nothing.
Really? See you at 6:30, then.
Yeah, I'll be waiting.
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
There's a troubled couple living
in an upper floor apartment.
And Wakasa-sensei's home is next door.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Woman With White Hands
(Part One)
"The Woman With White Hands, Part One!"
General, the tiger is afraid
of me and won't come out!
Every night this tiger leaves
its screen and causes trouble!
If you insist that I capture it,
then you must drive it out of the screen!
Then I, Ikkyu,
shall tie him up for you!
That was amazing, Conan-kun!
It's way better than the script I wrote.
R-Really?
You were like the real Ikkyu-san.
Really?
Impressive as always.
And you've got a sharp tonkatsu.
You mean tonchi (wit).
Menchi (ground beef)?
It's tonchi.
What's that?
Genta-kun, you've heard of tonchi.
I wasn't sure how it would turn out
since you've been skipping rehearsal,
but you show up when it counts.
Actually, I once played this role
my third year of grade school.
"Ikkyu-san"
Ikkyu-san
Priest
General
Who would like to play the role of
Ikkyu-san in the upcoming play?
Teacher!
Suzuki-san, do you want to play Ikkyu-san?
No. I think Ikkyu-san should be played
by the arrogant Shinichi-kun.
What?
Right?
Don't you agree, Ran?
Yeah. And Ikkyu-san is smart like Holmes.
No way!
You're going to be playing
Ikkyu-san in your upcoming play?
Yeah.
That's great, Shinichi. You're the star.
Well, yeah.
Then I, Ikkyu, will capture the tiger.
No, no!
You need to put yourself
in Ikkyu-san's shoes.
Let me see that.
Watch this.
Glare straight ahead.
Then I, Ikkyu, will capture the tiger!
Here. Now you try it.
Th-Then I, Ikkyu, will capture the tiger!
Why don't you change "will" to "shall?"
That'll make it sound more like a
folk tale and give it some weight.
Also, I think changing "capture"
to "tie up" would sound stronger, too.
Great idea, Yu-chan.
Who cares what I say?
It's just a play.
No.
Are you trying to embarrass the
great actress Fujimine Yukiko?
What?
My parents made me practice half to death.
I see.
So that's why you weren't
taking rehearsal serious.
I still remembered most of my lines.
Anyway, this tiger painting is amazing.
It is.
It's very realistic and powerful.
Wakasa-sensei, you painted this, right?
Yes. I'm pretty good at painting.
Okay, everyone.
The play is tomorrow.
Let's finish making the sets we have left.
Okay!
Oh, my.
The water for washing the
brushes is pitch black.
I'll get you some new water.
Thank you.
You're welco—
Ouch...
The folding screen!
Oh, no. What should we do?
I-I'll repaint it immediately.
Oh, but I took the photo of the tiger
I used for reference home...
I know it's a lot to ask,
but you could paint it once you get
home today and bring it in tomorrow?
But then I won't be sure
if the tiger is the right
size for Conan-kun's body.
In that case...
Want me to come over to your place?
I want to go, too.
We'll help you color it.
Really?
It beats working alone.
And I'm kind of interested to see your house.
Thank you.
Then can I count on you to
recreate the tiger screen?
Yes. I'll take the children
home once we're finished.
You live in a high-rise
apartment, Wakasa-sensei?
Yes.
It's just like Ayumi-chan's place.
Yoshida-san, you live in a high-rise, too?
Yeah.
Banno
This way.
She was wearing a lot of makeup.
Seems like she had business
with Wakasa-sensei's neighbor.
What does your neighbor do?
I think he's some kind of sports athlete.
I've only seen him a few times,
so I don't know him well.
I see.
It's done!
It's even better than the last one.
The size and intensity are perfect, too.
Now we just have to glue it to
cardboard once the paint dries.
Thanks, everyone.
I couldn't have done it without you.
You should always help a person in need.
You don't need to thank us.
In that case, to thank you for helping
me, I'll make you some omu-rice.
Seriously?!
Genta-kun.
I thought she didn't need to thank us.
Thanks for the food!
Eat up.
It's good!
It's delicious!
It's the best I've ever had!
Thank you.
Anyway, did you call your parents
to tell them you'd be home late?
Yeah.
Your neighbor's awfully loud.
I hear it all the time.
Apparently he plays music on a
timer instead of setting an alarm.
It's not stopping though.
That's odd.
Normally it stops pretty quickly.
I'm gonna go complain.
Wait, Genta-kun.
And Conan-kun.
Sheesh.
Hey, you're being too loud!
Wake up!
He's not home.
Huh? It's unlocked.
So he is home.
Wait, Genta-kun.
Hey!
It must be that stereo.
Sheesh. How do you turn this thing off?
I'll just unplug this.
It finally stopped.
What's wrong, Genta?
Damn, that's loud.
Huh? Who are you kids?
A-Are you a zombie?
Who are you calling a zombie?
And you shouldn't come barging
into people's homes uninvited.
Next to you.
Huh?
What is this?!
Looks like...
someone bludgeoned her to death.
B-Bludgeoned?
Wakasa-sensei.
Call the police.
O-Okay.
C-Come to think of it, a strange
woman zapped me in my doorway.
You have something on your right cheek.
Something? Like what?
See?
It's written in red.
I love you
"I love you?"
Did you make the dead woman write that?
N-No! This isn't Kurumi's handwriting!
I-It's her!
She did it!
Look!
This woman with the white hands wrote it!
After knocking me out and killing Kurumi!
Metropolitan Police
It's true.
You have to believe me, officers.
A strange woman suddenly showed
up at my place this evening.
The moment I opened the door, she zapped
me with a stun gun and knocked me out.
When I came to, these kids were in
my apartment and were yelling.
They told me to look next to me, so I did
That's when I saw my girlfriend Kurumi
on the floor, bleeding from her head.
I see.
By the way, what about those red
letters on your right cheek?
That strange woman wrote this.
The one who knocked you
out with the stun gun?
This Polaroid that was on the
floor next to me proves it.
Look.
This woman with white hands
is writing on my cheek.
Kurumi was supposed to come
to my place at 6:30 PM.
She must've entered without realizing
that strange woman was inside.
And that woman killed her when
they ran into each other.
An imaginary girlfriend.
Huh?
I've seen it on TV and in magazines.
Men put foundation and
nail polish on their hands
and take selfies to make it look
like they have girlfriends.
Maybe that's how you took that photo.
What are you talking about?
Look closely.
My right hand is behind my head.
And I couldn't write this
clearly on my own face.
Then maybe you made the woman write that
on your face before killing her.
Don't be ridiculous!
There was another photo.
Look.
She took a photo before she wrote on my face.
Kurumi couldn't have written it.
Y-You're right.
Anyway, officers, can I erase
this writing on my face?
It's creeping me out.
Once forensics has taken photos.
Then hurry up.
Do you remember what the
woman who knocked you out
with a stun gun looked like?
Yeah, but since I lost
consciousness almost instantly,
I only got a quick look at her.
She was wearing a broad-brimmed
hat and sunglasses.
A broad-brimmed hat and sunglasses...
Anything else?
Well, she was wearing a lot of makeup.
We saw her standing in front
of the door to this apartment.
Is that true?
She rang the doorbell a bunch of times.
When she realized he wasn't home, she
banged on the door and clicked her tongue.
Come to think of it, she had a scrunchy on
her right hand like the woman in the photo.
That's it! It was her!
She was relatively tall.
Just about your height.
R-Really?
Did you recognize the woman?
I had my first win the other day
and published a photo collection.
I've had a sudden increase in weird fans.
First win?
Are you the professional
golfer Banno Teigo-san?
You just noticed?
Th-Then the murdered woman is the model
you were rumored to have been dating...
Yeah, Iyama Kurumi.
Is she famous?
Yes. Her father's a lawyer.
She was being promoted as a socialite model.
So you have all these trophies because
you're a professional golfer.
The cabinets below are full of file folders.
Don't touch those!
Oh, uh... they're records of
the tours I've participated in.
I finally got them organized
recently, so try not to touch them.
Sorry.
By the way, why did the
murdered Iyama-san come here?
She was just coming to hang out.
She's my girlfriend.
Nothing wrong with that, right?
You were breaking up.
Right?
Huh?
I've been wondering, but who are you?
Oh, I'm their assistant
homeroom teacher Wakasa Rumi.
What's their assistant
homeroom teacher doing here?
I actually live next door.
Today the children helped
me paint the screen
we're using in a play tomorrow.
We heard loud music coming from next door.
Normally it stops immediately,
but today it kept playing.
So we came to check things out and
found the front door unlocked.
And that's how we ended up here.
I see.
What did you mean by breaking up?
This morning on my way to school
I passed by this apartment.
I heard the two of them arguing.
You heard them arguing?
About what?
I think he said he wasn't taking her
with him on his international tour.
And she demanded he pay her
damages for breaking up with her.
He said he'd cook for her so they
could talk about it tonight.
So she asked him to make paella.
And he said
it would be their last supper.
Th-Their last supper?
Oh, excuse me. I may have misheard them.
You haven't cooked anything, though.
We didn't smell any food when
we entered the apartment.
The refrigerator's empty, too.
I was just about to go buy ingredients
when the strange woman knocked me out.
And stop messing around in my kitchen.
Yeah, but when the strange woman rang
your doorbell, you were out, right?
You should've bought the
ingredients on your way home.
I do what I want.
In any case, see if any of the other
residents have seen the woman.
Yes, sir.
And Wakasa-sensei, could you return
to your apartment with the children?
Okay.
Come on, children. Let's
head back to my apartment.
Okay.
Damn it.
If I'd known this would happen,
I would've taken a photo of that
woman ringing the doorbell.
Her white hands are in the Polaroid, though.
Conan-kun.
Huh?
Can't you drag the woman out of the photo?
Aren't you Ikkyu-san?
I-I can't do that.
Besides, I'm not Ikkyu-san.
And not even Ikkyu-san could do that.
Oh?
What is this smell?
It smells like the cosmetics
section of a department store.
Did Wakasa-sensei spill
some of her cosmetics?
It's coming from Kojima-kun's right hand.
Who, me? But I'm not wearing any makeup.
I knew it.
Knew what?
Didn't I say I'm not wearing makeup?
No, I'm talking about the culprit.
Huh? The culprit?
Conan-kun, have you already
figured out who the culprit is?
Who is that woman?
Tell us, Conan-kun.
The person who killed the
model Iyama Kurumi-san is
the professional golfer Banno Teigo.
What?!
Episode Preview
It's hard to imagine someone could
write so clearly on their own face.
That's the thing.
There really was a woman wearing a
broad-brimmed hat and sunglasses.
It was probably that woman in
the photo with white hands.
Hurry up and find her.
These children claimed to
have figured something out.
The Woman With White Hands
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Woman With White Hands, Part Two!"
Seal
Next Conan's hint!
A seal!
Our omu-rice!
Don't miss the next episode.
We weren't...
...finished eating!
We'll eat next time.
It'll be cold.