General, the tiger is afraid
of me and won't come out!
Every night this tiger leaves
its screen and causes trouble!
If you insist that I capture it,
then you must drive it out of the screen!
Then I, Ikkyu,
shall tie him up for you!
While preparing for the school play,
Wakasa-sensei accidentally
ruined the tiger screen.
The Detective Boys came to
Wakasa-sensei's apartment
to help her repaint a new screen.
After finishing the screen,
while eating dinner,
we heard loud music coming
from the neighboring apartment.
Since the music wouldn't stop,
Genta went to her neighbor's
room to complain.
It finally stopped.
What's wrong, Genta?
The unconscious man was professional
golfer Banno Teigo-san.
Banno Teigo (32)
Professional Golfer
The murdered woman was Banno-san's
girlfriend and model Iyama Kurumi-san.
Iyama Kurumi (29)
Model
The words "I love you" were written
on Banno-san's right cheek in red.
At the crime scene were
Polaroids of what appeared to be
a pale woman's hand writing
the words on his face.
Banno-san claimed the woman with white hands
murdered Kurumi-san, but...
What is this smell?
It's coming from Kojima-kun's right hand.
Who, me? But I'm not wearing any makeup.
I knew it.
Knew what?
Didn't I say I'm not wearing makeup?
No, I'm talking about the culprit.
Huh? The culprit?
Conan-kun, have you already
figured out who the culprit is?
The person who killed the
model Iyama Kurumi-san is...
the professional golfer Banno Teigo.
What?!
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
The boyfriend who appears
to be a victim did it?
Expose the secret of the
realistic-looking photo!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Woman With White Hands
(Part Two)
"The Woman With White Hands, Part Two!"
B-But like he said,
his right hand was behind
his head in the Polaroid.
It's hard to imagine someone could write
so clearly on their own face.
That's the thing.
I haven't solved that yet.
Sorry you got caught up in this.
It's fine.
It's not your fault.
What's this piece of paper?
But you only came here
because I ruined the screen.
A convenience store receipt?
It's dated this morning.
Come to think of it, Wakasa-sensei...
Yes?
You were late this morning,
which was unusual.
Why?
When I checked my fridge as
I was leaving this morning,
I noticed it was empty.
I rushed to the convenience
store to buy more groceries.
When I go shopping after school,
most things are sold out.
Really? I see.
Oh, don't tell the other teachers.
Got it.
I hope the rest of you won't tell, either.
Understood.
You can count on us.
Inspector Megure!
Huh? Ah.
How'd it go, Takagi-kun?
There really was a woman
wearing a broad-brimmed
hat and sunglasses.
I see.
Several of the residents saw her.
The security camera footage
also captured her
riding up and down several times.
Her face was hidden by her hat, though.
I thought so.
We found the weapon.
What?
It was the five iron in Banno-san's golf bag.
The five iron?
Also, inside Iyama-san's
bag was the camera believed
to have been used to take the Polaroid,
and the pen used to write the note.
Unfortunately, the culprit's fingerprints
weren't on either one of them.
I see.
Was this really the work of a
crazy fan like Banno-san claims?
We'll pursue that possibility for now.
Takagi-kun, go to Banno-san's
management agency
and check his fan letters for anyone whose
handwriting matches the "I love you" note.
Yes, sir!
Sounds like the police
suspect the woman we saw.
Yeah.
But the killer is that
professional golfer, right?
Yeah. I could tell the moment I met him.
There were two strange things about him.
Huh? Strange things?
But I can't figure it out.
How did he write on his own face?
What are you doing, Haibara?
She's trying to see if she
can write on her own face
by using her phone like a mirror.
There are apps to make
your screen reflective.
I'm using one of those to write on my cheek.
But it's not working.
What?
Ai-chan, it looks like you
have a spiral on your cheek.
A spiral?
Permanent Marker
This is a permanent marker!
Conan-kun, don't laugh
at Haibara-san so much.
Yeah, but...
Oh, my.
Looks like Genta-kun got
tired and fell asleep.
Genta-kun, wake up!
You're sleeping on the tiger painting!
Sorry...
What are you laughing at?
Genta-kun, you look like a tiger.
Your sweat must have dissolved the
paint and made it stick to your cheek.
Uh, oh.
It's okay. This should be easy enough to fix.
Sorry...
Ugh, it's all over me.
Don't touch it.
I'll wipe it off for you.
Th-Thanks...
Ow, ow!
Aren't you going to erase
the spiral on your cheek?
I accidentally wrote it
with permanent marker!
I see. I was overthinking it.
What?
You didn't find anyone
with matching handwriting?
Did you check all the fan letters?
Yes, about fifty of them.
Fan Letters
What? Only fifty?
Yes. Banno Teigo-san's agency only
had this month's fan letters.
They apparently disposed of the rest.
I see.
In any case, find that letter even if
it means turning the agency upside down.
Banno-san's girlfriend Iyama
Kurumi-san was murdered
and the words "I love you" were
written in red pen on his right cheek
by this woman with the white hands.
Yes, sir!
Inspector.
I've told you everything I know.
Can I go now?
The media seems to have
gotten wind of the incident,
and have begun gathering around
the apartment building.
And I'd like to stop by my agency
to discuss my next golf tour.
You're discussing your golf tour when
your girlfriend has been murdered?
Like that lady teacher said, I invited
Kurumi here to break up with her.
I'm surprised she was murdered,
but since I no longer had feelings for her,
I'm not that broken up about it.
A-Anyway, the killer is that woman with
the broad-brimmed hat and sunglasses.
It was probably that woman in
the photo with white hands.
Hurry up and find her.
They'll never find her.
Conan-kun?
We'll never find her?
What does that mean?
Because that woman...
is Banno-san.
What?
Wh-What was that?!
Please, Wakasa-sensei.
We need you to wait in your
room until we contact you.
Oh, b-but...
These children claimed to
have figured something out.
Figured something out?
Yeah. It's Genta's hand.
Try smelling it.
Doesn't it smell like something?
You're right. It smells like cosmetics.
That's right.
That's the smell of foundation that
women use when doing their makeup.
Foundation?
What's that doing on Genta-kun's hand?
Remember how we said
we came into this room
and found the body because
the music wouldn't stop?
It got on Genta's hand when he
banged on the door to get inside.
And if you're wondering what
that was doing on the door,
it's because the woman we
saw banged on the door, too.
Sensei, do women put
foundation on their hands?
No, not normally.
Then maybe the suspicious woman we saw
was a dark-skinned man
wearing foundation
to make himself paler, and
pretending to be a woman.
I-I see.
But what makes me that
man disguised as a woman?
I'm just dark-skinned.
Because when we first met you,
you said two strange things.
What two things?!
Huh? You still have something on your face.
Huh?
Hey, where is it?
What's on my face?
See?
Normally when someone tells you
you have something on your face,
you unconsciously try to touch it.
Isn't that what you did, Genta?
Yeah.
You'd be curious what color it
was or how much of it was on you.
But you didn't...
You have something on your right cheek.
Something? Like what?
So your fingers wouldn't smudge
the words you'd written.
I see.
So you knew there were
words written on your cheek
that would become an important
piece of evidence later.
N-No!
It's not that I knew.
I just thought so instinctively.
Since Kurumi was bleeding on the floor,
I thought there might be something bad on me.
In that case...
Do you know what this is?
Love
Huh?
It's the character for love.
What about it?
What? You don't know?
One of Iyama-san's fans
uploaded the signature
To Adachi Yuto-sama
With love
they received at one of her events.
I traced and enlarged the character
for love that she wrote.
When I used my phone as a mirror
to show you the message on your
cheek, remember what you said?
You said it wasn't the
dead woman's handwriting,
but you don't even know what her
real handwriting looks like.
See?
It's written in red.
"I love you?"
Did you make the dead woman write that?
N-No! This isn't Kurumi's handwriting!
R-Really?
This is Kurumi's handwriting, huh?
I did think it looked similar.
But like I said, the "love" Kurumi
wrote and the "love" on my cheek
were written by two different people.
It's obvious enough that it's
not Kurumi's handwriting.
So you can tell?
Yeah, in a single glance.
In that case...
Huh?
Do you know which of these is Kurumi-san's?
You looked at the mirrored
characters reflected on the phone
and instantly knew it wasn't
Kurumi-san's handwriting.
Well, uh...
But it's hard to tell whose it is
when reversed, even if it's familiar.
It was just a feeling!
I just had a feeling it wasn't hers!
Officer, the photo.
Here.
In any case, the important thing
is this Polaroid the killer took!
Look!
My right hand is behind my head,
so the white woman's hand
in the front isn't mine.
Plus, I couldn't have written
so clearly on my own face.
If you think I did it, tell
me how I took this photo.
Hey, Mitsuhiko.
Huh?
You ready?
Yes. Go ahead and fall
like Conan-kun told us.
Got it.
Hey, what are you kids doing?
Just watch.
When you frame the scene like this,
doesn't Mitsuhiko's left hand
look like Genta's right hand?
I see, I see.
If you hid her fingertips behind your head,
your girlfriend's left hand could
have looked like your own right hand.
But our skin colors and
sleeves are different.
That's easy.
You can make your girlfriend's skin
look darker by using a dark foundation.
For her sleeve, you could
cut the sleeve off another
similarly colored shirt and wrap it
around her left hand under your head.
Then what about this message?
Are you saying I wrote this on my own face?
No, you didn't write it.
You pressed it onto your face, right?
Like a stamp.
First you wrote the words "I love you"
on a clear plastic file
using permanent marker.
Then you flipped it over and traced
the words with a non-permanent marker.
After killing your girlfriend
and taking a photo of yourself
with nothing on your face,
you created the stamp.
Then you pressed the non-permanent marker
side of the file onto your cheek.
See?
Now it looks like the words
were written on your cheek.
I see.
Then you colored your right
hand white using foundation,
applied nail polish and a scrunchy,
held the pen and took a picture of yourself,
creating that trick photo.
So is this what happened?
Having decided to murder Kurumi-san,
you disguised yourself as a woman
and lurked around your apartment...
to give the other residents the impression
that there was a suspicious
woman stalking you.
When Kurumi-san arrived, you
killed her with your golf club
and took the trick photo using the
technique Conan-kun just described.
Then you played loud music from your
stereo so your neighbor Wakasa-sensei
would come and discover the body,
and showed us the trick photo
so we would believe the
suspicious woman did all this.
In other words,
my initial theory about
the imaginary girlfriend
was right on the mark?
Ai-chan, you're so cool.
If only you didn't have
that spiral on your cheek.
What about proof?
The proof's probably in that bag you're
trying to take out of the apartment.
The clear file, foundation, scrunchy,
I love you
and sleeve you put on
Kurumi-san's left hand...
You wouldn't want anyone to
see you leaving the apartment
with those so you could throw them away.
Shall I take a look inside your bag?
It was Kurumi's fault.
I wanted to go on my international
tour with a blank slate.
But she demanded 100 million
yen for breaking up with her!
I doubt your international tour
would've gone well anyway.
What?!
You probably lost the
favor of the god of golf
the moment you used a club as a weapon.
What was that, you brat?
Move!
Stop!
Watch out!
You bi—
Wakasa-sensei!
Ouch...
Are you okay?
Yes. He pushed me, and I fell.
Is it true that there was a murder
in the home of professional
golfer Banno Teigo-san?
Who died?
Do you have a suspect?
Hold on!
Wait for our announcement for the details.
This guy did it.
What?
B-Banno did it?
So you were just subduing him?
No, I just fell because he pushed me.
No, stop!
Could we get your name?
Oh, actually...
Hey!
She's Teitan Elementary School Class
1-B's assistant homeroom teacher.
Wakasa Rumi-sensei.
This is hopeless.
I don't know whether she's clumsy or lucky.
Grade School Teacher Wakasa Rumi Saves the Day!
Subdues Professional Golfer!
Grade school teacher saves
the day... Wakasa Rumi...
Huh.
Now that's clever.
Why are we having cake
first thing in the morning?
Episode Preview
It's good!
Do you not care if you never get
to eat Amuro-niichan's cake again?
That can't happen! We have
to catch the culprit!
Okay, okay.
The Melting Cake!
The next episode of Conan
is "The Melting Cake!"
Electric Kettle
Next Conan's hint.
An electric kettle!
Don't miss the next episode.
Next episode Amuro-no-niichan bakes a cake.
But it melted.
What does that mean?
Watch and find out.