Coffee Poirot
Café Poirot Closed
Good morning!
Good morning.
Good morning, Mori-san.
But we're not open yet.
Well, it smells so good.
It's the meatballs and cabbage stewed in
milk and tomato we're serving this morning.
Looks good.
I'll have the morning special.
Sheesh.
Sorry.
Come in.
What will you have, Ran-san?
I'll have the morning special, too.
What do you want?
Uh...
Me, too!
Roger that.
Café Poirot Open
Huh? Has there always
been a refrigerator here?
Yeah, since about a month ago.
It's a cake fridge.
Poirot's Special Cake
Add a drink for +¥300
Oh, that cake?
Ran-neechan, have you had it?
Tokyo Summit Starting Soon
Yeah. It's really good.
After all, it's Amuro-san's special cake.
Huh? You use an electric kettle?
Yeah.
Our water heater's old.
It takes forever to boil water
first thing in the morning.
If I turn this on with my
phone when I leave the house,
it's boiling right around now.
With your phone? So it's an IoT appliance.
IoT appliance?
They're electrical appliances
that can connect to the internet.
Like that electric kettle.
Really?
Now let's see.
Again.
What is it?
What happened?
You don't need to shout.
But they melted again. Why?
There was nothing wrong when
you made them last night.
Again? This isn't the first time?
No.
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
Amuro-san's new special cakes face
trouble first thing in the morning!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Melting Cake!
"The Melting Cake!"
Here, Dad.
I said I didn't want any.
Why are we having cake
first thing in the morning?
It's good!
You can really taste the egg.
I use more than usual.
It tastes as good as ever.
But with them looking like this,
we can't serve these to
our regular customers.
Why did they fall apart?
Maybe they were made wrong.
Dad.
If it happened twice,
it could happen a third time.
Dad!
You might be right.
Unless we can figure out
why this is happening.
Yes.
We should come up with
some way to solve this.
Agasa
Yes, we're at the professor's
house right now.
You should come, too.
We're flying the drone the professor made.
Apparently it flies really high.
Professor, hurry.
What's wrong, Mitsuhiko?
Ayumi-chan!
What was that about?
How does this thing work?
What happened, Mitsuhiko?
The drone started flying on its own!
No one touched the controller.
It flew without anyone
touching the controller?
What is this?
I told you not to fly it without me.
We didn't.
We didn't touch the controller.
I just made this, too.
It'll take time to fix that.
What?
But what about today?
Don't count on it.
It won't be able to fly today.
But...
Anyway, the flight's been canceled.
Where are you, Conan-kun?
I'm at Poirot.
Huh?
Poirot has this really yummy cake lately.
We were just talking about that cake.
It's not fair that you're the
only one who gets cake, Conan.
Then we'll go get some cake, too!
Yeah!
But the cake is—
What?
Haibara-san, come with us.
I'll pass.
I need to help the professor.
What?
Beika Electric
Poirot's special cake
is sold out today.
We're very sorry.
There's no cake?
You should've said so.
I was trying to when you hung up.
But I was so excited.
Sorry.
The electrician's fixing it right now.
It should be fine tomorrow.
I examined the refrigerator, and
there's nothing wrong with it.
What?
Then why are the cakes falling apart?
I don't know.
Maybe...
Hey! What's gotten into you, Ayumi-chan?
Look at these cakes.
They look like the cake
before it melts, don't they?
Are these cakes copies of Amuro-no-niichan's?
Keep your voice down.
It is suspicious, though.
Hey, guys.
Luxurious Extra Cream Cake
How much do you have on you right now?
Just this.
This isn't nearly enough.
Conan, cough it up.
We know you have a lot of money.
Why?
Dough that uses a lot of eggs
is typically this color.
And if you apply the same amount
of cream in the same way,
it does look similar.
So it's not plagiarism?
I don't think so.
Thanks for the food.
It tastes completely different.
Yeah. Poirot's cakes taste way better.
That solves the mystery.
Does it?
That baker is breaking in during the night,
and destroying Amuro-no-niichan's cakes.
So they can't sell their cakes
since they taste better?
I'm 100% sure they're wrong.
That makes things simple.
What's simple?
We'll conduct a stakeout here tonight.
Who?
Us, of course.
The Detective Boys!
You can't.
You're children.
It's all right. We can do it.
Guys.
Do you not care if you never get
to eat Amuro-niichan's cake again?
That can't happen! We have
to catch the culprit!
Okay, okay.
Azusa-san, can we set up
a camera here tonight?
Huh? A camera here?
Conan-kun, you don't need to do that.
Yeah. This is the store's problem.
But...
Don't worry.
I'll feed all of you delicious cake soon.
Really?
Have you come up with a solution?
Yeah, I've got an idea.
What?
You were filming the store from outside?
Yeah, from closing time
yesterday to this morning.
I'm curious why the cakes
are melting when the fridge isn't broken.
You look into anything
that makes you curious.
Actually, it's because
those kids who are excited
about your cake would be disappointed.
Really?
So you'll investigate anything
for the people important to you.
So, did you find anything after
watching the store all night?
I didn't notice anything suspicious.
Here you go.
Huh? It's not melted.
Yeah, it was fine today.
They don't melt every day?
They fall apart about
two out of every three days.
Two out of three days?
And it's not regular either.
Really?
Teitan Elementary School
I set up a camera watching Poirot
for three days after that.
Class 1-B
Huh?
We can't see inside the store.
Why?
It's hard to tell from this video.
Day 1
4/21
Day 2
4/22
Day 3
4/23
It happened twice out of three days.
11 seconds at 01:00 AM
The first time was 11 seconds
at 1 AM on the 21st.
12 seconds at 02:26 AM
The second time was 12 seconds
at 2:26 AM today, the 23rd.
Poirot's special cake
is sold out today.
We're very sorry.
The 21st and today?
Those are both days the cakes melted.
We knew it.
In other words, it's
likely something happened
during the time we couldn't
see inside the store.
I know!
The culprit came in during that
time and melted the cakes.
But the store was locked.
Are there any signs the lock was broken?
No, there aren't.
In other words, this is an impossible crime.
Or else the culprit is
someone who has the key.
Oh.
What? You think I did it?
Hey.
There's always a car passing by
when we can't see inside the store.
Yeah. What about it?
It always passes by when we can't
see inside the other stores, too.
See?
You're right.
Is it the culprit's car?
It's possible.
Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah, but cars pass by even on
days when the cakes don't melt.
We can't draw any conclusions from this.
But it happens every time the cakes melt.
It must be connected.
Well, we don't have any other clues.
I'll ask the professor
to make it easier to see.
By professor,
do you mean the professor
who makes all kinds
of interesting gadgets for you?
Huh? Yeah.
I see.
That's a taxi.
And...
4/21 - 4/23
Teiko Transit 227
It's the same taxi on both days.
The same taxi passes by when we
can't see the interior of the store?
Has there always been a refrigerator here?
It's a cake fridge.
Why?
There was nothing wrong when
you made them last night.
I examined the refrigerator, and
there's nothing wrong with it.
The drone started flying on its own.
No one touched the controller.
Is it the culprit's car?
I finally figured it out.
What?
The culprit destroying the cakes.
Teiko Transit 227
Car 227, head to Beika Station.
Car 227, there's a Mori-sama
at Beika Station.
Can you get there?
This is car 227.
Mori-sama at Beika Station. Roger that.
Excuse me.
Azusa-san
Calling
It's from Azusa-san.
Then it must be.
Yeah.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, but I already have a passenger.
I know. I'm Mori, the person
who hired this taxi.
What? Mori-san?
Yeah. We're the one who called for a taxi.
But the culprit who melted
Poirot's cakes is...
Coffee Poirot
Ayumi-chan was right.
Poirot's special cake
is sold out today.
We're very sorry.
The cakes melted when we
couldn't see inside the store.
I knew it.
But why couldn't we see inside?
Because the windows fogged up.
Why?
Because of this.
What?
This kettle expels steam
when the water boils, right?
Yeah.
Is that what made the windows fog up?
And this electric kettle
is an IoT appliance, right?
So you used your phone to boil the water?
I got it.
She was turning the kettle on
using her phone during the night.
That makes it possible to melt the
cakes without being in the store.
H-Hold on. I wouldn't do that.
It's not Azusa-san.
What?
Then who did it?
The culprit was reflected
in the windows of the store.
What?
That car?
It was a taxi, right?
Yeah. We talked to the
taxi driver of that car.
Teiko Transit 227
Every night after midnight,
he naps near Poirot.
When he's radioed by dispatch...
He passes by in front of Poirot.
The window fogged up by the
steam from the electric kettle
makes it reflective like a mirror,
reflecting the taxi passing
in front of the store.
When I examined the times he was radioed,
it was the times the window fogged up.
In other words, it matched
the days the cakes melted.
So did the taxi driver do it?
No, the culprit is...
The culprit is the taxi's radio.
Right?
That's right.
The kettle's electrical circuits were
being activated by the taxi's radio.
The frequency of the taxi's radio
and the on/off switch of the
kettle happened to match.
What? Is that possible?
It's called radio-frequency interference.
It happens all the time.
Really?
It's what happened to the drone that
flew on its own at the professor's.
What?
You were talking to me
with your badge, remember?
That's it.
Our badges were causing radio-frequency
interference with the drone.
Yeah.
These badges have a broad range,
so their radio waves must be strong.
We'd better tell the professor to
change the frequency of his drone.
And that radio-frequency interference
was causing the cakes to melt.
What?
How?
You always keep the kettle here, right?
Yeah...
Oh.
That's right. This electric kettle
expels steam when it boils.
The vent on the back of refrigerator
draws in the hot vapor,
turning the inside of the fridge into a sauna
for the several seconds
the windows are fogged up.
That makes the cakes melt, and
then they're chilled that way.
Then I'd better stop using this.
Couldn't you just put it somewhere else?
Oh, right. I'll try it.
Does this mean we can eat
Amuro-san's cake again?
Of course you can.
But it's a slightly different cake now.
It's a half-baked cake that's
melted from the start.
Half-baked cake?
It looks like a shriveled cake.
It's made that way on purpose.
But the sponge inside is cooked.
See?
Wow!
It looks delicious!
Huh? The solution you mentioned...
Yeah.
With these, unlike cakes
that are already frosted,
I can store the cream and cake separately.
Then you don't have to
worry about them melting.
That's right.
I just have to add the cream and fruit
before serving them to customers.
That's not too much trouble at all.
Nope.
And now you can tell them apart from
the cakes from that other bakery.
Amuro-san, you were thinking
of recipes for cakes
that couldn't melt instead of
why the cakes were melting?
Yeah.
After all, isn't that my job?
Well, that aside,
I hope you're doing your job
as a public security officer.
Hey!
You've got something tasty looking there.
In that case, why don't all of you try it?
All right!
Coffee Poirot
This place's cakes are so good.
Who said he didn't want cake
first thing in the morning?
Dude, these are really good!
They're even better than the last cake!
The creamy texture is great!
Maybe that's why they taste even
more strongly of eggs than before.
Yeah.
I use the same number of eggs,
but in a half-baked cake,
the flavor comes through stronger.
And this cream.
It's not too sweet.
I use yogurt in the cream and dough.
So this is yogurt cream I'm tasting.
Yes.
Putting yogurt in the dough makes it softer.
Putting it in the cream makes
it taste better with fruit.
You can have bites of just
dough or just cream and fruit.
It's fun how you can eat
it in all kinds of ways.
I'm delighted to hear that.
That's right.
I forgot why I came here.
Here.
Thank you.
Residents of Beika City,
This letter is to notify you of the
Tokyo Summit traffic control plan.
For the Tokyo Summit that will be
held next month on May 1st, a special
traffic plan will be implemented.
We appreciate your cooperation.
The roads shown below will be closed.
Oh, it's for next month's Tokyo Summit.
Those roads are going to be
closed the day of the summit.
Azusa-san, I've told the manager,
but I'm taking that day off.
I'm counting on you.
Sure.
The manager told me.
Which means Amuro-san will be
involved in the summit's security?
Amuro-san.
You're not neglecting your
public safety duties.
You sure do love investigating, don't you?
At the time, I had no idea the Amuro-san,
who was enjoying baking
cakes over solving cases,
There's more.
would do something like that.
All right!
Episode Preview
Mifuyu! What's wrong, Mifuyu?!
Mifuyu, hang in there!
Why?
Is this really where your friend
was stabbed in the chest and died?
And there's a knife over here.
Tabata must've done it while
bringing Mifuyu-san's body here.
Damn! They got us!
The Real Culprit's Scream
The next episode of Conan is
"The Real Culprit's Scream!"
Suitcase
Next Conan's hint!
A suitcase!
Our movie's such a hit,
the frogs are croaking!
Don't miss the next episode.
Ribbit, ribbit!
But your joke level...
...is zero.