Mifuyu, good morning.
Saeki Ayano (25)
Huh?
Morita
Tabata-san, what are you doing?!
Please stop, Tabata-san!
Mifuyu! What's wrong, Mifuyu?!
Are you okay?! Mifuyu!
Mifuyu...
Mifuyu!
Mifuyu, hang in there!
T-Tabata-san...
Tabata-san?
Did Tabata-san stab you?!
R-Run...
Tabata-san is still...
Mifuyu! Hang in there, Mifuyu!
Mifuyu!
R-Run...
Tabata-san is still...
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
A murder occurs in a woman's apartment!
What on earth happened in there?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Real Culprit's Scream
"The Real Culprit's Scream!"
It stopped raining.
Yeah.
Anyway, I wanted to get lunch at Poirot.
I can't believe they were closed.
Kid, is there anything you want to—
Whoa!
E-Excuse me.
Miss.
Why are you in such a hurry?
You look pale, too.
Are you not feeling well?
Is that blood on your right shoulder?
A-Actually, Mifuyu... My friend
was stabbed by her boyfriend!
What?
This is her apartment.
Wait!
The culprit might still be inside.
Hey. Is anyone there?
Stay here.
Miss, come in.
Okay.
Why?
Is this really where your friend
was stabbed in the chest and died?
I-It's true! It really...
Mister.
Do you think this knife is the weapon?
There's blood on it.
And over here there are footprints
leading in from and out to the balcony.
But a body can't just disappear on its own.
What's going on?
Are you certain the deceased is the resident
of this apartment, Morita Mifuyu-san?
Yes.
How do you know Mifuyu-san?
We worked together at the
bakery by the station.
Today, Mifuyu invited me to hang out.
When I came at the time we agreed upon...
She heard the window
break and someone scream,
"Please stop, Tabata-san!"
So Ayano-san, who had been told
where the spare key was hidden,
unlocked and entered the apartment,
where she saw Mifuyu-san
with a knife in her chest,
who said, "Watch out! Run!" and died.
I heard a noise from the balcony.
I was scared, so I ran.
So the culprit was still
hiding on the balcony then.
Who is Tabata-san?
The man Mifuyu was dating.
Is this him?
Yes, that's him.
That's Mifuyu and Tabata-san.
They met about three months ago.
Someday I'd like to open
a bakery café in Paris.
Tabata Atsushi (35)
Really? What a wonderful dream.
Yeah.
Morita Mifuyu (25)
I'm working hard to save
money so I can do that.
I can provide a little help.
Are you sure, Tabata-san?
We're dating, aren't we?
Tabata-san...
But shortly after that,
he said he was having trouble with
a client and needed money urgently.
Sounds like your typical romance scam.
Did Mifuyu-san give him money?
Yes, about ten million yen.
T-Ten million?!
But Tabata-san, not realizing
I was Mifuyu's friend,
tried to approach me with the same story.
When I told Mifuyu about it,
she said she would sue him.
So Tabata came to silence her.
Also, Ayano-san,
the blood on the knife and floor were type B.
Do you know Mifuyu-san's blood type?
Yes. It's type B.
One more thing,
we found this piece of paper
in the trash can here.
Do these numbers mean anything to you?
I don't know.
293?
It wouldn't be impossible to
enter and exit from this height.
Huh?
What's this?
Hey! Quit wandering around!
Sorry...
Huh?
Is something wrong?
Her suitcase is missing.
She always kept a large suitcase in there.
That's it!
Tabata used that suitcase.
This is what happened, Inspector:
Tabata entered the room from the
balcony by breaking the window,
and murdered Mifuyu-san by
stabbing her with a knife.
However, before he could move
the body, Ayano-san arrived.
So he hid on the balcony, and
while Ayano-san was gone,
he put the body in the
suitcase and took it away.
I see.
Canvas the area to see if anyone saw
a suspicious man carrying a suitcase.
Let's go to Tabata's house.
Yes, sir.
Hello, Inspector.
Hello.
This is Tabata Atsushi's house?
Yes, sir.
Inspector!
There are footprints here.
They seem to be the same as the
ones in Mifuyu-san's apartment.
And these tracks are from
the wheels on the suitcase.
Tabata must've put the body in
the suitcase and brought it here.
Tabata
Tabata-san, are you home?
It's unlocked.
Hey, there's blood on those shoes.
These are the shoes.
The blood must've gotten on them
when he murdered Mifuyu-san.
Yeah.
Tabata-san?
He's not here?
Tabata-san!
What's the meaning of this?
This smell...
I believe he was poisoned.
It may have been in the
coffee left on the table.
That piece of paper.
This is...
What is it?
"I will go to see Mifuyu."
"Tabata Atsushi."
It looks like a suicide note.
Find something we can use to
identify Tabata's handwriting.
Yes, sir.
Mifuyu
It seems to be his handwriting.
Which means it's a suicide.
So he regretted murdering
Mifuyu-san and killed himself.
By the way, where is Mifuyu-san's body?
It doesn't seem to be in this room.
Yeah.
Let's search the other rooms.
Yes, sir.
I found it!
I'm opening it.
Okay.
It's empty.
Could this be a different suitcase?
What's this?
Based on its length, this is a woman's hair.
Inspector!
Tabata must've dumped Mifuyu-san's
body on the way here.
All right.
We'll head back to identify the
hair and search for the body.
Yes, sir!
Mori-kun, well done. We'll handle the rest.
Got it. Thank you, sir.
Once the police find Mifuyu-san's body,
this case is closed.
Let's go, kid.
What's wrong? Is there
something bothering you?
Why did Tabata-san bring the
suitcase all the way home with him?
Huh? Why?
He should've disposed of it with the body.
Yeah.
Now that you mention it, you're right.
And Tabata-san used his coffee
set for guests to drink coffee.
There was a mug he probably used
on a regular basis on the counter.
Huh?
It's like how some people groom
themselves before committing suicide.
Or he had a guest.
H-Hey!
There you go again.
It doesn't look used.
Maybe his guest washed it and put it back.
What?
I knew it.
Knew what?
See? There's lipstick on it.
What?
They did wash the cup to hide
the fact that they came here.
To hide it?
You mean it wasn't suicide because
they murdered Tabata instead?
There's no way, right?
There's a suicide note written
in Tabata's handwriting.
One that says, "I will go to see Mifuyu."
Does that really mean he
meant to commit suicide?
What else could it mean?
Maybe Tabata-san really did just mean
that he would go to see Mifuyu-san.
And maybe it was used to
look like a suicide note.
Then that means this wasn't a suicide.
Tabata was murdered!
And made to look like he killed
Mifuyu-san and then killed himself.
Then maybe they killed Mifuyu-san, too.
Hey, mister.
When we arrived at Mifuyu-san's apartment,
it had just stopped raining,
but the culprit's footprints were dry.
What? Is that right?
Which means it had been some time
since the footprints got on the floor.
It doesn't make sense that
the culprit broke the window
and attacked Mifuyu-san
when Ayano-san arrived.
But Ayano-san heard the window break
and Mifuyu-san scream,
"Please stop, Tabata-san."
That's it!
Ayano-san is lying.
The person who killed Mifuyu-san is—
But if Ayano-san did it,
then she wouldn't have
taken us to that apartment.
That's it!
The culprit made footprints
on the floor beforehand,
waited for Ayano-san to
arrive to break the window,
and made Mifuyu-san say Tabata attacked her,
before stabbing her and
hiding on the balcony.
No, I don't think there
was anyone on the balcony.
Huh?
But Ayano-san heard the culprit
make noise on the balcony.
They made a noise so Ayano-san would
think the culprit was on the balcony
and frighten her into leaving,
using a certain tool.
A certain tool?
A toaster.
There was a pop-up toaster in the kitchen.
They put bread in the toaster,
placed a tray on top of it,
and set the timer,
so when Ayano-san entered,
the toast would pop up,
and the tray would fall and make a sound.
There were crumbs on top
of the air conditioner.
Then who killed Mifuyu-san?
There's only one person who could've
prepared all of that beforehand.
Hey.
You don't mean...
What's this?
There's something written
under today's date...
Paris 293?
293? Wasn't that?
Do these numbers mean anything to you?
Someday I'd like to open
a bakery café in Paris.
Paris... 293...
Damn! They got us!
Now my new life begins.
I don't think so.
I thought you'd be here.
The 293 on the note thrown
away in your apartment
was the flight number of
your Paris-bound flight.
I knew you were alive,
Morita Mifuyu-san.
Who are you talking about?
You've mistaken me for someone—
Hey, mister.
I found Mifuyu-san.
France Fair
She's at the France Fair
café in the departure lobby.
Yeah, got it.
Anyway, it's time for my flight. I'm leaving.
I don't have time for you.
Ouch...
Isn't that pain from the wound
you inflicted on yourself?
So you could put blood on the floor, the knife,
and the shoes you used to make the footprints.
I thought it was strange.
There wasn't enough blood for
someone stabbed in the chest.
While Ayano-san was gone,
you went to Tabata-san's house.
You left the bloodstained shoes and
suitcase with the hair inside it.
Then you murdered Tabata-san and
made it look like a suicide.
Didn't you?
Wh-What are you talking about?
Who are you?
Edogawa Conan.
I'm a detective.
In any case, I have nothing to do with this.
Hold it right there, Morita Mifuyu-san.
We're the police.
Mifuyu, you're alive.
After investigating the
late Tabata-san's home,
we discovered his bankbook was missing.
We checked with his bank, who told us
ten million yen had been withdrawn.
Morita-san, you stole that money, didn't you?
No.
That ten million is mine.
I was just taking my money back.
Then who killed Tabata-san?
It's his fault.
He tried to steal my money.
So I...
I'll head to Paris first and
find a location for my café.
Yeah.
I'll be there soon.
You say that now,
but you actually plan to get
with another woman, don't you?
Of course not.
Then please,
promise me you'll come see me.
Then I won't doubt you anymore.
Fine.
If that'll put your mind at ease.
I was mortified, so I thought I'd trick him
and steal all his money.
He got that money tricking
other women, anyway.
Oh, well. I almost had my rich Paris life.
Mifuyu, did you use me?
I thought we were friends.
What?
How long are you going to keep
pretending to be the good girl?
Did I use you? Yeah, I did.
After all, it's your fault I killed him.
What?
I'm not stupid.
I suspected he was trying to deceive me.
But if he'd just stolen
my money and disappeared,
I would've remained a victim.
If only you hadn't snitched!
Because you snitched on him,
I had to get my revenge!
Hey!
Because of you, I killed him!
Because of you, he died!
Stop!
"You're being tricked, Mifuyu," my ass!
You just wanted to brag
that he didn't trick you!
That's enough!
You decided to kill Tabata,
and then actually did it.
Don't blame anyone else!
It's pretty late.
Yeah.
Women are terrifying.
A woman that beautiful
can change so suddenly.
Come to think of it, didn't
we leave to get lunch?
Let's get some soba in the area.
Mori-san!
Excuse me, but you're the great
detective Mori Kogoro, aren't you?
U-Uh, yes.
Lucky us!
We're huge fans!
Will you tell us about your cases?
In that case, why don't
we get dinner somewhere?
I'm so happy!
Are you sure?
It's fine!
We were just talking about
getting some French!
Hey, what am I supposed to do?
Episode Preview
Have you figured out who tried to kill me?
Ahem.
Of course.
There's no mystery Mori Kogoro cannot solve.
All truths will be revealed!
The Truths of the Locked
Room Revealed
The next episode of Conan is "The
Truths of the Locked Room Revealed!"
Ballpoint Pen
Next Conan's hint!
A ballpoint pen!
Huh? You're back already?
Don't miss the next episode.
Women are terrifying.
Mister, you've got no eye for women.