I've gathered everyone together,
just like you asked.
This is the perfect place, too.
I manage this property now.
It used to be some kind of research facility.
No matter how loudly we shout
here, no one will hear us.
Azuma Toichiro (44)
Real Estate Company President
So, have you figured out
who tried to kill me?
Which one of these three is it?
Ahem.
Of course I know who tried
to kill you, Azuma-san.
There's no mystery Mori Kogoro cannot solve.
All truths will be revealed!
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
Thanks to our viewers,
we've reached 900 episodes!
The old man's a little different today!
Always determining the one truth with the
body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Solving Mysteries in a Locked Room
"Solving Mysteries in a Locked Room!"
Azuma-san came to my
office yesterday evening
and said someone was trying to kill him.
A threatening phone call?
Yeah. They said they'd kill me.
I'm sure they were just trying
to intimidate me, though.
But, sir, there's a chance they were serious.
As you can see, Kasai's worried about it,
so I thought I'd ask you to
determine who called me.
I believe it's one of these three.
Kasai Haruhiko (32)
Real Estate Company Secretary
We think they may resent the president.
I see. You have a list of suspects.
Could you fill this out, please?
Now that the great detective
Mori-san has taken our case,
it's as good as solved.
I hope you're right.
The next day, or in other words, today,
I decided to begin my investigation.
Azuma-san has been pressuring me
to sell this property.
Yamanami Benkichi (52)
Office Worker
My wife who was against it died
in an accident the other day,
so I've decided to let it go.
But I realized something.
Azuma-san may have killed my wife.
What? So you stabbed him?
I told you, that wasn't me.
Fukunishi Auto Repair
Inspections Welcome  -  Cheapest prices around!!
I didn't do it, but I
understand how they feel.
That Azuma bastard stole the
land my dad left to me.
Kitao Mitsuru (26)
Auto Mechanic
Him, too.
What's going on here?
Is it possible your father
sold the property to Azuma?
Then where did the money from the sale go?
I see.
But, Tomurai-san,
it's true that you resent Azuma, isn't it?
Yes.
My father killed himself after Azuma
tricked him out of the property
Tomurai Kana (30)
Waitress
that had been in our family for generations.
Murderers always get their
comeuppance eventually.
It's true that all three of you are suspicious,
but there's no damning evidence.
That's when the threat
was turned into reality.
Toto General Hospital
I'm sorry!
It's because I left your side.
It's not your fault.
But...
It happened when I sent Kasai shopping.
It's like they were waiting
for me to be alone.
It was someone wearing a ski mask...
What did the police say?
I haven't told the police.
What?
I don't want to get the police involved.
I conduct a lot of shady business.
But this is attempted murder!
Are you saying you can't solve the case without
the police, you incompetent detective?!
Hurry up and figure out which
of the three of them did it!
If I pay them enough, I'm sure they'll stop.
I went to the place where
Azuma was attacked.
Repairs In Progress
The security camera in the parking
lot was undergoing repairs,
so I couldn't review the
moment of the crime.
Damn it!
I know it was one of you!
Confess already!
Now, now.
Later I went to your office and spoke
with a clerk named Suematsu-san.
Suematsu Sueko (21)
Real Estate Agency Clerk
But Mori-san didn't ask
me about those three.
They don't have any problems.
They're very close and always
whispering secrets to each other.
That made me realize their motive.
Kasai-san, it seems you've committed
a lot of crimes as Azuma's right hand man.
You can't conduct business without
getting your hands dirty.
But the situation changed.
Your beloved sister was unofficially
offered a job at a first-class bank.
I thought we were just making small talk.
If your crimes came to light,
your sister would lose the offer.
Fearing that, you tried to kill
Azuma, who knew your secret.
I...
It was you?!
No way!
You did this?
Damn it! Because of you...
No! It wasn't me!
You were captured on the
security camera's footage.
But you just said you couldn't review
it because it was undergoing repairs.
The parking lot camera was.
Later I went to a nearby
convenience store
to check their camera.
This is Kasai-san.
He's buying the things
Azuma-san asked him to get.
Wh-What's this?
A ski mask...
Then what about these guys?
The three of them had nothing
to do with this case...
This is it! The so-called...
Sleeping Kogoro...
Azuma was attacked by Kasai-san,
but there was someone
who ordered him to do it.
What do you mean?
If Kasai-san had always
planned to killed Azuma,
he would've killed him in secret
instead of threatening him.
He had plenty of chances.
In other words, Kasai-san isn't
the one who made the threat.
But since Kasai-san attempted to
kill Azuma, it's natural to assume
he didn't choose to do it,
but was ordered to do it by someone else.
When you consider Kasai-san recommended
hiring me to investigate the case,
he must have received the order after that.
Perhaps Kasai-san was
threatened late last night...
"I'll expose all the crimes
you've committed."
"Your beloved sister will go down with you."
"If you want to protect
your sister, kill Azuma."
Isn't that right, Yamanami Benkichi-san?
When I went to question you,
you had an expensive ballpoint pen.
It belonged to Kasai-san.
When you threatened him last night, you
likely picked it up after Kasai-san dropped it.
Surely you don't suspect me because
we happen to have the same pen.
This is why I didn't want to do it!
Shut up!
In order to keep your hands clean,
you manipulated Kasai-san and
made the threatening call.
By making the threat, you directed
suspicion towards yourselves,
so Kasai-san could kill Azuma during
that resulting opportunity.
You saw through my deception, Mori Kogoro...
All I have now is my last resort!
It was all a lie, Mori-san.
I see.
Prank Show Successful!
Nichiuri TV
Tada!
Our prank show was a huge success!
Our goal this time was for you to find
the culprit behind a fake crime.
And see the astonished face you made
when he threatened to blow himself up.
We're all paid actors.
They were all acting according to script.
A prank show, huh?
That explains everything.
You're not surprised, Mori-san?
I thought something was up
when Azuma refused to notify the police.
Yamanami-san and Kitao-san's
strange behaviors
also make sense when you realize they
were playing to hidden cameras.
Impressive, Mori-san!
We're a small theater troupe.
This job was given to us by
Nichiuri TV's Tomurai-san.
She's the one who wrote the script.
Normally we do comedies,
so this serious performance
was exciting for us.
But since you suspected
we were up to something,
you can't call this a huge success...
No, it was.
I hope you're right.
Now let's get out of here.
It's over.
We're getting yakiniku tonight, right?
Let's get ramen instead.
Who is she?
Huh? The door won't open, Tomurai-san.
Huh? I can't get the bomb off.
Excuse us, staff?
Could someone get this off him?
There's no point in calling them.
We're the only ones here.
This is when the real show begins!
The story about filming
a prank show was a lie.
We were never filming or
recording in the first place.
And naturally, I'm not an
employee of Nichiuri TV either.
It's locked.
I can't have you escaping
and calling the police.
Damn. There's no service.
Of course not.
This building blocks phone signals.
I'd been searching for the
perfect place for two months,
so I could execute this detective.
Execute?
What's wrong with her?
Damn. I won't let her kill him.
Crap! My shoes are out for maintenance!
You just sit there quietly and watch,
if you don't want your friend to blow up.
I installed the same detonator on
the dynamite wrapped around you.
You mean this isn't a prop?
Damn! What should I do?
Please do something, Mori-san!
Save us!
Mori-san!
Move. You'll get caught in the crossfire.
You said you'll execute me, but
what have I ever done to you?
Who are you?
Why don't you guess?
Aren't you the world's greatest detective?
You have a strong grudge against me.
You have a gun and explosives.
You could've surprised me or thrown
a bomb into my office, but instead
you went through the trouble of writing
a script and having me solve a mystery.
It was so I'd become the Sleeping Kogoro.
In other words, you don't
hate the ordinary Kogoro.
You hate the Sleeping Kogoro.
And you spent two months preparing.
Two months?!
Murderers always get their
comeuppance eventually.
Are you Utsubo Takashi's...
Impressive, Sleeping Kogoro.
Of course I swore revenge.
If not for your meddling detective work,
Utsubo wouldn't have gone to jail.
He wouldn't have died!
I see. You're Utsubo's...
Utsubo was a good man.
He was handsome and intelligent.
But he used his intelligence the wrong way.
Six months ago, Utsubo disguised a murder
as a suicide using a clever trick.
I solved the case as the Sleeping Kogoro,
and Utsubo was imprisoned for murder.
Utsubo Takashi (33)
Criminal
Two months ago, Utsubo suddenly fell ill.
He died in prison.
You took Utsubo from me forever!
Isn't your anger completely unjustified?
Shut up!
I did suspect something,
but I didn't realize there
was another plot behind it.
I had to execute you while you
were the Sleeping Kogoro.
I feel a little sorry for you,
but killing a detective while he's
proudly laying out his reasoning
is the ultimate irony.
Watch this.
I trapped you in here
so you could tell the world about
the great Mori Kogoro's final moments.
Goodbye, Sleeping Kogoro-san.
Say hello to Utsubo for me.
Stop!
Don't shoot him!
Please! Don't shoot!
Move! If you get in the way, I'll shoot you!
You'll shoot a child?!
You wouldn't shoot a child, would you?
You're right.
Kid, if you don't move, I'll
blow up that man over there.
But...
I know!
Make her laugh.
What?
Once she laughs, I'm sure she'll feel
stupid about trying to get revenge.
In that case, there's that thing
for our next performance.
That's hilarious. All right.
You're wasting time.
I don't have time for your stupid acts.
It didn't work.
Now move.
No matter how much you
stall, I won't give up.
No one's coming to save you.
A cockroach!
Mouse! Snake!
Centipede! Hornet!
I don't know what to do if the old man dies.
I won't be able to go to school.
I won't be able to eat anymore.
Please don't kill him.
His family will be so sad, too.
Don't you have family, too?
Regain your humanity!
You'll regret shooting him!
It's not too late!
Throw away your gun and detonator, okay?
Please don't kill him.
Please...
Get up.
There's nothing I hate
more than sob stories.
It's crude.
That should be enough.
She's going to shoot!
She's going to kill Kogoro-no-ojisan!
Mister!
Kogoro-no-ojisan!
No, you don't!
You'll never get your way!
You brat!
Move! Let go!
Damn it!
Sheesh...
What's everyone screaming about, huh?
What's going on here?
I'm out of time.
Kid.
Your protests, jokes, and tears.
You were buying time to fill
that bottle with water.
Well, yeah.
Hey.
What's this talk about buying time?
Oh, uh...
And what are they doing?
We're saving your life, Mori-san!
Hey, we could turn this into a play.
I'm saved.
I'll be the dynamite man.
You never learn.
I want to play the detective.
You wouldn't have to move.
Don't actually fall asleep.
Prank Show Successful!
Nichiuri TV
Huh?
Prank Show Successful!
Nichiuri TV
A prank show?
Was there a film shoot?
It's a long story.
Episode Preview
Here's your tomato juice and sandwich.
Thank you, Kuriyama-san.
Huh? You're starting to sound like Eri.
Really?
I don't like it!
Huh? Mom?
"I've been captured by some bad people."
"Could you call the police?"
What?
Counselor Kisaki's SOS
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is
"Counselor Kisaki's SOS, Part One!"
Tomato Juice
Next Conan's hint!
Tomato juice!
What? Eri's in trouble now?
Don't miss the next episode.
Like husband, like wife...