Come on, Dad, hurry up and get ready.
The movie's going to start.
Mori Detective Agency
No way.
Huh?
I don't want to go.
What?
Why not?
You were looking forward to seeing
the new movie starring Okino Yoko.
I don't like what it's about.
What it's about?
I don't mind that Okino Yoko-chan's
playing a beautiful and talented lawyer.
Court Detective
Kirie Saki
Summary
You're the only one for me.
A love-mystery starring Okino Yoko
that will bring tears to your eyes.
Protagonist Kirie Saki (Okino Yoko)
is known for being a beautiful
and talented lawyer. One day,
former police officer and detective...
But her boyfriend's a former police
officer and incompetent detective,
You're under arrest!
who accidentally becomes
a suspected murderer
Objection!
and clears his name using
her detective skills.
"You're the only one for
me!" is what he cries
as the detective clings to his girlfriend
in this moving love/mystery.
Who would go to see this movie?!
I-It sounds interesting...
Maybe they based his
character off the old man.
Besides, those movie tickets
are for premium seats.
Huh?
Invitation
Premium Seats
Oh, yeah.
Eri probably got them for me.
Well, yeah.
Unbelievable.
She's definitely planning
on showing up so she can tell me
to reflect on my mistakes like
the detective in the movie.
Does that mean there are things
you think you need to reflect on?
You're starting to sound like Eri.
Really?
I don't like it!
If more impertinent women
start appearing in this world,
we're done for.
Sheesh.
A friend request on my messaging app?
I wonder who it is?
Huh? Mom?
Kisaki Eri
Add
But we're already friends.
Maybe her secretary Kuriyama-san
sent a message as a joke.
Oh, right.
Then I'll add her to the group.
Huh?
Kisaki Eri
See you later.
See you later (Read)
Today
Kisaki Eri I've been captured by some bad
people. Could you call the police?
"I've been captured by some bad people."
"Could you call the police?"
What?!
Ran-neechan, let me see.
What should we do?
Start by asking her if that's true.
Okay.
"Is that true?"
Is that true? (Read)
She responded.
Kisaki Eri
Yes, but I don't know where I am.
Kuriyama-san's still at the office.
I'm worried about her...
She says she doesn't know where she is.
Damn!
Sounds like she was
kidnapped from her office.
Huh?
Kisaki Eri
Just kidding! I'm joking!
Don't take it seriously.
It was just a joke?
Jeez, Mom.
But wait... Look.
Kisaki Eri
That message was from an impostor!
They're using my phone to send messages!
The icons are different.
They're probably not the
same Eri-san you just added.
Hold on.
If the person using Eri's
usual icon is an impostor...
And the one without an
icon is the real Mom...
Kisaki Eri
What are you talking about? I'm the real Eri!
Damn!
They changed from Eri's
usual cat icon to no icon!
Kisaki Eri
What are you talking about? I'm the real Eri!
No! I'm the real Eri!!
Kisaki Eri
Shut up, impostor.
You're the impostor.
Kisaki Eri
No, you are!
The moms are multiplying?!
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
There's something wrong
with these phone messages.
What happened to Counselor Kisaki?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Counselor Kisaki's SOS
(Part One)
"Counselor Kisaki's SOS, Part One!"
Two hours earlier...
Kisaki-sensei, I'm back.
Here's your tomato juice and sandwich.
Thank you, Kuriyama-san.
I didn't have time to eat lunch.
I'm starving.
Should you be eating that?
Huh?
Don't you have a movie date with
your ex-husband after this?
We're not divorced, we're separated.
And it's not a date.
I'm just going to see a movie because
my daughter wouldn't stop pestering me.
Besides, there's no telling what he'd say
if my stomach growled during the movie.
Really?
You don't mind your stomach
growling in front of your clients,
but it bothers you if it's
in front of your husband.
O-Oh, is that right?
Huh? We shouldn't have any
more clients coming today.
Could you go check?
It could be a walk-in.
Sure.
If it's a client,
I'll probably have to eat lunch in
the car on the way to the theater.
Kuriyama-san, was it a client?
Kuriyama-san?
Kuriyama-san!
Sheesh. Who are you?
This is emergency services.
Are you calling about an accident or a crime?
Kisaki Eri, we're with
the Victims Association.
Jeez!
Your mom's going out.
Stay there and behave like a good cat.
Ouch...
Sheesh. How could you let a woman beat you?
Sorry...
Hello? Is something wrong?
Hello?
Sorry, prank call.
Hey!
Hey, what should we do with
the unconscious secretary?
Who cares? Just leave her.
She didn't see our faces.
You're taking the lawyer's phone with you?
Yeah.
We're going to show her husband, Mori Kogoro,
an embarrassing video of his wife.
Okay.
Bring the case with the lawyer upstairs.
I'll head up there first and
help set up for the shoot.
Got it.
Huh?
Sh-She's bleeding?!
Damn. I don't believe this.
What?!
The suitcase is bleeding?
But we're ready to start filming!
M-Maybe she bit her tongue off.
Open the case and check its contents.
Hey.
Huh?
Tell him to be careful when he opens it.
Huh? Yeah, I know.
Hey! What happened?
Answer me!
Hey! Hey!
My tomato juice plan worked.
It's no use.
The shutter's too heavy.
It's locked.
The windows are reinforced with wire.
I doubt I can break them.
Looks like I'll have to hide somewhere
in this abandoned building
until help arrives.
You idiot!
You mistook tomato juice for blood?!
I told you to be careful when you opened it!
S-Sorry...
On top of that, she stole your phone.
If she escaped, then we now have the
opportunity to enjoy capturing her.
Now let's catch that escaped doe
and rip her skin off.
But where should I hide?
Come to think of it, the
other day Ran said...
That's right.
The culprit hid a corpse inside
a dresser in the zombie case.
What a surprise, right?
That trick involved using a cart
so the body wouldn't be found
even if the drawers were opened.
It should be good enough to hide in.
Hey, Kisaki-sensei.
Are you in here?
Hey, come on out.
Making this difficult isn't
in your best interest.
Hey.
The drawers are sticking out
a bit, but I was able to hide.
Next I'll use this phone I stole
from that man to contact the police.
Incoming Call
Unknown Caller
Hey, are you calling your phone?
Huh? Yeah.
But she silenced my phone.
What if she calls the police?
Don't worry.
She doesn't know where we are.
And if she makes the slightest sound
while explaining her situation,
that's when we'll catch her.
All right. We'll split up and look for her.
Let's not make any sound either.
If I can't call anyone,
I'll have to e-mail them.
But I don't remember anyone's address.
I know. I remember Ran's
messaging app username.
C-Crap!
She's talking to her daughter
through a messaging app!
S-Seriously?
Look!
Kisaki Eri (3)
I have to be up early tomorrow.
See you later. (Read)
Mori Ran
See you later
Today
Kisaki Eri
I've been captured by some bad
people. Could you call the police?
Mori Ran
Is that true?
Damn! We have to stop her!
Pretend to be the lawyer and
join the chat to confuse them.
In the meantime, we'll find her.
Okay. Got it.
Use the same icon she's using.
Got it.
Mori Detective Agency
Damn!
They changed from Eri's
usual cat icon to no icon!
Kisaki Eri
What are you talking about?
I'm the real Eri!
Kisaki Eri
No! I'm the real Eri!!
What are you talking about?
I'm the real Eri!
Kisaki Eri
No! I'm the real Eri!!
Shut up, impostor.
Kisaki Eri
No! I'm the real Eri!!
Shut up, impostor.
Kisaki Eri
You're the impostor.
Shut up, impostor.
Kisaki Eri
You're the impostor.
No, you are!
The moms are multiplying?!
Damn.
Now we don't know which messages
are coming from the real Eri.
Kisaki Eri
Shut up, impostor.
You're the impostor.
Kisaki Eri
No, you are!
What's going on?
It's my fault for turning
it into a group chat.
A group chat?
But why isn't mom calling me?
Because she can't make any noise.
Huh?
She probably escaped from her kidnappers,
and is contacting us from
wherever she's hiding.
Then end the group chat immediately.
If you ask them separately for
her birthday or something,
we'll know who's the real Eri.
O-Okay.
No, I think it's better
to leave it like this.
What?
But the bad guys can see our conversation.
But she doesn't know where
she was taken, right?
Kisaki-sensei said she
doesn't know where she is.
So wouldn't it be better to keep chatting
with the bad guys so they reveal themselves?
Kisaki-sensei's smart.
I doubt she'd say anything that
would reveal her hiding place.
Yeah, but...
We don't even know if it's the real
Eri who's claiming she was kidnapped!
We do.
Huh?
Wh-What?
You can tell, Conan-kun?
Kisaki-sensei is a lawyer, right?
Yeah.
Shinichi-niichan told me
lawyers use Western commas
Japanese Comma
Western Comma
instead of Japanese commas in their
documents when writing horizontally.
That habit shows up in
their normal writing, too.
You're right.
Kisaki Eri
I have to be up early tomorrow.
See you later.
The messages I received from Mom
before all have Western commas.
Then check the "I've been kidnapped"
message you received first.
Okay.
It uses Western commas.
Damn. So she really was kidnapped.
Okay. I'm going to call the police
and have them check her office.
Ran, stay here and keep chatting.
Okay.
Tell them you don't know who the real Eri is.
Make sure you use Western commas.
Got it.
Damn!
We can't find her anywhere!
Where is she hiding?
Calm down.
She can't get out of the building.
She's a rat in a bag.
Yeah.
Hey, how are you doing?
Are you confusing them?
Yeah, by pretending to be her.
Sure enough, she can't tell who's who.
Kisaki Eri
Ran, don't be fooled!
Can't you tell? I'm the real Eri!
Mori Ran
I don't know which mom
is the real mom -_-;
This is great.
Mori Ran
I don't know which Mom
is the real Mom -_-;
Mori Ran
Which is it?
Ran started using Western
commas in her messages.
Looks like she knows which
messages are mine.
"Can you see anything?"
Mori Ran
I don't know which Mom
is the real Mom -_-;
Mori Ran
Which is it?
Can you see anything?
Like the Toto Tower or the Metropolitan
Government office building?
"Like the Toto Tower or the Metropolitan
Government office building?"
Mori Detective Agency
What are you asking her that for?
If she answers that, the bad guys
might figure out where she's hiding.
We don't even know if her hiding
place has windows to the outside.
Yeah.
That's why I doubt Kisaki-sensei
will answer, but the bad guys might.
Kisaki Eri
I can see the government office building,
but I can't see the Toto Tower.
She responded!
"I can see the government office building,
but I can't see the Toto Tower."
I see. So they're someplace
where the Toto Tower is visible.
That's right.
It's nearly 5 PM.
Ran-neechan, tell her to call us immediately.
What?
But if she speaks, they'll know where she is.
She knows that!
Mori Ran
Which is it?
Can you see anything?
Like the Toto Tower or the Metropolitan
Government office building?
Kisaki Eri
I can see the government office building,
but I can't see the Toto Tower.
Mori Ran
Can you call me?
Call?
They're calling.
Incoming Call
Damn.
It's an IP number starting with 505.
Hello, Mo—
Kisaki-sensei, you don't have to say a word.
Just do as I say.
The bell of the church near the
detective agency will ring soon.
If you can hear it from where you are, could
you tap your phone with your fingernail twice?
If you understand, tap your phone once.
Conan-kun?
Okay. It should be ringing soon.
About three seconds.
Huh? What about three seconds?
Sound travels at about 340 meters per
second, and there's practically no wind today.
So Kisaki-sensei is probably in a place about
a kilometer from here from which
the Toto Tower is visible.
Let's go!
O-Okay.
Conan-kun...
He's just like Shinichi.
Come to think of it, this has
happened a bunch of times.
Ran, what are you doing?
Let's go!
I'm coming.
Don't. I need to focus on
rescuing Mom right now.
Yes, that's right.
Yes.
Kuriyama-san just seems to have
been knocked out with a stun gun.
She's fine otherwise.
I-I see. Got it.
By the way, Mori-san, what are you doing?
You seem to be short of breath.
I'm heading to the place where Eri was taken!
What?! You know where she is?!
I'm panicked because I don't know!
It's okay, Mom! We're on our way!
Don't worry! Keep hiding!
What?
The lawyer and her daughter stopped chatting?
Is that true?
Yeah.
My messages aren't showing as read.
Maybe she's using the phone she
stole to call her daughter.
If the police figure out his number,
won't they be able to find us?
Don't worry.
I took the SIM cards out of our phones.
We can only make VoIP calls.
In other words,
they can't use cell towers
to determine our location.
Besides, you removed the
SIM card from her phone
and disabled the GPS, right?
Yeah.
More importantly, apparently the
daughter asked what she could see.
Did the lawyer answer her?
Uh, no.
Which means it's likely
she's hiding in a closed space where
she can't see out any windows.
Focus your search on those kinds of places.
Got it.
So we need to search all the lockers
and drawers in this building.
That's right.
I'll call you if we find her.
Episode Preview
Kisaki-sensei, are you listening?
You got a message from Kisaki-sensei.
What? No way.
Let's see.
Kisaki Eri
I can't call you.
The crab's only half-boiled,
but as a result, the two
swordfish look delicious...
Since it's light out tonight,
why don't we eat outside?
"The crab's only half-boiled, but as a
result, the two swordfish look delicious."
"Since it's light out tonight,
why don't we eat outside?"
Even if her daughter gets here,
we'll just capture her and skin
her along with her mother.
Counselor Kisaki's SOS
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is
"Counselor Kisaki's SOS, Part Two!"
Crab and Swordfish
Next Conan's hint!
Crab and swordfish!
Don't miss the next episode.
I'm done for!
Conan-kun's acting suspicious, too.
This is all kinds of bad.