Ran's mother and lawyer Kisaki
Eri-sensei was kidnapped.
However, Kisaki-sensei escaped from her
captors, hid in the abandoned building,
and used the phone she stole from
the kidnappers to ask Ran for help.
Kisaki Eri
Add
Huh?
Kisaki Eri
See you later.
See you later (Read)
Today
Kisaki Eri I've been captured by some bad
people. Could you call the police?
"I've been captured by some bad people."
"Could you call the police?"
What?!
Is that true? (Read)
"Is that true?"
She responded.
Kisaki Eri
Yes, but I don't know where I am.
Kuriyama-san's still at the office.
I'm worried about her...
She says she doesn't know where she is.
Damn!
Sounds like she was
kidnapped from her office.
Huh?
Kisaki Eri
Just kidding! I'm joking!
Don't take it seriously.
It was just a joke?
Jeez, Mom.
But wait...
Look.
Kisaki Eri
That message was from an impostor!
They're using my phone to send messages!
The icons are different.
They're probably not the
same Eri-san you just added.
Hold on.
If the person using Eri's
usual icon is an impostor...
And the one without an
icon is the real Mom...
Damn.
Now we don't know which messages
are coming from the real Eri.
We do.
Huh?
Wh-What?
You can tell, Conan-kun?
Kisaki-sensei is a lawyer, right?
Y-Yeah...
Shinichi-niichan told me
lawyers use Western commas
Japanese Comma
Western Comma
instead of Japanese commas in their
documents when writing horizontally.
That habit shows up in
their normal writing, too.
You're right.
The messages I received from Mom
before all have Western commas.
Using what few hints we could gather
from our exchanges with Kisaki-sensei,
we headed out to rescue her, but...
Which means it's likely
she's hiding in a closed space where
she can't see out any windows.
Focus your search on those kinds of places.
Got it.
So we need to search all the lockers
and drawers in this building.
That's right.
I'll call you if we find her.
Feel that bright morning sunlight!
Saturday is when the love and cases start!
Her life depends on a game of hide-and-seek!
Hurry, old man! Get there in time, Ran!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Counselor Kisaki's SOS
(Part Two)
"Counselor Kisaki's SOS, Part Two!"
Huh?
What are you doing, you idiot?
She can't hide in there!
And your stomach's growling.
Huh?
She doesn't seem to be in here.
Let's go.
O-Okay.
I'm lucky I'm hungry.
S-Sojoji Temple?
What are we doing here?
Conan-kun said to come here.
Let me see your phone.
W-Wait, Conan-kun!
Kisaki-sensei, are you listening?
There's going to be another
loud noise shortly.
If you hear the sound, could you tap
your phone with your fingernail again?
You'll know what sound I'm talking
about as soon as you hear it!
About one second.
Based on the speed of sound,
she's about 340 meters from here.
She's somewhere one kilometer from the
church next to the detective agency
and 340 meters from Sojoji Temple.
In other words, Kisaki-sensei's
in either Buroku or Sutan-cho.
Buroku-cho
Sutan-cho
But which is it?
Both districts have abandoned
buildings a kidnapper could use.
I told you,
I'm not hungry!
Liar! Your stomach was growling in that room.
Hey.
Huh?
Take me to that room.
But no one was in there.
It seems the doe we're hunting is hungry.
Seriously?
She really isn't in here.
No, these drawers are still warm.
She was hiding here until recently,
but moved somewhere else.
H-Hey...
If she got out of here, then she must have
seen what's outside the window, right?
If she and her daughter are messaging
each other separately through the app,
she might have told her where we are.
Calm down.
I've already hacked his phone.
As long as she's using it,
we'll know everything she and
her daughter say to each other.
Yeah, but...
Besides,
even if she tells her what
she sees out the window,
we'll know where she's hiding right now.
You're right.
You're always so smart.
I see.
If they can read all our messages...
I'll have to risk it.
Please.
Please figure it out.
Conan-kun, what are you doing?
Sorry.
You got a message from Kisaki-sensei.
What? No way.
"The crab's only half-boiled, but as a
result, the two swordfish look delicious."
"Since it's light out tonight,
why don't we eat outside?"
What is this?
This is no time to be talking about food.
The crab's only half-boiled,
but as a result, the two
swordfish look delicious...
Since it's light out tonight,
why don't we eat outside?
A full moon.
Two swordfish.
And a half-boiled crab.
I see.
So that's how it is.
Wha... Sutan-cho?
Yeah.
Kisaki-sensei is probably
somewhere in Sutan-cho.
Are you sure, Conan-kun?
How do you know that?
I get that Eri's in either
Buroku-cho or Sutan-cho since
they're within the overlapping area
Toto Tower
Church
Detective Agency
of a one kilometer radius circle
around the church next to the office,
and the 340 meter radius circle around here,
but how were you able to
narrow it down to Sutan-cho?
The message Kisaki-sensei just sent us.
Huh?
Let's see.
"The crab's only half-boiled, but as a
result, the two swordfish look delicious."
"Since it's light out tonight,
why don't we eat outside?"
What about this says Sutan-cho?
Crabs are black when they're alive, but
they turn red once they're boiled, right?
Yeah...
So if they're half-boiled,
then they're not very red.
In other words, something that's normally
red that's still partially black.
Something that's normally red...
But still partially black right now?
"Since it's light out tonight" refers
to the full moon out tonight.
And there's only one building that shuts off
half its lights when there's a full moon out.
Th-The Toto Tower!
Now that you mention it, the top
half of its lights are off tonight.
I've heard the Toto Tower shuts
off half its lights on full moons
so the moon can be seen more clearly.
Then what does "the two swordfish
look delicious" mean?
The "delicious" refers to
something that looks pretty,
and the English word for
the animal is swordfish.
Sword refers to a blade or katana.
Since there are two of them, she's telling
you to think of something with two blades.
Something with...
...two blades?
Wasn't there a really strong
samurai who used two swords?
The two-sword fighter Miyamoto Musashi!
That's right.
And what building is related to Musashi?
Speaking of Musashi,
the Bell Tree Tower is 634 meters tall,
which spells Mu (6) sa (3) shi (4), right?
Yeah. If she's able to see the Bell Tree Tower
clearly because the Toto Tower is darkened,
then Kisaki-sensei must be someplace
she can see the Bell Tree Tower
Bell Tree Tower
Toto Tower
Buroku-cho
Sutan-cho
behind the Toto Tower, or
somewhere in Sutan-cho.
Hey, this can't be good!
After that lawyer sent some nonsensical
message about crabs and swordfish to her daughter,
she keeps getting closer,
even though I'm sending her
false information as the lawyer.
Let me see that.
No, no! I'm not in Sutan-cho!
Kisaki Eri
I'm not sure. When I escaped from
the suitcase, I was already inside.
It's the commas.
The commas?
She was using Western commas
instead of Japanese commas
to help her daughter differentiate
between our messages and hers.
Now that we know that, send her
messages using Western commas.
That should confuse her daughter again.
Got it.
Even if her daughter gets here,
we'll just capture her and skin
her along with her mother.
Hey, what kind of building did Eri say it is?
No way!
The guys who kidnapped Mom started
using Western commas in their messages.
What?
"I'm not sure."
"When I escaped from the suitcase,
I was already inside."
"Based on the walls, I think it's
a reinforced concrete building."
"Don't be fooled!"
"The walls are wood, so it
could be a wooden building."
Reinforced concrete? Wood?
Which is it?
This isn't good.
They noticed I was using Western commas.
Then how about this?
She responded.
"The first floor is a garage."
"I think it has some yellowish
warm mouse-gray shutters."
"There aren't any gray shutters!"
"It was a wooden door!"
Damn! Now we don't know if there
are shutters or a wooden door.
No, it's the mouse-gray shutters.
What? How do you know?
Because Mom told me before
that things with animal names seem warmer.
Anyway, which gloves do you prefer?
Well, I guess I'd choose the black ones.
Oh, I prefer the gray ones.
Really?
Because they're mouse-gray.
Don't things seem warmer
when they have animal names?
Yellowish mouse-gray shutters...
I-It's this abandoned building!
That's...
Ran! Honey!
I'm up here!
Eri!
Mom!
We're on our way!
I finally caught you,
you tricky little lawyer.
We wanted to film you apologizing to us
naked, but it looks like the police are coming.
So we'll settle for knocking
you out, stripping you naked,
and uploading a dirty
video of you to the web.
You idiot.
The only person in this world who's
allowed to see Eri naked is me!
Damn!
Osoto!
Into...
triangle choke!
Honey, are you all right?
Yeah. Anyway, who is this guy?
An abusive husband whose wife divorced him.
In order to get revenge
for losing to me in court,
he gathered a group of other husbands
who lost to me to kidnap me,
so they could film a video of me apologizing.
I see.
Anyway, where are the other two?
Huh?
The skinny gambler and the fat cheater.
They should still be somewhere
inside this building.
Oh, in that case...
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
Wh-What's going on?
Hey, wait!
Get out of the way!
I-I won a kendo tournament once!
R-Ran-neechan, are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm more worried about Mom.
Actually... I'm more worried about these two.
Although...
She won the moment she kicked in the shutter.
By the way, honey...
Huh?
How did you come in through the window?
We're on the fourth floor.
W-Well, you know.
"You know?"
Was there an emergency staircase outside?
Wh-What does it matter?
Don't worry about the details.
That's right.
It's an abandoned building in Sutan-cho.
Please get here immediately,
Detective Takagi.
Now that we've called the
police, this case is solved.
No, there's still one thing
that hasn't been solved.
Huh?
You, Conan-kun.
What? M-Me?
The detective skills you
demonstrated to get us here.
It's hard to think that was the
work of a grade school student.
Conan-kun, are you...?
Yeah, you're right.
Huh?
It's exactly what you think.
See?
Huh?
What?!
Shinichi-niichan
You heard him.
I was so busy giving instructions to the kid,
I didn't get to eat dinner.
Tell your mom to check who it is
before opening the door for any
clients without appointments.
Later.
Hey, wait. Shinichi!
He was talking to me on
the phone the whole time,
since you and your mom were busy chatting.
I see. You were holding
your phone the whole time.
So that's what it was.
Huh? I thought you noticed.
You really are just Conan-kun.
Right.
Of course.
That was close.
So she did suspect me.
I was right to record my own voice.
Good work, Takagi.
No, thank you, Mori-san.
I'd like to interview you about the case,
so if you could come down to the station...
I can't.
Sorry, but that'll have
to wait until tomorrow.
I've got a dinner and movie
date with my wife after this.
What?
Right?
Yes.
No way. They're interlocking fingers.
Is this what you call a lucky hit?
In that case, uh... I'll call
you later to arrange a time.
Please do.
Thank you.
In that case, enjoy your evening.
Court Detective Kirie Saki
The truth will bloom!
No, I didn't just win the case.
I, Kirie Saki, simply saw the truth.
That's right.
You only ever need... one truth.
She's so cute.
That was great.
The incompetent detective character
wasn't a bad guy either.
Yeah.
What is this?
Huh?
She was giving out objections like candy.
You'd just be making a terrible impression
on the court by pestering them,
and there's no way a lawyer could
suddenly make a witness speak
without permission from the judge.
The scene in which she drunkenly complained
about the case to the bartender
was presented as comical,
but she'd be disciplined for
breaking confidentiality like that.
And how dare she speak
so highhandedly in court?
Wasn't that unduly pretentious?
You're not that different.
Maybe they modeled her character after you.
That can't be.
I'm nothing like her.
Yeah, you're right!
Ryoko-chan's a much better lawyer than you!
Why does it always turn out this way?
Come to think of it,
Kirie Saki is an anagram of Kisaki Eri...
Kisaki Eri
Kirie Saki
Episode Preview
Why do I have to apologize?!
Don't play dumb! You know exactly why!
Nichiuri Sports Reporter
Kagatsume Hiroshi
Hashizume Akira
Two Nichiuri Sports reporters famous
for their articles on scandals.
And that...
turned out the worst way possible.
Was it suicide?
That's what we thought at first, but...
Footprints?
Birds of a Feather at Loggerheads
The next episode of Conan is "Birds
of a Feather at Loggerheads!"
Tumbler
Next Conan's hint!
A tumbler!
Don't miss the next episode.
I'm Kirie Saki.
I'm Rira Unmo.
Then I'm Morogou Rikou!
Rikou (smart), huh?