Don't be ridiculous!
Hashizume Akira (38)
Nichiuri Sports Reporter
Why do I have to apologize?!
Kagazume Hiroshi (38)
Nichiuri Sports Reporter
Don't play dumb!
You know exactly why!
I was just doing my job!
Don't act so self-righteous!
You arrogant bastard!
What was that?!
What?!
E-Excuse me, but could you
keep your voices down,
Nichiuri Sports Newspaper Company
Newsroom Department Two
Kagazume Hiroshi
Hashizume-sama and Kagazume-sama?
Nichiuri Sports Newspaper Company
Newsroom Department Two
Hashizume Akira
I'm Hashizume!
I'm Kagazume!
I'm terribly sorry!
They're at it again.
Kuwana Kimiko (36)
Nichiuri Sports Reporter
I wish they'd stop.
I'm sick of it.
Hosoda Shingo (28)
Nichiuri Sports Reporter
It started a year ago.
They're making it hard for me to do my job.
What a nuisance.
It was their fault it nearly
turned into a murder.
When the countdown reaches zero, use your
detective skills to produce an answer!
They're so alike, but they get along terribly!
Their case is full of complex mysteries!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Birds of a Feather at Loggerheads
"Birds of a Feather at Loggerheads!"
Those guys sure are weird.
Huh?
They seem to hate each other,
but they're identical in every way.
You sure?
Shut up already!
You're right. Even their names...
Hashizume-san and Kagazume-san.
Tsume and tsume.
Maybe they don't like that.
Well, birds of a feather either
love or hate each other.
This is the last time!
You'd better not regret it!
Enough already, you hypocrite!
Huh?
Hey.
This is his, right?
Thank you.
Didn't he take the wrong one?
Y-Yeah...
I'll switch with him later.
Mori Detective Agency
I see.
Nichiuri Sports
Archive
Major company executive dead!
Yamakado Yuzo (76), president of major Japanese company
Yamakado Corporation, has died of cholangioma.
As his surviving family fights over the inheritance,
the whereabouts of Yamakado's will...
So this is the case they were referring to.
Yeah.
After the president of a major
company died, his will disappeared.
I remember now.
Weekly magazines were full
of stories about the family
accusing each other of stealing it.
That was these two.
Nichiuri Sports Reporter
Kagazume Hiroshi
Hashizume Akira
Two Nichiuri Sports reporters famous
for their articles on scandals.
They even made comments on TV.
And exacerbated the situation.
They even wrote scandalous articles
about the arguing family members.
Ultimately, the family members clashed,
resulting in an attempted murder.
I heard they garnered a lot of
criticism, and magazine sales fell.
And they're still suffering the consequences.
And that...
turned out the worst way possible.
We've identified the victim.
Nichiuri Sports Newspaper Company
Newsroom Department Two
Kagazume Hiroshi
Kagazume Hiroshi-san, thirty-eight years old.
He was a reporter for
Nichiuri Sports magazine.
The time of death is between 7PM and 9PM.
How did he die?
We're still waiting for the autopsy,
but judging by the body's condition,
we believe it was cyanide poisoning.
It's likely it was dissolved into
the coffee in his travel mug.
Was it suicide?
That's what we thought at first, but...
Footprints?
Yes.
They're not the victim's,
and they're fairly fresh.
In other words, it's possible someone
else was here around the time of death.
Hashizume Akira-san.
Like the late Kagazume Hiroshi-san,
you're a reporter at
Nichiuri Sports, correct?
Yeah.
Anyway, why am I being arrested?
You're not under arrest.
We just want to speak with you
as a material witness for now.
Kagazume and I got along like cats and dogs.
We always fought. It was a huge nuisance.
I'm sure my coworkers have
already told you that.
So I definitely had a motive to kill him.
But you didn't?
Of course not!
Then why were your fingerprints found
Travel Mug Fingerprint Results
Name: Hashizume Akira
on the travel mug at the crime scene?
Our travel mugs were identical.
I've accidentally touched it before.
It must've happened then.
Accidentally, you say?
We'll be confirming that.
Mori Detective Agency
Hey, kid.
You're sure Hashizume-san took
the wrong travel mug, right?
Yeah, but...
What is it, Conan-kun?
It may have been my imagination,
but it seemed like Hashizume-san
deliberately took Kagazume-san's travel mug.
What?!
Is that true?
Then if he deliberately
left his own poisoned mug,
and Kagazume-san drank
from it without knowing...
Yeah, it's murder.
But later...
Kagazume-san listened to what I said.
He knew it wasn't his.
But...
You're right. That is weird.
We can ask Hashizume about it.
Well, actually...
What?
You have an alibi?
Yeah. It was yesterday
night from 7 to 9, right?
I was...
He was staking out a celebrity's affair.
Is there proof?
Yes.
Cheetah Delivery
Refrigerated
He remembered the company name
and appearance of the deliveryman
who arrived during that time.
We confirmed his story
with the delivery company.
It would've been impossible for
Hashizume-san to make it to the crime scene.
Mori-san, delivery.
Coming.
Cheetah Delivery
Hello.
I have a package for you.
I'm here at the time you specified.
Okay.
Could it be?
This is it.
Hashizume-san claims he was here,
watching that apartment
building from 6PM to 7AM.
Conan-kun, did Mori-san really ask
you to investigate this place?
Hey, look.
What's this?
This is probably from a camera tripod.
Hello?
Yes, thanks for taking my call earlier.
What?
So the old man was right.
Yeah.
The delivery Hashizume-san saw
had a specified delivery time.
Not only that, but the address was unknown,
and the sender's name on
the voucher was made up.
Did Hashizume-san send it?
Yeah.
He filmed the delivery using an
unmanned camera on a tripod.
During that time, he went to the crime scene.
Later he checked the video
so he'd have an alibi.
Which means it was premeditated murder.
We found the evidence to support
it in a surprising location.
On the flash drive plugged
into the victim's laptop.
On it we found a plan to murder...
Murder Plan
By Kagazume Hiroshi
...you, Hashizume-san.
The method and alibi trick in it
is exactly as we just described.
Switch out travel mugs and return poisoned mug to Hashizume.
Exchange mug for my own. Reconcile with a toast. Send him to hell.
Alibi fabrication: Claim I was staking out a
celebrity's affair at an expensive apartment building
in the city between 18:00 and 7:00. To support claim,
set up tripod in plants across from apartment
building and arrange for delivery at specified time.
Film delivery with unmanned camera and head
to crime scene during that time to...
According to the plan,
he meant to "switch out travel mugs and
return poisoned mug to Hashizume."
"Exchange mug for my own.
Reconcile with a toast. Send him to hell."
Later, "claim Hashizume was stressed
about lack of progress at work,
suggesting suicide,
and write obituary about the
loss of a rival and friend."
He was quite the particular criminal.
Or maybe it was conceit.
Indeed.
What is it? Something's not right.
You either accidentally took or
stole the victim's flash drive,
and read its contents.
You learned of his plan to
kill you and became enraged,
and decided to murder him
using the same method.
N-No.
You pretended to accidentally
take the victim's travel mug home
and poisoned it.
No!
You invited the victim out
so you could return it
and exchanged mugs with him.
You made him think you reconciled
and made him drink it.
No, no, no!
Wh-What?!
Huh?
Murder Plan
By Hashizume Akira
Wh-What is this?
I-Inspector!
It's the murder plan we found
on the flash drive we
seized from Hashizume-san.
His target is the victim Kagazume-san.
What?
Both plans were written
at nearly the same time.
There are also no signs the
documents were unlocked and read.
Which means?
Unbelievably enough, they
coincidentally created the same plan
Murder Plan
By Hashizume Akira
to murder the other.
Because they're so alike, huh?
But still...
That's right.
I tried to kill Kagazume
according to the plan.
I fabricated an alibi,
poisoned the travel mug,
invited Kagazume out, and went to meet him.
I'm sure of it.
But...
But when I went...
Kagazume was already dead.
What?
He was dead when you got there?
That's absurd.
It's too convenient!
You're right.
But it's true.
I ran, washed the mug, and threw it away.
Quit playing dumb.
Who else could have killed him?
Those two...
Mori-san thinks they're suspicious?
No.
He just wants to know if they have alibis.
We looked into it, but it's unclear.
Hosoda-san was out gathering
information alone.
Kuwana-san was working late
in the office by herself.
Neither had anyone to confirm their stories.
Oh, really?
The old man asked me to do one other thing.
Huh?
Re-examine the crime scene?
Is there something bothering Mori-san?
Can you show me the crime scene photos?
Huh?
Yeah, here.
What's this?
It's coffee.
We think some coffee spilled
from his mug when he collapsed.
We found the same cyanide in
it, so we're fairly certain.
Then shouldn't it be on his pants, too?
Based on the length of his pants,
isn't it strange to only be on his socks?
Now that you mention it...
It certainly is odd.
How did the victim Kagazume-san get here?
By car.
He parked on the embankment
and walked here.
Did you search the inside of the car?
Yeah, but we didn't find anything suspicious.
Search it again.
Chiba? This is Mori.
There's something I want you to look into.
Is it true, Mori-kun?
That you've uncovered the
truth behind the case.
What?
I came here because you said
you found new evidence to—
Mister!
Are you okay?
Stand back, Conan.
Okay!
Excuse me.
Allow me to explain the
truth behind the case.
First, Detective Takagi, what did
you find in Kagazume-san's car?
Right.
On the floor of the driver's seat,
we found traces of cyanide.
What?
That can only mean one thing:
Kagazume-san put cyanide in
his own mug inside his car.
And while doing that, he
spilled a bit of coffee.
Sitting in the driver's seat caused the hem
of his pants to ride up, exposing his socks.
It's possible it splashed onto it then.
Doesn't that mean they tried to
kill each other at the same time?
They both had plans to murder the other.
Kagazume-san meant to
murder Hashizume-san
by returning a poisoned travel mug,
but he drank the coffee in the
poisoned mug he took first.
No.
Kagazume-san drank from Hashizume-san's
tumbler he had initially.
As Hashizume-san claimed, they
never exchanged mugs here.
How do you know that?
The fingerprints.
Fingerprints?
But it was originally Hashizume-san's mug.
It's not strange for Kagazume-san's
or his own fingerprints to be on it.
Yes, but I'm not talking
about their fingerprints.
It's Conan's fingerprints.
What?
Um...
I actually touched the mug.
I barely touched it,
so I'm not sure I left a print,
but it could serve as evidence.
So?
What does this mean?
In other words,
Kagazume-san drank from the
mug he poisoned himself.
Wh-What? Could it be?
N-No way...
But why?
This is why.
Will and Testament
At Mori-san's instructions, we found this on
another one of Kagazume-san's flash drives.
It was never revealed publicly
in last year's case.
It describes the death of a
major company's president.
The disappearance of a will that
exacerbated an inheritance dispute.
Scoop!!
Will disappeared?!
The Surviving Family's Darkness!!
How Hashizume-san and
Kagazume-san worked together then
to break into the law office and steal it.
Kagazume's USB data
Will and Testament
And this is his written confession.
What?
They wrote articles
mocking the people they enraged.
But after the attempted murder,
they destroyed the will and
never spoke of it again.
However, wracked with guilt,
Kagazume-san suggested to Hashizume-san
that they reveal the truth.
But...
...Hashizume-san rejected the idea.
What we saw in the restaurant
was part of that discussion.
Rejecting the idea and fearing
the truth would come to light,
Hashizume-san plotted to kill Kagazume-san,
without realizing Kagazume-san
had made his own plans
to kill Hashizume-san.
Hashizume-san and Kagazume-san.
The murderous intent you felt
due to your similarities grew
over years of working together,
eventually becoming murder plots.
But you were different in one way.
At the very end,
Kagazume-san changed his.
This is the last time!
You'd better not regret it!
Enough already, you hypocrite!
Kagazume-san realized you
deliberately took his mug,
and realized you'd come
up with the same plan.
We found signs that some of
Kagazume-san's data had been erased,
so we restored it.
After Hashizume-san's
death was ruled a suicide,
he wrote that he would also kill himself.
What?
He changed his plan
to make the remorseless
Hashizume-san suffer.
And there's one more thing.
Yes.
According to his physician, Kagazume-san was
sick and had not much time left to live.
What?
After judging himself guilty,
he plotted to frame Hashizume-san
for his own murder.
He may have been going for a double suicide,
since you're so similar.
He should've minded his own business.
It was a huge scoop!
We did whatever it took to expose the
unsightly darkness within people!
We brought lots of things to light!
He should've thanked me!
Don't be absurd!
You call yourself a reporter?
What did you gain from writing this article?
Money? Fame?
Think about it.
Did your article make a single person happy?!
I wish Kagazume-san had
been judged by the law,
and atoned for his crime instead.
That same day, Hashizume-san was arrested
for the attempted murder
of Kagazume-san
and stealing the will one year earlier.
Mori Detective Agency
Dad?
You must be tired. What
do you want for dinner?
Western or Japanese?
Depends on what I drink.
After beer, will I have
wine, cold sake, or shochu?
Or will I have whiskey?
They're all liquor.
They're all the same.
Listen, kid,
wine and sake have their
own uniqueness and flavor.
And shochu has its own unique...
I'm too young to know what
you're talking about.
Episode Preview
Yeah.
They're both probably dead.
It's my fault.
The sweater he was wearing was
from a pretty high-end brand.
If he was strapped for cash,
he couldn't have bought that.
I thought I'd give you an
accurate version of the events.
Result of the Draw
The next episode of Conan
is "Result of the Draw!"
Potted Plant
Next Conan's hint!
A potted plant!
Their names and faces are so similar.
Don't miss the next episode.
So names and natures often agree.
But your detective skills are weak.