There.
Hey.
Genta-kun, you're supposed
to kick it into the goal.
Sorry. I'll go get it.
Are you okay?
I can't keep going...
Huh? Is no one home?
Professor, you're a mess.
We're going to resume playing
as soon as Genta-kun comes back.
Don't you think he's taking
a while to get the ball?
He's probably having trouble finding it.
That voice...
Was that Genta-kun?!
Genta, you okay?
What happened?
Th-That...
This is...
Is he...
Hey!
Boys.
Oh, good. You're all right.
Hold on.
Professor, call an ambulance.
Someone inside has collapsed.
What?
I don't think anyone's there.
I rang the doorbell earlier.
Then we'll have to break a window.
What's all this noise?
What?
Wait, son.
Son.
What?!
Well?
Professor, call the police, not an ambulance.
Y-You mean...
Yeah.
They're both probably dead.
Both?
When the countdown reaches zero, use your
detective skills to produce an answer!
The police are called to
a wealthy man's study!
What happened to the two collapsed figures?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Result of the Draw
"Result of the Draw!"
There are two victims.
The large man is Kawai Shinzo-san,
the resident of this home.
Kawai Shinzo (55)
Real Estate
Company President
He was stabbed in the stomach,
but the cause of death is blood loss
from the ice pick in his chest.
The weapon was an object kept in this room.
The smaller man on the floor
is Shibata Kensuke-san.
His cause of death is a head injury.
Shibata Kensuke (38)
Former Real Estate
Company Employee
There's not much blood,
but he most likely struck his
head on the armrest of the sofa.
Also, the blood on Shibata-san's
sweater matched Kawai-san's.
The blood must've gotten on
him when he stabbed him.
When did they die?
About two hours ago.
The bodies were discovered
about an hour ago.
I see.
And they're the ones who found the body.
Also, they're the president and former
employee of a real estate company.
Several months ago,
Shibata-san was fired for
embezzling company funds.
Money troubles, huh?
Who is she?
Kawai-san's wife Yuko-san.
She was sleeping in the second floor
bedroom when the incident occurred.
Kawai Yuko (48)
Shinzo's Wife
Sleeping?
This room shows signs of a struggle.
It must've made a lot of noise.
Yes. I asked her about that.
She said she'd been looking
after her mother all morning,
and was too exhausted to notice.
The bedroom's far away from this room.
Ma'am, I'm sorry to question
you when your husband's dead.
Yes?
Had your husband arranged
to meet Shibata-san here?
Yes. Today was his repayment date.
Repayment date?
Shibata-san was using the
money he embezzled
to pay for his sick family's hospital bills.
My husband agreed to rehire him
if he returned the money by today.
I see. So that's why Shibata-san came.
By the way, do you know how much he owed?
I believe it was about a million yen.
Conan-kun, you can't just
enter the crime scene.
Oh, sorry.
Unbelievable.
Oh? You have a foot injury.
Oh, this?
I sprained it the other day.
You went to care for your
mother with an injury?
That must've been difficult.
My mother's in far worse shape than I am.
This is nothing.
She seems tired.
Maybe she's not getting much sleep.
Her foot's injured, and her husband's dead.
I feel bad for her.
Caring for her mother must be hard.
If I'd been awake...
If I'd noticed something was wrong, this
wouldn't have happened to my husband.
It's my fault.
By the way, you weren't answering the
door even though we kept calling.
Did the sound of the intercom wake you?
No, that large boy's scream woke me.
Large boy?
The biggest boy.
Oh, Genta.
And the intercom's not working right now.
It doesn't always work.
Sorry.
Um, Conan-kun?
Let's step outside.
Let's go, Conan-kun.
Shibata didn't embezzle the
money to pay for hospital bills.
How do you know that?
The sweater he was wearing was
from a pretty high-end brand.
If he was strapped for cash,
he couldn't have bought that.
Really? It didn't look expensive to me.
You don't know much about
fashion, Mr. Detective.
Sorry about that.
This bag was on the sofa.
There was money inside.
She said he owed a million yen.
That looks like the right amount.
So he raised the money.
In that case, why did they get into a fight?
Hello?
I see.
Yeah, got it.
What is it?
According to the employees
of Kawai Real Estate,
Kawai-san said he didn't
intend to rehire Shibata-san.
It was just an excuse to
make him return the money.
So he failed to fulfill his promise
after the money was returned.
If that was the reason,
then Shibata-san became hostile,
grabbed a weapon from the desk...
...and murdered Shinzo-san.
Looks like she wasn't lying
about the intercom not working.
Yeah.
There you are.
Let's go back to the park and keep playing.
Genta-kun, make sure you
aim for the goal this time.
I know!
Well? What do you think?
About what?
The case.
At first glance,
it seems like one man was stabbed
and immediately pushed the other.
The other suffered fatal injuries
and died.
Doesn't that explain it?
Well, yeah.
You don't sound like you believe it.
What, then? Did you notice anything strange?
No, not really.
Like you said, I think that's
probably what happened.
Then why not let the police handle the rest?
Conan-kun!
Let's go!
Genta-kun, do you have a cold?
No. I think I hurt my throat
when I screamed earlier.
I was so surprised.
We suddenly heard a weird voice.
Was my scream that weird?
Based on the direction it came from,
we knew immediately that it was you.
The direction of the scream?
Based on the circumstances, it
could only have been Genta...
Wait a minute.
Sorry. You guys go on without me.
What? Why?
The professor has something
he hasn't told the police.
Right, Professor?
What? I don't remember saying that...
Uh...
Oh, that's right.
I completely forgot to tell them that.
Come on. Let's go.
What is it, Shinichi?
Is there something bothering you?
Yeah. I don't think this case
is as simple as we think.
Really?
You saved me, though.
Now I don't have to exercise in the park.
Seriously?
So we should assume Shibata-san
was pushed forcefully
and fell, and not that he
slipped and hit his head.
The room's windows and the
front door were locked.
It seems unlikely that they
were killed by an outsider.
Were you able to confirm what the wife said?
Yes. She's telling the truth about her
foot injury and caring for her mother.
I see.
Even if she was awake,
it's hard to imagine an injured
woman could have pushed Shibata-san.
He might be right.
But what is it?
Something's bothering me.
Shinichi, how'd you hurt your hand?
Huh?
Oh, I probably hit the door
too hard when we came here.
Inspector, we found this button
in a potted plant on the shelf.
It's Shibata-san's.
I see.
His button must have flown
off during their tussle.
The sweater he was wearing was
from a pretty high-end brand.
The biggest boy.
H-Hey, Conan-kun!
Oh, sorry. I dropped something.
But it's not here.
Come on.
You can't just enter a crime scene.
Do something about him.
This isn't a playground.
Sorry...
There you go again.
I can't help it.
Anyway, that was a bold move.
I nearly missed it.
What do you mean?
I finally figured out the truth
about this case that was
hidden behind the veil.
They're so late.
Inspector, can we safely assume
they killed each other after getting
into a fight over money troubles?
I think so.
Yuko-san,
we'd like to ask you more questions
about their relationship and the case.
Could you come with us to the station?
Yes.
Hold on.
Agasa-san, what is it?
I thought I'd give you an
accurate version of the events.
What? But we just investigated
the case and concluded that—
Don't you realize there's no way
Shibata-san could have killed Kawai-san?
Couldn't have killed him?
What do you mean?
It should be obvious when you consider
the difference in their height.
Difference in height?
Kawai-san was 185 centimeters.
Shibata-san was 160 centimeters.
They do have contrasting builds.
That's it.
If the smaller Shibata-san
tried to stab the much taller
Kawai-san in the chest,
he would use a reverse grip.
Wouldn't the blood end
up on his pinkie finger?
There are other things that don't make sense.
Like what?
Like Shibata-san's button.
Conan-kun told me
he saw that Shibata-san's third button was
missing when he looked under his sweater.
Even if the button came off in the struggle,
it's hard to believe an unexposed button
could have ended up inside
the pot on the shelf.
Y-You're right.
And there's one more thing.
Yuko-san, you were in this room
until we arrived, weren't you?
No. I was in the second floor bedroom.
Then how did you know it
was Genta-kun who screamed?
The second floor doesn't have
windows facing the yard.
You couldn't have known which child
screamed just from the sound.
But you knew.
That's because you were watching Genta-kun
from this room when he screamed.
It's the only explanation.
Am I wrong?
I...
The ice pick and the blood on his hand.
The button in the potted plant.
And at the time, this house was locked.
When you put it all together, the only
person who could have killed Shinzo-san
was the person who was inside
the house at the time.
It's you, Yuko-san.
What?
But how did she stab him?
She's not very tall, and her foot's injured.
What if Kawai-san had been stabbed
in the stomach by Shibata-san
and was sitting in a chair?
A woman with a foot injury could
stab a badly injured victim.
Then it could have been Shibata-san
who stabbed my seated husband, not me.
That doesn't explain how
Shibata-san fell and died.
It's hard to imagine he pushed him
hard enough to kill him
from a seated position.
Shibata-san was most likely dead
when you looked in the room.
I don't know what happened
between you two then,
but you decided to kill
him, grabbed the ice pick,
and finished off your
gravely wounded husband.
Am I wrong?
You're making it all up!
I knew about the scream
because I overhead Genta
telling the police about it!
There's no proof I did it.
Stop acting like I did.
It's the button.
The button?
What does that prove?
Are you saying I picked it
up and put it in the pot?
No, the button flew into the
pot while they were fighting.
But you panicked and didn't
notice it had fallen off.
I didn't notice?
What are you talking about?
Hold on.
If the button came off
while they were fighting,
how did it get into the pot?
The answer's simple.
Shibata-san wasn't wearing a sweater.
Yuko-san, the sweater he was wearing
belongs to you, doesn't it?
What do you mean?
Not knowing what to do
with your bloody clothes,
you realized Shibata-san was
about the same height as you.
To make it look like he'd done
it, you put your clothes on him.
Fortunately, it was a color
that a man might wear.
It may have been missed if they were
assumed to have killed each other,
but a quick investigation should reveal
if you were wearing the sweater.
Kawai Yuko-san, can we ask
you again what happened?
It was what he said.
Darling!
Shibata thought he'd be
able to return to work
if he apologized and returned the money.
What?
But isn't that what you promised?
His family in the hospital died.
Shibata and his family got
what was coming to them.
That's awful!
Don't just stand there!
Call an ambulance!
You said you'd handle it!
You told me not to worry!
Shut up!
This happened because you
took sympathy on that trash!
Both of you are wasting money
on helping useless old people!
What?
What are you doing?
I'd put up with my arrogant
husband for so long.
But his callous words
brought me to my senses.
I even tried to frame Shibata-san.
Conan, you're late!
Sorry.
We only got to play a little soccer
to help the professor lose weight.
It's too bad.
I know.
Next time let's start in the
morning, for the professor's sake.
But I'm fine.
Yay, I'm so excited.
Right, Professor?
But I'm not...
That's great.
Now you'll lose weight soon.
I should help by restricting
your portion sizes.
You've got the wrong idea.
Good luck, Professor.
Episode Preview
What? No way!
A celebrity?!
What's that symbol?
Oh, this?
Masked Comet
Byun
It's the symbol of Masked Comet Byun.
It was...
pretty cool.
No!
Eyewitness Testimony Seven Years Later
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "Eyewitness
Testimony Seven Years Later, Part One!"
Comedy Duo
Next Conan's hint!
A comedy duo!
I wish I could diet by limiting my portions!
Don't miss the next episode.
Okay, now you're fasting.
I guess I am.