Seven Years Ago – Haido City
Hop, hop, hop.
When the countdown reaches zero, use your
detective skills to produce an answer!
The memory of a masked TV
hero controls a girl's time.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Eyewitness Testimony Seven Years Later
(Part One)
"Eyewitness Testimony Seven
Years Later, Part One!"
Nishiokuho Station
I can't believe we're spending the
weekend in such a wonderful place.
Sometimes you have some chic ideas, Dad.
What's that?
Nishiokuho
Guest House Hatobue Lodge
Have a luxurious time! Forget the hustle and bustle
of the city at this guest house
Owner
Yuri Asako-san
Ohara Shinsuke-san
This is an article about the boarding
house we're staying at today...
Loved by the Prince of Beer!
Favorite spot of Minakitaya Otaro-san, the
Prince of Beer. "The place has the best beer!"
Apparently the boarding house
has a wide variety of beers.
I see. So that's what Dad's after.
I'm going to drink, drink, drink!
Who's the Prince of Beer?
Ah, Minakitaya Otaro-san.
He's an entertainer who recently became
popular for hosting variety shows.
His knowledge of beer that he displays on
blogs and talk shows is supposed to be amazing.
So that makes him the Prince of Beer.
He used to be part of the comedy
duo Minakitaya Otaro and Kyujiro.
But his partner Kyujiro
committed an act of violence.
Their duo was dissolved.
That was three years ago, I believe.
Ide Masanari (28)
Web Designer
Hello. The name's Ide.
Are you Mori Kogoro-san?
Indeed. I am the great detective Mori Kogoro.
I'm so excited to meet someone so famous.
My name's Fujiyoshi.
Fujiyoshi Hiroko (35)
Stationery Company Employee
Are you headed to the Hatobue Lodge, too?
Yeah. Are you?
Yes.
Minakitaya Otaro
The Prince of Beer's
Good Day for a Drink
How could I not after the Prince
of Beer spoke so highly of it?
Sorry I'm late.
I'm Ohara of the Hatobue Lodge.
Ohara Shinsuke (29)
Hatobue Lodge Employee
You must be Mori-sama,
Fujiyoshi-sama, Ide-sama.
You must be Shirogane-sama.
Shirogane Toru (54)
Local Magazine Writer
Yes.
In that case, I'll take you
to the lodge. Get in, please.
It's about twenty minutes
to the boarding house.
We should arrive before 2:30.
Hatobue Lodge
Please leave.
We have nothing to discuss.
But...
Thank you for coming.
I'm Yuri Asako, owner of the Hatobue Lodge.
Yuri Asako (39)
Hatobue Lodge Owner
This is my daughter Miona.
Yuri Miona (12)
Asako's Daughter
Welcome.
You must be exhausted.
Have a seat.
Were these taken around here?
Yes. The scenery around here is beautiful.
I recommend you go for a walk before dinner.
What are these?
They're cow magnets.
Cows sometimes swallow nails
or bits of metal in addition to grass.
It's dangerous to leave
them inside their bodies,
so we feed them powerful magnets
to grab the pieces of
metal in their stomachs.
And that's called a cow magnet.
Huh...
The guests staying here last
night stuck bottle caps to them.
But there's an even more fun
thing you can do with them.
You take turns sticking
these onto the magnet.
And then...
Whoever makes the chain collapse loses.
Those weren't here last time I came.
Otaro-san, you're early.
Minakitaya Otaro (29)
Entertainer
What?! No way!
The Prince of Beer?!
I-I'm a huge fan!
Could I get your autograph?
Sure.
Gladly.
Here.
Thank you!
I got his autograph.
Minakitaya Otaro
Here.
Otaro-san, have some tea.
Thank you, Asako-san.
Do you come here often?
Yeah. This place has a
huge selection of beers.
Enjoying your favorite beers in a quiet place
with clean air is the ultimate luxury.
I come once a month.
What's that symbol?
Oh, this?
Masked Comet
Byun
It's the symbol of Masked Comet Byun.
The TV hero?
The show aired seven years ago.
It's about a hero who fights to protect the
Earth from the Hell Comet's Demon King Dyark
and his quest for world domination.
Byun himself was once a
henchman of the Hell Comet,
but he's touched by the
kindness of an Earthling girl,
reforms his ways, and becomes
the defender of the Earth.
Oh, I remember now.
But wasn't the show canceled?
Yeah, just when the story
was reaching its climax.
Of course it was canceled.
Its ratings were terrible.
Ratings have nothing to do
with the quality of the show.
It was pretty cool.
Miona!
Calm down. Deep breaths.
Is everything all right?
Sorry about that.
Oh, right.
We should start getting dinner ready.
Dinner starts at six.
You're free to do what you want until then.
Maybe I'll go for a walk.
Care to join me?
Sure. Miona-chan, why don't you come with us?
Okay.
In that case, I'll show you around.
What about you, Dad?
I'll be sleeping in our room until dinner.
I'll pass, too.
I'm going to read my book.
I need to call my manager,
so I'll join you another time.
Too bad.
Then the four of us will go.
Okay.
Robbery and Murder In Haido City
With culprits still at large,
investigation makes slow progress
Did you drop this, Shirogane-san?
Thanks, kid.
You're welcome.
Wow!
Otaro-san bought a new car.
First he bought a light truck, then a sedan.
I can't believe he has three cars.
Famous people really do
live in a different world.
Muramatsu-san.
Muramatsu Makoto (48)
Nishiokuho Police Inspector
He seems to have drowned after all.
He had nothing identifying on his person.
This is from that incident.
Please enjoy this pre-dinner fruit beer.
Fruit?
In Belgium, they've been making
beer with fruit for ages.
Like cherries and raspberries.
What a pleasant aroma.
Is this citron?
That's right.
This beer lets you enjoy the uniquely
refreshing smell and taste of citron.
Let's toast to our meeting today.
Cheers!
Cheers.
The combination of sweet and
sour flavors is interesting.
Next is a pilsner.
Pilsners are well known in Japan.
They have a good balance of
flavor, bitterness, and aroma.
This is an IPA.
You can't get enough of
this intense bitterness.
This meat is delicious.
Next we have a porter.
The fragrant aroma of roasted malt.
The strong, bitter flavor
of dark roast coffee
compliments the flavor of the meat.
For dessert, enjoy this
slightly unusual beer.
Is this beer?
It's definitely beer.
It's not too bitter and has a crisp flavor.
You're right.
Based on its color, I thought
it'd be sweet like a Blue Hawaii.
This beer is dyed blue with gardenias.
It tastes so different from how it looks.
It's confusing.
I was completely deceived by its appearance.
You lose.
He was here this afternoon.
Excuse me.
The police?
So he's a cop.
Huh? Aren't you the
detective Mori Kogoro-san?
Indeed. I am the great detective.
Muramatsu-san, like I
told you this afternoon,
if you're here about that case...
I'm not here about that.
That case?
Around five this afternoon,
the body of a man was found in a
lake seven kilometers east of here.
What?
We believe he drowned.
We're currently considering
all possibilities,
including accidental death,
suicide, and murder.
The river behind the lodge
is connected to the lake,
so we've been canvassing along the river.
Do you recognize this man?
Oh, that man...
You know him?
Didn't he stay with us about two months ago?
Kitamoto Shujiro
This is him. Kitamoto Shujiro-san.
What?!
What did you say?
Is something wrong?
Huh? Aren't you Minakitaya Otaro-san?
This is Kyujiro.
What?
Your old partner?
Yes. He's changed a lot,
but Kitamoto Shujiro is his real name.
When did you last see him?
Three years ago, when we dissolved our duo.
Rumor is he's an entertainment reporter now.
An entertainment reporter?
Come to think of it, he did ask
a lot of questions about you.
He doesn't have a very good reputation.
They say he'll even engage in criminal
activity to get information.
He's also drowning in debt and has some
aggressive debt collectors after him.
Maybe he was looking to
report a scandal on you.
Kyujiro...
The estimated time of death
is between noon and 1PM today.
Where were you around that time?
I was recording at a studio
in the city until 12:30.
After that, I drove here.
It took about two hours from the city.
Noon to one is when we were on the train.
What about you?
We were getting ready for our guests here.
Yes.
What about the rest of you?
We have nothing to do with this.
We'd just like to know for reference.
I was on the train.
The same train as Mori-san.
I was on the bus.
I took the 12 o'clock bus
from Tatsukawa Station
and arrived at Nishiokuho Station at 1:50.
I took the train an hour earlier
and was walking around the station.
Could you please identify yourselves?
Shirogane Toru. I'm a writer
for a local magazine.
Ide Masanari. I'm a web designer.
Fujiyoshi Hiroko. I'm an office
worker for a stationery company.
Do you recognize this?
Masked Comet Byun!
Was Kyujiro-san interested
in this kind of thing?
I'm not sure.
Miona-chan, are you okay?
Miona!
Miona-chan didn't seem well the last time
the Masked Comet was mentioned either.
It's nothing.
Come to think of it, there was a robbery
and murder in Haido City a long time ago.
A financial company employee was murdered,
and a large amount of money was stolen.
The culprits were wearing Masked Comet Byun
and Demon King Dyark masks.
I think that was seven years ago.
Robbery and Murder In Haido City
What?
Come to think of it, there was a
young girl who witnessed the crime.
A witness?
Miona!
Miona, calm down.
She can lie down in the
guestroom in the back.
Ide-san, why would you do that?
I... uh...
Robbery and Murder In Haido City
Who could it be at this hour?
Fujiyoshi-san?
Nishiokuho Police Station
It's an emergency, Muramatsu-san!
What's wrong?
The water found in the body's
lungs wasn't lake water.
It was ordinary tap water.
What? Which means...
Yes.
If the victim was murdered elsewhere
and brought to the lake
by car to be dumped...
Then Minakitaya Otaro could've done it.
Who would do this?
I was thirsty and came down to get
something to drink when I found this.
Dad.
Otaro-san's not answering.
His door's locked.
What?
What was that?
Otaro-san, are you all right?!
Please respond!
Otaro-san!
Mori-san, here's the spare key.
Thank you.
It's not opening.
Maybe it's bolted shut.
What if he's collapsed inside?
Dad, let me.
Otaro-san!
It's no use. He's dead.
What?
He's still warm.
It hasn't been long since he died.
Looks like the door was locked and bolted.
The window's locked, too.
Mister!
There's blood over here.
What?
That's a bloody fingerprint, isn't it?
Is it Otaro-san's?
There's something drawn over there.
The symbol of the Masked Comet!
Is it a dying message?
So it's murder?
And the Masked Comet did it?
Calm down.
It's possible he was drunk,
fell, and hit his head.
The Masked Comet's here...
What?
I promise I forgot everything...
I forgot...
Miona?
No!
Miona!
Are you okay?
Hang in there, Miona!
Let's get her to her room.
Okay.
Episode Preview
The water found in Kyujiro-san's lungs
was ordinary tap water.
What?!
Could it be?
It matched Otaro-san's fingerprints.
If you're such a great
detective, solve the case!
The door was definitely locked and bolted.
On top of that...
Eyewitness Testimony Seven Years Later
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Eyewitness
Testimony Seven Years Later, Part Two!"
Beer Bottle Cap
Next Conan's hint!
Beer bottle caps!
Don't miss the next episode.
Beer and a locked room.
The culprit vanished like bubbles.
How careless.
Whoa, whoa, whoa...