We came to the Hatobue Lodge
guest house in Nishiokuho.
Minakitaya Otaro (29)
Entertainer
Popular entertainer Minakitaya Otaro-san,
also known as the Prince of
Beer, was staying there as well.
For some reason Miona-chan, daughter
of guest house manager Yuri Asako-san,
Yuri Asako (39)
Hatobue Lodge Owner
Yuri Miona (12)
Asako's Daughter
was afraid of the Masked Comet Byun TV show
that aired seven years ago.
Meanwhile, a man's body was discovered in a
lake seven kilometers east of the guest house.
Minakitaya Kyujiro (31)
Entertainment Reporter
The body was Otaro-san's former
partner Minakitaya Kyujiro-san.
And that night, Otaro-san
was found dead as well...
When the countdown reaches zero, use your
detective skills to produce an answer!
Both members of the former
comedy duo are dead!
What did the Masked Comet do?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Eyewitness Testimony Seven Years Later
(Part Two)
"Eyewitness Testimony Seven
Years Later, Part Two!"
The deceased is Minakitaya Otaro-san,
born Minamida Kotaro-san.
Who was the last one to see Otaro-san?
Muramatsu Makoto (48)
Nishiokuho Police Inspector
Probably me.
Ohara Shinsuke (29)
Hatobue Lodge Employee
Otaro-san came to the dining room as I
was cleaning up before I headed home.
He took beers and a bottle
opener from the room.
Around what time was that?
It was about 11.
Did anyone enter the dining room after that?
I couldn't sleep, so I went down
to the dining room for a beer.
That was around midnight.
How long were you here?
Ide Masanari (28)
Web Designer
Fujiyoshi Hiroko (35)
Stationery Company Employee
I spent about thirty minutes attaching
beer caps to a cow magnet.
Then I went back to my room to sleep.
And Fujiyoshi-san discovered the
dining room in disarray around two.
Ide
drinks beer in dining room
12AM | 1AM | 2AM
Ide attaches beer caps to cow magnet
Fujiyoshi discovers dining
room in disarray
Time of Crime
It must have happened during that hour.
Otaro-san must have died
around the same time.
Yes.
Shirogane-san, what about you?
Shirogane Toru (54)
Local Magazine Writer
I was sleeping in my room.
How about you?
I was sleeping in my room in the
annex next door with my daughter.
I woke up when Ran-san called me.
I was at home and returned
when I received a phone call.
It was an accident.
He got drunk and fell when he
stepped on an empty bottle.
His head struck an empty bottle, and he died.
It's unfortunate that both members
of the former comedy duo
suffered accidental deaths
one after another.
The situation has changed.
What?
The water found in Kyujiro-san's lungs
was ordinary tap water.
What?!
In other words, he was dumped in the
lake after being killed elsewhere?
Yes.
Hold on.
Does that mean Otaro-san could've killed him?
Kyujiro-san was investigating
Otaro-san, wasn't he?
We found this listening
device in Otaro-san's room
with Kyujiro-san's fingerprints on it.
Maybe he discovered a major secret using
that bug and was killed to keep him quiet.
What major secret would that be?
Muramatsu-san, it's an emergency.
What is it?
What's going on?
We've determined the bloody fingerprint
on the table belonged to Otaro-san,
but that fingerprint...
What is it?
In the case seven years ago,
the culprits threw the masks they
were wearing into a ditch and fled.
There was a single fingerprint
they failed to wipe clean.
The culprit's fingerprint?
Could it be?
It matched Otaro-san's fingerprints.
Seriously?
In other words, Otaro-san
was one of the two culprits.
And Kyujiro-san was killed by Otaro-san
because he learned his secret.
Which means we can't simply assume
Otaro-san's death was an accident.
Was the witness in the seven
year old case Miona-chan?
The witness in the seven year
old case was indeed Miona-chan,
who was five years old at the time.
What?
I was assigned to the Haido
City station at the time.
I was involved in the investigation.
Did Miona-chan see the culprits' faces?
It's not clear if she did.
It must have been traumatizing for her.
Her memory is hazy.
Then the reason Otaro-san frequented this
guest house where Miona-chan lived...
He was watching to see if
she'd regain her memory.
What?
Boss!
Thank you.
That's why Miona-chan was afraid of
discussions about the Masked Comet.
That case was the reason Masked
Comet Byun was canceled.
The case did have an impact,
but ratings and merchandise sales
were failing to meet expectations.
They were considering ending the show early.
That case wasn't the only reason.
How do you know so much about it?
I'm actually a scriptwriter,
not a freelance writer.
I was the head writer for Masked Comet Byun.
What?
Really?
Did you know about Miona-chan?
You had a newspaper clipping about the case.
Naturally, Miona-chan's identity
was kept anonymous as the time,
but some heartless people publicly
revealed her name online.
When I visited this town a year ago
to cover a story, I saw Miona-chan.
I was worried about her and
the damage she suffered.
I decided to visit the guest house
since I wasn't busy with work.
Didn't you know, too, Ide-san?
Huh? Well, uh...
Yeah, I knew.
I investigated everything
I could about the case.
Why would you do that?
Because...
The financial company employee
who was murdered was my father.
What?
Ide is my mother's maiden name.
At the time of the case,
I was too busy caring for my
traumatized mother to worry about it.
But when my mother
passed away two years ago,
I suddenly became interested in the case.
I learned about Miona-chan
while doing my research.
So you even got a mask.
I thought she might remember something.
I didn't think it would be
so traumatizing for her.
I'm really sorry!
Come to think of it, there was a key
on the table at the crime scene.
Does anyone know what it was for?
I was wondering about that, too.
When I saw it before, he said it
was a key to the door to happiness.
The door to happiness?
What does that mean?
I seem to be hungry.
The sun's rising.
I'll make something light.
I'm sorry for making you worry.
She seems to have calmed down.
That's great.
I asked Miona-chan yesterday, but you
used to live in Haido City, right?
When did you move here?
We moved to Nishiokuho after the incident.
I thought living in a quiet place would
help heal her psychological wounds.
When did you start working
at this guest house?
Right after we moved.
I used to work as a hotel receptionist.
Excuse me.
There you are.
I made sandwiches.
Let's eat in the other room.
Thank you.
Ohara-san, are you originally from this town?
No. I moved here about four years ago.
After graduating from culinary school,
I saw a want ad for this place.
Really?
Kyujiro-san's hair was
found in Otaro-san's car.
We can leave now, can't we?
Hold on.
Otaro-san's death was an accident, right?
In that case...
No, we can't assume it was yet.
Are you saying it was murder?
There's no one here who would—
It was you, wasn't it?
Wh-What are you talking about?
Didn't he kill your father?
I just learned that!
Maybe Kyujiro-san told you.
Yeah. Maybe you killed Kyujiro-san, too.
That's insane.
When Kyujiro-san was killed,
I was on the same train
as Mori-san's family.
Mori-san, are you certain of that?
Now that you mention it, I
didn't see him on the train.
He spoke to us after we got off.
How can you be so heartless?
See?
The mark drawn in blood was the same
as the one on your shirt, right?
What?
Fujiyoshi-san, calm down.
Wasn't your show canceled
because of the case?
Are you sure you didn't resent him?!
You really shouldn't say that.
If you're such a great
detective, solve the case!
Yeah, but the crime scene was locked...
The door was definitely locked and bolted.
On top of that, the window was locked, too.
Huh?
Seven empty bottles, six bottle caps.
There's one missing.
Where is it?
Huh?
They're shaped differently.
And what's this key for?
What's this key doing here?
It's that blue beer.
I was completely deceived by its appearance.
The key to the door to happiness...
So that's what that means!
Hold on.
Then that means...
Could it be?
I knew it.
That must be it.
The size of the thumbturn,
the position of the bolt...
I'm starting to see the
truth behind this case.
Mori-san, what is the meaning of this?
Everyone.
I will now reveal the truth behind the case.
Really?
Way to go, Detective!
First, Otaro-san did not kill Kyujiro-san.
What?
But his hair was found in his car.
Otaro-san drove a convertible.
Could you transport a body in that?
He even owns a sedan.
You're right.
The hair was a camouflage
planted by the culprit
to frame Otaro-san.
However, driving the convertible he
recently purchased was a miscalculation.
Then that person killed Otaro-san as well?
I know who did it, of course,
and how they created the locked room.
But the window was locked, and the
door was locked and deadbolted.
How did they do it?
Very well. Allow me to demonstrate.
Conan!
Here!
I'll take this bottle opener...
and place it here.
And use this magnet...
The cow magnet.
To fix it in place.
If you close the door and use the
magnet to move the bottle opener...
You can lock the door and
deadbolt at the same time.
Then if you remove the magnet
and shake the door a little...
I see.
If there are empty beer bottles on the floor,
then it's not unnatural for a bottle
opener to be on the floor, too.
I knew you did it.
What?
You said you were drinking while
playing with a cow magnet yesterday.
I told you, it wasn't me!
Otaro-san left us a message
telling us who killed him.
What?
I knew it.
No, that's not Byun's symbol.
It's backwards.
Backwards?
Since the Masked Comet was
so involved in this case,
it looked like his symbol to us,
but if you look at the position of his
hand, it's clear that it's reversed.
In other words, it's two lines
sticking out of a circle?
What symbol is that?
In his signature,
Minakitaya Otaro
Otaro-san expresses the
"oh" sound as a circle.
In other words, the circle is "oh."
"Oh"
The two lines are the
Katakana symbol for "ha."
"Ha"
They simply overlapped.
Then the name Otaro-san wrote was...
Ohara-san, you killed him.
Th-This is ridiculous.
Why would I do that?
Because you were the other culprit
in the seven-year-old case.
Kyujiro-san overheard you
discussing your secret
using the bug he installed in
your room and threatened you.
That's it!
He had the Byun card to tell
you he knew everything.
First you killed Kyujiro-san to keep him quiet.
You must have prepared
some tap water beforehand.
You most likely drowned him in the van,
and dumped the body in the lake
on your way to pick us up.
Then you killed Otaro-san in order
to frame him for the murder.
You're lying! You're making it up!
Then why did you lie about
Otaro-san taking beers
and a bottle opener to his room?
I wasn't lying. I really saw him.
It's not unusual to take a
bottle opener to drink beer.
Otaro-san didn't need to
because he had his own bottle opener.
We didn't find one.
You've been fooled by its appearance,
just like that blue beer.
The key to the door to happiness
that Otaro-san described
is a bottle opener.
That key?
I get it.
For a beer-lover like Otaro-san,
opening a beer would be the same
as opening the door to happiness.
The upturned edges of caps on
the floor are slightly pointed.
It's a product of the shape
of the bottle opener.
In order to make this a locked
room, you needed a bottle opener.
You expected to find one, but didn't.
You hurried back to the kitchen to get one.
You lied to hide this fact.
Why was the dining room ransacked?
In the dining room was the
cow magnet you played with
that had many bottle caps stuck to it.
He had to remove them in order to
use the cow magnet in his trick.
However, it would be
impossible to put them back.
So he scattered the caps on the floor
and ransacked the room to camouflage it.
What about proof? Do you have proof?
You know better than anyone
that there's damning evidence
underneath your watch.
Normally you keep your watch in your pocket,
but since last night, you've
been wearing it on your wrist.
So, what?
That watch is broken, isn't it?
When you checked the time earlier, you looked
at the wall clock after looking at your watch.
W-Well, I...
Last night, after murdering Otaro-san,
you intended to return the cow magnet
to the dining room before going home.
However, Fujiyoshi-san discovered the
situation in the dining room first,
causing a commotion.
Unable to return to the dining room,
you climbed down the tree next to the
second floor guest room and escaped.
The cow magnet was in your
pocket during this time.
The pocket that also contained your watch.
So the magnetic force of the
cow magnet broke his watch.
When he returned after receiving a call,
he waited for an opportunity to
drop it on the dining room floor.
Could you take off your watch?
This mark was left by a bottle cap.
Otaro-san must have resisted
when you tried to kill him.
He pushed you to the ground, pressing one of
the bottle caps on the floor against your arm.
That's when you got that mark.
If we examine the bottle caps in the room,
we'll find skin or blood stuck to one.
Go ahead and examine them.
You won't find anything.
I'm sure we won't.
You took the cap with you.
However, you didn't have time
to dispose of it very far away.
Furthermore, even if skin
or blood aren't found on it,
the various caps are bent differently.
If one matches this mark,
it'll prove you did it.
Otaro's the one who said we
had to get rid of Kyujiro!
Then why did you kill Otaro-san?
He insisted on killing Miona-chan!
So I had to kill him to protect her!
Is that true?
This locked room trick is simple,
but you couldn't have
thought of it on the spot.
Are you sure you hadn't been plotting...
...to kill Otaro-san?
N-No!
You had always planned to murder
Otaro-san and frame him.
No, no!
Otaro wanted to kill her seven years ago,
but I stopped him!
I protected her!
It was really scary.
Miona?
The bloody mask came closer,
and... and...
I protected you.
Right?
Isn't that right?
Forget everything you saw here.
Got it?
Otherwise we'll kill you, too.
No!
Miona!
Miona-chan!
The man I saw seven years ago...
was this man!
It was an awful case,
but at least that girl will
be able to truly smile again.
Yeah.
Huh? Where'd everyone go?
In your case, you're not just
feeling groggy from the beer.
Episode Preview
Akagi-san!
Hide-san!
H-Have you recovered from your injury?
I hope this makes you feel better.
I'll be rooting for you!
Thanks.
Eventually the Japanese will understand
what gambling is all about.
Why?
The J League Bodyguard
The next episode of Conan
is "The J League Bodyguard!"
Stadium Tour
Next Conan's hint!
A stadium tour!
There's no Conan next week.
Don't miss the next episode.
We're taking the week off for J League.
I see you're not taking a week off from beer.