They are taking it in right from the start.
They are.
Eventually the Japanese will understand
what gambling is all about.
It is 8 by 2 now.
Should we proceed with buying?
Don't worry.
It is taken care of.
When the countdown reaches zero, use your
detective skills to produce an answer!
Though it started with some ominous English,
today's episode is set in a soccer stadium!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The J League Bodyguard
"The J League Bodyguard!"
Japan performance at the
World Cup was disappointing,
The second half of the J League starts now!!
but tonight's key match will predict
the latter half of the J League season.
J League Employee
Iwasada Yasuaki (40)
Indeed.
The fans must know this,
as tickets are sold out.
Merchandise sales are also up 30%.
Is that what's important to you?
Is 30% not enough?
It's not about the numbers.
Then there's tonight's match.
If the Spirits win, given
the remaining schedule...
That doesn't interest you?
Huh?
Nothing.
In any case, don't disappoint our fans.
Yes, sir. You can count on me.
Toto Stadium
Normally only the team and
their staff use this entrance.
Only players and coaches can enter
the locker rooms down this hallway.
Gamba Osaka
Those doors are open right now,
but when the teams are
inside, they're closed.
After that, they're not opened
again until the game's over.
In other words, no matter how
close you are to your opponents,
you can't even talk to them.
What? Naturally, you can't use phones either.
I wasn't going to ask that.
Ai-chan, you've been talking so much.
Is something up?
She's just overflowing with excitement
because we're at the stadium.
I'm the star here.
I just let you kids tag along with me.
You got that?
I'm surprised.
With a girl who knows so much about the
stadium in your group, you don't need me.
What you like, you'll do well and all that.
What you like, huh?
Since we're playing Big
Osaka tonight, Higo-sa—
Sorry.
Should we check out the
locker rooms while we can?
What? Really?
Aren't the rules strict?
Yeah, but the teams haven't entered yet.
Now's our only chance.
Let's go!
You'd better be grateful, kids.
Who do you have to thank for
this valuable experience?
Me?
The old man's bragging because at the
Tokyo Spirits versus Gamba Osaka game
being played here at Toto Stadium tonight,
he's been given the honor
of opening the game.
He's truly a great detective.
So fancy!
It's wonderful!
Is this the locker room?
This is the lounge.
The players relax here before the game.
The locker room is back here.
We can't sit in these, can we?
You totally can.
Really?
Me, too!
Hey, don't get it dirty.
I feel like a player after a match.
I bet sitting on this makes
you better at soccer.
I know.
There's no way it does.
I found it!
Hide's autograph!
How can you tell?
The number 11's written next to it.
Oh, so that's how.
The Spirits' #11 is Akagi Hideo.
Yeah.
Miss, are you a Hide fan?
Yeah. I heard Hide's coming back today.
He's been taking time off for an injury.
I brought him a special sports drink.
Really? Special, huh?
Don't do it.
Tokyo Spirits Roupeiro
Tonozuka Yuichi (45)
Gifts of food or drink before a match
will get you a yellow card, miss.
Tonozuka-san, it's okay.
I'll explain it to her.
You'd better.
See you later.
What a creep.
I agree.
A yellow card?
Did I do something bad?
Sorry, it's not like that.
I know you brought him a special drink,
but he can't drink it right now.
But he has an important match coming up.
It'll make him feel better.
Y-Yeah, you're right.
She's going to cry.
She's about to cry.
What if he's accused of doping?
He'll be out for longer
than he was for his injury.
He won't be able to play again.
Doping?
But it just has honey and—
It's not like that.
Nobody would suspect you.
It's just a rule for before games,
especially in professional sports.
You wouldn't want anyone to suspect
Hide of doping, would you?
Do you think I'm up to something?
What makes you say that?
Sorry. These kids don't get it.
You're right.
Want to see the doping control
room next to the infirmary later?
They'll be testing a few players
after today's match, too.
Too? You mean they do it every time?
It's not only after big matches?
Why does everyone suspect
the players of doping?
We do it because we don't.
We trust the players.
Isn't it amazing that not a single player's
been disqualified from the J League for doping?
Yeah.
I guess I'll be taking this home.
No, no. You can't give it to
him now, but you can later.
Really?
Trust me.
That's great. Now he won't get
an upset stomach during the game.
What does that mean?
What else did you put in there besides honey?
She mentioned aojiru.
Doesn't the stadium keep
an official sports drink?
Wasn't it viper sake?
Yeah.
Official?
They're that strict about it?
The packaging is only sold at the stadium.
Since the bottles are sealed, you don't
have to worry about their contents.
They're often placed by the goal posts.
You sure do know a lot.
Do you even need me to show you around?
She's special.
Let's go buy some!
I'll buy him some, too!
I thought we'd head to the locker
room now. What do you want to do?
What?
What do we want to do?
What does that mean?
The team's bus will be arriving
soon, so now's our only chance.
No one told us that.
Why would we need to
discuss it with you kids?
We won't be able to stay
once the players arrive.
We're going to go check it out.
You guys do what you want.
No way!
We want to see!
Wait!
I can't take you into a locker
room when players are present.
They'll be going over their
formations before the match.
You kids really do know a lot.
I'm disappointed.
I wanted to give the coach my strategy.
The coach? What are you talking about?
They'd definitely win.
Maedono-san will be changing his
compression shirt at halftime.
Put his on top.
Yes, sir. I know.
I know?
Don't you mean, "I understand, sir?"
Tokyo Spirits Roupeiro
Miyamoto Risa (22)
Sorry.
I'll go put Maedono-san's compression
shirt on top of his uniform.
If you don't say it out loud,
I won't be sure if you've
actually done it.
Sorry to bother you, sir.
We won't touch anything.
Just let me show them around.
And check the drinks again.
Yes, sir. I'll go check the drinks.
Keep an eye out for any
unfamiliar squeeze bottles.
Squeeze bottles?
He really is a creep.
I couldn't agree more.
I see. That happened?
Don't be mad, though.
He's prouder than anyone of being a roupeiro.
Popero? Is that a tasty food?
Roupeiro. It means equipment
manager in Portuguese.
Equipment manager.
Are you a Poupeiro, too?
It's with an "h" sound.
Oh.
The players haven't arrived yet,
but all their equipment is here.
You're right.
I see. The players don't have
to carry anything themselves.
That's not all they do.
What do you mean?
They maintain every player's
spikes, clothes, and drinks.
They even know everyone's favorite candies.
They allow the players to focus
on the game free of stress.
Simply put, that's their job.
Right? Right?
Isn't she amazing?
You're amazing!
You know all of that?
Do you ever get it wrong?
No, no.
He's the one who does that.
I'm still learning.
I'd get in trouble if I
called myself a roupeiro.
No way.
Tonozuka-san said you know more about the
players' preferences than he does now.
You can't be serious.
He's lying.
That guy complimenting someone?
He must be up to something.
You kids are tough.
I'll scold them later.
Hide-san! Naoki-san!
Hide-san! How do you feel
about today's match?
You can do it!
Akagi-san!
Hide-san!
Excuse me. Do you have a minute?
What's with the formality?
This girl has a gift for you.
Have you recovered from your injury?
I mean, of course you have.
I hope this makes you feel better.
I'll be rooting for you!
Thanks.
I couldn't ask for a better gift.
Tonight's game is in the bag now.
I'd better get going.
Thanks for your support.
Y-Yes, of course...
Hey!
Ayumi-chan!
She's out cold!
He got her.
Don't die! We haven't watched the game yet!
Not my problem.
Yikes. I'm starting to get nervous.
It's because I put this on.
Mori-san, you have a great figure.
It looks great on you.
R-Really?
I gave my drink to Hide!
I made an exception.
Then Akagi-san will have
leftover drinks tonight.
Lucky me.
If he doesn't need them, I'll drink them.
Why don't you buy one for yourself?
Time to make the shot.
Mister, calm down.
Conan-kun.
Endo-san!
I can't get any distance on it.
Maybe I'm practicing wrong.
Gamba Osaka
Endo Yasuhito (38)
It's amazing that you're
even trying that shot.
Oh, Mori-san.
Yes? Did you call?
I'm a huge fan of yours.
Can I shake your hand?
Sure.
Since I heard you were
opening tonight's match,
I thought I might get to meet you.
I feel so lucky.
You're embarrassing me.
Did you kids see that?
This is how people who
understand true value react.
Really?
Is Endo in a slump?
Endo-san's so cool...
What?
You're into that?
Mori-san, we should get ready
for the opening ceremony.
I-Is it time?
Good luck.
Thanks.
All right!
Time for a hat trick!
How are you going to do that?
Thank you for waiting.
Today's opening ceremony will be conducted
by the great detective Mori Kogoro!
This isn't good.
Tonight's opening ceremony
will be a penalty kick.
Goalkeeper Masunaga, don't
misread the situation.
I can't! I can't do it!
What is that? It's not funny.
Mister...
This is really embarrassing.
You've definitely got diarrhea.
It's easy to tell.
I can't move...
It's coming again!
I'm going to the bathroom!
What did he have for lunch?
Ran's curry.
Didn't you eat that, too?
Yeah.
Then maybe you'll get it, too.
I'm fine.
Why doesn't this bathroom have any doors?
Uh, oh! I should keep my voice down.
That's the testing bathroom.
Of course there's no door.
But I can't relax.
Not my problem.
If you want a regular bathroom, go outside.
No...
This is the drink the old man had.
Should we examine it?
Here?
Who do you think I am?
Why?
Goal!
Endo's left foot takes the first point!
Yeah.
I think that's when it happened.
Can I count on you?
Thanks.
You don't look happy.
This was found in a trash can in the kitchen.
They cut beneath the cap
and removed the plastic
after softening it by
submerging it in hot water.
I hope they didn't burn themselves.
How'd you do?
The water contained rhubarb, aloe,
senna, and bisacodyl.
In other words, laxatives.
Just laxatives?
Yeah, just laxatives.
It won't kill him.
Why?
Maybe they don't like detectives.
Yeah, right.
Wait, where's the bottle?
I threw it out.
Seriously?
Are you turning this into a case?
But there's a victim.
That old man doesn't qualify as a victim.
Isn't that kind of mean?
Not at all.
It's almost halftime.
The roupeiros will be busy
preparing for the second half.
Will the Sleeping Kogoro
be making an appearance?
He's alone in the VIP room.
How is he doing?
The medicine they gave him is working.
Everything works on him.
I'll tell them once the second half starts.
Very naturally and cutely.
The second half is starting.
The Spirits are behind by one point.
Will they be able to tie things
up and make a comeback?
Come in.
Excuse me.
Sorry for asking you to come here.
It's fine.
It's my first time in this room.
Have the others arrived yet?
You're the only one I called
here, Miyamoto Risa-san.
Just me?
That was brutal.
You must've seen that opening ceremony.
Three days of practice down the drain.
It was a disaster.
Is your stomach feeling better?
Is my stomach feeling better?
Since it was so lame,
I did my best to pass it off as back pain.
But I see now.
You knew.
Mori-san, I—
Risa-san, I heard you.
"Stop him. Please notice."
While you were checking the
drinks in the locker room,
you deliberately brought me Akagi's drinks.
Couldn't you have left
it at Akagi-san's locker?
If I hadn't drank it, were
you going to put it back?
It was a gamble.
I bet my life and my fate on you,
the great detective Mori Kogoro-san.
I've never gambled before.
And I won.
You won?
Yes, I won.
Are you saying you shouldn't
bite the hand that feeds you,
even if you know it's the wrong thing to do?
You really are amazing.
It was two years ago.
I was studying abroad to become a roupeiro.
I made a friend there who was
also an aspiring roupeiro.
We became co-signers for each other's loans.
But your friend disappeared,
and you took on their debt.
I can only describe you as amazing.
When did you look this up?
We just met today.
This may come as a shock to you,
but your friend and the Rodriguez
pretending to be a good person,
who discussed your loan with you,
are both part of the same
evil totocalcio organization.
But...
Rodriguez-sensei said...
Mori-san!
Tonozuka-san!
I'm sorry.
I heard everything. I...
Forgive her!
Please don't! This was my—
Don't get the wrong idea!
I'm not doing this for you!
I don't need a roupeiro who causes
problems for the team and players!
It's not fair.
Gamble, my ass.
If Mori-san hadn't noticed...
Are you saying it's our
fault we didn't notice?
Shouldn't you have come to
me first? Or Iwasada-san?
Did you think you could scare
us with the trouble you caused?
Mori-san!
She said Hide was moving strangely
during the first half.
She suggested we swap out the
spikes on just his right side.
She... she's learned so much...
What am I talking about?
This has nothing to do with you.
Basically, what I'm trying to say is...
I'm responsible for whatever she's done!
So... so...
Please forgive her!
Please!
Sir...
It's over.
If she'd taken things more seriously,
she could've done things directly!
She—
Look around and you'll see people
committing foul play everywhere.
But here in Japan, we have a
thorough early warning system.
Match fixing and other evil deeds
haven't occurred once since
the J League was formed.
That's the noble truth of
the J League you loved.
Akagi's overtime goal has
brought the game to 1-1.
It's a draw.
Tonight's game was a draw.
The players...
are returning.
I told you, I don't know
what you're talking about!
I didn't have diarrhea!
I'm hanging up!
Who would admit to that? It's embarrassing.
Didn't I tell you?
Mori-san said he doesn't
know anything about it.
There's no victim or physical evidence.
Nothing's going to happen to you.
Anyway, about that totocalcio
organization you mentioned...
I can't believe they arrested
all of them in a day.
Did some busybody put a powerful
organization on the job?
What?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Huh. Even in Tokyo,
there are places like this.
Episode Preview
The air's clear and the view's excellent.
What a great place to drink sake.
Cheese!
Isn't that because you suggested the
three of us go somewhere together?
Now, now.
What is that?
Friendship Washed Away In The Riverbed
The next episode of Conan is
"Friendship Washed Away In The Riverbed!"
Water Wheel
Next Conan's hint.
A water wheel!
Who supports the J League?
Don't miss the next episode.
Roupeiro!
Sounds like you've learned something.