Huh. Even in Tokyo,
there are places like this.
I know. It was worth coming, right?
The air's clear and the view's excellent.
What a great place to drink sake.
This way, please.
Hey, miss. That watermill isn't working.
That's right.
It used to deliver water to the wasabi farms.
Now we use it as an icehouse.
An icehouse?
That's like a natural refrigerator, right?
Yes.
It's where we keep the
natural ice we serve here.
Excuse me.
Are you Mori Kogoro-san?
Matsui Juri (21)
Teito University
Philosophy Student
Suzumoto Maria (21)
Teito University
English Student
Akiba Yuko (21)
Teito University
Education Student
Yes, that's me.
Could I take a photo with you?
Of course. I don't mind.
Why don't I take it?
No, thank you.
Over here. Line up in front of the river.
Mori-san, everyone, please.
Come on, Maria.
Here.
Move.
Yuko.
Here we go.
Say cheese.
Cheese!
When the countdown reaches zero, use your
detective skills to produce an answer!
Taking a commemorate
photo by a cool riverbed!
Do these three women even like each other?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Friendship Washed Away In The Riverbed
"Friendship Washed Away In The Riverbed!"
Ow! I have a blister.
I'm exhausted from walking so far.
But, you said you wanted to come here.
Isn't that because you suggested the
three of us go somewhere together?
Now, now.
We came here to make up.
Maria, do you have any band-aids?
Thanks.
Excuse me.
Here is your appetizer.
This looks delicious!
I'll take one, too.
What are they doing?
Dad, don't you know?
It's popular among girls these days to
upload photos made to look cute to the internet.
See? I do it, too.
Cute, huh?
Is there a problem?
I hear some birds singing.
I can't get the right angle.
Look.
That's cute.
You're trying too hard to act cute.
You never change.
How about mine?
Maria showed me a new app.
It's all right.
But using an app for photo
correction feels wrong.
How about yours, then?
What do you think?
Getting these shadows was really hard work.
Feels cold.
Did you say something?
No.
Let's have the great detective judge them.
I agree!
Excuse me.
Could you take a look at our photos?
S-Sure.
We're thinking of submitting them to
a publishing company's photo contest.
I know the one.
The winner gets a book
published of their photos.
Yeah.
Could you give us some advice?
But I don't know anything about photography.
Unbelievable.
You think that's good enough to win?
Don't make me laugh.
I'll be back.
Oh, no. My battery's dead.
Uh, oh. I'm out of storage, too.
Should we go now?
Yeah.
Sorry. The judging will have to wait.
What was that about?
Oh, Dad...
Anyway, those girls sure
are taking a long time.
It's been a while since they left.
Their food's getting cold.
She really should try it.
I know. Apps are so nice.
Huh? Yuko's still not back.
She was probably busy taking
photos and forgot about the time.
You're right.
Let's start without her.
Wow, this fish is transparent.
It's almost too pretty to eat.
Thank you for waiting.
This is our special natural shaved ice.
How cute!
Let me take a picture first.
What is that?
What's wrong?
Over there.
Y-Yuko?
Huh?
What?
It's an emergency!
Wait, Conan-kun!
Get a life preserver!
Dad!
Stand back, kid!
Mister!
Hey, are you okay?
She's gone.
Ran, call the police.
Got it.
What are these?
Hey, kid!
Ow!
How many millions of times do I have to
tell you to stay out of crime scenes?
Go away!
Okay.
Yuko.
Keep it together.
Here.
Mori-kun, did you just happen to be
at the scene of the crime once again?
I am ashamed.
It's a detective's fate.
In any case, why don't you explain what was
happening when the body came down the river?
W-Well...
Don't tell me you don't remember because you
were passed out drunk in the middle of the day.
A-As if, Inspector. You must be joking.
We came here to take photos.
But Yuko got a text from someone and left.
She hadn't coming back
yet, so we were worried.
Then suddenly some blood red water
came flowing down the river.
And we saw Yuko in the red river.
That's right.
Awakened by the scream, I leapt
into the river, and pulled her out.
I see.
So he was asleep.
Hey, miss.
What is it?
Earlier you said you came here to make up.
What did that mean?
Oh.
Well, you know...
Huh...
Inspector!
I have the results of the inspection.
The cause of death was a cerebral contusion
from a blow to the back of the head.
Do we know what the red
stuff in the water was?
Yes, sir.
It's a fern called Azolla japonica
that grows in lakes, right?
Conan-kun, you sure are knowledgeable.
I saw it on TV the other day.
Because the plant is small, buoyant,
and red, in large quantities,
they look like pools of blood.
I see.
We also discovered what we believe to be
the victim's belongings near the watermill.
You two. Do you recognize this?
That's Yuko's.
There's a label on it.
On the phone—excuse me...
We found this photo.
It's possible the victim accidentally
fell here while trying to take a photo.
Let me see that.
Hey!
This is...
Don't do that, Conan-kun.
Sorry.
Huh? What's wrong, mister?
I wanted to go to the watermill,
but they won't let me in because
of an investigation or something.
You mean the watermill converted
into an icehouse, right?
Yeah. What about—
Thanks, mister.
Sure...
Like Inspector Megure said, it's
possible she fell accidentally.
But what about the photo?
Metropolitan Police         Keep Out
Officer, did my beetle come flying this way?
I didn't see one.
There it is!
Hey!
Matsui Juri-san, right?
I heard you were out when
the incident occurred.
Am I a suspect?
No. We're just questioning everyone
as part of the investigation.
I just went to a convenience store
to buy extra storage for my phone.
Receipt
Why don't you check with the store clerk?
They'll confirm my story.
I'll take that.
The three of you came here together, right?
The decision was suddenly made
to disband our photography club.
I got in a fight with Yuko over it,
so we came here to make up.
It's cold.
This must be the icehouse.
The waterwheel that's supposedly
not in use is moving.
They put sawdust on it so it won't melt.
There's no mistaking it.
This wasn't an accident.
It's murder.
I went to get the charger I forgot.
I ran into the chef on the way. Ask him.
Who decided you'd come here?
Yuko.
She said one of her blog's
fans told her to come here.
Do you know why she went to the watermill?
Probably to take photos.
She can be so egotistical.
Ow...
Wild roses, huh?
This is...
I see.
So that's how it is.
Conan-kun!
Where did that brat disappear to?
Inspector, do we still have to stay?
I'm so sad. I don't want to be here anymore.
Inspector.
This was an accident.
Yuko-san wanted to win a publishing
company's phone photography contest.
She stole a march on her friends and
went to take photos of the watermill.
While trying various angles
with her selfie stick, sploosh.
Conan-kun.
Where have you been?
Sorry!
Wait, Conan!
Inspector, this wasn't an accident.
It was murder.
What are you talking about?
You just said it was an accident.
I was just elaborating on
a common line of thinking.
But now it's time for the
great detective to shine.
Don't you think it's strange?
Her selfie stick was
discovered in the riverbed.
But if she slipped while
trying to take a photo,
she and her phone should've
fallen in the river.
You're right.
In other words, the selfie stick was
placed to make it look like an accident
by the person who murdered Yuko-san.
What?
The killer lured her out
using a free texting service.
I'll be back.
Sorry. The judging will have to wait.
Later, she gave her own
excuse and went after her.
After meeting her at the watermill,
the killer asked her for
tips on taking good photos
and had the victim take selfies.
Then, she convinced Yuko-san to go into the
watermill after breaking the lock beforehand
and struck Yuko-san with some
natural ice, killing her.
In the watermill were traces
of sawdust being swept.
The killer must have erased their footprints.
After murdering Yuko-san,
the killer used a cart to transport
the body from the watermill.
Then she threw her into a pool
and left the selfie stick on the riverbank
so it would look like she fell.
The person who staged the accident
and murdered Yuko-san is among us.
Hey, listen.
What? Mori-san did?
But Mori-kun, when Yuko-san fell in
the river, weren't they with you?
That's right.
You saw Yuko float down the
river with the red water.
That was the killer's trick.
What?
Detective Takagi, are you ready?
Takagi? Now that you mention it, where is he?
Allow me to recreate that trick for you.
Ready!
The waterwheel spun.
Yes.
The killer opened a sluice not normally used.
The river water swept up the Azolla japonica
that had grown in the irrigation
canal and flowed into the pool.
Eventually the water level in the pool rose.
We've been waiting a long time now.
Nothing's happening.
That time is exactly what the killer
carefully calculated as part of their trick.
Pools are naturally formed when sections of
the river curve and separate from the main river.
Put a body in one and direct water towards it,
and eventually it will flow out into the river.
The one who planned all of
this was you, Maria-san.
Me?
There were thin scratches on the body.
She probably got them from the thorns of
wild roses while being carried to the pool.
Those same scratches should
be on the killer's body.
Maria, did you...?
N-No, Juri. These are...
Believe me!
I really didn't...
There's no point in playing dumb.
I already noticed.
You weren't wearing band-aids
when you first arrived,
but you were when you
returned from the riverbed.
Inspector, I had forensics
examine the watermill.
They found what we believe to be Yuko-san's
blood on one of the blocks of ice.
What? Is that true?
Why don't you give up already?
That's just your reasoning.
Show me the proof.
Proof that I killed her!
Maria-san, you have it on you.
The gloves you used to pick up the
ice haven't been found anywhere.
Those gloves must have
Yuko-san's blood and sawdust
from the crime scene on them.
Excuse me.
I found them.
She got what she deserved.
We were college friends.
If we won the contest, we'd have a
collection of our photos published.
To leave a lasting memory
of our college life,
we agreed it would belong to
everyone no matter who won.
But...
#todayslook
Gross stamps.
What is this? It's terrible.
But that day, I realized the person making those comments was Yuko.
Yuko, thanks for waiting.
Just go away (new)
No way. Yuko, did you...
Oh, no. Have I been found out?
But it's true.
Besides, I'm going to win the contest.
She was insulting everyone in the
photography club who were submitting
photos so she would win.
The next day, we were friends as usual,
but the slanderous comments didn't stop.
I couldn't take it anymore.
I tested it countless times.
My plan was perfect.
I anonymously commented on Yuko's
blog so she would come here.
Why? Why didn't you tell me about it?
Aren't we friends?
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm home.
Welcome home, Ran-neechan.
I found a shaved ice shop that
uses natural ice in the area.
Want to check it out sometime?
Sure.
It's not like you're penguins.
What's so fun about eating ice?
Who cares?
Mister, penguins don't eat ice.
Episode Preview
A nice campground was opened recently.
Conan-kun and his friends
are going next weekend.
I see.
All right!
We pitched the tent!
Urushibara, that's going too far.
I could crush you anytime I wanted.
Just like Danno!
Y-You bastard...
Mystery of the Burning Tent (Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "Mystery
of the Burning Tent, Part One!"
Managing Officer Kuroda
Next Conan's hint!
Managing Officer Kuroda!
It's summer vacation!
Don't miss the next episode.
I'm burning with excitement for camping!
It's a tent that's going to be on fire.
What?