Genius Shogi Player's
Mysterious Death
Genius Shogi Player's Mysterious Death
Grade School Teacher Wakasa
Rumi Saves the Day!
Subdues Professional Golfer!
Sir?
Managing Officer Kuroda?
Is something wrong, sir?
It's nothing.
I was just thinking.
Did you need something, Shiratori?
Yes, sir.
I finished the report on
the other day's robbery.
Here it is.
Good work.
Sir.
What is it?
You seem a bit tired.
I have a lot on my mind.
Why not take a break?
You haven't used any of your
vacation time, have you?
No.
I know.
How about camping?
A nice campground was opened recently.
Conan-kun and his friends
are going next weekend.
I see.
The Sleeping Kogoro's adviser, huh?
Yes. Normally they go with Professor Agasa,
but Agasa-san is sick.
This time they'll be accompanied
by their grade school teacher.
A grade school teacher?
You know, the one who was in the news
for subduing the pro golfer murderer.
Wakasa Rumi-sensei.
I'd actually planned to take time
off and go with Kobayashi-sensei.
But if we're going on a date, I thought it'd
be better for just the two of us to go.
I-In any case, I'll leave these
campsite pamphlets with you.
Toto Forest Campsite
NEW OPEN!!
Camping & Barbecue Site
Well, I should get going.
Sure. Good work.
If you don't need those pamphlets,
feel free to throw them away.
Sure.
Excuse me.
Camping, huh?
Toto Forest Campground
NEW OPEN!!
Camping & Barbecue Site
It's not my style.
When the countdown reaches zero, use your
detective skills to produce an answer!
Managing Officer Kuroda and Wakasa-sensei!
The suspicious duo meets at our campsite!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Mystery of the Burning Tent
(Part One)
"Mystery of the Burning Tent, Part One!"
Toto Forest Campground
All right!
We pitched the tent!
Good.
Okay, everyone.
Could you go gather some firewood for dinner?
Okay!
Ai-chan, let's go!
There's a bunch over there!
Don't run.
Wakasa Rumi-sensei.
Assistant homeroom teacher to class
1-B of Teitan Elementary School.
The other day we happened to
be invited to her apartment,
and we just happened to get involved
in the murder of her neighbor.
But the receipt I found in her
apartment from that morning...
7mart
Receipt
Eggs
Bell Pepper
Carrot
Onion
Plate (medium)
Glass
Mug
Total Due
Cash Tendered
Change
It showed she'd bought
plates and mugs for us.
In other words, that morning she knew
her neighbor would commit a murder.
In order to involve us,
she deliberately ruined the screen
and invited us to her apartment
under the pretense of repainting it.
No.
Not us.
Is she after me?
When we found the skeleton
in the old storage shed,
the rust on the trapdoor to the basement
that hadn't been opened in years
had been recently removed.
If she discovered the body beforehand,
and pushed me to get involved in the case...
Could this camping trip also be...?
Hey, Conan-kun.
There's someone like you.
Huh?
Someone like me?
That guy over there.
He's just like you.
I told you.
Three more.
The curry won't be thick enough unless you
add three more pieces of roux to the curry.
You've got to add at least two more.
I get it.
That's why Midori's out
buying more right now.
I see. It's those fingers.
That's exactly what a certain someone
influenced by his Gallicized mother does.
This gesture means three, right?
Yeah.
That's three, but this is two.
Huh? But that guy...
He did two like us.
I found some.
Here.
Why?
He represents three like
this and two like this.
On top of that, his fingers
are taped, which means...
Hey, aren't you guys...
Huh?
...basketball players?
What?
Basketball referees extend their pointer
and middle fingers to represent two,
but they use their pointer
finger, middle finger,
and thumb to represent three so you
don't confuse it with two, right?
I heard a lot of players
pick up the same habit.
That's amazing, kid. You're exactly right.
Furuoka Midori (22)
Basketball Team Manager
I'm Furuoka Midori, manager of the
Shiraami University basketball team.
The guy stirring the curry is the man
who became our star player this
year, Ashizawa Sumito-kun.
What? Don't call me that.
Ashizawa Sumito (22)
Basketball Team Member
I was riding the bench until last year.
But you've been approached
by professional teams, right?
The other day a scout came
to meet you before the game.
It was a coincidence.
I hope we'll still be friends
even after you become famous.
S-Sure...
Urushibara Fumiaki (22)
Basketball Team Member
I'm Urushibara Fumiaki, the
cornerstone of our team's defense.
I'm a stickler when it comes
to defending and making curry.
And I'm Danno Kuninori, the former ace who
was blinded by the cornerstone of our defense.
Danno Kuninori (22)
Basketball Team Manager
B-Blinded?
Seriously?
Yeah. I gently bumped him with
my elbow during practice.
It wasn't gentle!
I nearly lost my sight!
I almost got a glass eye!
She's grasping something.
What is it? What could it be?
Yeah, but...
Because of that, you got
closer to Midori, right?
You should be thanking me.
What?
Urushibara, that's going too far.
Watch what you say, Ashizawa.
Huh?
I could crush you anytime I wanted.
Just like Danno!
Y-You bastard...
I've had enough.
I knew shouldn't have come.
Hey...
I'm going to drink, have
some snacks, and go to bed.
Wake me before you leave tomorrow.
Urushibara-kun!
This sucks!
I invited everyone camping because
things have been tense recently.
Sorry. I just couldn't take it.
Now, now. He'll feel better
once he has some curry.
He loves curry.
That's good!
This curry is really good!
Yeah, it's delicious.
Curry tastes better when
you make a lot of it.
That's great.
There's more, so eat all you want.
Okay!
Thank you for letting us join you.
Don't worry about it.
We just combined your ingredients with ours.
And food tastes better when you're
sharing it with a large group.
I agree.
It's no use.
Urushibara's hiding in his
tent and won't even respond.
I see.
Maybe he's already gone to sleep.
He complained when I talked to him earlier.
Here, Ashizawa-kun.
Thanks.
But his light's on.
Huh?
You're right.
Looks like he's doing squats.
Come to think of it, Urushibara said
he does them every night before bed.
Really?
I know. Ashizawa, can I have that curry?
Huh? Sure.
I'm going to take this over there.
I see. You're going to lure
him out with the smell.
Yeah.
You can do it.
Hey, Urushibara.
Sorry for picking a fight earlier.
I know you didn't do it on purpose.
Come on, Urushibara.
I'm stuffed.
I can't eat anymore.
Of course not.
You had five heaping servings of curry.
You eat too much.
It's no use. He's not responding.
He's listening to music on his
headphones while doing squats.
I see.
Do you smell something burning?
Huh?
You're right.
Hey, look.
The tent's on fire!
Isn't that Urushibara's tent?
No way...
Seriously?
Water! Everyone get water!
Hurry!
Urushibara...
No...
No way...
Hey, Ai-chan.
What happened to the man inside?
Don't! You don't want to see that.
Okay...
B-But, Mitsuhiko, why did the tent catch fire?
Well, because...
Maybe the person in the tent
next door saw something.
Excuse me!
Are you awake?
Hello?
Can you hear us?
Excuse me!
Is anyone home?
Hello?
We're opening the flap!
Managing Officer Kuroda?!
Sorry. I was sleeping with earplugs in.
But I can tell at a glance what's happening.
Let's call the police immediately.
Any objections?
Wakasa Rumi-sensei?
Sensei? Sensei?
Wakasa-sensei!
What is it, Yoshida-san?
That police officer with the scary face
is asking if it's okay to call the police.
What?
Well, Wakasa Rumi-sensei?
A tent caught fire, and a man is dead.
It seems natural to me
that we'd call the police.
Why are you asking me?
And how do you know my name?
You were glaring at me with
such a fierce expression,
I thought you had an objection.
Because of this face, people often look away,
but they rarely stare.
Really?
And I saw your name in the news.
"Grade School Teacher Wakasa
Rumi saves the day!"
"Subdues professional golfer!"
You saw that?
How embarrassing.
This woman...
Her right eye's blind.
Come to think of it,
when Wakasa-sensei first introduced
herself as our assistant homeroom teacher,
she hit her head on the podium.
She hit her head on the trapdoor to the
basement in the old storage shed, too.
I was beginning to think she was pretending
to be a clumsy teacher so we'd
underestimate her, but...
What if hitting her head
wasn't an accident?
Sorry, Yuminaga.
I wasn't sure whether to call
you or violent crime's Megure.
No problem, sir.
A fire is arson's job.
I see.
So, what's the situation?
The origin of the fire was the
candle inside the lantern.
It melted into the other
candles scattered around it,
so it's kind of a mess.
The candle fell, igniting
comic books and clothing.
The fire spread quickly.
Then it enveloped the victim sleeping in
the legless chair, burning everything.
It seems the victim had quite a bit to drink.
The tent entrance was
zipped shut all the way.
It even had a lock on it.
So it wasn't arson.
No.
I believe it was an accident.
Isn't it strange, though?
See? There's a single strip of bamboo
mixed in with the melted candle.
That's probably one of the skewers
from the dango the victim was eating.
Huh.
I didn't realize you were here, Conan-kun.
You're familiar with the
Sleeping Kogoro's adviser?
Yes.
He's advised me before.
Also, if you look closely
at the hardened candles,
there's one with a hole near the tip,
and for some reason there's a V shaped burn
on the cover of the magazine
next to the laptop.
Maybe someone set some kind of mechanism.
I see.
You're right.
Which means that person
is one of you three
who visited his tent one at a time.
The first to visit his tent
was Furuoka Midori-san.
Next was Ashizawa Sumito-san.
And finally Danno Kuninori-san, correct?
Oh, my.
Earlier you said you were sleeping
inside your tent with earplugs in.
But you know the order in which they visited?
Actually, while nodding off,
I was watching through a gap in my tent flap
as you cheerfully ate your curry.
Was there someone who caught your interest?
No.
I had no particular reason for doing it.
No particular reason, huh?
Yes.
Since my tent was right next
to the tent that burned,
I remembered the faces and order
of the people who came this way.
But since I had earplugs in,
I don't know what the three of
them discussed with the victim.
And then you went to sleep?
Surely you didn't ignore
the tent engulfed in flames
so you could observe the person
you're so interested in,
right?
No.
I made the mistake of falling asleep.
Though since there was a
grade school teacher present,
I may have underestimated the situation
and believed nothing serious would occur.
I see.
Is she a teacher?
Yeah.
She's our assistant homeroom teacher.
I see.
So why don't we ask you one by one again...
What did you discuss with the victim then?
Let's start with Furuoka Midori-san
who visited the victim's tent first.
A-All right...
Episode Preview
Why did the victim Urushibara-san stay in his
tent instead of eating curry with everyone else?
We got into an argument.
Hey.
Danno-san claimed he used to be
the ace of his basketball team.
Is that true?
Yeah, he was.
Look.
A balancing acorn.
Mystery of the Burning Tent
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Mystery
of the Burning Tent, Part Two!"
Wakasa-sensei
Next Conan's hint!
Wakasa-sensei!
Don't miss the next episode.
Managing Officer Kuroda is a bit odd.
Wakasa-sensei...
No comment.