Mori Detective Agency
I'm sure you haven't forgotten, Mori-kun,
about how much trouble you caused me
when you worked under me in investigations.
Why did you suddenly drop
in and bring up the past?
Can't you figure it out?
You're the only one I can count on.
There's no time.
I need you to help me solve a case.
I-Inspector...
Raise your head, sir.
It must be a pretty big case if
Inspector Megure is this desperate.
What case is it?
This.
Japanese Literature Scholar
Reigan Yutaka (70) Murdered!!
I thought the suspect in this
case was already arrested.
Wasn't it solved?
Right?
Just before we were going
to start prosecuting him,
it was all overturned!
What?!
When the countdown reaches zero, use your
detective skills to produce an answer!
Something's happened at the MPD!
A mysterious case has been overturned!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Job Request From Inspector Megure
"The Job Request From Inspector Megure!"
As you know, the incident
occurred three weeks ago.
The famous Japanese literature scholar,
Reigan Yutaka, was found stabbed to
death in his home in Yotsubadai.
Reigan Yutaka (70)
Japanese Literature Scholar
He was killed the previous
night around eight o'clock.
It wasn't long before we had a suspect.
Maihama Ryuji (33)
Suspect
Yao Koichi (35)
Witness
I saw him last night around eight.
I'd seen him at a bar near the station.
He said he was Reigan-sensei's nephew.
He was the victim's nephew and
self-proclaimed event producer Maihama Ryuji.
Furniture
Home Improvement Store
We learned the day before the murder,
Maihama purchased the knife
that was the murder weapon.
Reigan Yutaka Murder
Investigation HQ
On the night of the murder,
Maihama claims he was in his
apartment in Sasago-cho,
but no one can verify his alibi.
He also claims he purchased
but lost the knife.
Maihama is Reigan's only living relative.
Apparently he was telling everyone that
Reigan's fortune would eventually become his.
However...
I've remained a bachelor until now,
but I finally found someone I want to marry.
Maihama had no alibi.
His uncle's fortune was his motive,
and he bought the knife the day before.
There's even a witness who saw him at the
crime scene when the murder took place.
Maihama Ryuji,
you're under arrest for the
murder of Reigan Yutaka.
I didn't do it.
Even after his arrest, Maihama
continued to deny that he did it,
but naturally, we could still prosecute.
However, yesterday, with two days
remaining on his detention period,
he gave an unbelievable statement.
Which was?
At this rate, I'm going to be framed
for murder, so I'll tell you the truth.
I actually have an alibi.
An alibi?
The night my uncle was killed, I was
committing a burglary in Sasago-cho.
Burglary?!
This is it.
Sasago-cho Burglar
Now that you mention it,
I remember that case.
A burglar entered a home in Sasago-cho.
After staying there for over an hour,
he stole about 500 thousand yen in cash.
The burglar's face wasn't seen,
but Maihama claims it was him.
While I was there, I had
something to drink and eat.
It's true that the burglar drank and ate.
The teeth marks we collected
from the food matched Maihama's.
We even found the 500 thousand yen he hid.
Maihama was definitely the burglar.
But if that's true, then he has an alibi.
An alibi?
How?
The burglar entered the
home in Sasago-cho at 7PM.
Since he was there for over
an hour, he left after eight.
Meanwhile, Reigan was murdered in his
home in Yotsubadai around eight as well.
It takes over an hour by car to travel
between Sasago-cho and Yotsubadai.
So it was impossible for
Maihama to murder Reigan.
But, Inspector...
There's a witness who says he saw Maihama at
the crime scene at the time of the murder.
Yesterday, that witness said...
I actually lied about seeing him.
What?!
He seemed like a bad guy when I saw him
at the bar, so I thought I'd frame him.
But I felt guilty about it.
I'm sorry for making it up.
He made it up?!
Furthermore, regarding the knife...
I bought it to use during the burglary.
I buried it behind my apartment
building after I used it.
This is it.
It's the same as the one
found in Reigan's body.
He must've planned all of it
so he wouldn't lose his inheritance and
to avoid being convicted of murder.
It's too convenient.
It's obvious he'd be a suspect
if Reigan were murdered
so he allowed himself to be
arrested so he could overturn it.
The witness who went back on his testimony
is working with him, of course.
He probably just bought
another one of these knives.
I know he committed the
burglary to create an alibi.
The problem is how in two locations,
separated by an hour's travel,
a single human committed
a burglary in Sasago-cho
while murdering Reigan in Yotsubadai.
Unless we can solve that, even if we
can prosecute him for the burglary,
which was material evidence, we can't
prosecute him for Reigan's murder.
So we spent all day yesterday
trying to solve the problem.
However, we ran into a dead end.
That's why I'm asking for your help!
Inspector, I, Mori Kogoro, shall assist you!
Honestly, I have no faith in you.
But when you're asleep, your detective
skills become mind-boggling.
Uh, I'm not sure how to respond to that.
A burglary and a murder in two
different places at the same time.
I've got it, Inspector.
Immediately after committing
the burglary in Sasago-cho,
he killed Reigan who he'd
asked to meet him nearby.
Then he put the body in a car and drove
it to Reigan's home in Yotsubadai.
Listen, Mori-kun...
Wouldn't the forensics team have
noticed if the body had been moved?
Reigan was murdered inside his own home.
There's no sign the murder was staged.
If anything was staged, it was the burglary.
Of course. Go away.
About the burglary.
It's strange that he stayed
there for an entire hour.
We're certain that the burglar entered
the home in Sasago-cho at 7 PM.
Tenyama Hide-san, who lives alone,
had just begun to watch the seven
o'clock news while eating dinner.
Don't move.
Move, and I'll kill you.
And I don't want you seeing my face.
Tenyama Hide (73)
Victim
Where's the money?
Don't underestimate me!
Though she tried to tell him
where she kept her money,
Hide-san was suddenly struck
and lost consciousness.
She awoke an hour later at eight.
She heard the sounds of a TV
show that starts at eight.
You're finally awake.
I looked for your money, but I couldn't
find it, so I've been waiting.
Where's the money?
In the middle drawer of the dresser.
Thanks.
I can't have you calling
the police right away.
The second time Hide-san
awoke was the next morning.
Wh-What is this?!
The money!
The money in the dresser!
Hello, police?
I've been burglarized!
I see. So that's how it is.
Hey, mister.
I've figured it out, Inspector.
Huh?
Really?
Maihama stepped out for a while.
There are two points to focus on.
First, that Maihama blindfolded Hide-san,
and second, that he knocked her out twice.
Don't underestimate me!
After entering at seven and
knocking Hide-san unconscious,
Maihama recorded the TV program.
He quickly drove to Yotsubadai
and murdered Reigan.
It happened after eight.
Then he returned to Sasago-cho,
replayed the video he recorded,
and woke Hide-san.
It was probably after nine by then,
but because of the audio of
the TV show Maihama recorded,
It's 8 o'clock! Music Top Ten
he made her believe it was eight.
In the middle drawer of the dresser.
Then he knocked out Hide-san again,
and made it appear as though
he'd been there for an hour.
In other words, Maihama wasn't in Hide-san's
home the whole time after he entered.
He left and traveled back
and forth to Yotsubadai
while Hide-san was knocked out.
Wow. That's perfect, mister.
This is the first time the
Inspector's asked for my help.
How could I disappoint him?
Mori-kun.
No, it was an honor to serve you.
Actually, we considered that possibility.
However, it's impossible.
Huh?
I forgot to mention that
when Tenyama Hide-san awoke,
she heard not only the sounds of the
TV show, but also a fire truck siren.
Maihama demanded the location of the
money while she could hear that.
We confirmed with the fire
department that eight
was the only time a fire truck was
dispatched in Sasago-cho that night.
Which means...
Yeah. Maihama never left.
No way.
If he didn't want his face to be seen,
he only needed to wear a mask.
There must be some reason he
blocked Hide-san's vision.
But why?
At 8PM on the night in question,
Maihama Ryuji was threatening
Tenyama Hide-san in Sasago-cho.
So how did he kill Reigan in Yotsubadai?
Is it not coming yet?
What?
Who's coming?
Not who, but those weird
exclamations you always make.
It's not that convenient.
But, Inspector,
are we sure Hide-san heard
the fire truck siren?
Yeah.
We checked with her, so I'm certain of it.
Yes. I know I heard it.
And I smelled something burning.
Smelled something burning?
It doesn't make sense that
she smelled anything though.
Apparently it was a prank call.
In other words, there was no fire.
Yeah.
But a fire truck was stilled dispatched.
Maybe hearing the siren made her
think she smelled something.
Probably.
She seemed to have it together,
but she's an old woman.
She was confused about all sorts of things.
Did she mention something else?
Yeah.
She claimed she didn't hear
a sound she expected to hear.
I heard the TV and the siren,
but I didn't hear the bathtub notification.
I set it to be ready at 8 o'clock.
Strange, isn't it?
I see...
Maybe she just missed it.
Probably.
Anyway, is it still not coming, Mori-kun?
What?
Get sleepy already.
But I got plenty of sleep last night.
You're unbelievable.
It reminds me of all the cases that
were nearly unsolved because of you.
I'm not responsible for this case.
Today's the last day we have left, Mori-kun.
At this rate, we're going
to have to drop the charges,
even though we know he's the culprit!
Yes, this is Megure.
I know that.
Mori-kun's doing his best right now.
Have some faith in your senior.
Damn it. If only I hadn't
slept so deeply last night.
We're just wasting time.
Take me to the burglary investigation.
Personally, I wish I could
admit to killing my uncle,
but I have an alibi.
If I drink...
...and stuff myself, I should
start to feel sleepy.
This old man's confused.
Confused?
Was Hide-san really confused, too?
If Hide-san's perception
wasn't wrong, what then?
That's it. So that's how it is.
Hey, mister.
What if everything Hide-san said is right?
And if you consider the culprit blindfolded
Hide-san and knocked her out twice,
does anything become clear?
It's here!
Is it?
The bathroom!
I was stupid to think I could count on him.
Don't go, Inspector.
But I can't stay here forever.
Just hold on.
Uh huh. Oh, I see.
Yeah.
He seems to have had an epiphany.
Really?
Anyway, he wants you to check
if any fire trucks were
dispatched to Yotsubadai that night.
Got it.
Yes. Yes. I see.
A truck responded to a small fire at 8 PM.
That's it.
Huh? What are you talking about?
Is this it, Mori-kun?!
Yes. I feel refreshed
after using the bathroom.
The mystery is clear to me now.
I'm glad I didn't leave.
Cutting to the chase,
Inspector, Maihama did leave.
What? I told you, that's impossible.
Not alone.
He took Tenyama Hide-san with him.
What?
What does that mean?
After entering Hide-san's
home at seven o'clock,
Don't underestimate me!
he knocked her out and
headed to Yotsubadai
with the unconscious Hide-san in the car.
Then he murdered Reigan and
started a small fire nearby.
Then he called the fire department.
He also called in a false report
to the Sasago-cho fire department.
As he heard the fire truck approaching,
Maihama turned on the TV in
his car and woke Hide-san.
You're finally awake.
I looked for your money, but I couldn't
find it, so I've been waiting.
After getting the money's location
out of her, he knocked her out again.
He took Hide-san back to
her home in Sasago-cho,
placed her in her original position,
and made it seem as though
he was there the whole time.
In other words, Maihama blindfolded Hide-san
not to confuse her about the time,
but to make her believe she heard the
TV and siren in her home in Sasago-cho,
so she wouldn't realize she was actually
in a car parked in Yotsubadai.
I see.
Tenyama Hide-san believes she was in
her own home the whole time, but...
She was taken back and forth to
Yotsubadai while she was unconscious
so she would confirm Maihama's alibi.
However, Maihama ended up
leaving evidence of his scheme.
Hide-san's nose and ears.
She smelled the small fire,
Bath is ready
and she didn't hear her
bathtub's notification.
If you examine Maihama's car
again, I'm sure you'll find
evidence that Hide-san was inside.
It's me. We've destroyed Maihama's alibi.
Thoroughly investigate his car.
That's right.
Your senior didn't let us down.
Mori Detective Agency
Mori-kun, thanks for the help.
I should get going.
I solved the mystery, Inspector.
Maihama has a twin with
identical teeth prints.
While he was committing the burglary...
What?
What are you doing?
I don't know what I was expecting.
This is the only time
I'm asking him for help.
Inspector, what about Maihama's alibi?
Maihama is...
This was supposed to have a good ending.
Episode Preview
What?
Conan-kun is a witness in a murder case?
We're also considering the possibility
of theft as we investigate,
but to be on the safe side,
we're checking everyone's alibi.
Look.
It's the lake.
That's where we got the drawing done.
Hooray!
It's right here.
"The Detective Boys Become Models"
The next episode of Conan is
"The Detective Boys Become Models!"
Canvas
Next Conan's hint!
Canvas!
Don't miss the next episode.
We'll be in the next episode, too.
With the Detective Boys again?
Should we dive back in?