Mori Detective Agency
Dad! I told you to wait until
after dinner to drink beer.
You always fall asleep when you drink.
You never help clean up.
Shut up.
I need more than one drink after all
the unbelievably hard work I did today.
Dad.
You may not understand,
but this is my only joy right now.
Yeah, yeah.
Wait until after dinner, though.
Hello, Mori residence.
Detective Takagi.
Yes, Conan-kun's here.
The truth is...
What?
Conan-kun is a witness in a murder case?
When the countdown reaches zero, use your
detective skills to produce an answer!
A shocking phone call from Detective Takagi!
What do I have to do with the case?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Detective Boys Become Models
"The Detective Boys Become Models!"
I'll summarize the case.
Please do.
Kitasono Seiho (72)
Painter
The victim is Kitasono Seiho-san,
seventy-two years old.
He died when he was struck
in the back of the head.
We believe the weapon was
the plaster bust over there.
Seiho-san was famous in the
world of Japanese painting.
He acted as the chairperson on judging
committees for various exhibitions.
His estimated time of death is around 3:30 PM.
His body was found by his
apprentice Higashio Kengo-san.
It was around 3:50 PM when
Higashio-san entered the studio
and found Seiho-san on the ground,
bleeding from his head.
Higashio-san then left the studio
and returned to the house,
where he reported what he found
to housekeeper Minamida Shizu-san.
At the same time, Seiho-san's
wife Kinuko-san returned home.
They confirmed Seiho-san was dead,
and Shizu-san called the police at 3:58 PM.
Later, his other apprentice
Nishiyama Daiki-san arrived.
He arrived after us around 5 PM.
I see.
Why is Conan-kun a witness in a murder case?
Well...
Wow, it's already finished.
It's Conan-kun and his friends.
This is the painting the late
artist Nishiyama-san
was working on at Lake Okuho today.
We had Conan-kun come to confirm the time.
I think we met Nishiyama-san around 11 AM.
But we left after about
fifteen minutes of sketching,
so I don't know how long
Nishiyama-san was painting there.
But...
But he finished this painting.
He must've been there for a while.
He's right.
Well, Detective?
Have you figured anything out?
We're still gathering information.
Nothing so far.
In any case, Kitasono-sensei wasn't someone
anyone would've hated enough to kill.
Higashio Kengo (33)
Kitasono's Apprentice
So you say.
Kitasono Kinuko (60)
Kitasono's Wife
But, Higashio-san, aren't you
the one who killed my husband?
Why would you say that?
You resented him for not
recommending you
for the teaching position
at the Beika Art School.
This is ridiculous.
In that case, weren't you
fighting with your husband
over the money you were
throwing at a young host?
You're more suspicious than I am.
Let's not discuss this right now.
Minamida Shizu (55)
Housekeeper
Kitasono-sensei just died.
Seriously, Nishiyama-san?
You're suspicious as well.
What?
My husband told you he'd select your piece
to win an exhibition if you paid him.
Nishiyama Daiki (26)
Kitasono's Apprentice
Maybe you killed him because
you couldn't afford it.
I-I would never!
Ahem!
Let me ask again.
When Higashio-san arrived, the
door wasn't locked, correct?
Yes. Normally it's locked,
but on days like today when he knew we
were coming, he sometimes left it open.
According to forensics,
the windows were unlocked.
Yes.
He did sometimes work
with the windows open.
Working with oil paints will fill a
room with the smell of paint and oil.
I see.
But he would've noticed immediately
if a stranger entered through
the door or windows.
Not necessarily.
When he was caught up in his work,
he'd forget to eat or use the bathroom.
I see.
By the way, was there anything
valuable in the studio?
I'm not sure if they were valuable, but my
husband kept a few of his paintings there.
Even if anything's missing, I wouldn't know.
At the very least, they'd
probably sell for a few million.
O-One million?
Sorry.
To be accurate, a few million.
His larger pieces are worth
close to ten million.
Which means it may have been a robbery.
Once again,
during the estimated time of
death between 3:10 and 3:40,
where were all of you?
I was at home all day today.
I left after three and drove here.
I went out before noon.
I ate at the Beika department store and
visited two other department stores after that.
I was on the train from
Lake Okuho to Beika City.
I left just before three to go
shopping at the nearby supermarket.
I returned about five minutes
before Higashio-san arrived.
I see.
Do you have anything or anyone
to verify your alibis?
Verify?
Our alibis?
But how can we verify...?
You were there this afternoon.
Yeah. You already finished
the painting of us.
Yeah. I was late coming here
because I was working on that.
I'd like to show the others.
Can I take a picture?
Of course.
Oh, right.
That reminds me...
Detective, this is a picture
I took at Lake Okuho Station.
Does this verify my alibi?
It's certainly clear that you took
it at Lake Okuho Station, but...
If it'd included the time, it
would've verified your alibi.
I see.
Let me see.
Sure.
Huh? Look at this.
If you enlarge the sign
behind Nishiyama-san...
Train Departure Time
Regular Previous 14:02
Regular Next        14:37
See?
That's right.
I took the 2:02 PM train back.
From Lake Okuho Station to here...
It takes close to two hours.
So he's probably got an alibi.
In any case, we're also considering
the possibility of theft as we investigate,
but to be on the safe side,
we're checking everyone's alibi.
We appreciate your cooperation.
I can't believe you four are tagging along.
Tagging along? How rude.
We're helping you with your investigation.
We remember when he asked
us to be his models.
Since he has the painting
and photos of the station,
Nishiyama-san's alibi is as good as verified.
It won't take long.
Yeah, but...
Why are you suddenly dropping in?
We appreciate your cooperation.
What do you want?
After canvassing the Mitsuboshi and Marukawa
department stores you claimed you visited,
we found no one who said they saw you there.
Naturally, we checked the
security camera footage as well,
but we couldn't find you
anywhere during that time.
Between noon and 4 PM yesterday,
why don't you tell us where and
what you were actually doing?
Aohata Station.
For Lake Okuho Station, transfer to...
Look.
So many mountains.
Who is it?
Higashio-san.
You said you were at home yesterday at 1 PM,
but the deliveryman who came to your
place said no one answered the door.
Oh, please. I was here.
I don't like to be seen in my
pajamas, so I didn't answer.
I see.
We'd like to ask you more about that.
Could you come down to the station with us?
Lake Okuho Station
See? It's just like we said.
That sign that shows the destinations
changed the moment the train started moving.
He only could've gotten on at 2:02 PM.
The station attendant said the same thing.
Sir, when does the sign switch
to showing the next destination?
It changes automatically when
the previous train departs.
After all, Japan has the most
punctual trains in the world.
The man who made that
painting is a good person.
You got that, Detective Takagi?
This is Takagi.
It's me.
Where are you?
Well...
Sorry, Inspector.
We just arrived at Lako Okuho.
I see.
We were able to confirm the
housekeeper Shizu-san's alibi.
We learned his wife Kinuko-san was visiting
a male host around that time, too.
We're just waiting for confirmation
on Higashio-san and Nishiyama-san.
Got it.
I'll let you know the
moment I learn anything.
That's where we got the painting done.
Hooray!
It's right here.
Let's see.
It certainly looks exactly the same.
Of course it is.
It's only been a day.
Genta-kun wouldn't lose weight
or Conan-kun wouldn't grow in a single day.
By the way, I've been
wondering since yesterday.
How did you end up being his models?
There was a dog here.
How cute.
What's your name?
Are you kids in grade school?
Yes.
We're first-years at
Teitan Elementary School.
Are you on a field trip today?
Would you like to model for me?
I see. So that's what happened.
Do you get it now?
The four of us can verify his alibi.
Okay, okay.
Since his alibi's been
verified, we can go now.
What? We came all the way here,
and we're leaving already?
Let's have some fun first.
We can't.
We didn't come here to play.
Train Departure Time
Regular Previous 13:17 Aohata
Regular Next        14:02 Aohata
I see. You're sure, then?
Yes. Nishiyama-san has an alibi.
That just leaves Higashio-san's alibi.
Sato-kun's talking to him now.
I see.
I'm hungry.
I can't take another step.
Okay, okay.
I'll buy you something while
we're waiting to transfer.
That's not good enough.
I want eel.
Since we're in the mountains,
they'll have wild eel.
Wild eel, huh?
Lucky me.
I get to be interrogated
by a beautiful detective.
Hurry up. The train's leaving.
This and this and...
I don't need this, but I do need this.
I'm sorry!
I lied!
Wait!
Are you all right?
Thank you.
Train Departure Time
Express Previous 13:37 Tachikawa
Special Express Next 13:49 Toto
Train Departure Time
Express Previous 13:49 Toto
Special Express Next 13:55 Toto
Detective Takagi, look!
Huh?
This is...
Why are we going back?
Are we going to play?
There's something I need to check again.
Something you need to check?
You didn't notice?
Notice what?
The sign at Aohata Station changed,
even though the train hadn't left yet.
What?
In other words, if the same thing happened
when Nishiyama-san took that photo,
then Nishiyama-san could've
boarded the previous train.
This is Takagi.
We confirmed Higashio-san's alibi.
He was with a married woman at the time.
Could it have been an intruder?
Forensics is saying there are no signs
someone entered from outside the house.
What? Yesterday?
Yeah. Were there any trains
that departed late?
Yeah, there was one.
What time?
It was the 1:17 PM train to Aohata.
Why was it delayed?
It tried to leave on time,
but the gates at the crossing just
outside the station wouldn't descend.
When the conductor examined it, he found
someone had vandalized the crossing gate.
Earlier you said the sign
changes automatically
when it's time for the
previous train to leave.
Does that mean the sign changed to 2:02 PM
while the previous train was late?
Yeah, that's right.
Could you look up what time the delayed
train arrived in Aohata Station?
Let's see.
It departed five minutes late,
but it made up some time on the way.
The train scheduled to arrive
at 1:50 arrived at 1:53.
So, what?
If you arrive in Aohata Station at 1:53,
you can get on the 1:55 special express.
But the question is...
They're the same.
There's no mistaking it.
He made this painting here.
But we met Nishiyama-san around 11.
He couldn't have painted this
in the less than two hours
between when he started and
when he got on the 1:17 train.
Huh? What's this?
He probably accidentally
got some paint on it.
It's yesterday's dog.
Mister, this dog was tied to
this tree yesterday, right?
Yeah. I was fishing down there.
There's good fishing here.
Do you live nearby?
Yeah.
Could you take a look at something?
Do you know what this is?
Yeah, it's barricade tape.
Barricade tape?
They were worried about a dead tree falling,
so a crew from town hall
cut it down last week.
Last week?
Around what time did you take
your dog home yesterday?
I went home to eat lunch,
so it was around 12:30.
There was someone painting here then, right?
No, I didn't see anyone painting.
What?!
He wasn't here?!
Really?
Thank you.
We solved it, Detective Takagi.
Yeah.
What? Nishiyama-san's alibi fell apart?
Yes. This is how Nishiyama-san
fabricated his alibi.
First, he made that painting last week.
But that's not enough to prove an alibi.
That's why he asked us to model yesterday
and painted us on top of the
scenery he'd already painted.
But there was something there
that shouldn't have been:
the tree that was cut down last week.
Then Nishiyama-san returned to the station,
vandalized the crossing
gate, and delayed the train.
He waited for the sign to
change and took a photo.
But since he actually
boarded the 1:17 PM train,
he was able to board the 1:55 PM
special express at Aohata Station.
That train would let him arrive at the
studio in time to commit the murder.
We don't know his motive, but if
he did all that work beforehand,
then Nishiyama Daiki-san definitely
killed Kitasono Seiho-san.
It... It wasn't my fault!
It's... It's...
It's Kitasono-sensei's fault!
He made people pay in exchange
for selecting them as winners.
I couldn't afford it,
so I always lost.
Nishiyama-san, why did you
decide to become a painter?
Because you loved painting?
Didn't you become an artist so the children
who saw your paintings would smile?
But you betrayed the children
who modeled for you.
You deceived your audience and stooped
to using them to commit a murder.
You've been betrayed as well
by the paintings you used to love.
Genta-kun, no fair.
You guys said you just wanted drinks.
You didn't say you wanted any.
Detective Takagi, we want ice cream, too.
Yeah, we wanted you to know
without us telling you.
You kids are hopeless.
Japan has the most punctual
trains in the world.
Ice cream!
Episode Preview
This is MPD Investigations!
Takabori Iwao!
You're under arrest for
robbing a jewelry store!
You're a bunch of uncultured swine.
How dare you interrupt my coffee time.
There's a checkpoint up ahead.
What will you do?
You can't just keep going forward.
Conan Kidnapped
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is
"Conan Kidnapped, Part One!"
Chimney
Next Conan's hint!
Wow!
A chimney!
Again in the next episode?
Don't miss the next episode.
You're involved in another case?
No fair, Conan!
It's not easy.