This is MPD Investigations!
Takatori Iwao!
You're under arrest for
robbing a jewelry store!
You're a bunch of uncultured swine.
Takatori Iwao (38)
Jewelry Store Robber
How dare you interrupt my coffee time?
Where's your accomplice?!
Where did you hide the jewels you stole?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Don't play dumb.
We know you entered a
Beika City jewelry store
at 8PM last night and stole 300
million yen worth of jewels.
Utsumi Tokuro (32)
Your accomplice is Utsumi
Tokuro, thirty-two years old.
Isn't he the partner you've
worked with several times now?!
Utsumi?
He's not my partner!
Huh?
So?
Were our faces caught on a
security camera or something?
W-Well, actually...
Hah.
In that case, we're done here.
No.
There's still plenty for
us to discuss, Takatori.
The Sleeping Kogoro.
Waiting until just before a store closes
to steal the freshly acquired expensive
jewels with guns as a pair.
That's your specialty, Takatori.
One more thing:
even though you always wore masks,
there was a damning piece of
evidence captured by the cameras.
You're sure, Mori-kun?
Of course, Inspector.
That is...
What?
Run!
To the rear exit.
Don't move!
Takatori, stop right—
Conan-kun?!
K-Kid?
Wh-What are you doing here?
I-It's too dangerous. You should go.
Stand up.
Don't move.
I'll blow the kid's head apart...
...like a crushed tomato.
Wait!
Takatori!
Conan-kun!
Damn.
Find them!
Hurry!
When the countdown reaches zero, use your
detective skills to produce an answer!
I'm kidnapped in the middle
of solving a mystery!
This is a first!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Conan Kidnapped
(Part One)
"Conan Kidnapped, Part One!"
Checkpoint
I see.
While I was sleeping—
Rather, while I was explaining my
reasoning, that's what happened.
But, Inspector,
we should prioritize rescuing the kid
over redeeming my name
after being interrupted.
I know that.
In addition to setting up checkpoints,
we'll reinvestigate yesterday's case.
What's going on?
There's a checkpoint up ahead.
What will you do?
Looks like you know where you want to go...
But you can't just keep going forward.
So the jewels that were stolen yesterday
had arrived just before
the store closed?
Shimazu Teruaki (55)
Jewelry Store Owner
Yes.
When I looked it up later, it became clear.
They were all expensive jewels
worth at least five million yen.
This is a major blow to the store.
I don't know what to do.
I assume your delivery
schedule was confidential.
Of course.
I hadn't even told my employees
until just beforehand.
Right?
Yamaga Setsuo (43)
Jewelry Store Buyer
Yes.
I have no idea who or how it was leaked.
But there's your supplier
and the delivery company.
Weren't there some things
you had no control over?
I-I suppose you're right.
Inspector, have you heard
from Takagi and Chiba?
Not yet.
The checkpoints haven't reported finding
the car we're looking for either.
Then we'll have to follow
this thread for now.
We've got to find a clue to the
kid and Takatori's whereabouts.
I'll have them investigate the jewelry
supplier and delivery company immediately.
Please do!
Huh?
Now that I get a better look, this
car doesn't have a navigator system.
Since we're on Kitahinode Road,
if you take the side road we passed earlier,
you'll end up on Nakahotoke Road.
Huh? Oh, I like going for drives,
so I remembered all the streets.
We can go shopping.
What?
The rope ladder.
I don't know what it's for, but you
dropped it while you were running.
I thought there might be a home
improvement store along a city road.
You're an interesting kid.
Shingetsu Bar
Kitahinode Shopping Center
Anyone. Is anyone here?
How about a public phone?
Are all the stores here closed down?
Crap!
He's coming.
He's going to run me over.
Do Not Enter
Huh?
Shingetsu Bar
Let's go.
What?
I didn't get a good look at those matches,
and I've already forgotten what was on them.
I promise I won't tell anyone about you.
Actually, if you take me with you, you'll
probably draw even more attention to yourself.
No matter how you look at it, you're
clearly not my dad or brother.
But maybe we should switch cars.
We could even get license
plates from another car.
I'm sure it'd be easy for you.
If only we could listen to the police radio.
We'd know how much they've figured
out and what they're looking for,
even the locations of the checkpoints.
What?
I didn't get a good look at those matches,
and I've already forgotten what was on them.
I promise I won't tell anyone about you.
Actually, if you take me with you, you'll
probably draw even more attention.
No matter how you look at it, you're
clearly not my dad or brother.
But maybe we should switch cars.
We could even get license
plates from another car.
I'm sure it'd be easy for you.
If only we could listen to the police radio.
We'd know how much they've figured
out and what they're looking for,
even the locations of the checkpoints.
What?
I won't say it again. Shut up.
Okay.
I wouldn't mind tying you up and keeping
you in the trunk until we get there.
There?
Where are we going when he
knows I'd slow him down?
Lulu Port
Underground Parking Entrance
He doesn't have all the
jewels he stole right now.
Which means...
he's most likely going to find the
rest of the jewels and his accomplice.
But...
Utsumi?
He's not my partner!
What happened?
What is that?
Listen up. Try to run, and I'll shoot.
If you don't want to die here and
get torn apart by stray dogs,
do as I say.
I just need to get a new rope ladder.
Okay, got it.
That way.
Stop there.
Is this the entrance to that chimney?
That's right.
I see.
So that's why you needed a rope ladder.
I was going to use it to climb down into
the chimney, but now I don't need to.
I've got you.
You want me to go in here?
Inspector Megure.
We found Takatori's car.
Where?
Nakahotoke Road
Shopping Mall
It was abandoned in the underground parking
lot of a shopping mall on Nakahotoke Road.
What about the kid?
So far nobody's reported
seeing Conan-kun or Takatori.
So they walked out of there?
Or did they change cars?
That must be it.
The question is, where did they go?
It's got to be wherever the
jewels and his accomplice is.
We'll have to broaden the area of our search.
Takagi, Chiba.
Yes, sir!
This is Megure.
Huh?
What? What does that mean?
Got it.
Thanks.
What is it, Inspector?
That was the local police.
They can't find Yamaga-san, the buyer
for the jewelry store that was robbed.
Yamaga Setsuo (43)
Buyer
What?!
Then...
Yeah.
It happened as soon as we started
checking their supplier and delivery company.
Inspector.
Let's head back to the crime scene.
Damn.
It must've happened then.
Now this is truly unexpected.
Are you listening, kid?
Come back in exactly three minutes.
If you're even a second late,
I'll throw this down there.
You must be joking.
If you do that, I'll get caught
in the smoke and suffocate.
Got it, kid?
Got it.
Damn.
This isn't my lucky day.
What exactly is going on?
We're about to investigate that.
Excuse me.
What are these?
I thought so.
W-Was it Yamaga?
Yes. It's probably what the thieves
paid him for leaking the information.
What?
If we looked into the supplier
and delivery company,
we eventually would've discovered that he
was the one person with all the information,
so he made a hasty escape.
That must be it.
I don't believe it.
Find him immediately.
A dead end?
It's the bottom of the chimney.
What?!
This man...
He's...
Utsumi Tokuro (32)
The jewelry robber's accomplice Utsumi.
The cause of death is
a whole body contusion?
Hey, what's he doing here?
Did you kill him?
Just the opposite.
He nearly killed me.
All right!
What a massive success.
Let's celebrate.
Not yet.
Huh?
We'll hand the goods over to him in
exchange for money, just like we planned.
We'll celebrate after,
two hours from now at that location.
Got it. You can count on me.
See you later.
He's still not here.
Utsumi!
It's been three minutes.
Come back.
I'll smoke you out.
Don't.
I'll be right back.
Damn.
It's covered in soot, so
there aren't any clues.
I won't be able to climb up there.
I have to head back.
Is this all?
Hiding them won't do you any good.
I'm not hiding anything.
I thought it was strange, too.
Didn't you steal 300 million
yen worth of jewels?
This clearly isn't enough.
It was him.
He talked him into it.
For less than half a share,
he agreed to kill me.
Idiot!
Who's "he"?
Mister, maybe you were betrayed.
What are you going to do now?
Are you going to...
Your job's over.
Keep your curiosity in check.
If you think I won't kill
a kid, you're dead wrong.
Where?
Where are we going?
He's slowing down?
What's happening?
What's he going to do?
Want to get out again, kid?
If you're lucky, you might be saved.
Huh?
Farewell.
Episode Preview
There's no mistaking it.
The body inside the chimney belongs
to Takatori's accomplice Utsumi.
Please.
Search for him immediately.
G-Got it.
You've forgotten my share.
And the fee you owe Utsumi
for hiring him to kill me!
Too scared to talk?
Conan Kidnapped
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is
"Conan Kidnapped, Part Two!"
Socks
Next Conan's hint!
Socks!
I finally understand how hard your life is.
Don't miss the next episode.
Mister.
Nothing's worse than being
interrupted while you're drinking.
What?