The police cornered jewelry store
robber Takatori Iwao in a warehouse.
Takatori Iwao (38)
Jewelry Store Robber
But just as I was beginning to explain
my reasoning as the Sleeping Kogoro...
What?!
Run!
Don't move!
Takatori, stop right—
Conan-kun?!
K-Kid?
Stand up.
Don't move!
I'll blow the kid's head apart...
...like a crushed tomato.
Wait!
Takatori!
Conan-kun!
Takatori kidnapped me so I could retrieve
the stolen jewels from the body of Utsumi,
the man who betrayed him.
Utsumi Tokuro (32)
Jewelry Store Robber
Is this all?
Hiding them won't do you any good.
I'm not hiding anything.
I thought it was strange, too.
Didn't you steal 300 million
yen worth of jewels?
This clearly isn't enough.
It was him.
He talked him into it.
For less than half a share,
he agreed to kill me.
Idiot!
Who's "he"?
Mister, maybe you were betrayed.
What are you going to do now?
Are you going to...
Your job's over.
Keep your curiosity in check.
If you think I won't kill a
kid, you're dead wrong.
Where?
Where are we going?
He's slowing down?
What's happening?
What's he going to do?
Want to get out again, kid?
If you're lucky, you might be saved.
Huh?
Farewell.
When the countdown reaches zero, use your
detective skills to produce an answer!
A kidnapping and someone
being pushed down a chimney!
Where is this case of betrayal headed?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Conan Kidnapped
(Part Two)
"Conan Kidnapped, Part Two!"
What happened to me?
Where am I?
Ow...
Huh?
Wh-What?!
You found Conan-kun?
What?
Where is he? Is he all right?
Beika Central Hospital
A chimney, huh?
Yeah. The body of his
accomplice Utsumi was there.
Takatori must've killed him.
No.
I don't think so.
He probably tried to kill him but failed.
Did Takatori tell you that?
I find that hard to believe.
But he said someone talked his accomplice
into trying to kill him for
less than half a share.
Someone...
Which means there's another accomplice.
No, a mastermind.
If that's true, then there's more
to this case than we thought.
Takagi, find the abandoned
factory immediately.
Confirm Utsumi's death and search
for clues to Takatori's whereabouts.
Chiba, determine who this "someone"
is from their mutual acquaintances.
Yes, sir!
Conan-kun!
Are you okay?
Ran-neechan.
Sorry for making you worry.
He's not badly hurt.
They're keeping him in the hospital
for a few days for observation.
That's good.
You didn't tell me anything, Dad.
Sorry.
I thought I'd make sure he was safe first.
I know. But I'm really glad
that you're all right.
Ran...
I feel tired.
Well, we should get going.
Right.
Look after him, Ran.
Got it.
Take care.
Conan-kun, is there anything you want?
Uh, I'm a little thirsty.
Then I'll ask a nurse if it's
okay for me to buy you a drink.
Okay. Sorry.
For what?
Just take it easy.
I'm really sorry, Ran.
The only clue I have so far is...
Shingetsu Bar
I need to stop Takatori soon.
In any case, I'd better check it out.
Huh? Conan-kun?
You can't be serious.
What?
Conan is missing again?
What should we do, Dad?
What if he's in danger again?
Find him and bring him back, Dad.
Jeez.
That busybody's always causing headaches.
Did something happen to Conan-kun?
You won't believe what happened.
Please help me look for him.
Got it.
Takatori's goals are most
likely acquiring his share,
and getting revenge on the
someone who betrayed him.
He talked him into it.
For less than half a share,
he agreed to kill me.
Idiot!
I'll stop him.
Stop the car.
Shingetsu Bar
Genji
This is it.
Shingetsu Bar
That's it.
It won't open.
Utsumi
Is this...
Utsumi Tokuro (32)
It's that man's apartment.
There's no mistaking it.
The body inside the chimney belongs
to Takatori's accomplice Utsumi.
However, we haven't found any
clues to Takatori's location.
Chiba is currently
looking into Utsumi's personal life.
This place is awful.
It's not that old.
This man...
He worked at the jewelry
shop Takatori robbed.
Jewelry Shop Shimazu
Buyer
Yamaga Setsuo
What's this?
Utsumi, Takatori, and Yamaga.
Who's the last person?
But I'm starting to see
what's really going on.
What's that?
What's this?
Today at 4PM, HK.
Hong Kong?
And it's at 4PM.
I've got an hour and a half.
What?
Takatori?
Sheesh. You're quite the
mischievous boy, kid.
Did you kill him?
I can see why you'd think that.
But he's not the one who betrayed me.
Then is the fourth man that "someone"?
Mister, wait!
Open the door!
In that case...
Crap.
Damn. What should I do?
I've determined Utsumi's address.
I'm on my way there now.
What?
Where did you come from?
Lucky me.
Taxi!
Drive, please.
Mori speaking.
Mister, where are you?
C-Conan?!
Chiba?
What?! You found Yamaga's
body at Utsumi's apartment?
What?
Don't be ridiculous, Conan.
Where are you?
Hong Kong?
What?
Yes. HK...
We believe he's getting on
the 4PM flight to Hong Kong.
I see. A plane.
Conan, are you on your way to the airport?
I am. Hurry, mister.
Thanks.
I appreciate the help.
Everyone head to the airport immediately!
Yes, sir.
So you've already exchanged the jewels for
cash and are off to an elegant overseas vacation.
You've forgotten my share.
And the fee you owe Utsumi
for hiring him to kill me!
Damn!
Will I make it in time?!
Too scared to talk?
Go to hell!
That's it.
Go!
Ow!
Mister, get down!
Now we're even.
You said you'd kill a child,
but you threw me into the median.
It wasn't a coincidence, was it?
You even slowed down.
Who are you?
Edogawa Conan.
I'm a detective.
You're a sharp kid.
Takatori.
You can't escape this time.
Inspector.
On the ground behind you
is the robbery accomplice
and suspect wanted for murder
and attempted murder.
Takatori's "someone" and jewelry store owner.
Arrest Shimazu Teruaki!
What was that?
What do you mean, Mori-kun?
I thought Takatori killed
his accomplice Utsumi
and the buyer Yamaga who
leaked the information.
No.
Utsumi died accidentally when he fell from
the chimney while trying to kill Takatori.
And Yamaga was killed
by none other than Shimazu Teruaki.
This is ridiculous.
What proof do you have?
He was trying to kill me.
I was defending myself.
Huh?
Mister, you smell like ramen.
Did you eat ramen somewhere? Or...
There were footprints at Utsumi's apartment
in the broth of a spilled instant ramen cup.
But the victim Utsumi's socks were clean.
That's right.
Which means it was...
Shimazu-san, could you
please take off your socks
so we can check them?
I refuse to accept this.
Why would I steal jewels
from my own jewelry store?
Because...
Because you insured the valuable jewels.
It'd be easy enough to figure out.
That and the jewelry store's
circumstances that required it.
Yamaga wasn't so much an accomplice
as he was forced to
cooperate with your orders,
without realizing he'd be framed
for leaking information and murdered.
You probably enticed him
by saying he could join you
and Utsumi in Hong Kong.
Cheers!
I'm impressed you noticed, Conan-kun.
The cup noodles were just
like someone else's crepe.
What?
Kogoro-no-ojisan told me about his
reasoning that was interrupted.
The Sleeping Kogoro.
One more thing:
even though you always wore masks,
there was a damning piece of
evidence captured by the cameras.
So that's what it was.
You're the great detective's assistant.
Actually, it's the other way around.
Well done, Mori-kun!
You finished your explanation
that was interrupted.
You've redeemed yourself.
Th-This isn't g-good!
Ow.
Something feels different this time.
Maybe you're hungover.
You're right. I did have too
much to drink yesterday.
Just yesterday, huh?
Oh, almost forgot.
Here.
Thanks.
Call Ran.
She's worried about you.
Right.
Mori Ran
Ran-neechan?
Conan-kun?!
Where have you been?!
What have you been doing?!
You'd better come straight home this time!
We need to talk!
Ran, I'm really sorry...
Episode Preview
Sorry.
Does this look like the arm you saw?
Yoshimura Reforestation Research Institute
Main Entrance
The same flowerbeds are on the roof.
If what I saw was on the roof,
then the body's buried up there.
There's one logical conclusion.
The culprit couldn't dispose of it.
In other words, the body should
still be hidden in this building!
High School Girl Detective Suzuki Sonoko
The next episode of Conan is "High
School Girl Detective Suzuki Sonoko!"
Rings
Next Conan's hint!
Rings!
Don't miss the next episode.
High school girl detective
Sonoko's in the next episode?
It's been a while.
I have a bad feeling about this.