I'm amazed we can see them so clearly.
It was sunny today, and
the weather's really good.
The humidity's low, so it's a little chilly.
All the conditions for clearly
seeing the stars are being met.
Really?
Conan-kun, you know something
about everything.
That's what my teacher told me.
You've got no dreams or
sense of romance, kid.
It's beautiful!
Watch out, Sonoko!
So, why are we stargazing?
The Milky Way refers to the
band of stars in the sky,
but Sonoko thought it was the name of a café.
She asked me which of their sweets are best.
What?
When she learned it referred
to the stars, she said,
"I'm so embarrassed! We're going stargazing
tonight!" and dug out her binoculars.
It seems like she's already bored though.
She's not looking at the sky.
Huh?
What is that?
What's wrong?
I-I saw a hand!
Someone's hand was in the flowerbed!
When the countdown reaches zero, use your
detective skills to produce an answer!
She coincidentally saw a pale hand and ring!
High school girl detective
Sonoko is fired up!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
High School Girl Detective Suzuki Sonoko
"High School Girl Detective Suzuki Sonoko!"
I don't see anything.
Calm down.
What happened?
Another hand grabbed an arm.
When they let go, it flopped down.
That was definitely the hand of a corpse.
Which way were you pointing the binoculars?
North.
I found the North Star and was
looking directly beneath it.
I'm sure of it.
Let's go, high school girl detectives!
Sonoko, that's south.
That way!
High school girl detectives?
This way is north of the park.
This is the place I saw.
They hid the body here.
There's no sign of any body.
I'm sure of it. These are the same flowers.
They must've buried it behind the flowerbed.
Who buried what?
A body...
Who are you?!
I work here.
Sasaki Hiroto (40)
Sasaki Studio Director
Who are you?
I see.
You build mannequins here.
Yes.
Here, have some coffee.
Thank you.
Minakami Rika (25)
Assistant
Sorry for interrupting your work.
It's fine.
Sorry.
Does this look like the arm you saw?
You must've gotten confused.
That's impossible!
But, Sonoko, were you able to tell at a
glance if it was a human hand or a doll's?
And could you have seen that flowerbed
from the top of the slide?
What do you mean?
Huh? What?
What?
You're right.
I can only see the clock.
Since you can't see it from here,
you couldn't see here from there.
But I know I saw something.
You can see the slide from the roof.
Hold on. A flowerbed, right?
Is there one on the roof?
Not here, but the same flowerbeds are on the
roof of the Yoshimura building behind ours.
Right, Rika-kun?
Huh? Yes.
This property used to be long and narrow,
but I split it with my friend Yoshimura.
The fastest way to his building
is to cut through mine.
I'm going to finish that rush order.
Thanks.
Sorry for interrupting you
in the middle of shopping.
We get some willful clients
sometimes. It's a hassle.
They suddenly called to modify their order.
I just had her come back.
His building is three stories, too.
His work means he's good
at designing flowerbeds,
so I had Yoshimura handle mine, too.
Yoshimura Reforestation Research Institute
Main Entrance
The same flowerbeds are on the roof here.
Maybe Nanae-san's not home.
Is this Yoshimura person not here?
He's in Hakodate for business.
He's repairing the front of
this building in the meantime.
She's Yoshimura's wife.
The three of us attended college together.
She always keeps her phone on her
when she goes out. That's odd.
I'm worried.
About what?
If what I saw was on the roof,
then the body's buried up there.
That's impossible.
The flowerbeds have the same design, but
since they're on the roof, the dirt's too shallow.
But I know I saw something.
Did you really see the body being buried?
N-No, but that hand definitely
didn't belong to a living person.
Excuse me.
Yoshimura?
Good timing.
There's something I wanted to ask you.
Yeah.
I tried calling, too.
I see.
Got it. I'm going inside.
We have spare keys to each other's buildings.
Yoshimura was worried about his wife.
She was supposed to call him now.
Does that mean she should be home?
Then maybe she really was...
You're jinxing it. Cut it out.
Right.
Nanae-san.
Her car's here.
Oh, I forgot.
The water pipe under the
street out front broke.
Then she can't move her car.
What time did it break?
Nanae-san complained about it over the phone.
Since it was after Rika-kun went
shopping, it must've been after 6:30.
She was all right until then.
Nanae-san.
Are you home?
This is Yoshimura's private living space.
What's this?
That's Nanae-san's phone.
The flowerbed's out here.
I can see the slide.
This must be the roof I saw.
There aren't any signs anyone buried a body.
But there's a spade over there.
Someone must've dug up
the dirt to bury a body.
Ouch...
It's too shallow to bury a body.
Does that mean the culprit
took the body somewhere?
You're still going on about that?
They'd transport it using a car.
It's the obvious choice.
They couldn't have done that.
The car's blocked in.
You're right.
By the time Sonoko looked
through her binoculars,
the road was already under construction...
Sonoko, what's wrong?
I've got it!
Got what?
The body of Yoshimura's wife
is still inside the building!
What?
The wife was murdered after
the director called her.
But the killer couldn't use the road.
When they failed to bury
the body in the flowerbed,
how did they dispose of the body?
There's one logical conclusion.
The culprit couldn't dispose of it.
Seriously?
In other words, the body should
still be hidden in this building!
Listen, miss.
Was the wife's body hidden there?
Huh?
Or over there?
Hold on, Sonoko-neechan.
Anyway, Ran.
Yes?
Let's find the body!
High school girl detectives, go!
Is she okay?
You can't hide a person
in there, Sonoko-neechan.
We didn't find anything.
We found something.
What?
The sleeping bag.
We found a man's, but not a woman's.
They put the body in there and hid it.
That's enough!
We searched everywhere
but didn't find anything.
She must've left on some urgent business.
I don't have anymore time for you.
This alleyway will take
you out to the street.
Just leave.
We're sorry.
I know I saw something...
...through these.
But we didn't find a body anywhere.
Besides, even if there was
a body, who killed them?
Well...
He's suspicious.
It's weird how he got so angry
and denied that there was a body.
Really weird.
You mean Sasaki-san?
Conan-kun, what do you think?
Conan-kun?
But, Sonoko, did Sasaki-san have any
time to go to the neighboring building?
He was alone in his office.
He must've snuck over.
If Minakami-san came down
while Sasaki-san was gone,
he would've been discovered immediately.
Besides, he knew the dirt
on the roof was too shallow.
Oh, come on.
Then it could be Minakami-san.
What does that mean?
What if on her way back from shopping,
she stopped at the neighboring
building and quickly took care of it?
But she was asked to return
to the studio by Sasaki-san.
I'm not sure she could do it that quickly.
Then she could've gone back later.
Sorry, but no.
She was working on the
third floor after that.
Sasaki-san would've found
her if she came downstairs.
I knew it didn't make sense.
Maybe the hand you saw belonged
to a mannequin and not a person.
I'm starting to think you're right.
Good night.
The ring...
Mannequins don't wear rings.
That must've been a human hand.
But where did they hide the body?
Where?
I'm sorry!
Huh? What is this?
Oh, the sign's backwards.
Sorry.
Here.
Now it's flipped back outside...
Backwards?
The back!
I never searched the back!
Conan-kun?
Are you thinking about Sonoko?
But like I said, we didn't find a body.
Even if Sonoko saw a real body,
neither Sasaki-san nor Minakami-san
could've hidden it.
It'd be different story if there were a
bridge connecting the two buildings though.
A bridge?
Yeah. I tried calling, too.
I see. Got it.
Huh?
I know what happened there.
And who did it.
You'll be in big trouble if
the director finds you again.
I'm glad I found you, Minakami-san.
I'm sure I saw a corpse and not a mannequin.
What?
Ran-neechan, remember what you said earlier?
It's a different story if there's a bridge.
Yeah, but...
I saw the shadow of the bridge
connecting the two buildings.
The culprit was able to return to the
flowerbed and dispose of the body.
I took this key without the
director's permission, so be quiet.
Thank you, Minakami-san.
You'd better hurry.
I will!
After killing the victim Nanae-san,
the culprit had to return
to the Sasaki building.
So they built a bridge
between the two buildings
so they could return quickly
using the scaffolding for
the Yoshimura building repairs.
But I didn't see a bridge.
They returned it to the roof
of the Yoshimura building when
they were finished with it
using some rope.
Then who did it?
The culprit is the person who was suddenly
asked to return to the Sasaki building.
The person who was able to hide the body
by the time we got to the roof
of the Yoshimura building,
and remove the bridge connecting their roofs.
Y-You mean...
That's right. The culprit
is Sasaki-san's assistant,
Minakami Rika-san!
The culprit must've been troubled since
they couldn't transport the body by car
like they planned because of
the water pipe construction.
Yes, it was troubling.
In their desperation, they remembered
the flowerbed on the roof,
but the dirt was too shallow.
Yes.
But why did the culprit grab the body's hand?
To remove the ring.
It looked really expensive,
so they must've wanted it.
If the culprit still has the ring on them,
that would be an important piece of evidence.
More importantly, where's the body?
A place we forgot to search.
Behind the scaffolding used for repairs.
We can get to the roof through there.
Sonoko-neechan and Minakami-san
are on the roof.
What?
The body would be found by
morning if they hid it here.
No. If the street repairs are
finished during the night,
they can take the car early tomorrow morning.
I see.
You certainly are a prodigy.
Seems that way.
Prodigiously stupid.
Oh, I'm not that astute.
So was Nanae.
Nanae? Yoshimura's wife?
Yes.
She didn't realize I'd stolen her husband.
Nanae paid to establish
her husband's company.
Naturally she assumed her
husband obeyed her whims.
Right? Don't you think she's stupid?
The pipes are in the way.
If only they'd come out a little farther.
And then there's Yoshimura.
His promises to leave Nanae were all talk.
Oh, don't move.
If I miss, it'll hurt even more.
H-Help me, Ran.
Now!
Sonoko, hang in there!
Ran!
I don't want to be a detective anymore!
I was negligent.
I'm sorry.
The culprit was unconscious
when she was arrested.
You can relax now, Sonoko.
Here.
Anyway, I'm impressed that
you figured out who did it.
You must be a genius to have
figured out that trick.
Someday I'd like to build a mannequin
of you striking a jaunty pose.
When you do, please name your mannequin
the high school girl detective!
We'll be hearing about this for a long time.
Yeah.
Of course.
Episode Preview
Okita
What?
It's like they were breaking in a new sword.
Furthermore,
this looks like the work
of a rather skilled swordsman.
Wh-Who are you?
Kendo Tournament of Love and Mystery
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "Kendo
Tournament of Love and Mystery, Part One!"
Box Cutter
Next Conan's hint!
A box cutter!
Impressive as always, Sonoko.
Don't miss the next episode.
Believing what you see is the first
step to becoming a detective.
Yup.