National High School
Spring Kendo Tournament
30th National High School Spring Kendo Tournament
Men!
Do!
Yes!
Shobu-ari!
Red, Hattori Heiji of Kaiho Academy!
Hattori-kun's in the finals now.
Yeah.
Since only Heiji won in yesterday's
semifinal team match,
they didn't make it.
But it seems like he should be able
to win today's individual match.
Y-Yeah.
As long as he's not here.
He who?
The boy he'll probably face in the finals.
Kyoto Senshin High School's...
...Okita Soshi-kun.
Heiji's lost to that
five-level strike before.
He's strong.
What? F-Five levels?
It only looked like one strike to me.
Whoa.
His opponent's being carried
away on a stretcher.
You just watch, Okita.
Today I'll settle the score between us...
...and tell Kazuha.
Time is the y-axis, and I'm the x-axis!
Inscribing love and cases
with deductive reasoning!
Heiji's rival Okita appears.
What will Heiji tell Kazuha?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kendo Tournament of Love and Mystery
(Part One)
"Kendo Tournament of Love
and Mystery, Part One!"
Toto Gymnasium
Thanks for coming today, Ran-chan,
to cheer him on.
No problem. It's Sunday. I didn't
have anything else to do.
The semifinal and final matches
will begin after lunch at 2PM.
2PM? That's two hours from now.
I'm going to get lunch with my friends.
You guys should get something to eat, too.
Okay.
What do you want to eat, Conan-kun?
We can go to one of the fast food
places we saw on the way here.
Should we go to the bathroom first?
Yeah.
No way.
The men's and women's bathrooms are crowded.
We won't be able to get in for a while.
Excuse me.
Do you know where the other bathrooms are?
The bathroom outside the north
entrance should be less crowded.
Thank you.
Hattori Heiji
Hattori texted me?
Kudo, want to get lunch?
Focus on your match.
Who texted you?
The professor.
Iori?
Have the preparations for Heiji-kun's
victory party been made?
Yes,
on the top floor of the Teito Hotel.
It's a surprise.
Don't let Heiji-kun find out.
I know.
So, do you think Heiji-kun will win?
I believe he'll make it to the finals,
but winning may be a bit difficult.
You mean my classmate Okita-kun?
Do we need to do something about him?
No.
He's one obstacle,
but there's another very strong
student in the tournament.
Really? I'm excited.
I'll be arriving soon.
Come meet me when I arrive.
Yes, Momiji-ojosama.
Nukitani Shido (43)
You're a Kyoto Senshin student, huh?
If you're planning to practice
here before your match, don't.
You'll damage the grass.
You'll get in trouble with the groundskeeper.
Excuse me.
I thought I heard a groan.
Did something happen?
Excuse me.
Where's the bathroom?
There it is.
Are you all right?
Hang in there!
It's no use.
He's already dead.
B-But...
His body's not that cold yet.
The killer might be nearby.
What?
We didn't pass anyone on the way here, right?
No.
Excuse me.
Did something happen after all?
"D-Did something happen?"
Mister, are you blind?
Yes, since three years ago.
What are you doing here?
I was listening to the sounds
of the kendo tournament.
The sounds?
The sound of feet striking the floor.
The sound of bamboo swords clashing.
The shrill vocalizations of the combatants.
I was listening to the sounds
that can be heard out here
and thinking about the past.
I used to practice kendo
when I was young, too.
Until four years ago, I used
to watch from the stands,
but since I lost my sight,
I started listening to the
tournaments alone here.
So, did something happen to someone?
A man's throat was cut. He's dead.
What?!
Th-Then the person who approached
me after I heard the groan
must've been the killer.
Did they ignore him because he's blind?
By the way, the killer said something.
"This box cutter is bloody and useless."
"Bring me another one."
You heard the killer's voice?
Yes.
I didn't hear the voice of the
person they were speaking to,
so they were probably on
the phone with someone.
Do you know which way the killer
went after they approached you?
Yes, that way.
Towards that bathroom.
Did anyone walk past you after that?
Yes, about two people.
I thought they went to the bathroom,
but after that, I don't think anyone
exited the bathroom and walked past me.
Then the killer...
is still inside that bathroom?
Okay.
Huh?
Don't, Ran-neechan!
What?
The killer told their accomplice
to bring them a new blade.
It sounds like they still
have another target.
It's better for us to call the
police and keep watch here.
I see. You're right.
There isn't a single defensive wound.
Detective Takagi?
Was he killed by someone he knew?
There's a dead man next to the
bathroom at the Toto Gymnasium.
You already sniffed out the murder, Hattori?
Yes.
Huh?
It's like they were breaking in a new sword.
Furthermore,
this looks like the work
of a rather skilled swordsman.
Wh-Who are you?
Who, me?
I'm Kyoto Senshin High School student,
Okita Soshi.
What?
Okita-kun?
The five-level striker Kazuha-chan mentioned?
You're really cute.
What's your name?
M-Mori Ran.
Ran-chan, huh? That's a nice name.
I live in Kyoto's Kamigyo Ward.
Let me know if you ever come to Kyoto.
I'll show you around.
Wh-Who is this guy?
He's exactly like Shinichi.
Ahem.
You said the person who attacked this
man might be a skilled swordsman.
How can you tell?
You mean you can't?
It certainly looks like he was
cut down by a single blow.
No, no. It's his clothes.
His clothes?
Yeah.
Navy blazer, gray pants, dark red necktie.
He's a kendo referee.
I see!
If he's a referee, he must be ranked.
I figured the killer must be pretty skilled
to kill a man like that with a single blow.
He really is just like Shinichi.
What? Have you fallen in love with me?
N-No...
Don't underestimate a samurai.
I can sense it.
No one can sense that, idiot!
Ow...
H-Hattori-kun.
And that's my friend's girl.
Stay away from her.
Who cares?
I haven't seen him around.
You sure have. Is there a problem?
Anyway, I just came to get some practice
swings in before my match against you.
I wasn't expecting you to be here,
much less caught up in a murder.
You came to do some practice swings, too?
Oh?
Too? Does that mean I'm on your radar?
Nah.
There's one other fighter I might lose to.
It sounds like the police are here.
Who's the old man?
Oh, he's...
What? You heard the killer's voice?
Is that true, sir?
Probably.
They called someone on the
phone and said the following:
Yasuoka Katsunari (78)
"This box cutter is bloody and useless."
"Bring me another one."
They said a bunch of other things,
but since they were speaking
quietly, I couldn't hear them.
According to you, after killing the
victim, they headed to the bathroom.
Later, about two people passed by you
and also headed to the bathroom.
But by the time Ran-chan and Conan-kun
came here and discovered the body,
no one's left the bathroom.
They must still be inside.
Yes.
Inside that bathroom
is the murderer.
I'll check the women's room.
Takagi-kun, check the men's room.
Got it.
Be careful.
The killer could still have a box cutter.
Okay.
It should be obvious who the killer is.
They'll be covered in blood.
Norimura Nenji (40)
Yokote Tsuneyuki (28)
What's going on?
The bathroom's available.
The toilet paper's almost out.
Sadamori Akane (31)
Be careful.
None of them...
...have blood on them?
Did something happen?
What?
N-Nukitani-san?
Nukitani-san!
Hold on.
That outfit. You're a referee, too.
In other words, you're ranked.
You sure you didn't kill him?
K-Kill him?
Nukitani-san's dead?
Yeah. Sliced his neck right open.
I-It wasn't me.
But it's true that you knew each other.
Yeah. We're both referees.
And we frequently faced
each other in tournaments.
But I'd never beaten Nukitani-san.
Hmm? You didn't kill him because
you couldn't win, did you?
O-Of course not.
I-I've never seen that man before.
Me, neither.
But there was a photo of you
with this man on his phone.
Right, mister?
Yeah.
See?
Uh, that's...
Come to think of it, Nukitani-san
often mentioned...
What?
...that he was being hit on by a student who
was a former Self-Defense Force official.
A student? Does that mean you
used to practice kendo, too?
Yeah, just for three years in high school.
Nukitani-sensei was the gym teacher
and adviser of the kendo club.
Then why did you say you don't know him?
B-Because I don't want to get
involved in the case, obviously.
By the time I walked past here, Nukitani-sensei
was already bleeding from his neck and dead.
Why didn't you report it to the police?
I had a lot going on. I-I was shaken up.
How about when you came to the bathroom?
I'm not sure.
I didn't have time to use the bathroom
this morning, so I was in a hurry.
It's possible I didn't notice Nukitani-san.
How about when you came?
I was in a hurry because I
was about to wet myself, too.
But I've never seen that man, and
I've never done kendo before.
I've got nothing to do with this case.
You're lying.
I saw you bragging to your lady
friend while you were having tea
at a café in Beika City with Nukitani-sensei.
You said, "I once won a kendo tournament."
You said, "I wish I could've shown you
the victory pose I struck after I won."
You were arguing with Nukitani-sensei
who was sitting next to you.
He asked you which tournament that was.
And I remember how the woman with you left
you there with a disgusted look on her face.
Well, you were arguing with him, too.
You said you'd kill yourself or someone
else if he didn't leave his wife.
Not to mention that ref
was arguing with Nukitani
after yesterday's final team match.
O-Oh, that?
When I said his refereeing
had been a little lax lately,
he said to hold my complaints
until after I'd beaten him.
It made me angry.
In other words, you all had a
motive to kill Nukitani-san.
Excuse me.
Can't we determine the killer
by asking this old man?
He heard the killer's voice.
Right, sir?
Well, actually...
None of them are it.
What?
I heard the hoarse voice of a man.
H-Hoarse voice?
Could it have been Nukitani-san's voice?
I-It was the victim's voice?
You heard the request for a new
box cutter before the groan?
Yes.
Then the person who brought
the box cutter killed him?
Well...
Who's the last person in
the victim's call history?
The victim's wife.
She's on her way here now.
What's going on?
It's possible the killer erased
themselves from his call history.
It's crazy back here.
What?
Behind the bathroom. Come check it out.
There's a bloody uniform and armor back here.
Maybe the killer was wearing them
when they killed Nukitani-san.
They're right between the
men's and women's bathrooms.
Isn't that a set of Kyoto
Senshin High School armor?
Come to think of it, after
yesterday's team match,
a first-year said our spare
armor and uniform were missing.
A spare set? Then it must've
been worn by a bunch of guys.
I wore that yesterday.
I was asked to practice with
someone before their match.
Then you must've met Okita then.
I did skip practice.
If it was worn by multiple people,
then it'll be difficult to determine
the killer's identity using DNA.
Yeah. Since the uniform can be worn over
your clothes, we can't expect much.
In any case, tell the tournament
organizer to put the matches on hold.
There's been a murder.
Got it.
Hold on! You can't stop the tournament!
What? Why not?
Because, well...
C-Could it be?
I-I...
There's something I've got to say
to her after I win this tournament!
Huh?
What?
We've got forty minutes
before the matches start.
We just need to solve the
case before then, right?
But...
In any case, you can't stop the tournament.
Hattori-han.
Maybe I misheard you,
but did you just say something
about winning the tournament?
I sure did. What about it?
I see.
Which means
you think you'll beat me?
Of course, idiot!
Then we don't need to wait until the match.
Why don't we settle this here?
I'd love to, cuckoo of Mt. Arigata.
Whoa, whoa.
Wait a minute.
He means Kazuha-chan, doesn't he?
That means if Hattori-kun
wins this tournament
he's going to confess his
feelings to Kazuha-chan?
Ran-chan sure is taking a long time.
If they don't hurry, the matches will start.
That's delicious. Fragrant, too.
Your tea is always fantastic, Iori.
Thank you, miss.
Episode Preview
Now that I've caught you,
you're not getting away.
It is I who has come to find you.
Onimaru
Th-This name...
A box cutter?
What about a change of clothes?
Sorry, Kudo.
This case is mine.
Kendo Tournament of Love and Mystery
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Kendo
Tournament of Love and Mystery, Part Two!"
Bamboo Sword
Next Conan's hint!
A bamboo sword!
Don't miss the next episode.
Nice to meet you.
You, too.
Win and confess your feelings!
What about the case?