National High School
Spring Kendo Tournament
Ran and I came to the Toto
Gymnasium to cheer on Hattori,
30th National High School
Spring Kendo Tournament
who traveled to Tokyo for a kendo tournament.
But while there, we came across a murder.
Furthermore, at the crime scene...
Wh-Who are you?
Who, me?
I'm Kyoto Senshin High School student,
Okita Soshi.
Hattori-han.
Maybe I misheard you,
but did you just say something
about winning the tournament?
You think you'll beat me?
Of course, idiot!
Then we don't need to wait until the match.
Why don't we settle this here?
Time is the y-axis, and I'm the x-axis!
Inscribing love and cases
with deductive reasoning!
Heiji and Okita, Kazuha and Ran.
How will the case and their contest end?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kendo Tournament of Love and Mystery
(Part Two)
"Kendo Tournament of Love
and Mystery, Part Two!"
Now that I've caught you,
you're not getting away.
Okita Soshi
Kyoto Senshin High
School Second-Year
It is I who have come to find you.
Come and get me.
My throat's wide open.
You're exposing your left shoulder.
The tip of your sword is low and to the back.
That's the Yagyu Shinkage-ryu
cleaving stance.
In that case...
That's the Tennen Rishin-ryu
hiraseigan stance.
Your blade is sharply inclined as you
aim for your opponent's left eye.
Shut up already.
If you want me to hit you, I will!
Hold it!
I wish I could keep watching,
but I can't let you mess up the
crime scene anymore than you have.
But...
if you can solve this case
by the time the matches resume,
then we won't have to cancel the tournament.
Really?
W-Wait, Sato-san.
Why not?
Those three are our only suspects.
Yokote Tsuneyuki (28)
Freelance Writer
Sadamori Akane (31)
Former JSDF
Norimura Nenji (40)
Tournament Referee
Besides, it seems like there's something
romantic about this tournament.
Hey...
E-Excuse me.
Could I go to the bathroom?
It doesn't look like I can use that one.
Sure.
We've already asked you all our questions.
In that case, excuse me.
I want to know...
Who is Hattori-kun's opponent?
Will he make it to the finals?
And will Hattori-kun be able to win and
confess his feelings to Kazuha-chan?
So, did you find a box
cutter in the bathroom?
No, not yet.
Then we'll be checking your belongings.
We'll start with your sword bag.
Okay.
Toto Gymnasium
Why did you bring your
sword bag to the bathroom?
The same reason as these boys.
I have a match tomorrow,
so I was going to do some practice
swings after using the bathroom.
I see.
Well?
We took apart the two swords
that were in the bag.
We didn't find a box cutter.
We were curious about this thing
that was in the bag though.
India Ink
India ink?
Why do you have this?
Since I'm a referee, I keep
a spare bottle on hand.
At this tournament, we paint
over the name of the losers.
30th National High School
Spring Kendo Tournament
Let's see.
Hattori-kun's opponent in the finals is...
Namakoshi Kurahiko
There.
It's Namakoshi Kurahiko-kun.
Hey, Namakoshi.
You should forfeit if your leg is cramping.
I-I'm okay.
I'll win in two more games.
But you're up against Kaiho
Academy's Hattori next.
Y-Yeah.
You've never beaten Hattori before.
S-Sounds like he'll make it to the finals.
So who's Okita-kun's opponent?
There it is.
They're representing Tokyo, huh?
Wait, what's with this guy?
His name sounds really strong.
There isn't a box cutter in my backpack.
Huh?
This chocolate is melted.
You're right.
Just the ones on the edge are really melted.
I-It's because I had it in
my jacket's inside pocket.
My body heat must've melted it.
Let's see.
Okita-kun's opponent is from Tokyo, so...
Ouch...
Excuse me.
Onimaru
Th-This name...
He's Okita-kun's opponent.
Are you all right?
Y-Yes...
Onimaru-kun!
Is it true that you're
forfeiting your final match?
What? Forfeiting?
Yes.
Something came up, and I must go home.
Wh-What came up?
The governor of Tokyo wants to
make me an honorary citizen.
He's at my home right now.
That's incredible.
I thought only the elderly
were given that title,
but it's not inconceivable since you've won
two consecutive national tournaments at your age.
I don't believe I'm worthy of that title yet.
I'm going home to reject his offer.
What a waste.
Don't worry. I'll participate
in my semi-final match.
It's someone I've been wanting to fight.
I see, I see.
Two consecutive national tournament wins?
That means he's the strongest
kendo swordsman in Japan, right?
And since he won't fight in the finals
even if he wins his semi-final match,
Winner
Okita Soshi - Onimaru Isamu
Hattori Heiji - Namakoshi Kurahiko
if Hattori-kun fights,
he'll win automatically!
What's Heiji doing?
His match is starting in twenty minutes.
It's from Ran-chan.
From: Mori Ran
Subject: No subject
Congratulations
Congratulations?
Heiji hasn't won yet.
Iori, how did it go?
As we expected.
Then let's watch as my future husband
takes first place.
Toto Gymnasium
You seem to like taking pictures.
Y-Yeah, I guess.
But the month's almost over,
and you've hardly taken any.
What?
Last month and the month before that,
you took close to 200 pictures.
I-I can do what I want!
Someone's calling.
I'm answering it.
Hello?
Huh? This isn't Tsuneyuki's phone?
Are you the girl who likes cutters
that Tsuneyuki said he met?
Cutters?
A-As in those big sailboats.
I've been into sailboats recently.
It's got nothing to do
with the murder weapon!
Didn't this old man hear the
culprit mention box cutters?
Now that I think about it,
I think they said "cutter."
Give me a break.
Cutter?
None of them had a box cutter though.
And we didn't find one in the victim's bag.
No.
Inside the bag we found a wallet,
a towel, a phone, a magazine,
an empty bag of stomach
medicine, and the box it came in.
There are still traces of that
medicine around his mouth.
His throat must have been
cut right after he took it.
But we have to find that box cutter.
You're right.
Did you hear any strange
noises inside the bathroom?
Like the blade of a box cutter being broken.
Speaking of noises, I heard
rustling outside the bathroom.
That was probably the sound of them throwing
the armor out the bathroom window.
I heard that, too.
I heard a scratching sound after that.
I heard it, too.
So did I.
In any case, they cut the throat of a
ranked swordsman with a single blow.
As another ranked swordsman,
that makes you the most suspicious.
B-But...
Don't be so sure.
If they were wearing this outfit,
maybe he thought they were a student in
the tournament and let his guard down?
O-Okita!
What do you think you're doing?!
That's evidence!
Yeah, but I was curious.
See?
There's blood on the thigh armor,
but none on the gauntlets.
And there's some on the butt of the skirt.
Don't you think that's weird?
You're right.
Oh, right. I knew I recognized this old man.
He was the referee for
my quarter-final match.
Really?
Yeah.
He crashed into the guy I knocked back with
my sword and was bleeding from his nose.
A nosebleed?
I remembered something.
It was the way he spoke.
The hoarse-voiced man who told their
friend to bring them another box cutter
spoke with a Kansai accent like you boys.
What?
Hey, you.
You said the victim's wife was on her way.
Is she bringing him a change of clothes?
Y-Yeah, she said she was.
What about a change of clothes?
Sorry, Kudo.
This case is mine.
Ten minutes until the semi-finals start.
We don't have a choice.
Could you have them cancel the tournament
and bring the tournament organizer here?
Got it.
Hold on.
In ten more minutes, we'll get
more than our money's worth.
More than our money's worth?
Does that mean you know who did it?
Yeah.
In that case, I've figured it out, too.
Since we can't find the murder
weapon, the killer is...
that old man!
Huh?
What? How'd he kill someone when he's blind?
Isn't it obvious?
That's a sword cane.
He senses his opponent like Zatoichi and
slashed his throat with a backhanded slice.
Well, sir? Am I right?
Say, "What an awful way to live."
Say it, and I'll forgive you.
Hattori, is this guy an idiot?
Sorry, it's just how he is.
So, do you know who did it?
No.
What I do know is the victim Nukitani-san
had some kind of beverage in his bag,
but after he was killed, someone took it out.
And that person who took it
was probably former Self-Defense
Force official Sadamori Akane-san.
What?
What makes you think that?
Because Nukitani-san took a powdered
medicine just before he was killed,
but he doesn't have a beverage on him.
Since the chocolate in
Sadamori-san's bag was melted,
she probably had a plastic bottle
containing a warm beverage inside it.
I-I told you, I was keeping the
chocolate in my inside pocket.
Then wouldn't all of it be melted?
Wasn't only the edge melted because
you poisoned a warm beverage
and were keeping it in your bag until
you could give it to Nukitani-san?
That's why you were hiding in the bathroom.
So you could erase the evidence
of your attempt to poison him.
I-It wasn't poison, it was laxatives!
I just wanted to inconvenience
Nukitani-sensei since he rejected my love!
I thought he'd be in the bathroom
so I came to check on him,
but he'd already been killed.
I retrieved the plastic bottle so
I wouldn't be suspected of murder.
It's true. You have to believe me.
I don't think she did it.
If she was in a kendo club, she'd
know how to put on a skirt.
It seems like the killer
wore the skirt backwards.
Then we're all innocent.
I used to practice kendo, too.
Did you really, Yokote-san?
You didn't even know you're not supposed to
strike victory poses during a kendo match.
What?
Isn't that right, Mr. Referee?
Huh? Yeah.
It says to in the referee's rules.
I see.
Nukitani-san pointed out your lie
when you bragged to your girlfriend about
striking a victory pose after winning a match.
You resented him for the
embarrassment he caused you.
Y-Yeah.
I thought I'd embarrass him, too, so I
followed and secretly photographed him.
Since that woman headed to
the same bathroom as him,
I thought they might be having a
tryst and came to check it out,
but this is how I found him.
I wanted to get out of here,
but those kids showed up,
so I was deleting my photos
of him inside the bathroom.
That's why you had hardly
any photos this month?
Y-Yeah.
But Yokote-san doesn't have a box cutter.
B-But, Conan-kun...
That's right.
I don't have a box cutter,
and I practiced kendo for a little
while, so I know how to wear a skirt.
Then why don't you put on that thigh armor?
Yeah, sure.
I think you cross these long straps in
the back, tie it in the front, and...
Done.
Wrong.
You're supposed to tie it under
the front to hide the knot.
What?
See? When you tie it correctly, you can
see the blood on the front of the armor.
In other words,
someone who knew how to wear the armor
deliberately put on the skirt backwards
to make it look like the work of
someone with no kendo experience.
Among the three of you, the only
one who'd need to do that is
the man dressed as a referee who's
obviously a ranked swordsman,
Norimura Nenji-san.
You're the only one.
No way!
You still haven't found Heiji?
But his match starts in
less than five minutes.
Ran-chan and Conan-kun are missing, too.
Maybe they know where Heiji is.
Kazuha-chan
Incoming Call
Kazuha-chan's calling.
If I tell her where Hattori-kun
is, she's sure to come here.
But until the crime is solved, we
can't afford to lose even a second.
B-But didn't the killer use a box cutter?
I don't have one either.
We had it all wrong.
What?
Is this what the victim
Nukitani-san actually said
while talking to someone on the phone?
"This cutter is bloody and useless."
"Bring me another one."
That's exactly right.
There's nothing strange about that.
In Kansai, a cutter refers to
what you call a dress shirt.
In other words, he said, "My nose bled on
my dress shirt and I can't wear it anymore."
"Bring me a new dress shirt."
That's it.
That's why Nukitani-san's wife is on his
way here to bring him a fresh dress shirt.
Yeah.
India Ink
Though even if his nose hadn't bled on it,
you probably meant to spill ink on
Nukitani-san's shirt so he'd come here.
B-But what about the weapon?
I don't have a blade.
You're carrying it.
Y-You're saying I cut a man's
throat with a bamboo sword?
Not an assembled sword.
If you sharpen a single piece of
bamboo and swing it horizontally,
the centrifugal force can
cut a person's throat.
I know someone who cut his
neck on a sword he parried.
It wouldn't stop bleeding.
Yeah.
The neck is the weakest part of the body.
The scratching sound heard in the bathroom
was you dulling the pointed
tip against the wall.
Which means...
Nukitani-san's blood must be stuck
to the inside of your sword bag.
We're going to check your bag.
Okay.
I'm sure you'll find some,
even though I tried to
wash it in the bathroom.
Sorry, Kudo.
I'm the star this time.
How frustrating.
But why a bamboo sword?
Wouldn't a blade have been better?
That bamboo sword was my son's.
What?
Two years ago, Nukitani-san
drove him to suicide.
He drove him to suicide?
Two years ago during this tournament's team
match finals, my son won a decisive bout,
but he accidentally struck a victory
pose, and his victory was invalidated.
Their opponents made a comeback,
and my son's team was eliminated.
My son had a strong sense of responsibility.
Unable to withstand the humiliation,
he took his own life.
That match was refereed by Nukitani-san!
But according to the rules,
it couldn't be helped.
Yes.
I thought Nukitani-san made
the right call, too.
Until I saw him ignore the victory pose
struck by Toto Senshin
High School's second man
during yesterday's team match finals!
I see.
Yeah.
Not only did he not invalidate his victory,
but he gave the student a pep talk!
He showed favoritism since
they're both from Kansai!
S-So I killed that biased man
with my son's bamboo sword!
He was probably holding this good luck charm.
A good luck charm?
That first-year second man
said he really wanted to win,
so I let him borrow my good luck charm.
This Hachidai Shrine charm's been
in my family for generations.
I've never lost while wearing it.
After winning his match, he noticed
it sticking out of his uniform.
While putting it back, he said he thanked
god while holding it with tears in his eyes.
Maybe you mistook that for a fist pump.
You're lying.
It's true.
Apparently the referee told
him not to cry during a match.
You're lying! You're lying!
You're lying!
Sh-She's so strong...
What are you doing? Hurry!
Hey, wait...
The charm...
Kazuha-chan, I brought him!
Ran... Ran-chan!
The match is over...
Victory by default!
What?!
Where have you been?
Heiji, you idiot!
Shall we go?
You're not going to meet Hattori-sama?
I'd like to meet my future husband
under better circumstances.
This is because you took your
sweet time solving that mystery.
You idiot, you slowed me down with
your nonsense about Zatoichi.
S-Solving?
Were you sticking your
nose into some case again?
I can't stand detectives.
What an awful way to live.
Episode Preview
Genta!
No one's escaped from my mini-patrol
car on these streets before!
I'm hungry...
Genta?
Genta-kun!
Damn. My tracking glasses aren't working.
His badge must be broken.
The Mini-Patrol Car Police's Big Chase
The next episode of Conan is "The
Mini-Patrol Car Police's Big Chase!"
Yumi and Naeko
Ready, and...
Next Conan's hint!
Yumi and Naeko!
Don't miss the next episode.
Once again, you're an idiot, Heiji!
This time you truly were an idiot.