Thank you so much for towing our car.
The mechanic will have an
easier time finding your car
Saeki Ryohei (24)
Goto Research Lab Assistant
at the station up ahead than
in the middle of the mountains.
We were planning on stopping there
to pick up groceries anyway.
Are you guys going camping?
Komada Takahiro (22)
Goto Research Lab Assistant
Our college lab always
goes camping together.
Goto Shoji (50)
College Professor
Our professor enjoys this kind of thing.
Really?
Komada-kun, you should get
a smartphone already.
Inoue Haruka (23)
Goto Research Lab Assistant
I will once this one breaks.
It takes too long to exchange data with you.
Try putting yourself in our shoes.
S-Sorry.
Oh, right.
This time we're also celebrating the
publication of our professor's paper.
Really? That's amazing.
The world must be ending if that perverted
drunkard is being recognized.
H-Haruka-san, he'll hear you.
He won't wake up. He always gets
like this when he's drunk.
Besides, it's not like you guys
like the professor either.
Hey, what are you talking about?
Maybe you all actually think,
"If only the professor would
disappear from this world."
Time is the y-axis, and I'm the x-axis!
Inscribing love and cases
with deductive reasoning!
The conversation inside the
car is rather ominous!
I hope nothing happens!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Murderous Carpool
"The Murderous Carpool!"
Thank you so much.
Excuse me. These are for you.
Oh, you didn't need to.
I wanted to thank you for your help.
Where's your friend?
Saeki-kun? He's over there.
Looks like we're leaving soon.
We should go.
Hey, wait.
Mori-san, are you all right?
Yes, thanks to you.
That's good.
Senpai, I'm putting some bags in the car.
Oh, thanks.
I was just thinking about
bringing the car around—
Professor?
Professor, are you all right?!
Damn! His phone's stuck!
Wh-What should we do?
What happened?
His phone was stuck.
The strap was caught on his neck.
He's dead.
Did something happen?
Ran, call the police.
G-Got it.
Everyone else, please get out of the car.
Don't touch anything at the crime scene.
It's wet...
Metropolitan Police Department
So after you returned from shopping
at this store you always stop at,
Goto-san, who had been sleeping inside
the car, slid down in his seat,
causing his phone strap to strangle
him, resulting in his death?
Yes, that's right.
Komada-san, you were the last
person to get out of the car.
Yes.
While getting out of the car, I thought
the air inside was a little cold,
so I draped a blanket over the professor.
Did you notice anything then?
Anything out of the ordinary?
Come to think of it, I didn't recognize
the air cushion the professor was using.
He said he'd hurt his back recently,
so maybe he bought it for today.
Inoue-san, you returned to the
car before entering the store.
That's right. I forgot my phone,
so I went to go get it.
But the professor was asleep.
He was snoring loudly.
Not that I went inside and
got a good look at him.
Isn't that right, miss?
Yes.
What?
You were with her?
Yeah. I dropped my wallet inside the van,
so I followed Inoue-san.
My wallet was on the seat,
so I left immediately,
but I did hear some loud snoring.
In other words, he fell
from his seat after that.
Finally, Saeki-san, you went to
the convenience store next door
to buy cigarettes after
you finished shopping?
Yeah, I'd just run out.
I returned to the car after
having a smoke over there.
We saw him smoking
cigarettes. Right, Ran-neechan?
Yeah. From right around here,
when we gave them our gift.
Come to think of it, did Goto-san
always drink that much?
Every time he'd be plastered
by the time we arrived.
He said he couldn't sleep unless he drank.
The professor took sleeping pills,
but he was a shallow sleeper.
Alcohol and sleeping pills, huh?
So that's why there aren't any signs of a
struggle even though he was strangled.
Anyway, it seems strange to me
that Goto-san's phone was found
open between the seat and headrest
when the body was discovered.
Goto-san was probably making a call.
A call?
It's possible the drunk Goto-san
tried to place a call,
but his hand slipped,
and his phone ended up in that gap.
Maybe it was that.
Do you know something about that?
I got a call from the professor
while I was shopping.
I thought he wanted me to get something,
Incoming Call
Goto Shoji
but he didn't answer, so I hung up.
11/17 Goto Shoji
I knew it!
Takagi-kun, investigate Goto-san's
call history immediately.
Yes, sir.
He got what was coming to him.
Haruka, behave.
Oh, Saeki-kun, but aren't you relieved?
Now that the professor who refused
to give you credits is gone,
you'll get that job you were promised.
That has nothing to do with this!
And, Komada-kun, the professor was
awfully verbally abusive towards you.
How did you really feel about him?
N-No way in particular...
Well, you complained that you wouldn't
forgive the professor for sexually harassing you!
That's right. That's why I feel relieved.
You must feel the same way.
Don't you remember what he
said last time he was drunk?
Listen up.
You idiots should shut up and listen to me.
I can change your futures
with a single word.
Th-That was...
Honestly, I couldn't take it anymore.
In the first place, he...
It sounds like all three of them felt
quite resentful towards the professor.
We'll need to investigate carefully.
Inspector.
Ah, Takagi-kun. How did it go?
We found a call placed to Saeki-san
in Goto-san's phone history.
We're certain it was during
the time he was shopping.
I see.
Mori-kun, did anyone approach
the car while you were here?
No. I was next to the car the
whole time since I was waiting
for the roadside assistance,
but I didn't see anyone.
If Goto-san died after placing the call,
and no one approached the car after that...
Then it must've been an accident.
Hey, don't you think it's strange?
C-C-Conan-kun, you shouldn't be in there!
Oh, sorry.
I dropped something inside the car.
Sheesh. You're always
barging into crime scenes.
Uh, so, what's strange?
The air cushion Goto-san was using.
Huh?
What's so strange about this?
They said he may have bought
it because he hurt his back.
Yeah, but there's a hole in it
even though it's brand new.
I was wondering about that, too.
I thought it had a hole because it was old.
And when I first looked at it,
the surface of the cushion
was slightly damp.
There weren't any other
wet spots on the seat.
Isn't that strange?
There's nothing strange about it.
It was damp because Goto-san
spilled liquor on it.
And the cushion was defective, so
a hole opened while he was asleep.
It made him lose his balance
and fall from his seat.
Well?! You got a problem with that?!
Now, now, Mori-kun.
This was definitely an accident.
An accident!
No, he's wrong.
Using that, they could've made the
victim fall, even from a distance.
But without any evidence, this
will be treated as an accident.
Is there anything?
Anything that would definitively
prove they did it?
What's that?
That's it!
Which means they must
still have it on them...
The conclusive evidence the
culprit used in their trick!
It's probably safe to assume
there was no foul play.
Yes. They seem to have motives, but
those three couldn't have killed him.
Excuse me.
How long do we have to wait?
We'd like to leave now.
We have people we need to call.
Don't worry.
After reviewing the crime scene,
all uncertainties have been—
It's become clear to me that this is a
murder made to look like an accident.
Goto-san didn't accidentally
fall from his seat.
He was made to fall by the culprit.
Didn't you just say none of
them could have killed him?
At first, that's what I believed, but
after examining the inside of the car,
I realized the trick the culprit used.
H-Hold on.
You think one of us killed him?
We were together the whole time.
We couldn't have killed the professor,
who was sleeping in the car.
It's not impossible.
All they needed to do was
slip the phone with the strap
through the gap between the headrest
and seat towards the back.
Even if that's true,
wasn't it a coincidence that
Goto-san fell from his seat?
The culprit set up what you might call
a timing device that caused Goto-san
to automatically fall from his seat
even if no one else was present
using the rubber air cushion and dry ice.
Dry ice sublimates from a
solid directly into a gas,
causing its volume to expand
by a factor of 800.
The culprit packed said dry ice inside
the air cushion and hid it on the seat.
As time passed, the cushion
began to expand like a balloon
to a size large enough to cause
Goto-san to fall from his seat.
The cushion was damp because the
low temperature of the dry ice
cooled the moisture in the air,
causing it to condense on its surface.
The cushion continued to
expand after Goto-san fell,
and once it could no longer
contain the gas, it burst.
Naturally, they experimented many times to
determine the exact amount they should use,
so it would all have turned to gas
by the time the body was discovered.
That would certainly leave no evidence.
But isn't it difficult to transport dry ice?
That's why the culprit used a certain
piece of outdoor equipment.
That's it! A cooler!
Yes.
Using a cooler allowed the culprit to
preserve the dry ice until they needed it.
Isn't that right?
The individual with the cooler
who used this trick...
Komada-san!
You created an excuse to remain in the
car and passed the open phone with strap
through the gap beneath the
headrest towards the back.
Then you draped a blanket over Goto-san's
legs in order to hide the dry ice-filled cushion,
and went shopping as though
nothing had happened.
I'm sure you calculated how
large the cushion would expand,
and how long it would take to
burst and bought one accordingly.
Wh-Why me?
Surely you don't think I did it just
because I approached the professor.
And you said I passed the professor's phone
though the gap and over the back of his seat.
Have you forgotten that the
professor called Saeki-senpai?
If his phone were back there,
he couldn't have called anyone.
I never said it was the professor's
phone that was used.
Huh? What are you—
I'm saying you're the one
who called Saeki-san.
You swapped out your phone for Goto-san's
and used it to fabricate your alibi.
In other words, the phone attached to the
strap that strangled Goto-san was yours.
That's why you behaved strangely.
Conan told me that when you saw
Saeki-san return to the van,
you returned to the car while carrying
heavy bags full of groceries.
Looks like we're leaving soon.
We should go.
Hey, wait.
Senpai, I'm putting some bags in the car.
Oh, thanks.
I was just thinking about
bringing the car around—
Professor?
Inoue-san, you were with him.
Didn't you wonder why he didn't
have Saeki-san bring the car
in front of the store instead
of carrying so many heavy bags?
Well, yes.
But, Komada-san, you went out
of your way to carry the bags.
Why is that?
There's one reason you returned.
It's because you needed to discover
Goto-san's body with someone else,
approach the body first,
and swap out your phone, which
you used for the murder,
for Goto-san's, which you used
to fabricate your alibi.
As the only other person with
a flip phone like Goto-san's,
only you could've used this trick.
If you wanted to save Goto-san,
you simply needed to pass the
stuck phone through the gap.
I knew something was off when you
deliberately removed the phone from the strap.
You probably planned to reattach it,
but you gave up on the idea when Conan and
I entered the car unexpectedly quickly.
You're making this all up!
Even if it was dry ice, there's
no evidence it was used!
If I'm the culprit, show me the evidence!
I could say the same thing.
What?
Detective Takagi, how did it go?
I didn't find the damage you
described on Goto-san's phone.
Huh? Damage?
And aren't these pieces of plastic?
Yes, they were stuck to the blanket.
When Goto-san fell, the
phone dangling over the back
struck a metal piece of the seat.
The shock sent those pieces
of plastic flying.
Komada-san, using an old
phone came back to bite you.
As we just heard in
Detective Takagi's report,
Goto-san's phone was not damaged.
Which means a different phone
was used in the crime.
You have that phone on you right now.
One with dents that should
match those pieces of plastic.
Damn it!
Komada, why would you do this?
Why?
You probably had no idea.
The professor's paper that won the award...
It was originally my thesis.
The professor stole my research topic.
What? Is that true?
Naturally, the professor threatened me.
He told me to keep my mouth shut if I wanted
to keep doing research at the university.
You should've told someone.
I had a dream!
Since I was a child, I dreamed
of becoming a researcher!
But... But that man...
Professor, this isn't what you promised!
Why can't I go to grad school?
Don't worry.
I'll help you get a job at some company.
A-A job?
Even if I can't stay here, can't I at
least go to a lab at another university?
Have you forgotten?
I have a lot of influence in this world.
I can change your future with a word.
You were never meant for research.
That's all.
It really is a shame.
I ignored my research to repeatedly
experiment and perfect this method.
I was pretty confident it would work.
But I messed it up in the end.
I guess I wasn't a good enough
researcher after all.
If you didn't know where we were going,
you should've followed the police.
We came this way on the way here.
I'm not doing something as pathetic
as asking the police for help.
But we're lost now.
We even have a GPS! How
does this even happen?
Because it's giving we weird directions.
Hey, look at that.
We made it out.
I knew my instincts were right.
Huh?
Weren't we just here?
We won't be getting home for a while...
Episode Preview
I'm hungry. Where are we?
Wh-Who are you?
Hello, Inspector Megure?
Wh-What? You're staking out
a counterfeiting operation?!
I-It's money!
You violated the contract, signore.
Why don't you return all the notes you took?
The Disappearing Detective Boys
The next episode of Conan is
"The Disappearing Detective Boys!"
Glazed Rice Dumplings
Next Conan's hint!
Glazed rice dumplings!
We're finally home.
Don't miss the next episode.
Thanks for driving...
But it's the next day.