Yaiba Kick!
Kamen Yaiba!
Cut! Okay!
I was worried since it was
raining on and off this morning,
but I'm glad we came to watch the show.
Yaiba's action is super cool even in the mud.
I know. It's so intense.
Tatsumi Masaya (26)
Hey, what are you doing?
Don't get angry, Genta-kun.
As another Yaiba fan, I understand
his desire to watch from the front.
Y-Yeah, but...
Are you worried about him?
Yeah.
Yaiba!
Yaiba, over here!
I'm not sure what's so interesting,
but at the very least, he
doesn't seem to be a Yaiba fan.
Where are we?
I'm hungry. Where are we?
What happened to us?
Huh? Conan-kun's missing!
Is it Conan-kun?
Wh-Who are you?
What?!
It's that man from before.
Time is the y-axis, and I'm the x-axis!
Inscribing love and cases
with deductive reasoning!
Something happened at the Yaiba show!
Where did you guys go?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Disappearing Detective Boys
"The Disappearing Detective Boys!"
2 hours prior
I'm not sure what's so interesting,
but at the very least, he
doesn't seem to be a Yaiba fan.
Cut! Okay!
We're moving locations! Hurry, please!
They're changing filming locations.
What's next?
Over there.
Let's hurry.
Conan-kun, Ai-chan, let's go.
Huh? Okay.
Huh? He's gone.
What?
What should we do?
Conan-kun!
We're leaving you behind!
Haibara-san, hurry!
Okay, fine.
We'll be right there.
That was fun.
Yaiba was awesome.
I'm so hungry.
Beika Dumplings
All right! Dumplings, please!
Oh, Genta-kun.
You're still thinking about him?
Yeah.
Nakama Toshie (75)
Thank you.
Someone help!
Oh, no!
That's ten thousand yen!
Catch it!
Genta-kun!
Catch that bill!
Wh-What's going on?
Genta-kun, catch it!
Huh?
Hey, wait!
I found it!
Found it!
No way!
Why?
There should only be one.
Let me see those.
Are these...
Yeah.
They all have the same serial number.
Which means these are...
What? Counterfeit bills?!
A few counterfeit bills were
discovered in the city recently.
Rumor is, an international criminal
organization is involved.
That must be it.
Which means...
That grandma is a counterfeiter?
What?
Then I doubt she would've
asked us to catch it.
Yeah. This one's different.
Conan-kun, it's a little damp.
It's probably wet from the rain.
This is orange juice.
It must be that.
A phone?
What does this mean, Conan-kun?
While someone was drinking some juice,
a strong breeze blew away
their counterfeit bills.
They spilled their juice then.
They rushed to gather them up,
but couldn't get them all,
and left without realizing
they'd dropped their phone.
Sounds about right.
Wow.
Way to go, Conan-kun.
This is a major incident.
But that means...
Yeah. Eventually the counterfeiter will
realize what's missing and come back for it.
What should we do?
Isn't it obvious?
The Detective Boys will apprehend him.
It's a stakeout!
Whoa, whoa.
I think we should call the police.
I'm going to call Inspector Megure.
Stay with them.
Got it.
Hello, Inspector Megure?
Metropolitan Police Department
Ah, Conan-kun.
Wh-What? You're staking out
a counterfeiting operation?!
Bella Hikifune (38)
Now to send these to the police.
Hey, wait!
Ai-chan, hurry!
She's getting away!
Please hurry!
Jeez...
What? Where did they go?
Tailing the culprit.
Huh?
Maybe she took a turn.
This way?
That way?
Let's go that way.
Huh? Hey!
She's not here.
Did she go that way?
It's a dead end.
Let's go back.
Yeah.
When did they get there?
Buongiorno, little children.
Playtime is over.
Hand over your phones.
That's it. They caught us then.
And made us inhale some kind of anesthetic.
Yeah, that's right.
Almost there.
I'm free!
We did it!
Me, too. Untie me.
You got it, bro!
Did you really think I'd say that?
What?
There's no way we'd untie you.
At first we thought you were a Yaiba
fan, but you're super suspicious.
You heard them.
And we don't know where we are.
Huh? Something's not right.
That tower...
I couldn't see it from here before.
That's it. There was a
container here earlier.
Damn it! Where are they taking us?
Taking us?
We're moving?
What?!
Anyway, where did they go?
The number you have dialed is either outside
the service area or currently powered—
What's going on?
Haibara, guys. Can you hear me?
Can you hear me?
Conan-kun!
Conan-kun! Conan-kun!
Damn it. I can't determine
the location of their badges.
Guys!
Are you guys okay? Where are you?
H-Hey!
It's that orange juice.
I knew it.
You're the one who lost his
counterfeit bills in the wind.
Wh-Who are you kids?
We are...
...The Detective Boys!
I don't know where we are, but we're moving.
We're trapped in here with
that man you found suspicious.
The counterfeiter.
You're what?
You're moving? And trapped?
So that's how it is.
Wow!
It's money!
They're all ten thousand yen bills!
Just how much is there?
How much eel can I buy with this?
None.
They're all counterfeit bills.
What?
Tatsumi Masaya
Why don't you explain yourself, Tatsumi-san?
That's it!
We can't see outside from here, so
we don't know where we've traveled.
The man trapped in here with us doesn't
seem to know where we're going.
Come to think of it...
It's those footprints.
In that case...
Crap! The footprints are disappearing!
Damn. Where did it go?
Guys, answer me!
Hit back!
We're in here, Conan-kun!
We're in here!
Damn. They're in that one?
If they keep heading this way...
They'll reach the harbor?
Are they traveling overseas from there?
Why don't you talk already, Tatsumi-san?
Why is this happening to you?
What does it matter? They're
just some counterfeit bills.
I just took a few so I
could pay off my debts.
Conan-kun!
We're leaving you behind!
Haibara-san, hurry!
We'll be right there.
All right!
Huh? Hey, wait!
Damn. Where did they go?
You violated the contract, signore.
Why don't you return all the notes you took?
That's why she was at that park.
Edogawa-kun, did you get all of that?
Yeah. She's probably a mafiosa.
Mafiosa?!
Probably one specialized in counterfeiting.
Am I wrong?
No.
But I was just an underling.
I got sick of being worked so hard.
We stopped.
It stopped?
Crap. Is the ship leaving?
We're being lifted?
That must be it.
Damn. Which one is it?
Haibara, guys!
What's going on?
It's like an elevator.
I feel sick.
Could it be?
Could it be? Could it be what?
Water?
Wh-What's wrong, guys?
Answer me!
Haibara! Genta!
Mitsuhiko! Ayumi-chan!
Answer me!
Bravo. Toys these days sure are amazing.
I called the police on the way here.
You can't escape now.
Oh, really?
Let go!
We're MPD Criminal
Investigations Division One.
You must be Bella Hikifune,
the owner of this ship.
We were told your ship was
full of counterfeit bills.
We'll be searching it.
We've also been informed that you've
kidnapped and imprisoned the child witnesses.
Oh, how scary.
But as exceptional Japanese policemen,
surely you realize this
isn't a Japanese ship.
If you don't find anything, this will
be a major international incident.
How does that sound?
W-Well...
You're welcome to search it if you'd like.
If you discover a single piece of evidence...
The evidence is right here!
Conan-kun?!
Look at that!
What?
What is it?
Keep it up, everyone!
Damn! I can't do this!
I'm at my limit!
H-Help!
I can't swim!
Guys. They're all right.
I-I was so scared. I was so scared.
We did it. We've been saved.
I'm hungry.
Could you come with us to the station?
Oh, I'm just the owner.
The crew must've done this on their own.
Hey, let me see your wallet.
You've got a ten thousand yen bill, right?
I don't have any counterfeit bills.
Not that. The old woman's
ten thousand yen bill.
That's it.
What?
But doesn't that make you a thief?
You're one cheap mafiosa.
More importantly...
If you've touched the other counterfeit
bills with those hands...
But they're soaked. The
evidence must be ruined.
You mean these?
Shall we compare your fingerprints?
No, there's no need for that.
Wow. Ai-chan, when did you grab those?
You must've been watching
while you were following her.
Yeah.
Tailing the culprit.
Really?
You really are amazing.
No wonder you're a member
of the Detective Boys.
That's not much of a compliment.
They can hear you.
I don't care.
Beika Dumplings
The ten thousand yen note was
returned to the old woman,
who generously thanked the Detective Boys.
So good!
Episode Preview
Who was that man?
Which means the weapon disappeared later.
Did someone take it?
We should be focusing on the
certainty of their alibis
when determining the culprit.
This time I'll run down the culprit.
So that's how it is.
A Day Without Conan
The next episode of Conan
is "A Day Without Conan!"
Coat
Next Conan's hint!
A coat!
Nom nom.
Don't miss the next episode.
The Detective Dumplings.
Don't call us that.
I don't like it.
I think it's nice.