We apologize for the inconvenience
We are working as safely as possible
We appreciate your cooperation
No Authorized Access
Time is the y-axis, and I'm the x-axis!
Inscribing love and cases
with deductive reasoning!
The Detective Boys were at the crime scene,
but Conan doesn't seem to be around!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
A Day Without Conan
"A Day Without Conan!"
The victim is a serial blackmailer
named Unmo Sadakazu-san.
Unmo Sadakazu (30)
There's no weapon at the crime scene,
but he most likely died instantly when he
was hit over the head with a metal pipe.
But, Mitsuhiko...
They're finished. I'll call you back.
These hot springs are great!
Compared to how cold it is in
Tokyo, this place is paradise!
Come on, kid!
Let's stuff ourselves!
The old man got free
hotel vouchers somewhere.
Gift
Mori Kogoro-sama
Congratulations on being selected
This invitation entitles you to free lodging
Ran was unable to come, so
he made me come with him.
So the estimated time of death
is today between 3:30 to 4:30.
It's four.
That's when the tall man wearing
sunglasses and a mask came out.
And you kids were watching this construction
site from across the street then?
Yes. We saw a woman in trouble.
It was regarding her grandson
who lives with her.
Kubo Hisae (73)
Housewife
Not only can he not hold down a job,
but lately he's being going out in the
evening and staying out until morning.
That idiot is out gallivanting around
when he doesn't even have a job.
We should catch him while he's out
fooling around and advise him to stop.
Yeah!
It's not like we're meddling.
I feel bad for that woman.
I didn't say anything.
He should be going out soon.
Hide!
That's a huge dude...
The suspicious man...
...came running out after about five minutes.
He ran away.
Did something happen?
We were curious about what
happened, but then...
Kubo
the grandson in question came out.
Kubo Yukihide (19)
Hisae's Grandson
When we followed him,
we discovered he was actually working.
He was working nights.
He's still a trainee.
He planned to tell her once
he became an employee.
By the way, who was that man?
The man you kids saw certainly
sounds suspicious,
but without knowing his appearance or age...
But he was really tall.
There are lots of men like that.
Unmo-san himself looks to
be almost two meters tall.
Inspector Megure, is it safe to assume the
suspect was being blackmailed by Unmo-san?
It seems Unmo-san had no
relationship with his neighbors.
The culprit was being blackmailed
by that Unmo guy, too.
So they lied about paying him, asked
to meet him here, and killed him.
Most likely, yes.
Huh?
Incoming Call
Edogawa Conan
Conan-kun.
Hello?
There's something bothering me.
There was no weapon at the crime scene, right?
Right. We believe the culprit
took it with them.
But the man who fled wasn't
carrying a metal pipe, right?
You're right.
Perhaps he was hiding it under his coat.
Got it. I'll be back tomorrow afternoon.
Let's find the culprit then.
All You Can Eat
All You Can Drink
Experience the flavors of winter
with our hot pot and seafood dishes
Got it.
Ow!
Mister!
We apologize for the inconvenience
We are working as safely as possible
We appreciate your cooperation
No Authorized Access
What?!
You can't come back now?
Hospital
Yeah, sorry. Stick with the police
and tell me everything you learn.
Got it.
Unmo
Found it.
Client List
It's a list of the people
he was blackmailing.
Ten men and one woman, huh?
Let's split up.
We'll join you.
We can't let you do that.
We saw the culprit.
If we encounter the suspect, we
may be able to recall something.
It doesn't make sense.
What happened to the metal pipe?
Perhaps he was hiding it under his coat.
If that's true, then they would've
noticed him running unnaturally.
Which means the weapon disappeared later.
Did someone take it?
We're sorry to have bothered
you on your day off.
Sadabetsu Kenji
Daimonji Iwao
Samei Rika
That just leaves Samei Rika-san, the woman.
Maybe that person was
actually a masculine woman.
It's not her.
Someone who makes such cute
drawings couldn't kill a person.
And she's hardly a masculine woman.
Samei Rika (28)
Illustrator
She's frail and small.
Samei Rika-san, where were you at four yesterday?
I was...
Oh, Kuniko-san.
Yes?
I was in my apartment
yesterday afternoon, right?
Tago Kuniko (36)
Rika's Neighbor
What? You started working at around 3.
Did something happen?
No, thank you.
I see.
Well, see you later.
Samei Rika-san 28
Illustrator
According to neighbor Kuniko-san (housewife)
started working around three
We didn't get any hits.
Then let's try calling the other group.
We're on the phone with them right now.
What? I see. Got it.
Everyone they spoke with had an alibi, too.
What?!
All the suspects are innocent?
We're stuck.
Then who killed that guy with the dumb face?
Dumb face?
The victim Unmo Sadakazu-san didn't
have a particularly dumb face.
That's because you didn't
see the body, Conan-kun.
Hold on.
Hello, this is Mori.
What? Are you feeling better?
Yeah. Could you put Detective
Takagi on the phone?
Very well. I can't refuse a
request from you, Mori-san.
I see.
Were his front teeth knocked
out when he was hit?
No, they weren't.
Yamamoto Dental Clinic
Unmo Sadakazu
They're dentures. We found
them in his apartment.
He was going to have them put
back in at the start of the week.
So they were out since before
he arrived at the crime scene.
I was just curious. Sorry
to have bothered you.
Anyway, the real problem is
all the suspects are innocent.
Why can't we find the man who
killed this person and fled?
He was wearing a button-down shirt.
Could it be?
But...
Unmo
They're making a new list of suspects?
So we're back to square one.
The estimated time of death?
I told you, it was around four.
That's when you guys saw the
tall man running away, right?
What time did the police determine it was?
Between 3:30 and 4:30.
Hospital
Until 4:30, right?
Yes. What about it?
So that's how it is.
He was wearing a button-down shirt.
Could it be?
But...
The estimated time of death?
I told you, it was around four.
That's when you guys saw the
tall man running away, right?
What time did the police determine it was?
Between 3:30 and 4:30.
Hospital
Until 4:30, right?
Yes. What about it?
So that's how it is.
Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko
In Call
Call Ended
That explains everything.
Hospital
Why we can't find the tall man,
why the weapon is missing,
and the victim Unmo-san.
I even have some idea of
why the culprit did that.
The problem is...
Who is that?
Hospital
According to Mitsuhiko, all
the suspects have alibis.
No, are we sure that's true?
Mitsuhiko, sorry. I want you guys
to split up and do something for me.
The first is to confirm her
alibi with the witness.
The second is a treasure hunt.
Got it. We'll give it a shot.
He's ordering us around
without even explaining why?
He treats us like errand boys.
Errand boys?
We just need to solve the case, right?
And Conan's always making
us run errands for him.
But this time he gave us
orders over the phone.
Why not? It's up to us to find
the key to solving the case.
You're right.
Let's go. We'll start with the treasure hunt.
Yeah!
I guess I'll talk to the witness.
But I'd better give Edogawa-kun
a piece of my mind first.
Did I visit my neighbor Samei
Rika-san's apartment yesterday?
No, I didn't.
Then how did you know she
started working at three?
Oh, because she came to ask
me for something yesterday.
I have a job I need to finish by tonight,
but I'm being followed by a strange fan.
If someone knocks on or
yells outside my door,
could you tell them I'm out?
So you want me to send them away.
You got it.
Thank you.
Now I can focus on my work.
She made her request and went back
into her apartment around three.
She was definitely working, right?
Fortunately, no weirdos showed up.
Oh, Kuniko-san.
Yes?
I was in my apartment
yesterday afternoon, right?
What? You started working at around 3.
Did something happen?
No, thank you.
In other words, we don't know if she was
actually in her apartment after three.
Yeah, but she looks nothing
like the tall man.
That's not important anymore.
Just tell me already!
What treasure are we looking for?
He just said to thoroughly search
the area around the crime scene.
What's that? It's waving.
What?
Is this...?
This belongs to the culprit!
I understand why they got rid of the weapon,
but why did they leave their
coat and other belongings?
Let's call Conan-kun.
Yeah.
This must be the treasure.
Conan will be so surprised.
It's me! We found them.
The metal pipe and coat, right?
What?!
How did you know?
Call the police.
We will, but what does this mean?
I made him tell me.
Edogawa-kun's deduction.
Take them back and have
them examined immediately.
Conan-kun figured it all out?
Is he back?
No.
He figured it out based on
the information we gave him.
Come with us.
Conan-kun isn't with us, though.
This time I'll run down the culprit.
You?
I'm more than just an errand boy.
It's still bothering him, huh?
There's nothing wrong with
having some backbone.
The other suspects' alibis are rock solid,
but you can't say the same,
can you, Samei Rika-san?
My neighbor Kuniko-san can—
Wait.
Your neighbor didn't actually see you.
You're right, but it doesn't
matter if I have an alibi.
Wasn't Unmo-san killed by a tall man?
We never would've found him.
Huh?
Not the man we saw.
What?
Because that man is...
He made it just in time.
Who are you?
Kogoro-no-ojisan is incredibly resilient.
Even the doctor was surprised!
I'm all better now!
You just had too much to eat.
More importantly, why
couldn't you have found him?
Tell them, Mitsuhiko.
Me?
Okay.
The tall man wearing sunglasses,
a mask, and coat
Tall man
Sunglasses
Mask
Coat
According to Inspector Megure,
more than two meters tall!
Warning: Has a metal pipe
Seen
Estimated time of death between 3:30PM
and 4:30PM (according to forensics)
Stream near park
Discovered coat wrapped around metal pipe!!
was Unmo Sadakazu-san himself!
What?
Nice one.
Really?
Hold on. The victim Unmo-san...
Was also the culprit?
Not the culprit, the suspect.
Mitsuhiko.
Conan-kun, could you handle the rest?
You're the one who solved it.
Fine.
Yesterday at four,
Unmo-san came to the construction
site to blackmail someone.
Since it was cold, he wore a coat.
In other words, the tall man
the Detective Boys saw
was Unmo-san himself.
They're still not here.
Bastard!
No, you don't!
Don't underestimate me!
I killed them.
Believing he had killed them, he
threw away the metal pipe and fled,
which was witnessed by the Detective Boys.
Later, Unmo-san returned.
He returned?
He must've remembered that his
fingerprints were on the weapon.
This isn't good!
I need to get rid of that metal pipe!
Where did it go?
Unmo-san was killed by
his blackmailing victim,
who had only been knocked unconscious.
That was around 4:30.
Then the culprit removed Unmo-san's coat,
and disposed of it along with the metal pipe.
The reason I thought the tall
man they saw might be Unmo-san
is because I saw this photo you sent.
Since it was a cold day, he
must've been wearing a coat,
and if he was going to blackmail someone,
he would've hidden the fact that his
front teeth were missing with a mask.
Once we eliminate the
requirement of "tall man,"
we should be focusing on the
certainty of their alibis
when determining the culprit.
Why did the culprit need
to remove Unmo-san's coat?
When they were fighting Unmo-san,
it's possible their blood
got on Unmo-san's clothes.
Blood?
Forensics just reported that
they found blood on the coat.
It belongs to the victim
Unmo-san and one other person.
It's mine.
But I didn't mean to kill him!
He asked me to meet him
yesterday and blackmailed me.
When I asked him to stop,
he told me not to underestimate
him and started strangling me.
In order to defend myself,
I grabbed a metal pipe,
but he nearly killed me.
I attacked Unmo with the
metal pipe when he returned
because I feared he'd come to finish me off.
I was caught up in the moment.
Huh? That contradicts your story.
What?!
You made your fake request to your neighbor
before you went to see Unmo-san, right?
If you hadn't been planning to kill him,
you wouldn't have done that in advance.
You're right.
Yeah!
The little brat is right.
I asked that pest to meet me and killed him!
Yes!
Case closed!
We did it!
Impressive work, Conan-kun.
It's thanks to the information
you provided me.
Thanks for all the work you did.
What? That doesn't sound like you.
But in the end, you did the heavy lifting.
Guys.
Look at them commending each other.
Huh?
Is it another case?
All right. Let's go!
Yeah!
Episode Preview
No!
I won't let anyone treat them so carelessly!
So this is what he meant when he
said we were his only visitors.
Is something wrong?
Hey!
Over here!
The Sun Sets Over Tangerine Fields
The next episode of Conan is
"The Sun Sets Over Tangerine Fields!"
Container
Next Conan's hint!
A container!
Don't miss the next episode.
The sky turns orange.
And the day...
...is over.
Like the citrus fruit?
Yeah.