Wow.
There are so many tangerines.
Take as many as you'd like today.
Terauchi Naoya (30)
Tetsuji's Son
You're our only customers today.
There's no need for restraint.
No!
Dad!
What?
If you harvest them so carelessly,
you'll damage the tangerines.
Terauchi Tetsuji (62)
Terauchi Tangerine
Fields Manager
We're sorry.
This is how you do it.
Got it?
Yes.
Dad, you don't have to say it like that.
These tangerines are my precious children.
I won't let anyone treat them so carelessly!
That attitude is the reason people
stopped coming to pick tangerines.
So this is what he meant when he
said we were his only visitors.
Um, I'm sorry.
My father can get nasty when
it comes to tangerines.
Don't let it bother you.
Terauchi Nobuko (58)
Tetsuji's Wife
He's just an awkward man.
Okay.
Mom.
I'm heading back down.
When you get there, could you send it up?
Sure thing.
Pick lots of fruit.
I'll cook up something tasty for you later.
Okay.
Is something wrong?
No.
I just haven't seen my mom in
such a good mood in a long time.
Really?
Lately she's been arguing with my dad a lot.
She's been on edge.
Hey, don't tell them that.
Sorry.
Time is the y-axis, and I'm the x-axis!
Inscribing love and cases
with deductive reasoning!
The aroma of citrus fruit drifts through
tangerine fields in perfect picnic weather!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Sun Sets Over Tangerine Fields
"The Sun Sets Over Tangerine Fields!"
We ended up picking a lot.
There's got to be a month's worth here.
Let's stop harvesting and head back.
Do we have to hike down the
mountain carrying these?
Don't worry.
We've got a convenient tool for that.
Hey, it's coming right now.
What's that?
An agricultural monorail
for transporting crops.
There's no one riding it. Is that okay?
Yeah. It automatically goes up and down
the mountain when you activate the lever.
Automatically?
Once it reaches the work shed at the peak,
it automatically switches into
reverse and returns to the shed
at the foot of the mountain.
Really?
Of course, it can be
operated manually as well.
Reverse     Forward
That's really convenient.
Thanks to this thing, transporting
crops has become much easier.
Let's load the containers onto the bed.
Okay!
We're finally finished.
Good work.
Kid, want to ride the monorail?
Me?
Since you have the opportunity, why not?
Okay.
I want to ride, too.
Unfortunately, it's overloaded.
Sonoko, let's go.
See you at the bottom.
Whoa. It shakes a lot.
Hold on tight so you don't fall off.
These look delicious.
I've never seen a bunch of these dishes.
Try some.
Thanks for the food.
It's so good.
I know.
Tangerines go with everything.
Yeah.
Of course they do.
My tangerines are the best in Japan.
I think you must be right. Right?
Yeah.
Oh, really?
In that case, have some
of more of this and that.
He's acting really different.
He's happy because you
complimented his tangerines.
He's a simple man, right?
Hey, you'd better not be saying
things you shouldn't again.
I was just complimenting you, Dad.
Don't be shy. Eat as much as you'd like.
Okay.
Whew. I'm stuffed.
Dad!
You found a buyer for the farm?
Yeah.
Why didn't you consult me?
Don't worry. It's someone we can trust.
That's not the problem.
I was making my own arrangements.
Don't tell Nobuko about this.
Got it?
Why not?
Because she always takes your side.
She'd obviously be against it.
Then all the more reason for
us to discuss this as a family.
I'm the head of this family.
I have the right to decide.
That's when we first started
the tangerine farm together.
That's the first time Naoya
harvested a tangerine by himself.
How cute!
Terauchi Tangerine Farm
This is when Naoya told me he'd
work on the tangerine farm.
I'm surprised you remember all that.
It's like your family's
history. It's truly wonderful.
Things were really great back then.
Did something happen?
A lot happens to a family over a few decades.
Want to see more?
Yes, please.
Ow!
Ouch...
Are you all right?
Yeah. It's nothing serious.
Maybe it's a frozen shoulder.
Sonoko...
It's fine. You can't overcome age.
I'll get it.
Get the third one from the right.
Here.
Thank you.
That's me.
Well? Pretty handsome, right?
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, I guess.
How pretty.
I can't believe this view.
I'm glad Nobuko-san told us to come.
Yeah.
It's dark.
This sound...
Someone must've come to pick us up.
Hey!
Over here!
He noticed us.
He just fell, didn't he?
No way!
Conan-kun.
I was watching from below, and
it looked like my dad fell.
Dad!
Conan-kun?
No...
Honey!
The deceased is Terauchi Tetsuji-san,
the manager of this tangerine farm.
The cause of death was a skull fracture.
Most likely, he hit his head
on a rock when he fell.
And you saw Tetsuji-san fall?
Yes.
Come to think of it, how did
you notice Tetsuji-san fell?
I was making repairs near
the sprinkler control panel.
Where is that?
It's near the base of the
mountain southeast of here.
And?
I turned to look when I heard the girls' shouts,
and just happened to witness my
father falling from the monorail.
I see.
I was looking for ingredients for dinner
in the fields at the base of the mountain.
Like Naoya, I heard the girls' shouts.
I see. Thank you.
Would it be natural to think
Tetsuji-san lost his balance
when he let go of the monorail to
wave to Ran-san and her friends?
But why was Tetsuji-san
heading towards the peak?
I asked him to.
What do you mean?
I told Ran-san and her friends
to go watch the sunset.
Since it'd be dark by the time they
returned, I asked him to go get them.
I see.
Hey, it seems like there's
blood on the inside of his hat,
but there's nothing on the outside.
What about it?
Don't you think that's strange?
Tetsuji-san died when he hit
his head on a rock, right?
Then normally wouldn't the rock have
left a mark on the outside of the hat?
You're right.
Maybe Tetsuji-san lost his hat
before he hit his head on the rock.
Huh?
Then when did the blood get
on the inside of the hat?
That doesn't matter.
We saw the moment he fell. Right?
Yeah.
So where is the monorail
your husband was riding?
It should be at the shed at
the foot of the mountain.
I see.
Then let's have the others hold things
down here while we go check that out.
Yes, sir.
Huh? Where did they go?
Mom. It's okay, Mom.
But...
You've got me.
There's nothing unusual about it.
It seems that way.
The number of containers doesn't add up.
Don't these containers...?
There's nothing particularly
suspicious about the incident,
so it's safe to assume it was an accident.
Indeed.
It's our fault for calling
out to him and waving.
No!
He shouldn't have let go of the
railing while riding the monorail.
It's my dad's fault for
not following the rules.
You're right.
He should've sounded the monorail's horn.
It's because he waved with his right hand.
That's it. I've figured it out.
It's safe to assume this incident
was an unfortunate accident.
We should get going.
Sonoko?
You're always such a tedious
man, Inspector Megure.
How?
Sonoko, could it be?
There's something that
I just don't understand.
What don't you understand?
Ran, do you remember what Tetsuji-san did
when we waved to him?
What he did?
I think he raised his hand high
into the air and waved back at us.
That's it. Tetsuji-san had a frozen shoulder.
Someone like that couldn't
raise their hand high up.
Don't you agree?
You're right.
Is it true that your husband
had a frozen shoulder?
Yes.
Tetsuji-san was probably
forced to wave his hand
by someone behind him.
But only Tetsuji-san was riding the monorail.
That person was probably hiding
in the bed of the monorail.
Wait a minute.
There's no space for anyone to hide.
Not now.
What does that mean?
Detective Takagi, there are footprints on
the front of the monorail bed, correct?
Yes, I see them.
Judging by the footprints,
they belonged to Tetsuji-san.
Could you place your feet in
them and try sitting on the bed?
Here? Ow!
Huh?
How was he able to sit with
his feet in this position?
That's right.
Perhaps there was an additional
row of containers there
so the culprit could hide.
What?
Even so, I don't think an adult
could hide inside these containers.
Are you sure?
It's impossible.
Sonoko-kun, do you still insist the
culprit hid inside a container?
Hey, look at what I found.
It seems to be a folded container.
What about it?
The bottoms and sides of those
containers can be adjusted.
If you fold the bottoms, three
containers can be merged into one,
creating a space large enough
for a person to hide inside.
Furthermore, if you leave the right
side that we couldn't see open,
it's even possible to make Tetsuji-san wave
from inside the container without anyone noticing.
I see.
Several similar containers were
scattered around the tangerine fields.
In other words,
the culprit hid inside the folded
containers and pushed Tetsuji-san,
then used the monorail's
automatic return system
to pass before us and return
to the foot of the mountain.
Later, they exited the monorail,
and pretended they saw Tetsuji-san
fall when they ran to the crime scene.
I see.
So, who did it?
I did it!
Naoya, you—
I killed my father, put him on that monorail,
and pushed him so it would
look like an accident.
I see.
You can tell us more at—
Wait! I'm the one who killed my husband!
What?
Mom!
I hid the hammer I used to strike
my husband under the workbench.
If you examine the fingerprints on the
hammer, it should prove that I'm the culprit.
I found it!
Why?
I could ask you the same question.
Why did you try to take the fall for me?
Because it's my fault.
It's not your fault at all!
I'm the one who decided to kill him!
What happened between you?
I overheard them talking
about selling the farm.
I thought he was doing it to repay the debt
he accrued fooling around
with other women.
But that's not true.
I'm the one who suggested he sell it.
What?
We wouldn't survive operating
this farm as a single family.
I recommended selling the farm
so it could be revitalized
using new techniques.
Not realizing that,
I was desperate to leave this farm to Naoya,
so I...
If you'd properly discussed
selling the farm as a family,
then this wouldn't have happened.
My father told me not to say anything.
He said my mother would never allow it.
He didn't trust me.
When I told my mother about the plan to
sell the farm on the way to the shed,
she suddenly started crying.
When I asked her about it, she confessed
that she'd killed my father.
If only it'd been written off as an accident.
But if my mom was a suspect...
I know it was a misunderstanding,
but she killed my father to help me.
That's why I decided to take the fall.
I shouldn't have told you
no matter what you said.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for using you as witnesses.
These are so good.
They taste better since
we picked them ourselves.
Ran?
Don't worry. Naoya-san said
he'd protect the tangerines.
Let's eat.
Okay...
Maybe you shouldn't eat so many at once.
It's fine.
Tangerines are low in calories so I won't
get fat no matter how many I eat.
Haven't you heard the expression,
"Fruit is gold in the morning,
silver at noon, and lead at night?"
What's that?
Your liver turns excess sugar into fat.
That's why they say not
too eat too much fruit.
People tend not to exercise at night.
Hey, you should've mentioned
something that important sooner!
My stomach feels squishier than usual.
Ran...
It won't turn into fat that quickly.
Episode Preview
You want to use the APTX4869 antidote
to restore your body so you
can participate, right?
I knew you'd understand, Haibara.
No.
What?
Wait, wait.
BIG might've won if
Higo-san were in the game.
Chiyari City?
It's recording.
The Heartfelt Strap
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is
"The Heartfelt Strap, Part One!"
Window Glass
Next Conan's hint!
Window glass!
Did you hear from Shinichi
about the school trip?
Don't miss the next episode.
Not yet...
I need to do something fast.