Thanks, Professor.
Sure.
What was Kudo-kun doing here
so early on a Sunday morning?
He came to get his phone that I repaired.
I told him you'd bring it
to the soccer game today,
but he said he'd come get it right away.
Huh...
Yikes! Seventeen received messages?
Media Browser Messages Calls Folder
Ran
School Trip  Answer my messages
School Trip  We're going to Kyoto!
Ran
School Trip  Answer my messages
School Trip  Is your phone broken?
Ran
School Trip  We're going to Kyoto!
School Trip  Answer my messages
Ran
School Trip  Is your phone broken?
School Trip  Answer your messages!!
They're all from Ran?!
Ran
School Trip  Answer my messages
School Trip  Is your phone broken?
Ran
School Trip  Answer your messages!!
School Trip  Let me know if there's
anywhere you want to go in Kyoto
Ran
School Trip  Is your phone broken?
School Trip  Answer your messages!!
Ran
School Trip  Let me know if there's
anywhere you want to go in Kyoto
Ran
School Trip  I signed you up for our group!
School Trip  Answer your messages!!
Ran
School Trip  Let me know if there's
anywhere you want to go in Kyoto
Ran
School Trip  I signed you up for our group!
School Trip  We're going to Kyoto!
Will you be able to make it?
Time is the y-axis, and I'm the x-axis!
Inscribing love and cases
with deductive reasoning!
Ran's messages are about the school trip!
I wish I could respond right away!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Heartfelt Strap
(Part One)
“The Heartfelt Strap, Part One!”
Yes!
Next stop, Beika. Beika.
That was amazing!
Did you see Hide's long shot?
Yes!
I can't believe he scored from that far away!
BIG Osaka's goalie was surprised, too!
What? A school trip?
Yeah, for Teitan High School. So, you know...
You want to use the APTX4869 antidote
to restore your body so
you can participate, right?
I knew you'd understand, Haibara!
No.
What?
The effects of the antidote
are still only temporary.
If you continuously take it in order to remain
in your original body during the school trip,
there's no telling what kind
of side effects there could be.
And besides, when you went to London...
Your passport.
Huh?
What?!
Oh, crap! I totally forgot!
There is one way you could go.
You've got Ai-kun's fantastic
idea to thank for this.
Yeah. I'm grateful.
Conan-kun and the professor aren't coming.
Ran-neechan!
Conan-kun?
When did you get here?
Just now. You didn't notice?
The effects of the medicine
wouldn't wear off,
so I was stuck in the
bathroom for 30 minutes.
Hello?
Sorry, Shinichi?
It's me...
What?
Oh, crap! This is Shinichi's phone!
Can't hear you hear the
sound of Big Ben over here?
Big Ben over here?
You're here in London?
Shinichi, you can't escape now!
Now why don't you explain
what's going on, Shinichi?
Did he take the antidote
he needed to return home?
Shinichi?
Sorry.
Something came up. I can't make it anymore.
You'd better thank Ai-kun.
Yeah.
And the Shiragami case!
I had a local doctor come.
I told you, he's fine.
But...
Haibara! What are you doing here?
There's no time to explain.
Take this immediately.
I-Is this...
Yes.
It's a prototype antidote to the
APTX4869 that turned you into a child.
The same as the one you took yesterday.
Will it last 24 hours again?
You idiot.
Just as habitually consuming the
same medicine reduces its effects,
your body has developed a
resistance to that medicine.
If you keep using it, its
duration decreases, too.
If you want to keep your identity hidden,
you'll have to say goodbye to
them before its effects run out
and you turn back into Edogawa Conan.
I've saved you countless
times with my quick wits
when the effects of the medicine expired
and your identity was about to be discovered!
You still haven't learned your lesson?!
Calm down.
I know you're upset because BIG Osaka lost,
but you were in a great mood since you
got to meet Higo-san in the stands,
who was out of the game due to an injury.
I even wore a BIG hat today
and cheered for them.
You shouldn't have done that.
You're the reason they lost!
She's still upset over the loss.
It's so shiny.
I just polished it yesterday.
Either way, give up on that school trip.
We apologize for the sudden
stop due to a red light.
Ouch...
The doors will open once we've confirmed
it's safe to exit the train.
Are you okay, Haibara?
Yes, I'm fine.
Thanks.
You're not hurt, are you?
No.
You scraped your knee!
Do you need me to support you?
The doors are opening.
Being nice to me won't work.
Really?
You met Higo in the stands, huh?
That's great.
Yeah. He was really cool.
Ai-chan was blushing.
We even got to talk with him a little.
Yeah.
And you got a Higo-san phone strap.
It was the last one.
I was very lucky.
Haibara's mood is improving.
BIG might've won if
Higo-san were in the game.
Genta!
Come to think of it, I got a photo of it.
I'll show you.
Yes, please.
Wait, what?
What's wrong?
It's recording.
What? You're right.
Since when?
It seems to have started
while we were on the train.
What?!
That long?
I seem to have pressed the button when
I made sure I hadn't dropped my phone
after the train suddenly stopped and we fell.
It's because you keep yours in
the rear pocket of your pants.
Why were you keeping it there?
I saw Haibara-san doing it, so I copied her.
Ai-chan, is your phone okay?
Yeah. It's right here in—
What's wrong, Haibara?
It's gone.
The Higo-san strap I attached
to my phone is gone!
No way!
Seriously?
You mean the very last one you got, right?
I'm sure you'll be able
to buy one online soon.
I can't!
Huh?
That strap is special. Today, Higo-san...
It's you.
You're the girl from the
case at Asuka-san's restaurant.
Yes.
Huh. They're selling that now?
It's actually cute, unlike me.
And then he touched it!
There's only one strap
like that in the world!
Ai-chan?
But where did we lose it?
Probably when we fell on the train.
Mitsuhiko, let me see that video you
accidentally recorded on your phone.
Okay.
Are you okay, Haibara?
That man next to the train doors...
He's picking something up.
Isn't that the Higo-san strap?
You're right. It looks like it.
That must be it.
Then maybe he delivered it to
the station's lost and found.
Call them right away.
Got it.
For Ai-kun.
What? You have it?
Yes, it's a phone strap of a soccer player.
Yes, that's it.
We'll come by later to pick it up.
All right!
Ai-chan, they have it!
She's still dazed.
Yeah.
We'll go to Beika Station to pick it up.
Yeah!
Wait, wait.
What?
It's at the station in Chiyari City.
Chiyari City?
Isn't that pretty far away?
What should we do?
I'm out of money.
My turbo-powered skateboard
is being repaired.
Professor, could you drive
us there in your Beetle?
Yeah.
Please!
My bartender friend's borrowing it.
No way...
There's no rush. You can go get it tomorrow.
In that case, I'll run there.
What?
But it's tens of kilometers away!
Oh?
Is something the matter?
Subaru-san!
Since I was told I hadn't stewed
my curry long enough the other day,
I brought a new batch to share.
More importantly,
Haibara-san's very important phone
strap was taken to Chiyari Station.
We're on our way to get it right now.
Could you drive us there?
I see.
She's not going?
No. She's pretty shocked
about the whole thing.
Unfortunately, I need to
use my car after this.
What?
You can't take us?
But I saw a familiar car
parked next to this house.
Why don't you ask him?
A familiar car?
A white RX-7.
I knew it!
It's Amuro-san!
What are you doing here?
I got sleepy while driving
in the area, so I took a nap.
What are you kids doing?
We're going to Chiyari Station to pick
up the phone strap our friend dropped.
Could you drive us there?
Please!
I'd also like to ask that you do this.
Though if there's some reason you
don't want to leave this place,
then I suppose it can't be helped.
I wanted to nap a little
longer, but that's too bad.
This is a thrillingly good place to nap.
Toto Metro Lost and Found
Thanks for waiting, kids.
Here. This is the strap, right?
What?
That's not it!
That's Sanada!
We lost a Higo strap!
What? This isn't it?
Was this the man who turned that in?
No, it was a younger man.
What's going on?
Maybe...
Could I see that?
This man in the photo appears to be the
father of the boy standing next to him.
Maybe he mistook the Higo
strap your friend dropped
for the Sanada strap his son dropped
and picked up yours.
Unless you're a passionate fan,
they probably all look the same.
Higo     Sanada
In other words, someone picked up
the Sanada strap his son dropped
and turned it in here.
Then we need to find the father
and son recorded by my phone.
But how are we going to find them?
We don't even know their names.
Yeah.
Why don't we think about that
once we return to my car?
Okay.
Oh, right.
Excuse me!
Yes?
Was a badge turned in along with that strap?
A badge? No, I don't think so.
I see...
Thank you!
Genta-kun, what are you doing?
Oh, sorry.
I lost my Detective Badge on the train, too.
Your Detective Badge?
The professor made them for us.
We all have them.
Now then, how should we
find this man with his son
who picked up the Higo strap
your friend dropped on the train?
Both of them look very tan.
You're right.
They're so dark.
Maybe... They're on their way
to go swimming at the beach.
No, that's not it.
Why not?
This video was taken while
we were on the train
after the soccer game that ended at 3 PM.
We arrived at Beika Station
ten minutes after that,
so if they were going swimming,
they would've left earlier.
You're right.
Then maybe they're on their
way back from the beach.
That's not it either.
What?
We were riding the Shonan Shinjuku train.
Takasaki
Omiya
Shinjuku
Odawara | Yokohama | Beika
Ofuna
It departs from Takasaki in Gunma
and passes through Shinjuku
and Yokohama on its way
to Odawara in Kanagawa.
And the beach doesn't reach Beika Station.
Maybe they went to an indoor pool.
Or bug hunting.
Or maybe they just went to
an acquaintance's house.
In that case, did you overhear
any of their conversation?
Their conversation?
I was bragging about how I polished my badge.
Come to think of it,
the dad said to his son,
“It's about as long as it
takes to watch Kamen Yaiba.”
But Kamen Yaiba wasn't on today.
Isn't it on tomorrow?
Before his father said
that, did the boy ask him,
“How much longer?”
Yeah, he did.
Which means it's possible he was using
the thirty minute Kamen Yaiba program
to explain to his son how much longer it
would take to arrive at their destination.
I see.
Do you know when they said that?
Yeah.
It was after the train screeched
to a stop and everyone fell.
Shinjuku
Beika
Yokohama
Chiyari
Ofuna
So it's 30 minutes from Beika Station.
That's here around Chiyari Station.
That boy seemed to be a first-year
elementary school student like us.
It's not unreasonable that his father
would use Yaiba as an example.
How do you know he's a first-year?
Because he breathed on the train window
and wrote something with his finger.
He said, “It's only hiragana, but I
can write it now. Aren't you proud?”
I think he was writing his own name.
Unfortunately, I couldn't see what he wrote.
Do you remember which car you were riding in?
We got on in the middle of the
third car from the front, right?
Yes.
You really don't remember what he wrote?
No.
I do remember his pale finger
pressed against the window though.
Pale finger?
They're both really dark from being so tan.
But if you look closely at the video...
See? It's both of them.
They're both pale from the wrist down!
And look at the dad's bag.
It looks like there's
something angular inside it.
Maybe he put his cooler inside
his bag since the strap broke.
Are they going fishing?
But they don't have fishing rods.
And they're too lightly dressed to go hiking.
Maybe...
Maybe?
They could be digging for clams.
Dig...
Digging for clams?
You go digging for clams in spring!
We're on summer break!
Actually, you can do it all year round.
What? Really?
Yeah.
April to May is the best season
because the climate means
the clams are full of
nutrients from spawning,
Yokohama
Yokosuka
Odawara
Miura
Ito
Oarai
Tokyo | Chiba | Choshi Port
Katsuura
Mera
but there are plenty of beaches that are
open to digging for clams as late as July.
And low tide at Chiyari
Beach is at 5:59 today.
When digging for clams, it's best to
arrive an hour or two before low tide,
so it makes sense that they took that train.
Really? Then...
If we go to that beach...
We'll be able to retrieve
Haibara-san's strap!
Once that boy realizes the strap
his dad picked up isn't his,
I'm sure he'll hand it over.
Yeah.
And once we get it,
we won't let anyone else take it
until we return it to Ai-chan!
No matter what!
Yeah!
Yes! Haibara-san will be so happy!
This is great!
Yes! I'm so happy!
I'll go settle the bill.
You kids head to the car.
Sure.
Thanks, Amuro-san.
Thanks for the food!
Kazami?
Episode Preview
She's in that state because
she lost her Higo strap?
Yeah.
It's less likely that it won't be found.
Japan's top two inspectors are on the case.
Breathe on it.
What?
Nice one, Amuro-san.
Now that we know that...
The Heartfelt Strap
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is
“The Heartfelt Strap, Part Two!”
Haibara's Strap
Next Conan's hint.
Haibara's strap!
Don't miss the next episode.
Amuro-san, thank you.
With you, looking for lost objects
becomes a profound experience.