[Eyecatch]
[ED]
Happy New Year, everyone!
Last year, the comic, TV anime, movie,
and various events were
met with great enthusiasm.
In particular, the movie
"Zero the Enforcer" was a huge hit.
We have all of you who support
us to thank for that.
We'll be working even harder this year,
so we appreciate your continued support.
H-Hold on, Sonoko.
Come on. It's been forever.
No, no, no, no!
Give me a break!
Come on.
I'll take a romantic photo of you two.
Let's take one of all of us.
Nope.
Feel free to share a passionate kiss, missus.
What?
In any case...
Go on!
Detective Conan
1 Hour Special
The Scarlet School Trip:
Bright Red and Red Love Arcs
The Scarlet School Trip
(Bright Red Arc)
"The Scarlet School Trip, Bright Red Arc!"
Sorry for bumping into you.
Did it hurt?
You probably shouldn't get too close to me.
I told you, I have a bit of a cold.
Are you okay?
I brought some cold medicine.
I'm fine.
The professor gave me some medicine.
Look at you two.
Are you planning tonight's tryst?
Sonoko!
If you don't cut it out,
I'm really going to get mad.
You're even cute when you're angry, missus.
Jeez...
I'd only been looking up at her from a low
angle recently, so I was starting to forget,
but seeing her up close...
Hey, you.
Huh?
Whoa!
Are you really Kudo Shinichi?
Y-Yeah...
Wh-What?
You remember me, don't you?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
Didn't we meet on the
beach when we were kids?
It's been ten years, right?
Ten years?
Has it really been that long?
Huh? Uh, yeah, of course.
Sera-chan, we're going to the Kiyomizu butai.
Okay.
See you later.
We can have a nice long chat then.
Sure...
Hey, Kudo.
We sure got lucky.
Nakamichi, what do you mean?
Three of the Teitan High School popularity
contest's top ten girls are in our group.
Really?
A popularity contest, huh?
What rank was Ran?
Since you confessed your feelings to Mori in
London, I'll pass on her out of respect for you.
You idiot.
Sonoko's got a really strong boyfriend,
and Sera's a Jeet Kune Do...
What?
How do you know I confessed my feelings?!
What? Suzuki told everyone.
What?
She said we should support you guys.
Damn that Sonoko...
Anyway, Kudo...
I'm surprised you were able
to come on the school trip.
I didn't think you'd come.
Oh, yeah.
It took a lot to get here.
That's not why we did it,
but if you don't mind, the
medicine to restore my body...
Absolutely not!
I didn't think so.
Do you have a cold?
Nah.
Conan jumped into the sea when the
strap nearly fell into the water.
It ended up belonging
to someone else, though.
And he kept looking even
though his clothes were wet.
Come to think of it, you kids
seem a little dirty, too.
We were looking under cars and stuff, too.
We did it for Ai-chan.
We're totally fine.
Yeah!
If it's to help Haibara-san,
We know.
I don't mind getting this dirty at all.
I guess I'll have to give
up on the school trip.
I wouldn't want people to know
Kudo Shinichi is still alive.
Ow, ow, ow!
What was that for, Haibara?
I'll give you the medicine.
Really?
Huh?
But you have to do as I say.
Got it?
Yeah, yeah. I know.
Wow.
What a nice view.
Yeah, but this place isn't too high up.
Looks like about 12 meters.
Sera-chan, don't lean over
so far. It's dangerous.
Apparently someone jumped to their
death from here the other day.
Really?
So?
Have you responded
to Shinichi-kun's confession?
What?
Not yet...
Then you really should kiss him here.
Imagine you're leaping
off the Kiyomizu butai.
I can't do that!
What's going on? Ran-kun,
are you going to jump off?
It's a matter of motivation.
You just wait, Dekuri-kun.
It won't be long now.
Excuse me, are you the
actress Kurachi Keiko-san?
Kurachi Keiko (37)
Actress
I came here secretly.
Don't tell anyone.
Sure.
Is she a celebrity?
Can we take a picture with you?
Yes, as long as we do it quietly.
Thank you.
Shinichi, Nakamichi-kun, come here.
Let's take a picture together.
Shinichi?
Thank you!
Hey, you.
Huh?
Are you Kudo Shinichi-kun,
the high school detective?
Yes.
You're Yukiko-chan's son, aren't you?
Yes, that's me.
I thought so.
I've changed your diaper before.
Are you here on a school trip?
Yes.
Hey, missus. Your husband's cheating on you.
They seem to know each other.
No way. We're staying in the same hotel.
We? Are you here with someone?
Yes.
Some college classmates and I came
to pay our respects to an old friend.
I say classmates, but they're
all celebrities, too.
Really?
I know. Since we're staying in the same
hotel, could you come to my room tonight?
What?
There's something I want to show you.
Show me what?
It's a cipher.
Detectives love those, right?
Come see me around nine tonight.
This is my room number.
She gave him something.
I was going to ask Yukiko-chan's husband.
Are you too busy?
No, it's totally fine!
It's decided, then.
You can bring your girlfriend, too.
Huh?
She's that long-haired
girl over there, right?
She's been staring at us this whole time.
See you later.
I'll be waiting. You have to come.
O-Okay.
Wait, Ran!
Tonight at nine, huh?
That's cutting it close.
Purify your body and mind
Beautifying water
Momoyama Palace
Bloody Ceiling
Cedar-board door painting
by Sotatsu at this temple
Please look up at the ceiling.
The general staying at Fushimi
Castle at this time...
Wow. So this is the bloody ceiling...
It's an ancient murder scene.
It figures a high school girl
detective would say that.
Hey.
Let's keep moving.
Don't worry. It won't drip on us.
I know that.
Besides, it was painted on the ceiling to
memorialize the men who died in battle.
You should look at it and pray for them.
Y-You're right.
Uh, oh.
This is too much fun.
What number is Kurachi-san's room?
Oh.
It's room 1506.
I'm sorry about the poster, Mai-san.
It can't be helped.
They've been friends since college, right?
Besides, I heard that movie is a
remake of one they made in college.
Kuraki Mai!
Who?
If my name appeared alongside
theirs on the movie poster,
it would look like I forced them to do it,
even though I sang the theme song.
I'm glad they turned us down.
I'm sorry.
I thought it'd be a good
opportunity to promote you.
Are you kids in high school?
Are you on a school trip?
Yeah.
I see. That's nice.
A double date on a school trip, huh?
Oh, to be young.
You made my heart skip a beat.
A double date?
I thought I was going to die.
Sorry.
Coming!
Welcome.
Oh...
You brought more than just her.
Sorry.
When I told them I was meeting
you, they insisted on coming.
Hello!
Should I not have brought them?
No, it's totally fine.
The more, the merrier, right?
I'll crack that code for you.
She's a detective, too.
A high school girl detective.
Really? How promising.
Excuse me.
You wear your hat inside, too?
Oh, this?
I tripped during filming
and got a bump on my head.
Were you filming for your movie
that comes out this weekend?
That's right.
"The Fighting Red Tengu."
Ihaya Shinya (37)
Actor
The highlight of this historical
fantasy film is its star, me.
No, no.
I believe the highlight of
the film is me, the director.
Mayama Mineto (38)
Movie Director
No, no, no.
I thought the selling point
of the film was my music.
Agata Riki (37)
Composer
What are you talking about?
This movie doesn't exist without its star.
You're wrong.
People have always said a
movie is made by its director.
They really are all celebrities.
That's right.
They're all my friends from college.
So, what's this cipher you mentioned?
Oh, right.
Our scriptwriter Nishiki-kun has it.
Let's go to his room together.
Yeah.
This is the cipher I received last week.
Let me take a look.
The envelope the cipher came in also
contained a dried paper plant leaf.
Excuse me.
Do you know what these four black
squares at the top of the cipher mean?
Yeah.
That's the mark of Dekuri, the
guy who came up with that cipher.
He drew that mark on his notebooks and bags.
Then can't you ask that Dekuri person
for the meaning of the cipher?
We can't anymore.
The other day, he jumped to his
death from the Kiyomizu butai.
What?
I thought that cipher was
a message he left to me
before he killed himself.
That's why I wanted you to decipher it.
Hey, kids.
We're going to get dinner
in the hotel lounge.
If you want to know more,
why don't you come with us?
No, thanks. We'll pass.
Then text me when you figure out the cipher.
Got it.
That's a pretty bare-bones cipher.
And the characters are arranged crookedly.
There's probably some meaning
to those crooked spaces.
Come to think of it, I wonder what the
paper plant leaf in the envelope was about.
Tengu often carry paper plant leaves, right?
It's from Keiko-san.
Come on. I haven't decoded the cipher yet.
From: Kurachi Keiko
Subject: No subject
Shinichi-kun, hurry!
Come to Nishiki-kun's room!!
What happened, Keiko-san?
He's been stabbed.
And there are bumps on his head.
Didn't you say you were
getting dinner in the lounge?
Yeah. After that, we returned
to our rooms to get ready.
We were supposed to meet at this room
in ten minutes before heading down.
He wouldn't answer the door no matter
how many times we rang the bell,
so we had a bellhop unlock it.
That's how we found him.
What is it?
Something fell on my shoulder.
It looks just like the bloody ceiling.
Yeah, and the footprints on the
ceiling lead to the window.
Most likely the culprit wanted it to seem like
he lifted the victim to the ceiling to stab him,
walked across the ceiling to the window,
and vanished from the window
of this 15th floor room,
as though a monster with
wings capable of flight
and magic powers capable of
manipulating human bodies
committed this crime.
Y-You mean a tengu?
Are you saying Nishiki-kun
was killed by a tengu?
D-Don't be ridiculous!
B-But a monster with magic
powers who can fly...
What are you talking about?
Those don't actually exist!
But it's the only possible explanation.
Tengu are imaginary creatures.
They only exist within movies like the
one we were filming until recently.
Are you saying Nishiki was
killed by a fictional monster?
Either way, it seems like the culprit wanted
it to look like the work of a tengu.
There's a paper plant leaf in the victim's
jacket, which tengu often carry.
And a new cipher as well.
Maybe the similar cipher
Nishiki-san received last week
was a warning.
A warning?
Hold on. If there's a new code...
Does that mean someone else will be killed?
Is it possible this Dekuri person
who came up with the code hated you?
Th-That's not possible. Right?
Y-Yeah.
Either way, this is probably
the work of someone unhappy
with your movie "The Fighting Tengu"
that comes out this weekend.
The movie's script is scattered
all over the floor.
By the way,
what are these smooth pieces of
paper stuck all over the script?
They're labels.
Nishiki had been using that
type of label recently
since they were easy to
stick on and take off.
Since the movie's going to be novelized,
Nishiki brought the script to the
hotel so he could make adjustments.
I see.
He was so excited to finish
it before the movie opened...
Excuse me.
Hello?
You said you planned to meet at this room
in ten minutes before going to dinner.
Who was first to arrive at the room?
Me and Agata.
By the time we arrived,
he wasn't answering his door.
If that's true,
then the culprit killed Nishiki-san
and sprayed the ceiling
with blood during those ten minutes.
Yeah. That blood wasn't there
when we came here earlier.
Did you call the police?
The bellhop who unlocked the
door called the police for us.
He just called to say a Kyoto Police inspector
named Ayanokoji would be coming.
Inspector Ayanokoji of the Kyoto Police, huh?
He's an odd inspector with a pet chipmunk,
but he's a smart man.
We don't have to worry about—
Is something wrong?
N-No, it's nothing.
Hey.
This isn't good. The medicine's wearing off.
Are you okay?
Y-Yeah.
I-In any case, the rest is up to you, Sera.
Hey!
What?
Are you okay?
Yes. The police will handle the rest.
I'll leave Sera with you.
If you need anything, talk to her.
Okay.
Shinichi?
You look pale.
Is it that bad inside?
Y-Yeah. Don't go in there.
Shinichi?
Don't follow me!
My cold returned with a vengeance.
I don't want you to get sick.
I should be fine after a good
night's sleep. Don't worry.
I can't turn back into Conan in front of Ran.
Shinichi...
Yes!
First one out!
Damn it!
Is it a teacher coming to check on us?
Seriously?
This isn't good. Kudo's not here.
Answer the door, Nakamichi.
Me?
Of course. This is your room.
We'll clean this up.
I'm coming.
Sorry, sir.
Whoa!
Oh, it's just you, Kudo.
Sorry, Nakamichi.
I forgot my key inside the room.
Don't scare us like that.
We thought you were a teacher.
Anyway, how'd it go?
How was meeting the great
actress Kurachi Keiko?
I-I'll tell you about it tomorrow.
I'm tired, so I'm going to sleep.
Don't wake me.
Seriously? We were looking
forward to hearing about it.
You're only interested in idols, Nakamichi.
W-Well, yeah.
Let's keep playing.
Your win earlier doesn't count, Nakamichi.
Why not?
We mixed up the cards because we
thought a teacher came to check on us.
Then you guys can play the
rest of the round yourselves.
Are you okay, Kudo?
Leave him be.
He's just excited because he
finally got to see his wife again.
Oh, right.
Ran!
Shinichi! I missed you!
Those idiots are always doing as they please.
Hey, you can come out now.
Just so you know, Kudo,
you really owe me for this.
Yeah, I know. Make sure no one finds out.
You can count on me.
Oh, right. Hey, Kudo.
Before you go to sleep, tell us about
your confession to Mori in London.
Don't be shy, Kudo.
You're not asleep yet, are you?
Did you guys kiss?
If you don't tell us,
I'll rip off the covers.
Yeah. Of course we kissed, you moron.
Th-They really did it?
They kissed?
Why do you have a Kansai accent?
When in Rome, do as the
Romans do, you know?
You guys had better learn to
speak in a Kansai accent, too.
Uh, sure...
They kissed?
Lucky.
I'd better keep my voice changer
on me starting tomorrow.
Following Haibara's rules isn't easy.
Listen closely.
The following three rules are important.
Don't take the next dose immediately
when the medicine wears off.
You have to wait eight hours.
Come up with a plan so the people around you
won't notice when you turn into a child.
Don't draw attention to yourself
when you're Kudo Shinichi.
And don't flirt too much.
Don't flirt?
Wasn't that four things?
Well, the fourth one's not important.
But following the first three is my condition
for giving you the APTX 4869 antidote.
Eight more hours.
This is going to be long.
Oh, right. I should show Hattori.
Huh?
A message?
What's this?
A cipher?
I see.
The high school detective Kudo
Shinichi-kun mentioned me?
Yeah. He said not to worry
since you're a smart inspector.
Ayanokoji Fumimaro (28)
Kyoto Police Division One Inspector
I appreciate it.
That's odd, though.
I've never met Kudo-kun before.
He really does have a pet chipmunk.
Perhaps Conan-kun told him about me.
Should a police officer be
bringing a pet to a crime scene?
This is quite the brutal murder.
Not only was he stabbed in the heart,
but he has two bumps on his head.
It will take some time to
examine the crime scene.
Could you please wait in your rooms?
After all, the victim and the
suspects are all celebrities.
I'm sure there will be quite
the commotion tomorrow morning.
Ow...
Come to think of it, I slept under the bed.
It's been eight hours.
Time for my medicine.
Will I make it until the
end of the school trip?
These guys didn't go back to their rooms?
Jeez.
It's Keiko-san.
From: Kurachi Keiko
Subject: No subject
Shinichi-kun, help!
Agata-kun's in
trouble now!!
Come to room 1504!
Something happened to Agata-san?!
Hey, Hattori! Wake up!
No, I can't eat anymore...
Hattori, it's a case!
Huh?
Did Agata-san really say that?
Yes. He was shouting loudly enough that I
could hear him from the neighboring room.
Shouting, "Help me!
He's going to kill me!"
Seriously?
Keiko-san!
Shinichi-kun.
You're Kudo Shinichi-kun?
Oh?
That boy next to you is
the Osaka Police chief's
son Hattori Heiji-kun.
What are you doing here?
K-Kudo invited me to come hang out.
I just happened to be here.
Anyway, what happened?
Agata-san was heard shouting something
rather strange inside his room.
This bellhop is unlocking the door for us.
It's open.
Thank you.
He's probably having nightmares after seeing
last night's crime scene and moaning in his sleep.
Agata-san, are you all right?
We're coming in.
Agata-san.
P-Please don't.
A-A tengu?
F-Forgive me. Forgive me!
Hey, you got any weapons?
No...
S-Stay back. Stay back!
Damn!
Stay back!
I-It disappeared!
It went up in flames and vanished!
N-No way!
Hey, Kudo...
We're not still asleep, are we?
Did you get any sleep after that?
None, but I'm hungry.
Where are we going today?
We're visiting power spots.
A tengu?
A tengu appeared in Agata-san's room?
Yeah, like some kind of
special effects movie.
So, what did the tengu do after that?
When Agata-san threw his ashtray at
it, it went up in flames and vanished.
It went up in flames and vanished?
That really does sound like a special effect.
According to him,
after Nishiki-san was killed,
he returned to his room to rest.
Unable to fall asleep,
he decided to get a drink at the bar,
but he had too much to drink and got drunk.
When he came to, he was back in his room.
When he lit a cigarette to have a smoke,
he sensed something strange
and looked up at the ceiling.
Keiko-san heard him from
the neighboring room.
We arrived after she contacted
us and saw the tengu, too.
If he returned to his room at some point,
it's possible someone took the drunk
Agata-san to his room and set something up.
But we didn't find any signs of a trick.
Then what about the cipher?
There was a new cipher, right?
There wasn't one of those either.
But...
...like the murdered Nishiki-san,
Agata-san had two bumps on his head.
Speaking of bumps,
Kurachi Keiko-san said she got
bumps on her head during filming.
Yeah.
She asked the director
to re-shoot the final scene
and got the bumps then when she tripped.
When I saw her earlier, her forehead
was still a little swollen,
so it's probably true that she tripped.
She said looking back, it's
possible someone pushed her.
When she tripped, she laughed about how she
looked like the Kobutori Jisan from the folktale.
What? I thought the Kobutori
Jisan's bumps were on his cheeks.
Each region seems to have its
own version of the story.
Anyway, was the blood on the ceiling at
Nishiki-san's murder scene really his blood?
No.
The police examined it and determined
that only the center of the blood spray,
in other words, the bit that dripped on
your shoulder, was Nishiki-san's blood,
and the rest was paint sprayed
onto the ceiling beforehand.
I knew it.
Also, they didn't find the blade used
to stab Nishiki-san at the crime scene.
I thought it'd be buried under
the pages scattered on the floor.
Which means the culprit still has the weapon.
R-Ran, what's wrong?
What's wrong?
People are saying you and
I French kissed in London!
What's going on?!
What?!
Nakamichi-kun's telling everyone
in a weird Kansai accent.
He says, "Those two
kids already smooched."
That was my voice, but it wasn't actually me.
What? It was your voice, but not you?
You're not making any sense!
Explain yourself, Shinichi!
Why's he speaking in a Kansai accent?
Explain myself?
I'm not sure.
More importantly, let's eat.
Apparently Shinichi-kun told him to
do as the Romans do when in Rome.
The food's delicious.
These sausages are the best.
Really?
Stop trying to trick me!
Hey.
Why are your sleeves folded up like that?
Huh?
Normally wouldn't you push your sleeves
up like this if they were in the way?
I didn't really think about it.
It's like a small child
was wearing that jacket.
Y-You idiot, that's obviously
not what happened.
It's a poster for the movie Keiko-san's in.
11/10 National Theatrical Release
Director: Mayama Mineto
Script: Nishiki Tarobo
Actor: Ihaya Shinya
Supporting Actress: Kurachi Keiko
Music: Agata Riki
"The Fighting Red Tengu," huh?
The Fighting Red Tengu
But considering what happened to the
scriptwriter Nishiki-san, it might not open.
Yeah.
I wonder what it's about.
It's set in the Edo Period.
A police officer of the Kyoto
magistrate's office named Kuranosuke
asks the magistrate if there's anything
unusual he can offer the general.
Hearing this,
his wife Mana presents her husband with a
golden paper plant leaf and says to him...
I found this paper plant leaf while
foraging for vegetables in the mountains.
Since it seemed divine,
I always prayed to it with clasped
hands, but I have brought it for you.
Now this is truly unusual.
I'm sure the general will be delighted.
Saying that, Kuranosuke thanks Mana.
But after that day, strange monsters
began appearing every night
in Kyoto and eating people.
That paper plant leaf was a magic seal a
tengu used long ago to imprison the monsters.
While this is happening, the tengu
appears to Kuranosuke in his dreams.
The monsters fear the one who broke the seal
will come to imprison them again.
They are looking for her
so that they may kill her.
If you hide the golden paper
plant leaf in your wife's bosom
and allow the monsters to eat her,
they will be imprisoned once again.
I won't do that even if it kills me!
I see. You're willing to risk your life.
Then take the paper plant leaf
and jump from the Kiyomizu butai.
The path will open to you.
Believing the Tengu's words,
Kuranosuke leaps from the Kiyomizu
butai and becomes a golden tengu.
He saves Mana from the monsters just
before they're about to eat her,
and defeats them using great magical powers.
But now that Kuranosuke is a tengu,
Mana can't see him anymore.
As Mana is crying over the sudden
disappearance of her husband,
she hears Kuranosuke's voice.
If you want to see me,
take a tengu's flower to the
Kiyomizu butai at sunset
when the leaves are reddest.
Mana picks a speedwell and goes to
the Kiyomizu butai as she was told.
Kuranosuke appears before her as a tengu
and explains to Mana what happened.
But why did you tell me
to come in the evening?
If I'd come when the sun were higher,
we could've spent more time together.
My rage at the monsters turned my face red,
and my entire body is red with their blood.
I thought if we were surrounded by
red, the color would hide it a little.
Answering her question, they
exchange a farewell kiss,
and Kuranosuke disappears into
the approaching darkness.
It's a sad story.
Wow!
How do you know so much about it?
It hasn't come out yet, right?
Actually, this movie is a
remake of a graduation project
they shot at Gion Art School.
The Fighting Red Tengu
Story
The entire story's available online.
They became famous because
of that graduation project,
so it's hard to imagine one
of them was unhappy with it.
Come to think of it,
when we met Keiko-san at the Kiyomizu butai,
she released a pressed flower into the wind.
Maybe that was a speedwell
like the one in the story.
Is that true?
Yeah.
I think she also said, "You just wait,
Dekuri-kun. It won't be long now."
What? Dekuri-kun?
Who's Dekuri-kun?
There wasn't anyone like
that on the staff list.
Mana and Kuranosuke kissed
at the Kiyomizu butai...
Does Shinichi want to kiss, too?
Okay, everyone.
This afternoon you'll be free to go
where you want with your groups.
Make sure you follow the course
you planned with your group
and return to the hotel by six.
Okay.
Have you heard, Kudo?
If you use a selfie stick at the hotel baths,
you can look into the women's baths.
Seriously?
Seriously.
Sera's chest isn't much to look at,
but Mori's must be crazy.
W-Well, yeah.
Well, yeah?
Not only have you kissed her,
but you've also bathed together?
Of course not.
Why did you hesitate?
Come on, tell me!
I told you, I haven't!
Sometimes I do as Conan, though.
Spit it out.
Tell me, and I'll forgive you.
Come on. Confess already.
Come on.
Time out. Someone's calling me.
Hattori?
Sorry, I gotta take this.
Sure.
Hello, Hattori?
Did something happen again?
It's not looking good.
The media's gathered in front of the hotel.
They're making a huge fuss.
It can't be helped since Naomoto Award
winner Nishiki Taro died last night,
but will you be okay with all this going on?
Your teachers might cancel the trip
and take you guys back to Tokyo.
Oh, yeah.
We're fine for now.
The teachers seem to be
avoiding mentioning the case,
and the rooms we're staying in
are pretty far away from the
room Nishiki-san died in.
Anyway, think you can slip away?
Huh?
Those four want to tell us about that
Dekuri guy who came up with the cipher.
It's hard for them to talk
here with the media around,
so they want to secretly meet for lunch at
a restaurant where they have a reservation.
I'm going with the police.
You'll want to speak with
them in person, right?
What's the restaurant?
Hey, where should we get lunch?
Yesterday's fruit sandwiches were good.
I want beef.
Then today...
Hey.
How about a place called
Isogiyama in Ponto City?
Ponto City
Isogiyama
Way to go, Sonoko.
At first they said they were booked solid.
The Suzuki Conglomerate sure is great.
Well, yeah.
What's this round barrier made of bamboo?
There are similar ones in
front of the other shops, too.
Maybe it's a fad in Kyoto.
That can't be right.
It's an inuyarai.
They say they're to deter thieves
or mark the edges of the street,
but they're apparently for
deterring dogs from urinating.
Momiji-san.
You know her?
Yeah. We met last time I
came to Kyoto with my dad.
Her tits are huge...
Are they your friends?
You're wearing the same uniforms.
Yes.
We came from Tokyo on a school trip.
I see. From Tokyo?
Thank you for coming all
the way from the provinces.
Th-The provinces?
But we're from the capital.
What do you have to eat to get that big?
My high school's off this afternoon.
I was thinking about having lunch here.
Shall we eat together?
Oh, right. Momiji-san, you attend
Kyoto Senshin High School, right?
Yes, I do.
Do you know Okita Soshi-kun?
Oh, yes. That kendo brat is in my class.
Really?
Let's not stand around out here.
Why don't we talk inside?
Okay.
Tengu!
There are tengu on Kiyamachi Way!
Tengu?
Really?
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Just how many are there?
Inspector Ayanokoji.
What's all this noise?
Sorry, sir.
People are saying tengu have
appeared on Kiyamachi Way.
Kiyamachi Way? That's just around the corner.
Do something about those idiots yourselves.
But, Inspector, it's not
just a couple of tengu.
What?
D-Do those tengu...
Have something to do with Nishiki's case?
H-Hey! You'll protect us, right?
Fine, then.
We have to step away for a moment.
Please don't go anywhere.
Okay.
I'm scared.
D-Don't let them escape.
We've got this.
What should we do, Kudo?
Start catching them!
Got it.
Ran-kun, let's help them!
Okay.
H-Hey, wait!
Don't leave me behind!
Iori.
Miss.
Iori!
Miss, are you hurt?
I'm all right.
Who's that?
Who the hell are you?
Damn it. I got caught.
Heiji-kun.
What are you wearing these weird masks for?!
Th-They were recruiting online.
100 thousand yen up front just for wearing a
tengu mask and running around Kiyamachi Way.
If you don't get caught for thirty minutes,
they said they'd pay a million.
Is that true?
Hattori!
Hattori, is it just those four
in the restaurant right now?
Yeah. We'd better head back soon.
Damn.
They got us.
It's the actor Ihaya-san this time.
Yeah. Sliced his carotid artery right open.
He's upside down with two
bumps on his head again.
What a strange culprit.
They must've taken the
time to make these marks
before inviting him out here to kill him.
No.
When we left ten minutes ago,
these marks weren't here.
Episode Preview
The blood spray and footprints
on the inuyarai...
A-Are we being tricked by a fox?
Huh?
There are weird marks around the inuyarai.
Did he just say "Huh?"
I don't have time to think
about that right now.
Time?
The Scarlet School Trip
(Red Love Arc)
The next special episode of Conan is
"The Scarlet School Trip, Red Love Arc!"
Next Conan's hint!
Movie Poster
A movie poster!
Let's say it again together.
Don't miss the next episode.
Thanks for another year!
Thank you!