I see. This was a blind spot.
We were watching the back door since
we expected passers-by out front.
But why did Ihaya-san go outside?
We told you guys to stay in your room.
We were going to the bathroom.
Mayama Mineto (38)
Movie Director
Ihaya, Agata, and I headed
to the bathroom together.
Ihaya said he was worried about
leaving Keiko-chan alone in the room,
Ihaya Shinya (37)
Actor
so he alone headed back.
Agata Riki (37)
Composer
I thought I saw him check his
messages before he headed back.
I see.
Did Ihaya-san return immediately to the room?
No.
I was afraid to stay alone in the room, so
I left for the bathroom shortly afterwards.
Kurachi Keiko (37)
Actress
It's possible he returned
after I left the room.
Ayanokoji Fumimaro (28)
Kyoto Police
Division One Inspector
How long were the two of you in the bathroom?
I left the bathroom right away,
but I got lost on the way back.
My stomach wasn't feeling great, so
I stayed in the bathroom for a while.
In other words, all three of
you could've messaged Ihaya-san
and murdered him.
What?
B-But...
We'd never do that!
Now, now. You're not wrong,
but the blood spray and
footprints on the inuyarai...
It looks like they were
painted on quite a while ago.
When you were here before
the body was discovered,
were these really not here?
Yes.
M-Maybe we're all being tricked by a fox.
What's this mark?
Huh?
What?
There are weird marks around the inuyarai.
Uh, oh. I did what I always do.
You're right. It goes all the way around it.
I wonder what it is.
Did he just say "Huh?"
He's doing an impression of that brat now?
How imprudent.
A-Anyway, was there a code?
Was it in his breast pocket again?
Yes.
Like Nishiki-san's murder,
it was there along with
this paper plant leaf.
The third cipher.
They left another nonsensical cipher?
And why are these four squares
at the beginning Dekuri's mark?
Maybe it's because the character
for "de" in Dekuri is formed
if you draw a big square around them.
Draw a big square around them, huh?
You're right.
Hattori, your phone's ringing.
Huh? Oh.
Incoming Call
Kazuha
Decline   Answer
It's Kazuha.
What is it, Kazuha? I'm—
Heiji, what are you doing?!
D-Didn't I tell you?
I'm really sick with a cold,
so I can't go to school.
Don't be ridiculous!
Actor Ihaya Moriya-san murdered!
Could it be a serial murderer?
I see you on TV!
What?
Oh, y-yeah.
I wandered over to Kyoto to find a
good luck charm that cures colds.
What?!
That's not a believable excuse.
I-In any case,
I need to solve a serial
murder case and crack a code.
Don't tell my parents about this.
Even I don't tell them,
Hey, Heiji-kun.
won't your parents know
if they see you on TV?
Those characters in the code remind
me of location names in Kyoto.
What?
This character is the "hisashi"
in the Kamigyo Ward's Hisashi-cho.
Kyoto City Kamigyo Ward
Hisashi-cho
To its left is the "to" in the
Shimogyo Ward's Tokusayama-cho.
Kyoto City Shimogyo Ward
Tokusayama-cho
To the left of that is the "adashi"
in the Ukyo Ward's Adashino.
Kyoto City Ukyo Ward
Adashino-cho
This is read "adashi?"
That's right.
Hold on.
If there are wards with top, bottom,
and right in their names, then...
Yes.
Kyoto contains the Kamigyo Ward, the
Nakagyo Ward, the Shimogyo Ward,
Kamigyo Ward
Nakagyo Ward
Shimogyo Ward
Sakyo Ward
the Sakyo Ward, and the Ukyo Ward.
Ukyo Ward
Top, middle, bottom, and left
and right are all represented.
Top
Right Middle Left
Bottom
What?
Then maybe this...
Could it be?
That must be it.
Hey, Heiji!
What?
I thought I heard Momiji-san's voice.
Why, little leaf. How have you been?
Mo!
Let me handle Heiji-kun.
You should focus on your studies.
I!
Goodbye, now.
I can't let you handle him, you idiot!
Can't let us handle it?
Are you going to clean the
classroom yourself, Kazuha?
That's not what I meant.
Jeez...
I believe we were in the
middle of our conversation.
Why don't you tell us this time
about the man named Dekuri who
came up with these three ciphers.
In my eyes are maximum creation!
My detective skills are tomorrow's reaction!
A serial murder stirs up trouble in Kyoto!
The tengu and the movie share
a surprising connection!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Scarlet School Trip
(Red Love Arc)
"The Scarlet School Trip, Red Love Arc!"
Ponto-cho Isogiyama
Dekuri Michio?
Was he also your classmate
at Gion Art School?
Y-Yes.
He was in fine arts, but
I was a music student.
I studied film.
Ihaya-kun and I were in the acting school.
And Nishiki was a literary arts student.
How did you get to know each other
when you studied different majors?
We all joined the special effects film club.
Dekuri was also in the comics club, though.
Every year, we'd show the movie
we filmed at the school festival.
I was always good at special effects.
Ihaya-kun and I were masters
of special effects makeup.
And I'd compose eerie music
for the completed film.
Nishiki would write the script,
and Dekuri would design the
costumes and monsters, right?
When Dekuri was busy with his comics,
we all pitched in.
Agata-kun was the only one who
was really useful, though.
Yeah.
But the name Dekuri doesn't
appear in the credits
of the graduation project
"The Fighting Red Tengu" is based on.
Why is that?
What? Why aren't you saying anything?
Nishiki was having trouble writing the
script for our graduation project.
That's when he found a self-published
comic Dekuri had produced.
It was a marvelous fantasy story.
It was "The Fighting
Red Tengu," wasn't it?
Yes.
Dekuri-kun said he planned
to officially publish it
once he became a
professional comic book artist,
so he asked us not to use it.
We thought Dekuri would accept it
once he saw the finished product,
so we decided to film his story.
And if we put his name in the credits,
it would be his graduation project, too.
But when he previewed the
film in our club room...
This isn't my work! You betrayed me!
Wait, Dekuri.
Don't put my name on it!
Dekuri-kun?
Later, our graduation project
received high praise.
The five of us were thrown
into the limelight.
He totally hates you.
But the night we announced the movie,
I got a call from Dekuri.
He said he'd given up on drawing comics
and was working at a small design firm.
He asked us to put his name in the credits
if we were going to remake that movie.
Dekuri-kun said it was his dream for his
comics to be adapted for the big screen.
Did you put his name in the credits?
We were going to, but there
was a little mistake.
When he saw his name wasn't in the
credits at the first screening,
he killed himself over the disappointment.
We even thought about canceling
the movie's release,
but our sponsors wouldn't let us.
I see.
Why?
Why are Heiji-kun and the others
allowed inside when we're not?
The little leaf left me to
look after Heiji for once.
He seems to have the trust
of Inspector Ayanokoji.
Seriously, who is he?
It's your job to do something about that.
Excuse me, Momiji-san.
What is it?
Where can I go to meet Okita-kun?
Well, that kendo brat
is probably practicing
in the dojo around now.
If you have a message for
him, I'll deliver it for you.
Actually, there's something I wanted
to discuss with him in person.
Huh?
It's you, Ran-chan.
What?
Okita-kun!
What are you doing here?
You brought all your henchmen with you.
I heard some tengu were running
wild on Kiyamachi Way,
so I brought the club to wipe them out.
Why, thank you.
He looks exactly like Shinichi-kun.
Does that mean...?
This girl says she wanted to see you.
Really?
So you did come to Kyoto
because you wanted to see me.
Oh, no.
C-Come with me.
Huh?
Kurachi Keiko?
Oh, Kyoko-chan.
We appeared in a lot of dramas together.
Of course, I always played the lead role.
Kyoko-chan? Not Keiko?
Her real name is Kyoko.
After all she went through over
her college graduation project,
she added the character for sun to
the top of "kyo" for "Kyoto,"
and made her stage name Keiko.
Really?
Speaking of names,
she said Nishiki-san and
Mayama-san changed their names
just for that graduation project, too.
They changed their names?
Yeah.
Mayama-san changed the mountain radical of
"mine" in "Mineto" from left to top,
Mineto
and Nishiki-san changed his
name from Taro to Tarobo.
Tarobo
Taro
Come to think of it, Japan's most
legendary tengu is named Tarobo, too.
Oh, yeah. Speaking of Kyoko-chan,
she fell in love during college
and hasn't gotten married
because she's still in love with him.
I see.
Is that man's name Dekuri Michio-kun?
No way. How did you know?
Hey, mom. That Dekuri guy...
How did you know?
She hung up.
A message from Sonoko?
What?
From: Suzuki Sonoko
Subject: Your wife is cheating on you
O-Okita?!
Wh-Why is Ran seeing Okita?
And what do their expressions mean?
Hey, Kudo.
What are you looking at?
Nothing.
Let's go.
G-Go where?
To the Gion Hotel.
When Nishiki-san tried to
reserve a smoking room,
at first they told him
they were fully booked,
but a reservation was canceled while he was
on the phone, so he got a room after all.
Curious, right?
Y-Yeah...
You're right.
I'm curious about this, too.
Yes, that's correct.
A reservation was canceled while we
were on the phone with Nishiki-sama.
He reserved the room for two
days starting yesterday.
I see.
Come to think of it, you
smoke, too, Agata-san.
Were you able to get a room right away?
Yeah.
Someone else canceled right
after Nishiki called.
We were gathered in Nishiki's apartment
and made our reservations together.
Right?
Yes.
Is this true?
After Nishiki-sama made a reservation,
someone else canceled, and
Agata-sama reserved the room.
It was a group of guests who canceled.
Speaking of Agata-san's room,
a giant tengu apparently appeared inside it.
Is it true that nothing strange
was found in the room after that?
Yes.
There was a glue-like substance
on the burned ceiling,
but it wasn't nearly enough
to support a large object.
There were also marks left by the
chair when Agata-san fell out of it
and a roughly three centimeter
burn in the carpet
when a cigarette fell from the
ashtray thrown at the tengu.
And for some reason, there was another
pillow in the middle of the bed.
Th-That's a habit of mine.
My legs cramp up if I don't
put a pillow under them.
What is it? Something in
that didn't sound right.
The glue on the ceiling...
The marks left by the chair...
I'm Okita Soshi.
The cigarette burn...
I wonder if we'll get to see Okita-kun.
The pillow in the center of the bed...
From: Suzuki Sonoko
Subject: Your wife is cheating on you
Your wife is cheating on you.
Damn it.
I can't focus on the case because I
keep thinking of that picture of them.
I don't have time to think
about that right now.
What? Time?
Shit. There it is.
It's sooner than yesterday.
H-Hey, Kudo. You okay?
Y-Yeah.
More importantly, I know who did it.
What?
Seriously?
B-But there's not enough
evidence to arrest them.
Then what are we going to do, Kudo?
Inspector Ayanokoji.
What is it?
Could I get s-some assistance
from the Kyoto police?
Yes, if we're able.
I-It may be a little... embarrassing, though.
In any case, since a new cipher was found
on the body of Ihaya-san yesterday,
The next day
the culprit may be planning
to kill another one of you.
Please remain in your rooms
until it's time to check out.
To be safe,
we'll be posting an officer
outside each of your rooms.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Hey, Kudo. Are you okay?
Yeah, just barely.
I took my medicine late this morning.
Your medicine?
Huh?
What medicine?
Cold medicine.
Really?
This has turned into quite the visit.
Yeah.
We never even made it to Dekuri's grave.
We'll have to go another time.
You're right.
See you later.
Yeah.
Your dream?
That's your dream, Dekuri-kun?
Yeah.
Seeing the words "based on a comic by
Dekuri Michio" on the big screen is my dream.
Really?
You'll really put my name in the credits?
Of course. You're the
one who wrote the story.
I'm glad.
What?
I've actually always regretted it.
Your graduation project was so well made,
I said that out of frustration.
I'm sorry. And thank you.
What's wrong, Dekuri?
We need to leave.
They're closing the theater.
That's odd.
No matter how long I wait,
my name never appears.
Isn't that strange?
Where are you going?
To the bathroom.
The bathroom in my room isn't working.
I'm going to the bathroom in the lobby.
I'll be right back.
Be careful.
Hello?
To Kiyomizu Temple.
Very well.
Hello?
Agata, how long are you
going to make me wait?
Wait? What are you talking about?
What?
You just sent me a message saying
you killed Nishiki and Ihaya,
Subject: It's Agata
I killed Nishiki and Ihaya.
There's something I want to tell you before the
police arrest me. Meet me at the Kiyomizu butai.
and wanted to talk to
me at the Kiyomizu butai
before the police arrested you.
What? I'd never send that.
Did you check the sender's address?
H-Hold on.
The sender's address is "chestnut@."
Chestnut...
Doesn't "kuri" mean chestnut?
Isn't that Dekuri's address?
That's right.
I'm the one who sent the message.
Me, Dekuri.
Th-That's impossible!
You're dead!
That's right.
After your betrayal,
in my despair, I threw myself from the
Kiyomizu butai and killed myself.
But...
In order to get my revenge, I've
returned from the underworld.
How could you trick me like that?
I'll never forgive you. Never.
I'll never forgive you!
N-No! Y-Your name was actually—
Apologize to Dekuri
in hell!
Why?
The butai is approximately 12 meters tall.
If you lay out a cushion beforehand,
you won't end up in the underworld,
Agata Riki-san.
How did you know I'd be here?
Did you crack the code?
Yes.
The key is the white cross-shape surrounded
by four black squares at
the top of the ciphers.
These refer to the Kamigyo,
Nakagyo, Shimogyo, Sakyo,
Top
Middle
Bottom
Left
Right
and Ukyo Wards of Kyoto.
The rest of the characters are
parts of location names in Kyoto.
Comparing them against the positions
of the characters in the white cross
tells you which location name they
refer to and how to read them.
Using that method,
the beginning of the cipher
sent to Nishiki-san contains...
"Kon" from Kamigyo Ward's Kontaka-cho.
"Ro" from Nakagyo Ward's Toroyama-cho.
"Suji" from Kamigyo
Ward's Sujikaibashi-cho.
"No" from Ukyo Ward's Adashino.
"Hate" from Sakyo Ward's Kamihate-cho.
If you string the first mora
in each character together,
you get "ko-ro-su-no-ha."
In other words, it becomes "I will kill."
The backwards character for "saki"
that appears occasionally
is the "pon" from
Nakagyo Ward's Ponto-cho.
If you flip them around, you get "nop,"
so you read it as just "n."
So the meaning of the first cipher is,
"I will kill three, starting
with the scriptwriter."
If you read the second cipher found
on Nishiki-san's body in the same way,
you get "two more to
kill, next is the star."
The third cipher reads,
"one more to kill, then
I'll fall from the butai."
After making Mayama-san's
death look like a suicide,
you probably intended to announce you
figured out how to read the code,
making it look like the third cipher
was Mayama-san's suicide note,
but because you wrote where
you'd commit suicide,
we were able to beat you here.
I-It's the curse.
It's the curse!
It's some curse that made me do all of this!
Didn't you see the ceiling in Nishiki's room?
A human couldn't have done
that in less than ten minutes!
Electrostatic notes.
By using static electricity, they can be
stuck to any wall or object without an adhesive.
You used the notes Nishiki-san
used to revise the script.
You started by staying in
that room the day before
and painting the blood spray and footprints
on the ceiling, allowing them to dry.
You hid them by covering the entire
ceiling with electrostatic notes.
Naturally, you reserved that smoking
room for the next day as well.
You also reserved every other smoking room,
and canceled your reservation
for the room painted with blood...
when Nishiki-san called the hotel,
Cancel your reservation?
Yes   No
allowing you to force Nishiki-san
to stay in that room.
After killing Nishiki-san,
you ran a rod over the
ceiling to remove the notes
and scattered Nishiki-san's script among
them in order to conceal your trick.
Then you sucked some of Nishiki-san's
blood into a syringe
and sprayed it at the center of the
blood spray you painted on the ceiling.
Wh-What about the tengu, then?
What about the giant tengu
that suddenly appeared
and vanished in my room?!
You were the only one who was useful when
you helped Dekuri-san with his comics.
Surely you were artistic and
dexterous enough to build
a paper mache tengu of about that size.
If you made it using the
flash paper magicians use,
just being exposed to the flame of a
cigarette would make it go up in flames.
The three centimeter cigarette
burn left in your room proves it.
If you screamed when you noticed the
tengu after lighting a cigarette
and waited to throw your ashtray at the
tengu after we arrived and opened the door
then it doesn't make sense for so much
of your cigarette to have remained.
In other words,
you lit your cigarette just
before we opened the door,
even though you should have been too
surprised by the tengu to do that.
Additionally, you painted the footprints
on the inuyarai present at
Ihaya-san's murder during the night,
and placed a larger inuyarai over it.
After killing him, you removed that
inuyarai, revealing the footprints,
and placed it over a different inuyarai.
Apparently they found all kinds
of stuff under that inuyarai,
like the murder weapon and a raincoat
covered in the victim's blood.
You probably wiped your prints from them
so you could make it look like
Mayama-san did it, though.
Wh-What are you talking about?
Weren't you watching?
Mayama was trying to climb over this railing!
He must've been possessed by—
No.
All that's here are these
clear electrostatic notes
with red footprints painted on them.
If you layered notes the same color
as the floorboards over them,
you could hide the footprints.
Because you attached nylon string to
them and removed them one at a time,
it looked to Mayama-san like the bloody
footprints were approaching him.
Additionally, you used
this directional speaker
so only Mayama-san would
hear this horrifying voice.
I'll never forgive you. Never.
It's no wonder he was desperate to get away.
Since you probably planned
to retrieve the notes
and speaker during the commotion
caused by his suicide,
your fingerprints should be on them.
Damn it!
Move, you brats!
What?
Sorry.
He asked the Kyoto police to
wear their old school uniforms
and pretend to be students on a trip
so you wouldn't be on your guard.
No way...
Damn.
Damn!
I don't get it, though.
Why did you put two bumps on the bodies?
It's the Kobutori Jisan folktale.
The bad man incurred the wrath of a tengu
when he copied the good man
and was given two bumps.
When I saw the bumps
Keiko got during filming,
I decided to incorporate it into my plan.
Was your motive the absence of
Dekuri's name in the credits?
Yeah.
When I told them during the after-party
that Dekuri sat stunned in
the theater, they said,
"Really? He was that surprised?"
"We did it. Well done, everyone."
But wasn't it a mistake?
I thought so, too, but was perplexed
after I checked with the staff.
They said they fixed the credits,
but instead of removing someone's name, they
just adjusted the spacing of some characters.
They never intended to include Dekuri's name!
They only invited Dekuri to the
screening so they could laugh at him!
You're wrong, Agata-kun!
They had to fix the spacing
of the characters!
It's too late for that.
Agata.
These are the credits that were
supposed to appear after the movie.
We had all five of our
names displayed at once,
changed our names,
and unevenly spaced our names
Dekuri Michio
so the name Dekuri Michio
would appear with ours.
N-No...
We wanted his name to appear as
the author of the original work,
but our producers said they
couldn't pay another staff member,
so we did this instead.
Since he loved ciphers so
much, we thought he'd notice.
We did the same thing in
our graduation project.
We wanted to express our gratitude to him.
We didn't tell you since you
and Dekuri were friends.
We wanted you to be surprised together.
We're sorry.
What have I done?
Kiyomizu Temple trembled with the
remorseful wail of the killer,
as though the red leaves surrounding it
had gone up in flames and withered.
They're late.
Yeah.
Oh, they're here. Shinichi!
Sorry I'm late.
Did you catch the culprit?
Yeah.
But you don't need to worry about it.
What's your problem?
We changed our plans so
we could meet up with you.
It was an unpleasant case.
Anyway, we still have some time.
Should we go somewhere?
Let's go to Kitano Tenmangu.
Okita-kun mentioned it before.
Nice. Let's go.
It's pretty far away.
How do we get there?
Hey.
How do you feel?
About what?
About me.
I heard you met with Okita yesterday.
You haven't forgotten that I confessed
my feelings to you in London—
I heard you met with Okita yesterday.
You haven't forgotten that I confessed
my feelings to you in London—
That's my answer.
Is that not good enough?
You—
You can't do that.
Not on the cheek.
Be still, my heart.
Listen to me, just this once.
Wait, which is this?
Which heartbeat is this?
Damn it! I knew it was this one!
Shinichi?
Sorry, Ran. A case is calling me.
I'll see you later.
Shinichi!
Seriously? He even had
you waiting for a kiss.
You were watching?
Well, yeah.
What did he say?
Huh? Oh, he said he got a call from a case.
But he didn't look well.
What?
Sera-chan?
What? A high school student
who had a hard time walking?
Yeah, a male high school
student who looks like this.
Did he pass through the Todoroki-mon?
I'm not sure.
I don't look at every student
who comes through here.
I see.
If you're looking for Kudo,
he just went running that way.
Maybe he went to the bathroom.
Really? The bathroom?
By the way, what's with the backpack?
Why wouldn't I have a backpack?
It looks pretty heavy.
Can I check what's inside?
Y-You idiot! I'm not showing you!
I've got underwear and other
stuff you shouldn't see in there!
Like porn magazines?
Yeah, really filthy hardcore stuff.
Wow.
Huh? There's a Teitan uniform
poking out of your bag.
What?
Just kidding.
Hey, Kudo.
Are you sure that snaggle-toothed
girl doesn't know your true identity?
Yeah, it's not good.
What?
Oh.
What is it?
Sorry, it's nothing. Bye.
I'm so surprised.
She's a girl after all.
We just received word that
Kudo Shinichi-kun of class 2-B
can't continue on the school
trip due to urgent business.
What?
Also, he'd prefer to keep his
involvement in the case secret,
so he asks that you not
mention it on social media!
Okay...
I was going to ask him about
the case on the way back.
I guess we can ask Sera-chan.
I can't believe that wannabe
detective actually left.
He never gave you a kiss.
Don't say that!
Also, Shinichi knew that
I met with Okita-kun.
I sent Shinichi-kun a picture
of your clandestine meeting.
So, what were you two talking about?
We were talking after I
delivered something to him.
Detective Sato gave me this good luck charm.
She said you dropped it
during the kendo tournament.
I've been looking for this. Thanks.
A-Anyway, so...
I left that charm on the desk
at the detective agency,
and my dad...
What's this good luck charm?
Is it Ran's?
There's something inside.
It's probably a picture of
that detective kid or...
What?
Dad, what are you looking at?
You looked at the picture?
Yes, I wasn't thinking.
Anyway, um...
Is that girl in the photo your girlfriend?
What?
I got curious,
so I thought I'd ask when I saw you.
No, she's not my girlfriend.
Not now, anyway.
You like her, then?
I think you'd make a good couple.
She's my rival's sister.
I can't tell her how I feel until I beat him.
Really?
Don't tell tits over there about this.
Tits?
I'll never hear the end
of it if she finds out.
That's all we talked about.
Really?
So you weren't cheating with his doppelganger
because you were frustrated
with your unreliable husband?
It's not cheating.
Thanks to that photo, you nearly got to kiss.
You should be grateful.
Listen here...
Hey, Mori.
H-How did it feel to k-kiss him?
How did it feel?
Aren't you asking the wrong person?
I only kissed him on the cheek.
It was only on the cheek,
but I kissed him like I was ready
to leap from the Kiyomizu butai.
But he...
It's from Shinichi.
From: Kudo Shinichi
Subject: No subject
Sorry, Ran.
I wish I could've stayed
with you a little longer,
but it didn't work out that way.
But I'm really glad I got to hear
your response to my confession.
Thanks.
Jeez.
I guess I'll forgive him.
Yeah.
There seems to be a medicine
that can restore your body, Mom.
Then we'll do whatever it takes to
find the inventor of this medicine,
and obtain the medicine itself.
Once I'm back in my old body,
no more running around.
We'll begin our counterattack.
Don't mess this up, Masumi.
Don't play with your phone
while we're driving.
It's dangerous.
I'm just going to look.
From: Ran
Subject: Thanks for the message
Thanks for the message.
This means we're dating, right?
Oh, man. I wish I could respond right now.
Anyway, I really panicked.
I had to stuff you into my bag while
you were shrinking before my eyes.
You should've told me before it happened.
It wasn't so easy for me, either.
Did something happen?
I-If you weren't watching,
don't worry about it.
Yeah, I didn't see anything.
I definitely didn't see you and that
girl smooching at the Kiyomizu butai.
So you were watching!
Listen, it was in the spur of the moment...
Damn it.
The Kiyomizu butai was next on my list of
breathtaking places to confess my feelings.
And they even kissed?
Damn it.
Making things harder when he doesn't need to.
It's all over the news here, too.
Of course it is.
The victims and the killer were famous.
I'm surprised, though.
The killer's motive was the suicide
of the man Kyoko-chan loved.
Yeah.
By the way, how did you know
Dekuri Michio-kun's name?
From the movie poster.
What?
Dekuri-kun's name wasn't on the poster.
I thought there might be some reason
your actress friend changed her name.
Director: Mayama Mineto
Script: Nishiki Tarobo
Actor: Ihaya Shinya
Supporting Actress: Kurachi Keiko
Music: Agata Riki
If you cover the top and bottom of
these unevenly spaced characters...
Oh, you're right.
Dekuri Michio
It says Dekuri Michio.
Since the poster was made
after the first screening,
it's possible Dekuri-kun
wouldn't have killed himself
and Agata-kun wouldn't have killed
anybody if they'd seen it.
Yeah.
The problem is how Shinichi,
the boy who shouldn't exist,
somehow solved this internationally
newsworthy case.
They're still only reporting that the case was
solved by a group of high school detectives, though.
It'll be fine.
Shin-chan's really thorough
when it comes to that.
I'm sure he asked them to keep it secret.
Mori Detective Agency
I'm home!
Great...
Your daughter's back from her school trip.
You should be welcoming her home.
Is Conan-kun upstairs?
No new messages
He still hasn't responded.
Did Shinichi read my message?
This means we're
dating, right?
Ran
Are you listening, Kudo?
When we get to Tokyo,
you're buying me a steak.
Yeah.
Not a cheap one, either.
One oozing with juices and, you know...
A really, really good one.
I know.
I'll treat you. Don't worry about it.
I shouldn't have offered
to take you back to Tokyo.
Preview   Send
Sending
A message.
From Shinichi?
From: Kudo Shinichi
Subject: Idiot
Of course we're dating.
Shinichi
This means we're dating, right?
Of course we're dating.