Ouch...
Don't.
Don't touch it.
But it's just a little scrape.
I know,
but we should put some medicine on it.
My apartment is nearby.
B-But...
Children shouldn't be so reserved.
Midorikawa Saki
Give me a minute.
Let's see...
Oh, there it is.
Let me see it.
First we'll disinfect it.
This will sting a little.
Ouch...
Be strong.
Good girl.
Okay, good.
Thanks, miss.
Want something to drink?
All I have is tea and orange juice.
Oh, but...
O-Orange juice, then.
Orange juice it is.
Here you go.
Thanks for the drink!
She's so pretty and nice.
Miss.
You have a boyfriend.
Huh?
So they have a friend over.
A friend?
Nothing.
She saw me!
In my eyes are maximum creation!
My detective skills are tomorrow's reaction!
A dark shadow lurks in a
beautiful woman's eyes!
It's a strange case connected to her window!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Woman Standing in the Window
(Part One)
"The Woman Standing in the Window, Part One!"
We're really going?
Don't you want to see her, too?
She's pretty and nice.
Why not? Just imagine
it's good for your eyes.
You, too?
That's Midorikawa Saki-san.
She really is pretty.
Yeah.
I heard she was good-natured
and cheerful, but...
She seems kind of lonely.
And what's she looking at?
Come to think of it, she
was looking yesterday, too.
Midorikawa Saki (28)
You go to the gym?
For your beauty and health?
No. My body's important for work.
What's your job?
What do you think?
What were you looking at from your window?
What? Who knows?
This is my stop. See you later.
She's mysterious.
Kind of, yeah.
What's wrong with being mysterious?!
Yeah!
Let's start looking for cases!
Since our long weekend starts today,
I'd like to solve a big case.
You really think you'll find
a big case just lying around?
What's wrong with that car?
It's out of control!
Excuse me.
What's going on?
It's her.
Dojima Tatsuko (43)
Social Critic
Tachibana Junnosuke (33)
Women's University Professor
Konno Michiyo (24)
Office Worker
Is something wrong?
Let's see...
What a terrible accident.
Dojima-sensei.
I was so surprised by the loud noise.
Well, we'd only get in the way here.
Y-You're right.
Let's go.
They were glaring at the nice lady.
I wonder what that was about.
You're here, too?
Saki-san, have you done anything
to make people resent you?
Well, when you live twenty and some years...
Do you have some idea?
I'm kidding.
I haven't done anything like that.
Oh, no. I need to get to work.
Later.
Work? I wonder what she does.
Hey.
Did something happen
between you and that lady?
What?
N-No.
I have no idea what you mean.
All three of them were startled.
And they tried to play it off by smiling.
Something must be up.
But I don't see how anyone
could hate the nice lady.
It's possible she incurred their
hatred without realizing it.
Like a misunder-handstand.
You mean a misunderstanding?
Let's check it out.
I wonder who they are.
Seems like all three of them live here.
Um...
Excuse me.
Ogi Kyoichi (58)
Apartment Manager
Huh?
What do those three people do?
Tachibana Junnosuke-sensei of room 102
is an English literature professor
at Beika Women's University.
Good morning!
I told you not to come to my apartment.
Right?
I'm jealous, Tachibana-sensei.
He's so popular with his
students because he's handsome.
Good morning.
See you later.
Konno Michiyo-san of room
302 works at a trading firm.
She's nothing if not earnest and polite.
She's a good girl.
Dojima Tatsuko-sensei of room
1107 is a social critic.
An information program on TV?
That's right.
They're going to have me on
as a regular commentator.
Someone finally realized my talent.
Took them long enough!
Now the entire country will
know your name and face.
Well, yeah.
Well, I'm sure she's capable.
Tachibana Junnosuke-san of room 102.
Konno Michiyo-san of room 302.
Dojima Tatsuko-san of room 1107.
A college professor, a serious office worker,
and a social critic asked to appear on TV.
They all sound like decent people.
No one strange lives here.
I guess we were worried for nothing.
That's good.
I hope you're right.
The water has stopped.
Let's keep looking for a case!
There must be something about those three.
Huh?
What's wrong?
Of course. Then naturally, from here...
You can see them.
Yeah.
You can't see room 1107, but
you can see rooms 102 and 302.
That's Tachibana-sensei and
Konno the office worker.
If we can see them from here, then they
must be visible from her apartment, too.
Maybe she was looking out her window
and saw them doing something.
Something they didn't want her to see.
Saki-san herself probably
hasn't realized what she saw.
It's possible she does know
and she's just playing dumb.
What? Why would she do that?
I'm just speaking hypothetically.
Tachibana-sama
So she was watching.
I saw it all. I'll tell. If you don't want me to tell,
you'll have to pay me. Don't bother contacting the police.
I saw it all
If you don't want me to tell
The woman who knows your secret
I wonder what she saw.
We're going to ask her that right now.
It's not clear if Saki-san herself
is aware of what she saw.
I sure hope none of them resent
her over a misunderstanding.
She saw something they
didn't want her to see...
That voice!
Wasn't that her?
Miss!
What happened?
A car...
A car crashed into you?
No, I was thinking and accidentally
tried to cross when it was red.
And a car nearly hit you.
You should be careful.
You're right.
We thought you were attacked
over a misunderstanding.
What?
Saki-san, there's something
we want to ask you.
Sorry, but my heart's still pounding.
Ask me another time.
She seems pretty shocked over
nearly being in an accident.
Then let's go ask them what she saw.
There's no way they'd tell us.
Let's take our chances.
You heard them.
I understand Tachibana-sensei
and Konno Michiyo-san,
but what about Dojima Tatsuko-san?
Room 1107 isn't visible
from Saki-san's apartment.
There's no guarantee she
saw it from her apartment.
I see.
It's possible she witnessed whatever
it was from somewhere else.
I wonder what she saw, though.
For example...
Maybe she shoplifted something,
or cursed someone,
or killed someone!
I'm sure she'd call the police
immediately if she saw that.
Normally, yeah.
In any case, we'll know once we ask them.
All three of them are out right now?
We can't take any chances if they're out.
Let's wait for them to return.
Wait?
Hello.
Oh, from this afternoon...
We're actually the Detective Boys.
That woman from this afternoon saw you doing
something you shouldn't have, didn't she?
Like what?
We were hoping you'd tell us.
Why would she have seen something like that?
You were glaring at her, right?
That's because she seemed like
a pretty, cheerful person.
What?
I was jealous.
I'm not pretty...
And I'm gloomy...
So that's why?
Oh, I definitely glared at her.
Is it because she saw
you doing something bad?
Because she looked like the cousin
I've hated since I was a child.
So that's why?
Huh?
Yeah, she looked like her.
The girl who rejected me amidst
a flurry of falling leaves
behind the school building one autumn day
during my second year of middle school!
Oh, it aches. The old wound aches.
Like the falling maple leaves,
so does my heart bleed!
Farewell, children.
I am—
Once we got to know them, not a
single one of them was decent.
In other words, you imagined
all of it, Conan-kun.
Yeah.
Hey, wait! You guys were worried, too!
Right?
You're ignoring me?
I'm glad, though.
It had nothing to do with Saki-san.
Let's go home.
Good night.
Welcome.
Thank you.
It's their fault for allowing
themselves to be blackmailed.
Right?
No one's going to kill me.
See you later.
Good morning.
Dojima-sensei, did you find
what you were looking for?
No. I thought I dropped it around here.
She suddenly fell from up there!
Sensei, pull yourself together.
I called the police.
Was there an accident?!
Miss!
She's dead? No...
What's going on?
What happened?
Episode Preview
There were scratch marks
on the railing on the roof.
We also found a woman's
earring on the ground.
But who, and why?
A car almost struck Saki-san at
an intersection yesterday.
I thought I saw them from my window.
There's only signs of water on this side.
She didn't come to the roof.
The Woman Standing in the Window
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The Woman
Standing in the Window, Part Two!”
Gloves
Next Conan's hint!
Gloves!
Don't miss the next episode.
So we weren't imagining things.
Doesn't look like it.
Miss...