The Detective Boys met a woman
named Midorikawa Saki-san.
She helped Ayumi-chan when
she tripped and hurt herself.
Midorikawa Saki (28)
We thought Saki-san was a
kind, good-natured person,
but shortly afterwards, we
noticed something strange:
there were three people glaring at her.
Tachibana Junnosuke (33)
Women's University Professor
Women's university professor
Tachibana Junnosuke-san.
Konno Michiyo (24)
Office Worker
Officer worker Konno Michiyo-san.
Dojima Tatsuko (43)
Social Critic
And social critic Dojima Tatsuko-san.
And then...
Dojima-sensei, did you find
what you were looking for?
No. I thought I dropped it around here.
In my eyes are maximum creation!
My detective skills are tomorrow's reaction!
A beautiful woman falls from a building!
What are the three mysteries
connected to her window?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Woman Standing in the Window
(Part Two)
“The Woman Standing in
the Window, Part Two!”
Looks like she fell to her death.
Yeah.
Did she fall from the roof?
I knew it.
Ma'am, you were at the
intersection yesterday, right?
What did you know?
Nakabayashi Naka (73)
The same thing happened to her yesterday.
Miss!
What happened?
Did someone push her?
So she was nearly killed yesterday, too.
Who pushed her?
I don't know!
Don't bring me into this!
Sounds like Saki-san may have been murdered.
The culprit came back to finish her off.
But who, and why?
Those three...
They're suspicious.
Indeed.
Saki-san hid the attempt on her life.
It would've been natural for
her to report it to the police.
Which means there was
some reason she couldn't.
But what would that be?
We don't know that yet.
Please clear a path.
Stand back, please.
Excuse me.
Hello, sir.
I told you, I was just looking
for a ring I happened to drop.
That's when...
She came crashing down right before my eyes!
She was here at the time of the incident.
Apparently.
The deceased is Midorikawa
Saki-san, twenty-eight years old.
She lived in an apartment across the street.
She worked as a dancer as
at a pub on third street.
So she was a dancer.
Someone fell to their death?
Akabane Towa (26)
So scary. How ominous.
She seems to live here, too.
Yeah. It looked like she
was returning from a trip.
Excuse me.
Can I leave now? I'm feeling dizzy.
Very well.
Goodbye, then.
Why did she kill herself?
I know, right?
Detective Takagi, about
Midorikawa Saki-san...
You kids are here?
Inspector Megure, the victim seems
to have fallen from the roof.
There were scratch marks
on the railing on the roof.
We also found a woman's
earring on the ground.
They match.
The building's security cameras also
captured the victim heading to the roof.
Was Saki-san wearing gloves then?
What?
No, she wasn't.
I see.
The victim took the elevator to
the 11th floor and got off there.
The stairs have to be
taken to reach the roof,
but she didn't fall until an hour later.
Then there's her phone.
Her last incoming call was
from a nearby payphone.
She came to this building
shortly after receiving it.
Which means the person who called
invited her up to a roof,
where they got into a fight.
So it's possible she was pushed.
Yes.
Excuse me.
Yes, I see.
Got it.
According to the victim's colleagues,
she used to be a good-natured
woman well-liked by everyone.
I knew it!
But for whatever reason,
her personality suddenly
changed about three years ago.
She started extorting
coworkers and customers.
People didn't think highly of her.
I see. I'm going to watch the autopsy.
You two question the
people she was extorting.
Yes, sir.
We'll start with her coworkers.
Hey, Detective Takagi.
Saki-san was pushed at an
intersection yesterday.
What?
What do you mean?
And there are three people who
have been glaring at Saki-san.
We should talk to those three.
Yeah, although Dojima-san has an alibi.
I don't know anything about her.
She saw you doing something unsavory
from that window, didn't she?
And she was blackmailing you with
it, right, Tachibana-san?
I did receive a threatening letter yesterday.
Could we take a look at it?
“I saw it all. I'll tell. Don't even
think about contacting the police.”
“The woman who knows your secret.”
So you hastily attempted
to silence her yesterday,
but when you failed, you tried again today.
No! I was here in my apartment when she fell!
And I have an alibi for yesterday.
If my students find out, my
popularity with them will be over.
He's innocent as far as
the attempted murder goes.
Over? What did she see?
You're still under suspicion for the murder.
I took this off without thinking.
It's so hot...
This moment never gets old.
She saw me...
But I didn't kill her!
Let's withhold judgment until we talk
to Konno Michiyo the office worker.
This arrived today.
It's the same as Tachibana-san's.
Yeah.
But I'd never do that.
I was here when that woman died.
After all, Saki-san called
me and told me to stay here.
Saki-san called you?
What did she say?
I suppose it can't be helped.
It's better than being framed for murder.
Wait in your apartment.
We need to talk...
about how you tried
to silence me yesterday.
She knows!
Then...
That's right. If she told anyone...
What did she see you doing?
I heard a wealthy man was looking for a
love child he conceived a long time ago.
I disguised myself as Konno Michiyo
in order to blackmail him, but...
A bulge...
She's flat...
Yeah. My real name is Numagaki Daihachi.
Numagaki Daihachi (32)
I'm a man.
Driver's License
Numagaki Daihachi
And she saw me.
Nothing beats this.
Being a woman is so restricting.
She even sent me that letter.
We're arresting him for
attempted murder and fraud.
I didn't do it!
Hey, wait!
What?
They found sedatives in the body?
So you drugged her with sedatives
before you pushed her.
I told you, I was in my apartment!
So it was him.
But that letter and phone
call were clearly...
I see.
She might've seen their
secrets while I was over.
After all, she said...
So they have a friend over.
A friend?
Maybe she thought he was someone else
since he looked different from usual.
No, wait. That's—
I'm the one who called the police!
I live in room 202! My name is Akabane!
I'd been traveling since
the day before yesterday,
and when I returned, all
my jewels had vanished!
Sounds like she was robbed.
We saw her this morning. Come think of it...
So scary. How ominous.
And room 202...
Then the friend Saki-san saw was...
Conan-kun!
We can see it.
It's certainly possible.
So she saw the thief.
But isn't that unrelated to the murder?
Numagaki's the one who killed her.
But we still don't know...
Anyway, she lived rather frugally
for someone blackmailing people.
Maybe that's her boyfriend.
Excuse me, ma'am.
His name was Suenaga Ryo.
They lived here together.
But he suddenly moved out.
He forced his shady debts onto Saki-chan.
That was three autumns ago.
Wait a minute!
She started extorting people
to pay off his debts?
And she was living frugally because of it.
Omori Hiroe (60)
Landlady
Saki-chan must have really loved Suenaga-san.
She waited for him, believing
he'd someday return.
It sounds like she often looked
out her window, but was that...?
Saki-chan, you're soaked.
I thought I saw him from the window.
She started sitting in her window after that.
She was waiting for him
for three whole years.
Did you tell anyone that Saki-san was
waiting for Suenaga-san to return?
Yes, I told that detective woman last night.
She asked me to tell her all about it
since her investigation was
very important to Saki-chan.
I've got it.
It even explains how they got
Saki-san to come to the crime scene.
Th-They?
Dojima Tatsuko, the woman
who killed Saki-san.
But she has an alibi.
She was on the ground when Saki-san fell.
And of course, not by coincidence.
I know that her apartment room
1107 is directly above here,
and the trick she used.
Could it be?
The woman in room 202 lost
her key about a week ago.
Apparently the key was turned
in to the building manager.
She must've made a spare key then.
Dojima received the offer to be a regular
guest on a TV show yesterday afternoon.
That's after the theft occurred.
That's why she needed to silence her.
Is she meeting with the TV station staff?
Hey, Detective Takagi.
Conan-kun!
There are only signs of water on this side.
So that's how she did it.
That's why she used gloves and sedatives.
Is it possible that she...?
She must've bought them in a hurry.
It sounds like you've figured it all out.
But I need your help now.
What do you mean, you want my advice?
Apparently Midorikawa Saki-san was murdered,
but there are some things us
Detective Boys can't figure out.
Since you're such a great social critic,
we thought we could use your advice.
Fine, then. Well?
When she died, Saki-san was wearing gloves.
I wonder why.
To protect her hands from UV rays, right?
It's possible the culprit put them on her.
Why would they do that
to push her off a roof?
Because she didn't come to the roof.
That's why they put the gloves on her.
They needed it to make sense that Saki-san's
fingerprints weren't on the door to the roof.
After exiting the elevator on the 11th floor,
she visited you in room 1107.
Hey, listen—
Why don't you wait until
we're finished to respond?
On a whim, you made a
spare of the key you found
and robbed room 202.
And then...
Saki-san saw you.
She saw me!
That can't be good.
Your theft would surely be discovered,
and even if Saki-san's memory was hazy,
if you started appearing on
TV, she was sure to notice.
In a hurry to silence her,
you noticed there were others
who didn't like Saki-san.
You realized she'd seen their secrets, too.
And you used that against them!
Impersonating Saki-san, you delivered
the letters so they would silence her.
And Numagaki fell for it.
But he failed, and Saki-san
hid the attempt on her life.
I was thinking and accidentally
tried to cross when it was red.
Since she knew she'd incurred the ire of
others, she thought that's what it was.
Next you plotted to frame Numagaki-san.
You impersonated Saki-san and called
Numagaki-san on the phone so he wouldn't have an alibi.
Wait in your apartment.
We need to talk...
Then you invited Saki-san
to your own apartment.
You used the information you got
from the landlady the night before
and lied about having
information about Suenaga-san.
Saki-san gleefully ran over, and you
put her to sleep using sedatives.
You made it look like she
was pushed from the roof.
You placed Saki-san on the platform made from
the materials and ice you bought last night.
Then you pretended to look for a lost
item on the ground and waited
for the ice to melt and Saki-san to fall.
That gave you an alibi,
and nobody noticed the
contraption on your balcony
because of the balloons you used to hide her.
This is ridiculous. It's all just conjecture.
You don't have a single piece of evidence.
One of the balloons was
missing from its string.
There was a thin scratch on Saki-san's neck.
I thought maybe got caught
on it when she fell.
So we searched for the balloon together.
You kids were right about this.
The abrasion on Midorikawa Saki-san's neck and
the shape of the string were a perfect match.
And we found fingerprints matching the
ones on your lease on the balloon.
A single balloon i-i-isn't evidence!
But that connects you to
the deceased Saki-san.
The police can search your apartment now.
I'm sure they'll find all kinds of things.
The woman in room 202 was an eyesore!
Despite being so stupid,
she wore all those jewels!
I swiped them because she needed
to be brought down a peg!
But she...
Have we met recently?
It's her fault for witnessing it.
Once the robbery was discovered,
Saki-san might have blackmailed you.
That woman was evil!
Being evil doesn't give
you the right to kill her!
She was also a kind person,
waiting for her beloved to return.
Be careful, Genta-kun.
Someone might be watching you.
You'd better be careful.
I bet Conan's got way more to hide than me.
Don't redirect the question at me!
Wow, he's right.
Episode Preview
We accompanied the old man to Kokura, Fukuoka,
for the Japanese Detective
League's award ceremony
so he could accept his Best Detective Award.
He was hospitalized for an injury?
He hit his head when he fell.
He's still unconscious.
Could we keep what I'm about
to tell you between us?
Sorry, but could you be
my girlfriend for a bit?
What?!
The Northern Kyushu Mystery Tour
(Kokura Arc)
The next episode of Conan is “The Northern
Kyushu Mystery Tour, Kokura Arc!”
Graffiti
Next Conan's hint.
Graffiti!
The walls have ears, the sliding doors have—
Don't miss the next episode.
Eyes?
No, Tom.
What? Who's Tom?