We accompanied the
old man to Kokura, Fukuoka,
for the Japanese Detective
League's award ceremony
so he could accept his Best Detective Award.
We've arrived in Kokura.
Kokura Station
The award ceremony starts at
seven, so we have plenty of time.
I know. I should give him a call.
Conan-kun, let's visit Munakata first.
Munakata?
I've always wanted to visit Munakata
Taisha and Miyajidake Shrine.
He's not answering.
And, and...
Who are you calling?
This camphor tree is
huge. I'd love to see it.
My senior from the MPD
runs a company in Kokura.
There's even a roadside station.
That might be a good place to
shop for souvenirs for Mom.
Your senior from the MPD?
Fukamachi Torazo.
Also, also...
I'm sure Mojiko Retro is photogenic.
They called him the Tiger of Sakuradamon.
The Tiger of Sakuradamon?
I need to buy souvenirs for
Mom, Sonoko, Sera-chan,
He's not answering.
Let's head over to his
office and surprise him.
Shinichi...
What? Hey!
You promised we'd go
sightseeing this afternoon!
We came all the way to Kokura.
We can afford to stop by.
Then you should go by yourself.
B-But...
I'd like to meet the Tiger
of Sakuradamon, too.
What?
But, Conan-kun...
And I'd be worried about leaving him alone.
Let's meet back here around lunch.
Okay!
But I wanted to go sightseeing together...
This is Northern Kyushu
In my eyes are maximum creation!
My detective skills are tomorrow's reaction!
The old man's been given a detective award?
Something's happening in Northern Kyushu!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Northern Kyushu Mystery Tour
(Kokura Arc)
"The Northern Kyushu
Mystery Tour, Kokura Arc!"
Wakato Bridge
Old Furukawa Mining Wakamatsu Building
Tiger Trading
He was hospitalized for an injury?
Yes.
Kiriyama Eisaku (45)
Tiger Trading Managing Director
A week ago, he hit his head when he fell.
He's still unconscious.
He's unconscious?
How did he fall?
Tell us exactly what happened.
Izumi-kun, tell them.
Yes, sir.
The president injured his
knee several years ago.
Izumi Noriko (28)
President's Secretary
As part of his rehabilitation, every
morning he takes a walk around the office.
Fukamachi Torazo (63)
Tiger Trading President
That day, he tripped on a parking block.
I found him on the ground and
called an ambulance immediately.
Which hospital is he staying at?
If you're hoping to visit him, don't.
You'd be hindering his treatment.
But...
Mister, don't be unreasonable.
Shut up.
By the way, Mori-san, I heard
you're a great detective.
Well, I don't mean to brag,
but I was chosen for the
Best Detective Award.
In that case, could you
catch a culprit for us?
A culprit?
You mean his injury wasn't an accident?
No, that's not what I mean.
Someone vandalized our office.
Vandalized?
Tiger
Tiger?
Who found this?
I did.
Who are you?
I'm the president's driver. My name is Ukaji.
Ukaji Makoto (42)
President's Driver
Three days ago, this was here when
I arrived for work in the morning.
This isn't the only place.
Tiger
It's also on the office parking
lot, the wall of the warehouse,
and even on the front door of my home.
Your front door?
Yes. It's clearly meant to threaten me.
Threaten you how?
The truth is, the stockholders' meeting
scheduled for this afternoon at three
will decide that if President Fukamachi
is unable to return to work,
I will become the next president.
Torahiko-kun must have heard about it.
Torahiko?
President Fukamachi's son.
He attends a university in Tokyo,
but we haven't been able
to get in touch with him
since he heard about the
accident and came home.
Torahiko was lazy and a handful.
In high school, he was suspended
for writing similar graffiti.
He also caused an uproar by
using fireworks to build a bomb.
He's gotten in trouble with the
police more than a couple of times.
He probably assumed he'd take
over his father's position.
So he's threatening you so you
won't become the company president?
If we don't do something, it's
possible he'll hurt the director.
Have you told the police?
We did, but they said the graffiti alone
would only allow them to investigate it
as a case of vandalism and trespassing.
Do you have proof that Torahiko-san did it?
I told you to shut up.
There's a witness.
A witness?
Iwata-san the security guard
saw the culprit fleeing.
Where is he now?
He should be at the warehouse on
the opposite side of the river.
It takes five minutes by
boat. I'll take you there.
Thank you.
Mister, I want to go, too.
You'd be in the way. Wait here.
Your necktie is crooked.
Shall we go?
Yes.
Be careful.
Tiger Trading
Miyajidake Shrine
President's Office
What?
Dad's doing what?
Yeah.
He went to gather information
with the secretary, Izumi-san,
in order to find the person
who graffitied the buildings.
Should he have accepted that job?
Where are you right now?
Miyajidake Shrine. It's famous
for its path of light.
Path of light?
The shrine approach stretches
straight to the ocean.
Twice a year, the sun sets right over
it. It's supposed to be breathtaking.
I went to Munakata Taisha, too.
Munakata Taisha
It's mentioned in the
Kojiki and Nihon Shoki.
It's one of Japan's oldest shrines.
It's famous for its Miare
Festival held in the fall.
The Sacred Island of Okinoshima and
Associated Sites in the Munakata Region
are inscribed on the World Heritage List.
World Heritage List, huh? That's amazing.
Anyway, let's meet somewhere for lunch.
Okay.
So this is President Fukamachi
and his son Torahiko-san.
Son, this is the president's office.
You shouldn't be in here.
Sorry.
And don't tell anyone I
was sitting in his chair.
Where's Director Kiriyama?
He's visiting the president in the hospital.
But isn't he still unconscious?
Today is a special day.
A special day?
You might be too young to understand,
but today at three,
the next president will be appointed
in a shareholders' meeting.
He wants to report it to the president,
even if it's only as a formality.
But he asked Kogoro-no-ojisan
not to visit him.
That's why I said today's a special day.
Today, the director will be taking the
president's car to the shareholders' meeting.
I haven't driven his car in a week.
It's a very important day for the company.
Where's the parking lot
where the president tripped?
Beneath that window.
Tiger Trading
Wakamatsu Ferry
Tobata – Wakamatsu
Mori-san.
Could we keep what I'm about
to tell you between us?
Of course.
It's a detective's job to keep secrets.
The truth is...
Tiger
Bloodstains.
So this is where Fukamachi-san hit his head.
The blocks are approximately
two meters apart.
Fukamachi-san looked surprisingly
small in that photo.
If he just tripped on the block,
he wouldn't have hit his head here.
It'd be impossible for him to hit
his head here unless he was running.
But Fukamachi-san's knees were
injured. He couldn't run.
Which means...
Director Kiriyama did?
Yes.
The director and president often argued
over how to manage the company.
In other words, you believe Director
Kiriyama pushed Fukamachi-senpai.
It's possible.
It's possible Torahiko-san
is trying to get revenge on the
director because he learned that.
Revenge, huh?
Tiger Trading
Iwata Genichiro (63)
Tiger Trading Security Guard
Yes, I saw someone run three mornings ago.
You're sure it was Torahiko-san?
When I worked as a fireworks maker,
Torahiko stole some gunpowder
from the workshop.
It reminded me of how he looked then.
Iwata-san and the president
are childhood friends.
It's the reason he knows
Torahiko-san so well.
I saw him from behind, but he had blond hair.
I'm fairly certain it was him.
Don't you remember what
you said in the ambulance?
The ambulance?
Are we finished?
I need to take the president's
car for cleaning.
Sorry to have interrupted your busy schedule.
What did he mean about the ambulance?
Inside the ambulance, the
president was barely conscious.
Kokura Castle
He only said the word “tiger.”
Kokura Castle - Toraccha
Tiger?
Apparently, the EMTs heard
him say “dorako.”
Dorako?
Kokura Castle Gardens
Maybe he was trying to say
“dora musuko” (lazy son).
Where it was tiger or lazy son,
he must have been really
worried about Torahiko-kun.
It's not like that.
What?
Iwata-san believes Torahiko-san
may have pushed the president.
He what?
He thinks he's threatening the director
because he found out in
order to keep him quiet.
Tiger
Is Torahiko that bad a guy?
Izumi-san, do you have any idea
where Torahiko-san might be?
There's a café near Mojiko
called Airs Café where
he worked in high school.
3 months ago
2 months ago
1 months ago
3 days ago
There he is. It's Torahiko-san.
Three nights ago? That's after
the buildings were graffitied.
Huh?
Mister, what are you doing?
Isn't this President Fukamachi's car?
Yeah. It's my job to clean it.
That's Toraccha, right?
Kokura Castle's mascot.
Who are you?
I'm Conan.
I came here with Kogoro-no-ojisan.
Kogoro? The detective Mori Kogoro-san?
Yeah. Do you know him?
He was just at the warehouse
asking about the graffiti.
So you're the witness, Iwata-san.
Yeah.
Hello?
What? In the president's office?
Understood. I'll head there immediately.
I just cleaned the car,
so don't make it dirty.
The president's office?
Where should we go now?
This is no fun alone.
Conan-kun?
I'm at Mojiko Retro right now.
There are lots of tasty looking
shops serving baked curry.
Want to come?
I'll wait for the old man a little longer.
What? Aren't you hungry?
No, I'm fine.
Eat lunch without me.
Okay.
This was supposed to be a fun trip.
Lovers' Bridge
Blue Wing Moji
I'm so lonely.
Sorry, were you waiting long?
Huh?
Sorry, but could you be
my girlfriend for a bit?
What?
I'm being followed by bad men.
I just need ten seconds.
What?!
Damn.
Let's go.
Hey.
Thanks. You saved me.
Tiger Trading
President's Office
What's this?
Old Moji Mitsui Club
Fukamachi Torahiko?
Fukamachi Torahiko (21)
Fukamachi Torazo's Son
Funny name, right?
My dad loves tigers.
Was your dad known as the Tiger
of Sakuradamon at the MPD?
What? How did you know?
My dad worked with your dad.
His name is Mori Kogoro.
Mori Kogoro?
Mojiko Retro Observation Deck
Someone must be talking about me again.
Torahiko-san was here three nights ago.
Three days ago?
That's the night the
buildings were vandalized.
Huh? Ran?
Torahiko? Could it be?
What is it?
I saw Torahiko-san just now, but he's with...
No, that can't be.
You saw Torahiko-san?
I'm not sure it was him,
but I may or may not have seen him with a
young woman who looks a lot like my daughter.
Ran and Torahiko-san?
I see. Your dad's a detective.
He's been hired to investigate some
graffiti at Fukamachi-san's office.
It's my dad.
Ran, where are you?
Where am I? A place called Mojiko Retro.
What? You're not with Torahiko, are you?
What? How did you know?
I knew it. What are you thinking?
What are you so angry about?
Torahiko-san is Fukamachi-san's son.
I know that!
Do you have any who he is?
I told you, he's Fukamachi-san's son!
Stop!
Let go!
Stop resisting!
What are you doing?
Stay out of the way!
Ran, what's wrong?! What happened?!
Ran!
Episode Preview
It's an emergency! Something
must've happened to Ran!
Who are you?
Did you write the graffiti, Torahiko-san?
It wasn't me.
If you're innocent, my
father will protect you.
Ran-neechan, listen closely. That Toraccha—
The Northern Kyushu Mystery Tour
(Moji Arc)
The next episode of Conan is “The Northern
Kyushu Mystery Tour, Moji Arc!”
Stuffed Animal
Next Conan's hint!
A stuffed animal!
Don't miss the next episode.
We still haven't grasped any information.
Catch a tiger by the toe!
Not that.