The old man was chosen for the Japanese
Detective League's Best Detective Award.
Kokura Station
We came to Kokura, Fukuoka,
to attend the award ceremony.
Miyajidake Shrine
Leaving Ran, who wanted to go sightseeing,
the old man and I stopped by the
company run by Fukamachi Torazo-san,
Munakata Taisha
Tiger Trading
his senior from his police days, but...
He was hospitalized for an injury?
Fukamachi Torazo (63)
Tiger Trading President
A week ago, President Fukamachi
accidentally tripped and hit his head,
and he was still unconscious in the hospital.
Graffiti threatening Director Kiriyama,
the man next in line for the
president's seat, was discovered.
As the old man began his investigation,
President Fukamachi's son Torahiko
emerged as his prime suspect.
Fukamachi Torahiko (21)
Fukamachi Torazo's Son
Sorry, were you waiting long?
Huh?
Sorry, but could you be
my girlfriend for a bit?
What?
I'm being followed by bad men.
I just need ten seconds.
What?!
Let go!
Stop resisting!
What are you doing?
Stay out of the way!
Ran, what's wrong?! What happened?!
Ran!
In my eyes are maximum creation!
My detective skills are tomorrow's reaction!
A series of cases plague those involved!
What is the deep mystery
hidden in Kokura and Moji?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Northern Kyushu Mystery Tour
(Moji Arc)
"The Northern Kyushu
Mystery Tour, Moji Arc!"
Stay out of the way!
Let's go!
What are you doing?
Oh, no!
This way.
It's an emergency! Something
must've happened to Ran!
Tiger Trading
Ran...
Damn it. Where did they go?
Ran!
Mori-san.
Don't worry.
Who are you?
Have you seen a young blond man?
What?
He came running this way with a young woman.
Who are you?
The police?
Yeah.
Those two were police officers?
I've known them since high school.
Nakamaru Ginji (38)
Kokura Station
Police Officer
Shigaki Shuhei (42)
Kokura Station
Police Officer
They're Kokura Station cops.
They've been chasing me around because
they think I wrote that graffiti.
What am I going to do?
I attacked some police officers...
You were trying to save me.
You did nothing wrong.
It's my fault.
Did you write the graffiti, Torahiko-san?
It wasn't me.
Then you shouldn't run.
You need to talk to the police.
If I go to the police now,
they'll treat me like a criminal.
Some of them think I hurt my dad.
What?
Someone pushed my dad from behind.
I can't let them arrest me until
I find evidence of the culprit.
What evidence?
Apparently my dad said
"tora" in the ambulance.
There's a stuffed Toraccha in my dad's car.
There used to be a GPS and
security camera inside of it.
It's possible the culprit's voice
or image or something else
that could serve as evidence
were captured by it.
Don't answer it.
It's okay. It's Conan-kun.
Ran-neechan, you're with
Torahiko-san, aren't you?
How did you know?
Kogoro-no-ojisan's desperately
looking for you.
Ran, where are you?!
Ran!
What should I do, Conan-kun?
Tiger Trading
It's okay. He'll solve everything.
Convince Torahiko-san not to run.
Torahiko-san.
If you're innocent, my
father will protect you.
Let's go back to the others.
My dad's a pretty good detective.
I know.
What?
My dad bragged that one of
his juniors from his MPD days
was a famous detective named Mori Kogoro.
I see.
Yeah.
Are you listening, Ran-neechan?
It's okay, Conan-kun.
Torahiko-san and I will head your way now.
That's good.
I also have a request for Torahiko-san.
A request?
What?
Ran and Torahiko are heading
towards the office?
Yeah. They want you to
reveal the truth there.
Who, me?
It's time for the great detective
Mori Kogoro to show off his skills.
Insolent brat!
Fine. As long as Ran comes back
safe, I'll handle the rest.
We'll help.
It's an honor to work alongside
the great detective Mori Kogoro.
Gather everyone connected to the case.
Director Kiriyama is at the hospital.
Izumi Noriko (28)
President's Secretary
I doubt he'll be able to return right away.
The hospital?
Yes, he's visiting the president.
That's odd. He told me not to visit him.
That's it! I've figured it out!
President's Office
I've been waiting for you, Director Kiriyama.
Kiriyama Eisaku (45)
Tiger Trading Managing Director
Mori-san, is it true that you've determined
who's responsible for the graffiti?
Yes. That's why I asked
all of you to come here.
The shareholders' meeting starts at three,
so we don't have much time.
Could we hurry, please?
Despite being short on time,
you visited President Fukamachi
in the hospital, didn't you?
Yes.
He's still unconscious,
but I thought I'd tell him about
the shareholders' meeting.
Was there some reason you
didn't want me to visit him?
Mori-san, what are you trying to say?
You're the one who pushed
President Fukamachi, aren't you?
What are you talking about?
Wrong guy, old man.
Once the president regains
consciousness, we'll know you did it.
Isn't that why you went to the hospital?
I-I-Is that it?
The Sleeping Kogoro?!
Director Kiriyama, please don't be upset.
Your visit to the hospital has
nothing to do with the case.
Then who did it?
If you know, tell us!
The first thing we should make clear
is that Torahiko-san didn't
write the graffiti.
What?
That's ridiculous!
Ukaji Makoto (42)
President's Driver
Iwata-san saw him do it.
Iwata-san, you said the
culprit was blond, correct?
Iwata Genichiro (63)
Tiger Trading Security Guard
Y-Yes.
But three mornings ago when
the buildings were vandalized,
Torahiko-san wasn't blond yet.
What?
Conan.
Here!
Torahiko-san was looking for work in Tokyo,
so he'd been keeping his
hair black for some time.
See?
Torahiko-san just sent me this photo.
And that's not all.
The night Iwata-san saw the culprit,
this photo was taken at Airs Café.
See?
Torahiko-san said he dyed his hair blond
the day after the graffiti was discovered.
Why don't you check with the salon?
But why did he dye his hair blond again?
Torahiko-san wanted to pump himself up.
He was determined not to let the police
beat him until he discovered the truth.
I-I may have been mistaken
about the blond hair.
Iwata-san, after we met at the parking
lot today, you came here, didn't you?
What? In the president's office?
Understood. I'll head there immediately.
I found this in the garbage can.
It looks like a bank envelope.
There's donut crumbs on it, so
maybe Ukaji-san threw it away.
Hey! Don't go making wild accusations!
I'm scared!
Officers, could you have your forensics
team examine that envelope?
I'm sure you'll find Iwata-san and
Ukaji-san's fingerprints on it.
Understood.
How much was inside the envelope, Ukaji-san?
I'm asking how much Iwata-san paid you.
A-Are you saying I blackmailed Iwata-san?!
That's right!
That's bullshit!
Ukaji-san, you don't know the truth.
The truth?
The culprit's goal.
Wasn't it to threaten Director Kiriyama?
No. The culprit's goal was to murder you.
What?
They were trying to kill me?
Isn't that right, Iwata-san?
You wanted to kill Ukaji-san.
But if you went after him directly, the
police would investigate his associates
and discover he was threatening
you and realize you did it.
That's why you used that graffiti
to make everyone believe Director
Kiriyama was the target.
If Director Kiriyama was killed and
Ukaji-san got caught in the crossfire,
then suspicion would fall on Torahiko-kun,
who was assumed to have vandalized the buildings.
You wouldn't be suspected.
On what basis do you say that?
Conan, bring it to me.
Okay!
Iwata-san, you left this inside
the president's car, didn't you?
I don't know what you're talking about!
I thought it was strange.
The Toraccha in the photo I took
was dirty and old like the
one Fukamachi-san was holding.
But this Toraccha is brand new.
Since you left it outside while washing
the car, it's a little damp, too.
Y-You're lying!
Maybe you hid the old
Toraccha in your toolbox.
See? I knew it.
Huh?
Did you use this toolbox to store the red
spray paint you used for the graffiti, too?
Let go! There's no time!
There's no time?
I-It's a bomb!
It'll explode in ten minutes!
What?!
A b-bomb?!
In ten minutes?
It's okay. I just bought this Toraccha.
It's not your bomb.
What?
If it's set to explode in ten minutes,
then that means you set it for 2:30, right?
2:30?
Ukaji-san would be driving
the president's car then.
He'd be taking Director Kiriyama
to the shareholders' meeting.
You were planning to blow
up me and the director?
Then the real bomb's still
inside the president's car?
Don't worry about that.
Mori-san called the
prefectural police earlier.
The bomb squad is already there.
He called to tell us about the bomb inside
the stuffed tiger in the president's car.
How did you know?
In high school,
Torahiko-san stole gunpowder from your
fireworks factory to build a bomb.
In order to frame Torahiko-san
for the murder of Ukaji-san
and Director Kiriyama,
you believed setting a bomb inside
the Toraccha was the best method.
You even had the skills to build a bomb.
Iwata-san, what happened in
the parking lot that day?
Torazo and I were childhood friends,
but he tried to fire me anyway.
Torazo, let me keep working a little longer.
Gen-chan...
I'm sorry, but I've already decided
to hire a security company.
You should learn to do desk work.
No! I like how easy things are now!
Don't be so selfish.
Torazo...
I got scared and ran,
but later...
Last month the president told
me to install a dash cam.
It's all on there.
You pushing the president.
Get me 500 thousand by the
end of the week, got it?
Maybe the president was trying to
say "dorareko" in the ambulance.
Dorareko?
Dorareko.
In other words, the dash cam. He wanted
us to check the dash cam footage.
I only took 500 thousand yen!
Why would you kill me over that?
You were going to blackmail
me for the rest of my life!
It would've been more than 500 thousand!
What?!
Shut up, both of you!
Do you have any idea how sad the president
would be if he found of what you did?
Torahiko-san and Ran are late.
It's an emergency!
The car the bomb is inside is missing!
No!
Where are we going, Torahiko-san?
You promised we'd rejoin the others.
I need to deliver Toraccha
to the TV station first.
The TV station?
I'm going to have them make a broadcast.
We still don't know who the culprit is.
If we don't leave the evidence with
them, the culprit might try to hide it.
Torahiko, stop the car!
I can't believe he stole
the car with the bomb.
Conan-kun.
Ran-neechan, listen closely. That Toraccha—
Ran-neechan, what happened?!
Conan-kun!
There's a bomb inside that Toraccha!
Huh? What?
It's going to explode in three minutes!
What's happening in three minutes?
Say it again.
It's a bomb! A bomb!
A bomb?!
What?
There's a bomb inside that Toraccha!
Throw it away!
What?
Stop the car!
Twenty more seconds.
Ran!
Dad!
Ten more seconds.
Go!
That former firework maker...
He even made a flamboyant bomb.
Aruaru City
Best Detective Award Ceremony
What a cozy party.
I'm overjoyed.
This event's being hosted by the
historic Japanese Detective League.
Sponsored by the Japanese Detective League
I've never heard of the
Japanese Detective League.
We've been waiting for you, Mori-san.
I-Izumi-san.
Congratulations on your Best Detective Award.
Izumi-san, why are you here?
Fukamachi-senpai.
Mori Kogoro-kun, congratulations
on your Best Detective Award.
Sir.
It's been so long.
I'm glad you're doing well.
You, too.
He actually regained
consciousness a few days ago,
but he'd lost his memories of the accident.
We decided to hire you to uncover the truth.
The Director even kept it secret from me.
I see.
The president will be our
president a while longer.
At least until Torahiko-kun
becomes a proper adult.
Good luck, Torahiko-san.
Thanks.
The Japanese Detective League
was created by President Fukamachi
to support you, Mori-san.
What? You did?
Keep up the good work.
Thank you, sir!
I'm sure the life of the man
known as the Tiger of Sakuradamon
will make a magnificent drama.
Since you're a tiger, it'll
surely be a roaring success.
Just kidding.
Dad...
Who are you, Kogoro the Punster?