Detective Conan Episode 933 “The
Thoroughbred Kidnapping Case (Part One)”
Go, go! Break away!
This is the last one, mister!
Ran-neechan will get mad at
me if you run out of money!
Keep a close eye on him, Conan-kun.
He just got paid,
and he gambled away all of it in
just half a day the other day.
Not only that, but that's actually my money.
Got it, Conan-kun?
Got it.
Mister!
Shut up. I know.
Yes, yes!
Yes! Yes, yes, yes!
All right!
What? You must be joking.
Here's the problem: should I man up and...
Yeah, and go home.
...bet the rest of my money?
Or drink my sorrows away?
Now that's the problem!
Both would be huge problems.
Excuse me. Are you the great
detective Mori Kogoro-sensei?
Huh?
Indeed. I am the great detective Mori.
Excuse me. I'm unfortunately
out of business cards.
I'm a freelance horse racing journalist.
I'd like to hire you for a job.
Yes, yes! More gambling money!
In my eyes are maximum creation!
My detective skills are tomorrow's reaction!
He keeps talking about gambling money,
but there's something fishy about
all these horse racing jobs!
Always determining the one truth...
...with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Thoroughbred Kidnapping Case
(Part One)
“The Thoroughbred Kidnapping
Case, Part One!”
Mori Detective Agency
We're home.
We're back.
Dad, hurry.
Huh?
You have a client, Dad.
W-Well, well.
Thank for you waiting.
I am the great detective Mori Kogoro.
Excuse me. I'm unfortunately
out of business cards.
I write horse racing predictions
and reviews online.
I'd like to ask you to do something for me.
Business is booming!
Are you sure, mister?
That job was the same as the last one.
Excuse me, but I'm a huge horse racing fan.
I'd actually like to hire you.
Huh?
What?!
Anyway, that's that.
Thank you, Detective.
What's going on?
We did it.
Yeah. Now we can relax.
You're right.
With a famous detective
on the case, surely...
I don't know what's going on, but
there's something fishy about these jobs.
TOKUYOSHI Stables
Why are you following me?
Ran-neechan told me to follow you.
She's worried because of
what the jobs are about.
If you're near a track when you get paid,
you might spend all of it like always.
Don't worry.
This time I'm earning triple the money.
Are you sure you should've accepted
the same job three times?
He's the most popular horse right now.
Coincidences happen.
I meant as a detective.
That's him!
White Spirits, the horse
with the pure white soul.
White Spirits
Racing Horse
Hase Yasutaka (40)
Trainer
It's a beautiful horse.
No wonder they say he's
the horse of the decade.
Indeed, indeed.
I've been blessed as a horse owner.
Who are you?
Please excuse me.
I took your call earlier.
I'm Tokuyoshi Kozo.
Tokuyoshi Kozo (55)
Horse Owner
You must be Mori Kogoro, the great detective.
Indeed, I am the great detective Mori.
I see. So you're the owner
of that amazing horse.
You said you were here about White Spirits?
Indeed.
Tokuyoshi-san, I understand you've
been receiving death threats...
...against White Spirits
since about a month ago.
H-How do you know that?!
Detectives are bound to confidentiality,
so I cannot answer your question,
but I've been hired to investigate
and protect White Spirits...
...by someone who heard about the threats.
By three different people, too.
I-I see. That's perfect, then.
Huh?
I'd like to hire you, too.
Please protect White Spirits, Mori-san.
What?
He's been hired by four people now.
Thank you, Mori-san.
The next day, White Spirits was being
transported to a track outside Tokyo...
...to participate in a commemorative race.
White Spirits
We're counting on you.
Shiomi Masao (50)
Horse Trailer Driver
Got it.
Why are you here, too, Ran?
I'm watching you.
I wasn't sure Conan-kun
could handle it alone.
You're unbelievable.
Just kidding. I'm actually
a White Spirits fan.
What?! Don't tell me you...
Of course not. I'm underage.
I just like how fast and
beautiful White Spirits is.
That's why I'm worried.
Yeah, but...
Why not, Mori-san?
I feel safer with more people.
Come, miss.
You're welcome to join me in my car.
Thank you!
Don't do this, sir! This is reckless!
If something were to happen
to White Spirits...
Don't worry.
The great detective Mori Kogoro is here.
White Spirits will appear
in the race as planned.
You all just need to do your jobs.
You all?
What's up with that car?
They shouldn't surprise people like that.
Hey, wasn't that this person?
This Month's Woman Jockey
White Spirits' Rider
Kakuta Chizuru (25)
Jockey
They're on schedule.
That's them.
But why were they wearing disguises?
What's wrong? Hey, you can't just—
Construction 50m Ahead
Detour
Huh?
Follow that car!
Where'd the trailer go?
What's wrong?
There's construction up ahead.
That sign was placed incorrectly.
I'm sorry. Thank you for waiting.
What a waste of time.
Now, now. We have time.
Let's take it slowly.
What is it?
Something not right.
I have a bad feeling about this.
Okuho Horse Track
I'm glad he's all right.
Nothing's gonna happen with the
great detective Mori Kogoro on the job.
I-It's not him!
Huh?
This isn't White Spirits!
What?!
What do you mean, Tokuyoshi-san?
It looks just like him.
It looks like him, but it's
a totally different horse.
What?
Famous Horses
White Spirits
Look, mister.
Th-That's...
No way.
And that.
What is that?
“Dear President Tokugawa.”
“We've taken White Spirits.”
“Gather 100 million yen in ransom and wait
at your house for us to contact you.”
A ransom letter?
Wh-What's going on, Mori-san?!
When did they take him?
Where did they swap out the...
That's right. That's the only
place they could've done it.
And if that's true, then...
Could it be?
Hey, you!
I'm sorry!
My wife and child were kidnapped!
I was being threatened!
You what?
Construction 50m Ahead
Detour
They told me to park the trailer
there and get in the other one.
They said they'd kill my wife and
child if I didn't. I had no choice.
I'm sorry!
I knew it.
You're right. There's no
construction happening at all.
This is ridiculous.
Look.
Is that...?
Yeah.
They're tire marks from the real
trailer the culprit drove away...
...after the driver Shiomi-san
got into the other trailer.
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
Nothing. I was just thinking
this is like that other case.
What? This has happened before?
It's called the “the
Adventure of Silver Blaze.”
What's that? I've never heard of it.
It's a Sherlock Holmes story
written by Conan Doyle.
You're talking about a book? What nonsense.
I hope that's all it is.
Hello?
Ah, Takagi.
That's good.
Any leads on the suspect?
I see. We'll meet you right away.
Was that Detective Takagi?
Yeah.
The driver Shiomi's wife
and child were released,
and made it back home.
But they were blindfolded, so they
don't know anything about the culprit.
I see.
I'm glad they're all right, though.
Tokuyoshi Kozo
Leave! Leave me!
Can't you read this?
Let me see that.
In one hour, come alone to the fountain
at Tsubaki Park. Bring the 100 million yen
with you. If anyone else comes,
White Spirits will never be returned to you.
Wh-What is this?
Tokuyoshi found it in his mailbox.
He said he was going out alone with
White Spirits' 100 million yen ransom.
Without our protection.
He what? That's too dangerous!
We said the same thing.
Danger? Protection?
It's all just to arrest the culprit!
I can't trust the police or detectives!
If you follow me, I'll sue all of you!
Don't forget that!
Inspector.
Of course.
We can't ignore a crime happening
right before our eyes.
We'll follow them carefully so neither
the culprit nor Tokuyoshi notice.
Yes, sir.
Wh-What is this?
WS → KM North ST.
WS...
WS?
Maybe they're referring to White Spirits.
That must be it.
In other words, White Spirits
is at KM North ST.
Where is that?
I wonder what word is
normally abbreviated as ST.
Station. The train station.
I see!
KM North...
Katsumata North Station.
Let's go.
Katsumata North Station
Tokuyoshi Kozo-sama from
Yagiri-cho, you have a message.
Please come to the station office.
There was a phone call for
Tokuyoshi about thirty minutes ago.
What was it?
They said to tell him, “Head to OND3BRG.”
OND3? BRG?
Where is that?
BRG...
If it's an abbreviation like before, BRG...
Bridge.
Maybe it's a bridge.
So OND3 is the name of the bridge?
OND... OND...
If that's an abbreviation, too, then...
Hey, look.
Up there.
Onodera Overpass 3
OND3! Onodera Overpass 3!
Could it be?
Damn it. I can't see from here.
I still can't...
I still can't see it.
Here should be good enough.
I see it!
Stake it out.
Yes, sir!
Damn. It's been thirty minutes.
What's going on?
Could it be? Chiba, Takagi!
Wh-What is this?
What happened?
It's not here!
Wh-What?!
Damn it! They got us!
What's going on?
After Tokuyoshi threw down the bag,
the culprit must've come out of hiding
and switched out the contents.
Then they left before we arrived.
Th-They what?
So the culprit was long gone.
The next day, there was another
sudden development in the case.
Episode Preview
I'm not his babysitter!
I see. So that's how it is.
But why?
Horse brothers?
You think you've used the great Mori
Kogoro, but you haven't at all!
The Thoroughbred Kidnapping Case
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is “The
Thoroughbred Kidnapping Case, Part Two!”
It's next Conan's hint! Just kidding.
Mane
A mane!
Don't miss the next episode!
White Spirits...
Is that the name of a liquor?
Please don't.