The old man was hired by
three suspicious people
to protect the racing horse White Spirits,
who had received several death threats.
Several days later,
White Spirits
Racing Horse
White Spirits was to be transported
Tokuyoshi Kozo (55)
Horse Owner
to a track outside of Tokyo for a race.
White Spirits
The old man escorted the
horse trailer, but...
At some point White Spirits was
swapped out for an impostor.
Horse owner Tokuyoshi received a ransom
note demanding 100 million yen.
Unable to trust the police or detectives,
Tokuyoshi followed the
kidnapper's instructions alone
and had the ransom money stolen from him.
In my eyes are maximum creation!
My detective skills are tomorrow's reaction!
The ransom money and horse go missing!
The two cases are connected
in a surprising way!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Thoroughbred Kidnapping Case
(Part Two)
"The Thoroughbred Kidnapping
Case, Part Two!"
White Spirits
I'm certain of it, Inspector.
This is the horse blanket
White Spirits was wearing.
Oh, no.
Is he already...?
Inspector, according to a local who
took their garbage out an hour ago,
that wasn't here at that time.
How did the police know this was here?
We received an anonymous tip.
An anonymous tip?
They thought it was dumped illegally.
And there seems to be blood on it,
so they wanted us to investigate.
Hmm...
I received a report from forensics.
The blood on the horse blanket
matched White Spirits'.
Are you sure?
We got the data from the stable's vet.
It's definitely his.
Which means it's possible he's already...
The media's starting to make a fuss, too.
That can't be helped.
He's an extraordinary and
popular racing horse.
We should prepare for a press
conference immediately.
Actually, they're also making
a fuss over something else.
What do you mean?
Famous Horse Missing, Kidnapped!!
100 million yen ransom!!
Death threats previously received!!
Bloody horse blanket discovered!!
Is the horse already dead?!
Massive failure!!
Kidnapping happened under the watch
of a great detective and the police!!
Mori Detective Agency
Damn it! Who do they think they are?
I hate to say it, but if Tokuyoshi had
cooperated, this wouldn't have happened.
You've had too much to drink, Dad.
How can I not drink?
It's not like I wanted to fail.
More importantly, we're still not
sure White Spirits was killed, right?
Well, yeah, but the blood was a match.
I'm sure he's fine.
The kidnapper got the
ransom money he wanted.
I'm sure he'll return him.
I know who did it. I'm absolutely certain.
Nagaura Saneaki (45)
Stable Hand
Shiomi Masao (50)
Horse Trailer Driver
So why did they hire the old man?
Hase Yasutaka (40)
Trainer
Kakuta Chizuru (25)
Jockey
I'll have to review the case again.
What's this?
Could it be?
That's it! So that's how it is!
How did I not notice this?
Hello, Detective Takagi?
Kogoro-no-ojisan asked me
to do something for him.
Over here.
Hey, Conan-kun.
Please play the tape.
Got it.
This is it. Stop the video.
This is the trailer the
real White Spirits was in.
Which means we might know where it went if
we follow it on the other security camera.
I'm impressed Mori-san noticed.
Is he really in there?
What?
Are we sure the real White
Spirits was in this trailer?
Well, we can't see inside the
trailer from here, but...
Could you show us that part again?
Sure.
Stop the video!
Look at this, Detective Takagi.
What? The date?
Wait, what? Could it be?
Which means...
But why?
There's only one conceivable reason.
Now I just need evidence.
Ihara Satoshi (25)
Trainee Stable Hand
I'm sorry, I'm still only a trainee.
I'm unsure of the details, but...
But there's something
bothering you, isn't there?
One of the horse trailers hasn't come back.
Since when?
I think it's been three days now.
Three days...
Come to think of it, it must
be since three days ago.
White Spirits
I couldn't find White Spirits'
spare riding or grooming gear.
So it disappeared along
with the horse trailer.
Where was White Spirits then? Here?
I'm not sure.
I was working with another horse
that day, so I was out at the track.
But when I returned that night,
White Spirits was here.
Which means it probably happened then.
Hey, is this a bloodstain?
A bloodstain?
Oh, actually...
What happened?
It's not a secret or anything.
That happened three days ago, too—
No, the day before that.
White Spirits rubbed against
a splinter that formed there.
But the vet said it
fortunately wasn't serious,
and wouldn't affect his ability to race.
I see. So that's how it is.
What's that?
The truth is starting to come together.
Hello, Takagi?
I need you to convey a message
to the inspector immediately.
Hello, this is Takagi.
Mori-san?
What's the meaning of this?!
I thought I said I was through
with detectives and the police!
Well, actually...
Takagi, it better be true that you discovered
the culprits and the truth behind the case.
What?
Mori-san, you told me to tell the inspector
that you uncovered the culprit's identity
and the truth behind the case.
What are you two arguing about?
Either way, it doesn't matter.
Hurry up and explain the situation.
Dad...
You can do it, old man.
Mori-san.
Fine.
Allow me to explain the culprit's
identity and the truth behind the case.
What?
All right.
This case—the kidnapping of White Spirits
and the stolen ransom money—used
fundamentally the same trick.
In other words, solve one,
and you've solved the other.
Is that true?
Then quit putting on airs and speak.
First, how was White Spirits
swapped out for another horse?
The driver swapped him for the horse
in the other identical trailer
parked on the side road.
Since his wife and child were kidnapped, he
was forced to follow the culprit's instructions.
Isn't that right?
Yes.
Takagi, what did you see there?
I believe it was...
Tire tracks from two trailers.
It's strange, though.
What was strange, Conan-kun?
One set of tire tracks was
much shallower than the other,
as though nothing were inside it.
Wh-What?
There was a convenience store at the
road leading to the crime scene.
At Mori-san's direction, I investigated
the security camera footage.
Did I tell you to do that?
What?
C-Continue, Takagi.
Yes, sir.
I found footage of a horse
trailer exiting that side road
and passing in front of
the convenience store.
Then that must have been it.
What about White Spirits? Was he inside?
Unfortunately, I was unable to confirm that.
But more importantly, the footage
was from three days ago.
Wh-What?!
Which means it's possible
the trailer and tire marks
were a camouflage created
three days earlier.
In other words, the other trailer
wasn't on the side road that day,
but made to look like it was.
The culprit did this to make us believe
the horses were swapped, and...
No, but White Spirits was actually
swapped out for the impostor, so...
Wait. Which means they were swapped
not there, but someplace else.
Could it be that they were swapped all along?!
What?!
What?
No way.
Yes.
That's what makes this case similar to
"The Adventure of Silver Blaze."
I actually investigated another
stable at Mori-san's direction, too.
What? You, too?
Continue.
Yes, sir.
Currently at that stable is this horse.
It's that horse that looks
exactly like White Spirits.
This is White Legion.
He's the brother of White Spirits.
Brother?
I see. I've got it.
In other words, the horses
weren't swapped there.
The disguise placed on White
Spirits' brother was removed.
That's right.
Conan-kun found this there.
Horse hair?
Yes.
According to forensics, one is White
Spirits' hair used in the disguise.
The other belongs to White Legion.
They probably both fell out
when the disguise was removed.
Which means the culprits are the people
who dragged me into this by hiring me,
setting me up to fail, and made
horse owner Tokuyoshi-san shun my
and the police's protection and attempt
to pay the ransom money alone.
Stable hand Nagaura Saniaki-san.
Trainer Hase Yasutaka-san.
Jockey Kakuta Chizuru-san.
You three.
Is this true, Mori-san?
How dare you?!
You think you've used the great Mori
Kogoro, but you haven't at all!
He couldn't do it.
I thought I'd let the old man handle
this one since he loves horses, but...
Huh? Is this it?
It took a little longer this time...
Mori-kun?
Dad?
Excuse me.
It's true that the three of
you committed this crime.
I had Takagi and Chiba confirm
that you have no alibis for when
White Spirits was being transported.
Nor for three days earlier,
when White Spirits and a horse trailer
temporarily disappeared from the stable.
White Spirits was probably already swapped
out for White Legion at this time.
There's one more person.
Trailer driver Shiomi-san,
you're also their accomplice.
If there wasn't a second
trailer on that side road,
that ruins your whole testimony.
Or were your wife and child
pretending to be kidnapped, too?
However, there's a ringleader—a
mastermind behind this plot.
You, Tokuyoshi Kozo-san.
Wh-What?
Is that true, Dad?
Well, well.
When did you become the
great confused detective?
I'm the victim who was made
to pay a 100 million
ransom for a mere horse.
A mere horse, huh?
Hard to imagine a horse owner saying that,
especially when you haven't
actually paid a single yen.
Wh-What? What does that mean, Mori-kun?
Remember that none of us checked to see
if there was actually 100
million yen inside that back.
You're right.
The bag Tokuyoshi-san took was
filled with worthless stuffing.
Just as it was a different horse
inside the trailer all along,
he pretended the bag stuffed with
magazines contained 100 million yen.
What?
Conan.
Here.
You stuffed the magazines in the rack in
your living room inside the bag, didn't you?
You left behind part of a ripped cover.
If there are any ripped
magazines inside the bag,
and it matches that...
Which means...
Could it be?
Yes.
It was all a lie.
But why?
Chiba!
Yes, sir.
Mori-san asked me to look into it.
Someone requested a payout
of the life insurance policy
on White Spirits with a major
foreign insurance company.
The beneficiary is Tokuyoshi Kozo.
The problem lies in the date
the money was requested.
It was the day before White
Spirits' horse blanket was found.
The day before? Wait a minute.
Yes.
How did you know White Spirits was
dead at that time, Tokuyoshi-san?
B-Because they threatened
to kill White Spirits.
Really?
Surely you didn't really think
you'd be paid the insurance money
over such uncertain circumstances.
It's actually because your
employees reported to you
that they'd killed White Spirits, isn't it?
That's right.
You—
I know nothing of this.
They kidnapped him on their own.
I'm innocent. I'm a victim.
And ultimately, White Spirits is dead.
They killed him.
It's within my rights to
request the insurance money.
Yes, that's right.
But only if White Spirits really is dead.
Wh-What?
What do you mean, Dad?
Could it be?
White Spirits!
He's okay. What a relief.
I-Impossible.
You knew?
Yes.
While acting according to Tokuyoshi's
White Spirits kidnapping and murder plot,
in the end, you hid White Spirits in
a safe place rather than killing him.
And to increase the credibility
of your report to Tokuyoshi,
you left an anonymous tip with the police
so they'd discover the horse blanket
White Spirits bled on when he
scratched himself at the stables.
Wh-What?!
Where has White Spirits been until now?
Conan!
Here!
Did you bring it?
Yeah, you mean this?
This photo wasn't taken at TOKUYOSHI Stables.
The color of the wall is different.
It's KITADO Stables.
We used to work there.
White Spirits and White
Legion were born there.
So he's been there until now?
Yes.
The trailer I used to transport
White Spirits is there, too.
But why did you do this?
Isn't it obvious, Inspector?
Because for them, he's not a mere horse.
We were bought with money.
That man, Tokuyoshi Kozo,
poached us and White Spirits.
But I loved White Spirits, as a jockey.
As a stable hand.
As a trainer.
You must've raised White Spirits
since the day he was born.
Tokuyoshi, who was under financial strain
due to some reckless foreign investments,
planned to fake the kidnapping of
and ultimately kill White Spirits
in order to fraudulently obtain
a huge insurance payout.
He used the debts his employees owned
to force them to carry out the crime.
In order to stop him,
they disguised themselves and hired
the old man to protect White Spirits.
Great Detective Mori Kogoro
With a great detective on the case, they
assumed Tokuyoshi would cancel his plans.
However, Tokuyoshi believed
having a famous detective nearby
would help him play the victim
and carried out his plan.
They pretended to follow his plan
and hid White Spirits instead,
hoping to reveal the truth and
that White Spirits was safe
once Tokuyoshi requested
the insurance money.
Tokuyoshi was arrested and his
employees were questioned,
but the police later chose not to prosecute
them due to their circumstances.
Later, White Spirits returned
to racing under a new owner.
White Spirits!
You can do it!
Episode Preview
What?
Sensei!
She was killed last night.
Last night?
Is there a problem?
Then the detective Mori
Kogoro might know something.
While these three are suspicious,
the culprit isn't one of them.
It's all three of them.
The Fortune Teller and the Three Customers
The next episode of Conan is "The Fortune
Teller and the Three Customers!"
Alien Ramen
Next Conan's hint!
Alien ramen!
This movie features a magic trick.
Don't miss the next episode.
This weeks' Friday Roadshow feature is?
The movie "The Last
Wizard of the Century!"