Sensei.
Sensei, if you don't leave
soon, you'll be late.
Sensei, I'm coming in.
What?
Sensei!
O-Oh, no...
Strangled, huh?
Using rope.
The victim is the owner of the home,
Baba Sadako-san, 62 years old.
She was a medium and fortune teller.
A fortune teller?
Yes.
Ogu Masaya (26)
Barbara Sadako's Secretary
She ran a fortune telling shop near
Shibahama Station under the name Barbara Sadako.
This is Sadako-san's
secretary Ogu Masaya-san.
He was the first to discover the body.
We're waiting on the autopsy for details,
but it seems she was killed last night.
Last night?
Is there a problem?
Then the detective Mori
Kogoro might know something.
Mori-kun?
He called yesterday.
Barbara Sadako's Fortune Telling
This is Barbara Sadako's
fortune telling shop.
One moment, please.
Sensei, it's Mori Kogoro-san.
The famous detective?
Baba Sadako (Barbara Sadako) (62)
Medium and Fortune Teller
This is Babara Sadako.
Mori-kun invited the victim out?
In my eyes are maximum creation!
My detective skills are tomorrow's reaction!
The old man called the victim on the phone?
I'm curious what his fortune was.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Fortune Teller and the Three Customers
"The Fortune Teller and
the Three Customers!"
I didn't call her.
But—
Don't "but" me.
Besides, I don't know
anything about the victim.
And you were at home all night last night.
That's right.
Wait, this brat followed me again?
I verified your alibi.
It's possible the secretary did
it and he's trying to frame me.
He discovered the body.
Naturally, we checked his alibi.
He's totally innocent.
I see.
The culprit probably used Mori-kun's name
to invite Sadako-san out
to the scene of the murder.
Yes.
She wasn't killed here?
No.
After being killed somewhere else,
she was transported to this house.
Why did the culprit bother to move the body?
To delay its discovery, of course.
Then wouldn't they take
it into the mountains?
And why did they use your name?
Maybe because he's famous.
But if someone used your name, wouldn't
you be determined to find the culprit?
Of course.
So why would they get a detective involved?
I don't understand what
this culprit is doing.
About the criminal profile...
Huh?
What's this?
"I was nearly killed again."
"Which one of those three did it?"
I was nearly killed again. Which one of
those three did it? Is it K? Is it E? Is it S?
"Is it K? Is it E? Is it S?"
Does she mean those three?
After appearing on a live TV
broadcast about a week ago...
You three...
I'm Kanawa. You told my fortune last month.
Kanawa Shinsuke (37)
Barbara Sadako's Client
I ran into these two on the way here.
According to them, they experienced
tragedies because of your fortunes, too.
We came running when we saw you on TV!
Endo Fukami (29)
Barbara Sadako's Client
Take responsibility for your fortune telling!
I'll never forgive you!
Sazanami Ryoichi (33)
Barbara Sadako's Client
Take responsibility!
Now, now. Please calm down.
What's wrong?
This place is too public.
We should leave for now and
come up with a plan later.
You'll pay for this, Barbara Sadako!
I don't know what fortunes she told them.
But if anyone hated her,
then it must have been Kanawa Shinsuke,
Endo Fukami, or Sazanami Ryoichi.
Kanawa, Endo, Sazanami.
One of them must be the culprit.
But to be sure, check to see if there
was anyone else who hated the victim.
Yes, sir.
Three suspicious persons.
One was a woman.
We found this next to the body.
That brooch.
It belongs to Endo-san.
So they accidentally dropped it when
they transported the body here.
If that's true, then they're
unbelievably careless.
Excuse me.
Hello? What?
Something suspicious was just
discovered at Shibahama Park.
Shibahama Park
That's Sadako-sensei's business card case.
Could this rope be the weapon?
This must be where she was killed.
I'm surprised you found them.
We received an anonymous tip this morning.
They saw a suspicious figure
packing something large
into a car in this park last night.
When I came to investigate,
I found signs of a struggle
and those objects.
So Endo Fukami strangled Sadako-san here,
drove her to that mansion,
and left the body there.
I found this here as well.
S. Kanawa?
Could it belong to Kanawa Shinsuke?
Hello?
A car was abandoned near the mansion?
What?
It belongs to Sazanami Ryoichi?
I was curious, so I looked
up the license plate number.
I learned it had already
been reported stolen.
It was stolen two days ago.
But what's my car doing here?
That's hair. Compare it to the victim's.
That's my lighter.
But I lost it a few days ago.
Me, too. I lost this brooch.
I've figured out who the killer is.
While these three are suspicious,
the culprit isn't one of them.
The three of them attacked the victim.
That's when Kanawa-san dropped his lighter.
Then they loaded the body
into the car of the trunk
and transported it to the
study in Sadako-san's mansion.
That's when Fukami-san dropped her brooch
and left without realizing she'd lost it.
It's all three of them.
What?
That does explain all their belongings.
Yes.
But...
Inspector, these three are the
only ones who hated the victim.
Wait, we didn't do it!
Yeah!
The hair belonged to the victim.
Sazanami-san, your car was
used to transport the body.
N-No way.
And all three of them hated Sadako-sensei.
Of course we did.
I was thinking of buying a house, so
I had her tell me my lucky direction.
Your lucky direction is north-northeast.
The moment I trusted her and bought a house,
the construction company I was working
for shut down, and my wife left me.
I asked her to tell me my romantic fortune.
The man right before your eyes
is the love of your life.
But when I trusted her and
married him, he swindled me.
I had a business I wanted to start,
so I had her tell me when I should start.
Now. Your luck is at its peak.
But when I rushed to quit my job and open
shop, it failed, and now I'm drowning in debt.
All three of you suffered serious blows.
They could definitely be motives.
And none of you have alibis
for last night, right?
I told you, someone called me.
It was a man.
We received the same call, too.
He was making sure we wouldn't have alibis.
The culprit set us up.
You expect us to believe
your convenient story?
Hello?
What?
The results of the autopsy
show the victim died between
8PM and 9PM last night.
She was killed by 9PM at the latest?
Then...
Kid, where are you going?
I knew it.
This document was created
after 10PM last night.
Which means...
The victim didn't write this.
The culprit wrote it when
they brought the body here
to cast suspicion on these three.
In other words, they really were framed.
See?
If one of them killed her,
they'd never write this.
If they tried to frame them,
the culprit must've known
they hated the victim.
Did you tell anyone else?
I haven't told anyone.
Me, neither.
I wouldn't embarrass myself
by telling anyone that.
Yeah.
But someone had to have told them.
It's hard to imagine them telling someone
about it on purpose, which means...
Please find the person who framed us.
Aren't you a great detective?
It would make up for accusing us.
If we examine the crime scene, I'm sure
we'll find a clue to the culprit's identity.
In order to find the culprit,
let's take a break before
discussing the case further.
Could it be?
No one besides those three
hated the victim, right?
Yeah. No matter how hard I looked,
I couldn't find anyone else.
Then it's possible they weren't framed,
but the culprit wanted us to think that.
In other words, one of
them is still the culprit.
Since there was no need to work
together, they probably acted alone.
Why did the culprit make us
suspect all three of them?
And why did they get the old man involved?
No, there must be some reason they
had to do both of those things.
And if I can figure that out,
I'll know who did it.
They didn't find anything, huh?
It's odd, though.
The secretary wouldn't have told
anyone they hated the victim.
It would hurt business.
And those three wouldn't tell anyone, either.
It would've embarrassed them.
Doesn't that mean no one else knew?
What? Where and when did I lose my lighter?
Uh, Kogoro-no-ojisan told me to ask you.
If he knew, he would've gone to retrieve it.
Is he really a great detective?
If they can't find the real culprit,
what's going to happen to this case?
They'll probably never solve it.
Well...
That bogus fortune teller
got what was coming to her.
I got my fortune told because I
couldn't make a decision on my own.
I was in the same boat.
I'm actually a weak person.
Me, too.
That's why I relied on fortune telling.
I see.
When you think of it that way, it explains
why all three of them were framed.
Well, my company wasn't doing well
since before I bought the house,
and my relationship with my wife
had been going poorly for a while.
And I lied a lot about the man I was dating,
so it's possible that clouded her abilities.
Then she doesn't deserve your hate.
I know that.
My situation's different.
If she hadn't told me to start right away,
Alien Ramen would've succeeded.
Alien Ramen?
It's the restaurant I started
after quitting my job.
Waiters dressed like aliens
bring your ramen to you
and throw pieces of star-shaped pork into
it while shouting, "Shooting star!"
As long as I opened at the right
time, business would've been booming.
Right?
Why is he so confident?
Don't ask me.
I need to use the bathroom.
What?
So that's how it is.
When you think of it that way, it explains
why they got the old man involved.
But there's not enough evidence.
In that case...
I'm detective Mori Kogoro, and I'm
assisting with the investigation.
There's something I'd
like to confirm with you.
I know.
Yes, could you please compare
it to the data I just sent you?
Thank you.
Everyone, Mori-kun just called
to say he's figured out the case.
What?
Shibahama Park
Kanawa-san, Endo-san, Sazanami-san.
You weren't framed by the culprit.
You wanted us to think you were.
What?
What does that mean, Mori-kun?
By pretending they were
framed by the true culprit
after killing the victim,
they tried to avoid becoming suspects.
In other words, there was never
a true culprit who framed them?
Yes. I was right all along.
All three of them are accomplices.
What?
It does make sense.
These three are the only
ones who hated the victim.
Sounds like we'll have to question you again.
Bring them down to the station.
Yes, sir.
Wait a minute!
I didn't do it!
Find the true culprit!
That should mean this case... is closed...
Wait, everyone.
All three of you being accomplices
is just one possibility.
There's also another way
to interpret the situation.
Another interpretation?
The key to solving this case
is in the culprit's character.
Character?
What does that mean?
The culprit moved the body,
even though it didn't
benefit them in any way.
They deliberately left personal items
at the murder scene and body's location
because they needed Sazanami-san's
car to move the body
so that along with the text document,
all three of them would be suspects.
To make it look like they'd been framed?
There was that, of course, but the culprit's
character required them to do it.
What?
If you look at their motive, it was clear
they'd eventually fall under suspicion.
Rather than fearing when the police
would arrive at their door,
they thought it'd be better
to be identified right away.
What kind of stupid logic is that?
They're not stupid, they're weak.
So weak they relied on a fortune
teller to make life decisions.
So all three of them did it.
Because the culprit was weak,
they felt uneasy doing it alone.
They wanted others beside them
who were in the same situation:
same motive, no alibi, and personal
items left at the crime scene.
Who is the culprit?
They also used my name and got me
involved because of their weakness.
If the investigation dragged on,
the police would be forced
to ask for my help.
Rather than anxiously waiting to see when
the great detective would turn up...
It'd be better for you to
be involved from the start?
Exactly.
And if I, a man trusted by the police,
deduced that the three of them
were framed by the true culprit,
there would be no greater assurance.
But, Mori-san...
There's no guarantee that you'd
come to the desired conclusion.
That's exactly the key point.
What?
A normal person wouldn't take that risk.
But the culprit believed it would work.
One of these three is
simultaneously weak-willed
but also incredibly confident.
Right,
Sazanami Ryoichi-san?
What?
It's him?
No, no. It couldn't be me.
Yesterday you called the
victim, inviting them out.
I am the detective Mori Kogoro.
I have something to discuss
with Barbara Sadako-sensei.
Then you called Kanawa-san and Endo-san
so they wouldn't have alibis.
Sadako-sensei will be visiting you tonight
to apologize for her fortune telling.
Please wait at your home.
Then you killed the victim in Shibahama Park.
You left Kanawa-san's lighter
at the scene of the murder,
which you likely stole when
you went to make a complaint.
You used your allegedly stolen car to
transport the body to the Baba mansion
and left Endo-san's brooch, which
you also stole, by the body.
You also left the text document
that would be discovered
during the course of the investigation then.
The culprit set us up.
After making that claim, you waited for
the time of death to be determined.
If one of them killed her,
they'd never write this.
You escaped into that blind
spot and tried to get away
while the police searched for a
true culprit who didn't exist.
Yes, so the case would never be solved.
Weak-willed but confident?
Now I'm the killer just
because of my character?
I have nothing to do with the case!
Then how did you know the
murder was committed here?
There's no way for me to—
You told us.
You mean the anonymous call?
I listened to the recording earlier.
I saw a suspicious figure in
Shibahama Park last night.
I didn't make that call!
I'll answer it.
Yeah, I'll let him know.
They said it's a match.
I had them compare your voices
after sending your voice to forensics.
You made the call.
You told us the scene of the murder,
which only the culprit could've known.
I dug my own grave with that phone call?
But why did he make that call?
He had to.
Only once we discovered Kanawa-san's
lighter left at the scene of the murder
would all three of them be together.
I felt hopeless without everyone here.
So you admit you killed Barbara Sadako-san?
If she'd properly told me my
fortune, it would've succeeded!
There's no way Alien Ramen
wouldn't draw customers!
Alien Ramen?
Weak-willed but confident.
What a character.
Easily flattered, drunkard,
and irresponsible...
Huh? Who are you talking about?
Does anyone that hopeless exist?
Nope, nope.
No self-awareness?