This is it.
Wow.
Shall we go?
Good work.
I'm sorry.
Genta-kun.
Sorry.
Are they coming to see the
studio on their day off?
Agasa-sensei requested a tour for the kids.
They're our future regulars.
If this place lasts that long.
Are we really in trouble?
Have you heard something?
Well, I heard a top-class corporation
called dibs on the place.
It's just a rumor, though.
In my eyes are maximum creation!
My detective skills are tomorrow's reaction!
The security guards' anxious conversation
leads to some toy-related crime!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Killer Fist of Talos
(Part One)
"The Killer Fist of Talos, Part One!"
I've been waiting for you.
Sorry to trouble you, Shinobu-san.
Kagami Shinobu (23)
President's Daughter/Secretary
The president said he
wanted to speak with you.
It must be about the plan
we discussed the other day.
What did that—
Oh, excuse me. What did your father say?
I'm sorry, but you'll
have to ask him yourself.
He's in his office.
I'll show the rest of you around.
Thank you. Please do.
I will.
That dome over there is for tours.
It's big.
The children must love it.
Unfortunately, it's designed
for professionals.
It's for requests for event
characters and modeling.
You can take all the pictures you want.
Really? In that case, say cheese.
No, no. You can't take pictures of me.
She must be shy.
Yeah.
Jeez...
But what if another company
copies your figures?
Yeah. You should watch
out for corporate spies.
Yeah. You don't want any bad supplies.
Genta-kun...
Don't worry. We check everyone's identity
and possessions before taking them on tours.
Besides, it's not that easy
to get inside the studio.
Really?
Come in.
First!
Is this...?
It's a goblin, like the ones
that appear in Western stories.
They're mischievous little imps.
This is the Greek mythological ship Argo.
Heroes like Perseus and Orpheus who
became constellations rode on this ship.
You sure are knowledgeable.
Wow!
It's like a dream.
It's Sun Wukong!
That's right. He's riding the Jindou cloud.
He appears in China's
"Journey to the West."
What a beautiful ship.
That's the floating boat in the sky.
It's a legendary flying ship that
appears in Japanese mythology.
It's facing this way.
Despite its appearance, it's made
of fiberglass, so it's light.
Really?
It doesn't seem that way at all.
You can control its position and orientation?
Yes, easily.
With this single remote,
you can control all the facilities
and even the security in the dome.
It would be terrible if it broke.
If the remote detects any
shocks or malfunctions,
control switches to the
control room inside the dome.
When control switches over,
the power inside the dome goes
out for a second, but it's safe.
As long as there's nothing wrong with
the remote, control switches back to it.
It's a mandragora!
People die if they hear its voice!
It's incredible!
Isn't that the roc?
Yeah, from the Adventures of Sinbad.
The Garuda?
They've even got Indian
mythological creatures.
It's the bronze giant.
Talos!
You kids sure are knowledgeable.
There aren't many adults who know who he is.
We're brimming with curiosity.
We're even part of the Detective Boys.
Talos moves even though he's so big.
That's right. We only move Talos and the
floating boat for special occasions.
Talos in particular took an
incredible amount of effort.
His fists and arms alone
were redone countless times.
Make Talos stand up.
I bet that's amazing.
I'm sorry.
He's not finished from the legs down.
What? When is he going to be finished?
Well...
Unfortunately, he'll never be finished.
We wouldn't want to get people's hopes up.
Hanyu Tadashi (25)
Kagami Studio Business Manager
Honestly, it's quite difficult to build
the entire body of something that large.
Because it's too expensive?
Children these days are so smart.
I wish Yamagata-san could've heard that.
Hanyu-san!
Who's Yamagata?
Yamagata Tokuichi (35)
Kagami Studio Chief Designer
Let's not talk about that anymore, Hanyu-san.
Didn't we decide that we'd
leave it up to the president?
That's easy for you to say,
but as the one holding the company's
purse strings, I'll never agree to it.
Whoa, whoa...
It's true that Talos was expensive,
but not having legs will kill him.
Do you kids know the story of Talos' heel?
Yeah!
The only weakness of the
bronze automaton Talos,
who protected the island of Crete
appearing in Greek mythology,
was his heel, right?
That's right.
Well, Hanyu-san?
For Talos to truly be Talos, he needs legs.
The Talos you saw is too
big to leave the dome,
but look.
By breaking him down into
parts and transporting them,
the bronze giant Talos can appear
before audiences around the world.
Look at this!
It's really light!
What are you doing, Genta?!
Put it back where you found it!
What if you break it?!
It's important!
Go on. Apologize.
Sorry...
It's fine.
You're free to look at and
touch everything in here.
Really?
Yes.
All right!
It even looks like bronze up close.
It looks so heavy.
I hope we get to see the
completed Talos soon.
I'm so excited.
Yamagata-san.
Yeah. We were right.
Your sense of professional self-satisfaction
won't fix the problem.
Whether we live or die
is a matter of business.
Then we should be investing in our future!
Under current circumstances,
our company has no future.
That's enough, you two.
It's not that easy a matter
to compromise, Shinobu-san.
What?
This day—no, every second is important.
In that regard, we agree.
Fine. Let's go get the
president's decision now.
Don't go bringing your family's
hobby into my business.
Tadashi-san!
Sorry.
Was it just a hobby?
I'll say it again! I'm rejecting your plan!
Do you understand?!
No!
Kagami Eizo (58)
Kagami Studio President
Shinobu-san placed the order.
She asked me to design Talos' driving
system as cheaply as possible.
What?
I wracked my brains because I
understood your daughter's suffering.
How can you say that without hearing me out?
You've lost your humanity.
You go too far.
Why shouldn't I?
President's Office
Because of your cowardice, Yamagata-san
will never be able to show off his talents.
You're not an employee.
You've no right to talk.
I employed Yamagata's father.
If he doesn't stop showing off his
talents, the company won't last.
Doesn't this studio exist because
of Yamagata-san's talent?
You don't know anything.
My company's been in the red
since his father worked here.
No...
That can't be...
President's Office
I'm out of time.
Wait, Kagami.
What's this?
Professor Agasa's meeting
sure is taking a long time.
You're right. He's late.
If he's not coming, I'm eating his food.
That's right.
The rumors about the company
being sold are true.
The president is acting
without telling Yamagata-san.
I've been talking to other companies,
but it's not going well.
I see.
Our top priority is keeping the Kagami
name, but that's become difficult.
It's been around since the Edo Period.
I'm sure my father can't stand
to let it fail in his generation.
They said they'd consider it if
we had a special plan in place.
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
I feel like I recognize Hanyu-san.
That's it. He was at a Suzuki family party.
Sonoko loved him.
Her uncle seemed happy about it, too.
That can't be good. Doesn't
she have Kyogoku-san?
We're talking about Sonoko.
She was just excited to
talk to a handsome man.
Well, I guess that's nothing new.
The buyer you're talking about is
the Suzuki Conglomerate, isn't it?
You knew?
A classmate said she saw you
at a Suzuki family party.
She said you were dancing with
their daughter all night.
Suzuki Sonoko-san took
a strange liking to me.
Isn't she young and pretty?
Not as much as you.
Those two are in love.
There's no room for Sonoko-neechan.
In any case, I need a plan to
present them to seal the deal.
That's the feeling I got, but...
If only you could ask Yamagata-san for help.
Future dreams
for children!!
I was a little too hard on him earlier.
I'm stuffed.
Mitsuhiko, where's the bathroom?
I think I saw one around there.
I see. Around there, huh?
Around there...
Where are you going?
Around there.
They've got snacks.
I really need to go.
Around there...
Sir, my kids are young. What
if the company goes under?
This place does pay better
than other companies.
Why is a company as clean
as ours going under?
Who knows? Maybe that's
just how the world works.
This doorknob is broken.
It won't lock?
This isn't good. Let's make
sure it gets fixed immediately.
Got it.
That was close. I almost wet myself.
Is someone there?
It's broken.
How careless.
We don't want any bad supplies getting in.
That should do it.
You're back?
You seem down.
Where have you been?
I was looking for the bathroom.
The bathroom's right there.
Oh, no!
Anyway, Professor, I'm sorry.
For what?
I ate your food.
But I left your dessert.
Really? Then you can have my dessert, too.
Really?
Thanks for the food!
Children are so energetic.
Sounds like your plan was rejected.
The company doesn't have
time for it right now.
What's happening?
They're selling.
What? They're selling?
They've steeled their resolve.
The president's set his focus overseas.
What a waste.
The company's technology and designs
have an established reputation here.
You can spend all the money you want building
good products, but if they don't sell, it's over.
It's ironic. Their exceptional technology
has become a burden for them.
We had a shouting match like the old
days, but that was the end of it.
It's a harsh world.
Wait.
Tadashi-san, where are you going?
I'm going to ask the president
how negotiations are going.
President's Office
Get your boss on the phone immediately.
Tell him Kagami has finally
made his decision.
I won't take much of his time.
Let's drop all pretenses and
have one last conversation.
Sorry, but wait there. I
can't come to the door.
Your father is a compassionate
man, but he's stubborn.
He has a habit of suffering alone.
I know.
He's often misunderstood because of it.
He's no good with people.
His nickname in school was the Wild Pitcher.
I was the Clumsy Catcher.
I constantly failed to catch his pitches.
Well? This is the most I'm
willing to compromise.
I hope you'll consider signing
a contract under these terms.
Later!
What? Franklin?
He's negotiating with Franklin Planning?
Yes. That's what Hanyu-san told me.
That's a top foreign corporation.
They're making a killing
in transmedia business.
Conan-kun, how do you know that?
Uh, Shinichi-niichan said so.
There it is.
He's asking them to keep the Kagami name.
Keep the Kagami name, huh?
They do care a lot about their honor.
Because he expects negotiations
to move slowly,
Hanyu-san has been talking
to other companies.
But their conditions are hard to swallow.
Then we'll exchange documents and confirm
the conditions we agreed upon over the phone.
Tell your boss I hope his business does well.
I'll talk to you later.
Sorry, sorry.
I kept you waiting.
Huh?
There's no one here.
Yamagata-san.
Excuse the intrusion.
Good luck with your work.
It was interesting.
Sorry for the trouble.
We look forward to seeing Talos completed.
Goodbye, Yamagata-sensei.
Sensei, huh?
Me?
I'm really sorry about today.
It's fine. Give my best to your father.
I will.
What was that?
Could it be?
Tadashi-san?
Tadashi-san!
Where are you?
Answer us!
Come out if you're okay!
Please respond, Hanyu-san!
Where are you?
Look!
Isn't that Hanyu-san?
What?
Episode Preview
What is this?
What is it, Shinobu-san?
This was on his hand.
Tell me.
Do you have your remote with you?
What are you doing?
What about this?
You mischievous brat!
Who is he?
The Killer Fist of Talos
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Killer Fist of Talos, Part Two!"
Swing
Next Conan's hint!
A swing!
The movie in theaters is:
Don't miss the next episode
The Iron Blue Fist!
Friday's movie is:
Zero the Enforcer!