The Detective Boys and Ran came to tour a
studio run by an acquaintance of the professor.
It's the bronze giant.
Talos!
It even looks like bronze up close.
It looks so heavy.
I hope we get to see the
completed Talos soon!
I'm so excited!
Yamagata-san.
Yeah. We were right.
Your sense of professional self-satisfaction
won't fix the problem.
Whether we live or die
is a matter of business.
President's Office
I'll say it again! I'm rejecting your plan!
Do you understand?!
I wracked my brain because I
understood your daughter's suffering.
How can you say that without hearing me out?
You've lost your humanity.
You go too far.
Why shouldn't I?
President's Office
Because of your cowardice, Yamagata-san
will never be able to show off his talents.
What was that?
Could it be?
Tadashi-san!
Where are you?
Answer us!
Come out if you're okay!
Look!
Isn't that Hanyu-san?
What?
Hanyu Tadashi (25)
Kagami Studio Business Manager
Tadashi-san! Tadashi-san!
In my eyes are maximum creation!
My detective skills are tomorrow's reaction!
A sad reality lurks within
a studio of dreams!
What happened on the observation deck?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Killer Fist of Talos
(Part Two)
"The Killer Fist of Talos, Part Two!"
What? I-It wasn't an accident?
No.
Judging by the wound on his head, it's
hard to imagine this was an accident.
Which means the culprit is still...
Yamagata Tokuichi (35)
Kagami Studio Chief Designer
...somewhere around here.
Hey, what's going on?
Kagami Eizo (58)
Kagami Studio President
Hanyu!
What's happening?
Manager Hanyu?
He's still breathing.
We've already called an
ambulance. More importantly...
It's likely the culprit
is still lurking nearby.
Search the area.
Please.
Yes, sir!
The culprit might have a weapon. Be careful.
Got it. Stay there, everyone.
Kagami Shinobu (23)
President's Daughter/Secretary
What is this?
What is it, Shinobu-san?
I found this on my hand.
I think it was next to Tadashi-san's injury.
I recognize that color.
Isn't that the color of Talos?
Could it be?
Did those fists strike Hanyu-san?
That's impossible.
Talos has no legs. He couldn't do that.
We didn't find any suspicious
persons inside the dome,
just figures and models that
fell when the power went out.
Could they have entered
through a window or vent?
There were no signs of that, either.
We're checking the security
camera footage right now,
but we haven't found any suspicious persons.
Then who hit Hanyu-kun?
Take good care of Hanyu-kun.
He's very important to us.
I will.
So the culprit took advantage
of the opportunity to escape.
But we ran here as soon
as we heard him scream.
I don't think they had time to do that.
Hey!
No one came through here.
I didn't see any suspicious persons, either.
Me, neither.
We came in a hurry, so we can't be certain.
Either way, this had to be the work of
someone intimately familiar with the facility.
It's natural to assume the culprit
used the situation created
by the loss of power and falling
models to hit Hanyu-san,
but that wouldn't have given
them enough time to flee.
Then there's the bronze paint...
Why was it on Hanyu-san's wound?
An outsider snuck in?
We're known domestically and internationally
for our products with originality.
I think it's possible.
Then shouldn't your security be tight?
It's just a possibility.
It would be wise to have our
security guards look into it.
We should tell them.
You're right.
Is there something bothering you?
Yes.
The service entrance door was broken.
It couldn't be locked.
That's it. The culprit must've
entered through there.
Wrong!
What?
That door's fine.
After all, I made sure it couldn't be opened.
You're right. It doesn't
look like it was moved.
This and the security camera
footage eliminates the possibility
that a suspicious person entered
through the main or service entrance.
Nice work, Genta-kun.
Yes!
In other words, one of us is the culprit.
Just before the crime, we were
saying hello to Yamagata-san.
Shinobu-san was with us the whole time.
Agasa, are you saying I did it?
O-Of course not! That's not what I'm saying.
I was just stating the truth.
They've been friends since college.
Apparently they argued often as students.
I see.
Hey, mister.
How many remotes are there that
control the dome's facilities?
There are two.
Yamagata and the tour guide
Shinobu each have one.
Yamagata-san, do you have your
remote with you right now?
Y-Yeah...
You must mean this.
Can you differentiate it
from the other remote?
No. They're both the same shape.
We'll start by asking
everyone for their alibi.
President Kagami, what were you doing?
When I heard Hanyu-kun scream,
I'd just concluded a deal over the phone
and was preparing to leave in my office.
The security guards were just returning.
Right?
Yes, that's right.
What I'm wondering is why Hanyu-san
was on the observation deck.
Why was it necessary to
shut off power to the dome?
The dome's lights shut off,
and we heard the models fall
after Hanyu-san's scream.
Since the lights came back
on immediately afterwards
it's likely Hanyu-san had a remote.
Which means he should have
dropped it around here.
Looking for something?
Good timing.
Could you split up and look for a remote?
You can stay within a ten meter radius.
Got it.
Why are we looking for a remote?
Remember how the dome's lights shut off?
But they immediately came back on, so...
So?
So Hanyu-san had the remote until then.
Hanyu-san used it to shut off
the power while standing there.
Maybe the power shut off because he
dropped the remote when he was attacked.
No.
If that were the case, the power would
have gone out after Hanyu-san screamed.
Right.
Which means Hanyu-san chose
to shut off the power.
But why?
We searched pretty thoroughly,
but we didn't find the remote.
Maybe the culprit took it with them.
That's it.
That must be it.
Yeah.
Even if they did,
they didn't have time to leave
without being spotted by us.
That's right.
Huh?
What?
What is it?
During the tour...
Ayumi-chan, you took a picture
of the floating boat, right?
What? Yeah.
Let me see.
Here.
Thanks.
I knew it. Look.
This is the last place we saw the
floating boat during the tour.
But now, it's over there.
You're right!
The boat is in a different location.
But why?
Maybe it moved when the power shut off.
It may be a light fiberglass boat,
but would losing power make it move that far?
I found this on my hand.
I see. So that's how it is.
Anything unusual?
No matter how small.
Is there anything at all?
Come to think of it,
while I was on the phone,
someone visited my office.
I heard the door open and close twice.
Twice?
That means someone entered and then left.
Do you have any idea who it was?
I thought it was Hanyu-kun or Yamagata-kun.
Was it you?
No. It wasn't me.
Then it must've been Hanyu-kun.
Or maybe the culprit had
already snuck in by then.
Inspector, we still haven't found any signs
that anyone entered or left the
studio around the time of the crime.
We'll have to thoroughly search the studio.
Please find the culprit.
This man's ideas alone are a treasure
trove for anyone in this industry.
P-Please don't, sir.
Don't be modest.
You should hold your head high.
But I burn so much money.
It's my job as well as Hanyu-kun's
to complain about you.
Don't worry so much about it, you fool.
There are plenty of places for the culprit
to hide, like offices and storage rooms.
If they came for our industry secrets, then
while they were looking for treasure...
I see.
It's possible they ran into Hanyu-san then.
What is it, Conan-kun?
There's something I want to ask Shinobu-san.
It's me.
How is Hanyu-kun?
You're crying too much to understand.
Pull yourself together.
He's in critical condition.
What should I do, Dad?
Why don't you believe in him?
When he wakes up, the first thing
he'll want to see is you looking well.
You're right. Thanks, Dad.
What about the culprit?
Unfortunately, they still haven't—
What?
Hey, listen.
What is it? You're a nuisance, aren't you?
He sure is.
Sorry, but could you do as he asks?
What are you talking about?!
Take this kid and—
Tell me.
Tell you what?
Do you have your remote with you?
What are you doing?
I have it.
What about this?
Never mind, then. Thanks.
You mischievous brat!
Who is he?
Looks like you solved the mystery.
Yeah, more or less.
Professor, there's one more
thing I want to confirm.
What?
We'll begin thoroughly searching
the entire studio for the culprit.
We appreciate your cooperation.
Yes, sir.
There's no need for that.
Professor Agasa, what do you mean?
I know who did it.
What?
The culprit?
Who is it?
Now, now. Calm down.
Uh, what's next?
Professor, he said something
about the remote.
Ah, yes. That's right.
Are you listening?
There are two remotes that
control the dome's facilities.
Isn't that right, President Kagami?
Yes, that's correct.
And one of those was used during the crime.
The power came back on immediately
after it was shut off, but...
During that moment,
all the models floating in the air fell.
But one of them behaved unnaturally:
the floating boat.
When the power goes out,
the no longer suspended swinging boat
should fall to its lowest point.
However, the floating boat is over there,
in a different position from the
one it was in before the attack.
How did that happen?
Uh, well...
I was the first to notice.
I was looking at the photos Ayumi-chan took.
See?
This was the floating boat's
final position during our tour,
and now it's over there after the attack.
You're right. It moved.
Someone must've moved it using the remote.
Yamagata-san, do you know anything?
I...
Or maybe Hanyu-san had a
remote during the attack.
As the last to arrive, wouldn't you have
had the opportunity to retrieve the remote
while we were distracted by
discovering the injured Hanyu-san?
I-I don't know anything.
Yamagata-san, aren't you the one who overheard
my conversation with Kagami in his office?
President's Office
Doesn't this studio exist because
of Yamagata-san's talent?
You don't know anything.
My company's been in the red
since his father worked here.
No...
What's this?
Then you should hate me.
Why did you attack Hanyu-kun?
That's right.
You were my target!
I tried to set a trap for you!
I've created something I'm proud of.
Use your remote in the dome.
You'll see something incredible
when the power goes out.
I left you a note.
I wasn't expecting Hanyu-kun to be there.
I finally get it now.
Hanyu-kun wanted to present your new product
to the Suzuki Conglomerate as a gift,
without realizing it was a trap.
Your target was President Kagami,
but Hanyu-san fell for your trap instead.
You can tell us all about it at the station.
There's no point in running!
There's no exit that way!
Could it be?
Stay back!
Watch out! Get down!
He vanished?
What?
What is that?
Talos's hand!
Run!
Yamagata!
I'm sorry.
No, you don't!
Yamagata!
Listen to me.
I just made a deal with Franklin Planning.
This studio will become
Franklin's Japanese branch.
None of the employees will be laid off.
We'll keep the whole staff.
The Kagami name and I will be gone,
but the studio will continue operating under
the name Yamagata Room on a trial basis.
You should be grateful, you imbecile!
Once you've gotten that through
your head, go do your job.
Everyone's waiting for you, you moron.
I'm sorry for the trouble.
Dad, Tadashi-san has regained consciousness.
The hospital director said
he's fine and not to worry.
I see. That's great news, Shinobu.
Did you find the culprit?
What's wrong, Dad?
Don't worry, Shinobu-san.
The case has been solved.
Your father was a good man after all.
I'm sure Talos will get his day eventually.
Yeah.
I'm sure someday the giant's
entire body will be completed.
Episode Preview
You may not be strong, but you've got money.
You'll pay, won't you?
Apparently they've found dinosaur
bones and footprints before.
All right! Let's find an ammonite!
Which means someone poisoned
the bathroom beforehand
and made the victim touch it.
The Dangerous Fossil Finding Trip
The next episode of Conan is
"The Dangerous Fossil Finding Trip!"
Insects
Next Conan's hint!
Insects!
Don't miss the next episode.
Golden Week!
Over the ten day break...
Playing at the movie theater is...
The Fist of Blue Sapphire!