"I saw the Oninohamura Village website."
"An article on there
says a moon's droppings
was found at the Oninohamura
Village Museum excavation site."
"Based on my research,
the fossil was found in a layer
of earth 130 million years old."
"There's no precedent of moon's droppings
being discovered in earth from that era."
"I was hoping I could visit you and
have an in-depth conversation."
Wait, she totally doubts us!
Yeah. So, what are we going to do?
At this rate, someone might discover
we lied about the fossil's origins.
There you go again.
You can handle a reporter or two.
Right, Mr. Politician?
Don't be ridiculous!
I'm not that influential!
I'm just a town mayor!
What? Seriously?!
Why do you think I'm working with you?
It's so you can do something about this!
Just solve it with money, then.
You may not be influential,
but you've got money.
But...
You'll pay, won't you?
After all, your political
career depends on it.
Useless.
In my eyes are maximum creation!
My detective skills are tomorrow's reaction!
A suspicious duo have a
suspicious conversation!
A rare fossil leads to a case!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Dangerous Fossil Finding Trip
"The Dangerous Fossil Finding Trip!"
Lodge &
Fossil Museum
I had no idea ammonites were so pretty.
I thought fossils looked more like rocks.
Well, your typical fossil
is much more plain-looking.
Then why's this one so sparkly?
Because it's made differently.
Typically fossils are made when the matter
that comprises bones and shells
is replaced with minerals.
That sparkly one is sparkly
because it was replaced
with a gemstone like opal.
You kids sure are knowledgeable.
You've got a lot of rare fossils.
You've got a keen eye.
Ogami Akira (38)
Fossil Museum Owner
They were purchased overseas.
I'm proud of my collection.
I see. From overseas, huh?
It's just my hobby.
I'll be going to America
to buy more next month.
The world's largest mineral fair
is held in Tucson, Arizona.
Closed
Tour
Mineral Fair Arizona
I see. Arizona, huh?
You must really love fossils.
Yeah.
Just looking at beautiful
fossils makes me happy.
Hello?
Yes.
Oh, you've arrived. I'll be right there.
Thank you for waiting.
I'm fossil museum owner, Ogami.
Miyashita Umika (27)
Journalist
I'm freelance journalist Miyashita.
Thanks for having me today.
Shall we get started?
Hello, hello! Thank you for
making the trip out here.
Nakatani Sogen (54)
I'm Nakatani, the town mayor.
Let's do the interview after the tour.
Please wait inside.
All right.
Ogami!
Like you said, I've decided to
settle the matter with money.
Good.
I knew I could count on you, Mr. Mayor.
So you don't need to worry about anything.
Sheesh.
A journalist? Did you come
to write a story on us?
Of course not.
They must've found some kind of rare fossil.
Come to think of it, I saw a story
about that on the village's website.
That's right. I came here
because I saw the same story.
See?
Moon's Droppings found at Oninohamura Village, Gunma Prefecture!
It says they found a moon's droppings.
What's a moon's droppings?
It's when the inside of a
conch shell becomes a jewel.
Does that make sense?
It's a very valuable type of fossil.
And they found that at
the excavation site here?
That's right.
Look.
It looks like a turd!
That's right. Droppings means poop.
What?!
Maybe ancient people thought the rabbit
in the moon had pooped on them.
But I don't see it on display anywhere.
We're thinking of making
it the village's symbol.
It's on display at the town hall.
Their symbol is poop.
Genta-kun, that's rude.
I hope it doesn't become a negative symbol.
Everyone, we're ready to begin the tour.
Go ahead.
Ogami-san, could I take a look at the site
where the moon's droppings was found later?
Yes, of course.
There's actually something
I'd like to tell you.
Very well.
All right! Let's find an ammonite!
Genta, you're not going to find an ammonite.
What? Why not?
We could make a major discovery.
Different types of fossils are
found in different layers of earth.
All you'll find here are
clam or oyster fossils.
Clams, huh?
I had some in my miso soup this morning.
But apparently they've found ornithomimus
dinosaur bones and footprints before.
Seriously?
I wanna find a dinosaur.
Let's do our best.
Yeah!
I don't see any fossils in there.
They're quite difficult to find...
Maybe there aren't any here.
I didn't find any again.
Genta, what if you hit someone?
Sorry.
This is a fossil.
What?
Look here. The color's darker.
This is a clam fossil.
It's tiny.
It's so plain.
It's not easy to find big ones.
The only shortcut to finding
good fossils is to dig a lot.
All right! Let's dig, dig, dig!
That's the spirit.
As long as you dig with passion,
the fossils will find you.
All right!
Fossils sure are complicated.
I don't understand them at all.
But I thought you were sponsoring
the moon's droppings PR program.
I've left most of it up to Ogami-kun.
All I do is sign off on it.
Do you have a minute?
Yes.
I've been wondering whether
or not I should tell you.
Ogami-kun!
Do you have a minute?
Sure!
Excuse me. We'll talk later.
Ai-chan, want to go to the bathroom?
Sure.
Someone's inside.
Are you all right?!
This smell...
Yoshida-san, stand back!
Ayumi-chan, what's wrong?
I-In the bathroom...
Ogami-san!
This smell...
Yamamura Misao
Gunma Prefecture
Police Inspector Division 1
I see, I see.
The victim was Oninohamura Village lodge
& fossil museum owner Ogami Akira-san.
And the cause of death was cyanide poisoning.
I-Is that right?
The victim didn't eat or drink anything
during the fossil excavation tour.
Which means someone poisoned
the bathroom beforehand
and made the victim touch it.
D-Do you think we did it?
We'd never do that.
That's right. Besides, why would
someone choose to kill him like that?
These children could have been harmed.
What? Oh, uh, you're right.
W-Well, if it isn't Conan-kun.
Does that mean Mori-san's here, too?
Mori-kun isn't here today.
Oh, it's you, Agasa-san.
You sure do get caught up
in a lot of cases, too.
Excuse me, but I don't think
this is a criminal case.
What? Who are you?
Nakatani the mayor.
What? You're the mayor?
Please excuse me.
Ogami-kun seemed worried about
something for a few days now.
I see. He was worried.
Yes. He said he couldn't
sleep and wanted to die.
Why?
I'm not sure.
Maybe it was because of the moon's droppings.
What?
What's a moon's droppings?
It's an ancient fossil of a shell.
I-I see...
The truth is, I came to expose that
that fossil's origins were faked.
Th-They were faked?
Yes.
I believe the moon's droppings were
found at a different excavation site.
So Ogami-san killed himself because
he thought he'd be discovered?
Yes.
He said there was something
he wanted to confess to me.
Perhaps he couldn't bear
the guilt any longer.
U-Unbelievable.
Nakatani-san knows barely
anything about fossils.
He couldn't help that he didn't notice.
But my village renewal
plan is already in motion.
Well, this looks like a suicide.
Darn.
I thought I'd finally get to
gloriously solve a case again.
But Ogami-san was excited
for his trip next month.
What trip?
He said he was planning to go to America.
There was a plane ticket on his desk.
Would someone considering
suicide buy plane tickets?
Maybe he felt like dying after
he made his reservation.
It's not too late to decide that until after
we determine if there's poison present or not.
We haven't searched everyone yet, either.
See?
We didn't find any poison anywhere.
Really?
Yes.
We didn't find anything on places the
victim was likely to have touched.
We found lots of fingerprints, though.
So it was a suicide, then.
Excuse me, but there's
something I forgot to report.
Huh?
We didn't find poison on the
victim's sanitary wipes,
but they are slightly
more acidic than normal.
Acidic?
Yes.
More than normal?
It's obviously unrelated.
Didn't I say we're looking
for a cyanide compound?
Okay, everyone. Shall we
search the lodge next?
That mayor is definitely the culprit.
Really?
But there's no proof.
Why are they all dead?
What are you guys doing?
Look. There's lots of dead bugs.
Poor bugs.
Let's dig a grave for them.
Wait!
What?
Could it be?
Don't touch those.
What's wrong, Conan?
Did you figure something out?
Yeah, thanks to the Detective Boys.
Since we didn't find any
signs of poison at the lodge,
this must've been a suicide.
It wasn't a suicide.
It's a murder.
I finally figured out how the
culprit killed Ogami-san.
But, Agasa-san, we didn't
find poison anywhere.
How did they kill him?
It's hard to believe the victim
would've drunk the poison himself.
Ogami-san didn't drink the poison.
What?
Wh-What are you talking about?
The victim clearly died of poisoning.
Yes, but aren't there methods of taking in
poisons besides swallowing or licking them?
You still can't figure it out?
That's it. The victim inhaled the poison.
That's right.
Inhaled it? But how?
People say cyanide compounds
kill when they're swallowed,
but actually, the compound
itself is not poisonous.
However, once it enters your body,
it reacts with your stomach
acid, creating a poisonous gas.
That's why people say swallowing
cyanide compounds kill you.
Yes.
What does that mean?
In other words,
adding acid to a cyanide compound
creates a poisonous gas.
Adding acid?
That's right.
The culprit probably dissolved the
cyanide compound in the toilet bowl.
Once the acid is added, the
poisonous gas would be released.
Come to think of it, there was
hydrochloric acid at the lodge.
I heard it's used to clean fossils.
No, that's not what they used.
Adding hydrochloric acid would
produce a poisonous gas immediately.
They could close the lid.
Wouldn't that run the risk of killing
whoever used the bathroom before Ogami-san?
Oh.
You're right. Then how did they do it?
The acid was added not by the
culprit, but by Ogami-san himself.
What?
When he wiped his hands with
a sanitary wipe and tossed it.
Into the toilet bowl?
Yes.
Forensics said the sheet was
slightly more acidic than normal.
The culprit added the diluted hydrochloric
acid to the sanitary wipes.
The cyanide compound in the toilet bowl
reacted with the acid in the sanitary
wipes and created a poisonous gas.
With this method, even if someone
entered the bathroom before him,
the cyanide compound would
be harmlessly flushed away.
The culprit most likely
told Ogami-san they hid
something valuable in the
bathroom so he'd search it.
The clean-freak Ogami-san
used the sanitary wipes
to wipe his hands and threw it in the toilet.
The poisonous gas was
formed, and Ogami-san died.
So? Who did it?
The only one who knew
Ogami-san was a clean-freak
who carried sanitary wipes with him.
Nakatani-san, you're the only one.
W-Wait a minute. That's just your theory.
What about evidence?
Do you have any proof that
Ogami inhaled a poisonous gas?
There is. There's one
piece of solid evidence.
Wh-What is this?
They're just dead bugs.
What's so important about these?
We examined them at Agasa-san's request.
Like the victim, these bugs
were poisoned with cyanide.
What?
Look.
This spot is right beneath the bathroom fan.
The bugs gathered around the fan
must have inhaled the poisonous gas.
No...
Fearing the poisonous gas would
remain inside the bathroom,
you must have left the
fan on, but it backfired.
Damn these insects!
Damn them, damn them!
Hey, wait. What are you doing?
These insects ruined my plan!
You mean you killed Ogami-san?
That's right. I killed Ogami.
You're the one who lied about the moon's
droppings coming from this village, too.
No, they were accomplices.
What?
Accomplices?
That's right.
We came up with the idea together,
but he tried to place all the blame on me.
So I told him I had a tape of evidence
and told him to come to the bathroom.
But you didn't have to kill him.
If I didn't kill him, my political
career would've been over.
There are so many things I still have to do.
What an awful mayor.
There's only one thing you should be doing.
The only thing you should be doing is
showing remorse and atoning for your crimes!
Look. I found an oyster fossil.
I only found clams.
What's going to happen to the fossil museum?
I'll try working to keep it open.
This is all I found.
What is that?
It's gross.
Right? This worthless thing...
Hey, wait. Isn't that dinosaur poop?
What?!
If that's true, that's a
major discovery, Genta.
Seriously? I guess I'm lucky.
Yeah, lucky.
Episode Preview
This is my girlfriend.
She suddenly disappeared a few days ago.
I doubt we'll find a body in this current.
We managed to stop him, but what now?
Conan-kun!
The Missing Girlfriend
The next episode of Conan is
"The Missing Girlfriend!"
Necklace
Next Conan's hint.
A necklace!
Don't miss the next episode.
It's Golden Week!
For two more days!
What?
Genta turned into a fossil.