Mizunuma Kaho (27)
Office Worker
"I'm free Sunday." And send.
Mori Detective Agency
She's missing?
Mizunuma Kaho. She's my girlfriend.
Naruse Jun (27)
Kaho's Boyfriend
She suddenly disappeared a few days ago.
She's pretty.
Yeah.
We planned to go ring shopping on Sunday.
Please find her! Please!
In my eyes are maximum creation!
My detective skills are tomorrow's reaction!
The client makes a desperate request!
An unexpected development
leads to the answer!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Missing Girlfriend
"The Missing Girlfriend!"
Kaho-san lived here alone?
Yes, since about three months ago.
Why did you guys comes with us?
I mean... right?
I don't see anything particularly suspicious.
Why only here?
Could she have gone to
visit family or friends?
Her parents are already dead.
She hasn't visited any friends or coworkers.
I see.
Huh? Was Kaho-san...?
It's an emergency!
The police just called!
Kaho-chan is...
What?
Excuse me.
Conan!
Hey, wait! Conan-kun?
Mizunuma Kaho
Suicide, huh?
No, this is...
I doubt we'll find a body in this current.
Yeah. It rained all day yesterday.
But these shoes and ID card aren't wet.
Hey! You're always snooping around.
That's because Mizunuma Kaho-san
jumped from the bridge at 5:15 AM,
long after it stopped raining.
What? How do you know the exact time?
Because someone happened to
witness Kaho-san jumping.
A witness, huh?
This morning I came to deliver
the paper at the usual time.
Ushio Tetsuya (21)
Newspaper Delivery Boy/College Student
That's when I saw...
Hey, you!
What?
Wait, wait! Hey!
Was that...?
As far as I can tell from that
video, it was definitely a suicide.
No way...
Naruse-san...
You're pretty amazing, though.
Huh?
You took such a good video.
It happened suddenly, right?
You're right.
P-Please. It's just a coincidence
that it came out well.
Come to think of it, this place is pretty
far from Kaho-san's house, right?
How did Kaho-san get here?
Well, obviously...
The trains and buses would've
just started running by then.
Her shoes are too clean for someone
walking outside after it stopped raining.
Oh, in that case...
Ohara Maki (46)
Taxi Driver
Well, well. So she did die.
Could you tell us what happened
when you gave her a ride?
It was around 2:30 at night.
I picked her up on the road and
drove for about thirty minutes.
We arrived here around three.
Her story's accurate.
It's what we confirmed on
the security camera footage.
She got off here looking
like she was going to die.
I knew she'd do it.
Then why didn't you stop her?!
Not letting people die when they want to?
Is that the right thing to do?
But something's not right.
Don't women carry handbags?
Come to think of it, Kaho-san was carrying
a handbag in the security camera footage.
I wonder where it went.
I-I don't know.
She took her bag when she got off.
And didn't Kaho-san get here around three?
What was she doing for over two
hours until she jumped after five?
Probably mentally preparing herself.
She must've gotten rid of her bag then, too.
We have the witness and video to prove it.
It was definitely a suicide.
Hey, officer.
Can I leave now?
I work nights and haven't gotten any sleep.
Can I go, too?
Yes. Thank you for your cooperation.
We might ask you for more details later.
We appreciate your continued cooperation.
Hey, as long as she's here,
let's take a taxi home.
Right, Ran-neechan?
What? But...
I don't mind, as long as you pay.
Why don't you guys ride with us?
The police will pay our fare, right?
I supposed we can cover
your transportation costs.
Lucky.
If you insist.
What about you, Dad?
I'll stay a little longer.
Then we'll head home. Let's go, Conan-kun.
There should be a clue in this video.
How long are you going to keep
watching that? It's my phone.
Conan-kun, Naruse-san is here, too.
Sorry.
Kids these days.
I managed to stop them, but what now?
That good luck charm...
Oh, it's my daughter.
She's dead now, though. It was an illness.
I see.
She was my only family.
Now I live alone and carefree.
Really? She kind of looks like
the girl who killed herself.
How?! They look nothing alike!
Don't compared her to a
girl who killed herself!
There's no need to be so angry.
I gotta go to the bathroom...
Hey, Ran-neechan?
What?
Is this...?
Eyewitness Information Wanted!
Face Unknown
Skinny Man
Long Brown Hair
Tattoos on Both Arms
Oh, I think it was three months ago.
A female college student fell down
some stairs at a park and died.
Isn't the park where this
happened near Kaho-san's house?
You're right. It's right next door.
Oh, that?
We keep it posted at the family's request,
but even the police say it was an accident.
I understand how they feel, though.
Is this really a man?
Oh, nothing. I just thought they
could also look like a woman.
Excuse me.
Be right there.
Huh? You're going to dye your hair black?
I've got an interview for a new job.
The money's good, but they seem strict.
I can't imagine you with black hair.
Shut up.
Wait a minute. In that case...
What is it, Conan-kun?
I need to go back to the bridge!
What? Wait, Conan-kun!
What is it, Conan-kun?
He forgot something.
Why did we have to come, too?
There might still be some trace of it.
Hey!
You're still wandering around here?
Mori-san, that's dangerous!
Oh, no!
Conan-kun!
Hey!
That's it! That light!
Conan!
Conan-kun!
Damn!
Maki-san!
Grab on!
Ran!
Pull! Heave!
It's hot.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Good thing you didn't die.
Ohara Maki
You're a very good swimmer.
I used to swim at the National Athletic Meet.
Could it be?
I see. So that's how it is.
Sorry, Conan-kun.
Jeez. This only happened
because you were wandering—
You're all amazing, though.
Huh?
Even though you couldn't
see her face clearly,
you all knew the person
in the video was Kaho-san.
Well, she had the same hair and clothes.
I see! I've figured it out!
Figured out what, Mori-kun?!
The truth behind this case.
What case? Wasn't Kaho's death a suicide?
No, Kaho-san didn't kill herself.
What? Didn't you see my video?
That was clearly a suicide.
If the person in the video
really was Kaho-san.
Yes, that was a different
person disguised as Kaho-san.
Right? You have a similar build as
her, and you're good at swimming...
Ohara Maki-san.
You faked Kaho-san's suicide.
You knew that Ushio-san would
pass by the bridge at that time.
So she waited for me to arrive to jump.
That's why you were able to film the video.
What proof do you have?
What? W-Well...
It's her shoelaces, right?
The shoes in Kaho-san's room and the ones
found at the crime scene were tied differently.
Over Wrap
In Kaho's Room
Under Wrap
At Crime Scene
You said someone must've
retied them, remember?
Uh, yeah...
But why would I—
In Ushio-san's video,
there's something flashing.
Hey, you!
What?
Wait, wait! Hey!
When I fell from the bridge, I saw
Ran-neechan's necklace
sparkle in the same way.
That was probably Maki-san's necklace.
I-It wasn't me! I'm sure that
Kaho girl wore a necklace, too!
No, Kaho-san never wore any jewelry.
Even when she wore a dress,
she didn't even wear a watch.
Kaho-san must have been
allergic to metals.
We'll know as soon as we analyze the video.
That's right. I killed her.
I'm drowning in debt from my
dead daughter's medical bills.
When I saw her credit card,
I couldn't help myself.
Then that long black hair...
That's right, a wig.
A keepsake of the daughter
who lost her hair to illness.
I never thought I'd be
able to use it like this.
No.
That's not what happened, Maki-san.
Well, that settles this—
I thought this was over...
Wait a minute.
Why did Kaho-san come to
this place late at night?
Isn't that because...?
Naruse-san.
Remember what you said when we met?
We planned to go ring shopping on Sunday.
Kaho-san, a woman allergic to
metals, wanted to buy a ring?
No way.
It's a big fat lie.
Then why did Naruse-san say that?
Naruse-san, you're sweating.
Why don't you roll up your sleeves?
You can't, can you?
You're afraid your tattoo
sleeves will be seen.
Tattoos?
Could it be?
I'm glad I had Conan drag you around
until you gave yourself away.
That's right.
You're the man who pushed the student down
the stairs at the park three months ago.
And Kaho-san...
"I'm free Sunday." And send.
If you tell anyone about this,
I'll kill you and your entire family.
I'll be watching.
The curtains in Kaho-san's
apartment were closed,
and there was dust beneath them.
It's because she'd been unable to
approach the window for a long time.
That proves you persistently followed
her around and watched her.
At the end of her rope, Kaho-san
came to this bridge. And then...
That's right, she died.
There's no proof to back up your reasoning.
There is proof.
Maki-san.
Your driver's license had no
mention of corrective lenses
that's required for persons
with impaired vision.
If you have such good vision,
why did you purchase—
Rather, for whom did you
purchase contact solution
and two lunch boxes?
Maki-san, you didn't kill anyone.
You simply faked Kaho-san's death
to protect her from Naruse-san.
Then Kaho-san is...
That's right.
She's alive and hidden in Maki-san's home.
You're lying!
It's true!
Kaho-chan!
Maki-san!
Kaho-chan...
I was so scared.
I was so worried,
but the police wouldn't take me seriously.
When I lost hope, I went to that bridge...
I'm terribly sorry.
So much time had passed, and it
had been treated as an accident.
But I won't run anymore.
For Maki-san, who risked
herself to protect me.
I saw him.
He did it!
Thank you, Maki-san.
But why were you so desperate
to protect Kaho-san?
He's right. You tried to take
the blame for killing Kaho-san.
Do you remember when you
told me about what happened?
I was so angry.
At Naruse, of course, but also you.
You thoughtlessly said you wanted
to die over something so small.
Why did my daughter who wanted to
live die, but this girl is alive?
I thought about killing
you, just like you wanted.
But then...
I had to help you.
Maki-san...
Courageous Testimony
Culprit Arrested
Site of Suspected Suicide
Dead Student
Suspect Naruse Jun
What a ridiculous client.
We baked these together. Thank you.
Maki & Kaho
Conan-kun, do you think you can become
family even if you're not related by blood?
I'm sure you can.