[Eyecatch]
The day after we returned from Kyoto,
Higashio Maria-chan missed class at Teitan
Elementary School without any notice.
Now that you mention it,
she said she found a letter
from her dead grandma in
her desk drawer the other day.
It sounds like Grandma set up a
treasure hunt in her house for me.
Do you guys want to invite Conan-kun
and look for it together sometime?
Sure, let's do it.
Believing Maria-chan went to her dead
grandmother's house to look for treasure,
Higashio
they visited her grandmother's home,
where they found a mysterious message.
Start! Maria-chan, good luck!
Meanwhile...
Hello?
I told you not to draw attention to yourself!
Everyone's talking about you online!
What?!
"High school detective Kudo
Shinichi solves the case!"
"The rumors that he's dead were wrong!"
Th-They're talking about me online?!
This isn't good! The news
has spread everywhere!
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
How will we combat the news spreading online?
The boss of the Organization is revealed!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Find Maria-chan!
(Part Two)
"Find Maria-chan, Part Two!"
Hey, Ran!
Look out the window.
Out the window?
Don't you think that's a
huge group of reporters?
Yeah.
Did something happen?
Something sure did happen.
Everyone's talking about your
boyfriend online right now.
What? Why are they talking about Shinichi?
Oh, my.
You just casually acknowledged that
Shinichi-kun is your boyfriend, madam.
Why shouldn't I? He is my boyfriend...
Hey, take your seats!
Let's get started!
This room seems to be
directly beneath that arrow.
What a cute room.
Maria-chan must have stayed in this
room when she came to this house.
Isn't it kind of cold in here?
Well, we are in the basement.
So, where's the next arrow?
I don't see an arrow,
but there's a note stuck to the
bedside table next to the bed.
What?
What does it say?
"Now you can use the
bathroom during the night!"
During the night?
She must've meant to turn on this
light before going to bed, so...
Could you turn out the lights?
Okay!
This is...
Wow!
The bumpy pattern goes all around the room.
But it doesn't look like an arrow.
No.
Something was left here.
These two rectangular marks must've
been left by this photo frame.
The shadow changed for some reason.
That's it.
Which means if we place something
in the other rectangular marks...
It must be this doll.
If you match the doll's
base to this square mark...
It changed again!
Is there anything on the floor over there?
Huh?
Not on the floor, but this
sailboat on the shelf fell over.
Could you try standing it back up?
Sure.
Try to keep it in the same place.
It's up.
Now move out of the way.
Okay.
Amazing!
There's an arrow on the wall!
That's it!
Then the next one must
be in the room next door.
Huh?
It's a bathroom.
Indeed.
But there's very obviously an arrow in here.
But the only thing it's
pointing towards is the bath.
That's not a bath, it's a shower.
There's a note in front
of the arrow on the sink.
"Take care of my bird!"
What bird?
Does she mean this doll?
It seems to have a beak.
But how do we take care of it?
What a strange doll.
I don't recognize it.
I feel like I've seen this before.
Now that we're stuck...
That means...
...we'll have to ask.
Huh?
Ask Conan-kun!
What?
Can't we?
Why not?
I'm sure he knows what it is.
Conan-kun's over his cold, right?
Then let's try calling him.
Don't we need to find Maria-chan
as soon as possible?
I hate to ask that promise-breaker for help,
but we don't have a choice.
I know!
Kudo Shinichi had a twin brother,
and it was his brother who died.
Why don't we spread that rumor online?
People would know immediately
that that's a lie!
Don't you get it, Shinichi?
If the Black Organization
finds out that you're alive...
Yeah, I know.
I'm so worried that if I don't joke about it,
I'll go crazy.
Damn...
Haibara Ai
Incoming Call
Haibara.
Well? Did you come up with a plan?
Huh?
What? You still haven't found Maria-chan?
But it's already evening.
I see.
Maria-chan seems to have stopped
by her grandmother's house
before school in order to look for the
treasure she hid, but you couldn't find her.
You followed the notes and
arrows left by her grandmother
and arrived at the bathroom,
but the arrow pointed to
an empty shower room.
That's right.
Hey.
You just laughed, didn't you?
If you've figured out the
answer, tell me, you traitor.
Traitor?
Conan-kun, please!
If we don't find her soon, then Maria-chan...
You guys aren't taking
care of the drinking bird.
Drinking bird?
Drinking bird? You mean...
This bird-like doll to
the right of the arrow?
Yeah.
Drinking birds use the slight heat
generated by evaporation to...
In any case, the bird will
move if you give it water.
How are we supposed to give it water?
There's a glass cup with
a toothbrush on the sink.
Pour water in that and place
it in front of the doll.
Okay!
I did it.
It's not moving.
Maybe it's broken.
Place the doll's beak inside the cup.
Like this?
That's it.
Now let go, and it should
stand up on its own.
After some time, it'll dip
its beak in the water again.
Why?
It's like it's actually drinking water.
Wow!
I see. This is how it's
using the vaporization heat.
So? What does this accomplish?
Look at the arrow through the cup.
Through the cup?
The arrow's pointing the other way.
Why?
The water in the cup is refracting the light,
changing the focal point because
of something called Snell's law.
It makes objects appear flipped.
In other words, the arrow is pointing not
towards the shower room in the bathroom,
but that room across from the bathroom.
Let's check it out!
Yes.
Maybe Maria-chan's asleep.
Call Kobayashi-sensei
once you find Maria-chan.
I know.
Later.
Who is it? Delivery?
Huh? Sushi?
Hello.
But I haven't ordered anything.
Aw, nah.
I came to make a delivery
in this neighborhood,
but I can't get through because
of the commotion next door.
I thought the neighbors might know what's up,
so I stopped by.
Sorry, I wouldn't know.
That guy works at Irohazushi
next to the detective agency.
I think his name is Wakita Kanenori-san.
No way...
It's really them.
Nice to meet you. I'm Kudo Yusaku.
And I'm Yukiko.
What? The door won't open?
No. It's the door the arrow in
the bathroom was pointing to.
What kind of door is it?
What kind?
It looks like it opens inward.
There are lots of flowers carved into it.
These look hand-made.
Maria-chan mentioned that her grandpa
was a really good hobbyist carpenter.
He could make anything, like
shelves and desks and chairs.
Then maybe her grandfather
made this door, too.
Yeah, but her grandpa passed
away before her grandma.
Does that door have a trick?
A trick?
Does it make any noise when
you push or pull on the knob?
It won't budge an inch
whether you push or pull.
In other words, there's no tri—
Did someone sneeze?
It's cold here in the basement.
I see.
The door won't open because the room
on the other side of the door is
warmer than the hallway you're in.
The air pressure is keeping
the door shut from the inside.
Normally carpenters build a
gap so that doesn't happen,
but her grandfather must
not have known to do that.
So? What do we do?
Since the door was left as is,
there's probably enough space
for an adult to open it.
If you all push with the
knob turned, it should open.
Maria-chan?
Maria-chan!
Ai-chan?
How is she?
It's okay. She's just asleep.
Wow!
The room is covered with
Maria-chan and her grandparents.
That's a lot of home movies.
I see.
This room full of their
memories is their treasure.
Is she awake?
Huh? Guys?
What's going on?
You missed school.
We were worried, so we came here.
Huh? School?
Oh, right!
I was going to go to school
after watching this video,
but I couldn't open the door.
I thought I had to finish
watching to open the door,
but I started getting sleepy.
I fell asleep, and now I'm hungry.
Come on, Hattori-kun!
Tell us something about Kudo-kun!
I already told you, that guy next
to me on the news wasn't Kudo!
That's impossible! No matter
how you look at it—
I'm not surprised you thought it was him.
That was Kyoto Senshin second-year and
Kudo lookalike Okita Soshi the kendo brat.
What?!
Huh?
The crowd of reporters
at the gates has shrunk.
You're right. I wonder what happened.
This is probably why.
The person who said they saw your
boyfriend at Kiyomizu Temple
says they might've been hallucinating.
H-Hallucinating?
But Shinichi was at Kiyomizu Temple.
Hattori-kun's saying the boy
seen on TV in Ponto City
was Okita-kun.
Looks like everyone's agreeing
your boyfriend wasn't there.
Our teacher did just tell us
not to respond to reporters
if they asked us about Shinichi-kun.
Makes you wonder if what we
saw was an illusion, too.
An illusion? That wasn't an illusion.
Shinichi really was there.
Of course we're dating.
See?
I'm the one who said she saw Kudo
Shinichi-kun at Kiyomizu Temple.
But now that I think about it,
I think that was a hallucination
produced by my own desires.
I'm sorry for the commotion I caused.
Mori Detective Agency
Thank you.
By the way, do you have any
plans for Christmas, Amuro-san?
None in particular.
I see.
What is it?
The manager wants to plan our shift schedule
for December, so he wanted me to ask you.
A message?
Seeking information on Kudo Shinichi.
Time is money!
Hurry, Bourbon.
Rum.
Roger that.
Send
That giant crowd of reporters is gone.
I'm not sure why, though.
Probably because the world's
biggest Kudo family fan,
who caused the commotion,
calmed their excitement
by posting that the Kudo Shinichi she
saw at Kiyomizu Temple was an illusion.
But why did she suddenly post that?
Because we used her fanaticism against her.
Shin-chan!
D-Dad and Mom?
What?!
You bribed her with your autographs?
Yeah. As our fan, we knew
she'd accept our terms.
We even told her why.
"Our son is still young."
"We don't want this case
to go to his head."
"Could you pretend the incident
at Kiyomizu Temple didn't happen?"
I'm surprised you were able to
meet with the owner of the blog.
We sent a message to the
administrator of the blog.
"This is Kudo Yukiko, avid
reader of your blog."
"There's something I'd
like to discuss with you,
so could you meet me and my
husband at the airport?"
"Please let us know once you've
confirmed it's actually us."
I see.
We also reached out to the
school to give them a heads-up,
so that should be the end of
the Kudo Shinichi disturbance.
Officially, that is.
It's extremely likely your so-called
Black Organization has zeroed in on this.
Sheesh. It's your fault for
going wild on your school trip.
I couldn't help it.
I got caught up in the case.
Well, sounds like something happened
between you and Ran-chan because of it.
How do you know that?!
The administrator of the blog said she
saw you kissing at the Kiyomizu butai.
Also...
The code left at the scene
of Haneda Koji's murder...
ASACA and RUM.
About that...
I discussed it with the FBI
agent living in our house.
He concluded that the code isn't
meant to be split into ASACA and RUM,
but instead should be read as a single
name containing all eight letters.
A single name?
Not split into two?
Eight letters, one name...
As a low-ranking member, the only thing I
know is that the organization's color is black.
Eight letters...
Could it be?!
Carasuma Renya.
If I'm right, then you're making an enemy
out of the most powerful man in the country.
The multi-millionaire who doesn't exist.
So until this is over, Yukiko and I are
staying in Japan to come up with a plan together.
This is the moment of truth, Shinichi...
No, Edogawa Conan-kun.
Yeah.
Just what I was hoping for.
Episode Preview
Tokyo Barls Collection?
What's that?
What's wrong, ma'am?
I can't breathe...
Have some water.
Calm down. Drink slowly.
Someone was trying to kill me!
They put the core of a cabbage in my monja!
The Tokyo Barls Collection
The next episode of Conan is
"The Tokyo Barls Collection!"
Poster
Next Conan's hint!
A poster!
Together this time.
Don't miss the next episode.
Once again...
Edogawa Conan-kun?
Yeah.