[ED]
Mori Detective Agency
You're such an annoying brat!
You're acting suspicious.
There's nothing suspicious about me!
Th-That's...
"Toyoko's monja restaurant
in Tsukishima."
"I hereby invite my beloved detective
Mori Kogoro-sensei to my restaurant."
"Signed, Toyoko."
It's an invitation from a fan.
So you trim your nose hairs
to go eat monja in Tsukishima?
It's my first time meeting
her. I want to look nice.
You mean perving on someone you're
meeting for the first time?
Perving?
Honestly, there's a little bit of that.
So you admit it.
I do.
I want monja, too.
What?
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
Kogoro is invited out for monja and
is hired by an unexpected client!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Tokyo Barls Collection
"The Tokyo Barls Collection!"
Let's see...
It's this way.
I want the deluxe gizzard and
garlic monja with cheese.
You idiot. Monja aren't
supposed to be so luxurious.
Monja are a simple food.
That's an old-fashioned way of thinking.
It's just down that alleyway.
What the hell is that?
Looks like Toyoko-san's
restaurant is over there.
Toyoko's Restaurant
What is that old woman doing?
How rude! Who the hell are you?
Are you the famous detective
Mori Kogoro-sensei?
I am indeed the super famous
detective Mori Kogoro.
My, my. One moment, please.
What?
Does she work here?
Excuse us.
Excuse me.
Oh, my. I'm Toyoko.
I received your invitation.
I'm the great detective...
Mori Kogoro...
Mister!
Oh, my.
I don't believe it.
The great detective Mori-sensei
is overwhelmed by my beauty.
I don't think that's it.
Ow.
I'm so upset!
Only the great river can
heal the wounds on my heart.
The great river has always healed my heart.
The great river?
The Sumida River has always healed my heart.
Sumida River, please
soothe this broken heart.
Ouch...
Kid, where's the old woman?
She said something about being
upset and went to the Sumida River.
Sumida River?
What?!
Was she so upset by my rejection that
she's jumping into the Sumida River?
No way.
There she is.
She's doing that weird dance again.
I used be a dancer at the
big theater in Ginza.
What?
The big theater in Ginza.
Heard of it?
The big theater in Ginza?
Come to think of it, I heard there
used to be a place like that.
It looked something like this,
and featured long lines of
beautiful girls dancing.
We can continue our conversation over monja.
Toyoko's Restaurant
It's good!
Is it? That's good.
Eat all you'd like.
Monja and draft beer in the afternoon...
This is great!
I think I'll have some, too.
It's good. Go, me.
Tokyo Barls Collection?
What's that?
What's wrong, ma'am?
I can't breathe...
Hey, are you okay? Pull yourself together!
Mister, water!
Have some water.
Calm down. Drink slowly.
Are you okay, ma'am?
What's this?
The core of a cabbage?
S-Someone was...
Someone was trying to kill me!
They put the core of a cabbage in my monja!
What?!
I know who the culprit is!
The culprit?
Calm down, ma'am.
It was one of my childhood friends.
What?
They called us the Bufu'usu of Tsukishima.
Tsu-Tsukishima's...
Bufu'usu?
Busujima Toyoko (75)
I, Busujima Toyoko, was Bu.
Fuda Eiko (75)
Fuda Eiko was Fu.
Ugajin Kyoko (74)
Ugajin Kyoko was U.
Suo Yuko (75)
Suo Yuko was Su.
Modern women are no good.
They don't drink skim milk
with their school lunches.
Those children know nothing of war.
I heard they don't do
that at schools anymore.
Don't do what?
Carry firewood while
studying, like Ikkyu-san.
That guy who came up with the
crying nightingale Jomon culture?
What? Jomon culture?
Bu, you're always showing off your intellect
since you're the only one
who attended high school.
Yeah.
You've got a big head just
because we didn't complete
our compulsory education
to your satisfaction.
I'm stuffing myself until
I'm full of this shit!
Me, too!
Don't stuff yourselves with shit!
It must've been one of them.
What?
I'm sorry.
Mid-century women can't
help but speak their minds.
I understand.
It's your age that makes you say that.
No, you don't. Your age doesn't
make you say anything.
Detective Mori Kogoro-sensei.
Huh?
Could you investigate this case?
What?
Here's your pay.
I accept!
Will suspect #1, Fuda Eiko-san,
also known as Fu of Tsukishima,
really appear on the bullet
train platform at Tokyo Station?
According to Toyoko-san, also
known as Bu of Tsukishima.
I-Is that her?
Fu of Tsukishima?
Excuse me.
Are you Fuda Eiko-san, also
known as Fu of Tsukishima?
You're here about Bu.
How did you know?
Did she die?
Not yet.
That Bu of Tsukishima is as tough as ever.
Do you resent her for some reason?
Of course I do.
During middle school, I was dating
ping pong team captain Cho-kun...
Let him break up with Eiko,
let him break up with Eiko.
Break up with Eiko, break up with Eiko.
Break up, break up, break up,
break up, break up, break up.
Fine, I'll do it! I'll break up with Eiko!
I see. I'm sorry about—
Huh?
Over there.
Please don't jog on the station
platform! It's very dangerous!
Suspect #2, Ugaji Kyoko-san,
also known as U of Tsukishima,
Toyonaka Market
butchers tuna at Toyonaka Market.
You're here about Bu, aren't you?
I'm surprised you knew.
Eiko called me. She said a detective
came to ask her about Bu.
So you do resent her for some reason.
Of course I resent that nincompoop.
During middle school, I was dating
baseball team captain Fuji-kun...
What a heavy roller.
Break up with Kyoko and date me instead!
What?
If you won't date me, then kill me!
Kill me!
Push that roller over me!
Okay!
I will have my revenge.
Eko Eko Azarak!
She's awfully energetic.
Suspect #3, Suo Yuko-san, also
known as Su of Tsukishima, is...
Hello, ni hao, guten tag.
I've got great souvenirs.
Good stuff from Mt. Fuji,
good stuff from Hokkaido.
You, boss. I've got good stuff from Nikko, too.
I'm not your boss, and I'm not a foreign tourist.
During middle school, I was dating...
The basketball team captain,
who she stole from you?
During middle school, I was dating
judo team captain Ban-kun...
Damn that Busujima Toyoko—I
mean, Bu of Tsukishima.
Ouch...
Anti-itch Cream
This medicine should work.
It's working!
I saw you!
I saw you doing something embarrassing!
Don't tell anyone.
If you don't break up with Yuko and
starting dating me instead, I might.
Don't tell anyone! Don't tell anyone!
Don't tell anyone!
Something's not right.
All three of the women named
as suspects resent Toyoko-san,
but all three of them resent
her for the same reason.
During middle school, I was dating
ping pong team captain Cho-kun...
baseball team captain Fuji-kun...
During middle school, I was dating...
The basketball team captain,
who she stole from you?
During middle school, I was dating
judo team captain Ban-kun...
Furthermore, Yuko-san said the exact same
thing after the old man's interruption.
But why did those three—
No, including Toyoko-san,
it's the four of them.
Hey, kid.
Huh?
What are you scowling and thinking about?
It's simple.
Those three women conspired to
put a cabbage core in the monja
to get their revenge.
But then...
I know.
We're dealing with women who
don't have long left to live.
I give them a proper talking to,
make them reflect on their actions,
and throw a proper sushi party with my pay.
Toyoko's Restaurant
What?!
So it was Eiko, Kyoko, and
Yuko who tried to kill me
by putting the cabbage core in my monja?!
The great Mori Kogoro doesn't make mistakes!
What happened to being proper?
By the way, detective Mori-sensei.
Yes?
I know I should go to the local police,
but they're so unreliable.
Could you ask your friends
at the MPD to handle it?
What? But...
My chronic pain...
A-Are you all right?
Please. My days are numbered...
Your days are numbered?
Very well. I'll talk to them.
Thank you!
I'll bring you another beer.
Don't worry about it.
He's too easy.
They're not answering...
Anyway, why is she doing this?
Huh?
Isn't that...?
I see!
So that's how it is.
Toyoko's Restaurant
Here's your beer.
Toyoko-san.
Yes?
Picking up where we left off,
when cooking monja,
you use two spatulas to finely chop
ingredients spread over a hot plate.
In other words, even if a cabbage core
were mixed in with the ingredients,
it should've been chopped too small to get
caught in your throat by the time you ate it.
Therefore, the cabbage core you choked on
must have been put in after you
finished preparing the monja.
Not only that, but if the core was
carelessly thrown into the ingredients,
the boy or I could've eaten it.
There would be no guarantee
you would choke on it.
The only certain way to choke
you would be to put it in
just before you served yourself.
However, this presents a fundamental problem.
Would you not notice a cabbage core
falling into the bit of
monja you were about to eat?
In other words, the four
of you worked together
to cause a commotion by
involving me and the police.
It was all a lie.
She's not even here.
Does that mean she didn't
listen to any of my reasoning?
I knew they'd be here.
If the great detective Mori Kogoro and the
MPD get involved in the investigation...
It'll be a huge story!
The media will swoop in!
Then everyone will be talking
about the Tokyo Barls Collection!
But won't we be arrested?
We'll cross that bridge when we get there.
Should we make a public apology then?
Then even more people
will be talking about us.
The Barls Collection is
guaranteed to be a success!
Maybe we'll be invited to appear on TV.
And interviewed by handsome men.
That would really get people talking.
The Barls Collection is
guaranteed to be a success!
Well, whatever.
Toyoko's Restaurant
Hello, Inspector?
I'm sorry, but there's something
I'd like to discuss with you.
Uh, oh. He got a hold of Inspector Megure.
Toyoko's Restaurant
We just wanted to cheer
up all the elderly people
around the country who are our age.
We're terribly sorry for the
inconvenience our carelessness caused.
We're sorry.
#tokyobarlscollection
Likes
No one stands a chance against
the Bufu'usu of Tsukishima.
Hey, kid. What are you doing? Let's go.
Okay.
What's wrong with those women?
But it ended well, right?
It'll cheer up some old women.
And besides, didn't you get paid?
Paid? There were just free
monja coupons in that envelope.
Oh, really?
The Tokyo Barls Collection is
guaranteed to be a success!
Episode Preview
Smile, Kagura. Look happy.
I'll earn more likes for you.
Kagura suffered collateral
damage about half a month ago.
What?
This can't be a coincidence.
Conan-kun, could it be?
I'll expose everything!
The Cost of Likes
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Cost of Likes, Part One!"
SNS
#summervacationstartstoday!
Next Conan's hint.
Social networking service!
We'd be the Moe of Beika!
Don's miss the next episode.
I doubt anyone would hire the Moe Detectives.