[Eyecatch]
Detective Conan Episode 944 "The
Cost of Likes (Part One)"
Beika Central Hospital
You're lucky it was just a scratch.
We were worried, you know.
We heard you were taken to the hospital.
Sorry, sorry.
That Kagura guy protected me.
It was unfortunate for the both of us.
But because of me, your arm...
It's not your fault.
Don't worry about it.
Kagura Sumito (26)
Besides, I might be able to use this.
Use this?
So, did they catch the culprit?
No, not yet.
Darn. Who would do something like that?
Either way, they sure did
cause a lot of trouble.
All the patients here were
collateral damage, right?
Yeah.
That Otsubo-san guy lives in Aobadai.
That's pretty far away, right?
Otsubo Kikuhide (33)
I happened to come to Beika City,
and look what happened to me.
I'm so unlucky.
How truly unfortunate for you.
Hey, Kagura.
Are you okay?
Kochiyama, Haruka. You guys came.
Who called us to come visit him?
Kochiyama Ko (26)
Ibe Haruka (24)
Right, Haruka-chan?
Yeah. You sounded like you were about to cry.
I broke my arm. Look.
You're really unlucky.
But I'm going to be compensated again.
Again? In that case...
Smile, Kagura. Look happy.
I'll earn more likes for you.
There you go again.
You guys are hopeless,
Kagura-san and Kochiyama-san.
What's wrong with these people?
He suffered an injury.
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
Injured as part of collateral damage
for a hilariously strange reason!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Cost of Likes
(Part One)
"The Cost of Likes, Part One!"
Yotsubishi Bank
It started with a phone
call made to this bank.
Hello, this is the Yotsubishi
Bank Beika branch.
Several bombs have been
placed around your bank.
They'll all explode in one minute.
What?!
Evacuate the building!
Shocked by the threat, the bank told all
customers and employees to evacuate.
However, the panicked customers caused
collateral damage to the people
who happened to be passing
by in front of the bank.
Pushed to the ground by the
people rushing out of the bank,
Genta and several others were
injured and taken to the hospital.
The phone used to place the call was
determined to be a public phone near the bank.
Because there was no explosion and
not a single explosive was found,
it was thought to be a prank.
Though the bank promised to
cover their medical expenses
and compensate the victims,
it was an unfortunate incident for
everyone involved nonetheless.
However...
You three seem unusually happy.
What?
But I mean... Right?
Yeah.
Kagura suffered collateral
damage about half a month ago.
What?
I was out hiking alone.
I suffered collateral damage
from an unexploded bomb.
Really?
I remember that.
So you were the victim who
suffered collateral damage.
Unlucky, right?
But because of all the money he received
from the construction company,
he was able to pay off all his debts at once.
The nerve of this guy.
Really?
Kochiyama's pretty cheeky, too.
The next day, he took me back
to the construction site.
Is here good?
Nah, go farther back.
Okay.
Smile more. Look happy!
He used me to get likes.
This is it.
"Unexploded Bomb Explodes!!"
"My friend was injured when he suffered
collateral damage from an unexploded bomb."
"He's an unlucky man."
"But look at him smiling after
he received compensation."
"Shameless, right?"
Indeed.
They say a wise man profits by his mistakes.
So this Tanuki Ponkichi name...
Tanuki Ponkichi
That's me.
Sorry.
So since something similar happened today,
Kagura-san will be compensated,
and Kochiyama-san plans to
get more likes out of him.
That's why you seem happy.
What a despicable pair.
It's a good thing you were injured
when you don't have any performances.
Performances?
He's an actor in some acting company.
As a token of friendship...
Chonenten
We're the Chonenten Acting Company.
Chonenten Acting Company?
Come to think of it, isn't there a café
with this name behind the station?
The chairman of our company runs that place.
I see.
There are photos of Kagura-san and you.
Huh? Kochiyama-san isn't on there.
Kochiyama is unrelated to the
company. He's an old friend.
But whenever we get together,
we have a fun time.
They're three best friends.
Sounds like it.
Anyway, whoever called the bank...
I'm sure they only meant to prank them,
but they injured people totally
unconnected to the bank.
They must be feeling really bad
about the stupid thing they did.
They'd better.
Right?
Yeah.
Let's have a drink tonight
to cleanse you of this evil.
You'll be at your apartment, right?
Yeah.
I can't work like this.
Nurse's Station
Excuse me. Could you give me the address
of the Otsubo-san staying in that room?
What?
Kojima Genta who's also in that
room is very grateful to him,
and wanted to surprise him
with a thank you letter.
One moment.
Let's see...
Here it is.
This is a one-time thing.
Otsubo Kikuhide-san...
"How can this be a coincidence?!"
You already uploaded the photo.
Good deeds should be done quickly.
Good?
Huh? You're leaving already?
Yeah. Everyone's been cleared to leave.
Genta-kun should be coming soon, too.
Do you guys know the Otsubo-san
who was staying in your room?
Huh? No.
We don't know him. Why?
No reason. I just thought you might.
Bye!
Uh, yeah.
Bye.
Where have you been, Conan-kun?
Sorry, sorry. I had to go to the bathroom.
Let's get started.
What? Started on what?
On finding the culprit, of course.
Genta-kun was injured.
We can't just ignore it.
Not just me.
That Kagura guy and all the
others suffered a horrible fate.
We've gotta catch the culprit.
Let's start by asking the police
if they've found anything.
Yeah!
Look at them. They're so excited.
What will you do?
Looks like they don't have any clues yet.
They're just starting to think
about how to determine the culprit.
Hey, isn't that...
"How can this be a coincidence?!"
Tanuki Ponkichi. That's
Kochiyama-san's new post.
"The man I introduced as my unlucky
but shameless friend half a month ago
suffered more collateral damage!"
"Unbelievable, right?"
Two incidents in half a month?
Kagura-san really is unlucky.
Yeah.
Unbelievable, huh? It really is.
What?
Could it be?
I'm not trying to sound like Kochiyama-san,
but this can't be a coincidence.
What?
Conan-kun, could it be?
The collateral damage from the bomb a
half-month ago probably was a coincidence.
But it's possible he got a taste
for the money he received then,
and tried to get some more.
Several bombs have been
placed around your bank.
He called the bank and caused a panic,
making it look like he
suffered collateral damage.
It's not impossible.
He doesn't have any performances
right now, right?
He was waiting for a time he
could afford to be injured?
So the culprit is Kagura-san?
Then Kochiyama-san and Haruka-oneesan...
He fooled us, too.
That is what it means.
But they're three best friends.
Let's investigate Kagura-san.
Let's ask around.
We could also follow him.
We might discover something.
Do it. I'm going to look into Otsubo-san.
Is he involved, too?
No, but there's something
about him that's bothering me.
Got it. Let's split up.
Yeah!
Izakaya Sasai
Sorry, boss.
As you can see, I won't be
able to work for a while.
Sorry.
It's fine. Anyway, you really are unlucky.
I know. I have no idea why I'm so unlucky.
Anyway, I'll call you later.
Sure. Take care.
Long time, no see.
Look. Something crazy happened to me again.
Oh, I saw the news. That must've been rough.
It's like he's telling everyone.
"I'm simply a victim
of collateral damage."
That could be his strategy to convince
everyone that's what happened.
Chonenten
What? Our Kagura?
Yes.
As the company chairman, what kind
of person do you think he is?
Dewa Chiichiro (30)
What kind of person is he?
He's a good-natured guy, right?
Yeah.
Right.
Are these guys in the company, too?
This is where we hang out.
Half a month ago, Kagura-san suffered
collateral damage from an unexploded bomb.
Do you know anything about that?
He didn't learn his lesson.
Afterwards he was saying, "Maybe I'll
suffer some more tasty collateral damage."
He did say that.
Like he was hoping he'd
receive more money, right?
Even though that never happens.
I know.
This sounds like what Conan said.
Yes.
He did it for the money.
Otsubo
Oh, Otsubo-kun? We're pretty close.
We're neighbors and have a lot of free time.
I am a poet
His life's purpose is finding
unusual and interesting things
to upload to social media for likes.
But he apparently has a
tough rival on social media.
Yasukawa Shiro (35)
A rival?
"Unexploded Bomb Explodes!!"
He got a bunch of likes again.
Who is this Tanuki Ponkichi who
keeps making interesting posts?
That's what he told me.
Really?
That's why he reacted like that upon learning
Kochiyama-san is Tanuki Ponkichi, his rival.
But Otsubo-kun said he wouldn't be beat.
I think it was two days ago...
I thought of a good idea.
I'm going to find this
unlucky man and follow him.
He's sure to suffer some misfortune again,
so I'll post about it first.
Stupid, right?
Otsubo-san came to Beika City and suffered
collateral damage not by coincidence,
but because he was following Kagura-san.
Which means... Could it be?
Apparently Kagura-san said he hoped to suffer
some more "tasty" collateral damage.
Since he couldn't just wait
around for it to happen,
he made the bomb threat and caused a panic.
Is Kagura-san really such a bad person?
What?
While following him,
he seemed like a very cheerful
and sociable person.
Even though he'd just been injured,
he never stopped smiling.
The people he was talking
to were smiling, too.
That's because he's going to be compensated.
But he didn't seem like a bad person
who would trick his friends.
But he's an actor.
It's possible it was all an act.
You think so?
He told his actor friends that he
hoped to suffer more collateral damage
so he'd receive more money.
That could be his true nature.
Then it's decided. The culprit is Kagura-san.
But the implausibility of the coincidence
isn't a strong enough basis for anything.
We need evidence.
That's where Otsubo Kikuhide-san comes in.
If he was following Kagura-san,
then it's possible he saw
Kagura-san make the call.
I was waiting to confirm that,
but Otsubo-san hasn't come home.
We'll do all of it tomorrow.
Yeah.
We'll check in with Otsubo-san and do
whatever it takes to find conclusive evidence.
Yeah!
I see.
So that's what happened.
I'll expose everything!
All right! Let's resume the investigation!
I'm going to check with Otsubo-san.
Then I'll—
Did something happen?
Otsubo-san?
No way!
Why him?
Kids, don't enter the crime scene.
Do you know him?
Yeah. Was he murdered?
Y-Yeah.
We don't know the details yet, but
he was probably struck with a rock.
We think it happened around eight last night.
Wait a minute...
You kids knew the victim?
You know the bomb threat made to
that bank yesterday afternoon?
Yes, though it turned out to be nonsense.
But because it was a Friday at the end
of the month, it caused a huge panic.
Genta-kun got caught up in it.
Otsubo-san was another one of the victims.
What?
And the night of the incident,
victim Otsubo-san was murdered.
Inspector.
We'll have to investigate to see
if yesterday's bomb scare
and this case are related.
Yes, sir!
Like Inspector Megure said, I wonder if
this is related to yesterday's incident.
Let's do whatever it takes to
find our culprit ourselves, too.
Yeah.
Let's do it.
It's possible Edogawa-kun
is right and Otsubo-san
learned a grave secret about yesterday's
incident and was killed for it.
What?
Wouldn't that mean Otsubo-san
was killed by Kagura-san?
Huh?
What?
Otsubo-san must've seen him yesterday
while following Kagura-san
for social media fodder.
He saw Kagura-san calling the bank.
At the time, he probably didn't
know he was making a bomb threat.
After leaving the hospital,
Otsubo-san followed unlucky man
Kagura-san for social media fodder.
Something made him realize Kagura-san
caused the bomb scare and questioned him.
So that's what happened.
I'll expose everything!
Knowing that would only end poorly for him,
Kagura-san acted to silence him!
It's not impossible. It makes sense.
Right?
It makes sense, but...
There's something...
Let's tell Inspector Megure our reasoning.
Even if he killed him to silence him,
that reasoning assumes Kagura-san
made the bomb threat.
Oh, right.
Since we don't have any proof of that,
the reasoning for Otsubo-san's
murder is just speculation.
You guys keep talking about evidence,
but even without it, I'll put the
screws on him until he confesses!
Genta-kun!
Hey!
What should we do, Conan-kun?
That might work.
What?
We won't give him a hard time,
but we might be able to pick something
up by going directly to Kagura-san.
He might reveal something about himself.
Yeah. Let's go talk to Kagura-san.
Episode Preview
Otsubo-san did?
So you heard, apparently...
It's all starting to sound suspicious.
Conan-kun?!
A love triangle?
I don't understand!
I thought Kagura was just
drinking a beer, but then—
The Cost of Likes
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is
"The Cost of Likes, Part Two!"
Phone
Next Conan's hint!
A phone!
These adults.
Don't miss the next episode.
Like.
No, wait.
Dislike.
I like that.