Yotsubishi Bank
A fake bomb threat made
to a bank caused a panic.
Genta, Kagura Sumito-san, and others
were injured as collateral damage.
According to his friends Kochiyama
Go-san and Ibe Haruka-san,
Kagura-san also suffered collateral
damage half a month earlier.
It's hard to believe two incidents
in half a month is a coincidence.
After getting a taste for the compensation
he received after the first incident,
perhaps he caused the panic himself
in order to receive more money.
We suspected Kagura-san and even
discovered testimony backing it up.
But just as we were setting out
to find conclusive evidence...
Otsubo Kikuhide-san, another one
of the victims, was murdered.
It's possible Edogawa-kun is right
and Otsubo-san learned a grave secret
about yesterday's incident
and was killed for it.
What?
Wouldn't that mean Otsubo-san
was killed by Kagura-san?
Huh?
What?
It makes sense, but...
There's something...
You guys keep talking about evidence,
but even without it, I'll put the
screws on him until he confesses!
Genta-kun!
Hey!
What should we do, Conan-kun?
That might work.
What?
We won't give him a hard time,
but we might be able to pick something
up by going directly to Kagura-san.
He might reveal something about himself.
Yeah.
Let's go talk to Kagura-san.
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
Adults with impure motives!
What are their unseen true intentions?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Cost of Likes
(Part Two)
"The Cost of Likes, Part Two!"
You're already here? On the
phone you said this afternoon.
Kagura Sumito (26)
Oh, it's you kids.
We need to talk.
What?
I don't know what it's about,
but we can talk on the way.
My payday was yesterday,
but I never withdrew the money
because of the commotion.
What? Murdered?
Otsubo-san was?
You already know all about that, don't you?
Why would I?
By the way, Kagura-san, didn't you
previously tell your acting company
that you hoped to suffer collateral damage
again so you'd receive more money?
Who said that?
You did!
I've never said anything that audacious.
Hey!
Wait...
That felt a little strange.
He doesn't seem to be lying.
Don't let him fool you!
He's an actor!
You're sure he said "another
tasty dream," right?
You're doubting us?
And our detective skills?
Chonenten
Kagura-san clearly said it, right?
Dewa Chiichiro (30)
Yeah. That's what I heard.
You heard?
You didn't hear it directly from Kagura-san?
Oh, not directly.
I heard it from him.
Didn't Kagura say he hoped to suffer more
collateral damage so he'd get paid again?
Yeah, apparently.
Apparently?
So you heard, apparently.
It's all starting to sound suspicious.
Then who told you?
Kochiyama. Not that you'd know him.
That Kochiyama?
Hey.
We saw her yesterday, too!
She's a witness!
Didn't you say yesterday that Kagura-san
hoped to suffer more collateral damage?
That's what I heard from Kochiyama-kun.
Wait...
Her, too?
It sounds like Kochiyama is
the source of everything.
Isn't Kochiyama-san Kagura-san's friend?
Do you guys know him, too?
We acted together in college.
He started working after graduation,
but we still hang out.
He even comes here sometimes.
So he's a former actor, too.
Oh, right. That might've been a lie.
A lie?
Kochiyama might've spread
the rumor on purpose.
If Haruka thought Kagura
were good for nothing,
she might go to him instead.
It's possible.
Yeah.
I wouldn't put it past him.
What does that mean?
Isn't that the lady who
was with them yesterday?
So they're not just three
best friends after all.
In any case,
we'll know if Kagura-san actually said
that or not if we ask Kochiyama-san.
Yes, but even if he did,
that's not conclusive.
What we need is conclusive evidence.
What would that be?
Are there any clues?
I knew it.
What?
"How can this be a coincidence?!"
Isn't that Kochiyama-san's post?
And the murdered Otsubo-san
was following Kagura-san.
If he was following him, then...
Could it be?
What is it?
But then why would he...?
Conan-kun?!
Where can we find her?
Ibe Haruka
This woman.
Kochiyama Ko (26)
A love triangle?
Between Kagura-san, Kochiyama-san, and me?
Ibe Haruka (24)
No, no way. Absolutely not.
But the acting company mentioned
something about one.
I was originally a fan
of Kagura-san the actor.
I joined the company a year ago
because I wanted to act with him.
Kagura-san introduced me to
Kochiyama-san shortly after that.
This is Kochiyama.
I've been stuck with this
idiot since college.
I-I'm the idiot.
What are you doing?
I'm Ibe Haruka.
We became close right away.
Here it comes, Kagura!
Bring it on!
Kagura-san and Kochiyama-san
were so close. I was jealous.
He's a tough one! Back me up, Haruka!
Got it!
Two on one? That's not fair!
I was so happy that they
allowed me to join them.
There's nothing romantic
about our relationship.
Oh, sorry. I'd better head back.
Later.
Even if she's not aware of it... Right?
Well, we can guess how they feel about her.
What about it, though?
What did we come to confirm?
What's behind the bomb threat
and Otsubo-san's case.
What?!
If you think of that way,
it explains everything.
And if I'm right, then...
Thank you.
We investigated the connection between the
bomb threat and Otsubo Kikuhide-san's murder,
but we haven't found anything yet.
You've found clues to the identity
of the culprit who made
the bomb threat, right?
No, not at all.
You haven't?
We heard a cleaning person was spotted
at the phone booth in question just before
and after the call was made to the bank.
According to the cleaning company,
no one was working around then,
so that must have been the culprit.
But we don't have any
clues to their identity.
Sounds like your reasoning was wrong.
Yeah.
Yup.
If they didn't leave any clues,
then the plan doesn't work.
What plan?
Inspector.
Yes.
What? I see.
We received an anonymous call.
Last night around eight,
someone was seen fleeing the
scene of Otsubo's murder.
Around the time of the murder?
Yeah.
Apparently the caller asked if the
suspicious figure might've been
the "unlucky man" who's
been seen online recently,
but we have no idea who they meant.
They must mean Kagura-san.
I knew it was him.
So that's how it is.
Their plan's not over yet.
But if their ultimate goal
lies beyond what I thought...
Could it be?
Yeah.
That explains why there weren't any
clues left in the telephone booth.
What?
What do you mean?
Which means we'd better hurry!
Come with me!
Hurry!
Us, too!
Let's go!
Yeah!
To bad luck and audacity.
And the nerve to use me for likes again.
Wait!
Police. We're coming in.
You kids?
The police?
I don't think you should be
drinking while you're injured.
Or...
Would you care to drink like this
instead, Kagura-san and Kochiyama-san?
What?
It wasn't a coincidence that Kagura-san
suffered collateral damage yesterday.
He was set up by the culprit.
Isn't that right,
Kochiyama-san?
What do you mean?
Yesterday, the 25th, was your payday.
You were sure to go to that
bank to withdraw the money.
And since you're friends, naturally
Kochiyama-san knew that.
He disguised himself as a cleaning
person and waited for you to arrive.
Just when you arrived in front of the bank...
Several bombs have been
placed around your bank.
Why would Kochiyama do that?
Kagura-san, half a month ago, you
received monetary compensation
when you were injured by
an unexploded bomb, right?
You got a taste for that money,
so you caused the panic yourself
and pretended to be a victim
in order to receive more money.
That's what he wanted people to think.
What?
I didn't do anything like that.
You even dropped hints in
advance to his friends.
I heard Kagura say
that he hoped to suffer more
tasty collateral damage
so he could receive more compensation.
To everyone.
I never said that.
He put another plan in motion yesterday.
He didn't make this post to earn "likes,"
"How can this be a coincidence?!"
but rather to frame you as the culprit.
Why?
Kochiyama-san's comment posted under
the handle Tanuki Ponkichi emphasizes
"How can this be a coincidence?!"
that it's hard to imagine
it was a coincidence
that you experienced two similar
incidents in half a month.
That's what made us suspect
Kagura-san did it for the money.
We totally fell for it.
Just like he wanted.
Not that! I'm asking why Kochiyama
would try to frame me!
But if he just wanted to frame you,
then he would've left clues pointing to you.
But there weren't any.
None at all.
Why?
Because leaving evidence would cause
the police to arrest Kagura-san,
preventing him from reaching
his ultimate goal, right?
What?
And you meant to try for that
goal last night, didn't you?
Let's have a drink tonight
to cleanse you of this evil.
You'll be at your apartment, right?
But it didn't go as planned when
Otsubo Kikuhide-san arrived.
Otsubo-san?
Yeah.
His life's purpose was earning
"likes" on interesting posts.
He was secretly following you for potential
material since you're so unlucky.
Me?
Otsubo-san also viewed Tanuki Ponkichi-san
as his rival because he kept
making interesting posts.
When that man appeared before him,
Otsubo-san decided to follow
Kochiyama-san instead.
He hoped to stumble upon
interesting material if he did.
But something made Otsubo-san realize that
you were the one who made the bomb threat.
No, I—
So you silenced him.
Shocked by the murder, you canceled
your plans for last night.
Today you anonymously called the police
so you could reach your ultimate goal.
It might've been the "unlucky man"
who's been seen online recently.
You were vague so the police
wouldn't arrive immediately.
In other words, this was
the story you came up with.
I successfully caused a commotion for money,
but Otsubo realized what I'd done,
so I killed him.
It's only a matter of time before I'm caught.
You planned to tell the police that's what he
said, and when they responded to your call...
I don't understand!
I thought Kagura was just drinking a beer,
but then he suddenly started choking...
You planned to act as though he killed
himself out of desperation, didn't you?
You were going to kill me and
make it look like a suicide?
Why?!
Probably...
Because of Ibe Haruka-san.
She has nothing to do with this!
Based on your reaction,
it sounds like he's right.
Haruka? What about her?
Haruka-san told us
the three of you are very close,
but there's nothing romantic
about your relationship.
That's exactly how it is!
But maybe it was different for Kochiyama-san.
You have feelings for Haruka?
While having fun together,
Kochiyama-san secretly desired
to make Haruka-san his own
and for you to disappear.
But the police would investigate
if he simply murdered you,
so he thought to make it look like suicide.
You needed a motive for that.
That's when you suffered collateral
damage from the unexploded bomb
and he came up with this plan.
"Unexploded Bomb Explodes!!"
Having gotten a taste for
the monetary compensation,
this time you called a bomb threat
into a bank and caused a panic,
but things got out of control,
so you took your own life.
He wanted that to be your motive for suicide.
In other words, his plan was already
in motion when he took this picture.
Half a month ago...
Otsubo-san probably didn't
know about the plan,
but he wanted to frame you for it, too.
He went as far as to kill a person to
strengthen your motive for suicide.
But everything I've said is speculation.
There's no evidence.
If we find poison in the glass
Kagura-san was meant to drink from,
the police will begin their investigation
into this attempted murder.
Then everything will become clear.
The boy's right.
You admit to killing Otsubo Kikuhide-san?
Apparently he saw me.
He saw a cleaning person making a phone call.
He didn't think anything
of it at the time, though.
Hey.
Aren't those clothes...?
Are you the one who made that call?
I didn't think anyone was following me!
You caused the commotion
so you could post about it.
So Tanuki Ponkichi has been using
underhanded techniques to earn "likes."
He was confused about why I called, but...
I'll expose everything!
If he did that, the plan I'd
spent half a month on...
So before he could...
I had to kill him!
Kochiyama-san?
Why are the police arresting you?
That idiot.
But they were three best friends.
It just means adults are complicated.
What is it, Genta-kun? You look so serious.
I wonder how much compensation I'll receive.
What?
At least enough to buy a hundred
broiled eels over rice, right?
The simple-minded are terrifying.
Was he better off not knowing?
Genta-kun, you're the worst!
You're the worst!
Huh? Hey, wait! I'll share with you guys!
That's not what we're talking about!
Don't follow us!
I'll throw in some eel liver soup, too!
What's that?
Gross!
Episode Preview
I killed them.
Why were you suspected of
running off with the ring?
It's all right.
None of the staff believed you took the ring.
What?
A fire? Could it be?
The Cursed Tears of Borgia
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Cursed Tears of Borgia, Part One!"
Next Conan's hint!
TV Film Shoot
Boi-oing...
A TV film shoot!
Next week there's no Conan!
Don't miss the next episode.
But Kuraki Mai-san...
...will sing a medley!
Maybe I'll sing, too.