Hey, Mizusawa.
Well, Umeki-san? Did you get
in touch with the police?
Umeki Hiromichi (45)
Kanoya Construction Company President
Sorry. My signal's weak,
so I couldn't reach them.
Mizusawa Sho (25)
Nonogaki Real Estate Employee
Could you try yours?
Got it.
Be careful. It's slippery.
Aye-aye, sir.
The worst drought in 50 years, huh.
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
A skeleton is discovered
at the bottom of a dam!
A drama spanning time and space begins!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Cursed Tears of Borgia (Part One)
"The Cursed Tears of Borgia, Part One!"
Do you remember the case of
the Cursed Tears of Borgia?
Forty years ago, while Beika
City-based Yamato TV was
Old Yamato TV
(Approx. 1975)
filming a show to commemorate
their fifth anniversary,
the leading lady went missing
while wearing a prop ring set
with the jewel known as the Tears of Borgia.
Suspect is Asahina Nagisa's assistant Saeki Yuri (30)?!
"Ran Off With
the Tears of Borgia?!"
Shock Leaves
Asahina Nagisa
Bedridden
However, suspect Saeki Yuri-san has
been discovered after 40 years
as a skeleton at the
bottom of a dried up dam.
"I Killed Them."
What?
It was the title of the
drama they were filming
Saeki Sumire (20)
Saeki Yuri's Granddaughter
when my grandmother allegedly ran off
with the ring that was discovered.
I see...
At the time, my grandmother
was living here in Beika City,
but after the case, the family fled
under cover of night because of the
abuse they suffered from the media.
But the ring wasn't in the car
my grandmother was found in!
On top of that, she...
Died after being stabbed in the
stomach with a fruit knife.
What? Really?
They didn't mention that on the news.
Yeah.
Mizusawa, the man who found the
body, is one of my drinking buddies.
My grandmother is a victim!
Someone must've stolen the
ring from her and killed her!
Of course, it's a 40-year-old case.
I know it will be difficult.
But if you could at least
clear my grandmother's name...
Very well.
Mori Detective Agency
Yes.
Yes. I thought so.
I understand.
Thank you, Inspector.
Goodbye.
What did the police say?
Like you said, it's a 40-year-old case.
Not only that, but during
that time, it was underwater.
There's very little evidence.
As it stands, they're unable
to conclude that your
grandmother Saeki Yuri-san was murdered.
B-But the knife...
That knife undoubtedly took
Saeki Yuri-san's life.
But it's possible that, for example,
she regretted running off with
the ring and committed suicide.
No...
It's a damn shame.
I'm sorry we couldn't help, Sumire-san.
It's okay. I understand what Mori-san said.
But when I think of how disappointed
my mother will be...
Hey, Sumire-san.
Why was your grandmother suspected
of running off with the ring?
Hey, Conan-kun.
It was my grandmother's job to
transport the ring from the
Yamato TV studio in Beika City to
the dam where they were filming.
She went missing after she left the studio.
Yamato TV was inside the aerial lighthouse
building that's being
demolished right now, right?
Why don't we head there now?
Safety First
Beika Tower Building
Redevelopment Construction
There's no trace of it left.
Yeah.
My mother would be sad if she found out.
Excuse me.
Yuri-chan!
What?
Excuse me. You looked
like an old acquaintance.
By Yuri-chan, did you mean Saeki Yuri?
What?
Saeki Yuri was my grandmother.
Kanoya Tatsuma (72)
Kanoya Construction Advisor
What a coincidence.
I can't believe we ran into an
acquaintance of your grandmother.
I know.
Yuri-chan's—rather,
your grandmother's body was
discovered by my nephew Umeki.
I thought it might be fate,
so I came to see the Yamato
TV building being demolished.
How did you know my grandmother?
I actually used to work for Yamato TV.
So that's how.
Yuri-chan was a great assistant.
Hey.
Do you remember the drama
"I Killed Them"?
Hey, Conan-kun.
But doesn't Sumire-san want to know
if her grandmother was innocent?
Yeah, but...
It's all right. None of the staff
believed that Yuri-chan took the ring.
What?
I was part of the main staff.
I know it was so.
What? It was broadcast live?
How can a drama be broadcast live?
At the time, small stations like Yamato TV
didn't know much about video recording.
So they turned that lack
of knowledge on its head
by calling "Killed 'Em" a "five
year anniversary special live drama."
"Killed 'Em?"
That must be short for "I Killed Them."
You figured it out.
This industry has a habit
of abbreviating everything.
Yamato TV
This is how we shot it.
I was the one behind the camera.
Everyone's so young.
That's her! That's my grandmother!
She looks just like you.
Yuri-chan and Asahina
Nagisa-chan were like sisters.
How long did the actress Asahina
Nagisa-san appear on TV?
She disappeared right after "Killed 'Em."
She only debuted because she
was a sponsor's daughter.
Nagisa-chan wasn't a bad girl,
but she had terrible stage fright.
I Killed Them
I... I...
I killed them. I killed them.
Asahina Nagisa (22)
Actress
Here, Nagisa-chan.
Saeki Yuri (30)
Nagisa's Assistant
What about apples?
She always had her peel
them to help her calm down.
Short strokes meant she was still anxious.
Long strokes meant she'd
managed to calm down.
My grandmother was a good assistant.
But on that day, she traveled
separately from Nagisa-chan
because she had to transport the ring.
How did that happen?
Because there were rumors the
Asahina family had purchased
counterfeit Tears of Borgia.
The Asahina family requested that Western
history Professor Senju proclaim it
was genuine before the drama.
The jewel had to be left at the studio
to accommodate the professor's schedule.
Yuri-chan would bring it to the filming
location once he gave his testimony.
They could've rescheduled filming.
They can't do that, Ran-neechan.
That's right, because it was broadcast live.
I was at the filming location as a cameraman.
Yamato TV
Nagisa-chan was the only actress there.
As long as the Tears of Borgia arrived by
20:20, it would be in time for the broadcast.
It must've been an important prop.
It was. It needed to arrive in time
for its close-up during the climax.
Yamato TV
Kanoya Tatsuma (32)
Cameraman
Switching from studio to filming
location in three, two, one.
We did it with one camera.
It was a chance to show off my skills,
until she started slowly peeling apples.
She peeled apples in the drama?
Yeah. It was Yuri-chan's
idea to help her calm down.
Being an assistant sounds like hard work.
Some actors even had her make cheat sheets.
For their lines? Why would they...
Oh, because it was live.
We didn't have time to rehearse, so
memorizing lines was quite the job.
But ultimately, the ring
never arrived, right?
Just in case, we brought
the prop ring with us.
It was a cheap one, though.
Oh, right.
But my grandmother went missing ever since...
We were so distracted by the
commotion after filming
that we put off worrying about Yuri-chan.
I'm sorry.
Did something happen?
Nagisa-chan collapsed right when we finished.
What? Why?
She actually had a 40 degree Celsius fever.
What? She filmed in that condition?
You can't cancel a live
broadcast for an illness.
She knew that when she was cast.
It wasn't uncommon back then.
Does Nagisa-san still live in Beika City?
In a nursing facility.
It's called "Grand Light."
I'm sorry.
Asahina-san is out right now.
We haven't been told when she'll be back.
Excuse me.
Yes, front desk.
What? You got separated?
Someone's here to see her right now.
I'm sorry.
Asahina
You looked away for a minute,
and she disappeared?
You've already told her doctor, right? I see.
She sometimes becomes panicked
because of an old trauma.
You have to be careful.
She mixes up her memories
of the present and the past.
In any case, I'm glad they found her.
Room 312
Asahina
Asahina Nagisa (62)
Former Actress
Ran-neechan!
Conan-kun's over there.
He's on the third floor.
Say, "ah."
Ah.
Let's peel some more.
Asahina-san, you have guests.
Two young ladies.
Yuri-chan...
Yuri-chan, I'm sorry! Forgive me!
Forgive me!
Um, I...
No!
She was supposed to be
friends with my grandmother.
Why did she scream like that?
Something happened between the
two of them that traumatized her.
That's probably what
Shinichi-niichan would say.
If only he were here.
He might know where the Tears of Borgia went.
Sumire-san, do you know what
"I Killed Them" was about?
Yes. There was once an old family that kept
the historically significant Tears of Borgia.
Back then, there was a notorious
thief known as "Red Hood."
Red Hood declared that he would
steal the Tears of Borgia.
The police were powerless against him,
The Tears of Borgia will be mine
Red Hood
and no one knew what he looked
like beneath his hood.
That's the story.
What happens to the Tears of Borgia?
A maid comes up with an idea.
She was played by Asahina Nagisa-san.
He'll find it if it's hidden, so
it should be kept in plain sight.
A fake jewel is locked
inside the mansion's safe,
while the real one is kept
on the maid's finger.
But Red Hood's true identity is
actually her boyfriend, the butler.
A common story.
While the thief waits for
an opportunity to strike,
the maid is sent to some distant
mountains by the master.
Excuse me.
Thank you for waiting.
About your meeting with Asahina-san...
Yes?
I'm sorry, but Asahina-san isn't doing well.
Could you come back another day?
They're worried her symptoms might get worse.
When you put it that way,
we don't have a choice.
Hey, you!
Yes, you!
You're Saeki Yuri-san!
Yuri was my grandmother.
What a coincidence.
I'm first-rate Western
history professor Senju.
You can't say that yourself.
Huh? Senju?
Wasn't he on TV?
You're right. He must know
about your grandmother.
You were exactly my type.
Senju Hideo (88)
Western History Scholar
I'm delighted to see you again, Yuri-san.
That's my grandmother.
You were the only saving grace of
that incredibly unpleasant program.
You truly were my ideal woman.
That wasn't me.
Don't be shy, Yuri-san.
Shall we get going, Sumire-san?
Indeed, how rude! Don't you agree, boy?
What?
Don't you remember, Yuri-san?
What did Yamato TV say about that program?
I don't know.
That's right! I told you
because you didn't know!
The Tears of Borgia was fake!
It never actually existed!
But Yamato TV didn't care about the truth.
They asked me to say it was real.
A sponsor's request?
What do they think history is?
What did you say on the broadcast?
That I'd overlook it since it was a legend,
but that the owners embarrass themselves
if they insisted it was real.
Really?
The TV station was displeased no matter
how much I denied its existence.
You're the only one who
listened to me, Yuri-kun.
That's why I fell in love with you.
What?
Nonogaki Real Estate
I'm here on time.
Mizusawa-kun, hey!
Whoa! Shut up, you idiot!
Mizusawa-kun! Hey, Mizusawa!
Didn't you want to talk to me?
Open up. Hey!
It's open.
Hey, Mizusawa-kun.
Didn't you say something
about the whatever of Borgia?
Mizusawa.
Something's burning.
Oh. Whoa!
It's Mizusawa's phone.
A fire? Could it be?
Mizusawa!
Hot, hot, hot!
I warned the Asahina family that employed
you not to embarrass themselves.
Don't put this counterfeit on TV.
You looked at me with your
cute round eyes and nodded.
My heart was pounding.
Excuse me, professor.
Boorish machine.
What? Inspector Megure?
Hello? Yes.
What? My father's caught in a fire?
How is he?
Is he all right?
Episode Preview
So where are we headed?
The dam.
There's something I want to
check at the filming location.
I don't see anything.
Not right now.
Huh?
I knew it.
Knew what? H-Hey, Shinichi!
"The Cursed Tears of Borgia (Part Two)"
The next episode of Conan is "The
Cursed Tears of Borgia, Part Two!"
Aerial Lighthouse
Next Conan's hint, fire!
An aerial lighthouse!
Dad, are you okay?
Don't miss the next episode.
I'm a man on fire! Hot, hot, hot!
Hot, hot, hot!