[ED]
[Eyecatch]
The body of Saeki Yuri-san, the woman who
went missing with the Tears of Borgia,
Umeki Hiromichi (45)
Kanoya Construction Company President
a jewel scheduled to be used as part of a live
TV drama broadcast forty years ago, was discovered.
Saeki Yuri-san's granddaughter Sumire-san
Saeki Sumire (20)
Saeki Yuri's Granddaughter
hired the Mori Detective Agency
to clear Yuri-san's name,
but...
Hey, Mizusawa-kun!
Didn't you say something
about the whatever of Borgia?
Mizusawa!
Something's burning.
A fire? Could it be?
Mizusawa!
Hot, hot, hot!
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
A skeleton emerges across time and space!
The case catches fire, putting
the old man in danger!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Cursed Tears of Borgia
(Part Two)
"The Cursed Tears of Borgia, Part Two!"
Dad!
Be quiet. We're in a hospital.
I'm glad you're doing okay.
Yeah, it's just a scratch.
Be careful.
Inspector Megure, I'm
sorry for all the trouble.
It's fine.
But I couldn't save Mizusawa.
Isn't he the one who found
Sumire-san's grandmother?
Yeah. He was my drinking buddy.
He said he had something
to discuss with me today.
Damn. If only I'd gotten there sooner.
About that, Mori-kun...
The autopsy revealed that he
hardly inhaled any smoke at all.
So by the time the fire
started, he was already...
That's right.
Come in.
Excuse us.
Ran-san.
What is it?
Forensics just called.
They examined the victim's phone
that Mori-san saved from the fire.
There wasn't a single image saved on it.
What?!
It wasn't just the images.
Aside from Mori-san's, they didn't find
a single fingerprint on the phone.
Which means...
Someone erased all the images on the
phone and wiped their prints off of it.
Right, mister?
Yeah, and it's probably the same person
who murdered Mizusawa and started the fire.
Takagi.
What about the erased data?
We're having forensics restore it right now.
I see.
Mori-kun, you were supposed to
meet the victim at six, right?
Yes.
Do you remember anything
from when the fire started?
Judging by the situation, the fire was
started about thirty minutes earlier.
It couldn't have been more than an hour.
Which means Mizusawa was murdered before that,
between 5 and 5:30.
What about his associates' alibis?
Nonogaki Real Estate, the site
of the fire, was closed today.
We haven't been able to
confirm the whereabouts
of President Nonogaki
or any of his employees.
I see.
Also,
the victim's friend and client Kanoya
Construction President Umeki Hiromichi...
I've heard that name before.
Yes, sir.
Umeki-san was with the victim when
they discovered the body at the dam.
Oh, right.
And? What about him?
He saw the news about the
fire on a TV at a bar
and came to talk to the police.
According to him, he'd been drinking
with several friends since around five.
So only Umeki has an alibi.
Hey, mister. Don't you want to
see photos of the crime scene?
What?
You might be able to figure
something out if you saw it again.
You're right. What do you think, Inspector?
Very well. Bring them immediately.
Yes, sir.
From: Kanoya Tatsuma
Subj: No Subject
I found the kine
Kinescope?
Isn't that the powdered roasted
soy beans you put on mochi?
Before video became widespread,
Oh, silly me.
I was thinking of kinako.
they used to convert important images
to film in order to preserve them.
Kanoya-san kept a kine, not kinako,
of the final scene of "I Killed Them."
That's a valuable record, but it's
not like it will solve the case.
Oh, I already know who killed Mizusawa-san.
What?
We're going for the other case.
This brings back memories.
"I Killed Them," or
"Killed 'Em" for short.
Kanoya Tatsuma (72)
Kanoya Construction Advisor
You remember?
Indeed I do. I think I was
in sixth grade at the time.
My, my.
Hey, mister. Was the window
open in the final scene?
No, we closed it.
We didn't want to distract from Nagisa-chan
in the important final scene.
It'd be ruined if the wind blew the curtains.
Come to think of it, that
line was incredibly intense.
I see. No, but maybe...
Your grandson is rather strange.
Oh, is he?
Yes, Inspector.
Yes. Thank you.
We've gathered the others,
but where are we headed?
The dam.
There's something I want to
check at the filming location.
According to Kanoya-san,
it should be around here.
Let's see...
I don't see anything.
Not right now.
Huh?
Beika City is...
I knew it.
Knew what? H-Hey, Shinichi!
We're leaving already?
Mori-san's late.
Yeah.
I have someplace to be after this.
Probably a gambling hall.
I heard you're being threatened by
some suspicious people recently.
Not here.
He's here.
This way, Mori-san.
Everyone's waiting for you.
Waiting?
Oh, Inspector. You're here, too.
What are you talking about?
You're the one who asked us to
come here to solve the case.
What? I did?
What? Already?
Hot, hot, hot! T-Today has been too much...
Dad?
That was quick.
Thank you for coming, everyone.
Have a seat.
Now then, I asked you to come
here to discuss the two cases
surrounding the jewel known
as the Tears of Borgia.
Unbelievable.
I doubt I have anything to
do with that, so I'm leaving.
No, its connection to you will
eventually emerge, Umeki-san.
I'm sure some of you have heard
that Western history scholar Senju
said the Tears of Borgia didn't actually
exist and that the jewel was a fake.
What?!
However, though the jewel itself was fake,
Saeki Yuri-san who was transporting
it was indeed found dead.
Unfortunately, 40 years is quite the barrier.
People thought it impossible
to determine the truth.
But a new incident occurred in the present.
Its victim was one of the
men who discovered Yuri-san,
Mizusawa Sho (25)
Nonogaki Real Estate Employee
Mizusawa Sho-kun.
Not only that, but he was
killed not by the fire,
but by someone who strangled him to death.
The investigation briefly
proceeded under the assumption
that the culprit was someone who had
no alibi for when the fire started,
but the crime scene suggested the
existence of another culprit.
Detective Takagi, the photos.
Yes, sir.
Take a look.
The platter that should be
on the shelf is on the table,
and the bottles are empty.
Why do you suppose that is?
It's because that's a picture
of a timed ignition device
made from the materials on hand.
This device the culprit made to get away
with his crime instead limited
who the culprit could be.
In other words, whoever has an alibi for
the time the fire started is the culprit.
Am I right, Umeki-san?
I have no reason to kill Mizusawa.
I see. Takagi, the photos from
the phone at the crime scene.
Yes, sir.
These two photos were restored
from the phone's deleted data.
They show the glovebox of
the car Yuri-san was riding.
Look at the time these photos were taken.
The first was taken at 9:41,
while the second was taken at 9:51.
The glovebox that was closed
in the first photo...
...is open in the second.
Chiba, what time was the body reported?
9:45 AM.
In other words, Mizusawa-kun
photographed the car at 9:41.
Then he switched with you and
reported the body at 9:45.
He then returned to the car
and photographed it at 9:51.
In other words, Umeki-san,
while Mizusawa-kun was away
from the car for ten minutes,
you're the only one who
could've opened the glovebox.
When Mizusawa-kun noticed
the open glovebox later,
he suspected you took something from the car.
He tried to discuss it with
me, but you killed him.
This is ridiculous.
Are you saying the Tears of Borgia
was inside that glovebox?
Why would I know about that ancient history?
I'm disappointed, Hiromichi.
I told you about the Tears of Borgia
countless times when you were a boy.
Damn it.
For this...
For this damn fake...
Damn!
No!
Even if it's fake, my grandmother
risked her life for this.
Damn...
So who stabbed my grandmother?
Allow me to take over for Mori-kun.
You?
Yes. After all, it happened forty years ago.
And it's more speculation than anything.
I'm better suited for
this than Detective Mori.
Kanoya-san, could you prepare the kine?
Very well.
Kanoya-san preserved the final scene
of the forty-year-old drama
"I Killed Them" on 16 mm film.
The maid played by Nagisa-chan calls
over her boyfriend the butler.
This is the scene suggested by Yuri-san
in which she begins peeling apples, right?
Yes, but...
"Red Hood has arrived"?
Nagisa-chan.
Masao-san.
Huh? Didn't you say only Nagisa-san
went to the filming location?
Were you waiting long?
No, but I was scared.
Since this card was here, I thought...
That's right.
But look. The man playing the
butler is there with her.
The butler's at the studio set.
Masao-san, do you not
need to walk with a cane?
What?
We're switching cameras at set times.
Masao-san, are you...?
But the maid is in the scene with him.
That's a stand-in.
Give me the Tears of Borgia
you're wearing on your finger!
We had a similar-looking actress
wear the same costume and
stand in for Nagisa-chan.
No!
Wait!
This shot was done on location.
Then we switched to the studio here.
Damn it! Where are you?
Where did you go?!
I see.
Could you pause it here?
The rest of the scenes are
unrelated to the case,
so we'll leave them out.
I'd like to present my theory to you now.
Sumire-san, I'd especially
like you to hear this.
Go ahead.
While the drama was being
filmed at the studio,
Nagisa-san waited on location
for her scene to start
and for Yuri-san to arrive
with the Tears of Borgia.
However, she never arrived.
Nagisa-san must've panicked.
Calm down, Nagisa.
We have three more minutes.
We need to film the real thing.
You're late, Yuri-chan.
She won't make it in time.
Yuri-chan! I'm glad you made it.
Quickly, the Tears of Borgia.
Yuri-san had been convinced by Professor
Senju not to embarrass the family with a fake.
They were both desperate.
Yuri-san had no time to explain, and
Nagisa-san had a 40 degree fever.
Yuri-san tried to get as far away
from the location as she could
so Nagisa-san wouldn't be blamed,
and so the fake Tears of Borgia
wouldn't appear in the drama.
At the studio, the stand-in
maid stabbed Red Hood to death.
All that remained was
Nagisa-san's final shot.
Nagisa-chan, the real jewel
won't make it in time.
I'm sorry, but you'll have
to wear the fake ring.
I-I understand.
I...
I killed him!
The End
That's what I imagine
happened behind the camera.
It's true that your story explains
the fallen car and the fruit knife.
And Nagisa-san's current condition, but...
It's too bad that it's only speculation.
It can't be helped.
Hey, didn't you say you had them
close the window for the final scene?
Yes, it was necessary for the performance.
Then if the window was open,
doesn't that prove Yuri-san came?
It wouldn't be conclusive, but it
would be circumstantial evidence.
But since the curtains were closed, we
don't know if the window was opened.
I saw something shining when
you showed us this film
on the editor this afternoon.
Just before the words "The
End" appear onscreen,
when Nagisa-san disappears from the shot.
Right here.
Can't you see something shining
through the lace curtains?
I see. You're right.
How embarrassing.
I hadn't noticed in forty years.
That proves the professor's story.
Yes.
Now I can report the results to my mother.
But I wonder what it was.
Could it be a star?
No.
It was cloudy that day. There
wasn't a single star in the sky.
Then was it plane lights?
A plane?
I see. This is...
That's right.
This light was probably
the now demolished Beika
City aerial lighthouse.
Several days later,
we learned Asahina Nagisa-san
kept calling Yuri-san's name,
so we went to Grand Light with
Sumire-san where Nagisa-san lived.
Nagisa-san.
Yuri-chan, you're okay.
Yes. I've been fine this
whole time, Nagisa-chan.
I'm so glad.
I had such a long and terrible dream.
Nagisa-san's heart, which had been tormented
by the ring's curse for forty long years,
was released by the kindness of one
grandmother and her granddaughter.
Episode Preview
Thank you.
It's only once a day, so enjoy yourselves.
The dinosaur bones fell apart!
I don't believe it! My brachiosaurus!
Like you, I wanted everyone to enjoy them.
But it was only for a few seconds, right?
The Man Crushed by a Dinosaur
The next episode of Conan is "The
Man Crushed by a Dinosaur!"
Dinosaur Show
Next Conan's hint, roar!
A dinosaur show!
Name a dinosaur.
Don't miss the next episode.
Arsonosaurus.
Roar...