I'll send that miserable bastard to hell
I've come up with a plan so I won't get caught
Nichiuri TV Radio Division
"Nino-chan's Until Noon Show"
Questions and Concerns Corner
Nothing will happen if this
doesn't get picked up first.
I hope they decide to use it.
Just kidding.
Challenging all cops and detectives
You'll never catch me!
Now let me show you exactly what will happen
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
It all begins with a letter
with dancing characters!
A suspicious contribution makes huge waves!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Radio Questions and Concerns Show
(Challenge Arc)
"The Radio Questions and
Concerns Show, Challenge Arc!"
Nichiuri TV
I've visited Nichiuri TV several times,
but this is the first invitation
I've received from Nichiuri Radio.
I'm Manda, the world's greatest producer.
What? Th-The best in the world?
Manda Teruomi (40)
Nichiuri TV & Radio
Production Unit Producer
Oh, please. I can't believe you
took me seriously, Mori-chan.
It's a joke.
I'm actually only the second
greatest in the world.
What's with this guy?
And this is the world's greatest
director, Kujirai-chan.
Kujirai Mamoru (35)
Nichiuri TV & Radio
Production Unit Director
I'm Kujirai Mamoru. Nice to meet you.
And beside him is the world's
greatest writer, Yashiro-chan.
I'm broadcast writer Yashiro Kaede.
I've been looking forward to today.
Yashiro Kaede (32)
Broadcast Writer
Nice to meet you.
Finally, there's Nichiuri TV's
poster-boy presenter, Nino-chan.
I'm Inuyama Ninosuke.
Thank you for coming today.
Inuyama Ninosuke (38)
Nichiuri TV Presenter
No, thank you.
So, Mori-chan, you got any
alcohol in your system?
Alcohol? No, of course not.
What?
World's greatest AD Abe-chan,
Abe Rie (24)
Nichiuri TV & Radio
Production Unit AD
ask him what he'd like to drink and
have it delivered to his greenroom!
Got it.
Are you sure? We're about to start.
What? But isn't it true?
They say Mori-san performs better
when he's had a drink or two.
I suppose they're not wrong.
Then it's decided.
Mori-chan, we'll be heading
into the studio now.
We'll see you later.
All right.
Is that Manda guy always like that?
I guess so.
Really?
Anyway, what would you like to drink?
Today's concern comes from TM-san of Tokyo.
"I don't know what to
do about the crazy woman
living in the apartment
directly above mine."
"She's noisy, and she throws cigarette
butts and empty cans onto my balcony."
"I have no idea what to do."
I see. This is a truly pressing concern.
Today's guest Mori-san, what advice
do you have as a detective?
It makes you angry because
you think of her as human.
That obnoxious woman is
nothing more than trash!
What?
I-I don't think it's right to
treat people like garbage...
TM-san, you should give her
a taste of her own medicine!
Throw trash back onto her balcony!
Burnable trash, non-burnable trash!
Even your food scraps!
Mori-chan's the best.
No, food scraps aren't enough!
I told you this would happen!
What are we supposed to do now?
Mori-san, you're the best!
Throw your extra large trash!
Play the jingle!
Show some backbone!
Jingle
He's still going!
Nino-chan's Until Noon Show!
If you don't get her back, then
you'll be on the losing side!
Detective Mori's comments
Truly nice
The curtains are now rising on my plan
Several Hours Later
Answer the door, you harlot!
What's all this about?
I could ask you the same thing!
You're the one who picked a fight with me!
Kijima Kumi (38)
Housewife
You trash talked me on the radio!
What? I don't know what you're talking about.
Manda Towako (31)
Housewife
It must've been someone else.
Don't play dumb!
Hey, stop!
I can't believe you used the radio!
That hurts!
They don't even know
they're being manipulated.
It's all going exactly according to plan.
You'll pay for this! Don't
think you'll get way with it!
Move out of here already, you nuisance!
Mori Detective Agency
Yes, Inspector.
I did appear on a radio show
yesterday. What about it?
I told you, I've got nothing to do with it!
Just come to Nichiuri TV.
You're a witness.
A witness? Witness to what?
A murder!
A-A murder?
Hurry.
The victim is Manda Towako-san,
thirty-one years old,
a resident of a nearby apartment building.
She was killed late last night around 12 AM.
She must've been struck with this metal pipe.
Ow!
We didn't find any
fingerprints on the weapon,
and there wasn't any
blood at the crime scene.
I see.
So, why am I a witness?
Because the murderer's motive
may have had something to do with
the radio show you appeared on.
What? How is that radio show the motive?
Yesterday evening, the
victim and Kijima Kumi-san,
who lives above her, argued about the show.
The listener's concern was
about the obnoxious behavior
of the woman who lived above her.
I believe the listener's name was TM-san...
TM?
Those are the same initials as
the victim Manda Towako-san's.
I see. Then the obnoxious woman must be...
Of course I'm angry!
When I came home from work yesterday,
I found a note in my mailbox...
Nuisance
and a recording of the radio show.
Now the whole world's laughing at you.
It makes you angry because
you think of her as human.
That obnoxious woman is
nothing more than trash!
So I went to yell at her!
Mister, you said those cruel things?
Well, you know...
I have no excuse.
I had a little too much of
the drink I was offered.
I'm sorry!
No, no, no, no. It's not your fault.
Anyway, the building manager intervened
and was able to calm things down.
You'll pay for this! Don't
think you'll get way with it!
Move out of here already, you nuisance!
What?
Then you did invite the victim
out later that night...
I told you, I didn't do it.
Now, now.
But immediately after the victim
wrote in about her concern...
It's not that simple, Mori-kun.
Yashiro-san.
Yes.
The listener TM-san isn't
the victim Manda Towako-san.
What?
Morikawa Tsugumi
It's someone completely different
named Morikawa Tsugumi-san.
But you received a CD recording of
the show in your mailbox, right?
That's it.
Manda Towako-san, who happened
to share the same concern,
heard the show on the radio
and recorded it onto a CD.
She put it in Kijima-san's
mailbox out of spite.
When Kijima-san heard it,
she thought it was about her.
I told you...
But, Mori-kun,
it wasn't the victim who
put the CD in her mailbox.
What?
I'm having Takagi look into it.
Isn't this case a little
too convenient for someone?
It may be a coincidence,
but the victim is the victim.
What do you mean?
We learned this when we arrived,
but the victim Manda Towako-san
is the wife of Producer Manda.
They're currently separated.
Your wife?
Oh, but don't worry about it, Mori-chan.
I was going to divorce that thing.
But your wife was firmly
against divorce, wasn't she?
What does that have to do with this case?
But since your wife is gone, that
means your wish came true, right?
Oh, please. Don't say such strange
things, Kujirai-chan and Nino-chan.
The conversation's gone
in a strange direction.
Yeah. It sounds like he's grateful
for what the culprit did.
I told you, it wasn't me!
I did harass her a little.
She kept boasting about
being a rising talent.
She was a rising talent?
It seems that way, but that has
nothing to do with this case.
Yes, but if the divorce proceedings
weren't going well...
Mori-san, you, too?
You're making it sound like I'm somehow
involved in her murder. Right?
Oh, please.
Yes?
Thank you.
I see. Right away.
There's a meeting scheduled in this room.
Understood. We'll move.
Inspector, there's a job I have to check on.
That should be fine.
Excuse me.
Thanks for doing this.
Sure thing.
Inspector Megure.
How did it go, Takagi?
Yes, sir. About that...
I knew it.
Manda-san, this is the CD
we were just discussing.
You're the one who put this in
Kijima-san's mailbox, weren't you?
What?
Just as planned
Our investigation revealed that
this CD wasn't a recording
of the broadcast but copied
directly from the source.
Some of the station staff claim
that yesterday afternoon
Manda-san asked them to create a copy.
Naturally, he told them not to tell anyone.
I wonder why.
Then you disappeared from the
station for about two hours.
During that time,
are you sure you didn't go to the apartment
and put the CD in Kijima-san's mailbox?
It certainly seems that way.
I knew it was you!
Manda-san.
During the review meeting
after yesterday's broadcast
someone said they wish
the woman living above my wife
could've heard today's show.
I'd told everyone that she was frustrated
with the obnoxious woman living above her.
That's when I realized something
interesting might happen
if I made it seem like
she'd complained about her.
You've gotta strike when the iron's hot.
Now the whole world's laughing at you.
And just as you planned,
your wife was killed.
What?
That's how he made someone
else do the killing.
Manipulating another so he
wouldn't get his own hands dirty!
No! I just wanted her to suffer a little.
I never thought she'd be killed for it.
I... I... I'm sorry!
Even if it wasn't deliberate,
you're still responsible
for causing a murder.
All I did was go and yell at her!
Mori-san, I have a request.
Please prove Kijima Kumi-san's innocence.
What?
Yashiro-kun.
You believe me?
It's for Manda-san, actually.
If he caused the murder, then Manda-san
will be held responsible, too.
I can't let that happen.
He's very important to
me. I owe him everything.
You owe Manda-san everything?
I debuted as a broadcast
writer with a radio drama.
He looked through the script I
brought in as a total amateur.
Yashiro-chan, you're lucky
you got to deal with me.
Manda-san, who was a director at the time,
took it upon myself to
put my show on the radio.
So you owe him for helping you debut.
We never worked together after that,
but one month ago, he returned as
the producer of the Until Noon Show,
and we were finally reunited.
I see. You want to save
the man who helped you.
It's true that if she's innocent, then
Manda-san won't be held responsible.
You gotta save me, Mori-chan!
Mori-chan, please! Save me!
Inspector, does Kijima
Kumi-san have an alibi?
Every Friday she goes bar hopping.
She said that's what she
was doing last night.
It's true!
I see.
Hello, this is Megure. Yes.
What? You found someone?
Got it. Thank you.
Kijima-san's alibi has been verified.
See?
An employee said she was drinking there last
night from around 11 PM until past midnight.
Which means...
I told you I didn't kill her!
In other words, what I did had absolutely
nothing at all to do with her murder.
That's great news, Manda-san.
I've got the god of radio on my side.
But then who's the culprit?
Who knows?
In any case, now that we know our program
had nothing to do with the case,
we can get out of here.
Before that, Manda-san,
where were you last night?
Me?
I went drinking with these guys.
But I suddenly felt tired, so
I went home and went to bed.
In other words, you were home alone?
Wh-What about it?
It's ironic, but now that our
prime suspect Kijima Kumi-san
has been proven innocent...
We're forced to consider who stands
to benefit the most from the
death of Manda Towako-san.
It's the end of the line, Manda-san.
You killed your wife,
and put that CD in Kijima
Kumi-san's mailbox
so it would look like she did it.
You made the police believe she had a motive.
What are you talking about, Nino-chan?
Inuyama-san.
We're also considering the possibility
Inuyama-san just mentioned.
But if that's true,
then wouldn't he have done something
to disprove Kijima-san's alibi?
Normally, yes, but...
It happened in the middle of the night.
He probably assumed she'd be unable
to prove her alibi even
if he didn't do anything.
After all, Manda-san's all talk.
Kujirai-san, why?
I've been wondering.
Do Inuyama-san and Kujirai-san
not get along with Manda-san?
I'm sure there's a lot going on between them.
I know all about you, Manda-san.
You're secretly scheming to prevent
me from becoming independent.
Well, you know, the station has its reasons.
You don't love radio!
You never have.
You only think of your programs
as tools to make yourself rich.
You misappropriate them
for your personal use!
That has nothing to do with this.
You're right.
Why don't you tell us all about it at the
station where there won't be any outsiders?
The station?
I told you, last night I was
sound asleep at my home!
You gotta believe me!
He's been sent to hell!
That damn bastard!!
He has motive and no alibi,
and it's true that he tried to have the
obnoxious woman living above her attack his wife.
Yeah, but...
Isn't this a premeditated murder?
Could Manda-san really have come
up with this if he's all talk?
He was just that desperate
to divorce his wife.
Okada-san.
Thank you for the other day.
Hey, Abe. How did it go?
Hey, Yashiro-san.
Huh?
Those two seem to really hate Manda-san.
What?
Are you saying one of them did it
and is trying to frame Manda-san?
I just thought it might be a possibility.
You're right.
That's not possible.
It's true that they don't
get along with Manda-san,
but I can't believe they'd kill
his wife just to get at Manda-san.
Right? See, you brat?
But they hate him so much.
I'm kind of hungry.
I should get something to eat.
Listen to me!
Boy, I'm hungry.
Mister!
Even if the boy suspects
something, it's too late
Everything has gone according to plan
It has ended in my victory!
To be continued
Episode Preview
Isn't this...
Nichiuri TV
Radio Drama
He Disappeared
Without Saying Goodbye
Script Yashiro Kaede
Director Manda Teruomi
Production Nichiuri TV
& Radio Production Unit
Inspector, in the case of
Manda Towako-san's murder
by her husband and suspect
Manda Teruomi-san...
The plot lurking behind it
most likely began a month ago.
The Radio Questions and Concerns Show
(Solution Arc)
The next episode of Conan is...
"The Radio Questions and
Concerns Show, Solution Arc!"
Next Conan's hint!
Radio Drama
A radio drama!
The culprit...
Don't miss the next episode.
...is still one up on us.
What should we do?
Do your best.