Nichiuri TV radio production unit producer,
Manda Teruomi, is a superficial man
who's been living off his glibness alone.
Manda Teruomi (40)
Nichiuri TV & Radio
Production Unit Producer
And Manda secretly murdered
his estranged wife Towako
because she wouldn't agree to a divorce.
Manda Towako (31)
Housewife
Furthermore, he used the
radio show he produces
Now the whole world's laughing at you.
to frame Towako's upstairs
neighbor, Kijima Kumi.
Kijima Kumi (38)
Housewife
However, he couldn't deceive
the eyes of the police.
Isn't this a premeditated murder?
Could Manda-san really have come
up with this if he's all talk?
He was just that desperate
to divorce his wife.
Hey, Yashiro-san.
Huh?
Those two seem to really hate Manda-san.
What?
Are you saying one of them did it
and is trying to frame Manda-san?
I just thought it might be a possibility.
Even if the boy suspects
something, it's too late
Everything has gone according to plan
You underestimate me.
I'll definitely expose the truth.
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
A strange case takes
place at a radio station!
The grinning culprit stands above the law!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Radio Questions and Concerns Show
(Solution Arc)
"The Radio Questions and
Concerns Show, Solution Arc!"
You still think they did it?
They really seemed to hate Manda-san.
Inuyama Ninosuke (38)
Nichiuri TV Presenter
I know all about you, Manda-san.
You're secretly scheming to prevent
me from becoming independent.
Kujirai Mamoru (35)
Nichiuri TV & Radio
Production Unit Director
You don't love radio!
You never have.
You only think of your programs
as tools to make yourself rich.
You misappropriate them
for your personal use!
I suppose. It's clear that
they found him disagreeable.
But remember what Yashiro Kaede-san said?
Yashiro Kaede (32)
Broadcast Writer
It's true that they don't
get along with Manda-san,
but I can't believe they'd kill
his wife just to get at Manda-san.
Yeah, but...
Hurry up and eat your
food. Then we're leaving.
Hey, wasn't that Okino Yoko-san?
What?! Yoko-chan's here?!
Where? Where?
This way? That way?
Miss!
Abe Rie (24)
Nichiuri TV & Radio
Production Unit AD
It's true that Manda-san was trying to
prevent Inuyama-san from becoming independent.
But I doubt he'd be able to stop Inuyama-san
if he really wanted to quit
working for the station.
Right?
Kujirai-san didn't get along
with Manda-san either, right?
Kujirai-san's such a serious person.
He'd never get along with
the slick Manda-san.
Honestly, he was disgusted with him.
That incompetent fool shouldn't
be working in radio.
Incompetent?
It's apparently about a drama Manda-san
put on while he was a director.
But it's an old story, so
I don't know much about it.
Oh, I remember now.
Huh?
I think that old drama was
Yashiro-san's debut work.
What?
You can read it in this reception area.
I'll be right over there.
Thanks.
Nichiuri TV
Radio Drama
He Disappeared Without
Saying Goodbye
Script Yashiro Kaede
Director Manda Teruomi
Production Nichiuri TV
& Radio Production Unit
This single drama made Yashiro-san
think she owed Manda-san everything,
while also making Kujirai-san
think he was incompetent.
How can that be?
She's not here either.
Okino Yoko-chan, where are you?!
Isn't this...?
Nichiuri TV
Radio Drama
He Disappeared Without
Saying Goodbye
Script Yashiro Kaede
Director Manda Teruomi
Production Nichiuri TV
& Radio Production Unit
Miss.
What is it?
Kogoro-no-ojisan said he'd like
to hear a recording of this drama.
Sure. I'll submit a request
to the records department.
Yoko-chan!
So that's how it is. Anyway...
Cast
Isaka Kiko – Adachi Towako
This name, Adachi Towako...
No, that's not possible.
They wouldn't have said that.
Producer Kamio Yoshitaka
I see. So that's how it is.
No, that's all I need to know.
Goodbye.
Which means...
Oh, so that's why?
That's why he drank even though
he was about to go on the air.
And someone said during
the post show meeting
that they wished Manda-san's wife's upstairs
neighbor could've heard the show, right?
Yes.
Do you know who said that?
I think it was...
I knew it.
They used the concern that was submitted
by coincidence in their plan.
Where are you?!
Why can't I find you, Yoko-chan?!
Coincidence?
It can't be coincidence that such
a convenient concern was submitted.
The listener TM-san isn't the
victim Manda Towako-san.
Morikawa Tsugumi
It's someone completely different
named Morikawa Tsugumi-san.
Could it be?
Hello?
Yes, I'm Morikawa Tsugumi.
Morikawa Tsugumi (32)
Housewife
What? The famous detective?
What does the famous Mori
Kogoro-san want with me?
Thank you.
Once I get the results of the
investigation I requested...
You damn brat!
Take a look.
Yoko in Hawaii
Yoko-chan couldn't possibly be here.
She's in Hawaii, huh?
We're leaving.
I need to use the bathroom first.
Hey, wait!
That damn brat.
Hello? Ah, Inspector.
What?
I see. I'm actually still at Nichiuri TV.
But why?
Hello? Hello? Hello, Inspector?
I feel better now. Should we go?
We can't leave.
What?
I don't know why, but the inspector told
me to wait because he was on his way.
And he told me to gather all the staff again.
I wonder why.
What do the police want now?
The situation's become complicated
since they found out the victim
was Manda-san's wife, right?
Inspector.
What is it, Mori-kun?
I heard you asked my detectives
to bring Manda here.
What? You told me to wait—
Told me to wait for you here...
Is this the rumored Sleeping Kogoro?
Inspector,
in the case of Manda Towako-san's
murder by her husband
and suspect Manda Teruomi-san...
The plot lurking behind it
most likely began a month ago,
when Manda-san was brought
here as the new producer.
When Manda-san was assigned to
be the new producer of the show,
Inuyama-san, he told you
about his wife then, correct?
Yes.
At the welcoming party we were
socially obligated to throw.
I wish my awful wife would just disappear.
I met her the other day about the divorce,
and she wouldn't stop complaining.
Something about her obnoxious
upstairs neighbor at her apartment.
That's not my problem, you know?
Right?
When they heard that, the culprit
came up with their plan.
They'd murder Manda-san's
wife and frame him for it.
Isn't that right, Yashiro Kaede-san?
What?
Why would I frame Manda-san
when I owe him everything?
Mori-san!
You were right.
When we showed this photo you sent us
to the residents of Manda
Towako-san's apartment building,
several of them remembered you.
They said half a month ago
you were asking around
about Manda Towako-san's upstairs
neighbor Kijima Kumi-san.
They said they told you that Kijima-san
goes barhopping every Friday night.
That's why you decided to
do it on a Friday, isn't it?
Just because I asked about Kijima-san,
that doesn't make me the culprit.
There's also the radio show submission.
You forged that, didn't you?
What?
I checked in with your friend
Morikawa Tsugumi-san.
I heard from Yashiro-san
that she asked you to do it.
What? Oh, Kaede admitted it herself?
She made me promise not to tell anyone.
We don't get enough interesting submissions.
I can write the submission myself,
but if it's chosen, the
station calls the listener.
So you want me to pretend I wrote it.
Sure. You can count on me.
Thanks.
You asked Morikawa Tsugumi-san
because her initials are TM.
The same as Manda Towako-san's.
It was necessary to involve Kijima Kumi-san.
Using Morikawa-san's name,
you wrote a fictitious submission
that would make Kijima Kumi-san
I don't know what to do about the crazy woman
living in the apartment directly above mine.
believe it was Manda Towako-san.
Nothing will happen if this
doesn't get picked up first.
I hope they decide to use it.
Once the submission arrived at the station,
you selected it for Friday's show.
As the show organizer,
it was your responsibility to
select submissions for the show.
Yesterday, on the day of your crime, you
gave a plausible excuse to make me drink.
They say Mori-san performs better
when he's had a drink or two.
You got me drunk and worked up.
Mori-san, you're the best!
After inciting me to make rude
comments during the show,
during the post show meeting...
I wish the woman living
above Manda-san's wife
could've heard today's show.
That's when I had an idea.
You've gotta strike when the iron's hot.
You incited Kijima Kumi-san to
fight with Manda Towako-san.
They don't even know
they're being manipulated.
It's all going exactly according to plan.
And after all that scheming...
What do you want? It's
the middle of the night.
But, Mori-kun, even if she plotted to
frame Manda-san for his wife's murder,
why did she need to involve Kijima Kumi-san?
Because even though he has a motive,
not having an alibi wasn't a compelling
enough reason to suspect him.
Inciting Kijima-san to attack his wife
guaranteed suspicion would fall on Manda-san.
Naturally, Kijima-san would
be suspected for a while,
but her alibi would be verified since
she spent her Fridays barhopping.
But the police were struggling
to verify her alibi.
That's when you asked me.
Mori-san, I have a request.
Please prove Kijima Kumi-san's innocence.
You wanted suspicion to be shifted
from Kijima-san to Manda-san
was quickly as possible.
You had me come on as a guest
in case the police took too long to
verify Kijima-san's alibi, didn't you?
So everything was calculated?
But I didn't need to do anything.
Kijima-san's alibi was verified.
And we suspected Manda-san.
Just like Yashiro-san wanted.
However, Conan suspected
Inuyama-san and Kujirai-san,
so you hastily denied that possibility...
That's not possible.
It's true that they don't get
along with Manda-san, but
because you were desperate
to frame Manda-san.
Everything you're saying is just speculation.
I doubt you've noticed,
but you keep repeating a certain action.
When suspicion fell on Manda-san
because of the CD...
Inspector Megure.
How did it go, Takagi?
Yes, sir. About that...
When we learned Kijima-san was innocent,
and Manda-san was the only suspect...
And when Manda-san was taken away...
You touched the band-aid
on the back of your neck.
Every time things went according to plan.
You must've been unconsciously worried
about the mark left there by your crime.
That's it. The sample sent for DNA testing.
Left under the victim's fingernails...
The blood.
In her final struggle, Manda Towako-san
scratched the back of her killer's neck.
Am I wrong, Yashiro-san?
I thought I'd won.
I never stood a chance
against the great detective.
Yashiro-san.
B-But why? I thought you owed me everything.
It was hate, wasn't it?
For Manda-san and Towako-san.
H-Hate? Over what?
When I asked about it...
She was a rising talent?
It seems that way.
But your answer was strange.
Conan, the script.
Okay!
Manda-san's wife's maiden
name was Adachi Towako-san.
Seven years ago, she played the
leading role in your debut work.
Cast
Isaka Kiko – Adachi Towako
But you tried to hide that,
which means it must have something
to do with the crux of this case.
"He Disappeared Without Saying Goodbye."
It's a very good script.
It's a masterpiece.
It's a masterful depiction of a person's
feelings for the lover they suddenly lost.
Truly a rare masterpiece.
But once it became a drama, you
couldn't stand to listen to it.
Because the director didn't
understand any of it.
And Adachi Towako-san's
infantile performance.
It was truly awful.
Worse than a school play.
R-Right?
I told the producer from the
start that she couldn't do it.
You're lying.
I checked with Kamio Yoshitaka-san,
the producer at the time.
You're the one who ignored the opposition
and cast her in the lead role.
You were already dating Adachi Towako-san,
and intended it to be a present for her.
Am I wrong?
That's a true misappropriation of a show!
But everyone does it!
Yashiro-san must've been frustrated.
Not because it was her debut work,
but because this work depicting
the loss of a loved one
is your own experience, isn't it?
You wouldn't have been able
to write it otherwise.
Manda-san, your and Towako-san's selfishness
ruined a work that was
important to Yashiro-san.
But, Mori-kun,
why would she act on a
seven-year-old grudge now?
Yashiro-san probably hadn't
been holding a grudge.
But one month ago, Manda-san was
assigned to be the show's producer.
It had been seven years,
but nothing had changed.
His superficial glibness and misappropriation
of programs had only increased!
That old frustration returned,
and she decided to seek
revenge on the couple.
She used a sedative at the
staff drinking party last night
to make Manda-san tired so he'd go home,
ruining his alibi.
After that, she headed to
Manda Towako-san's place.
What do you want? It's
the middle of the night.
I poured my soul into it.
It was so awful.
Boy, I'm beat.
I don't think I'm fit for radio.
After all, I'm too handsome.
This old man doesn't have
a concern in the world.
Episode Preview
Let me take a look.
Excuse me, but is this book yours?
No, it belongs to my husband.
You stole this from Mizutani-san's
house, didn't you?
No!
Tamaki Yujiro-san, could you come
down to the station with us?
No way!
Hand cream?
Yes.
The Whistling Bookstore 2
The next episode of Conan is
"The Whistling Bookstore 2!"
Rare Book
You're listening to "Next Conan's Hint."
A rare book!
What's a rare book?
Don't miss the next episode.
A book that's extremely difficult to find.
Like Detective Mori.