You let your guard down, Akai Shuichi.
I could say the same thing to you...
Bourbon.
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
An unbelievable pair run into each other!
A surprising case lies
at the end of the muzzle!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Unsolved Cocktail Case
(Part One)
"The Unsolved Cocktail Case, Part One!"
9 Hours Earlier...
What? You were just on your way out?
Mori Detective Agency
Yeah.
Oh, but I brought sandwiches.
Thank you as usual.
I'll have them as a late night
snack. You can leave them here.
Got it.
I'm sure they're just leftovers from Poirot.
Dad!
Is it that obvious?
So, are you going out for a case?
Why do you think that?
Huh?
We could be going out to eat together.
Mori-sensei just said he'd eat the
sandwiches as a late night snack.
I thought it'd be strange if
you were going out to eat.
Well, Mori-sensei?
Well, you're half right.
Some rich guy is freaking out because
he received a threatening letter.
I'm on my way to take these two to
talk over dinner with said rich guy.
I see. I still have a lot to learn.
Oh, right. Speaking of cases, Ran-san,
I heard a series of murders
happened during your school trip.
Oh, yeah.
But, well...
It seems your classmate Kudo
Shinichi-kun helped solved the case.
I guess...
So, where did he go afterward?
I'm sorry. Our teachers told
us not to talk about Shinichi.
I knew he'd ask about me.
I see.
But I heard from Sonoko-san that
you often go to his house to clean.
Yes, sometimes.
Hey.
You should come with us
to talk about the case.
Aren't you Kogoro-no-ojisan's apprentice?
What? Me, too?
Sure, you can come.
These sandwiches will cover the
cost of your detective lesson.
Well, my shift for today is over.
And if you insist...
Huh? Oh, no.
It seems I forgot my phone.
What? Where?
I think I left it by the
sandwiches I brought earlier.
Amuro-san, did you have your phone out?
I received a call from an acquaintance
while I was delivering the sandwiches.
Then I'll go get it.
Thank you, Ran-san.
Jeez. You're surprisingly scatterbrained.
I'm not a very good detective.
I found it, Amuro-san.
Thanks.
Thank you for getting this.
Let's go, then.
So, where are we going?
It's called the Black Rabbit Restaurant.
It's probably a trendy little restaurant.
Maybe it's a well-established
Western restaurant.
Aren't you excited, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
H-Hey, wait.
This isn't a normal restaurant.
It's a bunny girl club!
True to its name...
There are black bunnies everywhere.
Unbelievable.
I wouldn't have brought Conan-kun if
I'd known it was this kind of place.
I'm fine.
Look. They've got rolled omelets and
curry, and everything looks good.
Thank you for waiting.
You must be the great
detective Mori Kogoro-san.
Nice to meet you.
Morooka Gunzo
(50) Rich Man
I'm the man who contacted you, Morooka Gunzo.
Hello.
So, about this threatening letter...
I brought it, of course.
Fukamachi-kun, the letter.
Yes, sir.
Fukamachi Atsufumi (72)
Morooka's Butler
This is the threatening letter
my master received the other day.
Let me take a look.
A threatening letter made from
clippings in this day and age, huh?
"If you want to live, stay away
from the Black Rabbit Restaurant."
Wait, i-isn't this the Black Rabbit Restaurant?!
Yes, so I invited a detective to find
the scoundrel trying to kill me
who is surely at this restaurant.
That's insane.
But there's no guarantee you'll
be attacked inside the restaurant.
I have a few bodyguards with me at all times.
If I'm going to be attacked,
it'll be inside this restaurant.
Why aren't your bodyguards
with you right now?
Well, obviously...
If I brought a bunch of
stern-looking men in here,
I'd ruin the atmosphere of the restaurant.
Absolutely.
Oh, Morooka-san!
Welcome!
Thanks for coming back.
Asakura Yuri (25)
Employee
Ah, Yuri-chan. I'm here for
a special reason today.
Oh?
You brought a girl with you?
And a little boy.
So cute.
Actually, these kids are...
Oh, sorry. I couldn't help myself.
Mori-san, this isn't that kind of place.
Excuse me.
Who gropes a bunny girl in
front of his own daughter?
You'll be accused of sexual harassment.
I won't do it again.
Jeez.
Come on, order something.
Yuri-chan, order whatever you'd like.
Could I get some food, then?
I missed lunch, so I'm starving.
Of course.
Let's see...
In that case, I'd like a
fruit plate, rolled omelets,
and sandwiches.
You've got quite the appetite.
You can touch them, but I can't?
All right. Dinner's on me tonight.
Girls, you're all welcome to
order whatever you'd like.
Fukamachi-kun, you, too.
Let's not stand on ceremony.
Have a seat and drink with us.
Yes, sir.
I'm not sure where to look in
this type of establishment.
He's wiping his glasses so
he can stare right at them.
Thank you for waiting.
These rolled omelets look delicious.
Let's eat.
Let's see...
Fukamachi-kun, could you pass the sauce?
Huh? What?
Fine, I'll get it.
Glasses?
Are these yours?
Yes, sir. I thought I left them on the table.
I-In any case, I have a spare pair in the car.
I'll go get them.
Hold it. It's too dangerous to
get them without your glasses.
I'll get them for you.
Thank you. They're in the glove box.
Got it.
I'll go with you.
Excuse me, coming through.
Yuri-chan, thanks for the drink.
I didn't pay for it.
But everyone's drinks count as your
sales since Morooka-san ordered them.
Maybe you'll be first today.
Yeah, right.
Murakami Sana (28)
Employee
No way.
A-An earthquake?
I'm sorry.
It suddenly starting ringing
while I was checking my messages.
Let me see that.
Please be careful.
That type of phone sounds an alarm
if you press the power and increase
volume buttons simultaneously.
I-I see.
What a surprise.
I'm glad it wasn't an earthquake.
I'm really sorry.
It's fine.
All the bunny girls keep their phones
in the backs of their outfits.
Yeah.
Customers call us all the time to
ask if the restaurant's crowded.
And sometimes we call them to
invite them to the restaurant.
Oh, I'm sorry.
There are spare cuffs in the changing room.
Why don't you go change yours?
Okay.
Hello, Adachi-san?
Hello again.
I'm sorry, but we're full right now.
A table should open up in about an hour.
Found them. I found the spare glasses.
Thank you for coming with me, Mori-san.
Your butler sure is clumsy.
He can be old-fashioned and stiff,
but he's a very hard-working butler.
He's been employed by my recently
deceased wife's family for a long time.
I see.
Anyway, that employee... Yuri-san, was it?
The two of you seem quite close.
Really? Well, I do always ask for her.
Do you come here often?
No, actually. There's a clothing
store next to this one.
I'll stop by to see the girls while
getting a new suit made there.
That's about it.
I see.
Here, Fukamachi-kun.
Thank you, sir.
Huh? Where's Yuri-chan?
She hurried off to the
changing room a moment ago.
Oh.
But almost all the food she ordered is here.
And my deduction was exactly correct.
Wow!
Are you drinking, Fukamachi-kun?
Yes, some.
It's my fruit plate.
That looks good.
Come on. Everyone's been waiting
for you since you ordered.
Really? I'm sorry.
Now eat.
Okay.
Thanks for the food.
It's so good!
Is it? Let me try.
Let's see. My glass is...
This one.
Well? Seen anyone suspicious?
Not in particular.
What about you, Amuro-kun?
I don't detect any murderous intentions.
What?
Y-Yuri...
Yuri!
Are you okay, Yuri?!
Hey!
Yuri!
Don't touch her!
Ran, call an ambulance and the police!
Okay.
But why?
Perhaps she got food poisoning
from the fruit she ate.
Food poisoning?
No way.
That's not it.
Morooka-san had some of that fruit, too.
It's hard to believe only
Yuri-san got food poisoning.
Yuri-san said she was starving
since she missed lunch.
And food poisoning symptoms manifest 30
minutes after eating at the earliest.
I saw it in an experiment on a TV show.
Sounds like a crazy TV show.
Which means she happened
to eat some fruit
that had been poisoned by someone,
or someone poisoned this glass
she was just drinking from.
Is that right, detective?
Why are you asking me?
Why don't you ask Kogoro-no-ojisan?
Yes, it's called the Black Rabbit Restaurant.
Please come immediately. Thank you.
Huh?
My wallet's missing.
What does it look like?
It has ginkgo leaves on it.
There's not much cash in
it, but my house key...
Is this it?
Yes, that's it.
Oh, good. Thank you.
Where did you find it?
He said it was by the bathroom.
That dark and handsome man over there.
What? Amuro-san?
Too bad, though.
If that were Yuri's, I would've
investigated its contents
to figure out where she's been
secretly meeting Morooka-san.
What? Morooka-san and Yuri-san?
I know those two are together.
Morooka-san normally calls her Yuri-chan,
but he called her Yuri just now.
I don't know what your relationship is with
Morooka-san, but you should be careful.
O-Okay...
Arsenic?
You found arsenic in Yuri-san's drink?
Yeah.
No...
So, how's Yuri-san?
They've finished treating her at the hospital,
but she hasn't regained consciousness yet.
So, do you have any idea who
might've tried to kill the victim?
No idea...
It was me.
Someone was trying to poison me,
but Yuri-chan drank it instead.
What?
What do you mean?
I'm the one who was being threatened.
What? Threatened?
I see.
So you received this letter.
Yeah, but Yuri-chan was
poisoned instead of me.
But your glasses were
totally different shapes.
What?
Yuri-san's glass was a
skinny champagne glass,
and yours was a standard highball glass.
I don't think they'd mix them up.
Then Yuri-san really was the
culprit's intended victim.
We can't say that for certain yet.
Yuri-san collapsed after
returning to the table
and drinking from her glass.
She covered her glass with a
coaster before leaving the table.
It could only have been
poisoned by Morooka-san,
who passed by Yuri-san as she held her
glass before she left the table.
I'll get them for you.
Thank you.
They're in the glove box.
Got it.
I'll go with you.
Excuse me, coming through.
Or Fukamachi-san, who was sitting
next to her when she placed her glass
on the table when she was
startled by the phone alarm.
No way.
An earthquake?
I'm sorry.
It suddenly starting ringing
while I was checking my messages.
Let me see that.
Or Murakami-san, who spilled
red wine on her white cuffs
and created a reason for
her to leave the table.
And sometimes we call them to
invite them to the restaurant.
Oh, I'm sorry.
There are spare cuffs in the changing room.
Why don't you go change yours?
Okay.
As far as I can recall,
only those three could've
poisoned Yuri-san's glass.
Right, Mori-sensei?
Yeah, you're right.
He's been watching closely.
The three he just named...
Morooka-san.
Fukamachi-san.
And restaurant employee Murakami-san.
We'll be asking you in greater
detail about what happened.
Like Amuro-san said, one of
those three must be the culprit.
But who poisoned Yuri-san's glass, and how?
Episode Preview
He said he needed to talk to Yuri-chan,
and they headed out back together.
How far apart in age do you think we are?
I really was at a different table!
An injury?
Amuro-san, what's wrong?
You've been acting strange.
Oh, sorry.
This is goodbye...
Rei-kun.
The Unsolved Cocktail Case
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Unsolved Cocktail Case, Part Two!"
Champagne Glass
Next Conan's hint!
A champagne glass!
Summer vacation ends with
a child-turned-bunny girl?
Don't miss the next episode.
I didn't think we'd take it this far.