The old man brought me and
Ran, along with Amuro-san,
to meet a client who received a
threatening letter at a bunny girl club
called the Black Rabbit Restaurant.
The client was a wealthy man
named Morooka Gunzo-san.
Morooka Gunzo
(50) Rich Man
He brought his butler Fukamachi
Atsufumi with him.
Fukamachi Atsufumi (72)
Morooka's Butler
The threatening letter stated,
"If you want to live, stay away
from the Black Rabbit Restaurant."
Well? Seen anyone suspicious?
Not in particular.
What about you, Amuro-kun?
I don't detect any murderous intentions.
Asakura Yuri (25)
Employee
What?
You found arsenic in Yuri-san's drink?
Yeah.
I-It was me.
Someone was trying to poison me,
but Yuri-chan drank it instead.
I see.
So you received this letter.
Yeah, but Yuri-chan was
poisoned instead of me.
But your glasses were
totally different shapes.
What?
Yuri-san's glass was a
skinny champagne glass,
and yours was a standard highball glass.
I don't think they'd mix them up.
Then Yuri-san really was the
culprit's intended victim.
It could only have been
poisoned by Morooka-san,
who passed by Yuri-san as she held her
glass before she left the table.
Or Fukamachi-san, who was sitting
next to her when she placed her glass
on the table when she was
startled by the phone alarm.
Or Murakami-san, who spilled
red wine on her white cuffs
and created a reason for
her to leave the table.
As far as I can recall,
only those three could've
poisoned Yuri-san's glass.
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
As he determines how the glass was poisoned,
a strange memory emerges in
the back of Amuro's mind!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Unsolved Cocktail Case
(Part Two)
"The Unsolved Cocktail Case, Part Two!"
You went to your car to get his glasses?
You, the master of your
butler Fukamachi-san?
Yeah. I'm the one who accidentally stepped on
and broke his glasses that had
fallen beneath the table.
Glasses?
The sauce for the rolled omelets
was next to Fukamachi-kun.
These rolled omelets look delicious.
Let's eat.
Let's see...
Fukamachi-kun, could you pass the sauce?
Huh? What?
Fine...
But when I tried to get
it, they snapped. Right?
Yes.
But why were your glasses under the table?
I remember wiping the lenses and
setting them on top of the table.
I'm not sure where to look in
this type of establishment.
I probably bumped them with my
elbow and knocked them off.
I said it was dangerous for him to get his
spare glasses when his eyesight is so bad.
I'll get them for you.
Thank you. They're in the glove box.
I see. So that's why.
You have strange tastes, though.
Sauce on rolled omelets?
What? It's good.
Come to think of it, Yuri-chan put
sauce on her rolled omelets, too.
She said she picked up the
habit from someone else. See?
Sauce
Huh. Other people do it, too.
In any case, I don't have a
single reason to poison her.
She was my favorite.
So you say, but maybe she was
pressuring you to marry her.
What?
Maybe she put sauce on her rolled omelets
because she picked up the
habit from you, her lover.
I-I...
You fabricated the threatening
letter yourself, too.
Was your plan to make us believe
she was poisoned in your place
and murder her before your wife
found out you had a mistress?
Y-You can't be serious!
How far apart in age do you think we are?
And besides, my wife passed away
six months ago. She was sick.
What?
I see. You accidentally
triggered the phone's alarm.
Everyone in the restaurant,
including the victim,
believed it was an earthquake alert,
so they set their glasses
down to check their phones?
Y-Yes.
I was trying to check my messages while
my master was getting my glasses.
No way.
A-An earthquake?
I-I'm sorry.
It suddenly starting ringing
while I was checking my messages.
Let me see that.
Which means you weren't
wearing your glasses then?
No, so I couldn't see clearly.
I couldn't tell who set
their glass on the table.
Besides, they're all dressed similarly.
So you say, but maybe you had
surgery to improve your eyesight.
If that's what you think,
try putting on my glasses.
These are intense!
In fact, I'm surprised you can
see anything wearing these.
I've never worn contact lenses
or anything like that either.
Even if I were, those lenses would be
on my person or somewhere around me.
You're welcome to look for them.
In the first place, like my
master, I don't have a motive.
We only ever come here while we're waiting.
While you're waiting?
The master patronizes the
clothing store next to this one.
We only come here to pass the time while
the suits he purchased are being tailored.
Isn't that right, sir?
Y-Yeah.
I told you, I just bumped into her
and spilled a little wine on her.
Murakami Sana (28)
Employee
I'm not some super spy.
I couldn't have poisoned Yuri's
glass in that fraction of a second.
Oh, I'm sorry.
In that case, neither could I.
I couldn't have poisoned her
glass when I passed by her.
Well, we weren't there when it happened.
We can't speak on the matter.
Besides, how would I benefit
from poisoning Yuri?
If there is one, tell me!
Well...
You didn't want to lose the
number one spot to her.
What?
The other bunnies told me.
Every six months, the highest
earning bunny girl is chosen,
and she receives a large bonus.
For the past two years,
you've been number one,
but lately you'd been worried
since Yuri-chan was catching up.
Maybe you already bought something expensive
assuming you'd get the bonus and
felt like you had to poison her.
What?
In that case, tell me what expensive
"something" I already purchased!
Conan-kun, do you know who did it?
Wait, what? He was here a second ago.
That boy just asked where the
parking lot was and went outside.
With that dark handsome man.
With Amuro-san?
Yes, the boss did come to get his
butler Fukamachi-san's glasses.
He was with the detective Mori Kogoro-san.
Did you notice anything unusual then?
Like what?
Like them watching the restaurant
or checking their watches.
Not particularly.
Speaking of unusual, the boss's
weight has been strange, right?
Yeah. He'll suddenly lose a bunch
of weight, and then gain it back.
Maybe there's something bothering him.
And he's been getting injured
a lot recently, too.
Yeah. He said he tripped on a step.
An injury?
The next time you come in with an
injury, I won't be able to treat you.
I'm going far, far away.
This is goodbye,
Rei-kun.
Amuro-san? Amuro-san.
Amuro-san!
What's wrong? You were spacing out.
It's nothing.
Why am I thinking about her now?
According to Amuro-kun's testimony,
the victim Asakura Yuri-san's glass
could've only been poisoned by
Morooka Gunzo-san, who broke his butler's
glasses when he stepped on them,
left his seat to get his spare glasses
from the car, and passed by Yuri-san
while she was holding her glass.
Fukamachi Atsufumi-san, who triggered
his phone alarm accidentally
and was sitting next to Yuri-san's
glass when she set it on the table
to check for an earthquake
report on her own phone.
Or Murakami Sana-san,
who later spilled red wine
on Yuri-san's cuffs and encouraged
her to leave her glass
in order to get new cuffs.
But it took only a moment for
Morooka-san to pass by her
and Murakami-san to spill
red wine on her cuffs.
They didn't have time to poison her drink.
And Fukamachi-san wasn't wearing his
glasses when he triggered the alarm.
He says he couldn't tell
who put which glass where.
We'll just have to wait for
Yuri-san to regain consciousness.
Inspector Megure.
What is it?
Apparently the restaurant
staff want to talk to you.
They remembered something.
What? The butler Fukamachi-san
came to this store alone?
Was it to see Yuri-san?
Yes. At first we thought he
came to make a reservation.
He said he needed to talk to Yuri-chan,
and they headed out back together.
What?
At first Yuri-chan was smiling
while talking to him.
But the moment the butler produced
an envelope, things became awkward.
An envelope?
Do you know what was in it?
I don't know.
He was paying her to cut ties.
You know, as in, "Break up with my master."
And she said, "I won't take your
money!" and rejected his offer.
Does that mean she was Morooka-san's
lover and was pushing for marriage?
But why would he come here
to drink if she was here?
Then maybe it was the opposite,
and he came to ask her to be his lonely
master's lover in exchange for money?
So he retaliated by poisoning
her because she refused?
That doesn't sound very likely to—
Stay out of adult conversations, kid!
Dad!
So, when did Morooka-san
start coming to the store?
About six months ago.
That's exactly around the
time his wife passed away.
Yeah.
But he doesn't seem like
the type to have a lover.
No, he was quite the ladies' man.
He probably messed around
a lot when he was younger.
Come to think of it, he often said
he was a troublemaker in his 20's.
I knew it!
A troublemaker?
There was a girl he liked.
They ran away together and lived
in Tottori for about four years.
H-He eloped?
Not bad, old man.
But his parents dragged him back home, and
he married the woman he was engaged to.
The butler Fukamachi-san
came along with that wife.
He originally worked for the wife's family,
but the wife insisted that he come
with her to the Morooka family.
So, what happened to the
girl he eloped with?
Who knows? She probably received a
ton of money to break up with him.
Morooka-san's family has been
wealthy for generations.
Oh, right. Yuri-chan's from Tottori, too.
That's why the two of them got along.
Come to think of it, I think Sana-san's
family is from Tottori, too.
That's right. She tries to hide
it, but sometimes her speech...
My father's calling.
Is it all right if I answer?
Uh, sure.
Hello, Pop?
Sorry, I'm a bit busy at the moment.
What? What d'ya want?
Didn't I tell ya?
Don't worry 'bout the money.
Just focus on gettin' better.
I'll do somethin' 'bout the
money for the surgery.
Don't worry. You won't die that easily, pop.
We've got the same hard-as-nails
blood flowin' in us.
The same red blood...
Red...
...blood?
Amuro-san, what's wrong?
You've been acting strange.
Oh, sorry.
Her again. But why now?
Information on Kudo Shinichi. Hurry!
RUM.
Yes, yes. I know.
By the way, Murakami-san,
when Fukamachi-san triggered his phone
alarm and Yuri-san set her glass on the table,
where were you?
I-I was at a different table.
Everyone was making a huge fuss over
the weird sound he made with his phone,
so I came to check it out.
That's when I bumped into Yuri
and spilled wine on her.
Isn't that right?
I, uh...
I was out getting Fukamachi-kun's
glasses, so...
I remember Yuri-san went to replace her
left cuff that had wine spilled on it
shortly after the alarm sounded.
I can't recall if you were standing
next to her when the alarm sounded.
I told you, I wasn't there!
I'm not saying you're lying.
But if it's a question of whether
or not you were there...
It's true!
I really was at a different table!
You have to believe me!
What? Concerns?
You're saying Morooka-san was
worried about something?
Yes. That's what his bodyguards
out in the parking lot told me.
Lately he'd been acting strange.
He'd suddenly lose and gain weight, and was
frequently tripping and injuring himself.
Of course he was worried.
He received a threatening letter.
But, Mori-kun, the threatening
letter arrived...
An injury?
Miyano Clinic
Injury, injury! Injured person here!
Mom, I brought you a patient!
Let go!
Thank you.
I told it you it was no big deal.
Miyano Elena (29)
Doctor
But you're bleeding.
All this needs is a little spit.
But...
You again?
You sure do love to fight.
That's not it.
They won't stop making fun
of the color of my hair.
Even though I'm Japanese, born and raised.
Is one of your parents a foreigner?
What's wrong with that?
Then tell your friends you fought with this:
Even if people look different,
when you peel back our skin, we're
all just lumps of blood and flesh.
To prove it, every race in the world
has red blood flowing through them,
just like yours.
Got it?
Yeah...
Then let's get you cleaned up. Come in.
Miyano Atsushi (35)
Doctor/Scientist
All done.
Akemi, put a bandage on him.
Okay. Come with me.
O-Okay.
How unusual.
Honey.
You're normally shy and speak
the bare minimum with patients,
but you're so friendly with that boy.
Hold still.
Ow!
That boy is special.
Sorry.
He's half, like me.
I see.
Anyway, how'd it go?
Are we transferring to that facility
that'll back your research?
I'm thinking about turning them down.
What? Why?
I'd hate to leave you guys behind,
and your sister said it
seemed a little suspect.
But isn't the Karasuma
Group sponsoring them?
Yeah, but I've heard unfavorable
rumors about them.
I don't want to be called
a mad scientist again.
But your research can't be
done part-time as a GP.
If the pay's good, then it's
too bad for our patients,
but I don't mind closing
this clinic to help you.
It's fine. The three of us
are doing just fine as is.
It's four.
Huh? What?
I'm three months along.
Really?
Then maybe I'll reconsider their offer.
It's your dream. You shouldn't
give up on it so easily.
Yeah.
Well, I'm leaving now.
Can I come back if I get hurt again?
No. We don't treat boys who fight.
What?
But if it's an honorable injury suffered while
making up with the friend you fought with,
then I'll at least put a bandage on you.
I see.
So that's how it is.
Episode Preview
I found a fake nail.
That's why the culprit was able
to poison Yuri-san's glass.
I heard you're struggling to pay for
your seriously ill father's surgery!
What? At least I'm not an old man who was
trying to pay her to stop contacting him!
Please don't make your wife sad anymore.
The Unsolved Cocktail Case
(Part Three)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Unsolved Cocktail Case, Part Three!"
Amuro's Memory
Next Conan's hint!
Amuro's memory!
Don't miss the next episode.
Amuro-san, are you okay?
The case will be fine.
There's something off about him.