We came to a bunny girl club called the Black
Rabbit Restaurant to meet the old man's client.
But once there...
Asakura Yuri (25)
Employee
What?
You found arsenic in Yuri-san's drink?
Yeah.
I-It was me.
Someone was trying to poison me,
Morooka Gunzo
(50) Rich Man
but Yuri-chan drank it instead.
You're saying Morooka-san was
worried about something?
Yes. That's what his bodyguards
out in the parking lot told me.
Fukamachi Atsufumi (72)
Morooka's Butler
Murakami Sana (28)
Employee
Lately he'd been acting strange.
He'd suddenly lose and gain weight, and was
frequently tripping and injuring himself.
But, Mori-kun...
An injury?
Miyano Clinic
Well, I'm leaving now.
Can I come back if I get hurt again?
No. We don't treat boys who fight.
What?
But if it's an honorable injury suffered while
making up with the friend you fought with,
then I'll at least put a bandage on you.
I see.
So that's how it is.
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
Amuro's memory and a poisoned glass!
The trick is one both telling and surprising!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Unsolved Cocktail Case
(Part Three)
"The Unsolved Cocktail Case, Part Three!"
Excuse me, Detective Takagi.
Yes?
I found a fake nail.
I thought it might be Yuri-san's.
It has lilies on it.
Oh, yeah. That's one of
Yuri-chan's fake nails.
Where did you find it?
The thing is, I seem to have
stepped on it somewhere.
It was stuck to the bottom of my boot.
That's why it's so damaged. Sorry.
It must've come off when Yuri-san collapsed.
It couldn't be helped.
Hey, miss.
Does Yuri-san always wear those fake nails?
Yeah, she does.
I suggested she wear some
different ones sometimes,
but she insisted it was her trademark.
Really?
Today has been an awful day.
Awful how?
I unfortunately stepped
on Yuri-san's fake nail,
and I dropped my wallet at some point.
Your wallet?
Yeah, but apparently Amuro-san
found it in front of the bathroom.
Amuro-san did?
What about me?
Nothing.
Well, you couldn't help stepping on
a fake nail that fell on the floor.
It's not like we're walking around with
magnifying glasses, Sherlock Holmes-style.
That's it.
They could've used that.
That's why the culprit was able
to poison Yuri-san's glass.
They used her fake nails as a target.
How many times do I have
to tell you, Inspector?
It's true that I passed by Yuri-chan
while she was holding her glass...
Excuse me, coming through.
But it was only for a moment.
I couldn't have poisoned her glass.
I couldn't have poisoned it either.
I just bumped into her
and spilled wine on her.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't have time to poison her glass.
I wasn't wearing my glasses when
she set her glass on the table.
I-I'm sorry.
It suddenly starting ringing
while I was checking my messages.
Even if I wanted to poison her glass,
I didn't know which one was hers.
So why don't you let us go so we
can visit her in the hospital?
I'm worried about her.
I understand your concern,
but you're just a customer.
Why are you so worried?
B-Because... I'm a regular of hers.
So you say, but maybe she was
actually pushing for marriage,
and you want to watch the girl you
poisoned out of desperation die?
I-I...
Maybe he wants to go to finish her off.
Are you talking about yourself?
If she dies, you'll become
the restaurant's top earner.
Then the restaurant will
pay you a big bonus, right?
So, what?
Are you saying I poisoned Yuri for that?
I heard from Yuri-chan...
I heard you're struggling to pay for
your seriously ill father's surgery!
Didn't I tell ya?
Don't worry 'bout the money.
Just focus on gettin' better.
I'll do somethin' 'bout the
money for the surgery.
What? At least I'm not an old man who was
trying to pay her to stop contacting him!
Pay her? What are you talking about?
Don't play dumb.
Some of the girls saw your butler
over there trying to pay off Yuri.
Sounds like she turned him down, though.
What's she talking about, Fukamachi-kun?
I, uh...
In any case...
The three of you will remain here
for questioning for a while.
After all, you're the only ones who
could have poisoned Yuri-san's glass.
But, Inspector Megure...
I don't think the rich man did it.
Rich man? You mean Morooka-san?
Yeah.
Why do you think that?
He passed by Yuri-san while heading to
his car parked outside the restaurant
to get his butler's glasses, right?
Yeah.
When we talked to the bodyguards
by his car earlier,
they said the rich man just came with
Kogoro-no-ojisan to get the glasses.
They didn't notice anything strange at all.
Anything strange?
If I poisoned Yuri-san's glass,
I would definitely be checking the
time or glancing at the restaurant,
thinking she must've drunk the poison by now
and there must be a huge commotion
inside the restaurant.
Y-You're right.
The same thing goes for that bunny girl.
Even if she poisoned Yuri-san
when she spilled wine on her,
when Yuri-san covered
her glass with a coaster
and went to the changing room
to change her stained cuffs,
she wandered off somewhere to
answer a call from a customer.
Hello, Adachi-san?
Hello again.
I'm sorry, but we're full right now.
A table should open up in about an hour.
If it were me, I wouldn't
leave, no matter what.
After all, someone else might accidentally
drink from the poisoned glass.
I-I see.
Right?
Don't you agree?
U-Uh, yeah.
Which leaves the man sitting by
Yuri-san's glass the whole time.
It could only have been you,
Fukamachi Atsufumi-san the butler.
Weren't you listening to
what Fukamachi-kun said?
He wasn't wearing his glasses when
she set her glass on the table.
How was he able to identify
her glass and poison it?
Fukamachi-san had something on him
that could substitute for glasses.
What?
Substitute for glasses?
Is that true?
No. I was just checking my
messages on my phone then.
Hear that? He says the only
thing he had was his phone.
Yes, so...
Wow!
Phones are amazing!
Conan-kun, they're in the middle
of an important conversation.
Yeah, but if I use the camera
on the phone and zoom in
I can clearly see you all the
way down to your fingertips.
It's like a magnifying glass.
What?
H-He's right. If you use a phone like this...
You might be able to see without glasses.
Come to think of it, Yuri-san always
wore fake nails with lilies.
You could use those to identify her glass.
B-But Fukamachi-kun wasn't
wearing his glasses
because I happened to step
on them and break them.
That wasn't a coincidence. He planned it.
What?
If he knew you put sauce
on your rolled omelets,
he could've placed the sauce
far enough away from you
that you'd have to take a step to reach it.
By dropping his glasses by your feet
he could make it look like they
were coincidentally stepped on.
He had you step on his glasses
in order to use that trick,
but probably also to distance
you from the crime scene
so suspicion wouldn't fall on you.
However, it didn't pay off.
You passed by Yuri-chan while she was holding
her glass when you went to get the glasses,
and suspicion fell on you anyway.
I-Is that true, Fukamachi-kun?
And after you left the restaurant,
he deliberately triggered his phone's alarm.
He made Yuri-san set her glass on the
table to check for an earthquake report,
used his phone's camera's zoom
function to identify her glass,
and poisoned it.
It's likely he used two separate
phones to sound the alarm
and use the camera's zoom function.
So if you search Fukamachi-san,
you'll probably find two phones on him.
I'm sorry, Fukamachi-san,
but we'll need to search—
There's no need.
I do have two.
I bought a second one and
practiced countless times...
for your late wife.
Y-You poisoned Yuri-chan for my wife?
Yes, so you'd finally open your eyes.
O-Open my eyes?
If more time had passed
since she passed away,
I wouldn't say anything.
But it hasn't even been six months,
and you're already infatuated
with that young girl.
I served your wife since she was a child.
I felt so sorry for her.
I selfishly offered her
money to stay away from you,
but she refused.
With no other choice, I sent
that threatening letter.
But it had absolutely no effect,
so I decided to use force.
I thought if the girl you
were chasing were harmed,
you would stop visiting the club.
Sir.
This is my final request to you.
Please don't make your wife sad anymore.
Fukamachi-kun, you've got it all wrong.
That girl...
Yuri isn't just some girl I'm chasing.
She's your daughter.
Right?
H-His daughter?!
Don't be ridiculous!
Don't tell me it's because they both
put sauce on their rolled omelets.
No.
That's just their taste.
It's unusual, but coincidences do happen.
But the unique way they
hold their chopsticks...
It can't be a coincidence that they both hold
their pointer finger away
from their chopsticks.
When you were young and eloped,
the daughter you had while living in
Tottori for four years was Yuri-san.
If she learned to hold her chopsticks
by copying you as a child,
then it all makes sense.
You lost and gained weight so you'd
have to get your suits tailored.
You began tripping frequently so you'd
tear your suits and have to buy new ones.
It was all to create a reason to go
to the clothing store next door
so you could come here and
see your daughter, wasn't it?
Yeah.
I didn't have to see how she held her chopsticks
to know instantly that she was my daughter.
She looked just like her
mother I eloped with.
And I'm the one who named her Yuri.
I see.
So that's why...
Are you okay, Yuri?!
Yuri!
...he called her Yuri.
Sir, you could've told me.
I couldn't tell you I wanted to see
the daughter I had when I eloped.
Not to you, who was so devoted to my wife.
But...
Besides, my wife and I never had children,
which made it all the more difficult.
But... I may not have known,
but she was your daughter...
What have I done?
What have I done?!
I see.
Thank you for calling.
Goodbye.
What was that?
The hospital called.
Yuri-san has regained consciousness,
and her condition is improving steadily.
That's great!
Good...
I'm so glad.
Fukamachi-kun.
In a little while, let's go see
Yuri together and apologize.
No, sir.
I couldn't face her.
It's all right. She'll forgive
you if you explain why.
After all, she's my daughter.
Sir...
Thank you.
Anyway, I'm surprised you knew I was losing
and gaining weight to see my daughter.
I suppose.
I understand.
When I was a kid, there was
a doctor I wanted to see,
so I'd get injured on purpose
so I could go to her clinic.
Excuse me, Amuro-san.
Yes?
Thank you. I heard you found my wallet.
Oh, that was yours?
Yes.
Was everything still inside?
My cash, my house keys, and
everything else was still inside.
I see.
That's good to hear.
You let your guard down, Akai Shuichi.
I could say the same thing to you...
Bourbon.
Don't be ridiculous.
You lost the moment I saw through
your disguise as Okiya Subaru.
What if I knew you'd try
to sneak in here today?
That you'd make a spare key
and receive orders to
investigate Kudo Shinichi?
Looks like I'll have to pull the
trigger to keep your mouth shut.
You...
Hello. I'm Kudo Yusaku, master of the house.
I'm Yukiko.
Unlike last time, you don't seem
to have brought anyone with you.
Why don't you enjoy a cup
of tea prepared by my wife?
Would you like lemon or milk?
Episode Preview
What are you trying to
catch with that giant net?
Well... Tada!
Welcome to the Village
Operated Insect Man Ranch!!
Insect man ranch?
Welcome!
Seriously?
Kabutoya Restaurant
An insect man?!
The Secret of the Insect Man
The next episode of Conan is
"The Secret of the Insect Man!"
Village Mayor
Next Conan's hint!
The village mayor!
Conan's off next week.
Don't miss the next episode.
Would you like some tea?
Delicious.
I can't believe how good it is.