[ED]
[Eyecatch]
Excuse me, Genta-kun.
I've been wondering...
What?
Those clothes appear to be a traditional
insect hunting outfit, but...
What are you trying to
catch with that giant net?
I wanna know, too.
You guys wanna know?
Well...
Well?
Well... Tada!
Welcome to the Village
Operated Insect Man Ranch!!
Insect man ranch?
Welcome!
Seriously?
So you're trying to catch...
That's right.
I'm going insect man hunting.
It's every man's dream.
Kuronosu Station
Wh-What was that?
That was kind of a creepy sound.
That's the cry of an insect man!
What?
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
An insect man suddenly appears?
A secret world in a mountain village!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Secret of the Insect Man
"The Secret of the Insect Man!"
Kuronosu
Village Office
This way!
Kabutoya Restaurant
Chono Clinic
Kuronosu Village Post Office
Over here!
Gaga Shrine
Past this gate...
...is the insect man ranch?
It's kinda scary.
Let's go.
Yeah!
Okay!
Jeez...
Do Not Enter
This sound...
It's the same as before...
The cry of the insect man!
Aw, shucks.
Of course.
We're sorry!
Hey!
Kuronosu Village Post Office
Kabutoya Restaurant
An insect man?!
Excuse us.
Welcome.
I'm Kabuto Koichi, thirteen years old.
Kabuto Kochi (13)
This is my brother Kabuto Koji. He's seven.
Kabuto Koji (7)
I see...
How proper of you.
So, uh...
I know, I know.
You're wondering why we're dressed like this.
And why the adults of the village are doing
construction work at the village shrine.
Yeah.
It's too much trouble to explain it all,
so let me perform it for you
in a picture-story show.
A picture-story show?
Isn't that kind of a lot of trouble, too?
Creaaak... Slam!
An Accurate History of the Village
Operated Insect Man Ranch Incident
An accurate history of the village
operated insect man ranch incident!
Once upon a time, about one year ago,
an important Japanese government
official came to this village.
Casino
He said, "I shall build a casino and public
bath in the forest surrounding this village."
The adults of the village were overjoyed.
But the village mayor was strongly opposed.
He opposed the idea because in the
forest was the grave of Princess Gaga,
who loved all insects in the world.
However, the important Japanese government
official ignored the village mayor's protests
and went to inspect the forest.
And then...
He fell victim to Princess Gaga's curse
and was attacked by a giant moth!
The frightened official fled,
and the plans to construct the casino
and public bath were put on hold.
Casino
The village mayor decided to build
an insect man ranch instead.
The insect man ranch is an amusement park
where children dress in insect costumes.
The village mayor paid for these
costumes out of his own pocket.
I see.
When the children heard the
news, they were overjoyed.
But the adults of the village
were strongly opposed.
The village mayor decided
to give up on his plan.
How sad.
But later, after retiring
from being the village mayor,
he bought up the forest
with his retirement pay,
Do Not Enter
put up "Do Not Enter" signs, and
began construction with bulldozers.
What? Isn't that where we just were?
Yes.
That's when the former mayor
came to this restaurant.
Kabutoya Restaurant
The moment he ordered our famous katsu bowl,
the former mayor suddenly died.
What?!
The story's moving too fast!
But this is a work of non-fiction.
It may be non-fiction, but...
Right?
But then!
Unbelievably, a map showing the
location of Princess Gaga's treasure
was found in the former mayor's pocket.
We told you, you're moving too fast.
You need to establish more foreshadowing.
I can't follow the story.
The truth was, the former mayor
was excavating the forest
so he could keep Princess Gaga's
treasure all for himself.
Really?
When the adults of the village heard this,
they became obsessed with Princess Gaga's
treasure, and they began excavating the forest.
Meanwhile, the children who
the former mayor betrayed
were unable to give up on their
dream of an insect man ranch,
so they wear insect costumes and,
while the adults remain obsessed
with Princess Gaga's treasure,
do an admirable job looking after things
in their absence, if I say so myself.
The End
And they lived happily ever after.
How?
There's nothing happily
ever after about that.
Is that picture-story really true?
Yes, of course. After all...
Accurate History
It's an accurate history.
I'm kinda hungry.
I know.
Let's have some of the famous katsu bowls
that appeared in the picture-story.
Yeah.
I want an eel bowl.
I'm sorry.
As you can see, there are no adults here.
That kind of dish is beyond
what we can prepare.
What can you serve, then?
We can boil instant ramen.
Free of charge, of course.
Fine, then. I'll have ramen, then.
Me, too.
What about you, Conan-kun?
Huh? Oh.
I'm not hungry yet, so I'm
going to go for a walk.
Then we'll have three ramens, please.
Coming right up!
That's three orders of ramen!
"Casino and public baths
construction plans canceled."
"Mayor of Kuronosu Village retires."
Something's not right.
Did the mayor really say he'd
open an insect man ranch
so he could keep Princess
Gaga's treasure to himself?
Not only that, but he even paid for costumes
for the village's children out of his own pocket.
Then there's the cursed giant moth that
chased the government official away.
Sorry to interrupt your meal.
When you eat here,
you can rent an insect
costume free of charge.
Would you like to do that?
Costumes?
Free of charge?
Insect?
Costumes?
That's it. Maybe...
Kuronosu Village Post Office
Excuse me.
Excuse me!
Seta Mitsuo (10)
Huh? Oh, welcome.
I'd like to see a record of deliveries
made to the late former mayor.
That should be in those records over there.
Thanks.
Records
One year ago... One year ago...
Found it.
Kuronosu Village Mayor
Murano Chosuke-sama
Halloween Moth Costume
I knew it.
In other words, the late former
mayor wore this moth costume
and waited for the officials
to come inspect the forest.
Murano Chosuke
Mayor
Yes, yes!
Moth!
It's the curse of Princess Gaga!
So the mayor was behind
Princess Gaga's curse.
Was it really to keep
her treasure to himself?
Excuse me.
What did you think of my cicada impression?
Nice.
Kuronosu Village Post Office
Kabutoya Restaurant
Thank you!
Dressing like this is kind of exciting.
What?
Me, too.
Huh?
Dressing like this is kind of exciting.
In that case... me, too.
Chono Clinic
Excuse me.
Do you work at this clinic?
Yes.
I'm the only daughter
of this clinic's owners.
Chono Masako, eleven years old,
Capricorn, blood type AB.
Chono Masako (11)
I'd like to ask you about
the late former mayor.
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
Patient information is confidential.
I can't discuss it with you.
Of course not.
But...
I might accidentally mention
something while examining you.
Besides, you're kind of cute.
Chono Clinic
What? It was cancer?
The former mayor died of cancer?
That's right. It was pretty advanced, too.
I heard from Daddy that he had only
a year left by the time he retired.
Did he know?
Of course he knew.
You've got a lot of cholesterol in
your brain from thinking too hard.
You'll need a shot.
What?
Excuse me, Genta-kun and Ayumi-chan.
I know you're excited
about being insect people,
but it's dangerous for us to
enter an off-limits forest.
Mantis!
Huh?
Ladybug!
What?
Yeah!
Hey, wait.
Wait for me!
The former mayor knew he
didn't have long to live.
So why did he spend his retirement pay to
keep Princess Gaga's treasure to himself?
He even distributed costumes to the children
and lied about opening an insect man ranch.
Wait a minute. Does Princess
Gaga's treasure even exist?
Kuronosu
Village Office
Excuse me.
What happened?
W-Well, I put on this spider costume,
so I thought I'd practice making
spiderwebs, but then I slipped.
H-Help me.
Give me a second.
Kuronosu
Village Office
Fly, fly.
Mos-qui-to.
Fly.
Fly, fly.
Thank you for helping me.
I'm Kusuda Morio, eleven years old.
Kusuda Morio (11)
My father works here at the village office.
Do you know if there's a book
here on the village's history?
That bookshelf over there
contains the grade school teacher's
research on the village's history.
Found it.
History of Kuronosu Village
This is it.
Did you find it?
Yeah.
According to legend,
the grave of the noble Princess Gaga once
existed in the forest surrounding the village.
It was a large keyhole-shaped tomb.
Circular Back
Outer Levee - Moat - Front Section
It's not here.
Huh? What's not there?
There's no mention of
Princess Gaga's treasure.
Then why did the mayor buy up the forest?
What was the construction work for?
And then there's the treasure map
the mayor had on him when he died.
Did you hear something?
I heard something coming
from the village shrine.
Help, Conan-kun!
I told you it was dangerous
to enter an off-limits forest!
But Mitsuhiko-kun the dragonfly.
What?
It's only natural for an insect
person to want to enter the forest.
Ayumi the ladybug is right.
Thank you, Genta-kun the praying mantis.
Mitsuhiko the dragonfly, there's
something wrong with you.
What?
Genta-kun! Ayumi-chan!
Oh, no.
Wait...
Why are they wearing costumes?
You kids dressed as insect people so you could
steal Princess Gaga's treasure, didn't you?
No! We just wanted to enjoy
the forest as insect people.
Liar!
Where are you kids from?
Beika City.
The city? Then you can't be trusted!
No!
You're perverts!
Um, Genta-kun the praying mantis.
What is it, Mitsuhiko the dragonfly?
I don't think that makes them perverts.
What are they, then? Do you
know, Ayumi the ladybug?
I think it's called... pre...
Yes, it begins with pre...
Pre...?
Pre-ju-diced.
Yes, that's it!
Conan-kun!
You idiots!
There's another one! Get him!
Guys, run!
Don't let them escape!
This way!
Come down from there! Or do
you want us to drag you down?
What should we do?
Conan-kun?
Hey.
What should we do? We can't escape.
I see. So that's how it is.
Guys, calm down and listen to me!
Princess Gaga's treasure doesn't exist!
Impossible!
Don't lie to us!
To prove it, there's no mention of the
treasure in the village's historical documents!
Then why did the mayor buy up the forest?
To make an insect man ranch.
What?
The mayor tried to build the insect
man ranch you all opposed by himself.
But then he learned he wouldn't live to
see its completion because he had cancer.
So the mayor came up with a plan.
He spread the rumor that he was trying to keep
Princess Gaga's non-existent treasure to himself,
and made sure the fake treasure map
would be discovered after his death.
Were there detailed excavation
instructions written on the map?
Y-Yeah, almost obnoxiously detailed.
And that's the result of following those
obnoxiously detailed excavation instructions.
The mayor didn't just leave behind the
treasure map and excavation instructions.
That's the tomb of Princess Gaga,
who loved all insects.
They were plans to build
a keyhole-shaped tomb.
He probably left it up to
you to fulfill his dream
of building an insect man ranch.
The train sure is late.
Yeah.
Anyway, Genta-kun...
That outfit...
Just how much do you like it?
Doesn't it seem strange for an insect
man to be carrying a bug catching net?
No.
It's very strange.
There's nothing strange
about it. After all...
After all?
After all, insect men...
Insect men?
Insect men go people hunting!
What?!
Episode Preview
It seems the victim Kadowaki Eiji-san
was abusing his mother Yasuko-san daily.
There's no domestic violence in our family!
That's just an irresponsible rumor!
What? Their son was killed?
But I didn't do it!
The Mystery-Solving Water Taxi
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Mystery-Solving Water Taxi, Part One!"
Next Conan's hint!
All You Can Eat & Drink
Three Hours ¥3330
All You Can Eat & Drink!!
Nebada Brewery
Hint, hint!
All you can eat & drink!
The bug episode is over already?
Don't miss the next episode.
Why?
Vermin verm-end!
One eel bowl.