So there was nothing left behind that
would help us identify the culprit.
Their motive was probably a grudge.
They hit him once in the
head with a metal pipe.
You again, Mori-kun?
I just happened to be passing by,
and it seemed like there was a case.
And this kid insisted we take a look.
Anyway, are they the victim's
surviving family members?
Yeah.
We had them come to confirm
the identity of the body.
His mother Kadowaki Yasuko-san,
Kadowaki Yasuko (63)
Former Grade School Teacher
and his older brother Kadowaki Yuichi-san.
Kadowaki Yuichi (28)
Eldest Kadowaki Son
Government Office Employee
Mom, keep it together.
The father died five years ago.
The three of them were living together.
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
A chance encounter with
yet another assault case!
The surprising true face
of a troubled family!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Mystery-Solving Water Taxi
(Part One)
"The Mystery-Solving Water Taxi, Part One!"
The victim was Kadowaki Eiji-san, twenty-three
years old, who lives down the way.
Kadowaki Eiji (23)
Kadowaki Second Son
Unemployed
He was killed last night around ten.
According to his mother,
the victim went out to
drink yesterday evening.
He was probably attacked on his way home.
So unaware of what happened,
his family was waiting for
the victim to return home.
No.
Last night, his older brother Yuichi-san
was staying at a hotel in the city
to work on some documents.
Apparently he works as an
official in Kasumigaseki.
For the Chuo government office, huh?
So he's an elite.
Inspector Megure! Oh, Mori-san and Conan-kun.
Well? How did it go?
Right.
The victim Kadowaki Eiji-san didn't have a
very good reputation in the neighborhood.
Since he dropped out of
college three years ago,
he hasn't been able to hold down
a job and wanders the area.
Last Friday, he got drunk and
argued with a bar employee.
He spent the night in jail.
We also found two interesting
pieces of information.
Which are?
The first is passers-by reported
that several days ago,
a well-built man in his thirties appeared
to be watching the Kadowaki family,
as though investigating them.
He was also questioning the neighbors
about the Kadowaki family.
Considering the victim's reputation...
It's possible he had some trouble
with that man and incurred his wrath.
Got it.
Keep trying to figure out who that man is.
Yes, sir.
What's the other piece of information?
According to the neighbors, it
seems the victim Kadowaki Eiji-san
was abusing his mother Yasuko-san daily.
What?
Furthermore, the older brother Yuichi-san
would always stop his brother's
explosive violence.
I see.
So the victim was the problem
child of the Kadowaki family.
Yeah, but...
That woman seems genuinely sad.
They say the worse a child is,
the more you love them.
Indeed.
But if that's the case,
we'll have to question
the older brother again.
N-No!
There's no domestic violence in our family!
That's just an irresponsible rumor!
Besides, what does that have
to do with Eiji's murder?
Kadowaki Yuichi-san,
I'm sorry, but could we
talk to you at the station?
Y-You think I killed Eiji?
N-No! Yuichi would never do that!
Didn't I just tell you?
I was working all last night!
Please calm down, Kadowaki-san.
I know. Around ten, I ran
into a woman at the hotel.
She was extremely drunk.
In any case, find her.
Then this will all become clear.
No. Yuichi would never...
MPD Beika Police Station
Are you listening?
I would never do something
as stupid as kill a person!
I see. So, what about
Eiji-san's domestic violence?
It's not true.
Your father died five years ago, didn't he?
What about it?
According to your neighbors, your mother
has been frequently injured since then.
It's a coincidence.
And two years later, Eiji-san
dropped out of college.
You managed to protect your mother until then,
but after that, you couldn't handle it anymore.
This is nonsense.
Furthermore, you've been
busy with work lately,
so you've been out of the house a lot.
And around that same time, your mother's
injuries became more frequent.
I didn't do it.
If you didn't do something about Eiji,
he might do something
that couldn't be undone.
I didn't do it.
So in order to protect your mother...
You had no choice.
I didn't do it.
But...
He's become totally stubborn.
I didn't do it.
Come in.
Inspector Megure, a moment.
What is it?
Well, actually...
We went to canvas the hotel
Yuichi-san was staying at.
What? You found her?
Yes. She's still staying at the hotel.
Beika Business Hotel
According to her...
Ow.
Excuse me.
It's all right. I wasn't
looking where I was going.
Um, here.
The time displayed on the phone she
picked up was approximately ten.
Additionally, the hotel employee who
happened to pass by witnessed the scene.
So he has multiple people
backing up his alibi.
Yes, sir.
So I can leave now, right?
My alibi has been verified.
I'm terribly sorry.
We'll give you a ride home.
No, thank you. More importantly...
I'll never forget the humiliation I suffered
while being treated like a murder suspect.
Clear the way, please.
Of course.
We came up empty.
Yeah, but it's for the best.
Indeed.
It would be tragic if one brother killed
the other out of concern for his mother.
Anyway, if we were wrong about him...
Yeah. It's the guy Takagi is after.
Chiba, get in touch with Takagi.
Yes, sir.
The well-built man in his thirties.
This guy.
Yeah. This is the guy.
It's definitely him.
He was asking around about Eiji-san.
Excuse me, but could I borrow this video?
Sure. I'll get it ready for you.
Thank you.
Hello? Oh, Chiba.
I just finished checking some convenience
store security camera footage for the man's face.
I'm about to bring it to the family.
This is him.
Oh?
This is Takase-kun.
What? You know him?
Who is he?
His name is Takase Rintaro-kun.
He was my student back when
I taught grade school.
Your old student?
Is this him, then? Did he kill Eiji?
No. Impossible.
We don't know that yet.
I was treated as a suspect
because of this man.
W-We still don't know if he did it yet.
I don't think he did.
What?
Rintaro-kun was rowdy and
caused a lot of trouble.
But at heart, he was a good kid.
He's not someone who could've
killed another person.
I see.
Right? Why would Rintaro-kun kill Eiji?
He has no reason to.
So, have you met with Takase-san recently?
Yes, last week at the
hosp—in the neighborhood.
What? Did you exchange addresses
or contact information then?
No.
He just said he was working at a
construction site near Hinode Pier.
Takase Rintaro (32)
Construction Site Worker
Takase-san.
Huh?
You're Takase Rintaro-san, correct?
Graduated from Haido Elementary School One.
What if I am?
We're the police. Could we have
a few minutes of your time?
Sure. Wait for me at the pier.
I'll go ask my foreman for his permission.
He wasn't even surprised that
the police suddenly showed up.
He was smirking.
And he didn't even ask why we were here.
He must've been expecting the police to come.
The water taxi for Asakusa is departing.
Kadowaki Yasuko-sensei?
Yeah, of course I remember her.
I was a rowdy kid.
She scolded me all the time.
Honestly, I hated her.
But that was twenty years ago.
You've been asking around the neighborhood
about the Kadowaki family recently.
I think it was last week that I ran into her.
I wanted to know how she was doing.
I felt nostalgic.
Who suddenly feels nostalgic
about someone they hated?
Huh?
Takase-san, did you know that
Kadowaki Yasuko-san's younger son
Kadowaki Eiji-san was killed last night?
What? Her son was killed?
We came to talk to you as
part of the investigation.
I see.
So, Takase-san, where were
you at ten last night?
I knew it. You think I did it, don't you?
But if I wanted revenge, wouldn't I
go after Kadowaki-sensei directly?
Why would I kill her son?
A parent's greatest treasure is their
children, no matter how old they are.
Maybe you wanted to make her sad
by taking the life of her son.
I see. The police have put
a lot of thought into this.
How informative.
But I didn't do it!
Last night around ten, I was
in the middle of a three hour
all you can drink session in Nebada.
What?
Oh, I remember him well.
Three Hours ¥3330
All You Can Eat & Drink!!
Nebada Brewery
He was sitting in that corner.
He was facing the wall and kept
shouting about fighting spirit.
Spirit, spirit!
Ten katsu skewers and a large beer!
He probably went to the bathroom,
but aside from that, he was eating
and drinking the whole time.
Do you know what time that was?
I think it was three hours
starting just after eight.
Would you like to check our security cameras?
They're only installed
at the entrance, though.
You said around eight, right?
Yeah. He's here.
It's this guy in the loud Hawaiian shirt.
That's definitely Takase.
The time is 8:01 PM.
And three hours later...
He's leaving the restaurant after 11.
What? He has an alibi?
Yes, sir.
We were able to confirm that he was at a bar
in Nebada from eight to 11, just like he said.
I see.
I told you so.
I didn't do it.
It seems that way. I'm sorry.
But then who did?
How would I know?
Isn't it your job to figure that out? Right?
Mr. Inspector.
Well, I'm leaving now.
Good luck with your job.
Wait a minute.
Megure here.
What? A fire at the
Kadowaki family residence?
I don't believe it.
It's completely destroyed.
What about them? Where's the Kadowaki family?
Over there.
They're at that ambulance.
Yuichi-san.
You're all right.
What about your mother?
They just took her away.
They're going to determine
the cause of death.
Sensei...
So that was your destiny.
Hey, what's so funny?
Damn it.
Sometimes there's nothing you can do.
Well, Inspector, I'll be leaving now.
Yuichi-san.
I'm terribly sorry to ask at this time,
but could you tell us what happened?
For your late mother's sake, too.
All right.
Haido West Third Street Police Box
When the fire broke out, I was sleeping
in my room on the second floor.
Perhaps it's because I'd been questioned by
the police, but I had a terrible headache.
So by the time I realized something
was amiss, it was a sea of fire.
Mom! Are you there, Mom?!
It was all I could do to save myself.
It may be a coincidence, but I can't believe
he lost his mother right after his brother.
About that...
Yuichi-san, can you think of anyone
who might have resented you
and the rest of the Kadowaki family?
Another one of your family
members died today.
Don't you think it's too
much of a coincidence?
He's not wrong.
But, Inspector...
It's a possibility. We should confirm it.
Yes, but...
Well, Yuichi-san?
No. I can't think of anyone like that.
I know what he said, but check out everyone
associated with the Kadowaki family tomorrow.
See if anyone hated that family.
Yes, sir.
What is it, Mori-kun?
You don't like it?
No, that's not it.
In any case, Inspector, we should get going.
All right.
Let's go, kid.
Okay.
That Takase guy definitely did it.
What? But when the fire happened...
The fire is unrelated.
I'm talking about Eiji-san's murder.
That fire was just an
unfortunate coincidence.
It's true that his behavior was unnatural.
He wasn't surprised at all that
the police suddenly showed up.
Or when he heard Kadowaki
Eiji-san was murdered.
What? Her son was killed?
It seemed so deliberate.
Yeah.
He knew that Eiji-san had been murdered.
Most likely, yes.
Nebada Brewery
Three Hours ¥3330
All You Can Eat & Drink!!
Nebada Brewery
But he has an alibi.
He was taken off the
suspect list as a result.
He must've used some kind of trick.
I, Mori Kogoro, swear on my
name that I'll expose him.
But I don't think the Kadowaki family
residence fire was a total coincidence.
But if that's true, then these two cases...
How in the world are they connected?
Episode Preview
9:08 to 10:35.
That's about an hour and a half.
You were just saying how I could've
killed him, too, weren't you?
What proof do you have that I did it?
You get in trouble at school, too?
What?
So that's how it is.
Which means the fire...
The Mystery-Solving Water Taxi
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Mystery-Solving Water Taxi, Part Two!"
Fireworks
Next Conan's hint!
Fireworks!
Don't miss the next episode.
These two cases...
There's just no connection between them.
As if obscured by smoke...
The truth is hazy.