A man named Kadowaki Eiji-san was murdered.
Eiji-san was a man with a bad reputation
who was often taken into police custody.
He also allegedly abused his mother,
while his older brother Kadowaki
Yuichi-san protected her.
He was suspected of killing
his younger brother
to protect his mother from
his repeated acts of violence,
but his alibi was verified,
and Yuichi-san was released.
Meanwhile, another suspect emerged.
This is Takase-kun.
Takase Rintaro-san, one of Yasuko-san's
students from when she was a teacher.
Kadowaki Yasuko-sensei?
Yeah, of course I remember her.
I was a rowdy kid.
She scolded me all the time.
Honestly, I hated her.
But that was twenty years ago.
What? He has an alibi?
Yes, sir.
I see.
I told you so.
I didn't do it.
Well, I'm leaving now.
Good luck with your job.
Wait a minute.
Megure here.
What? A fire at the Kadowaki family residence?
That night, there was a fire at
the Kadowaki family residence,
and the mother Yasuko-san was killed.
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
A complicated family situation
and a former student and suspect.
With a fire layered on top of that,
the truth is hard to see.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Mystery-Solving Water Taxi
(Part Two)
"The Mystery-Solving Water Taxi, Part Two!"
I told the cops who came
yesterday about that customer.
Three Hours ¥3330
All You Can Eat & Drink!!
Nebada Brewery
He sat in that corner seat for the
three-hour all you can eat and drink.
You're sure it was from eight to eleven?
Yeah. We even checked the security cameras.
Hey.
Which side was Takase-san sitting on?
I think it was that side.
What does it matter?
So his back was facing the other customers.
We should check the security
cameras next, right?
Yeah. Can we?
Sure.
That's definitely Takase.
And the time is 8:01.
Next let's check three hours later at 11.
Yeah.
Hey, can't you make it go any faster?
Yeah, but...
What?
Oh, sorry. Wrong person.
Jeez.
Their builds looked similar.
Idiot.
He's wearing totally different clothes.
He's got glasses, too.
Look closely.
Okay. Huh?
What now?
Look. He came back out
in less than ten minutes.
It seemed like he was meeting someone.
He checked inside the shop,
but no one was there.
He said he'd come again and left immediately.
He came back about an hour and a half
later, but there was still no one there.
He said he got the date wrong and left.
Huh. Sounds like a real scatterbrain.
Right? Isn't it funny?
Come to think of it, we got an even
stranger customer the other day.
Look at this.
What? Did you find something?
Yeah.
This is the second time that person came,
and this is when he left.
What about it?
I'll play it again. Watch his face.
This is when he came after nine.
You can see his face, right?
And this is when he left. He's facing
downwards so you can't see it.
This is when he came back
an hour and a half later.
You can't see his face clearly here either.
And this is the last time he left.
You can clearly see his face,
and he seems to have a satisfied smile.
Isn't it strange for him to be satisfied
if he got the day of his meet-up wrong?
When did he first leave and return?
He first left at 9:08 and came back at 10:35.
9:08 to 10:35.
That's about an hour and a half.
Hey.
From here to the crime scene...
It's about a thirty minute walk.
So that's how it is.
Three Hours ¥3330
All You Can Eat & Drink!!
Nebada Brewery
Hello, Inspector?
He had an accomplice.
Yes, the store's security cameras caught him.
Yes.
I'll tell the waiter to expect you.
Bye.
Now we just need evidence
that Takase-san did it.
We don't need evidence.
If we tell him we've disproved
his alibi, he'll give it up.
Safety First
Later.
Takase Rintaro (32)
Construction Site Worker
Is that...?
What's he doing here?
Damn it.
The water taxi for Asakusa is departing.
Sucks for the great detective.
So you thought you got away.
The fact that you fled when
you saw me proves it.
Takase Rintaro-san, you're the culprit.
I fled?
I just wanted to try riding the water taxi.
You only have forty more minutes to crack jokes.
Then this boat will arrive in Asakusa.
Yes, Inspector. Mori here.
Yes. I'd like to turn over
Kadowaki Eiji-san's murderer.
Could you come to the water
taxi pier in Asakusa? Yes.
I'll tell you more then. Bye.
The alibi you've been relying
on to prove your innocence
is easily constructed if you have,
for example, a friend to help you.
Bingo.
You used a person with a build
similar to yours as a stand-in.
Ten katsu skewers and a large beer!
Welcome.
I'm meeting a friend. Can I look inside?
Go right ahead.
You swapped places with
your friend in the bathroom,
Spirit, spirit!
Looks like he's not here. I'll be back.
Okay.
left the store, and murdered Eiji-san.
Then you returned to the restaurant and
swapped places with your friend again,
creating your fake alibi.
Unfortunately, this is the
end of the line for you.
Right. There's a fireworks show today.
Listen, Takase-kun.
It would be best if you came
clean and turned yourself in.
Where's the proof?
Not good.
You were just saying how I could've
killed him, too, weren't you?
What proof do you have that I did it?
Well...
I think I'll go have a beer downstairs,
until the great detective
remembers what proof he has.
I told you we needed evidence.
Shut up.
He's not getting away, damn it.
Jeez...
But now that we've started this,
we have to do whatever it takes to get him.
A man as kind-hearted
as me could never kill a man.
You called yourself rowdy just yesterday.
Hey, mister.
What?
Let's let him talk.
He might accidentally reveal something.
Damn it. I'm having a beer, too.
Hey.
Give yourself up and confess already.
But I didn't do it. I can't confess to anything.
In that case...
Who do you think killed
Kadowaki Eiji-san, and why?
How should I know?
He probably got on someone's bad side.
I heard he was one hopeless dude.
Really? So Eiji-san wasn't a very good person.
But since the good brother
was around, Kadowaki-sensei—
I gotta use the bathroom.
So he knew.
But if that's true, isn't it strange?
What's strange?
If he wanted to get back
at Kadowaki Yasuko-san,
he would've killed Yuichi-san
instead of Eiji-san.
Hey, mister.
Oh. It's you, kid.
Don't scare me like that.
Were you really that rowdy
when you were a kid?
Yeah, I guess. Bad enough that
my parents abandoned me.
It must've been hard.
Abandoned at home,
yelled at by teachers at school.
You get in trouble at school, too?
What?
Uh, yeah. Sometimes.
Someday you'll understand
what a blessing it is.
I see. So that's how it is.
But why now?
Why after running into her for
the first time in twenty years?
Drink up.
Thanks.
Once you finish that, confess.
You never give up.
I can't confess to something I didn't do.
Come on!
Hey.
You said you ran into
Kadowaki-sensei. Where was that?
She was there when I went to the
orthopedist for my chronic back pain.
She was at the hospital, too.
Full body contusions?
Th-That's right. I accidentally missed
a step on the stairs last night
Kadowaki Yasuko (63)
Former Grade School Teacher
and rolled all the way down.
Accidentally?
I laughed, too.
I couldn't believe that happened
to that careful teacher.
That's it.
I think it was last Saturday.
She must've lied on the spot.
She couldn't tell her former student
that her son was abusing her.
So that's how it is.
Which means the fire...
Wh-What? Th-This bridge...
We just passed Ryogoku Bridge.
The fireworks show grounds are approaching,
so we'll be lowering the lights within the boat.
Damn. Asakusa is getting closer.
Please enjoy the sights from the windows.
A fireworks show, huh? What fun.
Damn it.
Let's go upstairs to watch the fireworks.
Good idea.
We should go upstairs, too.
Yeah, let's.
I'm so excited.
Damn it!
I told the inspector to come.
There's no turning back now.
Too bad, Detective.
Jeez. Who's calling? I'm busy.
Incoming Call
Inspector Megure
I-Inspector Megure?
Crap!
What do I do, what do I do, what do I do?
Yes, hello! Mori here!
Yes. No, of course not.
In just a few more minutes...
Yes.
What? What do you mean?
Damn. That just leaves this.
Takase!
What? Did you find the evidence?
I don't have any.
I'll force it out of you if I have to.
What's gotten into you?
Hey, are you okay?
Takase-san.
You probably thought you were returning
the favor when you killed Kadowaki Eiji-san.
When even your own parents had abandoned you,
Kadowaki Yasuko-san was the only
one who paid you any attention.
You felt indebted to her because of that.
Don't be ridiculous!
Who would feel indebted to that woman?!
All I had for her was hatred!
When you saw her again at the hospital,
you couldn't believe that careful
woman could have done that.
And when you began investigating the
Kadowaki family, you heard a certain rumor.
Yasuko-san was being abused
by her younger son Eiji-san daily,
and her older son Yuichi-san
was trying to protect her.
You had an idea.
Fortunately, Yuichi-san had protected
Yasuko-san from Eiji-san's violence until now.
However, there was no guarantee Yuichi-san
would always be there in the future.
At this rate, Eiji-san might eventually kill her.
Believing that, you...
I told you, I didn't do it!
When you think of it that way,
it explains what you said.
So that was your destiny.
You thought you'd saved her
from her son's violence,
but in the end, she was destined to die.
Isn't that what you meant?
You're making all of this up!
If you're so determined to pin this
on me, bring me the evidence!
Takase-san.
You shouldn't assume rumors are true.
What?
You ran into Kadowaki-sensei
at the hospital last Saturday.
In other words, Kadowaki Yasuko-san
was injured the day before, on Friday night.
But that Friday night, Eiji-san wasn't at home.
Last Friday, he got drunk
and argued with a bar employee.
He spent the night in jail.
But since Yasuko-san was injured
regardless, there's only one explanation.
It was the older brother Yuichi-san who was
abusing his mother Yasuko-san daily,
and it was the younger brother
Eiji-san who was protecting her.
Y-You can't expect me to believe that!
And without Eiji-san to put the
brakes on the situation,
the worst possible outcome occurred.
Yasuko-san's murder at Yuichi-san's hands.
Perhaps he did it for revenge.
Isn't he the one who did it?!
Your former student?!
Yuichi-san couldn't let go of his rage.
Isn't he the one who did it?!
Your former student?!
Th-There's no way. Even the police
said they weren't sure yet.
I don't care about the police!
I'm asking you!
Maybe you didn't teach him well enough!
Because of him, I suffered that humiliation!
Damn it!
After killing his mother, Yuichi-san
set the house on fire to destroy the evidence.
No. That's just your fantasy!
What evidence is there of that?
I just got a call.
When asked about the unnatural way
the fire started during his deposition,
Kadowaki Yuichi-san admitted to it.
He killed his mother and started
the fire to hide the evidence.
No... Then what I did was...
No... No...
Later, Takase Rintaro-san confessed
to Kadowaki Eiji-san's murder.
He was taken away by the police
officers waiting at Asakusa.
The final water taxi from Asakusa
to Hinode Pier is departing.
Huh?
Huh? What?
Hey! Hey, wait!
Mister!
Huh? Fireworks ho! Huh?