[Eyecatch]
How wonderful!
It's like a festival.
They're launching these fireworks to
celebrate Anna-san's birthday, right?
That's amazing.
Anna-san's dog food company Happywow is
experiencing explosive growth right now.
A couple hundred fireworks
are nothing to her.
Kogoro-san!
Anna-san!
Ran-chan, Conan-kun!
Hinomiya Anna (24)
Happywow President
Anna-san!
It's eight already.
Anna-san, we'll be right there!
Congratulations, ma'am.
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
Enami Machiko (31)
Happywow Director
You went through a lot to get here,
but this is the best time of your life.
It's all thanks to you,
Machiko-senpai and VP Inamura.
This is from me.
Inamura Koshiro (45)
Happywow Vice President
It's champagne from your birth year.
Thank you.
I got you something, too.
A present.
What is it?
Wh-Why?
Stop!
Right now at this moment,
light pierces the darkness!
Overcome all limits with
your cool reasoning skills!
A beautiful company president is shot
in a terrifying incident by a
nimble man wearing a black mask!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Poodle and the Shotgun
(Part One)
"The Poodle and the Shotgun, Part One!"
So the culprit suddenly fired
at Anna-san with a shotgun?
Yes. Their only target was the president.
After shooting Anna, they immediately
leapt onto another boat.
They fled in an instant.
Their testimony is accurate.
I witnessed it, too. Not just me.
I saw it, too. So did Conan-kun.
Huh?
Where did that kid go?
Fine scratches on her nails...
What are these?
Hey, kid!
Don't you know you'll get in the way there?
Ow!
Ouch...
Sorry.
Huh? Something smells.
It's dog food.
Dog food, huh?
It's a new product Anna-san's
company will be selling.
In here?
Yes. I heard something.
Dad, be careful.
I've got this.
You said you were Morishima-san, right?
What on earth happened?
Well...
Morishima Sota (22)
Happywow Secretary
I was suddenly hit over the head.
When I came to, I was in there.
Were you invited to Anna's
birthday party as well?
No. I'm Anna's secretary.
I arrived an hour early at
seven to prepare for the party.
I was suddenly struck on the head
while loading luggage into the cabin.
I woke up when I heard the gunshots
and found myself inside the locker.
So you were unconscious until then?
Y-Yes...
Inspector, if no one's seen their face, it
will be impossible to identify the culprit.
No, I know who did it.
That's right. He's the only
one who could have done this.
He?
Hyodo. Hyodo Makoto.
What? Hyodo?
Mori-kun, you know him?
Yes. Hyodo is Anna-san's ex-boyfriend.
He claimed to be a management consultant,
but when I looked into it, I
discovered that he was a conman.
Hyodo Makoto (38)
Anna's Former Boyfriend
A conman?
He offered Anna-san a fake investment offer
and stole close to 50 million from Happywow.
That's not all.
He also owed Anna-san herself
a huge amount of money.
Only the president herself
knew exactly how much he took,
but we repeatedly urged her to
file a proper reimbursement claim.
And now this has happened.
Damn that Hyodo!
He won't get away with this!
Huh?
Takagi.
Yes, sir.
Hey, Morishima-san.
Did you bring the presents for Anna-san, too?
A present?
There was a bottle decorated with
a ribbon and a box on the deck.
VP Inamura and Director Enami
brought those themselves.
The VP got her champagne, and
the director got her a watch.
A watch?
How do you know that?
They're busy people, so I went
to buy their gifts for them.
Both the champagne and the watch
are incredibly high quality.
Are you also the one who brought
the dog food into the cabin?
Yeah. I thought the president
would bring her dog.
Right. Anna-san is always
with her poodle Sally-chan.
But I wonder why she didn't bring her today.
Did Anna-san expect this?
Stop! Stop right there, Hyodo!
You bastard!
How dare you kill Anna-san!
Don't hurt him, Mori-san!
Let go! I'll beat this guy to a pulp!
Wait! I didn't do it!
He's the one who killed Anna!
He?
The vice president Inamura!
He's got a shotgun!
What?
It's true that I own a shotgun.
Skeet shooting is my hobby.
Why did you hide that fact?
I wasn't trying to hide it.
It was stolen recently.
Stolen?
Yes. Three days ago while I was preparing
to go out, along with my entire car.
That gun must have been used in the crime.
But I have nothing to do with the case.
I even filed a robbery report.
I'm sure it's all a ruse.
What?
Or maybe Machiko stole it.
Me?
You've got plenty of motive to kill Anna.
Stop that.
What are you talking about?
You're the one who taught Anna about
business when she was an unsuccessful idol.
Now your positions are reversed.
You were angry and in disbelief
that Anna was the president.
You're lying.
I know everything.
After all, you and I used to date.
What?
You resented Anna because I
dumped you for a younger woman.
You swore you'd kill her someday.
You're making it all up!
You're the one who had a motive to kill Anna!
You owe Anna-san a huge amount of debt.
Maybe you killed her because she
was demanding you repay her.
You're one to talk.
You're the one who benefits most from
Anna's death as the vice president.
What?
Making Anna the president was your idea.
But once the company was on track,
you didn't need her anymore.
She was just in your way.
That's enough!
Anna-san wasn't shot by
Inamura-san or Enami-san!
It was the masked man! In other words, you!
What? Do you have anything to prove that?
Proof?
Uh, well... you see...
See? You're assuming I did it when
you don't even have any evidence.
Hyodo-san, does that mean you have an alibi?
An alibi?
Between seven and eight, the culprit
hid in the cabin of the cruiser
and waited for Anna-san to arrive.
Surely you can prove where
you were during that time.
Seven to eight?
I have no choice. I guess I'll confess.
I knew it. You killed Anna-san.
No. During that time, I was
robbing Anna's apartment.
Robbing her?
It was on a whim.
I had a spare key to Anna's place.
And I knew she was throwing her
birthday party here at eight.
So I went when she'd be away.
I think it was around 7:20.
There was only 30 thousand in cash,
but just as I was leaving with it
I accidentally dropped
my gym membership card.
If you think I'm lying, search her apartment.
Where is Anna-san's apartment?
It's about ten kilometers west
down the coast from here.
It's a fifteen minute drive one way.
Why is he so confident?
This must be the card.
That's Hyodo-san's card.
What? Conan-kun!
I followed you.
It's just like he testified.
Uh, yeah...
Conan-kun, you shouldn't look in there.
Ow!
No, Sally-chan!
I'm beat...
I fell on my butt on the boat,
and then got it bitten by a dog.
What's that?
A pet camera.
It livestreams footage to the owner's phone
so they can check on their pet
while they're out of the house.
So today's video should
be on Anna-san's phone.
If Hyodo's testimony is true, then...
There should be video of him
robbing the house on here.
Someone's coming in.
Hyodo's testimony was right.
We can't see his face.
We don't know that it's Hyodo.
But the time is 7:20.
That's the same time Hyodo said.
This is it.
This is the card.
It's just like Hyodo testified.
You knew she had a pet camera and
dropped your card on purpose.
What are you talking about?
Don't play dumb!
You did it to fabricate your alibi!
You're not the thief in the video!
It's your accomplice pretending to be you!
Accomplice?
If I have an accomplice, why
don't you bring them here?
What?
See? It was impossible for me to kill Anna.
But even if he didn't have an accomplice,
he still could've killed Anna-san.
Morishima-san, weren't you unconscious
inside that locker the whole time?
Yeah...
If he left the boat while
Morishima-san was unconscious
and sped to Anna-san's apartment,
he could've arrived by 7:20.
That's it.
If he broke into her apartment
pretending to rob her,
deliberately dropped his card
so the camera would see it,
and then returned immediately by car,
he could've killed Anna-san by eight.
I see.
Well, Hyodo?
Your alibi has broken down.
Are you sure about that?
It's only possible if Morishima-san
was actually unconscious.
What do you mean, Conan-kun?
I'm sorry.
I wasn't actually unconscious the whole time.
What?
I actually regained consciousness as
soon as I was stuffed into the locker.
I was watching the masked man's
back from inside the locker.
I didn't know what he'd do if he noticed,
so I pretended to be unconscious.
So the culprit was on
the ship the whole time?
Yes. I'm certain of it.
Why didn't you say anything?
I'm sorry.
If I'd raised the alarm then, it's possible
the president wouldn't have been shot.
I let the president die.
I'm surprised you knew Morishima-san
had regained consciousness.
Morishima-san's mouth was covered with tape,
but he wasn't blindfolded.
Maybe the culprit knew that Morishima-san
would wake up immediately
and that he'd stay quiet inside the locker.
In other words, they planned to use
Morishima-san as their alibi from the start.
Most likely.
If he planned all that, it makes
him all the more suspicious.
You're treating me like a suspect
based on suspicion alone?
There's no evidence of any of this!
Detective, his testimony
has made things clear.
The culprit who shot Anna
never left the ship.
I'm the one who robbed her apartment,
and it was someone else who shot Anna.
Detective, I'm admitting to a robbery.
Why don't you arrest me already?
We still need to conduct an
investigation before we arrest you.
We'll question you again tomorrow.
Really?
Fine.
Then I'm leaving for today.
Sally-chan.
What?
Later.
Inspector, it's him.
He's the one who shot Anna-san.
Proof. We need to find proof.
Anna-san was shot with a shotgun
by the masked culprit.
And they're the one who did it.
Episode Preview
It was definitely Hyodo who killed Anna-san.
The question is...
You're certain that this is your gun?
That's definitely mine.
The wood is cracked.
I'm not lying!
They were going to kill me, weren't they?
You're accusing me of being an accomplice?
Sally-chan!
The Poodle and the Shotgun
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Poodle and the Shotgun, Part Two!"
Pet Camera
Next Conan's hint!
A pet camera!
Poodles love Happywow!
Don't miss the next episode.
Ran-neechan, he's eating it.
What?