[OP]
Invited to the Nichiuri TV Building Completion
Commemorative Movie Announcement Event,
we headed out to Osaka.
But during the event,
the brutally murdered body of the
movie's producer was discovered.
Hattori Heiji and I joined the investigation
and identified the culprits,
but they fled using a car parked
in the basement parking lot.
But in the next moment...
The rhythm on my lips is footloose!
The rhythm of my detective
skills is perfect!
People keep dying at the grand event!
What will happen to the film's production?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kaiju Gomera VS Kamen Yaiba
(Interlude)
"Kaiju Gomera VS Kamen Yaiba, Interlude!"
Osaka Police HQ
I see.
Hattori Heizo
Osaka Police Chief
I more or less understand the situation.
And no one else was injured in the explosion?
Otaki Goro
Osaka Police
Division One Inspector
No.
I guess you could call it the silver
lining, thanks to Inspector Ayanokoji.
Ayanokoji Fumimaro
Kyoto Police
Division One Inspector
Wasn't it Mori-san's daughter who was
nearly hit while protecting Kazuha?
Toyama Ginjiro
Osaka Police Chief Detective
We had her examined at the hospital,
and there was nothing wrong with her.
I see. I'm glad she's all right.
Naniwa Police Hospital
You didn't need to stay
with me the whole time.
What are you talking about?
You were nearly hit by a car!
Well, I'm glad nothing happened.
What are the kids doing?
Kazuha-chan's with them.
I think I'll head back to the
investigation headquarters.
You can't. We have a film shoot today.
What?
Film shoot?
Have you determined why
Yonekura-san's car exploded?
We believe it was an explosive made
from an acetone peroxide mixture.
It was in the trunk.
You haven't found the detonator?
Not yet. But the explosive was unstable.
His reckless driving probably bumped it.
And Kouchi died instantly.
I'm truly sorry.
Apologize later.
More importantly, isn't it
about time you explained
what a Kyoto police inspector was
doing at the same crime scene?
Two days ago, there was an accident
on a road near Takaragaike in Kyoto.
The male driver of the car died.
The deceased was a scriptwriter
named Onda Takashi-san.
Never heard of him.
He was a scriptwriter in name only.
Onda Takashi (43)
Scriptwriter
In reality, he was a profligate son who
burned through his parents' wealth.
He had a mansion in Iwakura and two cars.
Apparently he had a comfortable life.
So what were the circumstances of his death?
He and his car were found at the bottom of
a cliff off a mountain road near his home.
The local authorities determined that he
failed to make a turn and that it was an accident.
Kyoto City
Takaragaike Plaza
Was it definitely Onda-san who was driving?
Wasn't the body pretty messed up?
Using his fingerprints that escaped
injury and his dental records,
we were able to confirm it was him.
Yeah, but it doesn't look
like that sharp a turn,
Kyoto City
Takaragaike Plaza
and wouldn't the road have
been familiar to the victim?
How did he get in an accident?
Apparently Onda-san was drunk when he fell.
I see. So the accident was
the result of drunk driving.
But you have a different opinion?
Yes.
He may have been drunk, but there
were hardly any skid marks.
It's hard to believe this
was just an accident.
You think someone messed with his brakes?
It's possible.
But didn't Onda-san have two cars?
That's right. He had a red
and a blue sports car.
Apparently he drove the red one on even
dates and the blue one on odd ones.
What about the day of the accident?
He drove the red one.
What? But it was an odd date two days ago.
The blue car was having mechanical trouble.
That's why he drove the red car two days ago.
Naturally, the blue car really
did have mechanical issues.
But we didn't find any signs
of tampering with the brakes.
If someone tampered with his car, why
did they only tamper with the red car?
If they wanted to kill him as soon as
possible, wouldn't they have done it to both?
You're right.
We get that you have doubts
about the Takaragaike case.
But what's that got to do with you
coming all the way out to Osaka?
The truth is, while investigating Onda-san,
I learned he associated with
Yonekura-san in the past.
I came to ask Yonekura-san about it,
but I arrived after Nichiuri
TV had been locked down.
I could've approached directly,
but I didn't want to make unnecessary
waves, so I restrained myself.
So you were quietly watching us work?
That's not very nice of you.
Forgive me.
I haven't found anything concrete yet.
Hey.
How were Onda-san and Yonekura-san connected?
Right.
Onda-san and Yonekura-san were
once part of the same group
sponsored independent
film screening society.
Did you know about this?
N-No.
Inspector Ayanokoji.
I didn't find Yonekura-san's
name in Onda-san's phone either.
Then why?
Yonekura-san was seen near Onda-san's home.
And while investigating that, you
discovered their past connection.
Things are getting complicated.
Onda-san's case aside, we can't
ignore the bomb that was in the car.
Maybe someone other than those two
was trying to kill Yonekura-san.
There's something I've been wondering.
What is it, kid?
Remember the small scratch on the top
shelf at Yonekura-san's murder scene?
Yeah.
Mihara probably accidentally dropped
the knife while cutting the rope.
Then it must've made a noise, right?
Why didn't Yonekura-san notice that?
Why?
If he noticed the person
on top of the scaffold,
he could've dodged the falling kaiju.
Otaki, go confirm that immediately.
Yes, sir!
What? The knife?
Mihara Yoshito (38)
Nichiuri TV Movie Production
Department Producer
Yeah, I dropped it.
It made a surprisingly loud sound.
I thought he'd notice, and that I was screwed.
Yonekura-san didn't notice?
Nope.
I don't know why, but he was
glued to his phone screen.
He kept saying "damn that
Onda" in a real tense voice.
Is that true? Did he really say Onda?
Yeah.
Tell me. Is Kouchi really dead?
I can't believe it.
Was it really a coincidence that you
tried to steal Yonekura-san's car?
Of course! Besides, Kouchi said he knew
where the spare key to his car was hidden.
I see.
I heard the car was rigged with a bomb.
Was someone else trying to kill Yonekura?
That's currently under investigation.
Seriously?
Then what was the point of what we did?
Yonekura-san was probably
looking at an online news site.
Everyone was covering the car
that went up in flames in Kyoto.
But it could be a coincidence.
Maybe he was just shocked to see an article
about the death of an old acquaintance.
Inspector Otaki, where were
Yonekura-san's belongings?
They were left in the staff
room on the sixth floor.
Could we look at those now?
I've got a list of the items.
His plane ticket to Bangkok,
his passport, and...
What is it?
He had six newspapers,
including sports papers.
Accidental Fall Leaves One Dead
The Truth Behind the Accident
Takaragaike Accidental Fall
Caused By Drunk Driving
They're all from the day of the incident.
Smells fishy.
It's possible he wanted to know more about
Onda's case and bought everything he could find.
Sounds like we'll have to
re-investigate our case.
We'd appreciate your help.
Understood.
I'll ask my forensics team
to reexamine Onda-san's car.
Thank you.
Hello?
Conan-kun, what are you doing?
Heiji, what are you doing?
The film shoot has started!
Crap! I forgot!
Osaka Castle Park
Okay, everyone!
We'll now begin the rehearsal.
Please imagine a kaiju's head
at the end of that pole.
What face should I make when I run?
Don't ask me.
I don't think you need to
think about it that hard.
You're right. After all, no one's
actually been chased by a kaiju before.
You'll be running that way.
How you want to act while
fleeing is up to you.
But please don't smile or behave
strangely in an attempt to stand out.
Good grief. This is a lot of work.
Let's start with the rehearsal.
Suemura Ryohei (51)
Daiho Films Employee
Gomera
It's a kaiju!
Help!
Ayumi-chan! This way!
I-It's a kaiju! Heiji, I'm scared!
I-It's okay! Come with me!
I can't believe he's this bad at acting...
Conan-kun!
Wait a minute. Isn't this...?
How was my fleeing?
It was a brilliant performance.
What about me?
You guys did great.
Do exactly that when we film.
All right!
You were good, but your
movements were a little stiff.
Try to relax a little more.
You were great, too, especially
how you carried the child.
Oh, and I'm sorry.
Huh?
Could you try a little harder?
Sure...
Gomera
Okay, we're ready to film.
Hei-chan, we've got another case.
This is crazy.
I can't believe there was only one
victim in an explosion this large.
The company that owned this warehouse
went bankrupt a year ago.
They haven't found a buyer since
then, so it's been abandoned.
So who got caught in the explosion?
Suemura Ryohei-san of the Daiho
film production department.
What? Daiho Films?
Suemura-san was looking for a warehouse to
use in the filming of "Gomera VS Yaiba."
He came to take pictures to study the place.
Have you determined what the explosive was?
We're not certain yet,
but according to forensics, they
most likely used acetone peroxide.
In other words, just like the
bomb that blew up Kouchi.
We believe it was the same substance.
I see.
So the two bombings are connected.
Which means...
My, my. How could you exclude me?
You caught me.
Did the Kyoto police figure anything out?
Yes.
The results of our re-investigation
have increased the probability
that Onda-san's death
was a murder by bombing.
In other words, a bomb was rigged in
his car, just like Yonekura-san's.
Which means these are three
serial bombing cases.
Then the Osaka and Kyoto Police will have
to form a joint investigation headquarters.
We'd be happy to have the help.
I see.
Then Dad won't be back for a while.
He'll probably be stationed at the
joint investigation headquarters.
Anyway...
Kamen Yaiba Café
Kamen Yaiba
What are we doing here?
Kazuha-chan insisted on coming.
Good grief. But...
I guess it's fine since
that's so interesting.
Heiji, what are you doing? Come over here.
What? You want me to stand with you?
Of course!
It's Kamen Yaiba!
Yeah? So, what?
Strike a pose. I'm taking the picture.
Does Kazuha-neechan seem different to you?
It's love.
He's so cool! So cool!
Hey, you're freaking out Yaiba-san.
Ran-chan, take some with me.
I'll be back.
Haibara, there's something
I want you to look into.
Lately I feel like I've been demoted
from your partner to your errand girl.
Okuda Mansion
Okuda-san, we heard you once sponsored
an independent film screening society.
Yeah, I did.
It went well for a while, but things have
been terrible for the last few years.
I quit about three years ago.
Do you recognize these three men?
I remember them well.
They were involved about twenty years ago.
They called themselves Team Yonekura.
They had interesting ideas.
Yonekura was the idea man and
came up with all kinds of plans.
Onda was the aspiring scriptwriter,
and Suemura was the aspiring director.
Could you tell us more about that?
Kyoto-Osaka Serial Bombing Investigation HQ
According to Okuda-san, there was another man
who worked with Yonekura-san and the others.
Ishizawa Katsuji (38)
Kyoto-Osaka Serial Bombing Investigation
Key Witness
Born in Kyoto
Engineering School Graduate
Bachelor's Degree Acquired
Member of Team Yonekura
Ishizawa Katsuji-san,
an engineering graduate.
Engineering. In other words, he has the
scientific knowledge to build a bomb.
Apparently he was dexterous and came up with
all kinds of ideas for props to use in movies.
Where is he now?
His whereabouts are unknown.
He changes jobs and residences all the time.
Excuse me. Hello?
But isn't it a bit much to treat him as a
suspect just for being an engineering graduate?
According to Okuda-san, Ishizawa-san
was bullied by the other three.
They threatened him into building
props and performing odd jobs.
Ultimately, he gave up on finding
a job in the movie industry.
I see. That would be a motive.
We've found Ishizawa.
He's got an uncle in Sakai,
and he ended up at his house.
What about his uncle?
He died last year.
So he's living alone.
According to the neighbors,
he doesn't have a steady job.
Inspector!
What's all the fuss?
We found fingerprints.
We found Ishizawa's fingerprints on
the bomb at Suemura's murder scene.
What?
Shall we head there immediately?
We should be cautious.
There may still be bombs in his house.
If too many of us go, he might
find out and cause a commotion.
We'll have to go as a small group.
The question is, who will lead it?
I'll let you handle that.
We'd better get back the
investigation headquarters.
Y-Yeah...
Ran-chan, look at this.
Where'd you get that?
Heiji bought it for me.
How nice.
I know, right? Isn't it nice?
Do I look good? Does it look good on me?
It looks great.
Good for you.
Y-Yeah...
We watched him all night, and
we didn't see any movement.
Is he really in there?
The outdoor AC unit is working, and
the directional mics picked up sounds.
Ishizawa
There's definitely someone there.
Ishizawa-san.
Let's check the back door.
Yeah.
Hey, are you all right?
Hang in there! Who did this?
This man...
It's Ishizawa!
What's going on?
Episode Preview
What's Iwazawa's condition?
He has bruises all over his body.
He'll need total bed rest for a while.
Shouldn't we check out Iwazawa-san's house
one more time before returning to the hotel?
Fine, fine.
Kaiju Gomera VS Kamen Yaiba
(Climax)
The next episode of Conan is "Kaiju
Gomera VS Kamen Yaiba, Climax!"
Crazy Trick
Next Conan's hint!
Crazy Trick!
Gomera's the best! Yaiba is amazing!
Don't miss the next episode.
What about Heiji-niichan?
He's third best!