Detective Conan Episode 968 "Kaiju
Gomera VS Kamen Yaiba (Finale)"
[ED]
The murder that took place at
the new Nichiuri TV building
turned into a serial bombing case.
Yonekura Isato Murdered
Hattori Heiji and I assisted
the police investigation,
and uncovered the terrifying truth
the true culprit had plotted.
However...
Hey! What are you filming for, you idiot?!
Who cares, Yone?
Ryohei must be Suemura.
Yeah.
If we copy this video and distribute
it to everyone, no one can betray us.
All right. This is it.
We should contact the
Hyogo police immediately.
Exactly.
Wait!
Look at the screen.
There are four men in the shot, right?
Then who's shooting the video?
So there were five robbers.
Yeah.
Which means in the presence
of the final man...
It's already been set.
A bomb that could go off at any time.
The rhythm on my lips is footloose!
The rhythm of my detective
skills is perfect!
Find the final remaining bomb!
The climax will have you
on the edge of your seat!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kaiju Gomera VS Kamen Yaiba
(Finale)
"Kaiju Gomera VS Kamen Yaiba, Finale!"
They went to question Ishizawa after that,
but it seems like he didn't talk.
It was already nighttime,
and they were at a hospital.
They couldn't push him too hard.
Which means it's our turn at bat.
Yeah. It's time to do whatever it takes.
That's right.
What? Ran-chan, you're not going to audition?
No. It's not really my thing.
Why not?
Well, you know, I have
to look after the kids.
I guess it can't be helped.
You've got to consider
Kudo-kun's feelings, too.
It's not like that.
But I'm doing it, even if I'm doing it alone.
I'm going to get the part
and shake Gomera's hand!
I-I'm not sure you can shake Gomera's hand.
Then Kamen Yaiba's!
We should probably leave soon.
You're right.
I'll get the others. Let's go
to Abeno Harukas together.
Okay.
No New Messages
That Heiji...
Kyoto-Osaka Serial Bombing Investigation HQ
Well, everyone?
Found anything?
Nothing yet.
The Hyogo police already conducted a
thorough investigation, so it's not that easy.
I know that.
I'm telling you to figure something out.
Listen up, everyone.
We've learned that what we thought was a team
of four robbers was actually a team of five.
Not only that, but it's possible a bomb has
been planted in the vicinity of the fifth man!
They must've left something behind.
Find him!
Yes, sir!
Explosion at Osaka Nanko
Ishizawa Katsuji (38)
Bombing Suspect
Well, well.
You seem to be doing well.
Who are you?
Curious about that article?
Of course you are.
After all, the bombs you made are killing
your old accomplices one after another.
So you're with the police.
Didn't Yonekura attack you and lock you up?
I think it'd be best if you gave
yourself up and talked to the police.
You've got your last
accomplice to worry about.
Isn't there still another bomb you made?
So wouldn't it be planted near
your surviving accomplice?
It'd be better to talk to the
police and have him taken into—
I don't know! I don't know anything!
Hello? What's up?
What? Got it! I'll head back immediately!
Abeno Harukas
Wow!
Look at all these Gomeras!
What a view!
Let's go over there!
Yes!
There are so many kaiju balloons.
Yeah, you're right.
You still haven't heard from Hattori-kun?
It's fine. He's always like this.
I know. Ran-chan, take some pictures for me.
Nice.
Kazuha-san.
Thank you for coming today.
This is Suzuki. He'll be
running today's event.
I'm Suzuki of Nichiuri TV.
Suzuki Naoki (29)
Nichiuri TV Presenter
Thank you for auditioning today.
Thank you for having us.
Didn't you MC the production
announcement event, too?
Yes. I'm terribly sorry about
everything that happened then.
Anyway, I'll show you to the audition space.
Your green room is there.
Okay.
Naniwa Police Hospital
Changing Room
Authorized Personnel Only!
Chief, we've confirmed
there were five robbers.
I knew it.
They were caught on the security cameras.
Hey.
Yes, sir.
Here you are.
This is the entryway of the victims' home.
Look closely at this gap.
He's got a watch on his right hand.
So he's left-handed.
Yeah.
None of the other four are left-handed.
Which means this is the fifth man.
The Hyogo police knew there was
a left-handed man in the group,
but that wasn't enough for them to go on.
All right. Search their
associates for left-handed men.
Yes, sir.
It's me, Katsuji.
You're in there, aren't you?
There better not be anyone with you.
Nah.
Ishizawa Koichi (40)
Katsuji's Brother
What? Ishizawa has a brother?
Is that true?
Yes.
Ishizawa lost his parents when he was young.
He and his brother Koichi, who's two years his
senior, were raised at an orphanage in Kyoto.
Koichi went missing after he
left the orphanage at sixteen.
Ishizawa himself left soon afterwards.
Koichi seriously injured his right
leg in a fight when he was fifteen,
and he has a slight limp.
And his brother Koichi is left-handed.
What?!
Bro, what are you going to do?
Run, obviously.
Where?
I don't know! If I stay here, the
police will come for me eventually.
Then why didn't you flee sooner?
Yonekura's on the news.
I've got my hands full
evading debt collectors!
I don't have time to watch the news.
They shut off the power to my house.
I see.
So that's how it is.
What are you guys doing here?
We just followed you from the hospital.
Your brother's the fifth robber, isn't he?
Bro...
Damn it!
Move!
Hey, wait!
Run, bro!
Hey, let go!
Bro!
Don't let him escape, Kudo!
Damn!
Don't make this difficult.
You can't escape now.
Damn...
Thank you for coming to the
"Kaiju Gomera VS Kamen Yaiba"
Public Audition!!
Kaiju Gomera VS Kamen Yaiba
production announcement event.
Please turn off your cell and smart phones,
and please refrain from
taking pictures or videos.
Yeah, we're on the West Amagi overpass.
Are you okay, bro?
Thanks.
New Message
Close   View
A text?
Kazuha
1 Message
It's from Kazuha.
At Harukas ♥
Jeez. She's so carefree.
Did something happen?
No, it's nothing.
I'm sorry, bro.
Jeez.
If I'd known this would happen,
I would've gone into work instead.
Sorry.
You're supposed to be working right now?
Yeah.
Yonekura asked me to work
security at an event for him.
Where?
Abeno Harukas.
I think it was a movie production
announcement or something.
What?
Ran and the others should be at that event.
Yeah.
Did Yonekura give you any other instructions?
I can't remember all of that.
Answer the question!
There are lives on the line!
It's no use. They're not answering.
Damn!
He really didn't give me any details.
He said there'd be kaiju
balloons or something,
and that I should stand next to them.
Balloons? You mean these?
Yeah, probably.
There are numbers written on
the weights of the balloons.
He told me to stand between
numbers 26 and 27.
That's it, then.
Yeah.
There are two bombs: one
in 26, and one in 27.
The bombs are probably in the
weights of those two balloons.
Shouldn't we cancel the event?
I wish we could, but if people find out
about the bombs, it could cause a panic.
These bombs are incredibly unstable.
The slightest shock could set them off.
In other words, we have to do something
until the bomb squad arrives.
Thanks to your cheers, Yaiba was able
to defeat Jocker's monster!
Finally, let's thank Yaiba with a loud cheer!
Ready, everyone?
Yeah!
"Kamen Yaiba, thank you!"
Kamen Yaiba, thank you!
They said they'd provide a costume, but...
Do I really have to wear this?
What is this?
Th-There are all these balloons?
Let's split up and search.
Yeah.
Got it.
Damn it. Where are they?
Officer!
I'll help.
In that case, could you check to see if
balloons have been placed anywhere else?
Got it.
Otaki-han! Have you found them?
Not yet.
There's so many of them.
I found it!
I found 26!
I'm opening it.
Ten minutes left.
We don't have time to
wait for the bomb squad.
It's an emergency!
One Gomera and one Yaiba balloon have
been moved to the stage on floor 58!
What?
I became a huge fan after my brother took me
to see a Gomera movie when I was three.
If I'm given the opportunity to appear
in "Kaiju Gomera VS Kamen Yaiba"...
What should we do, Hei-chan?
You guys head upstairs.
Kazuha and Mori-san's daughter are there.
We'll handle things here.
But...
There are tons of guests upstairs.
You'll need people to help evacuate them.
Got it.
But if things get dangerous
here, you'd better run.
Yeah, I know.
Let's hurry.
Yeah.
Got it.
Kosugi-san, you stay here. I have a request.
A request?
It's time for our final participant.
Entry number 5, from right here in Osaka.
Kazuha-chan, you can do it.
Toyama Kazuha-san.
Huh? The music...
Did it break?
I wonder what happened.
Kazuha-chan...
I'm terribly sorry, everyone.
Due to technical difficulties,
we'll be taking a break now.
We'll be holding a handshake event with
Gomera and Yaiba in the elevator hall.
Please feel free to participate.
What's going on?
I'm sorry. There's actually an emergency.
What?
I was asked to give you this.
In Call
End   Hold
Hello?
Kazuha, is that you?
Heiji?
Listen, Kazuha. Stay calm and listen.
A bomb has been planted
on that stage you're on.
What?!
Ran-oneesan?
Let's hurry.
If we don't get in line
soon, we'll be too late.
Okay.
Let's go.
Is this a joke? A bomb?
See the two balloons onstage?
Yeah. There's one of Yaiba and one of Gomera.
There's a bomb inside the weight that
has the number 27 written on it.
I found it.
27 is written on Gomera's weight.
All right. Unzip it and open the lid.
Got it. Give me one second.
Well?
Okay.
The surrounding wires are bypasses,
so she just needs to cut them in order.
Then she can remove the detonator.
Got it.
What is it, Kazuha?
No, no, no! I can't do this!
Calm down, Kazuha!
Let's leave this thing and get out of here.
You idiot!
What do you think will happen to the other
guests if a bomb goes off right now?
There's no time to evacuate everyone.
Listen, Kazuha.
Otaki-han and the others
are headed there now,
but we don't know if they'll make it in time.
I need to deal with the bomb
here, so I can't go to you.
What? There's a bomb over there, too?
Yeah, so you'll have to disarm that one.
You just have to do as I say.
It's okay. I know you can do it.
What should I do?
Okay.
Switch to video and show me your bomb.
Got it.
Switch to video...
Let me. I'll do it.
Ran-chan.
Just like I thought, it's
the same as this one.
Kazuha, there should be small scissors
in the sewing kit you carry with you.
Use those to cut the wires.
Okay. I'm ready anytime.
All right.
1 Black
2 Yellow
3 Green
3 Black
4 White
5 Brown
Leave red and blue!
First is black.
Kazuha, the black wire is first.
I'll try cutting mine first. If
nothing happens, you cut yours, too.
Okay.
Here we go.
Okay. Cut the black wire.
Got it.
I did it.
All right.
Let's keep going.
Next is yellow.
Okay. That just leaves the big one.
Inside the tube connected to the red wire,
see the tube connected to the blue wire
being held up by some plastic rods?
Yeah.
Remove the dangling tube without
touching the surrounding tube,
cut the blue wire, and you're done.
First we'll unscrew the plastic
rods supporting it, and...
I can't!
What's wrong, Kazuha?
I don't have a screwdriver.
What should I do?
You don't have one in your sewing kit?
Of course not!
Damn! We're so close...
This isn't good, Hattori.
We've got less than three minutes left.
Is there anything in the area
that you could use instead?
There's nothing that convenient
just lying around...
I found it. I found something, Heiji.
Hurry, Kazuha! There's no time!
Forgive me, Yaiba.
Give me the scissors.
Okay.
Ran-chan, cut it!
Is it over?
Looks like it. It didn't explode.
There's no bell or buzzer or anything?
No. It's over.
You did a good job, Kazuha.
Yes!
By the way, Kazuha...
What?
That outfit looks great on you.
Don't look!
Filming Underway!!
So they blew up the new building in the end.