Detective Conan Episode 972 "Target: MPD
Transportation Department (Part Two)"
[OP]
[ED]
[Eyecatch]
After finishing her shift, Sergeant
Miike Naeko sang away her troubles
over Detective Chiba at a karaoke
box with two senior female officers.
On the way home...
Are you okay? Can you handle her?
Yagi Shiori (28)
Transportation Department
(Lieutenant)
Momosaki Toko (28)
Transportation Department
(Sergeant)
I'll be fine.
Chiba-kun... You big dummy...
Excuse me.
I've been hearing the sound of a small girl
crying in the park bathroom for a while.
Could you go check it out?
Is someone there?
I knew it. I'd sensed an
odd presence recently.
I'm a cop.
Looks like you chose the
wrong target for your trap.
I didn't choose wrong.
I didn't choose the wrong target!
The body of Sergeant Momosaki
was discovered in the park.
Next to it was a bent 100 yen coin.
There was also a mark that led us to believe
the body had been pointing at something.
And in the direction she was pointing was...
The rhythm on my lips is footloose!
The rhythm of my detective
skills is perfect!
Risking her life to send a message!
Stop the chain of assault cases!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Target: MPD Transportation Department
(Part Two)
"Target: MPD Transportation
Department, Part Two!"
Please stand back.
Yes.
Not yet.
Were the victim Sergeant Momosaki
and Lieutenant Yagi close?
Yeah, apparently they were
high school classmates.
Weren't you, too, Yumi-san?
You called them a bunch of times
while we were at the karaoke box.
You again, Yumi?
If you have time to call, come sing with us.
It'll be just like high school.
Yeah, that's right. You
should join us, Yumi-san.
Oh, that.
That's someone different.
That was their classmate Yumiko.
Yumiko-san?
I think she works as a
hostess in Ginza these days.
And they called that friend Yumi?
I told them to call her something
else since it's confusing.
So, you really have no idea if
anyone resented Sergeant Momosaki?
I can think of way too many people who
might have resented her, justified or not.
Oh, but three of the traffic violators
they fined made a bunch of complaints.
When was that? Where did the incidents occur?
It was a week ago.
I think all three were at an intersection
on Fifth Street in Beika City.
Fifth Street is right next to
the Mori Detective Agency.
Do you remember those three?
Yeah.
Miike and I helped question them.
I wrote their names down.
The first was Aono Kengo-san, who was
not only using his phone while driving,
Aono Kengo
but didn't have a driver's license.
The second, who was driving a motorcycle against traffic without a helmet on,
Akamine Manji
was Akamine Manji-san.
The third was Shiroyama Yuzo-san,
who was driving a vehicle with an expired
inspection without a seat belt on.
Shiroyama Yuzo
All three seemed to be in a big hurry.
Since they tried to flee before
they were issued tickets,
they were forced to arrest them
for interference of public duties.
Those three sound suspicious.
According to what we heard earlier,
Sergeant Momosaki felt someone had been
following her since about a week ago, too.
Damn.
I thought the old man
might have seen something,
but a week ago he was off on a trip
with the neighborhood association.
But wait.
Maybe Poirot's Amuro-san saw something.
Hey, Conan!
We're going to school!
O-Okay!
How did it go?
The victim was a female police officer
with the transportation department.
What? A policewoman was killed?
This is a serious case.
That's so scary.
Right, Ai-chan?
Yeah...
I find a kid who barges into a
crime scene far scarier, Kudo-kun.
Is something wrong?
Not really.
Sounds like we'll have to share what
we have on those three traffic violators.
I'll pass the word on.
I'll also see if I can find anything else.
Please do.
Well, we're heading back to our post.
Let us know if there are any developments.
Okay.
Miike!
Incorrect passcode has been entered ten times
Reformatting device
Damn!
I'm impressed you found this place.
I asked one of your colleagues from work.
They said you'd be here
if you weren't at home.
Japan's police truly are exceptional.
I knew it!
You're the one who killed Toko!
Well? What do the exceptional
police want with me?
Have you come to get revenge on me?
Turn yourself in.
It's not too late.
Turn yourself in immediately.
You'll follow the established rules
and accept the judgment of the law.
Exceptional and rigidly follows the rules.
You truly are an insect.
Hold on!
Just one more.
MPD to all stations.
A woman bleeding from the head
has been discovered in an alleyway
off Third Street in Haido City.
All officers and patrols in the
neighborhood, please head to the location.
That's nearby, Chiba-kun.
Let's check it out.
C-Commissioner Kuroda.
What are you doing here?
I happened to be in the area,
so I came to the scene.
But now it's clear.
What? What is it?
One of the officers who arrived knew her.
The victim is Lieutenant Yagi Shiori
of the MPD Transportation Department.
And next to her body is a 100
yen coin stuck inside her phone.
Just like the one found next
to the body of the officer
discovered in the park this
morning, it was deliberately bent.
100 yen coins are engraved
with a cherry blossom.
It goes without saying that the cherry
blossom is the emblem of the Japanese police.
Th-Then this is...
Yes, without a doubt.
This case is a serial murder
of female police officers.
What? Seriously?
Someone died at the bottom
of an apartment building.
No way.
Where? Nearby?
There's a ton of police here...
Apparently someone fell from the building...
Crap, someone's dead
I happened to be there
Someone died...
Apartment Incident
Crap, someone's dead
I happened to be there
Someone died...
Someone's dead in Haido City on Third Street
All these cops
Something serious is going on
The victim was MPD Transportation
Department Lieutenant Yagi Shiori,
twenty-eight years old.
Judging by the body's condition,
she died from the fall.
She was probably pushed from this
apartment building's external stairs.
Not only that, but like the body of Sergeant
Momosaki that was discovered this morning,
a bent 100 yen coin was left at the scene.
Because 100 yen coins are
engraved with a cherry blossom,
the emblem of the police,
it's extremely likely that these crimes were
committed by an individual who resents the police.
Naturally, all female
officers like the victims,
as well as all other officers,
should be on their guard.
Don't overlook any illegal activity
when you arrest the suspect.
Yes, sir!
Let's canvas the area first.
Yeah. We'll start with
this apartment building.
Let's split up and ask around.
Commissioner Kuroda, we'll see you
later at the investigation meeting.
Yeah.
What is it, Sato?
Something on your mind?
Nothing. It's just Lieutenant Yagi's face...
We believe the wound on
her right temporal region
was inflicted when she fell to the ground.
In that case, it would be more natural
for the wound to be facing the ground,
but it's currently facing upwards,
in the opposite direction, instead.
Then there's this. The victim's
hand is reaching towards her phone.
It's not standard for a person to use
a touchscreen without looking at it.
If the victim was trying to place a call,
her head would be facing
left, towards her phone.
But she's facing right, preventing
her from seeing the screen.
Like her head wound, it feels unnatural.
Is it possible that it's accidental?
Sometimes the shock from a fall can cause
a person to face a different direction.
It's also still unclear what she was
attempting to do with her phone.
True, but look closely at this.
There aren't any large visible
wounds on the victim's face.
But there appears to be some kind of
scratch on just the tip of her nose.
Similarly, the lipstick around her mouth is
smudged as though it was wiped in one direction.
It's as if she forced herself to face right
while scraping her face against the ground.
You're right.
Maybe she followed the direction
the suspect fled with her eyes.
We'll have forensics examine
her phone immediately.
If she called someone,
they may have heard something.
They didn't hear anything.
I broke it before they answered.
But there's one more.
Where's the last one?
Aiko... The one who took Aiko's life...
That's right.
They tried to run, so we arrested them.
We have to question them now.
We'll be pretty late by
the time we head there.
That woman...
We'll definitely be there.
Tell her to sing by herself.
Okay.
Where is that woman?
You heard her.
See you later, Yumi.
Do the traffic violators from a week
ago have something to do with this?
I'm not surprised no one's talking
about some traffic violations.
I guess I'll go to Poirot to gather information.
A week ago?
Poirot Coffee
There was a commotion at that
intersection over there.
Could you tell me more
about what happened then?
What is it?
Conan-kun wants to know more about the
commotion that happened at the intersection a week ago.
I see.
Two female officers got into a
shouting match with some drivers.
Apparently there were three
traffic violators in a row.
They said, "We'll question you all at
once, so come down to the station."
"We've got your license plate numbers,
so there will be hell to pay if you run."
Was anyone really angry when they said that?
All three of them were angry.
They had someplace they had to be right away.
The man who was using his phone while driving
and forgot his license cried
that his neurotic girlfriend
was waiting for him and asked
to be allowed to leave.
The man driving against traffic without
a helmet shouted that his ex-wife
was being abused by her new boyfriend
and demanded they let him go rescue her.
The man driving with an expired inspection
without a seat belt was panicked
because his sister was being stalked
and she'd be in danger if he wasn't with her.
What about it?
Both of the female officers they
were arguing with were murdered.
No way.
Did any of those three men
participate in sports like baseball
or golf or work in the music industry?
What? Why?
The first female officer murdered in
the park was pointing at a swing set.
I thought the "swing" might be significant.
Oh, right. We say we swing
baseball bats and golf clubs.
And getting into a jazz rhythm
is also called swinging.
I see.
But I couldn't tell what those three men did.
Call me if you remember anything.
Okay.
Conan-kun is just like a detective.
It's true.
Not only that, but he's a
pretty shrewd private eye.
You let your guard down, Akai Shuichi.
I could say the same thing to you.
Don't be ridiculous.
You lost the moment I saw through
your disguise as Okiya Subaru.
What if I knew you'd try
to sneak in here today?
A private eye?
Wouldn't that be interesting if it were true?
Is that true, Miwako?
Yeah. We just finished the
investigation meeting.
No. Yagi-san, too...
It's likely the suspect is going
after female police officers.
You two are both in the
Transportation Department, too.
Be careful.
Yagi-san...
Miike.
Yes, ma'am. I'm fine. I won't cry anymore.
Do they know who the suspect is?
They're calling the three traffic
violators they arrested a week ago,
but none of them are answering.
Is the only clue we have that swing set?
Yeah. About that...
Did Lieutenant Yagi have any habits?
Like expressing something by
turning her head like this?
Who knows? I've never
heard anything like that.
Her head?
I'll send the photo of her to your phone.
Contact me immediately if you notice
anything after seeing the photo.
I'm going out canvassing after
this, so I'm counting on you.
S-Sure...
Yagi-san...
It's true. It looks like she
forced her head to turn.
This is the alleyway off Third
Street in Haido City, right?
Yes.
What? Wait a minute.
This alleyway and the park...
A number I don't recognize is calling me.
Y-Yes? Hello?
Why are you blocking my calls?!
Ch-Chukichi?
Sorry, sorry.
You kept calling every ten
minutes, so I blocked you.
Because I'm worried!
The news just said another
female officer had been killed!
Yeah, thanks.
By the way, whose phone are you calling from?
A senior shogi player's phone.
He was here today at the
shogi hall for an interview.
Aren't you bothering him?
Yeah, but...
In any case, you should hurry home and only
think thoughts about your upcoming title match.
O-Okay...
Yumi-tan, you should head
home early today, too.
You were up all night playing mahjong at my
place last night, so you haven't gotten much sleep.
All night mahjong?
Oh, and don't forget to eat a proper meal.
And if you don't hydrate enough,
it's not good for your skin.
Yeah, yeah. Got it.
I'm just so worried about—
Jeez, he worries too much.
Yumi-san!
You were up all night playing mahjong again?
I told you not to do that!
Huh? What?
Man, you're all on my case.
Wait, this is no time for that.
Wait, Yumi-san! Where are you going?
I've got someplace to stop
by. You can leave without me.
Be careful on your way home.
Got it?
Well? Any witnesses?
No. At the time of the crime, most
of the residents weren't home.
The only person who was home was
an old man confined to his room.
Naturally, he didn't witness the incident.
Then we'll canvas the
neighboring residents, too.
Yes, while their memories are still fresh.
Right.
I know I took the mini patrol car,
but since I'm helping the
investigation, go easy on me.
Wh-Who's there?!
Oh, just my imagination.
Jeez. I'm jumping at shadows.
Let's see. This area is...
We may have figured it out,
Episode Preview
but calling the number 7155
didn't connect us to anyone.
M-Miike?
I can't keep holding onto that forever.
Yumi-san.
Yumi...
There's a dead policewoman!
What?
Damn. I nearly have the answer, too...
Target: MPD Transportation Department
(Part Three)
The next episode of Conan is "Target: MPD
Transportation Department, Part Three!"
Road Sign
Next Conan's hint.
Road signs!
You were up all night playing mahjong again?
Don't miss the next episode
Of course! I got another
yakuman daisangen last night!
Wow, that's impressive.