[Books, left to right]
[Eyecatch]
[OP]
[ED]
Excuse me.
Your help is appreciated.
Higuchi Masaki (32)
Office Worker
I'm looking for my wife.
Your help is appreciated.
Please.
Excuse me. I'm looking for my wi—
Tomomi...
Tomomi!
Excuse me.
May I take a flyer?
Yes. Here you go.
Could I see one, too?
Here.
Thank you.
Missing Person
Name: Higuchi Tomomi
Age: 29 years, height 165cm, slender build
Since she was excited to perform with her
community theater, I don't believe she
chose to disappear.
Even if it seems small, please contact
me if you have any information.
Contact: 080-976-0020 Higuchi Masaki
Huh? This woman...
You know her, Ran-neechan?
Yeah.
She works at the florist in
the shopping center, right?
Th-That's right! That's her!
Have you seen her anywhere?
I don't know where she's been since she
came home from the florist three days ago.
The rhythm on my lips is footloose!
The rhythm of my detective
skills is perfect!
A strange mystery lies in the flyers
passed out by a desperate man standing
on a street corner searching for his wife!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Secret of the Search for His Wife
"The Secret of the Search for His Wife!"
Mori Detective Agency
I see.
So this is one of those flyers.
Please!
Please find Tomomi—my wife!
He was desperately looking
for her in this rain.
At least do something for him.
Easier said than done.
It's only been three days
since she went missing, right?
Maybe she'll return if
you wait a little longer.
But...
People run away from home all the time.
Are you sure you didn't
do something to upset her?
Maybe you stood her up because you
got caught up playing mahjong.
Are you talking about yourself?
What?
No.
She's the one who didn't show up that day.
What? The Beika Center Building's
observation tower and restaurant?
Higuchi Tomomi (29)
Masaki's Wife
Yeah.
I'm surprised you got a reservation
at such a fancy restaurant.
Tomorrow is special.
I'm so happy!
It was our wedding anniversary.
I made a reservation at a restaurant.
She was genuinely excited since it wasn't
the type of restaurant we could normally visit.
So she couldn't have run away!
Besides, her phone and wallet
were left in the living room.
Have you told the police?
Of course I told them.
But they couldn't say for
certain if a crime took place.
I see.
I'm worried she was kidnapped
or got caught up in something.
I'm just so anxious.
Dad.
Very well. I'll take on your case.
Thank you!
Really, thank you!
I appreciate your help!
That husband looks like he's going
to break before his wife is found.
Try to find her soon.
I know.
That said,
all I can do is question her
workplace and neighbors.
Tomomi-san went missing
three days ago on Wednesday.
That's the day after the
photo on the flyer was taken.
She left her job at the florist at 2 PM.
Her date with Higuchi-san was at seven.
It was a weekday afternoon.
It'd be convenient if someone saw her.
Ow!
You followed me again, brat?
Why not?
I think people will be more relaxed and
willing to speak to you if I'm around.
Well, if you're going to beg, not even Mori
Kogoro is heartless enough to turn you away.
You can tag along, but don't get in my way.
I'm not begging.
Higuchi
Masaki & Tomomi
This is Higuchi-san's house.
Let's start by questioning
his next door neighbor.
Yeah.
Three days ago?
Yes.
I saw Tomomi-san return from work.
What time?
I think it was around 2:30.
Did you notice anything unusual then?
No. She was her usual self.
She seemed happy and said she'd be having
dinner at a restaurant that night.
Did you see any suspicious people
or vehicles around here that day?
I can't recall.
Recently I've been so forgetful.
I remember the distant past so well, though.
Does that mean you didn't hear
any suspicious sounds either?
No.
Besides, if that kind of sound were made in
a residential neighborhood like this one,
people would've made a fuss.
You're right.
I don't know.
I don't interact much with the
people who live around here.
Damn it!
There isn't a single clue.
All we learned is that she was looking
forward to eating at the restaurant.
Yeah.
Let's try asking around behind
Higuchi-san's house next.
Higuchi-san's wife?
I didn't see her that day, but last
week I saw her by the Teimuzu River.
Last week?
How did she seem?
It seemed like she was arguing with
her husband, so I didn't speak to her.
Arguing with her husband?
Yeah.
She was saying ominous things like "let
me live tonight" and "kill me tomorrow."
I did hear shouting.
From Higuchi-san's house?
Yes.
They often argued at night.
It seems like those two didn't get along.
Did the wife run away or something?
Yes, I did see her fighting with her husband
on Sunday in the park next
to Higuchi-san's house.
How exactly were they fighting?
Well...
"Send me away!"
Hey! Go finish your homework.
Okay.
Uh, what was that?
I'm sorry. That's actually
what she was screaming.
Higuchi-san's wife shouted that at him.
Did something happen to Higuchi-san's family?
Please leave!
Who are you people?
That's Higuchi-san's voice.
Yeah.
You said you were the police,
so I thought you came to investigate
Tomomi's disappearance.
Is something the matter, Higuchi-san?
Mori-san!
What's all the fuss, Takagi?
We just received an anonymous tip.
This officer is saying I murdered Tomomi
and buried her body in the yard!
Gardening
Complete Works of Shakespeare
World of Herbs
My First Kitchen Garden
Gardening
Well then, Higuchi-san.
May we begin?
Just get it over with quickly.
Go ahead. Get started.
Yes, sir.
You won't find a body.
First of all, Tomomi isn't dead.
We found something,
Detective Takagi. A woman's body.
N-No!
Tomomi!
Don't!
I understand how you feel, but
please stay away from the body.
Tomomi...
Tomomi!
The victim is Higuchi Tomomi-san,
twenty-nine years old.
She's a housewife who lived in this house.
We believe the cause of death is blood
loss after being stabbed in the abdomen
with these pruning shears
buried along with the body.
That man over there is the victim's
husband Higuchi Masaki-san.
I see.
And at Mori-san's recommendation,
we've had several of the neighbors
come to serve as witnesses.
Higuchi-san, according to the tip,
you murdered your wife and
buried her in your yard.
There must be some mistake!
I would never murder Tomomi!
It's not possible!
You can tell us all about it at the station.
Takagi-kun.
Yes, sir.
Mori-san.
Mori-san...
What's this?
I don't believe it. "Look
for my wife?" Yeah, right.
Hey, Mori-kun!
According to your neighbors, you and
your wife had a terrible relationship.
They said you fought about
whether or not you'd kill her.
Wait a minute. We never fought.
And I thought you were innocent.
But over the course of making inquiries,
I became certain you did it.
Why? Why is this happening?
I was completely fooled by your act.
Takagi-kun.
Yes, sir.
Please stand up.
Hold it right there.
What is it, Mori-kun?
What? Who, me?
I've figured out the true culprit
who murdered Tomomi-san.
Hey, didn't you just say you were
fooled by Higuchi-san's acting?
Yes, but it wasn't me who
was fooled by his acting.
It's those people standing over there.
What?
These people are the neighbors who testified
that Higuchi-san argued with Tomomi-san.
All three of them clearly remembered
what they argued about.
I remembered because their
argument sounded so ominous.
After all, she was screaming "let me
live tonight" and "kill me tomorrow."
Me, too.
I heard her screaming "forgive me" and
"don't kill me" in the middle of the night.
When I heard them arguing, she
was screaming, "send me away."
That's...
Yes.
"Kill me tomorrow—but let me live tonight."
What?
Don't you recognize them?
They're lines spoken by Desdemona
in Shakespeare's "Othello."
What? "Othello"?
That's right. We weren't arguing.
We were rehearsing.
Conan.
Here.
Conan-kun?
Look. It's written here, too.
What?
You're right.
Tomomi-san was part of a community theater.
Y-Yes.
That day...
Hey, look.
What is it?
Something great happened today.
It was the first time she'd
been given a big role.
She was so excited.
So you went to the riverside
and park to rehearse together.
Yes.
We couldn't speak loudly at home.
You thought you'd bother the neighbors.
But doesn't that make
things a little strange?
Sakie-san's testimony, which claimed
she heard you rehearsing at night...
Tsutsumi Sakie (35)
You're right.
I-I...
I just made a mistake.
No, it wasn't a mistake.
You deliberately gave false testimony.
Why would I lie?
Because you're the true culprit
who murdered Tomomi-san
with the pruning shears.
What?
Wh-What are you talking about?
She just lives in the house behind mine.
I didn't have any motive to kill her.
The flyers made by Higuchi-san
told me the answer to that.
These missing person flyers?
Yes.
This photo was taken the day
before Tomomi-san went missing.
Look closely at the picture. Notice anything?
Notice anything?
There doesn't seem to be anything unnatural.
Look at the fragrant olive
tree behind Tomomi-san.
See how the branches are currently
shorter than they are in the photo?
You're right.
Tomomi-san cut them
using the pruning shears
used as the murder weapon.
Come to think of it,
she said she wanted to cut them because
they cast a shadow on her kitchen garden.
But how is that a reason to murder Tomomi?
It's perfectly plausible.
Neighborhood disputes over whether or not
to cut branches can become quite serious.
It's not unusual for them
to turn into lawsuits.
That's right,
but Tomomi-san cut the olive
branches without realizing that.
Sakie-san, you became furious and stabbed
Tomomi-san with those pruning shears.
Wait a minute! I cut those branches!
Huh?
But all the flowers in your yard are dead.
You're right.
Judging by the state of your yard,
it's hard to imagine that you
gardened on a regular basis.
That's right!
She's the one who cut the branches!
But so, what?
That doesn't prove that I killed her!
Y-Yes, but...
Mori-kun, is there proof?
Of course.
Furious at having your branches cut,
you didn't go to the trouble of
using the gate to enter the yard.
What are you saying?
In other words, you climbed
over that rose bush.
H-How do you know that?!
The scratches on your legs.
Did you not get those then?
When I looked at the bushes earlier, there
was just one area unnaturally devoid of roses.
That's how I knew.
Takagi-kun, doesn't the photo on
the flyer show roses in this spot?
Huh? Yes, there are roses there.
Huh? There's something that looks
like blood on these thorns.
What?
Go get the forensics team waiting outside!
Yes, sir!
If examined, I'm sure it
will match your blood.
Will you tell us why you climbed over
the bushes to enter another home's yard?
I-I...
Inspector Megure.
What is it?
There was blood other than
the victim's on the weapon.
It's almost certainly your blood.
You can wipe away fingerprints,
but the blood remains.
It's a shame.
Did she call in the anonymous tip, too?
Definitely. She wouldn't have been
exposed if she hadn't reported it.
She probably thought she could frame Higuchi
since we were questioning the neighborhood.
That's right.
I was going to frame you!
Why would you do that?
I was sick and tired you seeing you happily
fiddle with your garden day after day!
And ultimately, you even ended up
messing with another person's tree!
Hey, you!
Yes?
What are you doing?
Your branches are growing into our
yard, so I thought I would cut—
Don't touch my tree!
I-I'm sorry.
But the branches are crowding each other.
It would be better if you pruned them.
Don't you feel bad for the tree?
What did you say?
It's none of your business!
You're always looking down on me!
Who do you think you are?!
In any case, we'll hear what you have
to say once we return to the station.
Hold on.
That's...
That's why you killed Tomomi?
Crap!
Wait, Higuchi-san! Calm down!
Stop, Higuchi-san!
Think about it.
Doing that won't make your wife happy.
Tomomi...
Something great happened today.
I finally got a big role.
What are you doing?
I was planting herb seeds.
These herbs are supposed
to be good for your throat.
Tomomi...
Your help is appreciated!
Please! I'm looking for my lost cat!
Excuse me.
Yes?
May I take a flyer?
Yes! Thank you.
Miss.
Dad.
Let the great Mori Kogoro find
your missing cat for you.
I promise I'll find him.
It's the great detective!
That's the Sleeping Kogoro!
Huh?
Find my dog, too!
And my turtle!
What?
And my goldfish!
What?!
H-Hey, wait!
Why don't you find all of them?
Good luck, mister.
Is there a goldfish in the local fish-inity?