[Eyecatch]
Detective Conan Episode 993 "Kyogoku
Makoto the Understudy (Part One)"
[OP]
[ED]
Everyone, Happy New Year!
Thank you for all your support last year.
Thanks to you, Case Closed
has been airing for 25 years.
And the 1000th episode will be airing soon.
We'll work together again this year
to produce an entertaining product.
So we appreciate your continued support.
Osu!
What's that?
From heaven, earth, and man,
the silent voices call.
Kamen Yaiba!
Born in Japan.
Are you the ones who called me?
No matter the time or place, I,
Yaiba, shall defend justice...
Superhero Team
Azengers
Amazing the world!!
That was great.
Superhero Team Azengers
was as good as they say.
Yeah,
although I was a little dumbfounded by
Kamen Yaiba's reason for joining them.
You're right.
After all, it was, "We want to
increase our Japanese audience."
It was so blunt, I laughed out loud.
If that movie were real, I bet
they'd recruit Makoto-san first.
Th-Thank you.
I think Ran-kun and I
would be pretty good, too.
You think so?
When you think about it,
it really is a waste.
What?
After all, you're Kanto's
strongest karate practitioner.
A tomboy equally skilled in jeet kune do.
And a young martial artist with
a 400-0 undefeated record.
But you're just watching movies
and strolling around town.
What's wrong with that? It's peaceful.
This isn't a manga.
You can't expect incidents to
occur at your own convenience.
What?
Stay back!
I'll blow her brains out!
No!
I expect you to fulfill the
three demands I'm about to list.
First, I want a car.
Bring me a car so I can get out of—
What?
Are you all right?
Cut!
What?
Makoto-san!
Huh?
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
What?
Find the question that solves the mystery!
Apply miraculous detective skills
to the secrets of the heart!
Kyogoku-san makes his acting debut?
Solving mysteries at a
filming location with Sera!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kyogoku Makoto the Understudy
(Part One)
"Kyogoku Makoto the Understudy, Part One!"
I-I'm sorry.
I thought a woman was in danger.
Oh, Makoto-san.
Well, we were just watching
that kind of movie.
It's no use. He's unconscious.
It's your fault for not
keeping an eye on the crowd.
Sorry.
I didn't think anyone would come running
from the other side of the street.
Tomioka Shigematsu (50)
Director
Give me a break.
He still has scenes left to shoot.
Is there anyone who can take his place?
Since the role involves
wearing a full face helmet,
anyone can do it.
We can dub his lines in later.
But finding an actor who can do action
scenes on such short notice will be difficult.
Odori Daisaku (48)
Assistant Director
Now that I get a better look
at you, you're pretty fit.
Was that something special
that you did earlier?
Well, I know a bit of karate.
Oh, really? Really? You don't say.
Let's do a camera rehearsal.
Ready, action.
Makoto-san, you're amazing!
Nice. Nice.
Huh.
He's the understudy?
He moves pretty well.
Tokuzono Saiya (34)
Actor
I wish he'd do my stunts for me.
You used to be able to
move like that, Nanako.
You mean when I just started.
I can't do that anymore.
Jinmei Nanako (29)
Actress
Plus, I'd hate to break a nail.
I see.
I guess you're no longer a youngster.
You're a mid-level actress now.
Don't make me sound so old.
I'm still in my 20s.
Excuse me.
Anyway, I was hoping I could get
this famous actress' autograph.
My nephew is a fan.
What?
Sure, fine.
I can do that.
What's his name?
Ow!
What is this?!
A practical joke.
It produces an electrical current
when you press the button.
How stupid.
I bet you're the one who planted that whoopee
cushion on my chair in the makeup room.
Yeah.
It's what you get for leaving
those things lying around.
What things?
Excuse me.
Aburai Hideka (26)
Makeup Artist
He might be talking about
your false eyelashes.
When two of them get stuck together,
they look like a centipede.
So you just mistook them for something else.
I'm asking you to be careful.
You know I don't like it.
Isn't it kind of pathetic for
you to be scared of bugs?
You're supposed to be a man.
Now that's inappropriate.
It's like you don't even realize
you're a famous actress.
He's infuriating!
Anyway, he sure is great.
He was quick to learn the fight scenes, too.
Yeah.
This only happened because
he jumped to conclusions.
Have we actually unearthed an
unbelievable diamond in the rough?
But he's just a meathead.
An actor's all about the face.
What?
Wait, what?
He's super handsome.
Maybe I'll scout him to play
a new police detective.
It's about time your character
died in the line of duty.
You can't be serious.
But even we could handle
those fight scenes, right?
Yeah.
What? You girls can do action scenes, too?
I guess.
Better than the average person.
Th-They're so cute!
In that case, maybe I'll have one
of you do Jinmei-chan's stunts.
I don't need a stunt person.
L-Let me do my own stunts.
What? Really?
What?
You were scouted to play a police detective?
Y-Yes.
I told them I don't have the time, though.
Why not give it a shot?
What kind of drama is this?
KEG48
It's called KEG48.
It's a police drama people are talking
about for all kinds of reasons.
That show with 48 officers, so
you can't remember them all.
That's why it doesn't matter
much if they swap one out.
But doesn't that mean I might eventually
become the wife of an action star?
Huh? What about a wife?
Nothing. Just talking to myself.
Talk all you want, gold digger.
I can't ignore what you just said.
What?
Take it back.
It's fine, Makoto-san.
But...
Don't get into a fight before your debut.
Hey, there's a nail on the ground.
Sorry.
That's where the carpenter flipped
his toolbox over earlier.
Hoegi Yota (26)
AD
Then clean it up.
What if I stepped on this and hurt myself?
S-Sorry.
It's because you're careless.
This is why the previous
AD died in an accident.
Unlike you ADs, us actors can't be replaced.
Be careful.
The previous AD?
This is the last scene. Good luck.
Got it.
And give some thought to playing
the new police detective.
O-Okay.
I'll explain how the safety
tether works later.
Please head up to the fourth floor.
Understood.
Sonoko-san, excuse me.
Could you hold onto these?
Okay. Makoto-san, good luck.
Where's Tokuzono-chan?
He's supposed to kick our
future star off the building.
Tokuzono-san was looking for his phone.
He said he couldn't find
his main girl's phone.
Aburai-chan, your allergies have
been going on for a while this year.
That's just what he said.
He's probably already up there talking
to his main girl on the phone.
Maybe he really is looking for it.
He keeps a different phone for each girl
but leaves them lying around all the time.
Are you speaking from experience?
No. He and I were never...
Uh, well...
Not that it matters.
Come to think of it, he asked me
earlier if I'd seen his phone.
Jeez. We're supposed to film soon.
Jinmei-chan, why are you short of breath?
Because I just filmed a fight scene
with the culprit on the fourth floor.
That was you?
Not the stunt woman?
What? Didn't I tell you?
What are you even talking about?
I'm joking, I'm joking.
If you yell too much, your
fake wounds will come apart.
I know that.
Sir, how's this for the camera angle?
Be right there.
Looks pretty good. It's got intensity.
So, has anyone seen Tokuzono-chan?
Hey, we're not ready ye—
Excuse me.
Is something wrong?
Makoto-san.
The deceased is actor Tokuzono
Saiya-san, 34 years old.
While the staff was down here
preparing to film the next
scene for their TV drama,
Tokuzono-san, who had ascended
to the fourth floor,
shouted and fell.
He died when he struck the ground.
I see.
And at that time,
the only person on the fourth
floor with him was you,
Kyogoku Makoto-kun.
Yes.
You think Makoto-san did it?!
Why?!
Sonoko.
Was there really no one else there?
Yes.
Tokuzono-san came in while I was
visualizing the action scene by myself.
Did you notice anything then?
Come to think of it,
Tokuzono-san said he was looking for his
phone and called it using another one.
But I think I heard a strange
noise other than a ringtone.
Then I heard his scream.
When I turned around, he was gone.
A strange noise?
There was a sound just before he fell.
Then someone else must've set something up!
There's no way Makoto-san
would do something like that!
Sonoko, calm down.
Do you have any idea what
could have made the noise?
All that was in the fourth floor classroom
were the safety harness he was going to wear.
We'd finished filming the
scenes inside the classroom.
All we had left to film
was the culprit falling
from the fourth floor shot
from inside the schoolyard.
Once the actor playing the
culprit reached the fourth floor,
and the camera position was set,
I was supposed to head up there, too.
But then Tokuzono-san...
Is it possible that it was an accident?
Could Tokuzono-san have accidentally fallen
while playing around with his harness?
He was looking for a phone
that was important to him.
I doubt that's what happened.
Although it is true that he
frequently pulled childish pranks.
Hideka-chan, you've been his
victim a few times, right?
Y-Yes.
He often pranked me with jack-in-the-boxes
and whoopee cushions.
He pranked us with some bleeding soap once.
That was intense.
The AD who fell for it
screamed like he was dying.
It made everyone in the studio
gather in the bathroom.
That AD went on to actually die later.
Because of those practical joke devices?
He got into a car accident on
his way to a filming location.
I see.
But weren't there staff members who
resented Tokuzono-san for his pranks?
Yes.
Some ADs even quit over it.
And actors who quit after getting
into arguments about it.
Tokuzono-chan himself was
trying to break the ice.
He didn't have any malice.
Speaking of arguments,
that guy playing the culprit got into an
argument with Tokuzono-san just before he fell.
I guess he made fun of his girlfriend.
What?! That hardly qualifies as an argument!
Sonoko, restrain yourself.
In any case, let's head to
the fourth floor classroom.
Kyogoku-kun, director, and AD, come with us.
The rest of the staff will wait here.
After a fight, the culprit is kicked
out the window in this scene.
This is the safety harness you mentioned.
It seems fairly standard.
Could you call the last number the
victim called using his phone?
Got it.
It's over there?!
Huh? That's odd.
Nobody would forget their phone here.
C-Conan-kun?
Isn't it possible that something made
him drop it there after he found it?
But look. There isn't a
scratch on this phone.
In other words, it wasn't dropped or thrown.
It was carefully placed there by
someone other than Tokuzono-san.
That's right.
What are you kids doing?!
You, too, Sera-san?
I mean, after all, we're detectives.
Because of us, we now know that someone
may have used this phone to do something.
Jeez.
We don't know what their intention
was or who left this phone there.
After Tokuzono-san entered the classroom
and said he'd call his phone,
I heard the ringtone immediately.
I believe it came from the window.
That narrows down the time
when the phone was placed.
Did anyone else enter the classroom?
Everyone did.
We filmed the fight scene
in the classroom first.
All of the staff—camera, lights,
and makeup—were here in this room.
After that, we left to film the
falling scene from outside.
With all the equipment being
moved, things were busy.
So anyone could've taken advantage of that
to leave the phone outside the window.
We were up here watching them work,
so nobody was keeping an eye
on the window from the outside.
Sounds like we should ask who
was last to leave the classroom.
Indeed.
Please don't pick anything up until
forensics has a chance to examine the room.
My shoelace came untied.
What are you doing acting in a drama, anyway?
I-It's a long story.
He knocked an actor unconscious.
Not that he can tell them that.
What? Who left the fourth
floor classroom last?
How do you expect us to remember that?
We took a lunch break after that.
People were eating their
lunches all over the place.
It was about 30 minutes.
From down here, the fourth
floor is a blind spot.
In other words, it would've
been possible for someone
to return to the fourth floor
during that break and lay a trap.
Come to think of it, Jinmei-chan, you
were oddly short of breath earlier.
That's because I had an action scene.
But you had a 30 minute
break after filming ended.
Though it would make sense if you ran
up to the fourth floor at that time.
I haven't done an action scene
in a while, and I'm out of shape.
I run out of breath easily these days.
You did suddenly insist on doing it yourself.
In any case, someone placed the phone
outside the window during the break
between the time filming ended
and when Tokuzono-san and Kyogoku-san
returned to the fourth floor.
It's possible they were lurking nearby in
order to retrieve whatever trap they set.
Is there anyone who was
missing during that time?
We were about to start filming.
We would've noticed if someone disappeared.
Would you like to check the camera footage?
We happened to start filming
shortly before Tokuzono-chan fell.
I don't see you, director.
I was looking through the
camera to check the angle.
Hey, we're not ready ye—
See? That's my voice.
Sorry. This is an inappropriate time
for me to laugh about the past.
Only four people besides
Ran-san's group are visible.
And we can't see the fourth floor.
Odori Daisaku
Found the culprit [music]
Episode Preview
Anyway, what are we going
to do about the shoot?
It's obviously canceled.
Don't touch the cut on my temple.
It's real.
Yeah, I kno—
I'll buy drinks for the staff.
Let's take a break for tea.
Hey, what's that?
You've found a fun toy, haven't you?
Th-That's the sound.
Kyogoku Makoto the Understudy
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is, "Kyogoku
Makoto the Understudy, Part Two!"
Medicine
Next Conan's hint!
Medicine!
Oh, Makoto-san.
Don't miss the next episode.
Thank you.
Oh, you beefcake.
It's the year of the ox.