Detective Conan Episode 1024 "Ooka
Momiji's Challenge (Part Two)"
[op]
The message Ran received from Ooka Momiji
pit me against Hattori in a code breaking race.
However, we solved the code at the same time.
Following the decoded message, we
headed to a warehouse at Haido Harbor.
Finally arriving after
swaying back and forth,
draw close to mysteries and
begin deducing the truth!
One of the brothers is the culprit!
How will the mystery-solving
contest conclude?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Ooka Momiji's Challenge (Part Two)
"Ooka Momiji's Challenge, Part Two!"
The deceased is Hamana
Benzo-san, 42 years old.
He worked as a department store buyer.
So he fell to his death.
Looks like he fell from up there.
Yes. We don't know yet if it was
an accident or suicide.
It was murder.
What?
Look closely.
Those metal-frame glasses are
lying crooked on his face.
It doesn't make sense that the right
side of his face is uninjured.
Hamana Benzo (42)
Department Store Buyer
You're right.
Wouldn't that mean
the victim's glasses fell off when he fell,
and the culprit put them back on
the body's head for some reason?
Right, Shinichi-niichan?
He's on the phone with Kudo-kun?
Apparently those three men were
already here when you arrived,
but why did you come here?
Because of the code.
One indicating where the treasure is hidden.
The treasure?
Yes.
Their mother, who worked as a
housekeeper at a certain mansion,
received a treasure from the master
of the house before her death.
She expressed the treasure's
hiding place in four codes
and gave one to each brother.
However, after the brothers shared
their codes with each other,
they suddenly lost contact with
the eldest brother Benzo-san.
Since the Ooka family has a relationship
with said master of the house,
he asked us to solve the code, and I
asked Heiji-kun and Kudo-kun for help.
When we came here after solving the code,
these three were already here,
and that body was lying on
the ground at their feet.
All three of them claim they came here
because their murdered eldest brother texted them.
Normally you'd assume whoever arrived first
pushed the eldest brother and killed him.
Who arrived first?
Well...
Kashiwagi Suguru (39)
Bank Employee (Second Brother)
It was...
It's true that I seem to have arrived first,
but our brother was already dead on
the floor like that by that point.
Isn't that right?
Kanda Katsunobu (38)
Bike Shop Employee (Third Brother)
I don't know about that.
All I can say is that this guy was
already here by the time I arrived,
and that our brother was dead.
Jinya Saisuke (36)
Part-time Worker (Fourth Brother)
S-Since I arrived after these guys,
that means I'm not the culprit, right?
Not necessarily.
After killing the eldest brother Benzo-san,
you could've hid in the area
and waited for someone to discover
the body before popping out.
Anyway, you seem rather standoffish for
brothers, calling each other "this guy."
Of course we are.
We were put up for adoption 30 years ago.
We hadn't met since then.
We're practically meeting for the first time.
Come to think of it, they don't
really resemble each other.
Are they really brothers?
Hold on.
We've got the photo to prove it.
Take a look.
See?
All three of them have got the same photo?
But they're such young kids in the photo.
It's hard to tell if they look like them.
I don't know what to say to that.
This is the only photo we have.
And it was 30 years old.
Excuse me, detective.
Was there a burn scar on the body's hand?
A burn scar?
There's an oddly-shaped burn
scar on the body's right palm.
If they're really brothers, then they
should all have the same burn scar.
Could you show us your hands?
Could those burn scars have come from...
Jingisukan Beika
Coupon
...a Jingisukan pot?
Yeah.
Before we were put up for adoption,
we were invited to the mansion where
our mother worked and had Jingisukan.
I still remember how that lamb tasted.
While we were cleaning up after we finished
eating, someone flipped the pot over.
Our mother was about to get burnt, so we
reflexively stuck out our hands and ended up like this.
We're lucky it wasn't worse.
It was heavy, and our hands
were there for a long time.
Yeah. On top of that, we cooked
a ton of meat that day.
That's right. I'm impressed we were
able to catch it since it was so hot.
Speaking of Jingisukan, apparently there
was a Jingisukan pot inside a plastic bag.
Where?
Around that area where we believe
the victim was pushed from.
What? The order in which I
escorted them to Warehouse 4?
I remember the bearded man arrived first,
but I don't remember the order
in which the other three arrived.
I-I see.
Can I go now?
There are a lot of people here today.
I need to keep things organized.
Is something happening?
Apparently today's the day for great social
media posts that happens once a year.
I-It's what?
What?
Tell me all about it.
Momiji-ojosama, we have
a rather serious problem.
Look at this.
A lovely spot for great social media
posts that happens once a year?
Today, here at this harbor?
How marvelous.
According to the information I gathered,
Hattori-sama is waiting for the opportunity to
confess his feelings in front of a picturesque view.
If he defeats Kudo-sama in
the mystery-solving contest,
he may confess his feelings to Kazuha-sama
before he realizes how attractive you are.
We'll have to do something about that.
Kudo-kun must win, no matter what.
It's so hot.
Conan-kun, want some water?
Yeah, thanks.
There's not much we can do if we don't know
the order in which the three brothers arrived.
Yes. It's not clear why they suddenly
lost contact with the victim either.
It's because he lost his phone while
traveling abroad on a business trip.
He wrote in his message that he found it
at the airport when he returned to Japan.
He was surprised to find a ton of
messages from us in his history
that we sent while his phone was lost.
I'm not sure exactly why he asked
us to meet him here today though.
So you often exchange
messages with Benzo-san.
Yes. Not only that, but we
frequently sent each other gifts.
The other day, he gave me his
favorite watch with a leather band.
Apparently he didn't need it anymore.
He gave me a leather jacket.
But I was surprised when he returned my gift
of chocolate and nuts he liked as a kid.
The same thing happened to me.
Since he used to like crab,
I sent him canned crab,
but for some reason he returned all of them.
Huh?
Something just caught my attention.
What was it?
Hey, Conan-kun.
Huh?
Are you keeping Kudo-kun
updated on the situation?
Y-Yeah.
If you'd like, Iori would be willing
to discuss things with you.
What do you think?
I-I'm fine.
That's what Shinichi-niichan said.
Momiji's helping Kudo-kun.
Heiji, you can do it!
Heck yeah.
If I beat Kudo, I'll ride that
momentum to the lovely spot
and confess my feelings to Kazuha!
What's going on?
I'm only getting a bad feeling from him.
Speaking of crab, he sends me
crab-flavored crackers all the time.
Says he recommends them.
Then it's not as though he
doesn't like crab anymore.
Crackers...
What's wrong, Genta-kun?
Are you itchy?
I suddenly started feeling itchy
after eating these crackers.
Kojima-kun, you might be
allergic to shellfish.
You shouldn't eat any more of those crackers.
I see. So that's how it is.
That's why the culprit was forced to do that.
Looks like Hattori hasn't solved it yet.
Ran seems to be rooting for me, too.
Huh? Wait a minute.
Isn't that face...?
These donuts are good.
Yeah.
It's okay. You can have it, Shinichi.
Okay, thanks.
Actually, you can have it, Ran.
I'm full anyway.
Really? Thanks.
She's making the same face she did back then.
Which means what she really wants is...
Hey, Conan-kun.
Didn't Kudo-kun just explain the truth
behind the case to you over the phone?
What?
Iori says your expression changed.
No, it wasn't about that.
He said he noticed something
about the victim Benzo-san.
Benzo-san probably developed a crab allergy.
Benzo-san used to like crab, but he
returned the gift of canned crab, right?
Then what about my chocolate and nuts?
Maybe it's a snack allergy or something.
What? I've never heard of that allergy.
He's allergic to metal.
What?
Canned goods absorb metal from their cans.
Red King Crab
Canned
Chocolate and nuts contain metals
such as nickel and cobalt.
And fluid chrome is applied to leather
products to make them more flexible.
I see.
But why does that matter?
Don't you think it's strange?
There were metal-frame
glasses on Benzo-san's head.
You're right. If he were allergic to
metal, he'd avoid wearing those, so why?
Those were the culprit's glasses.
Benzo-san grabbed the culprit's
glasses when he was pushed.
They broke when they fell.
The culprit was forced to
wear Benzo-san's glasses.
After all, the brothers he invited
there would be arriving soon.
In other words, the culprit who
made Benzo-san fall to his death
is the only one of the
suspects wearing glasses.
Jinya Saisuke-san.
You're the only one.
Wh-Why would I kill my brother?
We were finally reunited after 30 years!
And remember what I showed you earlier?
This burn I suffered while protecting our
mom as a child proves we're brothers!
You said someone flipped over the Jingisukan
pot while you were cleaning up, right?
Yeah.
The pot was about to burn our mom,
so we reached out to
catch the piping hot pot.
What?
No, that's wrong.
It was actually the pot that
had fallen on the floor.
Your mom was about to fall onto it,
so you slid your hands between
her and the pot to protect her.
Isn't that right?
Yeah.
That's how we got these burns.
Our hands were pressed against
the pot until she got up.
What? But you said it was heavy.
I was referring to mom's weight.
She was pretty fat back then.
Oh, right. I remembered it wrong.
But as you can see, I've
got a burn scar, too.
I'm sorry. I spilled my water.
Jeez.
Huh?
I thought it was water, but
it was actually lemon juice!
What? Hey, wait!
I need to wipe that off quickly!
Since you're panicking, you
must've made that burn scar
by applying citrus juice to your
skin and exposing it to sunlight.
Oh, it was actually water after all.
What?
You thought you'd use the
photosynthetic chemicals
in fruit juice react to UV light
and cause phytophotodermatitis.
And besides, your large unattached earlobes
tell us you're not one of the brothers.
What?
Those earlobes are a dominant gene.
People are rarely born with them unless
one of their parents have them.
You probably talked to the real brother
and decided to use what you learned.
You thought you'd get some of the
treasure by pretending to be him.
Yeah.
I gave myself this burn scar
because I thought it was cool
when I met Saisuke and copied him.
We were both in edgy bands during college.
You didn't hurt Saisuke because
you wanted the treasure, did you?
I didn't do anything like that!
Saisuke died of an illness
just the other day.
Before he died, he told me about
the code and your mom's treasure.
He said he wanted to see his brothers again,
but doubted you'd remember him.
While I was organizing his
possessions after his death,
his phone received a message from Benzo-san.
It said, "The treasure is in
Haido Harbor Warehouse 4."
"I'll be waiting there. Let
me know if you can come."
Our faces were similar, and
I had this burn scar, too.
I thought I'd get a share of the treasure
if I pretended to be him, so I showed up.
See? We got these when we caught the pot.
Who are you?
You're not my brother Saisuke.
What?
What did you do with Saisuke?
Uh, I...
Hold on. I'm calling the cops.
The police?
My brothers will show up later. We're
going to lay into you, you con artist!
N-No, wait! I can explain!
What are you doing? Let go!
So I didn't meant to kill him!
I just thought it'd be nice if I
got a little bit of the treasure...
There's no splitting that treasure.
Wh-What? But I heard she received
it from a wealthy man.
Yeah.
It's the memento that gave the
brothers their honorable injury
when they protected their mother.
The Jingisukan pot Benzo-san
was holding before he fell.
What?
Your mom probably intended
for you to remember
how close you were as a family 30 years ago
if you ate Jingisukan from
that pot again as brothers.
Then the reason our brother
invited us here...
...was so we could eat Jingisukan together.
Not realizing that, you ended up
burning yourself out of greed,
with the serious burn of murder.
Heiji...
He's so cool.
I knew my future husband could do it.
In that case, Iori, as
per our arrangements...
Yes, Momiji-ojosama.
All right. I've still got time.
Kazuha, this way!
What?
Hey, wait! Heiji?
Hey, Heiji! Where are we going?
Heiji!
Wow, what a pretty sunset.
You dummy.
Look closely at the two passenger
ships in front of the setting sun.
The white ship in front and the
ship with the red chimney behind it
are only both at this harbor once a year.
In other words, today's the only day
those ships line up to form a heart.
Which makes today a heart's day to remember.
Kazuha, I'm about to spill my
heart to you, so listen closely.
K-Kazuha?
Wh-Where did you go, Kazuha?
Hattori.
K-Kudo?
Kazuha-chan just headed down the stairs
after that Iori guy whispered something in her ear.
What are you doing here?
I came to let you know since it
seemed like you hadn't noticed.
What? Jeez.
There she is. Over there.
Lovely!
Let's take another picture.
Iori said he'd invite
Heiji, but he's not here.
I doubt boys are interested in lovely spots.
What's Kazuha doing? I was going to...
"Heart's day to remember."
I-I-I-It's not what it sounds like!
I was just caught up in the moment!
Yeah, it was a joke!
Pretty funny joke, right?
What a pain in the ass.
Well, whatever. Seems like you let
me have all the glory this time.
Yeah, I owed you for the school trip.
Anyway, I don't understand women.
The less we understand something...
The more detectives want to solve it.
Yup.
Anyway, I wonder whose mansion
their mother was working at.
Iori the butler told me.
It's the mansion of a famous
guy you're quite familiar with.
A famous guy?
The hextuple crown shogi player.
It's the home of Haneda Shukichi's family.
What?
Apparently the rest of the world
doesn't know about it yet.
I-I see.
Isn't Haneda Akai-san's younger
brother and Sera's older brother?
17 years ago, his brother-in-law Haneda Koji
was force fed APTX 4869
by someone in America.
In other words, the quadruple
crown shogi player Haneda Koji
was the son of a wealthy family.
Episode Preview
It's like, where are all the hot guys?
Hikaru-san, I'd like to talk
to you about something.
What is this?
What's going on?
We were too late.
The Unspeakable Witness
The next episode of Conan is
"The Unspeakable Witness!"
Next Conan's hint!
Sneakers
Sneakers!
I blinked.
Don't miss the next episode.
Then let's take another picture.
How many is that now?
The sun's going to set.