[Eyecatch]
Detective Conan Episode 1029 "Police Academy
Arc Wild Police Story CASE. Matsuda Jinpei"
[OP]
[ED]
Spring, the season when new things begin.
This is the story of a group of new police
recruits who joined the academy in the spring.
Several Years Earlier
I'm surprised you're still
standing after taking my punches.
Furuya Rei (22)
Matsuda Jinpei (22)
I could say the same thing.
Blondie!
I don't know what it is about
me that you don't like,
but I have to become a police officer.
Don't get in my way.
There it is.
That I-love-cops attitude
is what I hate about you.
That's ridiculous.
You joined this academy so you
could become a police officer, too.
Who could it be at this hour?
Morofushi Hiromitsu (22)
It's two in the morning.
Huh? There's nobody here.
Huh? Z-Zero?
Sorry, Hiro. I ran out of band-aids.
If you've got any, could
you share some with me?
H-How'd you get those injuries?
Someone picked a fight
with me, so I fought back.
They really got you good.
So, think you'll be able
to get along with them?
What? You must be joking.
Wait in my room.
I'll go get the medicine
box from the infirmary.
Thanks. I owe you one.
Finally arriving after
swaying back and forth,
draw close to mysteries and
begin deducing the truth!
This is the adolescence of
Amuro Toru and his friends,
and the story of their unbreakable bond!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
Police Academy Arc
his name is Detective Conan!
Police Academy Arc Wild Police Story
CASE. Matsuda Jinpei
"Police Academy Arc Wild Police
Story CASE. Matsuda Jinpei!"
Metropolitan Police Department Police Academy
The Metropolitan Police
Department Police Academy.
Welcoming new students primarily
in April and October,
it's a vocational school where roughly 1,200
students annually receive instruction and training,
in order to become fully-fledged
law enforcement officers.
Assemble in three columns!
Onizuka's class, attention!
Onizuka Hachizo (48)
Rookie Class Instructor
What happened to your
faces, Matsuda and Furuya?
You wanna hear the story?
Yes, I'd love to hear it.
Date Wataru (22)
Last night, a bunch of cockroaches
appeared in the room.
They were so caught up in exterminating
them that they hit their heads on desks.
They had a terrible time.
I see. However—
That said, as punishment for
damaging school furnishings,
Onizuka's class will run an extra lap.
Let's go.
Got it.
Hey, wait.
Two columns. Start running.
Wait. I'm not done talking to you.
Hey, Jinpei-chan.
What happened to your face?
Hagiwara Kenji (22)
You've ruined your good looks.
Shut up, Hagi.
You even lost your false
tooth. It's hilarious.
That Furuya guy's pretty tough.
He put up quite a fight, and you
were trained by your pro boxer dad.
So, who won?
Well, obviously...
I did.
What? Are you sure getting hit too many
times didn't make you lose your mind?
Are you talking about yourself?
What was that?
I don't know what happened between you guys,
but invite me to join you next time.
Hey, idiots!
You'd better be running properly!
One, two. One, two. One, two.
Instructor Onizuka, you've taken
on some troublesome students.
Not only that, but five at once.
Yeah.
I drew the short end of the stick this time.
They're a peculiar bunch.
With A's in all subjects,
he entered the academy with exceptional grades
unprecedented even in the academy's long history.
Perhaps because of his overly
serious attitude and hair,
class representative Furuya can't stop
getting into fights with other students.
Morofushi, whose older brother is an
excellent officer with the Nagano police,
has a strong sense of justice but is
still traumatized by his parents' case.
Second to Furuya in overall ability,
Date has leadership qualities,
but can't let go of his father's
retirement from the force.
Hagiwara has exceptional observational
and communication skills,
but he only uses them to chase skirts.
Finally, there's Matsuda.
He made up for his poor interview
with his studies, practical skills,
and high level of specialized knowledge,
but his outrageous behavior and
lack of cooperativeness are fatal.
I'm worried about the future.
Anyway, police gather eyewitness information
from the area around the crime scene.
Instructor Onizuka
Does anyone know what you should
be careful of while doing this?
Yes, sir.
Tell me, Furuya.
It's important to note that
with eyewitness information,
the stress of being present
during a crime, preconceptions,
or leading questions from the police
can twist a witness' testimony.
Because of this, rather than
blindly believing their testimony,
it's necessary to obtain supporting evidence.
Exactly. Impressive as always, Furuya.
It's questionable if this academy's graduates
are actually capable of doing that.
Hey, Matsuda!
What do you think the police are?
Well, obviously...
They serve the people with
a sense of pride and duty,
respect human rights, justly and
considerately carry out their duties,
fairly uphold the law,
strengthen cooperation,
cultivate their character, raise their
skills, work on improving themselves,
and maintain a lifestyle of
integrity and reliability.
That's what police officers do, right?
As long as you understand.
That's all for today's lecture.
Make sure you review the
material on your own.
Here you go. One chicken and egg stir
fry meal with a small serving of rice.
Thank you.
You're going to sit there? Hey.
If no one's sitting here, doesn't
that mean this seat is open?
Here.
You've been spacing out a lot recently.
Thanks.
Why are you sitting here, too?
What? Isn't this seat open?
Man, I'm hungry.
Team leader, I don't want
this. You can have it.
You don't?
Yeah. I don't have much
of an appetite right now.
Then don't mind if I do.
Hey, have you got any sauce at this table?
Here.
I thought procuring supplies
was your specialty.
For some reason all the other tables are out.
Thanks.
Jinpei-chan, you're ruining your good looks.
What are you doing?
You shouldn't rub that with those hands.
Mind your own business.
Here. Do it yourself, then.
That's it. Men shouldn't quibble.
Hagiwara-kun!
Yes?
Can we eat lunch with you?
Of course.
Here's the sauce.
What's with the change of heart
you had during class earlier?
All the tables are out, so you can use this.
If I recall correctly,
you hate police officers.
Don't tell me you're hot-and-cold for them.
You can't seriously be
blond at a police academy.
Leave it.
I'm not.
I still hate them at heart.
Police officers can eat shit.
Found it.
Suspect Matsuda Arrested
Pro Boxer
Matsuda Jotaro
Murder
This is it.
Pro boxer Matsuda Jotaro,
arrested for murder.
That case caused quite an uproar at the time.
Hiro.
Reference Room
You're looking into Matsuda's father, huh?
Yeah. I wanted to know why
he hates cops so much.
I heard about it from
Matsuda's friend Hagiwara.
Apparently it was a mistaken arrest.
What? A mistaken arrest?
On his way home from the gym,
Matsuda's pro boxer father saw
some men engaged in a scuffle.
Because he had a title match coming up, he
avoided getting involved and left the area.
But the next day, one of the men
was found dead at the scene.
Because witnesses claimed to have seen
Matsuda's father near the area
when the crime took place,
the victim was a former boxer
who had history with him,
and the victim was bludgeoned to death,
the police arrested Matsuda' father.
Later, the true culprit was arrested,
and he was cleared of charges,
but his scheduled title match was called off.
He quit boxing and drowned himself
in drink like a changed man.
I see. So that's why he hates the police.
But why would he want to
become a police officer?
Who knows? Even Hagiwara admitted
that was a mystery to him.
Whoops, look at the time.
It's a bit early, but shall
we head to the classroom?
You go on without me, Zero.
There's something I want to look up here.
I see. Don't be late.
Nagano Family Murdered
Case Type: Murder
Location: Nagano Prefecture, Family Home
Damage Report: One Man and
Woman (Married Couple) Dead
Case Status: Unsolved
Hiro...
Listen closely. What you're
holding right now is a Sakura.
This five-round revolver is the official
firearm of the Japanese police.
In this shooting test, you'll
fire four sets of five rounds.
Your score will be the total
of your two best sets.
A score of less than 70 is a failing grade.
Five shots practically right in the middle.
Nice shooting, Furuya-chan.
Furuya, you've got a knack for shooting, but don't
forget that there's always someone better than you.
There's a genius who scored full
points on his first test—
in other words, he fired all
20 shots right into the middle.
He must currently be a top
cop in Division 1, then.
Actually, he quit the force and currently
runs a detective agency in Beika City.
Damn it, I can't hit the thing at all.
What's wrong, Matsuda?
You're quick to fight, but handling
a gun's too difficult for you?
Are you sure someone didn't drop this gun?
Revolvers are sensitive to being dropped.
Maybe the cylinder stop's broken.
Don't be ridiculous! Hurry up and shoot!
You're always quibbling over everything.
H-Hey, Matsuda.
I knew it. The cylinder stop's broken.
The barrel and cylinder
were out of alignment, too.
No wonder I couldn't hit anything.
Matsuda, put that thing
back together immediately!
Huh?
Yeesh, he's at it again.
Again?
Yeah.
Jinpei-chan's an analysis fiend.
He's always had to analyze
everything since he was a kid.
Because of it, he knows a lot
about gadgets, especially bombs.
The shooting test is canceled!
Return your firearms immediately!
Matsuda, stay there!
What? One bullet hasn't been returned?
Yes, sir.
I recounted all the guns, but
I came up one round short.
Well, I say all of them, but I still
haven't collected Matsuda's gun.
Matsuda! Why haven't you
put it back together yet?
What? You're the one who
told me to stay here.
Forget it. Just hand over
the bullet you swiped.
I don't have any bullets on me.
I fired all my rounds. I even
handled over my empty cartridges.
Don't lie to me!
Huh?
Now, now. Out of consideration for your
team leader, let's lay down our arms.
I promise we'll return the bullet.
Excuse me, Instructor Onizuka.
Is it all right if I check
on the roof repairs?
Sure, I'll show you the way.
You'd better make him turn
in that bullet voluntarily.
Yes, sir.
What? You think I did it, too?
It wasn't you, right?
No.
Then hold your head high.
I'll uncover the true culprit and
make them turn themselves in.
You're too soft on him, team leader.
Make him prove his own innocence,
or he'll end up like his father.
You don't know the first thing about my dad.
Yeah, so why don't you tell me about him?
While you're at it, you can tell me why
you're trying to become a cop, too.
Sure, I'll tell you,
after I knock you on your ass!
This isn't good. The lifeline's
wrapped around the instructor's neck.
The worker who fell looks unconscious.
We're going to go get help!
Will you make it in time?
We have to climb up to the
roof and cut the rope!
You idiot, there's no time for that!
But at this rate, the instructor...
You guys know what to do, right?
Get a gun.
Find a bullet.
Take the shot.
I'll be the foundation.
Does that make me the
supporting rod on top of you?
Yeah! Come on, guys!
Let's go!
Morofushi!
You should be able to breathe
a little easier now.
Our friends are will be here to help us soon.
Try not to die until then.
How long?
Huh?
How long does it take you
to assemble that gun?
Well, generally...
One round.
One round? Three minutes? That long?
Yeah. Just assembling the thing
wouldn't take me 30 seconds.
But not only is the gun broken to begin with,
it needs to be precise enough to
fire accurately without test firing.
We need you to shoot that rope
with a single shot, blondie.
You'll use the bullet
Hagiwara's finding right now.
Excuse me.
Huh? What's this?
Hey, there's a bullet lying right here.
Bingo.
H-Huh? It's still here.
You're the one who swiped
the bullet, aren't you?
S-Sorry. I wanted something to remember
my first firearms training by.
Damn it.
Something's still not right.
Don't panic.
A person's respiratory center stops
functioning within a minute of being strangled,
but the heart continues to
beat for several minutes.
Even if their heart stops, as long as lifesaving
measures are performed within three minutes,
it's entirely possible to save a
person without any brain damage.
Let's go, Furuya-chan!
Catch!
Take this, too. The gun's perfect.
If you miss, I'll kill you, Zero.
Sir, we brought help!
Sir! Instructor Onizuka!
There was a serious violation
of firearm handling rules,
but at Instructor Onizuka's recommendation,
they're going to overlook this incident.
Of course they are.
We dragged him back from the brink of death.
Apparently your father
was arrested mistakenly.
Hagi told you, didn't he?
He's got a big mouth.
I'm sorry about the mistaken
arrest, but in that case—
It's likely the murder wouldn't have
occurred if he'd stopped the fight, right?
I know that,
but I can't forgive the police for acting like
nothing happened after crushing my dad's dream.
So, why do you want to
become a police officer?
That's obvious.
Because I want to kick his ass and
dispel these pent-up feelings.
The boss of the MPD—the chief of police.
What's so funny?
That won't be easy.
Why are you trying to become a cop, anyway?
So I can find someone.
I'm looking for a woman very dear
to me who suddenly disappeared.
A woman? You're surprisingly shallow.
Right?
Episode Preview
Please find the past that's
been erased from my memory.
Find the past?
Maybe it's just a misunderstanding.
It's all right. You don't
have to try so hard.
Yeah.
What happened?
Apparently they regretted
some bad choices they made.
The Blank Year
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is
"The Blank Year, Part One!"
Dog
Next Conan's hint!
A dog!
Don't miss the next episode.
When's the next part?
Is it my turn next?
You'll just have to wait and see.