[Eyecatch]
Detective Conan Episode 134 "Taiko
Meijin's Shogi Board (Brilliant Move)"
[OP]
[ED]
On the way home from school,
Miyamoto Yumi-san forced me to accompany
her as she tailed Haneda Shukichi Meijin,
who she suspected of infidelity.
However, Haneda Meijin was simply
meeting some young shogi players
at an apartment for a shogi study session.
When we went to the apartment where
the study sessions were held...
It's unlocked.
Come on, man. At least lock the door.
Genda-san?
G-Genda-san!
Hishinuma-san?
Genda-san, are you all right?! Genda-san!
What's wrong, Hishinuma-san? No way!
Genda-san?
You're kidding, right?
Something's really wrong with Genda-san.
He's not moving.
How is he, Hishinuma-san?
He's not breathing.
N-No...
He's not dead, is he?
Genda-san, wake up!
Open your eyes, Genda-san!
Hey, Genda-san!
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
What is Taiko Meijin's next move?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Taiko Meijin's Shogi Board
(Brilliant Move)
"Taiko Meijin's Shogi Board, Brilliant Move!"
Is it true that you all left Genda-san
in this room to go shopping
before Haneda Meijin, Yumi,
and Conan-kun arrived?
Y-Yes.
He said he'd put together some snacks.
It's what we always did.
What kind of snacks?
Like cheese and prosciutto on crackers.
You can eat them while playing
without getting your hands dirty.
Genda Yasukiyo
Shogi Player
This must've happened when someone came here
during the ten minutes we were out shopping.
The front door was unlocked.
He probably unlocked the door
because he thought we'd returned.
But isn't it possible that one of you
pretended to leave but actually
returned to the room to kill him?
Th-That's not what happened!
Hishinuma Kosuke (24)
Shogi Player
I bought enough hot coffee for all
of us at the nearby coffee shop.
They were kind of lukewarm,
but I really did buy them, right?
Y-Yeah.
We heard the coffee's
flavor had gotten worse,
so we drank some at the entrance downstairs.
But couldn't you use instant coffee and water
from a hot water heater
to make lukewarm coffee?
Actually, the water
heater's broken right now.
It only dispenses cold water.
We'd been talking about how
we needed to call a repairman.
Then how about an electric kettle?
I broke that the other day, too.
What about that stove?
Couldn't you use that to boil water?
Well, yeah, but...
But when we found Genda-san,
Hishinuma-san and Mina put the bags
they were holding on top of the stove.
Why don't you check the bottoms of the bags?
There's nothing unusual about them.
Then nobody used that stove.
We were out shopping for about ten minutes.
If someone used the stove to boil water,
it would stay hot for about 15 minutes.
The bags should be burnt or melted.
I see.
Then who bought this bread?
I-I did.
Katsumata Mina (23)
Female Shogi Player
I'm really into that bakery's bread.
The store's nearby, and I always bought some.
But you could buy bread
beforehand, couldn't you?
I bought hot freshly baked bread.
They really were warm and tasty looking.
It's too bad they didn't have any
freshly fried curry bread, though.
It's their most popular
item, so it was sold out.
Well, there doesn't seem
to be a microwave here.
It would be impossible to reheat bread.
Uryu-san, what did you buy?
Right.
Uryu Shoko (23)
Female Shogi Player
I bought ice cream.
They're from a shop that
opened around here recently.
Everyone said they loved them
after I bought some once.
That must be the melted
ice cream inside the box.
Yes. Putting them in the freezer
wasn't a priority at the time.
They were freezing cold
when I bought them, right?
Y-Yeah.
But if you hid the ice
cream in the freezer...
Before we went shopping, we all checked
to see if we were out of anything.
There wasn't any ice cream then.
And today we met at the shogi hall
before heading here together.
Nobody could've put something
in the room beforehand.
Hishinuma-san came empty-handed,
and Mina and I only brought small handbags.
Which means this murder might
be the work of an outsider.
Not only that, but it's likely
that these are serial murders.
S-Serial murders?!
It was publicly announced this afternoon that
when missing shogi player Nishikido Kimiharu,
Nishikido Kimiharu
Shogi Player
who was suspected of match fixing, was found,
one of the legs of the shogi board
next to the body had been cut off.
And two legs have been removed from
the shogi board next to Genda's body.
It's only been a couple hours
since the announcement,
so it's unlikely that this was a copycat.
Did any of you know Nishikido?
The three of us didn't,
but apparently the late Genda-san
and Nishikido-san were friends.
These study sessions were
originally run by Nishikido-san.
The four original members were
Nishikido-san, Genda-san,
Kishimoto Yuhei-san, who
recently became depressed,
Kishimoto Yuhei
Shogi Player
Uryu Kinji
and Uryu Kinji, who went pro
around the same time I did.
Uryu?
Uryu is Shoko-san's older brother.
I've heard rumors about those four, too.
They say there's a foursome that's been
rapidly improving their skills recently.
But why did Nishikido stop
attending the study sessions?
It could be because only Nishikido-kun was
winning a bunch of games and had ranked up.
Everyone wants to play stronger
opponents when they advance in rank.
By the way, why did Kishimoto
become depressed?
B-Because...
I think it's because my
brother Kinji killed himself.
He killed himself?
Why?
I don't know.
Not only that, but Kinji-san was doing great
at the time and winning a bunch of games.
We were so certain he'd rank up
that we even celebrated beforehand.
Mina was dating my brother.
So you don't know why he did it?
N-No.
Just before he died, he said someone
from the Shogi League asked to meet him.
Kishimoto-san became depressed
after Kinji killed himself.
He really looked up to Kinji.
After that, I was invited
to join the study sessions
because they didn't have enough
members, and I invited the girls.
These two were totally disheartened
after Kinji's death,
so I also invited them to cheer them up.
In any case, it sounds like
we'll have to talk to Kishimoto.
He may know why Uryu killed himself.
And his suicide may be connected to the
murders of those two shogi players.
Those two may not be the only ones.
There are two legs left on the shogi board.
Y-You mean there's going to be more murders?
No way.
You're kidding, right?
Hey!
What are you scaring them for?
But I bet that's what
Shinichi-niichan would say.
Do you know Kishimoto's address?
Not his exact address, but I think he lives
in a detached house next to the public bath.
The public bath?
It's quicker to show you.
Next to the black chimney
you can see from here is...
Wait, I see smoke.
Isn't that around Kishimoto's house?
C-Could it be?
Is Kishimoto-san their next target?
But why?
In any case, let's head there.
Return to your homes and wait there.
Don't do anything without
speaking to us first.
And don't forget that your
lives could be in danger, too.
Inspector Yuminaga.
What's the situation?
We avoided a total loss, but the resident
who was inside was burnt to a crisp.
Since no vital signs were
detected in the body,
he seems to have died
before the fire started.
Forensics said it's possible he was alive
until shortly before the fire started
because his rectal temperature
hadn't fallen much.
Shortly before?
You mean he died after that shogi player
was murdered at the Beika City apartment?
I heard from Megure that a shogi
board was found at the crime scene.
We actually found one here, too.
A shogi board missing three legs.
So they really are serial murders.
Right after Genda's murder.
But now we can't ask him about the suicide.
Let's check out other people
who may have known him.
Hey.
More importantly, what's
Conan-kun doing here?
Oh, uh, he snuck into the
patrol car at some point.
I'm sorry for dropping by suddenly.
So this is where you moved to.
What's this?
You look like you don't
know why I turned up here.
The truth is, I came to encourage
you to turn yourself in.
You're the one who killed Genda-san at
the apartment in Beika City, aren't you?
These serial murders are targeting
professional shogi players.
What these murders have in common is the
shogi board left at every crime scene.
Next to the missing shogi player
Nishikido suspected of match fixing
who was found bludgeoned to death was
a shogi board missing one leg.
Near the head of Genda, who was found
strangled to death in a Beika City apartment,
was a shogi board missing two legs.
And immediately after that, Kishimoto was
found dead after his house caught fire,
and a shogi board missing three
legs was discovered at the scene.
The potential suspects are the
three people who left Genda
at the second crime scene to go shopping.
Hishinuma Kosuke bought enough hot
coffee for everyone at a coffee shop,
Katsumata Mina bought freshly baked bread,
and Uryu Shoko bought ice cream.
They all drank Hishinuma-san's coffee
at the apartment building entrance
and commented that the flavor had declined
in quality and the coffee was cold.
He could've used lukewarm water
and instant coffee to make that,
but the hot water heater and electric kettle
were both broken and wouldn't give hot water,
and the stove wasn't warm.
There were no signs that anyone
had boiled water on it.
The same can be said of the
hot bread Mina-san bought.
In that room without a microwave, it
would've been impossible to heat up that bread.
The ice cream Shoko-san
bought seemed to be cold,
but with a cooler, she could've kept
ice cream purchased beforehand cold.
But when we arrived at the room,
all three were dressed lightly.
It's hard to believe they were
carrying anything like that.
Not only that, but only Genda-san
and Mina-san had keys to the room.
Shoko-san couldn't have arrived
early and left a cooler in the room.
Naturally, Hishinuma-san couldn't
have left a thermos in there either.
Could any of them have killed
Kishimoto in the first place?
Together we discovered Genda-san's
body in the Beika City apartment.
After an investigation by the
police who arrived at the scene,
we began discussing the
location of Kishimoto's home.
By the time we looked out the
window to confirm the location
and noticed Kishimoto's house was
on fire, three hours had elapsed.
Those three were with us the whole time.
Kishimoto's body discovered at the scene
of the fire showed no vital signs,
which means he died before the fire started.
But since Inspector Yuminaga said the body's
rectal temperature hadn't fallen completely yet,
it's likely he was still alive until
shortly before the fire started.
That would make it impossible for
those three to have killed Kishimoto.
This is impossible. Aw, man.
What's impossible, Genta-kun?
It's this Yaiba capsule toys.
I got a #1 the day before
yesterday and a #2 yesterday,
so I was sure I'd get a #3 today,
but I got another #1.
I bet these capsules are rigged
not to give you a #3.
Genta-kun, things don't always
happen so conveniently in order.
Maybe I'd get one if I mixed them up.
You'll get in trouble.
It'll be fine.
Please don't get worked up over capsule toys.
I've got this.
What? Are you interested
in capsule toys, too?
No, it's not that.
You're going to break it.
I feel like I just received
an incredible hint.
Huh? Someone's calling.
It's Yumi-san.
Hello, Yumi-san? What is it?
Don't do that.
What?
Taiko Meijin hasn't come home?
Not since last night?
Yeah, late last night he said he'd be out late
since he was meeting a friend and headed out.
I went to sleep without
waiting for him to return,
but he wasn't there when I woke up.
I thought he must've come home and
left again early in the morning,
but I've asked around and nobody's seen him.
Did you call those three shogi players?
Yeah.
I tried calling, but none
of them said they knew.
I thought you might know, so I called you.
Come to think of it, Taiko
Meijin had an odd expression
on his face after we discovered the
body and before the police arrived.
Is it possible that he noticed something?
Was Taiko Meijin acting strange when you
left the apartment where the murder occurred?
I wouldn't call it strange exactly.
When we left the apartment
with the three shogi players,
Chukichi suddenly said he forgot something
and borrowed the key and headed back inside.
I asked him what he forget when he came
back, but he said it was a mistake on his part.
What is it? What did the Meijin see?
Well, whatever. I'll try
calling someone else.
Hey, wait!
Maybe he's shocked you
suspected him of cheating.
It sounds like he wasn't cheating after all.
I just tailed him a little. Could you
guys not make a huge fuss over this?
"Just tailed him a little?"
You're not a detective.
You guys are lucky you get along so well.
Uh...
Actually...
Naeko-chan and I just got into
a huge argument last night
because of a difference in opinion.
Because you laughed and called me an idiot
because I served cream stew over rice.
Nobody does that. It's not curry.
It's all the same once it's in your stomach,
and that way you only have to wash one dish.
It's annoying how in love they are.
Where am I?
Last night I went to see them, and then...
The truth is, I came to encourage
you to turn yourself in.
Why don't we talk about this inside?
They knocked me out with a stun
gun, and then I ended up like this.
My hands are tied behind my back, but
my phone is still in my back pocket.
I can get it out, but I doubt
I'll be able to call anyone.
They look pretty irritated.
They seem to be waiting for
the police announcement.
But I've crushed that path to victory.
Kudo
How unusual for you to call me, kid.
Shin-chan's calling?
What?
Shukichi's missing after
getting involved in a murder?
Yeah.
Taiko Meijin might've identified
the culprit and gone to see them.
All three suspects are
shogi players like him,
so he probably wanted to convince
them to turn themselves in.
Tell me more about the case.
Could you put your phone on
speaker so I can listen, too?
I've got nothing better to do.
The world's leading mystery enthusiast
is currently at your disposal.
I see.
So as the number of victims increases, the
number of legs on the shogi board decreases.
But you already know the number
of legs is a feint, right?
Yeah, but like I said earlier,
all three of them have alibis.
You said Akai-kun's brother seemed
to have noticed something.
What made you think that?
When the Meijin moved around the people
in front of him to get a look at the body,
he touched the kitchen counter.
He held his hand as though
he'd touched something.
I don't know if it was hot or cold,
but his expression changed then.
What was on top of the kitchen counter then?
Nothing significant.
Just two ice trays, a mixer,
and a toaster, I think.
Sounds like there was a magic tool one of
them could've used to fabricate an alibi.
What? Which one of those sounds like—
Oh, right.
In any case, sounds like we need to hurry.
Meet up with Akai-kun and make
sure his brother is safe.
We're counting on you, Edogawa Conan-kun.
Yeah, I know.
Episode Preview
It's been a while, kid.
Like a certain high school detective,
officially I don't exist.
Would you like to play a game
of blind shogi with this Meijin?
He might be using the game record of that
blind shogi game to tell us where he's being held.
Taiko Meijin's Shogi Board
(Checkmate)
The next episode of Conan is
"Taiko Meijin's Shogi Board, Checkmate!"
Blind Shogi
Next Conan's hint!
Blind shogi!
Check!
Don't miss the next episode.
That's a double pawn.
Check!
That's your own king.
Seriously?