[Eyecatch]
Detective Conan Episode 1035 "Taiko
Meijin's Shogi Board (Checkmate)"
[op]
[ed]
On the way home from school,
Miyamoto Yumi-san forced me to accompany
her as she tailed Haneda Shukichi Meijin,
who she suspected of infidelity.
However, Haneda Meijin was simply
meeting some young shogi players
at an apartment for a shogi study session.
It's unlocked.
Genda-san?
G-Genda-san!
Hishinuma-san?
Genda-san, are you all right?! Genda-san!
Additionally, a third victim appeared in what the
police determined were a series of serial murders.
Inspector Yuminaga.
What's the situation?
We avoided a total loss, but the resident
who was inside was burnt to a crisp.
Since no vital signs were
detected in the body,
he seems to have died
before the fire started.
Shortly before?
You mean he died after that shogi player
was murdered at the Beika City apartment?
I heard from Megure that a shogi
board was found at the crime scene.
We actually found one here, too.
A shogi board missing three legs.
And furthermore, Taiko Meijin
was kidnapped by the culprit.
You said Akai-kun's brother seemed
to have noticed something.
What made you think that?
When the Meijin moved around the people
in front of him to get a look at the body,
he touched the kitchen counter.
He held his hand as though
he'd touched something.
What was on top of the kitchen counter then?
Nothing significant.
Just two ice trays, a mixer,
and a toaster, I think.
Sounds like there was a magic tool one of
them could've used to fabricate an alibi.
Oh, right!
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
What will be the final move
that tears down their alibi?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Taiko Meijin's Shogi Board
(Checkmate)
"Taiko Meijin's Shogi Board, Checkmate!"
Ramen to Die For
Ramen Ogura
It's been a while, kid,
since I last met you while wearing this face.
We didn't have a choice.
I doubt you had time to disguise yourself.
Yukiko-san certainly wanted to disguise me.
So, do you know where my brother is?
He's probably being held
at the culprit's home,
but apparently they moved recently.
I could only figure out their phone number.
They answered Yumi-san's call this morning,
so I thought about calling and
getting their address out of them,
but they're on their guard
and won't answer their phone.
Naturally, I've been calling the Meijin's
phone as well, but it's powered off.
It's possible he expected
the culprit to capture him,
and didn't take a phone containing
information about his close friends.
Although as his brother, I wish he'd
consider how not to get captured.
Who are you calling?
My brother's other phone.
We use it exclusively for
secret conversations.
Like a certain high school detective,
officially I don't exist.
Brother
Incoming Call
Answer     Decline
A-An incoming call.
Must be my brother.
He picked up.
Really?
Excuse me.
You seem to be waiting for something.
We're both shogi players.
If you've got nothing better to do...
Would you like to play a game
of blind shogi with this Meijin?
4-5 P.
Same P.
5-5 S.
2-4 P.
6-4 P.
Same P.
5-6 G.
2-5 P.
Well, well. Not bad.
In that case, 6-4 S.
5-5 P.
Th-They're playing blind shogi?
Yeah.
My brother must be up to something.
He might be using the game record of that
blind shogi game to tell us where he's being held.
No, that's not necessary.
Since I could complete
the call, I can use this.
A GPS?
In any case, I'll hurry to this location.
Could you listen to my brother's blind
shogi match while explaining to me
how you identified the culprit?
The suspects are the following three people who
said left the victim in the room to go shopping.
Hishinuma Kosuke, who went to a coffee
shop to pick up coffee for everyone.
Hishinuma Kosuke (24)
Shogi Player
Katsumata Mina, who bought
freshly baked bread at a bakery.
Katsumata Mina (23)
Female Shogi Player
And Uryu Shoko, who purchased
freezing cold ice cream.
Uryu Shoko (23)
Female Shogi Player
Even if they'd wanted to acquire what they
purchased beforehand to fabricate an alibi...
But couldn't you use instant coffee and water
from a hot water heater
to make lukewarm coffee?
Actually, the water
heater's broken right now.
It only dispenses cold water.
Then how about an electric kettle?
I broke that the other day, too.
What about that stove?
Couldn't you use that to boil water?
Well, yeah, but...
But when we found Genda-san,
Hishinuma-san and Mina put the bags
they were holding on top of the stove.
Why don't you check the bottoms of the bags?
There's nothing unusual about them.
Then nobody used that stove.
We were out shopping for about ten minutes.
If someone used the stove to boil water,
it would stay hot for about 15 minutes.
The bags should be burnt or melted.
I see.
Then who bought this bread?
I-I did.
I'm really into that bakery's bread.
The store's nearby, and I always bought some.
But you could buy bread
beforehand, couldn't you?
I bought hot freshly baked bread.
They really were warm and tasty looking.
It's too bad they didn't have any
freshly fried curry bread, though.
It's their most popular
item, so it was sold out.
Well, there doesn't seem
to be a microwave here.
It would be impossible to reheat bread.
Uryu-san, what did you buy?
Right.
I bought ice cream.
They're from a shop that
opened around here recently.
Everyone said they loved them
after I bought some once.
But if you hid the ice
cream in the freezer...
Before we went shopping, we all checked
to see if we were out of anything.
There wasn't any ice cream then.
Our hint is the objects on the kitchen
counter that caught Haneda Meijin's attention.
Two ice trays, a mixer, and a toaster.
One of the three suspects could've used
one of those tools to fabricate an alibi.
Oh?
It's the mixer.
The mixer?
If you put room temperature water in
a mixer and mix it for five minutes,
the kinetic energy from the friction
generated by the water molecules
turns into thermal energy.
Its temperature rises three
degrees to 42-3 degrees Celsius.
If you put instant coffee in the hot
water, you can make lukewarm coffee.
In other words, the culprit
pretended to go shopping
and then claimed to have forgotten
something and returned to the room.
They put water in the mixer,
and while it was mixing,
they strangled the victim Genda
to death with an electrical cord.
They placed the shogi board missing two legs
they'd hidden in the room next to the body,
indicating that Genda was the second
victim of the serial murders.
They poured the lukewarm
water heated using the mixer
into cups they previously purchased
from the coffee shop and made coffee.
They placed the coffees inside a coffee shop
bag and descended to the building entrance.
Then he pretended the victim wouldn't
let him in after he went to buy coffee.
That's right.
Hishinuma Kosuke must be the culprit.
3-3 G.
5-4 B drop.
While Genda's death by strangulation
was being investigated,
Kishimoto's house caught fire.
A shogi board missing three legs
was placed next to the body
to confuse the order in which
the murders took place.
He killed Kishimoto before going
to the second crime scene,
the Beika City apartment where
the study sessions were held.
After killing him, he left the body in
a room with the AC set to 37 degrees.
As long as he made sure
the house would catch fire
automatically after Genda's
murder was discovered,
a body with a relatively
high rectal temperature
would be discovered in
the wreckage of the fire.
Naturally, the body was burnt,
which broadens the estimated time of death,
but he could use the number
of legs on the shogi board
to convince us that it happened
after the second murder.
I see.
In other words, by leaving a shogi board
missing one leg next to Nishikido,
his first victim,
he was laying the groundwork to make
it seem like he killed Kishimoto,
his second victim, after
Genda, his third victim.
Yeah.
I see it.
The GPS is pointing to that
building directly ahead of us.
Yeah.
The question is which room
is the Meijin being held in?
He's probably playing blind
shogi in order to tell us that.
That's how my brother honks his horn.
He must've come for me.
What's the matter, Meijin?
Need some time to think?
8-3 B promote.
Oh, no! That was a bad move!
Now my jeweled general will be
taken by your incense chariot!
An 8-3 B promote means an incense
chariot will take his king?
8-3 B is the square eighth from
the right and third from the top,
which would be the eighth room from the
right on the third floor below the roof.
And if his piece was promoted,
that means it was flipped.
In other words, Taiko Meijin
is in the room in that location
when the building is viewed from behind.
Akai-san.
Impressive work, kid.
I knew Haneda Meijin wouldn't
make such a bad move.
You tricked me so you could tell
someone about this location.
If the police found the written confession
and you agreed not to tell anyone about me,
I planned to release you
and go into hiding, but...
It looks like I'll have to kill you!
I knew it. He's being
held in the living room.
In English, the incense chariot is
called the lance, or L for short.
Incense Chariot
Living Room (L)
"Living room" starts with an L, too.
But how can we rescue him?
Kid.
You see that clothesline pipe
on that apartment's balcony?
Yeah. What about it?
Could you use your ball to change its angle?
It wouldn't be impossible.
Then follow along with the
plan I'm about to describe.
Damn it. What are the police doing?
Perhaps it's none of my business,
but you should turn yourself in soon.
It's not too late.
Shut up!
Akai-san, I set my voice
changed to loudspeaker mode.
Give the signal in 30 seconds.
Roger that.
Wh-What just happened?
Where'd this ball come from?
This is the MPD!
We're the Special Assault Team!
Hishinuma Kosuke, we're
watching your every move!
Discard your weapon and give yourself up!
Shut up!
Stay away from me!
Or don't you care what happens to the Meijin?
I thought he might do that.
In that case...
That was a warning shot!
A detached force is on
its way to your location.
Stay there and wait quietly
until they arrive.
I somehow made it in time to tranquilize him.
Thanks for saving me, Conan-kun.
It wasn't me. It was all Akai-san.
I suppose so.
Anyway...
Why did the culprit Hishinuma-san stay
here instead of immediately running away?
He was waiting for the police
to find the written confession.
Written confession?
Yeah, a letter confessing that those
four shogi players were cheating.
Four shogi players?
Nishikido Kimiharu,
Genda Yasukiyo,
Kishimoto Yuhei,
and Uryu Kinji kept pens equipped with
miniature cameras in their pockets.
They sent videos of their matches
to their accomplices' phones,
who searched the web for expert moves.
They won a bunch of games by
casually informing each other
about the moves when they passed each
other in the bathroom or hallways.
Nishikido ranked up without getting caught,
but someone from the Shogi League warned Uryu
that he was going to the
bathroom too many times.
When he asked the others what he should do,
they apparently responded coldly.
Rule of Silence (kuchinashi no okite)
They told him to follow the
rule of silence and die.
The rule of silence?
The legs of shogi boards are modeled
after gardenia (kuchinashi) fruit.
It comes from the ban against speaking
during someone else's match (kuchi wo dasu).
They made their own agreement
modeled after the gardenia.
If any of them were in
danger of being exposed,
he'd keep the group's secret and
protect the others by killing himself.
Because of it, Uryu was
forced to commit suicide.
He found his suicide suspicious,
so he tracked down their cheating,
and made his first victim Nishikido confess.
In order to avenge his friend
Uryu, he killed the three of them
and left shogi boards missing their
gardenias at the crime scenes.
Before we began our blind shogi game,
he actually told me to sit quietly and
listen so he could tell me why he did it.
Nishikido in particular used
their cheating to fix matches.
He called him a disgrace to shogi players.
Well, the confession was
meant to frame Kishimoto,
who was found dead in the burnt wreckage.
It apparently said he killed the other two
and himself in order to
atone for their cheating.
But why haven't the police
found the confession?
Because I got to it before them and took it.
What?
At the time, I knew Hishinuma was
responsible for the serial murders.
Hishinuma might've burnt
down Kishimoto's house, too.
If that were the case,
I thought he might put a confession
in the apartment's mailbox
so it would seem like Kishimoto
came to the apartment to kill Genda
before setting fire to his
own home and killing himself.
Confession
Come to think of it, Yumi-san said the Meijin
went back inside while they
were leaving the building.
That must be when he took the confession.
In any case, I'd expect no less
from the great Taiko Meijin.
Ah, Camel?
There's something I'd
like you to take care of
while the police are escorting
the murderer to their car.
Yeah.
One broken glass window and
a bullet stuck in the wall.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's right.
Thanks for taking care of this, Camel.
Nii-san, I've got a question about Mom.
What about Mom?
She's refusing to meet my girlfriend.
She won't even answer her phone.
You haven't told her I'm alive, have you?
No.
Don't worry.
You'll get to see Mom eventually.
Once their mist concealing the truth clears.
Yahoo!
Episode Preview
Can't you nod your head in agreement today?
I know.
But Ishibashi-san, you've been
hiding something important from me.
Hurry. They're right behind us.
Crap.
At this rate, we won't be able to escape.
Whiteout
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan
is "Whiteout, Part One!"
Snowy Mountain
Next Conan's hint!
A snowy mountain!
Thanks for saving me.
Don't miss the next episode.
You'd better not do it.
Do what?
Cheat on Yumi-san.