While traveling through snowy
winter mountains to go skiing,
we helped a car stuck on the road.
Later, the driver Ishibashi Kengo stabbed
and killed the passenger, Doctor
Yokoyama-san, with a knife.
Ayumi-chan happened to witness his
crime from the ski lift at the resort,
and the Detective Boys ended up being
pursued by Ishibashi Kengo the murderer.
What's that?
It's a cabin.
We're saved.
Now they've done it.
Come on, hurry up.
Yes, sir.
You just wait, kids.
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
It's a desperate situation!
The culprit closes in amidst a blizzard!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Whiteout
(Part Two)
"Whiteout, Part Two!"
We're looking for some lost children.
Edogawa Conan-kun, Kojima Genta-kun,
Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko-kun, and Yoshida Ayumi-chan from Beika City.
Your guardian is waiting for you.
Please come to the information
desk immediately.
Looks like they're not coming.
Where could they all have run off to?
Shall I try making another announcement?
Please do. Let me know if
they show up here later.
I'll call you on your phone
right away. Don't worry.
Thank you.
The number you are calling is either
powered off or outside the service area.
Where did you kids go?
Ishibashi Kengo (54)
Medicine Manufacturer
Company President
They're just kids.
They didn't consider the
footprints they'd leave behind.
Sir, are you really going to kill those kids?
Tannai Taro (29)
Office Worker
Mori Masaki (33)
There's no turning back now.
I've already killed a man.
You're going to kill all of them?
Yeah, every last one.
If we bury them beneath
the snow with Yokoyama,
I doubt anyone will find
them until early spring.
Sounds like this job is going
to weigh on my conscience.
If you'd captured them sooner,
we wouldn't have had to do this.
Sorry.
Let's hurry.
If we don't catch up before the snow starts
falling heavily, their footprints will van...
They're gone.
What's this?
Must've been that kid again.
"Contact me immediately. Agasa."
And send.
They haven't gotten themselves
into trouble again, have they?
It's a little cold.
But it's way better than being outside.
Yes, but how long do we have to stay here?
Since we erased our footprints using
my snowboard on the way here here,
we'll probably be fine for a while.
But there's no telling when
they'll catch up to us.
That said, if we carelessly leave
this place, it could be disastrous.
The weather seems to be getting worse.
It's hard to judge what's
the right thing to do.
What should we do?
Should I go alone to the other cabin, or...?
If only my phone had service.
I got through!
What?
Please answer your phone, Professor.
Hello?
Professor, it's me!
He picked up!
All right!
Where... you? Is every... okay?
Professor, my signal's weak. Just listen.
We're currently being pursued by
that Ishibashi guy and his goons.
You what?
We're being chased.
Please come save us.
Please, Professor.
Quiet.
We're being pursued because Ayumi-chan saw
Ishibashi kill a man while riding the lift.
We're currently... higher... cabins.
Police... rescue team immediately.
Sorry... say that again? I couldn't hear...
The police. Call the police and a
rescue team to the cabins immediately.
Ishibashi and his goons are nearby.
About Ishi...
What?
I...
Hey, Professor. Professor!
It's no use. The call dropped.
What?
But you got to talk to the professor, right?
Since the signal was weak, I don't
know how much he understood.
Does that mean help might not be coming?
Yeah, I can't deny the possibility.
But...
I'm getting kind of hungry.
The blizzard's getting stronger.
Don't worry.
Yeah, that's right. It'll all work out.
After all, we're here, too.
Yeah.
The blizzard's getting stronger.
Where did those kids go?
Let's move.
What?
Move? In the middle of this blizzard?
Yeah.
Why?
First, because I'm not sure
this cabin will stay standing.
Honestly, I don't think it
can withstand this blizzard.
Second, because our pursuers are closing in.
Third, because there's a
landline in the other cabin.
A phone?
Yeah. I saw phone and power lines running
from that cabin on the way to the ski resort.
With a landline, we can make calls
without worrying about signal strength.
Which means we can call for help.
At the very least, it's got power.
As long as we can reach that cabin,
we'll be able to get out of this cold.
This is no time to sit around chatting.
But you can't see anything outside.
It's all right.
I see.
Now we don't have to worry
about getting separated.
Nice thinking, Conan-kun.
That said, it's a blizzard outside.
Let's be careful.
Yeah!
A whiteout.
It's no use. I can't see anything.
Everything's white.
Conan-kun.
Calm down. Use the rope and carefully
move forward one step at a time.
Got it?
Yeah.
Yes.
The other cabin is that way.
Let's go.
I can't see anything.
This would've been bad if I didn't
have this rope and my glasses.
Crap!
Ow!
Crap, my glasses.
The rope's been cut.
Ayumi-chan.
Genta.
Mitsuhiko.
Ayumi-chan!
Genta!
Mitsuhiko!
If you can hear me, say something!
Guys!
I could probably manage something if
I were on my own, but those guys...
Unknown caller?
Hey, kid.
Ishibashi?
I bet you're wondering why
I know your phone number.
You got it from the professor, didn't you?
Nothing strange about it.
What an insolent brat you are.
I'll be right there. Wait until you
see what I have in store for you.
Not just you.
I'll break all your necks and bury
you in the snow next to each other.
I promise.
You may be a little clever,
but you're still just a kid.
There's only so much you can do.
Unlike me, you're going to
die so others can succeed.
You're just a kid.
A weak little child who can't do anything.
Uh, sir?
The call ended.
That brat!
How much does he have to
make a fool out of me?!
Damn it. I thought I finally had a
signal, but my phone died.
I need to find the others.
Think. First, I have to find my glasses.
Which direction did I fall from?
Calculate how far I fell.
My glasses are that way.
Guys, can you hear me? Stay where you are.
I promise I'll come get you.
My leg... I must've hurt it.
You just wait.
They should be around here.
Where? Where are they?
I need to hurry, or they'll freeze.
All right.
I need to hurry.
No, no, no. Come on.
Why is this happening now?
Please, just give me a second.
Turn back on, please.
Guys.
I'm hungry.
I'm cold.
Am I going to die here?
Someone help me.
Conan-kun...
I can't take it anymore.
Ayumi-chan.
Sorry I took so long.
Conan-kun, I knew you'd come for me!
Yeah.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Genta.
Took you long enough.
Mitsuhiko, good job hanging in there.
This is nothing.
They're dead.
It's all right. We'll keep
heading straight ahead.
It's the cabin!
We're saved.
We did it.
We should be all right now that we're here.
Let's head inside and look
for the heat and the phone.
Conan-kun!
Watch out!
All right. Let's go.
Hey, Conan!
Say something!
Conan-kun!
Conan-kun! Conan-kun!
Conan!
Say something, Conan-kun!
Hey! Conan!
Okuyama Central Hospital
Guys, where are we?
Looks like you're awake.
We're at a hospital.
A hospital?
Did you forget?
You collapsed when a bunch
of snow fell on you.
Snow? Is that right?
Professor, what about the case?
What happened to Ishibashi?
Ow...
You need to lie down.
Yeah, but...
Don't worry. The professor
handled everything.
After I got your call,
it was quite the ordeal.
I called the police, met up with the
rescue team, and rushed to that cabin.
We carried you inside the cabin.
They found the victim where
Ayumi-kun said he'd be.
They were able to put out an APB for
Ishibashi and his goons right away.
And?
Don't worry. All three have been arrested.
The rescue team found them stuck
in the mountains in the blizzard.
Apparently they gave themselves up.
Conan-kun's asleep.
He must be exhausted.
Is he not hungry?
You worked hard in that blizzard.
So all the culprits were
arrested. That's good.
Yeah, while I was asleep.
Ishibashi's accomplices were
apparently his employees.
They're telling the police everything they
know in order to get reduced sentences.
He's supposed to be saving
people with medicine,
but he killed a man over it instead.
Seriously? Again?
What should we do, Professor?
Well, normally I don't
go looking for trouble,
but I guess we'll help.