Detective Conan Episode 1038 "Police Academy
Arc Wild Police Story CASE. Date Wataru"
[op]
[ed]
[eyecatch]
By one month after entering the academy,
the students have grown accustomed
to life at the police academy
and are finally permitted to leave
the academy and stay out overnight.
Onizuka's class, keep those hands moving!
Let's get this place cleaned
up quick so we can eat!
Yeah!
Sorry, Matsuda.
Could you lend me your dustpan?
Sure thing.
But you'd better Rei-turn it later.
Pathetic. Two points.
Don't you mean zero points?
Those two have become fast friends.
As Jinpei-chan's best friend,
I'm a little jealous.
Hagiwara-kun!
Don't forget we've got a
mixer on our next day off.
You can count on me.
Make sure you bring a bunch of hot guys.
Like that blond foreigner over there.
Who are you calling a foreigner?
Oh, uh...
Sorry, Instructor.
Excuse us!
Tomori Cleaning here.
I've come to collect your uniforms.
Sorry they're always so sweaty.
No problem.
Someday you'll be protecting us citizens.
It's a small price to pay.
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
Their youth is in full bloom!
The bond between Amuro and
his friends will never fall!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Police Academy Arc Wild Police Story
CASE. Date Wataru
"Police Academy Arc Wild Police
Story CASE. Date Wataru!"
Crap, I haven't prepared for English class.
That English teacher really hates me.
I'm scared they'll call on me.
Then get Furuya to teach you.
Hey, Furuya.
You look like you'd be fluent in English.
I'm all right.
Figures since you're blond and half.
I bet your English is better
than the instructor's.
Huh?
Hey, don't make assumptions about
people based on their appearance.
I, uh...
And...
Quit trying to look cool
by chewing on a toothpick.
It makes me sick.
S-Sorry.
As long as you understand.
Just be careful from now on.
Hey, Team Leader.
Have you got a crush on Furuya-chan?
You were oddly defensive of him
while we were cleaning, too.
What?
You don't need to hide it.
It doesn't bother me.
Obviously not. I've got a girlfriend.
Huh?
What?!
You don't have to be so shocked.
No way.
You told your police
academy friends about us?
Sorry, it just came up.
Neat and Tidy
Oh, come on. We promised to keep it a secret
until we could meet each other's parents.
Sorry.
Did you ask your dad about his schedule?
I'd like to meet him
sooner rather than later.
We can ignore my dad.
There you go again.
So, how's the academy?
It's pretty fun.
There's a combative guy, a flashy playboy,
a guy who's normally calm but secretly
researching something like crazy,
and a guy like you who attracts a lot of
attention just because he looks a little different.
Everyone's so interesting, I'm never bored.
I'll introduce you to them sometime, Natalie.
Okay. I'm looking forward to it.
Arresting techniques are based
on ancient Japanese martial arts.
These techniques were developed for
arresting suspects and criminals.
The most effective targets are the
chin, shoulder, body, and hands.
Methods include jabs, kicks, joint
locks, throws, chokes, holds,
police batons, police sticks,
and handcuffs. Anything goes.
The most important part
of arresting techniques...
...is bringing your target under control
without harming them or yourself.
Ippon! That's enough!
Good work.
Jeez, the team leader's crazy strong.
Damn it. I could beat him
in an ordinary fistfight.
And I'm better with women and cars.
But the team leader apparently
has a girlfriend.
Hey, why don't we go somewhere
this weekend to change our luck?
Sure, as long as it's a car or bike
shop and not a machine parts store.
If you're going somewhere, I'll go with you.
Then it's decided.
Where do you want to go,
a car shop or a bike shop?
What?
Speaking of bike shops, I saw a guy
with a strange tattoo the other day.
A strange tattoo?
Yeah, like a cup with a fancy base.
I think it's called a goblet?
That kind of design.
What was he like? Where does
he live? What's his name?
I don't know.
What's gotten into you, Morofushi-chan?
Sorry, Matsuda.
If you're so interested, why don't
we go to that bike shop tonight?
Ippon!
He's beaten ten guys?
Next, Furuya!
Yes, sir.
Now this'll be interesting.
Furuya's grades are better, but
who knows how this will turn out.
Get him, Zero!
Don't let lover boy beat you!
That's what's bothering you?
Begin.
Hey, Hagi. Wanna bet on the winner?
I'll bet a yakisoba roll from the
academy store on Zero winning.
Then I'll bet a melon
roll on the team captain.
He'll beat him. He's on a roll.
No, the team captain injured his
knee in his match against me.
Zero wouldn't overlook that.
You filthy cheater.
Zero?
Whoa, seriously?
That yakisoba roll is mine!
Bringing your opponent under control unharmed
only applies if you actually
bring him under control.
I'm disappointed in you, Furuya.
Why didn't you hit my knee?
Why did you hesitate?
If this were the real world,
you'd be badly injured,
and the suspect would be fleeing.
Mercy doesn't get you anywhere
with dangerous criminals.
Show any weakness, and you're finished.
They'll take full advantage of it.
All that's waiting for you is the
same terrible fate my dad suffered.
Unless you're stronger than everyone
else, you can't carry out justice.
Am I wrong?
Unless you're stronger than everyone
else, you can't carry out justice.
Come in.
Zero—
Oh, sorry. Were you asleep?
No, I was just lying down and thinking.
I see.
I'm about to head out with
Matsuda and Hagiwara.
Do you need anything?
Not really.
I see.
Sorry to have bothered you, Zero.
Sure.
Oh...
If you're going to the convenience store,
could you get me some toothpaste?
They're already gone.
Well, I guess I'll go out, too.
Team Captain Date?
Furuya.
Sorry about this afternoon at the dojo.
I went too far.
It's fine.
My dad's got nothing to do with you guys.
Wasn't your dad a police officer, too?
Yeah.
He was a patrol officer
assigned to a police box.
He was skinny and looked weak,
but I respected him.
Until that day my dad was off duty...
Hey, Dad. Why do you always
chew on toothpicks?
Your old man's skinny and
doesn't look very reliable.
I chew on these so bad guys
won't underestimate me.
Then buy me some toothpicks, too.
You'll have to make do with candy on a stick.
Dad, hurry up!
Yeah, sure.
It happened right after
my dad entered the store.
An agitated man covered
in someone else's blood
came running in with a wooden sword
in one hand and demanded money.
Naturally, there was panic inside
the store, but I wasn't scared.
He was just one guy. I knew my dad, the
police officer, would do something about it.
I had total faith in him,
but what I saw was...
You can have my wallet.
Take mine and spare the other customers.
My dad's a police officer!
He's gonna beat you up!
My words were like oil on fire.
The man swung his wooden sword
down on my dad over and over.
Eventually we heard the sound of sirens,
and the man left the convenience store.
But my dad ended up in
the hospital for a year.
He ended up quitting the force
because of his injuries.
I learned later that the
man was a gang member
who lost a dispute and was
looking for getaway money.
Apparently he caused injuries
at another store after that.
In other words, if my dad had been
strong and arrested that man there,
justice would've been carried out
without producing a single victim.
Sorry for making you listen to my nonsense.
Nobody make a sound!
What? Why can't you tell us?
That guy with the goblet tattoo
is a regular here, isn't he?
Why are you looking for him?
Hey, Morofushi. Tell him why
you're looking for that guy.
Because... Because I...
Morofushi...
I can't go sharing my customers'
personal information without a reason.
I'm telling you, he forgot why.
If you won't tell us—
I remember now.
What?
You know, didn't the team leader say
something at the dojo about his dad?
Yeah.
When I was a kid, I saw a guy
with eyebrows like his get beaten
by a yakuza-looking guy
at a convenience store.
Hagi, tell me more about that.
Come on, quit stalling.
Put your phones in the box.
O-Okay.
Is that everything?
Yeah.
Furuya.
There are two culprits.
If you and I handle one of them
each, we can take them down.
I'll draw the attention of the guy in the
beanie. While he's distracting, you—
Hey, this phone is a brand new model.
You idiot, we'll be able to buy whatever
we want once we finish this job.
Wait.
Something's not right.
Why aren't they stealing the money in
the register and fleeing immediately?
Who knows?
But rescuing all the customers
here right now is our top priority.
We haven't been tied up
yet. Now's our best chance.
What are you guys whispering about?
I'll kill you.
Damn it. The clerk was working with them.
Hey.
Shall we get this started?
Just how many of them are there?
Quit dragging your feet.
Walk quickly.
How much more?
Looks like about 400-500 thousand.
Nobody better make a sound.
Damn it. We need to do something
about these zip ties first.
What is he doing?
I see.
By passing a shoelace through the ties, we can
use the friction from rubbing against them to...
Nice thinking, Furuya.
Help me untie the others.
It's locked after all.
Anyway, what are the culprits after?
Probably the ATM cash resupply.
The resupply schedule is kept
secret to prevent theft,
but you can predict when it'll occur by checking
the ATM's approximate balance on security images.
I see.
So they couldn't have done
this without the clerk's help.
Yeah.
Anyway, why aren't they
concealing their faces?
The clerk wasn't even wearing sunglasses.
They may not intend to let their hostages
leave alive once they're finished.
B-But I just came here to get water.
I came to get snacks for my daughter.
Don't worry. We'll do something about it.
In any case, we need to come up
with a way to get out of here.
A switchboard.
This could work.
I can see why Team Captain Date
would think his dad is a
coward if that happened.
Yeah.
After all, he watched a police
officer grovel before a criminal.
I understand how he feels.
When my dad was mistakenly
arrested for murder,
everyone called me the son of a murderer.
Murderer
It almost made me hate him.
In my case, I managed not to crack
because the guys at the gym told
me to believe in my dad and wait.
Huh.
So, Morofushi.
I don't know what happened to you,
but if you tell us, our dumb advice
might be able to help you in some way.
Help...me...
Now?
No, look over there.
That convenience store's sign is flashing,
like Morse code.
Wait a minute. That's...
That's not like Morse code.
What? No way.
It's being remodeled?
Remodeling in Progress
We're terribly sorry for any inconvenience
I guess we'll have to go to
another convenience store.
Yeah.
The security company car
crossed the traffic light.
Go take down the remodeling sign.
Got it.
Yo!
Whoa, seriously? Isn't that a rifle?
Don't be a wuss. It's obviously a replica
for filming movies or something.
Hey, what movie are you guys
filming? Let us be in it.
What's happening? What's all that noise?
Three strange men have entered the store.
I'll be Tequila, some kind of police officer.
Idiots!
It doesn't matter if it's just
three of them. Kill them!
No way. Are they really filming a movie?
Oh my god, I'm so excited.
Hey, guys. They said they'd let us be extras.
It's pretty noisy out there. What's going on?
Sorry to have kept you waiting, Zero.
Hiro.
M-Morofushi? What are you doing here?
We saw the sign's Morse code and
came to take down the culprits.
Not by force...
But with numbers.
We're just doing what your dad tried to do.
What?
Right, Hagi?
Yeah.
What do you mean, what my dad tried to do?
I was actually at the convenience store
when your dad was beaten by that gangster.
You were there?
Yeah.
You were probably too distracted
by your bloodied dad to notice,
but several of the men's accomplices
entered the store after that.
Hey, what are you doing?
The cops are coming. Let's get out of here.
Your dad probably noticed his
accomplices were in a nearby car.
Even if he'd attempted to arrest him,
if his accomplices had joined the fight,
he couldn't have beaten them.
If a fight broke out inside the store
or if they barricaded themselves inside,
the other customers could've been harmed.
There were a bunch of us in
there at the time, like me,
a pregnant woman, and an old man.
And since the police arrived so quickly,
your dad probably reported the crime
and was trying to keep him from going deeper
into the store until the police arrived.
So, Team Leader,
your dad wasn't begging for his life.
It was his cop heart that refused to see
anyone get hurt that made him do that.
Hello?
Hey, Dad. How you doing?
Wataru?
Why the sudden phone call?
What? There's someone you want me to meet?
You're already that age, huh?
I'm already 22. You probably forgot
since we haven't met in a while.
Anyway, how's the police academy going?
Think you'll become a good cop?
Yeah.
Not as good as you, though.
Don't be ridiculous.