Detective Conan Episode 1039
"The Flying Jack-o'-lantern"
[op]
[ed]
[eyecatch]
Whew, we just barely caught the last train.
Kuwano (30)
Officer Worker
Kajiyama (30)
Office Worker
Not that it matters since
I've got tomorrow off.
You're lucky.
I have to be up early tomorrow.
Road Closed
The wind's awfully strong today.
The ground is uneven. Watch your step.
Good evening.
The wind's strong today, isn't it?
Yikes.
What's this thing?
It's creepy.
The shopping center is holding a
jack-o'-lantern carving contest on Halloween.
Halloween
Jack-o'-lantern Carving Contest
Beika City Shopping Center
See?
Huh, really?
What is it?
Did something just...?
What is that?
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
It's a Halloween supernatural phenomenon!
What's the truth behind the flying pumpkins?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Flying Jack-o'-lantern
"The Flying Jack-o'-lantern!"
Café Poirot
We will be closed until this afternoon
I'm sorry, but we're closed
until this afternoon.
Huh?
Oh, it's you, Conan-kun.
Kogoro-no-ojisan and Ran-neechan went out.
They told me to stay here.
That's fine. Come in.
Here.
You're good with your usual
seat and milk tea, right?
Yeah, thanks.
Are those pumpkins for Halloween?
Impressive as always, Conan-kun.
That's right.
I asked a farmer I know
to share some with me.
Here you go.
What?
You can give me a hand in
exchange for your milk tea.
Halloween was originally an ancient
Celtic religious celebration, right?
They held their harvest
festival on October 31st.
It's the day the souls of their ancestors
and evil spirits would visit.
They used turnips to ward off evil spirits.
And it's said that when the tradition
came to the United States,
it became pumpkins instead because
they were easier to acquire.
Here, all done.
Thank you.
You know a lot about Halloween, Conan-kun.
I saw it on TV the other day.
Then you must know these pumpkins
are called jack-o'-lanterns, right?
A scoundrel named Jack makes a deal
with the Devil that he'll
never go to Hell when he dies.
Later, when Jack dies,
he's not allowed into Heaven because of
all the wicked deeds he committed in life.
Because of his agreement,
he can't go to Hell either.
So with no other options,
Jack wanders forever, carrying with
him the lantern the Devil gave him.
Oh, right. Conan-kun, do you know
about the jack-o'-lantern ghost
that appeared around here last night?
What?
Yeah!
Hey, what's that?
Huh?
What are those?
I'm scared.
[Eye-witness Account] Jack-o'-lantern Ghost!
308 views
Like   Dislike
Aren't those jack-o'-lanterns?
Apparently quite a few people
saw them late last night.
Huh.
Making these was easier than I expected.
Maybe I didn't need to close
the shop this morning.
By the way, where's Amuro-san?
He called a few days ago.
He asked for some time off.
He left me to run the café
on my own. Selfish, right?
I wish I could put a collar on
him and keep him at the shop.
Hey, Conan-kun.
You and Amuro-san are close, right?
Yeah.
What about it?
Is Amuro-san...?
Azusa-san, it's an emergency.
Tamie-san, calm down.
They've been stolen.
What?
Café Poirot
We are closed today
Here you go.
These people are café regulars.
This is Tamie-san.
She's a preschool teacher.
She was in the hospital for six months
and was just released last week.
Kono Tamie (50)
Preschool Teacher
I'm going back to work at
the preschool next week.
I can't wait to see the children's smiles.
Did you all meet each other here?
No, we're neighbors who live in the area.
Kashiyama Tomomi (29)
Housewife
Mizunuma Satoshi (60)
Former University Professor
Our houses are next door to each
other, so we get along nicely.
This year the three of us planned
to carve jack-o'-lanterns
for the shopping center's contest.
Azusa-san shared three
of her pumpkins with us.
And those were stolen?
That's right.
Yesterday afternoon after
receiving the pumpkins,
we gathered at my house and
carved jack-o'-lanterns.
Since it was our first time,
we thought Tamie-san could show us how.
Tamie-san is a master carver
who's won the jack-o'-lantern carving
contest three years in a row.
It's certainly terrible if
your pumpkin was stolen.
It wasn't just mine that was stolen.
Their pumpkins were taken, too.
Wait up!
I understand stealing
Tamie-san's jack-o'-lantern.
But you couldn't even attempt to flatter
us by claiming ours were any good.
I think it was a nasty prank.
I always take my winning
jack-o'-lanterns to the preschool.
The children love them.
I was glad I was released from the hospital
just in time to carve a
jack-o'-lantern this year, but...
Three stolen pumpkins...
People saw three ghosts around here, right?
I heard about that, too.
Last night some jack-o'-lantern
ghosts appeared, right?
Ghosts?
Do ghosts really exist?
Unable to go to Heaven or Hell,
carrying the lantern the Devil gave to him...
Conan-kun?
Jack still wanders the Earth.
Azusa-san, let's check things out.
This is Tamie-san's house.
To the right is Tomomi-san's house,
and to the left is Mizunuma-san's house.
I live with my husband and daughter.
My daughter attends Tamie-san's preschool.
She's very excited to see Tamie-san.
I'm looking forward to it, too.
I was a university professor
until I retired last year.
My wife passed away two years ago, and
my only son lives at his company's dorm.
I currently enjoy a nice easy life on my own.
Where were your pumpkins
before they were stolen?
Mine was on top of the gatepost.
Mine was also on top of
the entrance gatepost.
Mine was on top of a table
in front of the front door.
Around what time last night was the
last time you saw your pumpkins?
I saw mine around ten last night
when I locked the front
gate and went back inside.
My husband came home after eight.
That's the last time I saw mine.
My daughter and I went to sleep after that.
Last night my son suddenly
stopped by with some coworkers.
I saw mine when I let them in.
I think it was just before seven.
We were up all night after that.
My son's coworkers just left.
So the pumpkins were there until
around ten when Tamie-san saw them.
I wonder how the culprit
carried off the pumpkins.
I think it would be difficult to
carry three large pumpkins at once.
Maybe they used a car.
I don't think that's possible.
Last night they were doing some construction
work on a gas pipe at that corner over there.
The notice we received said the road
would be closed to vehicles after 10PM.
Road Closed
Could they have ridden
a bicycle or motorcycle?
I don't think I heard a
motorcycle drive by yesterday.
But the wind was really strong last night.
It was howling. It scared me.
Even the carving contest poster that
was up over there was blown away.
Maybe we can figure out who did it
if we see that camera's footage.
You're right. Let's go ask.
I'm sorry. I'm feeling a little tired.
Tamie-san, are you all right?
I'm sorry.
Don't push yourself too hard.
You should take a break.
I'll go with her.
Shall we go, then?
Yes.
Kokubo Masashi (35)
Jack-o'-lantern Carving
Contest Committee Member
All right. Now we can see the footage.
I installed the camera because lately people
have been drawing graffiti on my fence.
Could you show us the footage
from after ten last night?
Got it.
Here you go.
There's a lot of traffic.
It's a shortcut from the station.
Everyone looks suspicious to me.
You'd need a large bag or something
to hide three pumpkins.
But no one's carrying anything like that.
Huh?
Could you rewind a little?
Sure.
That's Kajiyama-kun and Kuwano-kun who
live in the apartment building over there.
Are they running from something?
They seem to be in a big hurry.
Oh, last night?
It was quite the surprise.
Are you talking about the
jack-o'-lantern ghosts?
Yeah.
I was walking with my coworker
Kuwano when they suddenly appeared.
How many ghosts were there?
There were three things.
Wait, do I really mean three ghosts?
Where did the ghosts come from
and which way did they go?
That's actually about all I remember.
I had a lot to drink last night.
What about the coworker
you said you were with?
He's got work today.
I talked to him on the phone this morning,
and he said he didn't remember
anything about last night.
While you were running from the ghosts,
did you see the pumpkins in
front of a row of houses?
Sorry, I can't remember.
Beika City Shopping Center
Supermarket Tatamaru
So we still don't know what the
flying jack-o'-lanterns really were.
Sounds like it.
What's that?
The wind's strong today.
Keep a firm grip or you'll lose it.
Thank you.
Beika Books
Hey, mister.
Hey, it's you guys again.
Did you meet up with Kajiyama-kun?
Where can you buy those balloons?
Those? We give them out to people
who shop at the shopping center.
They're pretty popular.
The ones I made yesterday
were gone right away.
You make those balloons?
I'm a committee member for this year's
jack-o'-lantern carving contest.
I put up posters and make balloons.
It's a lot of work.
I see.
I didn't get home until late last night
since I was putting up these posters.
I thought I'd take my car,
but there was a road I couldn't enter
because of some gas construction.
We apologize for the inconvenience
Gas Construction Underway
Since I walked the rest of
the way, I was exhausted.
Did you put up one of those posters
across from Tamie-san's house?
Yeah, I did.
But it was gone when I checked this morning.
The wind must've blown it away.
Around what time did you put up the poster?
I think it was between ten and eleven.
Could I get one of those balloons?
Sorry, but like I said, they're popular.
I'm all out of balloons for today.
Could you come back tomorrow?
Where do you keep the balloons you've made?
They're in my car at my house.
I see. So that's how it is.
Beika Liquor
Beika Real Estate
Well, I've got to prepare
for tomorrow. See you later.
Azusa-san, Mizunuma-san.
I know who took your pumpkins.
Thank you for waiting.
Tamie-san's still not feeling well.
I think we should have her rest at home.
I see.
Anyway, Conan-kun, did you
really figure out who did it?
Yeah.
The culprit was after Tamie-san's
jack-o'-lantern after all.
Right, Mizunuma-san?
What do you mean, Conan-kun?
Why would Mizunuma-san want to
take Tamie-san's jack-o'-lantern?
Honestly, I don't know
what his motive was yet,
but considering the circumstances
before and after they disappeared,
there are a lot of things that make
it look like Mizunuma-san did it.
First, where did the culprit go?
The pumpkins were taken after 10PM.
If they went that way, the gas construction
workers would've seen their face.
Road Closed
If they went this way,
they would've been seen by the security
camera at Kokubo-san's house.
Then there're the pumpkins.
Where did the culprit hide three pumpkins?
Mizunuma-san probably originally planned
to keep the pumpkins in his house.
Since he lives alone, they'd be easy to hide.
But something unexpected happened yesterday.
His son brought a couple of coworkers home.
They would've found it suspicious if he
entered the house with three pumpkins,
so he had to find a new hiding place.
Kokubo-san's garage is across from the
fence surrounding Mizunuma-san's house.
There are two cars parked in the garage,
and they're filled with
jack-o'-lantern balloons.
I see.
The best place to hide
a leaf is in the forest.
That's what you're saying, right?
The balloons inside the cars
will be distributed tomorrow.
He just needs to find an opportunity
before then to move the pumpkins
from the car into his house.
That was probably Mizunuma-san's thinking.
But I can't climb over that fence.
You probably could with
something to stand on,
like the table in your yard.
There were footprints on
it when I looked earlier.
You probably used this table
to climb over the fence.
It wouldn't be impossible with my hands free,
but wasn't the culprit
carrying three pumpkins?
My hands would be full.
I couldn't climb the fence like that.
You could if you had an accomplice.
That's right.
What?
It would've been possible
with Tomomi-san's help.
But... I didn't do anything...
What makes you say that?
Tomomi-san said she put her daughter
to bed at eight and then went to sleep.
But she's probably lying about that.
There was a jack-o'-lantern
carving contest poster
on that utility pole that was blown away.
Kokubo-san put up the poster.
The gas construction started at 10PM,
so Kokubo-san must've put
the poster up after 10PM.
By morning, the poster had been blown away.
Since Tomomi-san went to bed at eight,
she had no opportunity to see the
poster in front of Tamie-san's house.
So how did you know a jack-o'-lantern
carving contest poster had been put up?
After receiving the pumpkins from Tomomi-san,
Mizunuma-san probably removed three
jack-o'-lantern balloons from the car
in Kokubo-san's garage and swapped
in the three real pumpkins.
There must've been a strong
gust when Mizunuma-san
climbed down from the fence that blew
away the jack-o'-lantern balloons.
Those were probably the jack-o'-lantern
ghosts Kajiyama-san and Kuwano-san saw.
But why did they steal all three
pumpkins, including their own?
Probably because of that.
The security camera...
They considered the possibility
the footage would be checked.
A single pumpkin could
be placed inside a bag.
They did it so suspicion
wouldn't fall on passersby?
If Mizunuma-san's son and his coworkers
were here until a moment ago,
then the pumpkins are still
inside Kokubo-san's car, right?
I'm sorry.
The boy is right. Mizunuma-san
and I hid the pumpkins.
But there's a reason for it.
Could you tell us?
Coming.
Who is it?
Happy Halloween!
Surprise!
Oh, my. Is this for me?
So that's why.
Remember how we told you Tamie-san's
jack-o'-lanterns are popular?
But this year Tamie-san was in the hospital.
We thought she wouldn't be able to carve one.
So the preschool children decided to make
a jack-o'-lantern to give to Tamie-san.
But Tamie-san was released early, and she
fully intended to carve a jack-o'-lantern.
She even got Azusa-san to
share her pumpkins with her.
We decided to hide it so as not
to disappoint the children.
We never thought this would happen.
We're sorry for what we did.
We're sorry.
Azusa-san and I will handle
the jack-o'-lanterns you hid.
You can count on us.
But...
We're sorry.
Thank you.
I'm glad this year's Halloween
turned out happy this year.
Apparently the shopping center's Halloween
jack-o'-lantern carving contest was a huge success.
However, during that time,
we were caught up in a horrifying
plot taking place in Shibuya...
Episode Preview
I'm going to go check things out.
What?!
While I was tied up and rolling around,
they were talking about a bomb.
The Case of Ayumi's Illustrated Diary 2
The next episode of Conan is "The
Case of Ayumi's Illustrated Diary 2!"
Bump
Next Conan's hint!
A bump!
Don't miss the next episode.
What's happening in Shibuya?
We'll be waiting for you
at the movie theater!