[op]
Illustrated Diary
Ayumi's illustrated diary.
Kobayashi-sensei said the illustrated
diary I drew the other day was great.
Ogino Produce Store
Jewelry Kaneko
She called the Detective Boys super
cool for solving the jewel theft case.
Ogino Produce Store
Jewelry Kaneko
This time I'll be including
even more drawings
Fujioka
Illustrated Diary
so she'll give us even more praise.
The Case of Ayumi's Illustrated
Diary Part 2 begins now!
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
Ayumi's illustrated diaries
depict the events of a crime.
What is the truth behind the bomb threat?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Case of Ayumi's Illustrated Diary 2
"The Case of Ayumi's Illustrated Diary 2!"
It started when we were on
our way home from a drive.
Conan-kun, Conan-kun.
What's that?
Something's flashing.
I see flashing?
Is there trouble?
Flash, flash, flash.
Flaaash, flaaash, flaaash.
...What does that mean?
It's something code...
What's it called again?
You mean Morse code?
Oh right! It's called Morse code!
Someone decipher it!
So, what does it mean?
Isn't that Morse code?
Yeah.
Not only that, but they're signaling SOS.
Good job spotting that, Ayumi-chan.
Is someone being held captive up there?
Who knows?
I'm going to go check things out.
You guys wait here.
Don't let your guard down.
He kind of looks like a shachihoko.
Are you all right?
There's a bomb!
Someone's planted a bomb in the building!
What?!
Run!
Who planted the bomb?!
I don't know.
I just came here to make a delivery.
While I was tied up and rolling around,
I heard them talking about a bomb.
Professor, we need to
report this to the police!
Y-You're right.
Huh? Where's Conan-kun?
What?
He's not still inside, is he?
It's dangerous, kid. We need to run.
I'll be fine. Don't worry about me.
I can't do that.
Hey, wait! Hey!
There's no way a kid could disarm a bomb.
Put me down!
Detectives Takagi and
Chiba, you got here quick.
We received an anonymous tip that a
light in that office was signaling SOS.
Anonymous?
Detective Takagi, he's the man
who was being held in the office.
Could you tell us about that?
First, what's your name?
My name is Danno Masaru.
Danno Masaru (26)
Motorcycle Deliveryman
Written as "Danno Dai,"
read as "Danno Masaru."
DD Motorcycle Delivery
I'm a motorcycle deliveryman.
When I went to the third-story office
in that building to deliver a package
and receive a signature, a gun fell out
of the pocket of a nasty-looking guy.
Why did he suddenly drop a gun?
I think he was trying to get his
stamp out of his inside pocket.
I see.
So you were captured because you saw his gun.
Yeah, I guess.
I lost consciousness when I was
struck on the head from behind.
When I came to, I was tied
up and couldn't move.
That's when I heard them talking.
They said they didn't need to kill me
because they'd blow up the whole building.
Why were the culprits discussing
that in front of you?
Because, uh...
I'd been unconscious until moments before.
I see.
You were pretending to be asleep.
Exactly.
After the two of them
left, as you all know...
You used the light switch
to signal SOS in Morse code.
While looking like a shachihoko.
Hey, mister.
Why did you think to call for
helping using Morse code?
Why?
Because I used to be a Boy Scout.
I happened to remember the
Morse code I learned then.
I see.
By the way, is that your motorcycle?
Yeah, that's my beloved bike.
We just received word from the
bomb squad inside the building.
They found a possible bomb
in the third-story office.
They're hearing what sounds like the second
hand of a clock ticking inside a cardboard box.
It really was an SOS!!
Did they find a bomb?
The SOS was real...
Was there a bomb?
So it was Morse code
Seriously lol I'm gonna go check it out lol
Yooo this is crazy lol
I'm impressed by whoever deciphered the Morse code
Did they find a bomb?
Is it gonna explode?
Is there anyone inside the building? Was everyone evacuated?
It's really a bomb lol
← You should evacuate...
They've deployed a bomb squad!
The SOS was for real!!
That's near me lol
I hope they send the bomb squad lol
No way!!
Don't stand there and watch, run!
A bombing or terrorist attack...
Run away, guys!!
Such a dangerous country
No way...
Scary! Gonna lock my door
A bomb... why...
Good luck bomb squad
So dangerous...
I sense an impending catastrophe lol
Heck yeah bomb squad!!
What... my neighborhood is so dangerous...
Another peaceful day in Beika City.
So much for cat country
It won't be funny it blows up lol
Isn't it just a prank?
Evacuate those kids!
I can't believe something like
this happening near me...
The bomb squad is so cool
What am I gonna do if it explodes?
Children...? But why?
loooool
Civilians should get away from the area.
Those rubberneckers have seen some shit,
you can tell from their expressions
What!! Holy crap
Why... why do incidents like
this happen every day...
So many rubberneckers lol too funny lol
What's happening?
I hope nothing happens...
The bomb squad will do something about it!
Why...
Good luck bomb squad
Isn't it clickbait?
Their lack of sense of danger is frightening
Seems like there's a real bomb?
The police sure have got it rough
Is everything okay?
Where was the bomb? Inside a building?
A terrorist attack? Scary
You should get away from there!
Watch out!
Boom!
...is what we thought would happen,
but all they found inside the
box was an ordinary alarm clock.
BRRRING     BRRRING
We thoroughly searched the building,
but we were unable to find any explosives.
What should we do, Takagi-san?
We'll remove the blockade
surrounding the building
and leave just part of the forensics team.
Yes, sir.
So they never found a bomb.
But I know I heard them say they set a bomb.
I wonder why they didn't kill
you if they hadn't set a bomb.
That's an ominous thing to say so casually.
Well, no explosion at all is
the best possible outcome.
Conan-kun, where have you been?
Oh, you know, around.
Hello?
Yes.
What?
Takagi-san, there was an armed robbery
at the Jewelry Kaneko in Beika City.
What?
Jewelry Kaneko?
That's the store on our route to school.
Ogino Produce
Jewelry Kaneko
Unbelievably, a new armed
robbery had taken place.
SOS Signal and Confinement Case
And that's how the SOS signal
and confinement case
took an unexpected turn!
I can't believe they were robbed again.
How unfortunate.
I see. So that's how it is.
What?
Professor, could you bring the car around?
Conan-kun, you figured
something out, didn't you?
You just said, "So that's how it is."
We were made accomplices in an
armed robbery without knowing it.
Accomplices in an armed robbery?
Yeah.
Written Danno Dai
Read Danno Masaru
Working With
Armed Robbers
That Danno guy is probably
working with the robbers.
What?
It's suspicious he stayed in the building
and used Morse code to call for help
when he didn't know when
the bomb would go off,
and if or when anyone
would notice his signal.
But don't you also find it strange an armed
robbery occurred during a fake bomb scare?
Ultimately, it caused a lot of
police to gather at the building.
They even dispatched a bomb squad.
It's a good diversion.
But couldn't it be a coincidence?
You need proof to suspect someone.
That's what I thought, so I observed
him closely and didn't notice one.
Didn't notice what?
A bump.
A bump?
He said he was knocked out by a blow,
but there wasn't a bump on the back
of his head or even any kind of wound.
If he wasn't struck, then...
You mean everything he said was a lie?
In other words, we and the
police were fooled by that man.
Not quite.
What does that mean?
I thought he was suspicious, so I
stuck a transmitter on his motorcycle.
What?
Then we're currently headed towards...
Yeah. Danno's bike is parked up ahead.
Hey, look.
Isn't that Danno-san?
He's not asleep, is he?
This time he's got a big bump on his head.
He's unconscious,
but he's all right. He's alive.
But why?
They probably had a falling out.
Mitsuhiko, call an ambulance and the police.
Got it.
Try not to touch anything, guys.
There it is.
What's that?
A dash cam.
I thought he might have one since
the keys weren't in his pocket
and his bike was parked strangely.
He parked his bike so the warehouse would
be visible and left his dash cam running.
You mean he didn't trust his accomplices?
Yeah, that's what that means.
We've got a clear view of them.
That looked painful.
I'm going to skip ahead.
All right.
Captured clearly on camera.
Hello, Detective Chiba?
We've identified the robbers' car.
It's a blue car, license plate number...
Fifteen minutes ago,
they drove west from the abandoned
factory in Haido City 7-chome.
Got it. We'll put out an APB.
Report from the traffic monitoring system.
Target vehicle has been spotted.
Let's roll.
Target vehicle is heading
west through Haido City.
Vehicles in the area head there
immediately and secure the target.
Fleeing vehicle spotted.
Currently heading north from
Dashinomoto Stadium on Koume Highway.
Professor, exit at the next interchange.
Let's hurry.
Got it.
Is this...?
A car chase!
Speed limits were broken and tires squealed in
a back-and-forth description-defying chase
between culprits and police that
would make even Hollywood blanch.
And then, a giant explosion!
...never happened, and on top of that...
Report from PC21.
They lost sight of the fleeing
vehicle north of Hama Cemetery.
Once again...
I wonder where the culprits' vehicle went.
We're past the stadium.
Where should we head now?
They were heading west before
they were spotted here.
They started heading north
the moment they were found.
Take a left at that light.
What?
How do you know that's the right way?
If they started heading north when
they were spotted by the police,
it's hard to believe their
destination is that way.
Furthermore, normally your pursuers would assume
you'd keep heading north once you lost your tail.
So you do the opposite
and head south instead.
It's what I would do.
I see.
They'll avoid highways and major
roadways that have security cameras,
which means they'll probably take this road.
We're looking for a blue car, right?
Yeah, but...
Where is it?
There it is.
A blue car.
That's definitely the car from the video.
Nice work, Ayumi-chan!
Yeah!
Professor, don't let them get away.
I know.
This time, is this actually...?
A car chase!
And then maybe this'll happen.
Transformation
Button
Transform!
Kachang, kachang!
B [for Beetle]
Whirrr!
What's that?
Bro!
Killer Beetle Right Straight!
Kablam!
...which isn't what happened.
We quietly followed the car...
...and arrived at a parking lot
outside a housing complex.
What are they doing?
They're trying to steal a car.
That's terrible.
We need to stop them.
I know.
Will there be a shootout?
Shootout!!
Obviously not.
But we can't just sit here doing nothing.
Professor, call the police.
Got it.
Then Conan-kun approached the robbers.
Anyway, Bro, why were the police chasing us?
We were basically obeying the speed limit.
They probably realized it was a stolen car.
You think so?
We just stole that car this morning.
Quit your whining.
We made off with all this treasure.
You're right.
Your plans are always perfect, Bro.
But why did you betray Danno-san?
Why?
Because the bigger the share,
the better, obviously.
Wait, who are you?
I see.
So you intended to use and
discard him from the start.
What?
Who is this kid?
You're the one who planned this, right?
You asked Danno-san to cause a disturbance
so you could rob the
jewelry store, didn't you?
Kid, I don't know why you thought
you should get involved,
but it's way past your bedtime.
The attack on the jewelry store
itself was simple enough.
All you had to do was crash the dump truck
you stole from the factory into the store.
How do you know about that?
Were you watching?
Since you were caught by a child like me,
doesn't that mean your plan was a failure?
Want me to tell you why it failed?
Yeah, why don't you tell us?
It's because Danno-san knew you'd betray him.
I'm telling you this for your own good.
You should give up and turn yourselves in.
Bro, wh-wh-what should we do?
Kid, you should turn around and go home.
Otherwise, you'll regret it.
I thought you might say that.
And nasty adults like you should be punished.
Take this!
Killer shot!
Pow!
Wumph!
Yeah!
And that's how the robbers were rounded
up and the jewels were recovered.
We did it!
The other culprit knocked out at the
abandoned factory was arrested, too.
Like Conan-kun deduced, after the diversion,
when he went to collect his share,
he was struck on the head from behind.
Jewelry Kaneko
The owner of the store was very
happy when we returned the jewels.
As a reward for solving the case,
Detective Takagi is treating us again.
All right!
I-It's just before payday, too.
I believe Detective Takagi
said it's just before payday.
I guess we can't hope for a fancy meal.
That's not what happened at all.
There was a very extravagant
meal waiting for us.
Thanks for treating us to all we can eat.
Thanks for the food.
More, please.
It's not all you can eat, guys.
Episode Preview
Did you see the culprit?
Uh, no. I didn't see anything.
We have no idea what he's doing.
Detective Takagi, why did he go
to the police in the first place?
Why can't you tell us?
I can't remember.
If I'm right, then...
The Unstated Alibi
The next episode of Conan
is "The Unstated Alibi!"
Ballpoint Pen
Next Conan's hint!
A ballpoint pen!
Huh?
I think I'll draw more diary entries.
Don't miss the next episode.
Please don't.
Thanks for the food.