Detective Conan Episode
1041 "The Unstated Alibi"
Hey, all ones.
Takezawa Watch Store
Yes, it's 1:11.
What's so special about that?
It means I'm lucky today.
North Kanto Ramen
D-Does it?
I might be having eel
bowls for dinner tonight.
We're leaving you guys behind.
That was a police officer.
It felt like he was rushing to a crime scene.
Maybe something happened.
Calm down. Calm down, okay?
Take your time. Tell me what happened.
I was pushed by a strange young woman
from the top of these stone steps.
What?
Did anyone see what happened?
No, huh?
"A young woman" isn't enough
of a description to go off of.
That guy...
Hey, Mister.
Did you happen to see someone suspicious?
What?
Did you see the culprit?
Uh, no. I didn't see anything.
Well, bye.
He didn't, huh?
It seemed like he wanted to say something.
Maybe he really did see something.
Then why did he say he didn't?
Maybe he doesn't want to get
involved with the police?
Why not?
For example...
Maybe he himself has done something wrong.
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
The witness refuses to speak.
What is the truth behind
this series of cases?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Unstated Alibi
"The Unstated Alibi!"
If he's about to get up to something...
Then we'll stop him.
He's a man wearing a black down
jacket with a medium build.
He has a shaved head.
Haven't seen him.
Hey.
We figured it out. He's over there.
Oh, him?
Apparently his name is Kanieda-san.
He lives in Shikabone City.
Shikabone is rather far away from here.
Yeah.
Even by car, it's about an
hour away from Beika City.
Is he a regular?
I think today was his first time here.
Then why do you know his name?
We got a call.
There should be a man named Kanieda
from Shikabone City there.
One moment, please.
Is there a Kanieda-sama
from Shikabone City here?
Yes, that's me!
Kanieda from Shikabone City.
I'm Kanieda from Shikabone City.
Hello? Yes, good seeing
you the other day. What?
I see. In that case, we'll have
to reschedule for another day.
Yes, bye.
They were supposed to meet at one,
but he couldn't make it anymore.
That's probably what the call was about.
After all, he left immediately after that.
Did that person do anything strange
besides receive a phone call?
Strange? Not really.
If you're looking for that man,
could you deliver this lighter to him?
He forgot it here.
Okay.
About that...
We have no idea what he's doing.
What do you mean by that?
Well...
Yasuda Pork Buns
First he headed to the shopping center.
So good.
Oh, it's so good. I've never
tasted anything so good.
So good.
100-yen Shop
Next he headed to a 100-yen shop.
These are pretty decent.
Tableware
How much are these?
No, wait. Everything's 100 yen, right?
What a dumb question. Excuse me.
Then he wandered around the area for a while.
What a cute baby.
They look so smart, too.
There, there.
He wandered around Beika City for about
an hour while closely watching the time.
Hello? Yes.
Yes. I see. Yes.
An inbound train stopping at
Midoridai will be arriving shortly.
Then he got on the train and left.
Totally nonsensical, right?
Normally someone doing something
wrong would sneak around
and avoid being seen,
but he did the opposite.
He repeatedly took actions
to draw attention to himself.
And we talked to lots of people,
but nobody mentioned anything
that sounded like a case.
It's possible we just imagined
he was up to no good.
No, there's something odd
about that Kanieda guy.
He had a cell phone, right?
So why did he receive a call at a café?
And he got on an inbound train.
He should've headed in the opposite
direction if he were going home to Shikabone City.
And since that train stopped one
station over at Midoridai...
Beika
Midoridai
Kokubo
Midoridai Station
Maybe he's planning to do
something here in Midoridai.
But where should we look for him?
We could try talking to the police, but...
What's that?
That was him.
But if he's with the police, then...
Does that mean he did something?
They're probably headed to
the Midoridai police station.
What? His name is Usui-san?
Usui Eiichi (35)
Yeah.
Usui Eiichi-san, who lives here in Midoridai.
We even checked his drivers license.
Then why did he lie about being
Kanieda from Shikabone City?
There's that, too.
Detective Takagi, why did
the police pick him up?
He's a person of interest in an injury case.
What?
Just now, behind Midoridai Park, a
woman who lives nearby found a man
who'd been struck on the
back of the head with a log.
The victim is Hachiya
Takeru-san from Midoridai.
Damn it.
Hachiya Takeru (45)
I don't know who it was, but they
suddenly hit me from behind.
Quick slacking off, officers!
Go find the culprit and bring him to me!
According to his neighbors,
he's not a very nice person.
The man got into a rather
fierce argument with Hachiya?
Kakimoto Sueko (28)
Several days earlier, outside the station.
I'd seen the man several times before,
so I figured he was a resident of Midoridai.
Inspector.
We found this on the pen on the ground.
E.U.?
Eiichi Usui.
He's the man we identified as
our primary person of interest.
I admit I got into a fight with Hachiya
because I have a grudge against him.
But I just lost this somewhere,
and I haven't been to the park.
Then where were you and what were you doing
today around 1PM when Hachiya was attacked?
W-Well, I...
Why can't you tell us?
I can't remember.
I know. At exactly that time,
I experienced temporary amnesia.
It's probably him.
His lie is extremely unconvincing.
Wait. Hachiya was attacked around 1PM today?
Yeah, according to Hachiya-san's testimony.
Then he's innocent.
What?
He has an alibi.
He was in Beika City around that time.
That's right.
Yeah.
What?
He forgot something in Beika
City while he was there.
His fingerprints should be on this.
What? The kids saw him?
They're witnesses?
Did something happen?
Someone claims to have seen you in
Beika City when the incident occurred.
N-No! I've never been to Beika City!
What? He denied it?!
Yeah.
He said it must've been someone else.
But...
Excuse me, Takagi-san.
I see. Thank you.
None of Usui-san's fingerprints
were on the lighter you turned in.
What?
In other words, the man you saw in
Beika City wasn't Usui Eiichi-san,
but someone else.
MPD Midoridai Police Station
But it was definitely him.
Yeah.
Then why won't Usui say he
has an alibi when he does?
There must be some reason he can't.
Could it be?
Found it.
Telephone Book
Shikabone City
There really is a Kanieda
from Shikabone City.
What?
Kanieda Akira
Looks like there's only one.
Kanieda Akira...
If we check out this person,
we may be able to figure out why Usui
Eiichi is behaving so mysteriously.
The Next Day
To Beika City
Current Time
Destination
Sawabukuro
Local Express
Stops At Every Station
Hey, all ones again today.
I really am lucky.
Hey, hurry up. Let's go.
Coming.
Huh? They're leaving. Hey, wait.
Kanieda Stamps and Seals
What? Your neighbor Kanieda
Akira-san is in the hospital?
Yeah, apparently he was hit by a car
yesterday afternoon on the other side of the station.
A traffic accident...
If you kids have business with
Akira-kun, why don't you come with me?
Would that be all right?
I was just on my way to visit him.
Shikabone City General Hospital
According to the nurse,
he's not seriously injured,
but he still hasn't regained consciousness.
Excuse us, Akira-kun.
What? This is him?
Kanieda Akira (36)
This is Kanieda Akira-kun.
They look similar, don't they?
He and that Usui guy...
Look exactly alike.
Anyway, what was he doing on
the south side of the station?
He thinks it's bad luck.
Bad luck?
Akira-kun's been living with his
mother since his father passed away.
Shikabone City Saruwatari Dental Care
About a year ago, his mother had some
dentures made by a well-known dentist
named Saruwatari-sensei on the
south side of the station.
Saruwatari Kanzo (40)
But shortly afterwards, something
unfortunate happened.
Mom, I'm home.
You'll catch a cold if you nap there.
Hey, Mom.
Mom?
Mom! Wake up! Mom!
She fell asleep while wearing the dentures
and they got caught in her throat.
She didn't wake up after that.
It wasn't an accident!
It wasn't an accident.
Those dentures were poorly made.
That quack Saruwatari killed my mom.
That's what you call unjustified
resentment, Akira-kun.
That quack killed my mom.
Because that dentist is over there...
He'd consider the south side
of the station unlucky.
Then why did he go there?
You said Kanieda-san's accident
happened yesterday afternoon.
Did it happen to be around one?
Yeah, I heard it was just after one.
I knew it.
That's the same time Usui-san started
wandering around Beika City.
That's around the time we
saw all ones on the clock.
So, what about it?
If I'm right, then...
When Kanieda Akira-san was
transported here by ambulance,
did he have any possessions on him?
Possessions?
What are these?
Gloves and rope?
Was he planning on doing some kind of work?
Could it be?
Yeah, probably.
Shikabone City Saruwatari Dental Care
Hours
Appointments Accepted
Until Noon
Afternoon Appointments
From 14:00
Saruwatari-sensei lives alone,
And he apparently always eats
lunch at home next door.
Then like you suspected...
Yeah, he was probably aiming for that window.
Midoridai Apartments
I got the landlord's testimony.
Usui-san suddenly shaved his head the day
before yesterday even though
he'd worn it long before.
MPD Midoridai Police Station
I don't know why, but these
children insist on seeing you.
Uh, have we met?
We met yesterday in Beika City.
You mean...
We weren't wrong. It really was him.
But I've never been to Beika City.
Kanieda Akira-san asked
you to lie, didn't he?
He wanted you to be his double
in his plot to kill the dentist.
I see. So he was plotting a murder.
Yes.
It may have been unjustified,
but Kanieda-san couldn't
forgive Saruwatari-sensei
and attempted to avenge his mother.
But suspicion would've fallen
on him due to his motive.
That's when he happened to see Usui-san and
came up with a way to avoid being caught.
He attempted to fabricate an
alibi for the time of the crime
by using this man who looks just like him.
So you're an accomplice to a murder plot.
You're lying.
You seem to be unemployed, so
you probably did it for money.
I've got a way to get rich quick
that only works for you.
Here's your advance payment. Take it.
If I'm successful, I'll pay you double.
Not a bad deal, right?
You're lying!
Yesterday, on the day of the planned murder,
Kanieda-san had Usui-san cut his
long hair to look like his own
and sent far away from
Shikabone City to Beika City.
He had him enter a café
he'd picked out beforehand
and waited for the right
time to place a call.
There should be a man named Kanieda
from Shikabone City there.
Yes, that's me!
Kanieda from Shikabone City.
That allowed him to create
numerous witnesses for the alibi.
Furthermore, by leaving behind
a lighter with his fingerprints,
he had physical evidence as a backup.
With his fake alibi secured,
Kanieda-san headed out to
murder Saruwatari-sensei.
That dentist accepts appointments
until noon, right?
Shikabone City Saruwatari Dental Care
Hours
Appointments Accepted
Until Noon
Afternoon Appointments
From 14:00
Even if his appointments ran over,
he'd be done by 1PM at the latest,
and then eat lunch at home.
Kanieda-san would sneak into his
home and kill him using that rope.
That was the plan, wasn't it?
If the dentist didn't show up after 2PM
when his afternoon appointments started,
naturally someone would go check
on him and discover the body.
Since he clearly would've been killed
during his lunch between 1PM to 2PM,
you just needed to fabricate an
alibi for that one hour period.
Meanwhile, you witnessed an old woman being
pushed down some steps in Beika City.
But you couldn't testify.
If you came forward as a witness, the
police would ask for your identity.
Even if you wanted to claim to be
Kanieda Akira from Shikabone City,
the name on your license would be different.
So you said you didn't see anything and ran.
You kept fabricating Kanieda-san's alibi.
And repeatedly took actions people
around town would remember.
You hid the fact that you had an alibi
because the alibi itself was part of an evil scheme.
You didn't want to be suspected
of injuring Hachiya-san...
But you hid it, believing it was better
than the police discovering
you were helping a murderer.
Your scheme was all for nothing, though.
While heading to Saruwatari-sensei's house,
Kanieda-san was involved in a traffic
accident and never managed to attack the dentist.
What?
Huh?
What?!
You mean I could've said from the start that
I was fabricating an alibi in Beika City?
Then what have I been doing
these past three days?
Man, I'm beat.
You fool!
It was a coincidence that you didn't
become an accomplice to a murderer!
You're absolutely correct.
Incoming Call
My phone...
You can answer it.
Okay.
Hello?
Yes.
Yes, sounds good.
Yes. Bye.
That was Kanieda-san.
He's decided not to get revenge
because he believes it was divine
punishment that he was struck by a car.
I'm terribly sorry for the trouble I caused.
In any case, we'll be
putting this on the record.
Takagi and Chiba, go talk to Kanieda.
Yes, sir.
But now we're back to square
one with the injury case.
Seriously. Who's the culprit in that case?
If Usui-san's pen was at the crime scene
even though he never went to the park,
then the culprit must've put it there.
And the only person who had the
opportunity to do that was...
Could it be?
The woman who found the body.
It was her?
I got the idea when I saw that Usui guy
arguing with Hachiya a few days ago.
I could get back at Hachiya
and frame him for it.
I picked up the ball point pen he
dropped then and used it yesterday.
Even if Usui had an alibi,
I figured you guys would
do something about it.
"He must've employed some
kind of clever trick."
That's what you thought, right?
I feel dizzy...
MPD Midoridai Police Station
From now on, you'd better
stick to proper jobs.
I will. I'm really sorry for the
trouble I caused you kids, too.
By the way, didn't you see the culprit who
pushed the old woman down the stone steps?
That's right.
Did you see them?
No, I really didn't see anyone. After all...
Hup.
I've been pushed! Someone help!
You mean she was lying?
Yeah, but why would she do that?
Maybe she's the troublemaker grandma
everyone's been talking about.
I've heard about her, too!
She's the old woman who delights
in causing a commotion
when nothing has actually happened, right?
Apparently.
Then we'd better tell that
police officer about her.
He's probably still looking for the culprit.
Oh, but...
We solved three whole cases in one day.
The Detective Boys are on fire.
It must be because I saw all ones.
Don't get ahead of yourself.
Episode Preview
Dude, that's an RX-7 FD3S.
Oh? Zero, do you feel like
going for a ride now, too?
After all, you're both zero.
N-No.
What if these brakes are the gates to ruin?
Don't bite your tongue.
Step on it, Zero!
Police Academy Arc Wild Police Story
CASE. Hagiwara Kenji
The next episode of Conan is
"Police Academy Arc Wild Police
Story CASE. Hagiwara Kenji!"
Onizuka Classroom
Lightning Speed
Instructor Onizuka Hachizo
Assistant Instructor Matsumoto Naota
Lightning Speed
Next Conan's hint!
Lightning speed!
Things you can't say, huh?
Don't miss the next episode.
We've got a few.
You mean too many.