[op]
[eyecatch]
Detective Conan Episode 1042 "Police Academy
Arc Wild Police Story CASE. Hagiwara Kenji"
[ed]
Between six to ten months
at the police academy,
students receive education and
training to become police officers
and establish deeper bonds with friends as
they become fully-fledged police officers.
Nonbei
Welcome.
Let's get this started.
Cheers!
Man, nothing beats free beer.
Date Wataru (22)
Hey, what do you mean by free beer?
Hagiwara didn't tell you?
He said he'd pay for our drinks
if we attended this mixer
with girls from another class
so there'd be enough guys.
Matsuda Jinpei (22)
And that's why you're here even
though you have a girlfriend?
Hagiwara himself still
hasn't arrived, though.
What? Date-kun, you have a girlfriend?
Yeah, you can tell.
Really?
What about you, Matsuda-kun?
Huh?
Y-You don't, do you?
You can tell...
Hey, Hiro.
Furuya Rei (22)
Morofushi Hiromitsu (22)
This appetizer is really good.
Even I could make this.
I'll show you how sometime.
After all, you don't know the
first thing about cooking.
Yeah, sorry about that.
Morofushi-kun, teach me, too.
I just want Furuya-kun to cook
for me, even if he sucks at it.
Don't bother.
Zero's interest in women other
than older lady doctors is zero.
Matsuda-kun, keep saying unkind things...
and I'll arrest you.
Hey, that sounds fun.
Nice punch, right, Zero?
Yeah.
Unbelievable.
Sorry I'm late.
Hagiwara Kenji (22)
There was an old woman stuck on
the long steps on the way here.
After carrying her up the steps,
she said she dropped the very lucky
fortune she just got at the shrine.
We tried looking for it, but couldn't find it,
so we went back to the shrine to buy
fortunes until we got another very lucky one,
and that brings us to now.
He's definitely lying.
Wow!
You're so nice!
What?
That was good.
Hey, you've had too much to drink.
Should we go karaoke next?
Yeah!
Thank you!
I'm so tired.
I'm stuffed.
Like I expected, Hagi's
getting all the attention.
Looks like it.
Excuse me.
Do you know that tall man over there?
Yes.
Not only did he carry me earlier,
he even bought me some fortunes.
Could you thank him for me, please?
Yes.
So it was true after all.
Hagi doesn't lie about that kind of thing.
Although he probably called the
old dude he helped an old lady
because he knew it would be received better.
Hey. What's wrong, Hiro?
We'll leave you behind.
I'm coming.
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
Their passionate youth known
only by their classmates.
Cherry blossoms that don't fall are forever.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Police Academy Arc Wild Police
Story CASE. Hagiwara Kenji
"Police Academy Arc Wild Police
Story CASE. Hagiwara Kenji."
My throat hurts from singing
too much at karaoke yesterday.
Well, good for you.
It was the Hagiwara show at karaoke, too.
How cool is that?
Dude, that's an RX-7 FD3S.
Who's driving?
Onizuka Hachizo (48)
Rookie Class Instructor
It's Instructor Oni's?
That's your car, Instructor Onizuka?
This is no ordinary car.
In some ways, this baby's a fighter plane.
Its lightweight body was inspired
by the Zero fighter plane, right?
The spirit of the Zero lives
on in that incredible car.
I'm impressed, Instructor Onizuka!
You drive my favorite car.
Actually, it's not my car.
It belonged to one of my
seniors who died on duty.
Four years ago, his daughter declared to me
that she'd become a police officer,
so I'm holding onto it until then.
Park it in the garage for me, will you?
You'd better not scratch it.
Yes, sir.
Maybe that guy's daughter is cute.
She wants to be a cop. She's
probably a stubborn tomboy.
Oh? Zero, do you feel like
going for a ride now, too?
After all, you're both zero.
N-No. I'm not into flashy cars like that.
So that is what you're into.
Heavy Equipment Training
Come on, one more lap.
Quit lollygagging and pick up the pace.
I see.
Your family runs an auto
repair shop, Hagiwara?
So that's why you knew so much about the car.
Yup. Jinpei-chan used to come to
our shop all the time as a kid.
He got in trouble with my dad for disassembling
and modding stuff without permission.
I was just trying to install
gull wings on a Porsche.
That would make anyone angry.
It's not just cars either.
By the end, he was researching explosives.
I can mostly tell how one's
built just by looking at it.
Since I like tinkering, too,
I wanted to take over the shop.
Then why did you decide to
become a police officer?
Just as business was going well and we
were increasing the number of shops,
the economy suddenly collapsed.
My dad's shop ended up going bankrupt.
On the other hand, the police will
never go out of business, right?
I guess not.
You're not wrong.
You've got half a lap left!
Show some spirit!
Shall we go for a last spurt?
Yeah.
Motorcycle Skill Training
Hey, Hagi.
It sounds like your carburetor's
not regulating fuel properly.
I thought so, too, and was about to fix it.
I'm not as fast as you, but...
See? All better.
You're as dexterous as they say.
Matsuda Jinpei and Hagiwara Kenji.
Do you have any interest in the riot police?
What?
Specifically, I'd like to
scout you for the bomb squad.
The riot police bomb squad?
I'm obviously interested!
Thanks for reaching out to us!
That doesn't sound like a thank you.
Oh, uh... What about you?
I'll think about it.
Morofushi
Hiro, I'm going out. Want me
to pick anything up for you?
Did Hiro go out somewhere?
What are you gonna tell him, Hagi?
Apparently they think we'd immediately
be useful members of the squad.
I'd love to be on the same
squad as an old friend.
Not only that, but I'd get to
tinker, which I love to do.
Then...
My dad...
Because I saw what happened to my dad's shop,
when everything's going
well, I step on the brakes.
I can't help but wonder if
these are the gates to ruin.
Lounge
If you're not sure about
it, then don't do it.
The bomb squad is pretty serious business.
If you're going to eat, I'll join you.
I'm going to check out Instructor Oni's car.
When I told him I could tell what part
of a machine is broken from the sound,
he asked me to check out the car's engine.
He asked to wash it while I was at it, too.
I can't get out of here and into
the bomb squad fast enough.
Matsuda.
The bomb squad doesn't scare you?
I'd be lying if I said it didn't scare me.
But I've been interested in
the bomb squad for a while,
and besides...
I'm all gas, no brakes.
I'm sure you are.
Speaking of bike shops, I saw a guy
with a strange tattoo the other day.
Like a cup with a fancy base.
I think it's called a goblet?
Sorry, but I followed you.
You had an unusual look on
your face when you left.
T-Team Leader Date.
I don't know what you
came here to investigate,
but if you don't want to tell
me, then you don't have to.
I'll just be watching you
from right next to you.
I won't get in your way.
I might occasionally talk to myself though.
You don't give up, do you?
I told you, I can't give out my
customers' personal information.
I just need you to arrange a meeting
with the man with the goblet tattoo.
Tattoo?
Are you talking about Irie-san?
What?
You're the cleaner.
Please, Tomori-san.
It's all right. These guys are
trying to become police officers.
They helped some people at a
convenience store the other day.
Thank you.
What is this Irie person like?
He's a quiet hardware salesman.
He joined us on the neighborhood
association's trip to the hot springs the other day.
Do you have a photo?
Irie-san doesn't like photos.
Normally you'd take group photos
on a group trip like that.
Now that you mentioned it, we did take one.
R-Really?
Here it is.
This guy in the black tank top is Irie-san.
But why are you looking
for a man with a tattoo?
These days there are plenty
of people with tattoos.
There's a scorpion tattoo on
the back of this clerk's neck.
And I've got the goddess
Kannon on my upper arm.
No, the tattoo I saw years ago was
a goblet on someone's shoulder.
What's happening out there?
I'll check out the driver seat of the truck.
Got it. Hey, what happened?
We hit the gas instead of the
brakes and crashed into the truck.
Now our bumper is stuck.
And the truck drove off
without noticing, huh?
Excuse me. There's a car stuck
to the back of your truck.
This isn't good, team leader.
The driver is unconscious
because he's sick or something.
Damn it. He's accelerating.
He must've lost consciousness
with his foot on the gas.
I need to call someone.
Didn't Zero say he was going out?
What? A runaway truck has a
car stuck to its rear bumper?
Is the truck driver unconscious?
Yeah. He's currently
speeding towards Hachioji.
Team Leader Date and I are following him on
a bike we borrowed from a soba restaurant.
Please clear the road ahead!
This is a runaway truck!
It's all we can do to use
the bullhorn we borrowed
from someone making a campaign
speech to clear the road.
Have you called the police
and fire departments?
Yeah, but you're closer.
Clear the road!
You'd get here quicker
in the instructor's car.
What? The instructor's car?
Jinpei-chan's checking out the FD right now.
Huh? He's not here.
That's odd. He should be
repairing or washing it.
Huh?
It's barely driving straight ahead
while scraping against the guardrail,
but at this rate, sooner or later...
Hey, team leader.
Thanks for waiting.
You sure?
We're forbidden from driving
vehicles like that one.
What?
I can't hear you over
the sound of the engine.
We need to do something to stop that truck.
Then it's simple.
Ramming it will physically force it to stop.
It's not working. The difference
in weight is too great.
Hey, Hagiwara.
Think you can do that for me?
Sure thing.
Do what?
Hey, open your sunroof!
O-Okay.
What are you doing?
Zero.
Don't bite your tongue.
What are you planning?
A passenger car's bumper got stuck
when it crashed into a truck
and is now being dragged along behind it.
Not only that, but something caused the
truck driver to lose consciousness.
What are you planning to do
under these circumstances?
Oh, you'll see.
W-Wow!
Open the hood when we get
to the front of the car.
I'll remove the bumper.
You get the truck driver.
Got it.
Team leader, this road isn't on the GPS.
It might be an under-construction highway.
Wait, this road comes to a sudden end!
Okay, I removed all the clips
on the inside of the bumper.
Pull the handbrake as hard as
you can and rip the bumper off.
Furuya-chan, hurry.
You're running out of road.
Even if he slams on the brakes,
it takes a ten-ton truck
roughly twice the distance
of a passenger car to
come to a complete stop.
Even if he brakes now,
he won't make it in time.
And besides...
I'm all gas, no brakes.
The gas! You have to step on the gas!
Step on it, Zero!
Crap.
He's not making it.
Hey.
Are you okay?
Your advice was perfect.
Without it, I'd be...
It wasn't me.
I figured that's what he would do.
Maybe stepping on the gas every once
in a while isn't such a bad idea.
By the way, I haven't been
filled in on the details yet,
but I heard you helped rescue some people.
That was nothing.
So, have you finished
fixing and washing the FD?
Of course. The engine's in perfect
shape, and the car's been washed.
As you can see, it's sparkling clean.
Keep up the good work.
Yes, sir!
That's an honorable scar
you've got there, FD-chan.
Episode Preview
Did you guys make all of these?
Yeah.
All the university club members here.
You can't be serious. Could it be?
I'm pretty sure, but I
understand how he feels.
After all, Yuri ended up like that because...
Yes, I should be able to get it done in time.
Anyway...
The Figure of Revenge
The next episode of Conan
is "The Figure of Revenge!"
Tissues
Next Conan's hint.
Tissues!
Don't miss the next episode.
Golden Week is almost over.
We'll be waiting for you in Shibuya.