Detective Conan Episode 1043
"The Figure of Revenge"
[op]
[ed]
Aoki Keiji (21)
University Student and Figure Club Member
Mizuhara Naoto (21)
Midoriyama Saki (21)
University Student and Figure Club Member
Shiraishi Kazuya (21)
Oh? Is that a delivery?
No, it must be Mitsuhiko-kun and his friends.
Mitsuhiko?
A boy who lives in the area.
I told him I'd show him our figures.
What? Some kids are about to show up?
I invited them.
They said they like Yaiba.
But we'll barely finish
in time for the deadline.
Sorry.
Don't apologize.
It's your fault it came down
to the wire, Shiraishi.
What was that?
We had to redo it because you got
cigarette ash on the figures.
That was your fault for—
Now, now. They're already here.
Let's not fight.
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
A group of students with a
fiery passion for figures.
But those same flames cause
their friendships to crumble.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Figure of Revenge
"The Figure of Revenge!"
Wow! It's so pretty!
Did you guys make all of these?
Yeah.
All the university club members here.
Wow, that's impressive.
A-A gun?!
Hey, what are you doing?
Th-The gun is glowing!
What's going on?
It's just a gun-shaped lighter.
A lighter?
Um, Ayumi-chan...
Hey, how long are you
going to stay like that?
Get away from her, Conan.
Shut up already!
If you're going to interfere
with our work, then leave!
Hey, you don't have to put it like that.
What was that?
Aoki, why don't you show the kids the
Yaiba figures you're so proud of?
Yeah. That's a great idea, Aoki-kun.
You're right.
Wow!
Wow, so many Yaibas.
This is a limited edition Yaiba, isn't it?
I'll be right back.
You can hang out in here until then.
Okay.
Why'd you have to invite those kids?
I said I was sorry.
If we don't finish in time for the contest,
we can display them at the school festival.
No way. I have to submit something
to this contest and win an award.
I don't mind if I don't win an award.
My future depends on this.
Your future? Are you talking
about getting a job?
Shiraishi, are you hiding something from us?
Shut up. It's nothing.
In any case, you'd better
finish by the deadline.
It's all right.
Since the first round is judged by photos,
we'll be fine as long as we
upload them to the site today.
Today?
But the deadline's tomorrow.
Tomorrow is the anniversary of Yuri's death.
We need to visit Yuri's
grave and show her our work.
Winning a contest was Yuri's dream.
Yeah.
Out of all of us, Yuri did have
the best instinct for figures.
No matter how talented you are,
none of it matters once you're dead.
Shiraishi-kun!
Is she gonna file my figures
for me from the afterlife?
Hey, don't smoke in here.
Shiraishi!
Award
Excellence in Design Award
Shiraishi Takuya-sama
An excellence in design award, huh?
Huh?
Conan, here it comes.
What?
Go!
Hey!
Ow!
You again?
Sorry.
Are you okay, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
Hey, Genta. What if you broke this?
Put this back and stop messing with it.
Fine.
Conan-kun, where are you going?
To the bathroom.
It's not working.
This might leave a stain.
It's fine. Don't worry about it.
I'm sorry.
Aw, shucks. It's empty now.
Huh?
What is this?
You can't be serious.
Could it be?
I'm pretty sure.
Is he really that consumed by it?
But I understand how he feels.
After all, Yuri ended up like that because...
I know.
I can't let it go either.
Yes, I should be able to get it done in time.
Anyway...
You'll come through on our agreement, right?
Your company will make me an unofficial
offer if I win the contest.
Conan-kun, what are you doing?
Nothing.
Mizuhara-san bought us ice cream and drinks.
Get over here.
Sure.
Wow, there are so many.
Choose whichever one you'd like.
What should I have?
Huh?
Where's Shiraishi-kun?
Working, probably.
I'll bring him something.
Shiraishi said he'd work a little
longer before having something to eat.
I see.
Man, that was good.
Genta-kun, you already finished yours?
Yeah. I wish I could have more.
Then you can have mine.
Really?
Go ahead.
I know.
Do you kids want to watch a Yaiba DVD?
Yes!
Give me a minute.
Let's see.
Which one should we watch?
Did the power go out?
Don't!
But didn't something happen in that room?
It's dangerous in there.
Shiraishi! Shiraishi, are you okay?
Shiraishi-kun!
C-Conan-kun?
It sounded like something exploded.
Damn it. It's locked.
Shiraishi-kun, unlock the door!
Shiraishi-kun!
Mizuhara, bring the key to this room!
Got it.
You guys go outside and
call the fire department.
Shiraishi-kun!
Got it. Let's go.
Say something!
Okay.
Shiraishi! Say something, Shiraishi!
Shiraishi-kun!
Where was everyone when the fire broke out?
We were in the living room with these kids.
We were eating the ice
cream he bought together.
Then there was a loud noise
and the power went out.
We heard another explosion after that.
Two explosions?
What did you all do?
Naturally, we went to the
studio to help Shiraishi.
But the door was locked.
Is it normally locked?
No.
I think he locked it today
because the kids were here,
so they couldn't bother
him while he was working.
I see.
If only I'd found the key sooner.
So, what caused the fire?
There was a lighter in the room.
We believe he was trying to
light a cigarette or something,
and that ignited the fire.
Hey, listen.
I heard another sound
before the power went out.
Another sound?
Yeah.
Um, Inspector.
How is Shiraishi?
Unfortunately, he inhaled a lot of smoke.
By the time he was taken
away, he was already gone.
No...
I know I heard something
other than an explosion.
What was it?
Hey, what's that?
Huh?
Oh, a rubber glove and copper wire.
A rubber glove and copper wire?
The outlet is burnt.
That sound must've been this.
Looks like the burns are most
severe around the garbage bin.
What's this?
This must be the lighter.
Huh?
But wasn't his lighter...
That's a bottle of thinner.
Not only that, but it's open,
and there's a nylon thread tied to it.
Could it be?
Hey.
You shouldn't be in here.
Sorry.
Detective Takagi wanted me to ask if you
found a lighter other than that gun-shaped one.
No, we didn't find anything else.
There wasn't another lighter?
Come on, now get out of here.
One more thing.
What's that?
An exploded plastic bottle, I think.
It's hard to tell because the heat warped it.
An exploded plastic bottle...
I'm pretty sure he put it in here.
I see.
So that's how it is.
But what was that bottle
of thinner doing there?
It's the professor.
Hello?
Hey, miss.
Why was the window in that
room covered with cardboard?
Yesterday Mizuhara-kun broke the window.
We put it up as a temporary measure.
I see.
Normally you keep the room
ventilated while you paint, right?
Generally we keep it open,
but we thought it'd be okay not to today
since we wouldn't be painting much.
Could we have your attention, please?
After examining the scene,
we believe it's likely the
fire was caused by a person.
First, regarding the power outage,
the outlet next to the TV stand was burnt.
We also found copper wire and
a rubber glove on the balcony.
In other words, we found what we
believe are signs someone
inserted copper wire into the outlet
to deliberately cause a power outage.
When the first explosion occurred,
there was someone searching
for a Yaiba DVD near the TV.
Mizuhara-san!
What?
Well, Mizuhara-san?
I-I have no idea what you're talking about.
B-But why would he do something like that?
Apparently you heard two explosions
during the fire, correct?
All the solutions in that room
must've exploded at different times.
But only the area around the garbage bin
and Shiraishi-san were badly burnt.
The rest of the room
wasn't burnt much at all.
In other words, the solutions
didn't explode one after another.
Come to think of it, there was an
exploded plastic bottle in the room.
You mean this?
Yeah.
Someone probably put dry ice inside that
plastic bottle and made it explode.
What? Why would it explode?
If you put dry ice inside a
plastic bottle and close it,
the pressure from the vaporizing dry
ice causes the bottle to explode.
It can be dangerous, so
don't ever try this at home.
Okay.
That explosion signaled when
to cause the power outage.
And the power outage activated the
mechanism that caused the fire.
This is the mechanism.
This bottle of thinner with a nylon
thread tied around it was in the room.
Mizuhara-san, when you brought
the ice cream to Shiraishi-san,
you put dry ice inside the plastic bottle
containing water you prepared beforehand.
You left both it and an
open bottle of thinner
with nylon thread tied to it that you'd also
prepared beforehand on the shelf next to the door,
and exited the room after attaching the end
of the nylon thread to the lock on the door.
Later, the plastic bottle exploded.
The blast caused the bottle
of thinner to fall,
pulling the nylon thread
and locking the door.
Then the thinner spilled
out of the fallen bottle.
If Shiraishi-san lit a cigarette
under those circumstances,
the flame would ignite the
fumes and cause an explosion.
However, there was no guarantee
he would smoke a cigarette then.
So you listened for the sound of the plastic
bottle exploding and caused a power outage,
plunging the room into darkness.
That's probably also the reason you broke the
window and used cardboard as a temporary fix.
Excuse me.
What do you mean when you say
he caused a power outage because
he wouldn't necessarily smoke?
I doubt he'd smoke just because
it was dark in the room.
Wouldn't he turn on the
lights if the room was dark?
Were you listening? The power was out.
Oh, right.
Put yourselves in Shiraishi-san's
shoes and think about it.
What would you do if a plastic bottle
suddenly exploded and your room became dark?
I'd use my lighter's flame as a light source.
Yeah.
Mizuhara-san, in order to
guarantee he'd ignite the fumes,
you stealthily took Shiraishi-san's phone
and lighter so he'd use the gun-shaped lighter coated
with fluorescent paint next to the door.
Conan-kun found his phone and lighter
inside the ice cream box in the freezer.
Furthermore, judging by the severe
burning around the garbage bin,
you must've filled it with a large number
of tissues soaked in a flammable liquid.
Well, Mizuhara-san?
Do you have anything to say?
I-I'm sorry.
Before the fire broke out,
I threw away a bunch of tissues I used to
soak up the ethanol I spilled over there.
S-So...
It's not Saki's fault.
I told her to do it.
So this was an accident.
Please believe us.
I knew it. That conversation...
You can't be serious.
Could it be?
I'm pretty sure.
Is he really that consumed by it?
They were aware of Mizuhara-san's plan.
Wait a minute.
But I understand how he feels.
After all, Yuri ended up like that because...
I know.
I can't let it go either.
Could it be?
Could it be that those two...?
It was a coincidence. Please believe us.
Damn it. So that's how it is.
Professor, where are you now?
I-It was just an accident.
That's enough, guys.
The police are right.
You admit it, then?
Yes.
But why would you do this?
I did it for Yuri.
Who is Yuri?
She was a member of our club.
She killed herself last year.
The other day, Yuri's parents
showed me her designs.
And among them, we found the
same designs we're working
on now that Shiraishi allegedly created.
When I asked Shiraishi about it,
he admitted he'd been
stealing Yuri's designs.
On top of that...
Who kills themselves over some figures?
What a dumb woman.
Yuri looked up to Shiraishi as someone who'd
participated in contests since high school.
She was so happy to be
in the same club as him.
But he took advantage of her
pure feelings and betrayed her.
She lost hope and took her own life.
So I...
You can tell us more about it at the station.
Hold it right there.
Agasa-san.
Conan-kun filled me in on the details.
It almost certainly was Mizuhara-san who
used the mechanism to start the fire.
But shouldn't it have been possible
to help Shiraishi-san right away?
After all, Mizuhara-san's
mechanism didn't work.
What?
Detective Takagi, where was the bottle
of thinner used in the mechanism?
On the floor in a corner of the room.
That proves the mechanism
didn't work correctly.
What?
Think about it.
If the mechanism had worked,
the bottle of thinner would've
hung beneath the lock
and eventually fallen when the thread burned.
It should've been directly
in front of the door.
The blast from the plastic bottle
exploding was probably too strong.
The entire mechanism,
including the thread and bottle,
must've been blasted across the room.
I see.
But the room really was locked.
The two of them realized what
Mizuhara-san was planning,
and that his plan was likely to fail.
So when the first explosion
occurred and the power went out,
they stopped Conan-kun from
going to see what happened
Don't!
But didn't something happen in that room?
and waited for the second explosion.
It's dangerous in there.
But sure enough, the mechanism failed,
and as Shiraishi-san attempted to flee...
Shiraishi!
Aoki, open the door!
Shiraishi, are you okay?
Shiraishi-kun!
Hey, Aoki! Open the door! Saki, let me out!
Damn it. It's locked.
Shiraishi-kun, unlock the door!
Shiraishi-kun!
Mizuhara, bring the key to this room!
Guys...
We heard you and Shiraishi arguing.
Yeah, that's right.
She drew these designs.
Shiraishi, you bastard.
Yuri had shown us her designs, too.
And when we saw them...
These kind of look like Shiraishi's designs.
Come on, Yuri-chan.
You need to demonstrate more
of your own individuality.
Yeah, don't just copy Shiraishi's designs.
We didn't know at the time,
but we still hurt Yuri.
What if that's the reason she...
Beika City
Figure Art Contest
Excellence in Design Award
Kurose Yuri
Episode Preview
We should talk to the boyfriend first.
I see.
In that case, I promise
my complete cooperation.
The company I worked at
suddenly went bankrupt,
and my sister was being stalked.
What a series of unfortunate events.
In that case...
The Deadly Pork Soup Signal
The next episode of Conan is
"The Deadly Pork Soup Signal!"
Vegetables
Next Conan's hint!
Vegetables!
Make sure you eat your vegetables.
Don't miss the next episode.
Every single day.
Don't forget about that, too.
Eat what?
Eel bowls, of course.