[ed]
[eyecatch]
Detective Conan Episode 1044
"The Deadly Pork Soup Signal"
[op]
Hey, Mister.
Inspector Megure always says some
kind of incident often happens
when we're hanging out together, right?
Well, yeah.
It's what you call a coincidence.
Huh.
So, is that a coincidence, too?
Yup, what a coincidence!
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
Put your life on the line as
you put the pot over the fire!
There's a message hidden in the vegetables!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Deadly Pork Soup Signal
"The Deadly Pork Soup Signal!"
The victim is Lisa
Hewitson-san, 25 years old.
The cause of death is
shock due to blood loss.
Lisa Hewitson (25)
Floor Staff
The estimated time of death
is between 1:00AM and 1:30AM.
Judging by how much blood she lost, the
culprit probably got her blood on themselves.
Yeah.
So, what's the weapon?
M-Mori-san? What are you doing here?
C-Conan-kun, too?
We haven't found a weapon yet.
What about fingerprints?
We found three sets of fingerprints
other than the victim's.
I see.
Hey.
What was inside that pouch?
They're on that table over there.
Her ID, wallet, and various cosmetics.
There was a ball-point pen and notepad, too.
There were no signs the front door
or windows were forced open, so...
This may have been the
work of an acquaintance.
Then we should talk to the boyfriend first.
Hara Takashi-san, 23 years old.
We were able to confirm with their
acquaintances that he was dating the victim.
Additionally, the fingerprints collected
when he committed a traffic violation
matched the fingerprints
found at the crime scene.
Wh-What?! I can't believe Lisa was murdered.
Hara Takashi (23)
Office Worker
But she was so full of life yesterday.
Does that mean you met
with Lisa-san yesterday?
Hara
I saw her three days ago.
Yesterday evening we spoke on the phone.
Where were you last night
between 1:00AM and 1:30AM?
Last night I was drinking
with my coworkers until 3AM.
By the way, did you notice anything
unusual about her recently?
Anything unusual?
Like suspicious persons hanging around her.
It was him!
Komaki, the owner of the
store Lisa worked at.
She always complained
about him hitting on her.
He must've done it. You have to arrest him!
Komaki Satoshi-san, 47 years old.
Previous offenses include tax
evasion and attempted extortion.
According to rumors, he has connections
to some rather rough individuals.
Furthermore, his fingerprints were
also found at the crime scene.
What?
Komaki Satoshi (47)
Bar Manager
Officer, you don't think I did it, do you?
I didn't say that.
It's just that one of your employees is dead.
We need to speak with you.
I see.
In that case, I promise
my complete cooperation.
Could you tell us about your
relationship with Hewitson-san?
Officially, we had an
employment relationship.
In other words, we were an
employer and his employee.
And privately?
In exchange for a little pocket money,
we played Old Maid together late at night.
What?
In other words, you've been
inside Hewitson-san's home.
Well, yeah.
Old Maid is a game you play at home.
Could you tell us your alibi
for between 1:00AM and 1:30AM?
Come on, now. Aren't there more important
things you should be investigating?
I'm talking about the conclusive
evidence left inside her home.
I'm sure you found something, right?
Like a bloody weapon, for example.
Or a wine bottle with fingerprints on it.
Or the jacket the culprit was wearing.
What are you talking about?
Huh?
Do you know something about the case?
Oh, no. I was just, uh...
I know. It's because he did it.
He who?
I'm talking about that brat Hara.
He was always making eyes at my employees.
So he must've done it.
Don't you think that's too
much of a logical leap?
Hardly.
He's definitely the culprit.
Are you sure you're not the culprit?
What was that?
You still haven't told us your alibi
for between 1:00AM and 1:30AM.
My alibi?
My alibi, huh? I've got that covered.
I've got an ironclad alibi.
I was at home during that time.
If you think I'm lying, ask my wife Mihoko.
Komaki Mihoko-san, 28 years old.
No previous offenses.
Since they married two years
ago, she's been his housewife.
But can we really trust that
man's wife's testimony?
The credibility of her testimony
probably comes with a question mark.
Before they married, when she worked
Komaki's bar like the victim,
he pressured her into marrying him.
If he's having his wife provide
false testimony, that works for us.
I, the great detective Mori Kogoro,
will identify any contradictions in
her testimony and solve the case.
Have a seat, please.
Excuse us.
You're definitely Komaki Mihoko-san, correct?
Komaki Mihoko (28)
Komaki Satoshi's Wife
Yes. Ask me anything.
My husband insisted I answer
all your questions truthfully.
Then what time did Komaki-san
come home last night?
My husband usually returns between
2AM and 3AM after his bar closes.
Last night he said there was something
on TV he wanted to watch
and returned at 11PM.
What exactly did he want to watch?
The news. An accountant
he knows was arrested.
He said he had to watch it.
In this day and age, you
can watch TV from anywhere.
Just knowing what happened on
a TV program isn't evidence.
You think my husband did it?
Despite how he seems, he despises lies.
What's going on?
Is there something special
about that figurine?
What's that?
That's a mic.
Then someone's listening
in on this conversation.
Ma'am, how did a young and
beautiful woman like yourself
end up married to that man?
I'm sure you had plenty of better options.
I married him two years ago.
At the time, I was engaged to another man.
Back then, I believed I
would marry my fiancé,
but just before the wedding,
he was stabbed by an unknown assailant.
Did you lose your fiancé in the incident?
He died.
The culprit was arrested soon afterwards,
but they apparently died in prison.
After that, a series of unfortunate
events occurred around me.
Specifically, what happened?
The company I worked at
suddenly went bankrupt,
and my sister was being stalked.
My father's factory caught fire.
My mother fell off a train platform.
I-Is that true?
Who would joke about this?
What a series of unfortunate events.
The silver lining was that none
of my family members died.
When I was at my lowest point,
it was Komaki who reached out to me.
Something's not right.
The hidden mic and her pleading glances.
Then there's her life story and
her marriage to her husband.
And more than anything, her expression.
Hey, do you love your husband?
Huh?
What?
O-Of course I do.
Why would you ask that?
Huh, I see.
Don't ask weird questions.
I'm sure of it.
She's lying.
In that case...
December 7th
December 7th – Events
Read details of what occurred on December 7th
Incidents occurring on December 7th
What happened on December 7th
This must be it.
From: Conan-kun
Subject: No subject
Kogoro-no-ojisan says
this room is bugged.
Kogoro-no-ojisan says this room is bugged.
What? Bugged?
It must be her husband
Komaki who's listening.
By why would he bug the room?
The wife wants to tell us the truth, but
she can't because the room is bugged.
Kogoro-no-ojisan says we need to communicate
using something other than words.
Other than words?
But how?
By the way, he says he'll continue
pretending he hasn't noticed.
You're free to say you love your husband.
Could I interrupt for a moment?
Mihoko-san, could you answer the questions
I'm about to ask you with either yes or no?
What?
Yes or no.
Yes, I understand.
Huh?
You're Komaki Mihoko-san, correct?
Yes.
Did you lie about any of your testimony
concerning your husband's alibi?
Of course not.
By 11PM, he had returned home.
I can vouch for that.
We already—
Do you believe your husband
is involved in this case?
No, I'm sure the culprit is someone else.
Then the culprit must be—
Why are you here?
What?
Is there something preventing
you from going somewhere else?
I'm here of my own free will.
Excuse me, ma'am.
The police will guarantee your safety.
Would you be willing to help us?
I know.
My husband will be returning soon.
I should cook.
Ma'am?
First I'll chop the vegetables.
What's going on here?
Green onions, burdock, and daikon radishes.
I know.
She's cooking pork soup.
Is that important?
If not that, then this is Morse code.
She's pretending to chop vegetables
so she can tell us something.
What's this?
Excuse me, ma'am.
That's enough.
Stay away from my wife.
Komaki.
You've heard enough.
If you're not going to arrest
me, then get out of here.
Hey, ma'am.
Here.
It's a good luck charm. Well, bye.
The culprit is almost certainly
Komaki, but we don't have evidence.
If only we had concrete evidence.
Don't worry about that.
What?
Mori-san, did you figure something out?
She was cooking pork soup.
After that, she'll cook
the rice and a main dish.
In other words, a pork soup
made with pork belly—
Mori-san?
Detective Takagi, take us
to the victim's apartment.
Roger that!
But why are we going to
the victim's apartment?
The first thing she was trying to tell us was
about the mic hidden on the horse figurine.
She couldn't speak freely because of it.
The second thing was the art on the wall.
There was a date on the work.
Detective Chiba, try searching for
incidents that occurred on December 7th.
Sure. Let's see...
What's this?
A slasher murder.
The victim was probably Mihoko-san's fiancé.
It's likely the person they
arrested was falsely charged.
How do you know that?
It's the evidence.
Like a bloody weapon, for example.
Or a wine bottle with fingerprints on it.
Or the jacket the culprit was wearing.
The evidence collected from
the slasher murder case
was exactly the same as the
items Komaki mentioned earlier.
This must be what they mean when
say "bite the hand that feeds."
What are you talking about?
I'm disappointed. And here I
thought I'd taught you well.
He probably left the same evidence at the
crime scene in order to frame Hara-san.
But for some reason, the evidence was missing.
In other words, this is what happened.
After I left Lisa's home, you snuck back
inside and took the evidence with you.
Am I wrong?
It wasn't me.
Don't lie to me.
You desperately tried to tip off the police.
I never did that.
I installed a camera in the
stuffed bear on the sofa.
In other words, the third set of fingerprints
found at the crime scene were hers.
Yeah. Then there's the
life story she told us.
That must've been true.
She's stuck because of it.
Even if Komaki were arrested,
she was probably told her family would
be harmed if he learned of her betrayal.
What a awful man.
What are you going to do to me?
Nothing. You're my precious wife.
But unfortunately, my precious
wife has gone missing.
There's no point in leaving the cops a body to
find when they've already got their eyes on me.
By the way, why did she
start chopping vegetables?
That was a hint from her as well.
A hint?
What do green onions, burdock, and
daikon radishes have in common?
They're used to make pork soup?
No.
They're long and thin.
That's right.
But not believing that would be enough,
she began doing something else.
When Komaki showed up, the
rest of us weren't looking,
but Conan confirmed it.
She chopped the vegetables and created...
It looks like an ordinary ball-point pen.
Why don't we try disassembling it?
Sure.
What's this?
It's a cleaning receipt.
Cleaning Receipt
We finally acquired some concrete evidence.
If we examine the DNA of
the blood on the shirt...
The case is as good as solved.
Hello, this is Chiba.
What?!
Komaki has gone missing!
Any last words?
Why did you kill her?
She rejected my advances despite
the good offer I made her.
How dare she be faithful to that man?
You're the worst.
You're one to talk, traitor!
The police will arrest you.
Do you really think the only thing
I did was get rid of the evidence?
You're bluffing.
I told them everything, including
about your past evils.
Is that all you have to say?
It's the cops!
But how?
Because my good luck charm worked.
Police! Nobody move!
Bitch!
Stop!
You're not getting away, buddy!
In the investigation that followed,
it was proven that Mihoko-san's
fiancé's murder
and crimes committed
by his alleged murderer
were the work of Komaki.
Hello? Ran?
Could you make pork soup for dinner tonight?
What? You already went shopping?
Who cares about that? I want pork soup.
I'm telling you, pork soup.
Pork soup, pork soup, pork soup.
Green onions, burdock, and daikon radishes.
I want pork soup!