Detective Conan Episode 1045 "The Birthday
Party of Divine Punishment (Part One)"
[op]
[ed]
[eyecatch]
Yamai Bookstore
Found it.
Doremi
It's Sekizawa Remi's photobook "Doremi."
Sekizawa Remi's 1st Photobook
Looks like we got the last one.
Lucky us.
Your sister sure is popular.
Thanks.
Sekizawa Yumi (17)
Teitan High School 2nd Year
Although to me, she's just
my clumsy slob of a sister.
But the detective's assistant she
played in that recent drama was cute.
She was a terrible assistant lacking
in detective skills, though.
Listen, that's a script issue.
Besides, her main job is modeling.
So, are you sure we can go tonight?
To Sekizawa Remi's birthday party.
Even though we're ordinary people?
Yeah.
It's just a little party we're holding at a
restaurant my sister's classmate works at.
And it's actually my birthday party, too.
Oh, right. Your birthday's two days
after Valentines Day, right?
Yeah, February 16th.
Since my sister's birthday is
the day after Valentines Day,
we've celebrated them
together since we were kids.
And besides, there's another
reason I want you guys to come.
Is something the matter?
Oh, no.
It's not a big deal.
Anyway, Yumi-chin, about that
thing I mentioned earlier...
Oh, right.
He's a boy in first grade, right?
Don't worry.
I'm sure it'll be fine if there's
one extra kid at the party.
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
It's the birthday party of a popular model!
A scream rings out when
the cake is brought out!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Birthday Party of Divine Punishment
(Part One)
"The Birthday Party of Divine
Punishment, Part One!"
The restaurant isn't that big.
But everyone here is a
model, actor, or celebrity.
No wonder everyone's so fit.
Aren't you glad you got
to come, too, Conan-kun?
What's wrong? You don't seem well.
Conan-kun has a mouth ulcer so
it's hard for him to talk.
Did you remember to bring your medicine?
'eah, I brough' ih.
You should've left the kid at
home if he had a mouth ulcer.
I know, but my dad has a neighborhood
association meeting tonight.
Conan-kun would've had to stay home alone.
Why don't you take your medicine
before the party starts?
O-hay.
Let's see. I think I'm supposed
to take one tablet at a time.
Oh, right. I put my mouth ulcer medicine in
the case I was keeping that medicine in.
Hey.
Huh?
What's that blue and white capsule?
Nu-hing.
It's not like I can tell her it's the APTX-4869
antidote Haibara gave me on our school trip,
and that I've been secretly
holding onto the spare capsule.
What? Does the kid not like
medicine or something?
I don't think so.
Hey, Mom.
As we thought, Conan-kun
had some kind of medicine.
I see. But if it was white and blue,
then it's not the poison I was given.
Judging by his flustered reaction, it's
likely an antidote that would restore my body.
Steal it if you can.
Okay, Mom.
That's right.
They force-fed me a red and white capsule
when I was beaten on
Vauxhall Bridge in London.
So you're my sister Yumi's classmates.
This is Ran-chan, Sonoko-chan, and Sera-chan.
Nice to meet you.
Sekizawa Remi (21)
Model
Enjoy yourselves today.
Anyway, um... I bought your photobook today.
Could I get your autograph later?
Oh, I can take care of that right now.
Kushiyama-san, could you hand me
the permanent marker in my bag?
Kushiyama Mitomu (28)
Remi's Manager
All right.
Here you are.
Thank you.
Is "To Ran-chan" okay?
Yes, thank you.
Not at all.
Huh?
This marker doesn't work.
I smelled thinner when I
opened your bag just now.
Maybe the cap came off.
No way.
Jeez.
You never put the cap back on tightly enough.
Here, I've got a spare permanent marker.
Nice one, Yumi.
Jeez.
Thanks for waiting. Sonoko-chan, right?
Hey, Yumi-chin.
It's Ran.
Who can we talk to for some water?
This kid wants to take his medicine.
Um...
I'll get you some.
Thanks.
If you have any allergies, I'll let
the staff know while I'm at it.
None in particular.
Yeah.
Understood.
To Ran-chan
Wow, I'll treasure this.
You're welcome.
Come on, sis. You shouldn't
stick a pen there.
It'll leave a weird stain.
But what if someone else
asks me for my autograph?
I'll hold onto it for you until then.
You can't tell who's the older sister.
Yeah.
They've been like that since they were kids.
Yumi-chan's four years younger, but
she's always been more put together.
I genuinely believed it was Yumi-chan
who applied to the modeling job.
Hatsune Tsuguo (21)
Pastry Chef
Oh, I'm Remi's middle and high
school classmate Hatsune Tsuguo.
I'm a pastry chef who hopes to
open his own restaurant someday.
I asked the chef to let me make the birthday
cake for today, so you won't want to miss that.
All right.
Oh, yeah?
You want to become an independent
pastry chef and open your own shop?
Well, yeah.
Good luck with that.
Hanasaki Mizutoshi (32)
Hair and Makeup Artist
Maybe your cakes will sell if you say
they're made by Sekizawa Remi's classmate.
Y-Yeah, I guess.
Ah, Remi-chan. Happy birthday!
Hanasaki-san.
Here, a bouquet for your birthday.
Wow.
Thank you, Hanasaki-san.
Who's the creep?
You're welcome.
Hanasaki Mizutoshi.
He's a hair and makeup artist
who's hit on and been rejected
by my sister a bunch of times
despite having a wife and kid.
What a scumbag.
What are you wearing those glasses for?
You'll have to wait and see.
On top of that, he even
hit on me the other day.
Just ignore him.
But he's a good hair and makeup artist.
I can't totally disregard him.
I see. So that's why you invited us.
To prevent him from hitting on you again.
Yeah.
And it's easier to avoid
him if I'm with friends.
It's all right. We'll protect you.
Don't worry.
Thanks.
She's got nothing to worry about with
a Jeet Kune Do expert, karate master,
and the Suzuki conglomerate protecting her.
Suzuki Conglomerate
That was great.
That just leaves dessert.
It's time for that birthday cake.
I'm so excited.
Happy birthday to you.
Happy birthday dear Remi and Yumi.
Your glasses are glowing.
What do you think? Pretty cool, right?
While the cake is being distributed,
please enjoy some of Remi
and Yumi's favorite photos.
Yumi-chin is so tiny.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Sis.
Three second rule.
Jeez.
D-Did someone collapse?
Was it that hair and makeup guy?
I'm sorry, I broke a wine bottle!
Please stay away from this area!
This area?
What area?
In any case, someone turn on the lights.
Damn. It's too dark to see.
Hanasaki-san's glowing glasses
are coming in and out of sight.
There's someone by his head.
What are they doing?
Divine Punishment
Poisoned?
The victim Hanasaki Mizutoshi-san
ate something poisoned and died?
Yes, according to forensics,
the cake the victim ate before he
collapsed was probably poisoned.
We even found a small bottle containing
cyanide taped beneath the table at the victim's seat.
But how did the culprit
do that during a party?
He apparently collapsed while photos
were being shown using that projector.
It was dimly lit inside the restaurant.
The restaurant may have been dimly lit,
Divine Punishment
but wouldn't someone have seen a person
writing on the victim's forehead
with a permanent marker?
Immediately after the victim collapsed,
the projector suddenly turned
off, and the room became pitch dark.
But if it was pitch dark,
Divine Punishment
then how did someone write
these letters on his forehead?
The victim's glasses were a novelty
item that glowed in the dark.
I see.
So it would be possible to write by touch if
the culprit knew where the victim's head was.
Divine Punishment
Since the writing is rather distorted,
it seems they used their non-dominant
hand to disguise their handwriting.
But between the guests and staff, there are
close to 40 people inside the restaurant.
Identifying the culprit won't be easy.
'ere are 'our 'uspects.
'uspects?
I think he's trying to say,
"There are four suspects."
You guys are here, too?
Our classmate's sister is
Sekizawa Remi-san the model.
We were invited to her birthday party.
So, what's this about four suspects?
Can't you tell?
The left side of the victim was blocked
by the projector and our seats.
And the right side of the
victim—well, take a look.
An employee dropped and broke
a wine bottle in the dark.
The floor is covered in wine, but there's
no sign anyone stepped through it.
And the kitchen is through the
door past the victim's head,
but the kitchen staff said
nobody came through the door
between the time the projector
turned off and the lights came on.
In other words, this murder
scene was a closed space
nobody could leave once the victim
ate the poisoned cake and collapsed.
Excluding us, who didn't know the victim,
there were only four people in that area.
I see. So, who are those four?
We're having them wait in the corner of the
room so they can't take anything out of the area.
These four are the suspects who
could've poisoned the victim.
Hey, wait.
Yumi-chin's a suspect, too?
Keep her out of this.
It's just for now. After all,
she seems to know the victim.
Right, Conan-kun?
'eah.
What's this? Your cold
sore hasn't healed yet.
Maybe you should have more of that medicine.
I'm 'ine.
In any case, we'll let the other guests
leave and speak to each of you individually
about your relationship with the victim,
and what you were doing before
and after the victim collapsed.
The late Hanasaki-san was
a hair and makeup artist.
He did most of my hair and makeup.
Since he was skilled and popular,
I appreciated his work.
So your relationship was
strictly professional?
Yes.
Though he did hit on me several times.
H-Hit on you? Wasn't Hanasaki-san married?
Was he cheating?
That's why I turned him down every time.
Besides, I figured he was half-joking.
I see.
So, what were you doing during the incident?
Hanasaki-san was wearing the glowing glasses.
I commented on his glasses and was
eating the cake that was brought to me
when Hanasaki-san suddenly
stood up and collapsed.
I didn't leave my seat after
that until the lights turned on.
So you didn't do anything besides eat cake.
It was dim inside the restaurant so
photos could be shown on the projector,
and I dropped the strawberry
on my cake onto the table.
I saw that, too.
She said, "three second rule,"
and ate the strawberry.
Th-Three second rule?
You didn't need to mention that part.
Sorry.
So, Yumi-san, were you next to
your sister the entire time?
Yes.
I love cake, so after scarfing mine
down, I tried to go to the bathroom.
That's when Hanasaki-san
groaned and collapsed.
You didn't rush to his side?
No. It was pitch black,
and someone said a wine
bottle had broken nearby.
So you weren't close with the victim?
No.
He hit on me several times as
well, but I rejected his advances.
You, too?
Yes.
I frequently met Hanasaki-san on the job.
After all, he did the hair and
makeup for the model I manage.
So you never experienced any
problems with the victim?
As she mentioned earlier, he was a skilled
and popular hair and makeup artist,
so he did make several demands in
exchange for prioritizing Sekizawa.
What demands?
Like asking to know her
favorite flowers and foods.
Or in this case, requesting
to be seated next to her.
What were you doing during the incident?
I received a phone call during that time,
so I left my seat before eating my cake.
And to prove it, look. You can
see my cake hasn't been touched.
Yes, I see.
Anyway, Hanasaki-san collapsed
while I was on the phone.
The lights turned on,
and then police arrived.
I haven't returned to my seat since
leaving it to take a phone call.
Yes, I'm the one who made this cake.
Since it was my middle and high school
classmate Remi's birthday party,
I asked the chef to allow me to make it.
You're the one who cut the cake and brought
a piece to the victim, aren't you?
Yes. I put a strawberry
on each and every piece.
Strawberries are Remi's favorite.
Did you know the victim Hanasaki-san?
No, today was the first time I met him.
Although I had heard from Yumi-chan
that he was bothering Remi
by persistently hitting on her.
What were you doing during the incident?
It suddenly became pitch black while I
was cutting and distributing the cake,
so I held onto the cart the cake
was on until the lights came on
so no one would bump into
it and knock it over.
Anyway, wouldn't it be faster
to examine our belongings?
What do you mean?
I'm talking about the pen.
The culprit wrote something on
that Hanasaki guy's forehead.
Whoever has that pen now must've done it.
Of course, I don't have a pen on me.
Then allow me to check your pockets.
You don't seem to have one.
Manager, what about you?
Oh, right. I normally
hold onto Sekizawa's bag.
She generally keeps a permanent
marker in it for writing autographs.
It doesn't work, though.
You're right.
The inside of this bag smells like thinner.
Are you sure you didn't leave the cap off
after the murder so it would become unusable?
Before the party started, Sekizawa tried
to give her autograph to that girl,
but the pen didn't work.
Is that true?
Yes.
So you didn't get her autograph?
No, I did. Yumi-chin had a spare permanent
marker, so she used that instead.
So currently Remi-san has a working marker?
No, this must be a mistake!
Oh, no.
There's no way Sekizawa would kill anyone!
I returned the marker to my sister.
It's true. The pen is inside my bag.
But I didn't do it!
I didn't kill anyone!
Please believe me!
Sera-chan, do something.
Like what?
It's my mom.
Sorry, just a sec.
Jeez...
Hello?
Well? Do you think you'll
be able to get the medicine?
Someone was poisoned at the restaurant
where the party's being held.
I don't have time for that right now.
I'll call you back later.
Poison?
Poisoned, huh?
You're late,
Tsutomu-san.
Sorry, Mary.
It's been so long, I had a hard time
remembering our usual meeting spot.
I'd completely forgotten
it was by the railing
on the Vauxhall Bridge right
in front of the SIS Building.
So, did you figure out
who killed Haneda Koji?
No.
I was only able to determine that
it was a large organization.
Running away from them once I'd caught
their attention took everything I had.
Why didn't you contact me for over a decade?
I told you when we ran into each
other in town the other day.
I suffered a major head injury
while fleeing from them.
I'd been wandering around town in
a state of amnesia for a long time.
My memories finally returned
because I met you again.
I should be able to resume my
duties with MI6 a year from now.
More importantly, did you
come here with the boys?
No, it's just me and our daughter.
Daughter?
You mean you still don't
remember the daughter you held?
Oh, her.
Is she a big girl now?
What's wrong, Mary?
Why are you crying?
When Tsutomu-san and I parted ways,
my daughter was still inside me.
Who are you?
That's right.
I'm not Akai Tsutomu.
I'm the woman who's about to
kill you using this poison.
Episode Preview
Yumi-kun's the only one
who had a working marker.
It makes sense they'd suspect her first.
But isn't she a little far away
to have poisoned the cake?
Do you know if there was anyone who may
have held a grudge against the victim?
Well, I mean...
More than I can count.
He was a serial complainer.
I see.
The Birthday Party of Divine Punishment
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The Birthday
Party of Divine Punishment, Part Two!"
Permanent Marker
Next Conan's hint!
A 'ermanent 'arker!
Huh? What'd he say?
Don't miss the next episode.
Permanent marker, right?
'anks, Ran-neechan.