Ran and her friends brought me to the
birthday party of model Sekizawa Remi-san.
At the party, Sera noticed the
APTX-4869 antidote I had with me
and reported it to her mother Mary.
However, someone was murdered
at the birthday party
Meanwhile, Mary recalled the
time she was force-fed APTX-4869
in London by...
Tsutomu-san.
Sorry, Mary.
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
The words "divine punishment" were
written on the victim's forehead.
What truth is hidden within the darkness?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Birthday Party of Divine Punishment
(Part Two)
"The Birthday Party of Divine
Punishment, Part Two!"
When Tsutomu-san and I parted ways,
my daughter was still inside me.
Who are you?
That's right.
I'm not Akai Tsutomu.
I'm the woman who's about to
kill you using this poison.
MI6 agent Mary Akai-san.
I finally caught you.
I'd been wandering the city
regularly for some time now
while wearing your husband's face.
I see.
You allowed our colleagues
to see you dressed like that
in order to lure me to this country
to confirm if it was really him.
You spent three years waiting for us
to "coincidentally" run into each other
so I wouldn't realize it was a trap.
That's right.
His wife who suddenly vanished
was the bottleneck preventing
the allegedly deceased Akai Tsutomu
from resuming his duties with MI6.
It's true that I'd be able to
determine if it was really him
or the witch with a thousand
faces disguised as him.
Sorry to disappoint you, though.
If I don't return on time,
I've instructed my daughter to notify MI6
that this Akai Tsutomu was an impostor,
and to leave London immediately.
Then perhaps I'll disguise myself as you next
and go visit your daughter.
You make it sound like you know where she is.
You didn't even know she existed.
There's no way you know.
You're right.
It sounds like I should
infiltrate MI6 another time.
In that case, I'll simply complete
my other objective.
Eliminating Mary Akai.
Letting you live creates
a lot of problems for us.
How does it feel to die by the poison
created by your own younger sister?
What happened? What was that sound?
Looks like someone fell.
Mom's late.
What is she doing?
Mom, did you meet with Dad?
Huh? Mom?
Masumi.
Huh?
Who are you?
It's me.
The strange drug they
force-fed me did this to me,
but I'm your mother Mary.
Really? Are you really my mom?
Yes.
That's hard to believe.
It's hard to believe, isn't it?
Huh?
That Yumi-chin's a suspect in a murder case.
It can't be helped.
The only four people who could've poisoned
the cake the victim Hanasaki-san ate were
the model Sekizawa Remi-san,
who was sitting at the same table,
Sekizawa Remi (21)
Model
Remi-san's younger sister
and our classmate Yumi-kun,
Sekizawa Yumi (17)
Teitan High School 2nd Year
Remi-san's manager Kushiyama Mitomu-san,
Kushiyama Mitomu (28)
Remi's Manager
and Hatsune Tsuguo-san, who baked
the cake and was passing it out.
Hatsune Tsuguo (21)
Pastry Chef
Hanasaki Mizutoshi (32)
Hair and Makeup Artist
Because the culprit not
only poisoned the victim,
but also wrote "divine
punishment" on his forehead,
whoever currently has a marker
on them becomes suspicious.
We confirmed that Remi-san the
model didn't have a marker,
and while her manager Kushiyama-san,
who was holding onto her bag,
had a marker, it didn't work.
Yumi-kun's the only one
who had a working marker.
It makes sense they'd suspect her first.
'ut isn't she a li'l far away
to have 'oisoned the cake?
You're right.
Remi-san and Kushiyama-san were
sitting on either side of the victim,
and Hatsune-san was distributing the cake.
Any of them could've poisoned it.
'ut since Remi-san was sitting
'etween Sekizawa and the victim...
Yeah. It would've been most difficult
for Yumi-kun to poison the cake.
Anyway, you call Yumi-kun
by her last name, huh?
It's almost like you're her classmate.
I-I meant Yumi-neechan.
Was poison found in any of the other pieces?
No. I just received a call from forensics.
A large amount of cyanide powder was found
on the cake eaten by the victim Hanasaki-san,
but no poison was found on Sekizawa
Remi-san's half-eaten cake
or Kushiyama-san's untouched cake.
They also found nothing on
Sekizawa Yumi-san's plate,
who had finished her cake.
And they found nothing on the
cakes Hatsune-san distributed
to the other guests or the uncut cake.
I see.
Also, Yumi-san's bag, which
contained the working marker,
was placed inside this basket
beneath Yumi-san's seat.
Huh?
There's an odd dark stain on the floor.
What is that?
Who knows?
This stain wasn't here before
Hanasaki-san was killed.
What?
Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
I took a video of the sisters blowing
out the candles on the cake.
Look at the floor.
There's no dark stain.
You're right.
Then what is this stain?
Wait a minute...
You can't just walk into a crime scene.
Go on, you two. Get out of here.
So, Yumi-san's bag was in this
basket beneath her chair?
Yes, so if someone tried to touch it,
she would've noticed right away.
What about their possessions?
Remi-san had a single handkerchief
and eye drops for dry eyes.
Hatsune-san had a phone,
cigarettes, and an oil lighter.
Which just leaves the question of the motive.
Do you know if there was anyone who may
have held a grudge against the victim?
We understand if you don't
want to speak ill of the dead.
Well, I mean...
More than I can count.
I don't know where to begin.
In any case, he had a terrible
reputation among my model friends.
He was a skilled hair and makeup artist,
but he moved quickly on women.
He made awful demands in exchange
for prioritizing certain clients.
He even demanded to know models'
bust, waist, and hip measurements
so he could send them clothes.
What about you?
My sister is scatterbrained.
She forgets things in makeup rooms,
and I'd go get them for her,
but often, they'd be missing.
Like her wallet or accessories?
No, like half-finished cans
of soft drinks and snacks.
What?
I asked the makeup artists
and stylists about it,
but they didn't remember throwing them out.
S-So, what about you?
He was a serial complainer.
He made complaints at
restaurants all over the place.
The other day, he became furious because the
fork and knife on his table weren't parallel.
He stirred up a storm online when the fork he
threw at an employee struck another customer.
He had to issue an apology.
None of those really sound
like murder motives.
You're right.
Inspector!
What?!
There was a marker in the
kitchen's garbage bin?
Does it work?
Yes, sir.
None of the kitchen staff
recall throwing it away.
But we were told no one entered or left
the kitchen when the murder occurred.
That's just the staff who were
originally in the kitchen.
Once the lights went out, the
staff called out to each other.
But since it was dark,
they might not have noticed if
someone snuck into the kitchen.
For someone to have done that...
They'd have to know where the
kitchen's garbage bin was located.
Hatsune-san the pastry chef.
It could only have been you.
No, wait. It wasn't me.
Come to think of it,
the projector turned off because the power
cord was disconnected from the outlet.
That outlet is located
next to the kitchen door.
Since you were cutting the
cake next to that door,
it would've been easy for
you to disconnect the cord.
I-I may have been near the outlet,
but everyone was looking at
that man on the ground then.
Anyone could've unplugged the cord.
And here I thought I was cleared of
suspicion because I didn't have a marker on me.
I can't believe I'm a suspect again
because of a dumb reason like that.
Again?
I'm being falsely accused!
You're no different from
that serial complainer!
A serial complainer?
I see.
Hanasaki-san wasn't poisoned.
He accidentally poisoned himself
without realizing the words that would twist
the truth would be written on his forehead.
Hey, Inspector Megure.
Huh?
Think abou' it.
There are staff 'olding
knives inside the kitchen.
Even if I knew the layout,
I wouldn't wanna walk around a 'angerous
place like that in the dark.
You're right.
But if it wasn't Hatsune-san, then...
That means the culprit poisoned
Hanasaki-san's cake right in front of him.
That's the thing.
Huh?
The culprit didn't poison Hanasaki-san's cake.
They poisoned their own cake.
What?
Sera-chan, I bought two strawberry
shortcakes, just like you asked.
Could you place them side
by side on the table?
Okay.
Watch this.
Imagine Sonoko-kun's the
victim and I'm the culprit.
When the culprit left their seat,
they did this while
Hanasaki-san wasn't looking.
They tipped over the strawberry
on their neighbor's cake?
So that's why Hanasaki-san swapped
his cake for the culprit's.
But if he didn't like it,
he could've asked the restaurant
staff for a new piece of cake.
Normally he would've, but
Hanasaki-san couldn't do that.
Just the other day,
he issued an apology for striking a customer
with the fork he threw at an employee.
People would blast him again if he complained
about a minor thing like a crooked strawberry.
Isn't that right?
The man who claimed to
have received a phone call
and left his seat before touching his cake,
Remi-san's manager Kushiyama Mitomu-san.
The crooked strawberry on the cake you
supposedly didn't touch proves it.
But I really did receive a phone call then.
R-Right?
My phone rang, didn't it?
You probably called a test number.
It's a service that calls you
back after a few seconds.
As long as you muted the call so the message
would be inaudible, no one would notice.
By waiting for the right
time to call that number,
you could claim to have received a phone call
and leave your seat before he ate his cake,
after poisoning your own cake, of course.
B-But what about the marker?
As you know, the permanent marker I had
didn't work because it was uncapped.
How could I have written anything
on Hanasaki-san's forehead?
Ran-kun, did you buy what I asked you to get?
Yeah, a permanent marker
and nail polish remover.
Like you said, I removed the cap from
the marker so it wouldn't work anymore.
Thanks.
Permanent markers primarily stop working
when dried ink hardens on the tip of the pen,
like this.
If you pour nail polish
remover into the marker cap
and leave the non-functional
marker in it for a while,
the acetone in the nail polish remover
melts the hardened the oil-based ink,
so it works again.
Then that dark stain on the floor was...
He discarded the nail polish
remover in the cap on the floor.
After committing the murder,
he needed to remove the cap so
the pen wouldn't work again.
In summary, you expected someone to ask
Remi-san for her autograph at a party.
You had her use a non-functional
permanent marker
to create the impression that
your marker didn't work.
After Hanasaki-san collapsed
from being poisoned,
you unplugged the projector, making
it dark inside the restaurant.
Then you used his glowing
glasses and your revived marker
to write on Hanasaki-san's forehead.
You convinced him to wear the glasses by
telling him Remi-san would like it, didn't you?
And as her manager, it was possible
for you to arrange to sit next to him.
Additionally, you threw away the
marker in the kitchen's garbage bin
when you went to get water for
Conan-kun before the party started.
Saying a party guest had a food allergy
would give you an excuse
to enter the kitchen.
This is just a hunch,
but I'm guessing you planned this expecting
that when Remi-san signed her autograph,
she'd accept a spare pen from her sister
when the one you gave her didn't work.
Suspicion would initially fall
on Remi-san, who had the marker.
Then you'd desperately cover for her,
and she'd be cleared once the new
marker was discovered in the kitchen.
Unfortunately, Remi-san returned
the marker to Yumi-kun,
and things didn't go as planned.
But why would Kushiyama-san do that?
So you'd fall for him.
He's probably the one who took
the half-finished soft drinks
and snacks from your makeup room.
What?
Hair and makeup artist Hanasaki-san probably
saw him and blackmailed him with it.
Did he ask you for money?
Yeah.
He kept increasing the amount, too.
I felt like I had to kill him!
Move!
Conan-kun, watch out!
Conan-kun, are you okay?
Y-Yeah.
Good.
Case closed.
Sure is.
Well, I've got something to do.
Did Sera just...?
Yeah, Mom. I got it, just like you wanted.
This medicine that might be
able to restore your body.
Nice work.
Now I can finally set back in motion...
the hands of the clock...
they stopped then.
Anyway, come in.
We need to get you out of those wet clothes.
You're right.
What's with the cough?
Did you catch a cold?
No, it's because of the strange
drug they force-fed me.
It could be a side effect of the drug.
Wimbledon.
It's already that time of year, huh?
Yeah, I recorded this afternoon's match.
Anyway, what are you going to do now?
Will you go to the hospital?
No.
If they expected that drug to do this to me,
we should assume they're waiting
for me at the hospital.
But you can't fight back against
them unless you figure out
how that happened to you and
have your body restored.
This body's good enough.
I won't be beaten by them.
But they force-fed you
some kind of weird drug.
Minerva!
In any case, we need to figure
out what that drug was.
I'll help you!
I am Holmes' apprentice!
Hey, who is this boy?
He looks just like the boy we met
on the beach a long time ago.
He's the magician who made Shu-nii laugh.
I think his name was Kudo Shinichi.
He said the same thing then.
Yeah, he called himself Holmes' apprentice.
I'm Kudo Shinichi, Sherlock
Holmes' apprentice.
I had my MI6 colleagues look into him.
The name Kudo Shinichi was
on the flight passenger list.
Apparently he's a second-year high
school student like you, Masumi.
So did he come to London
with his younger brother?
No.
He has no younger brother,
and his traveling companions
aren't relatives either.
What's even stranger is that Kudo
Shinichi is a high school detective.
He's solved countless cases while
we've been away from Japan.
But in the past six months,
that's suddenly stopped.
Instead, there's a boy who
frequently appears at crime scenes
who looks exactly like this boy.
Looks like him?
Are you sure he isn't Kudo Shinichi himself?
This boy took the same drug I
did and was turned into a child.
It's likely he restored his body somehow
when he boarded the plane.
If such a drug exists,
then we must establish contact with him
and do whatever it takes to acquire it.
And that drug is currently in my hands.
What?
Just that capsule is missing.
B-But why?
Removing the antidote to APTX-4869
from the pill case was the right call.
Conan-kun, we're leaving.
We'll leave you behind.
Hey, wait.
I'm coming.
Huh?
Sounds like your mouth ulcer has healed.
Hey, you're right.
Solving mysteries is the best
medicine for a detective.
That brat...
Episode Preview
Look who came to save me.
Sorry, Ryo-tan.
That's the head chef's knife.
The Red Sheep's Eerie Game
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Red Sheep's Eerie Game, Part One!"
Masks
Festival Memories
Next Conan's hint!
Festival memories!
I'm glad your mouth ulcer has healed.
Don't miss the next episode.
Witnessing that kick would heal anything.
Yeah, that.