[ed]
[eyecatch]
Detective Conan Episode 1047 "The
Red Sheep's Eerie Game (Part One)"
[op]
Mori Detective Agency
A red sheep?
Beppu Ryota (20)
"La Mucho" Employee
My girlfriend was kidnapped by a red sheep.
Please save her, Detective!
Hey, calm down.
So, what exactly do you mean by "red sheep"?
I'm talking about this.
Who is this guy?
I don't know who he is.
But my girlfriend told me before
that her ex was a scary guy.
It could be him.
A threatening message, huh?
"I've kidnapped Takigawa Ami."
Ami's my girlfriend.
We work together at a place called La Mucho.
La Mucho?
"If you want to see Ami returned safely,
come to Beika Park alone
tonight at midnight."
"Don't contact the police."
"The Red Sheep."
Is this all you have?
Yes.
So, did they demand a ransom?
No.
No?
A red sheep, huh?
I feel like I saw one
someplace a long time ago.
I seem to vaguely recall a red sheep, too.
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
The kidnapper is a red sheep?
Behind the video is an unsettling case!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Red Sheep's Eerie Game
(Part One)
"The Red Sheep's Eerie Game, Part One!"
If they didn't demand a ransom,
then what does the culprit want?
That's not good.
Ryota!
Ami?
Look who came to save me.
Hey, where's the red sheep?
Takigawa Ami (20)
"La Mucho" Employee
What? Who are you, mister?
I'm Mori Kogoro, a detective.
A detective?
I hired him.
I was too scared to come alone.
Aw, but I wanted you to come by yourself.
I thought you were kidnapped.
Yeah, I totally thought you were.
This is a game, Detective.
What? A game?
Yeah, it's the Red Sheep game that tests
your boyfriend's courage and love.
It's popular on social media right now.
That's what this was about?
Don't scare me like that, Ami.
Sorry, Ryota.
It's okay.
Are you mad?
No, I'm not mad.
Do you forgive me?
I don't know.
You can't be serious!
Game, my ass!
I took your boyfriend's concerns
seriously and did my job!
What's so fun about dragging a responsible
adult into a couple's shit test?!
Crap. It's almost midnight.
Conan-kun.
Where are you going this late at night?
I was curious about the Red Sheep.
What are you doing?
I-I was actually curious
about the Red Sheep, too.
What is that?
What is it, Conan-kun?
Call the police and an ambulance!
Damn it.
Ran, Conan.
Dad.
Inspector, has there been a murder?
Yeah. Ran-san and Conan-kun
found the body.
Did you see the culprit?
I don't know if they did it,
but we saw a red sheep.
What? A red sheep?
They were wearing a costume.
Someone wearing a sheep costume
ran away from the body.
See?
Their horns left a mark where
they rubbed against the ceiling.
Who's the victim?
Wakabayashi Tetsusaburo-san, 45 years old.
He's the owner and head cook of
a restaurant called La Mucho.
Wakabayashi Tetsusaburo (45)
"La Mucho" Owner and Head Cook
La Mucho?
We work together at a place called La Mucho.
That couple...
What is it, Mori-kun?
Inspector, allow Mori Kogoro
to handle this case.
M-Mori-kun?
Sounds like this case might be
connected to Beppu-san's workplace.
La Mucho
Temporarily
Closed
Mukai Kokichi (45)
"La Mucho" Assistant Head Cook
Kamio Daiki (25)
"La Mucho" Cook
This knife is the murder weapon.
That's the head cook's knife.
Wakabayashi-san's?
Which means Wakabayashi-san was
stabbed with his own knife.
Who are you?
I'm Wakabayashi's business partner Hirasawa.
Hirasawa Motojiro (40)
"La Mucho" Co-owner
Is it true he was murdered?
Yes.
Forgive me, but where were you
last night around midnight?
Working at my office.
My primary business is spatial design.
Alone?
Yes.
In other words, there's no one
to corroborate your alibi?
You think I did it?
No, we're just asking everyone.
We're in the same boat.
The store was closed yesterday,
and I was at home all day.
Both Kamio and I are single,
so we don't have alibis.
Yeah.
Were you out riding your
bike all night again?
I was home all day.
I haven't ridden my bike since the accident.
Hey, Inspector.
Maybe you should ask them
about the red sheep.
The red sheep?
We saw someone wearing a red sheep
costume flee the scene of the murder.
Kamio-san, do you have something to say?
N-No.
It's just that people have been talking about
a red sheep on a video sharing site recently.
A video sharing site?
Yeah.
Found it. This is it.
Since a few weeks ago,
videos were uploaded of a red sheep scaring
couples on dates and then running off.
Who is this red sheep?
Nobody knows. They were uploaded anonymously.
This is the same sheep we saw.
Right?
Y-Yeah.
The color and design are the same,
but I feel like there's something
different about them.
Hey, what are you guys doing?
Get in here and accept your fate.
You two?
Who are they?
They work on the restaurant floor.
That's Beppu Ryota and Takigawa Ami.
These two dragged me into their red
sheep game when the murder occurred.
Game?
A lowbrow game in which someone sends their
boyfriend a fake threat in order to test him.
Yeah, it's just a game.
Why are you making such a big deal over it?
You haven't heard about the case?
What case?
Head cook Wakabayashi
was killed with a knife.
What?
The culprit is a red sheep.
Y-You don't think I did it, do you?
Where were you last night around 12?
At Beika Park with this detective.
What?
You used me to fabricate an alibi?
No.
Why would we kill the head cook?
Yeah. We've never spoken to the chef.
I doubt he even knew what we looked like.
Don't lie to me.
You worked at the same restaurant.
There's no way he didn't know.
Actually, I doubt he did.
What?
We have over ten floor staff, and
Wakabayashi was only interested in cooking.
He hardly ever left the kitchen.
See?
Then what does Wakabayashi-san
have to do with the red sheep?
Why did someone kill him?
You two must be involved somehow.
I'm telling you, we had
nothing to do with it.
I just copied something I saw online
because it's popular on social media.
Maybe Wakabayashi-san received
a threatening message
from the red sheep saying they
kidnapped his girlfriend.
That's not possible.
Wakabayashi was married to his
work and didn't have a girlfriend.
You stay out of this.
Inspector, apparently a threatening message
was sent to the computer
at Wakabayashi-san's home.
A threatening message?
Yes, at 10PM.
The sender was the red sheep.
The red sheep?
I've kidnapped Anri.
Bring 50 million yen to the
Beika bridge tunnel at midnight.
50 million?
If you want to see Anri returned safely,
don't contact the police.
Got it?
Is this Anri woman
Wakabayashi-san's girlfriend?
I don't know.
This is the first time I've heard
anything about a girlfriend.
I think they probably met on a dating app.
A dating app?
I recommended it to him a month ago.
The chef didn't have any
opportunities to meet women.
Do you know anything about Anri-san?
No, he never mentioned her.
Maybe he still wanted to keep it a secret.
Which means we still have no clues.
But now we have a clear
picture of the whole case.
Wakabayashi-san's girlfriend
Anri-san was taken hostage,
and he was instructed to bring a 50
million yen ransom to that tunnel.
Ran-neechan, the red sheep was
carrying a black bag, right?
Yeah, you're right.
Maybe the ransom money was inside the bag.
Which means the culprit stole the ransom
money and killed Wakabayashi-san.
What a brutal fellow.
I wonder if Anri-san is all right.
Kamio-san, how was your
relationship with the head cook?
What?
You told him about the dating app.
It sounds like you two were rather close.
Close? He yelled at me every day.
It's his fault.
He'd sneak his phone into the kitchen.
I wanted to use my phone to record the
recipes because I couldn't remember them all.
You deserve to get yelled at for that.
So I recommended the app to him because I
thought getting a girlfriend might soften him up.
I told him in this day and age, people
even find their spouse on dating apps.
The head cook was serious about it.
He showed me the photo he
used for his dating profile,
"Chef" Aged 45
Nice to meet you.
I work as a chef at a restaurant.
Ask me anything about cooking.
I look forward to hearing from you.
and he was smiling like I'd
never seen him smile before.
I think his user name was "Chef."
Chef?
The head cook actually wanted
to work at a French restaurant.
That's why he wanted people to call him chef.
We're only as successful as we
are because we serve ethnic food.
And I'm the one who decided
he should be called head cook.
Wakabayashi agreed to all of that.
Let's try to calm down.
Could I see that video again?
Yeah, sure.
I knew it.
Is there something about that video
that's caught your attention, Conan-kun?
Y-Yeah.
Oh, right. Ran-neechan, didn't you say you
saw that red sheep somewhere a long time ago?
Yeah, but I can't remember where.
Take a closer look. Kamio-san, is that okay?
Yeah, sure.
Thank you.
Let me get a better look, too.
Here.
Huh?
What is it?
Ran?
I see. I remember now.
That's when she encountered the red sheep.
Are you okay?
I remember now. I know who the red sheep is.
What?
La Mucho
Beika Costume Rental Storeroom
This is the place.
Ow...
The red sheep.
This is it.
These horns scraped the ceiling.
I've caught you, thief.
What?
I'm turning you in to the police.
Beika Costume Rental Storeroom
Is this the place?
Yeah, probably.
I'm not a thief!
Conan-kun?
What?
Conan-kun, what are you doing here?
I'm sorry. He's with us.
Who are you guys?
Oh, excuse me.
I'm Mori Kogoro, a detective.
There's something I'd like to ask you.
What? Sure.
I see. That red sheep, huh?
I thought you came to borrow it again.
Borrow it?
Yeah.
For the past few weeks,
I've noticed signs showing it's been removed
from the store a few times during the night.
Iwami Hideto (50)
Beika Costume Rental Company President
Since it's always back by morning,
I wasn't sure if I should
report it to the police.
Is the red sheep the only
costume that's been taken?
Yeah. It wasn't popular at all before.
It was only rented once three weeks ago.
Three weeks ago?
That's around the time the
red sheep video was uploaded.
It was returned the very next day.
Do you know who rented it?
Yeah, I still have the records.
How did you know this was the place?
How did you guys know?
I remembered I saw that red sheep at a
nearby festival when I was in kindergarten.
That led us here.
I thought so.
You did?
Huh?
It was when I was in kindergarten.
You wouldn't have been born yet.
Yeah, but I think my teachers
mentioned a festival at school.
Found it.
I was with her at that festival.
This is him.
What?
Red Sheep
Hirasawa Motojiro
Hirasawa Motojiro?
The co-owner of the restaurant?
Episode Preview
Detective, if you've called us here,
does that mean one of us killed Wakabayashi?
You're the one who killed
Wakabayashi Tetsusaburo.
I-I have no idea what you're talking about.
The red sheep and 50 million yen vanished?
I see. Could it be?
The Red Sheep's Eerie Game
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Red Sheep's Eerie Game, Part Two!"
Next Conan's hint!
Sheep's Horn
A sheep's horn!
So the "tusk" at hand is seeing if we
"cant'ler" figure out whose horn that is.
Don't miss the next episode.
What does that even mean?