Detective Conan Episode 1048 "The
Red Sheep's Eerie Game (Part Two)"
[op]
[ed]
[eyecatch]
The Red Sheep game was simply a game meant
to test a boyfriend's love for his girlfriend.
But Ran and I discovered
the scene of a murder,
thought to be committed by someone
wearing a red sheep costume.
"Chef" Aged 45
Nice to meet you.
I work as a chef at a restaurant.
Ask me anything about cooking.
I look forward to hearing from you.
The victim was La Mucho
head cook Wakabayashi-san.
Wakabayashi Tetsusaburo (45)
"La Mucho" Owner and Head Cook
The red sheep kidnapped Anri,
a woman he met on a dating app.
Hirasawa Motojiro (40)
"La Mucho" Co-owner
Mukai Kokichi (45)
"La Mucho"
Assistant Head Cook
Kamio Daiki (25)
"La Mucho" Cook
Beppu Ryota (20)
"La Mucho" Employee
Takigawa Ami (20)
"La Mucho"
Employee
The sheep demanded a ransom,
and then he was murdered.
Beika Costume Rental Storeroom
This is the place.
Ow...
The red sheep.
This is it.
These horns scraped the ceiling.
Is the red sheep the only
costume that's been taken?
Yeah.
Iwami Hideto (50)
Beika Costume Rental
Company President
It wasn't popular at all before.
It was only rented once three weeks ago.
Three weeks ago?
That's around the time the
red sheep video was uploaded.
Do you know who rented it?
Yeah, I still have the records.
This is him.
What?
Red Sheep
Hirasawa Motojiro
Hirasawa Motojiro?
The co-owner of the restaurant?
It comes to visit after falling asleep!
Fall in love with logical deduction
and the pleasure of solving mysteries!
In both of our memories resides a red sheep.
What truth will we find within the costume?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Red Sheep's Eerie Game
(Part Two)
"The Red Sheep's Eerie Game, Part Two!"
La Mucho
Mori-kun, is it true you've
figured out who the culprit is?
Temporarily Closed
Yes, Inspector.
I've tracked down some decisive evidence.
Detective, if you've called us here,
does that mean one of us killed Wakabayashi?
That's right.
You're the one who killed
Wakabayashi Tetsusaburo.
Hirasawa Motojiro-san.
What? W-Wait a minute.
Hirasawa-san, three weeks ago,
you rented this red sheep costume
from Beika Costume Rental.
What?
Your name was in the rental company records.
I did rent that costume,
but I didn't kill Wakabayashi.
Then why did you rent this costume?
This year is the restaurant's
fifth anniversary.
I thought I'd use the red sheep
for our anniversary event.
La Mucho Fifth Anniversary
But wasn't this costume used
at a festival ten years ago?
Why would you use something so old?
Because I designed this costume.
What?
I thought your primary
business was spatial design.
Back then, I did anything and everything.
I was the one wearing the costume, too.
So I felt a kind of attachment to it.
I didn't want to forget how
much I struggled back then.
But when I told Wakabayashi I
wanted to use it for our event...
What are you thinking?!
This creepy costume isn't appropriate
for our restaurant's image!
He was unusually strongly
opposed to the idea.
I tearfully backed down from the idea.
So you killed Wakabayashi-san
because you resented him for that?
As if!
Wakabayashi and I were co-owners.
He was important to me
as my business partner.
If you were partners, then you must
know everything about Wakabayashi-san.
Huh?
The threatening message on Wakabayashi-san's
computer was received at 10PM.
Banks would've been closed by then.
How could he have gotten 50 million yen?
In other words,
the culprit knew Wakabayashi-san could
immediately access a large sum of money.
I-I have no idea what you're talking about.
But I saw you glance toward the kitchen when
you heard the ransom was 50 million yen.
50 million?
You looked without thinking because you knew
there was 50 million yen in the kitchen, right?
50 million yen in the kitchen?
Inspector, there are marks on the
floor indicating this shelf was moved.
Inspector, there's a hidden safe.
There's no cash inside.
There is this one notebook, though.
It looks like an account book.
Could this be a secret account book?
I'm sorry.
Every year, we under-reported
our profits and hid it as cash.
In other words, tax evasion.
Yes.
But only Wakabayashi and I knew about it.
Which means you wanted to keep the 50 million
yen you made from dodging taxes to yourself,
so you kidnapped Wakabayashi-san's
girlfriend and threatened him as the Red Sheep.
Well, Hirasawa-san?
But if Hirasawa-san's the culprit,
I doubt he would've used his own
name when he rented the costume.
What?
And it was a couple weeks ago that people
started talking about the red sheep.
Since the costume was returned three
weeks ago, the timing's a little off.
You're right.
The rental company owner said the costume had
been taken several times after it was returned.
For the past few weeks,
I've noticed signs showing it's been removed
from the storeroom a few times during the night.
Maybe someone's trying to frame Hirasawa-san.
Come to think of it...
Didn't I ask you to hold onto the
cardboard box the costume was stored in?
I told you a delivery service
was coming by to pick it up.
Huh? Oh, right.
This costume was inside that box?
There was no way for us to know that.
Hirasawa-san, did you remember to
put a shipping slip on the box?
Yes.
Shipping slips have a field
for the package's contents.
What did you write there?
I believe I wrote "one costume."
I-I don't remember that.
I never saw any slip.
The storeroom used to store the costumes
is old, and the door isn't even locked.
It would be easy to take a
costume if you wanted to.
But there would've been no way for us
to know the storeroom's lock was broken.
Huh?
All he said was that the
storeroom isn't locked.
He never mentioned it was broken.
The kid's right.
There's a padlock on the storeroom door,
but it comes undone easily.
Only the culprit would know that.
Y-You tricked him.
All he did was accidentally
say the wrong thing.
Ami, we can't keep lying.
Ryota...
Mr. Detective, we're the red sheep.
Ami would wear the red sheep costume.
And I would film it.
We uploaded the videos
to a video sharing site.
So it really was you guys.
It's all clear now.
The red sheep Ran and I saw scraped
the ceiling with its horns,
but the horns of the red sheep on the video
sharing site don't reach the ceiling.
In other words, Wakabayashi-san
was killed by someone taller.
How could you do this?
This is your fault.
We heard you were going to make us
hand out fliers in that costume,
so we ruined the sheep's image.
What?
We only meant to do it once,
but since our video got popular,
we started having fun with it.
Hold on.
Who told you you'd be handing
out fliers in costume?
Huh?
Hirasawa-san, did you tell anyone about that?
No, only Wakabayashi.
I didn't tell anyone else.
Which means you eavesdropped
on their conversation.
What?
I bet you heard about the 50 million
yen in the hidden safe then, too.
Um, Mori-san, weren't they with
you when the murder occurred?
Y-Yeah, that's right. We've got an alibi.
Then who killed Wakabayashi-san?
It's true that someone else may
have carried out the murder.
But these two definitely kidnapped Anri-san,
and demanded 50 million
yen from Wakabayashi-san.
This red sheep in the video
is definitely you, right?
No.
What? Don't lie to me.
You just said you were the red sheep.
I'm telling you, I'm that sheep,
but I'm not this sheep.
There is no that sheep or this sheep.
Counting all those sheep
would put me to sleep.
You know, like one sheep,
two sheep, three sheep.
Hold on a second.
Besides—
The sheep, the sheep!
Excuse me.
Everyone, please allow
me to make a correction.
The red sheep featured in the threatening
message on the tablet is not Ami-san.
What? It's not Ami-san?
That's right.
Mori-kun, what do you mean by that?
Ami-san isn't the red sheep, but
the girlfriend being held hostage.
What?
Ami is the hostage?
That's right.
The woman named Anri-san who met
Wakabayashi-san on a dating app
and became his girlfriend
was actually Ami-san.
Wh-What are you talking about?
I'm Ami's boyfriend.
She can't be the head cook's girlfriend.
Wakabayashi-san didn't know the faces
or names of the part-time employees.
In other words, he wouldn't have noticed
if Ami-san called herself Anri instead.
Ami, say it's not true.
Then who is the red sheep in this message?
Hirasawa-san,
didn't you say you made Wakabayashi-san's
title at this restaurant head cook?
Yes, although he wasn't happy about it.
Perhaps because of that, he called
himself "Chef" on the dating app.
And there are two people here who
accidentally called him chef.
One is Ami-san.
Yeah. We've never spoken to the chef.
I doubt he even knew what we looked like.
And the other one is you, Kamio-san.
Huh?
I recommended it to him a month ago.
The chef didn't have any
opportunities to meet women.
Chef and head cook are
practically the same thing.
You think I did it just
because I called him chef?
That's not the only reason.
Conan, could you use the costume's
head to explain it to them?
Sure thing.
The head of this costume has a helmet
inside so it's easier to wear.
Kamio-san, could you put this on?
What? But...
Kamio-san, please follow
Conan-kun's instructions.
Okay.
Hold still and don't move your hands.
Kamio-san...
Kamio-san, that hairstyle you're
so proud of has been ruined.
What? Aw, come on.
Yesterday, your hair was
flattened in the same way.
Oh...
I remember it clearly because
you kept messing with your hair.
Yesterday my hair was like that because
I rode by bike to the restaurant.
Didn't you say you hadn't ridden
your bike since the accident?
I was home all day.
I haven't ridden my bike since the accident.
You're right. He did say that.
And finally, there's one last
decisive piece of evidence.
Detective Takagi, could you
examine Kamio-san's watch?
Got it. Excuse me.
Look closely.
Are there red fibers stuck in the band?
There does seem to be something
that looks like thin red string.
Those are nylon fibers covering
the surface of this costume.
They would only be stuck to his
watch's band if he wore this costume.
It's because I just wore the head.
It just got there.
No, I believe Conan told
you not to move your hands.
He's right.
You haven't touched the costume.
Kamio-san, you probably bugged the kitchen
to gather information about the restaurant.
That's how you learned about
the hidden 50 million yen.
Ami.
The jig is up.
Damn it. I should've quit this restaurant
and its crappy wages sooner.
Ami, you're with Kamio-san?
Yes, since a long time ago.
I was just having a little fun with you.
I used the Red Sheep game to lure you
to the park so I'd have an alibi.
B-But...
Then Mori-kun is correct?
It's true that Ami and I planned
to steal 50 million yen
from the chef and sent him
a threatening message.
But that's the only part
that went according to plan.
We never got the ransom money.
We didn't kill the chef either!
You're still insisting you didn't do it?
Conan-kun and Ran-san saw
you fleeing the scene.
I clearly saw a red sheep carrying
a black bag running away.
I'm telling you, that wasn't me!
It really wasn't.
What do you mean?
After Ami headed to Beika Park,
I put the costume in the trunk
of our car and took a break.
But then...
When I woke up, the sheep was gone.
Gone?
That's right.
The red sheep had vanished.
The red sheep and 50 million yen vanished?
I see.
Could it be?
Inspector, I've secured the area.
Come on in.
You're the one who killed
Wakabayashi Tetsusaburo-san
and stole the 50 million yen, aren't you?
Wh-What are you...?
Apparently 50 million yen in cash
weighs about five kilos, so...
Ow...
Just that penguin was hanging
lower than the other costumes.
I hit my head on it.
I was trying to catch the culprit.
The culprit?
I staked out this place so I could
catch the scoundrel taking costumes
in the middle of the night
without paying a rental fee.
That's when I happened to overhear their plan
to steal 50 million yen from
a man named Wakabayashi.
My company's about to go bankrupt,
and they're trying to get their hands on a
huge sum of money like it's some kind of game.
I figured there'd be nothing
wrong with swiping that money,
so I followed them.
He wouldn't know who I was
if I wore the costume.
Leave the money there and back away.
He obediently placed the 50
million yen in front of me.
Why did you kill Wakabayashi-san
after you got the money?
Because when I opened the
bag to check its contents,
I found a knife inside.
There was a knife inside the bag?
Wakabayashi-san hid his own
knife in there for self-defense.
When I looked up without thinking...
I didn't mean to kill him.
If only... If only he hadn't seen my face.
Mori Detective Agency
What's wrong with him?
Apparently he can't sleep at night.
He keeps seeing a sheep in his dreams.
A sheep?
Even Dad was scared of
that red sheep after all.
He keeps telling someone
to go away in his sleep.
Stay away.
Go away.
Stay away from me.
Stay away.
I... have a feeling this is something else.
Keep uncorking those bottles,
my pretty little lambs!
Episode Preview
They pressured Yamakabe, who became
successful selling imported goods,
to publish an autobiography.
We found something rather incriminating
left behind in the vehicle
used to transport the body.
The gas tank of Temukai's car was
full when the accident happened?
It's been a while, Temukai-kun.
We can save the inspector!
The Threat to Megure's Police Career
The next episode of Conan is "The
Threat to Megure's Police Career!"
Clay
Next Conan's hint!
Clay!
Dad, wake up.
Don't miss the next episode.
If this is a dream, don't wake me up.
Take your time.