[eyecatch]
Detective Conan Episode 1049 "The
Threat to Megure's Police Career"
[op]
[ed]
Metropolitan Area Tenma City 9PM
What's the situation?
We received an anonymous emergency
call saying someone's dead.
Inspector Megure, good evening.
DOB July 9th
Driver's License
Iwao
Effective Until
We determined from the victim's license
that he was Yamakabe Iwao-san,
Yamakabe Iwao (56)
Import Goods Distributor
56 years old, who lived in Hikaridai.
The cause of death was a
cerebral contusion caused
by a blow to the back of the
head with a blunt object.
The estimated time of death is roughly
two hours earlier around 7PM.
However, because we haven't
found the victim's shoes,
we believe he may have
been murdered elsewhere.
So he was murdered indoors somewhere else,
and his body was transported
and abandoned here.
Inspector Megure.
I've been trying to get in
touch with the victim's family,
but no one's answering.
Perhaps he lived alone.
You said he lived in Hikaridai, right?
Let's have the local station look into it.
When officers from the local station
visited the victim's home...
Metropolitan Area Hikaridai: Yamakabe's Home
Kawai from the Hikaridai West police
box has arrived at the scene.
I'm on my way to verify the situation.
Yamakabe-san, police.
Yamakabe-san?
Yamakabe-san? Is anyone home?
Yamakabe-san? I'm with the police.
Wh-What is this?!
There are signs of a scuffle in the room.
And the unique shape of this ornament
with blood and hair stuck to it
matches the wound on the
victim's head, which means...
This room is most likely
the scene of the murder.
Our read on the situation
should've been correct.
I never thought I, of all people,
would commit such a grave mistake.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
Inspector Megure makes a regrettable mistake!
With his resignation riding on the
outcome, how will the investigation end?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Threat to Megure's Police Career
"The Threat to Megure's Police Career!"
MPD Tenma Police Station
Tenma Station
It happened two days after the case.
Inspector Megure! We've identified
someone suspicious in our investigation.
What?
They relentlessly hounded the
victim, who avoided them.
Apparently he had a lot of money troubles.
I see.
We noticed some other curious things
about this man named Temukai Kyosuke,
who lives in Tenma City.
Temukai Kyosuke?
Y-Yes...
You know him?
About three years ago, one of the
suspects in a certain murder case
was Temukai Kyosuke, who worked
at a government office.
When I asked him to accompany
me to the station,
and questioned him about his
alibi for the time of the murder,
Temukai reluctantly confessed he'd been
secretly meeting with a certain businessman.
His confession proved his
innocence in the murder case,
Thanks for waiting.
but his government office learned of his
inappropriate meetings with the businessman.
I've been fired as of today.
If I hadn't been suspected of murder,
this wouldn't have happened.
I won't forget what you've
done for me, Inspector.
But he was just reaping what he sowed.
You aren't responsible for what happened.
You're not wrong.
So, he works in publishing now?
He gets close to successful people and makes
them write and self-publish autobiographies.
But it's hard to imagine they sell
since there's no market for it.
It sounds like a shady business.
He pressured Yamakabe, who became
successful selling imported goods,
to publish an autobiography.
And Yamakabe was avoiding him.
Temukai Publishing
Excuse me.
We're with the police.
What do the police want with me?
It's been a while, Temukai-kun.
You...
Anyway, I'm surprised.
I didn't think you'd be in charge
of this investigation, Inspector.
Temukai Kyosuke (38)
Publishing Company Operator
What were you doing around 7PM two
days ago on the night of the 7th?
I was working alone in my office.
In other words, you don't have an alibi.
But I didn't do it.
Wasn't Yamakabe-san killed
at his home in Hikaridai?
Then his body was transported
here to Tenma City and abandoned.
It takes an hour by car.
What kind of culprit would
go through all the trouble
of transporting a body to
their own neighborhood?
It's possible they moved the body
so they could use that exact excuse.
You could apply that logic endlessly.
Apparently you destroyed your
own car in a one-car accident.
It was the morning after Yamakabe was killed.
That has nothing to do with the murder.
Something rather incriminating
could have been left behind
in the vehicle used to transport the body.
It's possible you caused the
accident that destroyed the car,
in order to get rid of the evidence.
You're over-thinking things, Inspector.
In any case, I didn't kill Yamakabe-san.
Excuse me.
The section chief disapproved of
the lack of decisive evidence,
but I was willing to risk my career
and arrest Temukai Kyosuke anyway.
But the next morning—in
other words, this morning—
when his arrest was reported,
a woman named Chikaba Yasuko
came to investigation headquarters.
Chikaba Yasuko (57)
Supermarket Manager
What do you mean he didn't do it?
I manage a chain of inexpensive supermarkets.
I decided to publish an autobiography
on Temukai-san's recommendation.
I attended a meeting with Temukai-san
on the 7th when the murder took place
at my home here in Tenma City from
that evening until around 9PM.
Yamakabe was killed in Hikaridai around 7PM.
Since he was meeting with Chikaba-san
in Tenma City during that time...
It would've been impossible for him to do it.
In other words, you arrested the wrong man.
Why didn't you say you had an alibi?
Oh, I was confused. I thought I'd
met with Chikaba-san on another day.
Besides, it's no trouble at
all for me to be arrested.
After all, I trust you since you're
such a capable police inspector.
I know you'll find the true culprit.
Then I'll be acquitted and released.
So that's how it is. He intended
for this to happen from the start.
You were set up.
Yeah.
That Temukai guy came up with this plan
on the spot when he learned you were
in charge of the investigation.
He plotted to ruin my reputation
with a mistaken arrest to get revenge
for what happened three years ago.
I never expected my police
career to end like this.
What?
Inspector, you can't be serious.
I told the section chief I was willing
to risk my career to arrest Temukai.
I'm sure they didn't take
what you said at face value.
My principles won't allow it!
Before I knew it, I ended up here.
It would seem you're the
only one I can complain to.
Inspector...
This is Megure.
Arrested Without Warrant
Publishing Company Operator Arrested!!
Yeah.
Got it.
Temukai was just released.
I'm not resigning until
I find the true culprit,
but I'm not sure I'll be able to do that.
This isn't like you, Inspector!
You can't end your career on a loss.
I'll secretly help you find the true culprit.
I see.
I appreciate it.
Now, where should I begin?
Hey, mister.
Huh?
The inspector doesn't have to resign
if Temukai Kyosuke really
is the culprit, right?
Well, yeah.
But he's got a legit alibi.
But there's something suspicious about him.
You're right.
If this guy's actually guilty
and we can prove it...
then we can save the inspector!
Even the police admitted
it was a mistaken arrest.
What does the great detective
Mori Kogoro want with me?
I wanted to see the face of the man who
set up my former superior Inspector Megure,
and tell him I won't let the
culprit get away with this.
I don't know why you're telling me that,
but I do hope you find the true culprit.
He definitely feels guilty.
But that confident smile means he's
certain he'll get away with it.
Yes.
Yes. No, nothing else.
I understand. Sorry to
interrupt your busy schedule.
I was hoping forensics found something,
but all they found was a bit
of clay beneath a table.
Clay?
Maybe it was the victim Yamakabe's hobby.
He seemed to be a collector of knickknacks.
About that. The ornament used as
a weapon was really lumpy, right?
Why did the culprit use that one?
This one would've been way easier to hold.
They probably just happened to grab that one.
Just happened to?
The gas tank of Temukai's car was
full when the accident happened?
Traffic Accidents Today 5
Yeah, so the thing blew
up and burnt to a crisp.
I can only assume the inspector was right,
and he did it to erase some
incriminating evidence.
You're absolutely certain
Temukai was at your home
from the evening to around
9PM on the day of the murder?
Yes.
Aside from stepping out once to buy
cigarettes, he was there the whole time.
Temukai-san went to buy cigarettes?
Yes, but he was only gone
for about ten minutes.
He left during their meeting?
Was that around seven o'clock?
Um...
It was when the news started airing on TV,
so it must've been around seven o'clock.
I see.
Now we can save the inspector!
What?
Did you figure something out?
Yeah, I know what clichéd
trick he used to do it.
Temukai actually killed Yamakabe right
here in the vicinity of Chikaba's house.
Temukai lied about buying cigarettes
and left Chikaba's house.
He invented a plausible reason to
meet with Yamakabe at seven o'clock
and killed him using the
ornament he had him bring.
Then he returned to Chikaba's
home and resumed their meeting.
Afterwards, he transported and abandoned the
body in the location where it was discovered,
went to Yamakabe's home, stole the money,
made it look like a scuffle
had taken place there,
and left the ornament used
as the weapon on the floor.
I don't think that would've been possible.
What?
Tenma City
Chikaba's House
Hikaridai
Yamakabe's House
Since he left this house in
Tenma City around nine o'clock,
the earliest he could've arrived
at Yamakabe's house in Hikaridai,
which is an hour away,
would've been ten o'clock.
But Yamakabe-san's body was
discovered after nine o'clock,
Location of Body
and when the police officer who received
Inspector Megure's call visited his house...
Yamakabe-san? I'm with the police.
Wh-What is this?
There were already signs of a scuffle, and
the ornament in question was at his home.
Naturally, I'm fully aware of all that.
He's on the right track.
We just need one more
thing to bring this home.
All they found was a bit
of clay beneath a table.
Could it be?
Hello, this is Mori.
What kind of clay was the
clay you mentioned earlier?
Ah, that type of clay?
No, thank you.
I see.
It's true that Temukai could've
done it using that method,
but that just means it would've
been possible for him to do it.
Yes.
We need something that proves
he's the true culprit.
Anyway, Inspector...
Inspector Megure, we still
haven't found a single witness.
Should we try expanding our search?
Let's go.
What?
èfaC
We still haven't heard from Mori-kun?!
What?
Didn't he say he figured out
the trick and just needed to track
down the physical evidence?
He even said he knew where to find it.
Physical evidence? Could it be?
Isn't that...?
Temukai.
It's here.
I doubt they'll find it, but perhaps I
should throw it into the sea after all.
I see.
So that was the actual weapon.
You set me up this time?
You can provide us with the explanation.
You're the one who saw through
everything, Mori-kun.
What? I did?
Mori-kun?
I did?
Temukai Kyosuke-kun,
you plotted to kill Yamakabe Iwao and
steal the money in the safe at his home.
You thought securing an alibi
by killing him in Tenma City,
while convincing the police Yamakabe's
home in the distant neighborhood Hikaridai
was the scene of the murder, would
allow you to get away with it.
Then wouldn't I have transported
the body to Yamakabe's home?
That would've immediately convinced
them that was the scene of the murder.
No.
Transporting a body always
leaves traces on the body.
They would've discovered right away
that he'd been killed elsewhere
and transported to his home.
You knew that and used that
knowledge to transport
and abandon the body in a place
near the scene of the murder.
Meanwhile, if you ransacked Yamakabe's home,
you could convince us
he was killed there and then transported
to where the body was abandoned.
Furthermore, the fake and actual weapons
were essential to fabricating your alibi.
On the day of the murder,
you visited Yamakabe's home to discuss
publishing an autobiography.
You forced him to open his
safe by threatening him.
You waited for the sleeping
pills you slipped him
to take effect before
creating your two weapons.
Using a clay that softens when heated and
hardens when cooled, you created a mold.
To give it some weight,
you added a steel rod,
and used UV resin to create
the weapon you'd actually use.
Meanwhile, you attached Yamakabe's
blood and hair to the ornament
so it would seem as though it
was the weapon used to kill him.
Then you ransacked the room and carried
the sleeping Yamakabe out of the house.
In other words, the crime
scene and weapon were in place
hours before you killed him.
The fake one, that is.
After that, you visited Chikaba Yasuko-san
with Yamakabe still sleeping in your car.
Around seven o'clock, you left her house,
saying you were going to buy cigarettes,
and killed Yamakabe, who was asleep
in your car, using the actual weapon.
After leaving Chikaba's house,
you dumped Yamakabe's body and
disposed of the actual murder weapon.
Then you anonymously called
the emergency number.
By making the police discover
Yamakabe-san as soon as possible,
you prompted them to determine his time
of death and visit Yamakabe's home,
convincing them it was impossible
for you to have killed him.
The next morning, you pretended to get
into an accident and destroyed your car...
to erase any sign that your vehicle
was the actual scene of the murder.
I can't talk my way out of
this with this thing around.
Everything you said was correct, Mori-san.
You just happened to win
this time, Inspector Megure.
I could've tossed this piece
of evidence into the sea.
You mustn't underestimate
the police, Temukai-kun.
Huh?
Even if we hadn't discovered
the weapon like you said,
once we knew you fabricated your alibi,
we would've thoroughly
re-investigated your affairs.
We would've followed the money,
re-examined security camera footage,
collected every last speck of
dust left in Yamakabe's home,
and had the entire forensics
team re-analyze the material
until we found evidence proving you did it.
This time I took a chance on Mori-kun's plan,
but that's what typical
police work looks like!
Temukai-san, could you come
with us to the station?
Looks like I won't have to
write my resignation, Mori-kun.
You're welcome to come
complain to me anytime.
I can't be depressed all the time.
Hey, Mister.
Come on, wake up. It's evening.
Kid, I just came up with a good idea.
What?
Let's lay a trap for Temukai.
We'll make him accidentally
tell us the trick he used.
I'll get you, Temukai!
You mean you're not going to
solve the mystery yourself?
Episode Preview
You must be joking.
You're not capable of accounting, bro.
What did you say?
Stop it, you two!
There are guests here!
Yes?
Yuichiro-san, were those ingredients
for your new soft serve?
Yeah.
I wanna see.
Intrigue at Morikawa Mansion
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "Intrigue
at Morikawa Mansion, Part One!"
Key
Next Conan's hint!
A key!
You're in trouble, Inspector? Are you sure?
Don't miss the next episode.
Yes, Mori-kun. It's true.
Are you two best buds?