Listen up, boys.
Do you know what you should value
most in life going forward?
I don't know.
What is it?
I'll tell you.
It is...
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
A luxurious mansion built on a remote island!
A case swirls around an inheritance dispute!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Intrigue at Morikawa Mansion
(Part One)
"Intrigue at Morikawa Mansion, Part One!"
Wow, the entire island is your property?
Oi Hiroki (36)
Lawyer
The owner Morikawa Yuzan made
significant contributions
to the development and advancement
of soft serve ice cream.
In a single generation,
he created the massive joint
venture company Morikawa Holdings.
And Chairman Morikawa
himself invited us here.
I wonder what such a wealthy
man wants you to do.
There it is.
That's Morikawa Yuzan's mansion.
I'm dying soon.
What?
Yuzan's entire body has been
consumed by late-stage cancer.
Morikawa Yuzan (68)
Morikawa Group Chairman
He's been told he doesn't have long to live.
B-But...
So I thought I'd gather my
relatives and rewrite my will.
I see.
That's why he invited you, the
great detective Mori Kogoro.
What do you want me to do?
We want you to use your exceptional
observational skills to evaluate the candidates.
We'd like you to advise us on how to
distribute his legacy based on your assessment.
You want my advice?
The aggregate market value of his legacy
is several tens of billions of yen.
What?
Make sure you don't overlook any
part of their true character.
By the time I rewrite my will tomorrow,
I'd like you to select the one person
worthy of inheriting my legacy.
Come in.
Excuse me.
This woman manages everything
concerning this house.
My name is Shito Yuka. Call me Yuka.
Shito Yuka (24)
Chief Butler
This is the gallery.
This is the dining room.
This is the tank room.
That's a big tank.
Do those all contain soft serve?
That's right.
Anyway, have some soft serve.
Who are you?
This is Morikawa Yuichiro, the eldest son.
Morikawa Yuichiro (33)
Self-employed
He researches soft serve.
Have some before it melts.
Thank you.
Thanks for the food.
Wait!
The first bite always tastes the best.
Focus carefully while you eat it.
Thanks for the food.
Yum!
It's so good!
That's because it's freshly made
using carefully selected ingredients
and cutting-edge machinery.
I'm impressed. You can tell the Morikawa
family is particular about its ice cream.
No.
It's not ice cream, it's soft serve.
Ice Cream
Rapidly Frozen
at -30°C
Ice cream is rapidly frozen
at negative 30 degrees.
In contrast, soft serve is frozen between
negative 5 and negative 7 degrees.
Soft Serve
-5°C ~ -7°C
It's totally different.
I see.
Well, we've got plenty.
Have as much as you'd like.
We've got all kinds of
flavors available, too.
By the way, Yuichiro-san, do you
work for your father's company?
No, I'm not associated with the company.
I independently research soft serve.
What exactly do you research?
The potential of soft serve.
I research and develop
new flavors and toppings.
I see.
So, what kind of flavors
are you working on now?
That's still a secret.
I hope you'll try it once it's ready.
This is the reception room.
Allow me to introduce you.
This is Morikawa Yujiro the second son
and Morikawa Yuzaburo-san the third son.
Morikawa Yujiro (31)
Morikawa Holdings Executive
Nice to meet you.
So, you're the famous detective?
Yes, I'm Mori Kogoro.
What was Dad thinking hiring a detective?
Morikawa Yuzaburo (27)
Morikawa Livestock Rancher
Instead of being so stingy, he should
just split it evenly three ways.
He can't do that.
I doubt he wants to leave his legacy
to someone as unreliable as you.
Didn't you say you lost
a ton of money on stocks?
If I inherited everything, I'd be able to
protect all the company's assets and land.
You must be joking!
You're not capable of accounting, bro.
What did you say?!
Stop it, you two!
There are guests here!
Yujiro!
Cut it out!
Don't talk down to me!
This is only happening because
you won't settle down.
You can't start acting like
the eldest when it suits you!
What was that?
Enough of this!
I'm sorry you had to see that.
It's fine.
You'll be staying here.
I've had your luggage
brought up to your room.
What a wonderful room.
Is this a soft serve machine?
Special soft serve machines have
been installed in every room
so you can eat soft serve anytime, anywhere.
Would you like to make some?
What?
Go ahead.
Yes, that's it.
There's a trick to creating
the perfect swirl.
Like this.
You're great at that.
You get good at it working
here, like it or not.
Here you are, Mr. Detective.
Thank you.
Dinner will be served at six.
Make yourselves at home until then.
Time to take it easy until dinner.
Conan-kun, where are you going?
I'm going for a walk.
Hello? Yeah.
I know.
It's all right. I'm about to
come into a bunch of money.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm telling you, just a little...
Hello? I'll call you back later.
Yes?
Yuichiro-san, were those ingredients
for your new soft serve?
Yeah.
How do you make it?
I wanna see.
Sorry, but recipes under development
are top secret information.
I can't even allow a
child to see them. Sorry.
I see.
Then it can't be helped.
But I promise you'll be the first to eat
my new soft cream once it's finished.
Okay. I'm looking forward to it.
Sure.
Can't you do something about that?
You're bothering me.
My father trusts you most.
Can't you put in a good word for me?
I don't know what to say to that.
If I inherit his legacy,
I'll give you 3%—no, 5%.
I know. Why don't you become my wife?
Please stop.
Hey, miss.
What are you doing over there?
Think about it.
Thanks for rescuing me.
It's fine.
I hate how things are now.
It didn't used to be like this.
Be like what?
Despite how they seem, they used to be close.
But as the company grew, they
started arguing with each other.
And since they learned their father is
sick, all they think about is money.
What about you?
I've been with the family since
my father worked for them.
The master of the house has been
kind to me since I was a child.
Huh.
If only they could all get along.
Seriously.
They should be thinking about their
father right now, not themselves.
Everyone seems on edge.
Y-You're right.
Where's Yujiro-san?
I've been looking for him,
but I can't find him.
Are you sure you're not thinking
it would be convenient
if he never came back so you'd have
one less rival to contend with?
Shut it, Yuzaburo.
Unlike you, I'm an honest man.
Why don't you show the detective
over there what you're really like?
Oh?
Yuichiro-san, are you hiding something?
No, nothing.
I don't know about that.
You're still arguing with
everything going on right now?
Father.
How are you feeling?
I'm not dying yet.
I'm sorry. Yujiro hasn't shown up yet.
We told him to be punctual.
We have guests, too. Unbelievable.
They very obviously started
speaking more politely.
I would, too, if I had a chance
at inheriting billions of yen.
Seriously?
Detective Mori, I'm sorry I'm
speaking to you through a monitor,
but I hope you'll forgive me.
Don't worry about it.
In that case, please enjoy your dinner.
Begin the meal.
Very well.
This is a soft serve rice bowl.
What?!
Whoa, whoa...
Sir, dinner has concluded.
The will shall be rewritten
tomorrow afternoon.
Make sure you're present for the occasion.
They said they'd rewrite the will tomorrow.
What kind of advice are
you going to give them?
Who knows? They all seem to
have something wrong with them.
And now one of them is missing.
What will be, will be.
Morikawa Yuzaburo (27)
Third Son of the Morikawa Family
Morikawa Livestock Rancher
· Manages Morikawa Ranch
·Wants inheritance to
be split evenly between
the three brothers
Morikawa Yujiro (31)
Second Son of the Morikawa Family
Morikawa Holdings Executive
· Suffered a large loss investing
in stocks
· Thinks he should inherit the
entire legacy
Morikawa Yuichiro (33)
Eldest Son of the Morikawa Family
Soft Serve Researcher
· Researches and develops
new soft serve flavors
and toppings
· Will soon complete the
new soft serve flavor
he is researching
What's that sound?
So Yuzaburo is missing this morning as well.
What are those two doing?
It's weird, don't you think?
Huh?
Today's the day the will is being rewritten.
You're right.
Let's check on them.
Yes.
Yuka-san, bring us the master key.
Yes, sir.
We'll check Yujiro-san's room first.
No one's here?
There's nobody in here.
Or over here.
I don't see any signs of
suspicious activity either.
Let's go.
We'll check Yuzaburo's room next.
Yuzaburo!
Don't go in there!
It's no use. He's dead.
No...
All the windows are fixed,
and the room was locked.
Which means...
It's a locked room murder.
Locked room...
There are no signs of a struggle
or obvious wounds on the body.
He's curled up in a crouched position.
Hey, mister.
Huh?
Look at this.
Right here.
Looks like someone scratched the door.
That's odd, though.
The key is on the counter,
and he should've been able to open the
door from inside the room without the key.
Yuka-san, call the police.
O-Okay.
You can't.
What are you talking about?
The police will not be allowed to intervene
until the will has been rewritten.
Yuzan insisted upon this requirement.
Don't be absurd. I don't care
if that's what Yuzan wants.
You're free to call them,
but it would be considered
a breach of contract.
Morikawa Yuzan
Your signature is on this contract.
Did you not agree to prioritize
the rewriting of the will,
Detective Mori?
We are employed by Yuzan.
Yuichiro is a candidate
to inherit his legacy.
You don't object to Yuzan's wishes, do you?
I'm not telling you not to solve the case,
nor am I saying we won't call the police.
I'm simply stating that rewriting
the will is our top priority.
I understand.
In that case, I shall find the
culprit who killed Yuzaburo.
I'm hoping you do, Detective.
This place is a remote island anyway.
It would take two days for the police
to arrive even if we called them.
Yes, the master key is strictly managed.
It was kept in the same place
until we used it earlier.
Not only are all the windows fixed,
but there aren't any signs someone
broke into the room either.
The room was locked,
and the master key was kept
under strict management.
Judging by the layout and neighboring rooms,
it seems unlikely that there are
secret passageways or doors.
It's a completely closed room.
Which means the keys to solving
this locked room mystery
are the scratches left
on the inside of the door
and the location of the body.
What's this?
Black fragments?
How long have you been there?
I just got here.
What do you want?
Mister, you expected this
to happen, didn't you?
To some degree, yes.
Is the motive money after all?
Money leads people astray,
both those who have it and those who don't.
Those who have money build
walls to protect it,
while those who don't easily break laws
and hurt people to get their hands on it.
Is that why you invited Detective Mori here?
Who knows?
Hey, what's that?
This?
This remote allowed me to move
my bed and turn on the TV.
It's got a lot of buttons
for that, don't you think?
I had it custom-made so I could
reach hard-to-scratch places.
Everyone in this mansion is a suspect.
And one of them, Yujiro-san, is missing.
Who is the culprit?
Or is it...?
Conan-kun.
Ran-neechan, what are you doing?
I thought I'd make some soft serve.
I'll make some for you, too.
Okay, thanks.
You pull this, and...
Huh?
Come in.
Excuse me.
May I clean your room?
Sure.
Is something the matter?
The soft serve isn't dispensing.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Let me take a look.
Hey, Yuka-san.
Could you tell me how that machine works?
What?
Sure.
You use that to adjust
the temperature, right?
Yes.
Since it's made to handle both
soft serve and ice cream,
the temperature goes all
the way down to -50°.
By the way, what's the highest temperature?
I think I heard it goes up to 40°.
Hey, Yuka-san.
You made a weird face
when you inserted the key
into the lock of Yuzaburo-san's room.
Oh, that?
The keyhole was sticky for some reason.
I knew it.
Huh?
What is this?
Ran-neechan, is something wrong?
I-It should be vanilla soft serve.
Why?
What is this?
Could it be?
Episode Preview
Yes, this is definitely a serial murder case.
Oi-san, you still won't change your mind?
It's done.
Could it really be?
Yuka-san.
What is it?
What do you love most in this world?
Naturally, that would be...
Intrigue at Morikawa Mansion
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Intrigue
at Morikawa Mansion, Part Two!"
Soft Serve
Next Conan's hint!
Soft serve!
Don't miss the next episode.
Three day weekend coming up!
Take Tuesday off, and
it's a four day weekend!
Yeah, isn't that obvious?