Yu
[eyecatch]
Detective Conan Episode 1051 "Intrigue
at Morikawa Mansion (Part Two)"
[op]
[ed]
Wow, an ice cream cake!
We'd better eat it quick before it melts.
Hold your horses.
Yuichiro, would you cut the cake for us?
Yes, Father.
We were invited to the remote
island where the mansion
of Morikawa Holdings chairman
Morikawa Yuzan is located
to advise him on the rewriting of his will.
At the mansion were Yuzan and his heirs,
Morikawa Yuzan (68)
Morikawa Group Chairman
Morikawa Yuichiro (33)
Self-employed
his eldest son Morikawa Yuichiro-san,
Morikawa Yujiro (31)
Morikawa Holdings Executive
his second son Morikawa Yujiro-san,
and his third son Morikawa Yuzaburo-san.
Morikawa Yuzaburo (27)
Morikawa Livestock Rancher
Also present were Yuzan's
lawyer Oi Hiroki-san.
Oi Hiroki (36)
Lawyer
Shito Yuka (24)
Chief Butler
and chief butler Shito Yuka-san.
The next day, the third son Yuzaburo-san
was found murdered in a locked room,
and even Yujiro-san turned up dead, too.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
An inheritance dispute swirls about the case!
What is the mystery of the locked
room and the family's motives?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Intrigue at Morikawa Mansion
(Part Two)
"Intrigue at Morikawa Mansion, Part Two!"
Yujiro!
No...
Dad, is this...?
Yes, this is definitely a serial murder case.
Oi-san, you still won't change your mind?
Yuzan's mind has not changed
is what I'd like to say, but I
already called the police yesterday.
Y-You mean...
The police should arrive by the time
the will is rewritten this afternoon.
You should've told us.
Shouldn't you be getting started on
the investigation, like that boy?
There's a bruise on the back of his head.
This must've killed him.
What is it, kid?
What's this?
Mister, what do you suppose
this dark stain is?
It's... not mud. It's coal-colored.
I've had enough!
Aren't you supposed to be a great detective?
Hurry up and catch the culprit!
Please calm down.
My brothers were killed one after another.
No matter how you look
at it, I'm clearly next.
We don't know that yet.
My father's heirs have
been killed in succession.
Enough of this!
What good will it do to take out
your frustrations on the detective?
Excuse me.
Where are you going?
I'm returning to my room. I have work to do.
I can't believe this inheritance dispute
turned into a serial murder case.
Hey, mister. Have you already
figured out who the culprit is?
Of course.
Who do you think I am?
By the way, who is it?
Normally you'd assume it's
the eldest son Yuichiro.
But it's hard to believe he did
it based on his earlier behavior.
But it goes without saying that he stands
to benefit the most from their deaths.
It's done.
Come to think of it, that
lawyer is suspicious, too.
He didn't want us to call the police.
You're right.
Depending on how you look at it, it seems
like he's afraid of the murders coming to light.
Or what if it's actually Yuka-san?
What?
Why?
They say every rose has its thorn.
That's your reason?
Flavor,
texture, and taste.
It's perfect.
This is the soft serve I've been looking for.
Its jet black appearance doesn't give the
slightest hint of its mild chocolate sweetness.
The high-quality cacao flavor
spreads throughout the mouth and
leaves a refreshing aftertaste.
It's truly perfect!
Yujiro and Yuzaburo are dead.
The inheritance is all mine.
Now I just need my father to die.
Once he's dead, it'll be my time to shine!
I shall reign supreme!
Mister!
I-I know.
Yuichiro-san?
You stay here.
One shot through the heart from behind.
He probably didn't even
have time to feel pain.
No...
Look. His tongue is black.
What does that mean?
He must've been up there.
Conan-kun?
Ow...
Yuka-san!
They say every rose has its thorn.
Could it really be?
Conan-kun, I heard a gunshot. What happened?
Yuichiro-san was shot. Yuka-san,
stay with the others.
Wait, where are you going?
Why did you follow me?
I can't leave you by yourself.
I manage everything at this house.
Then what's in the room up ahead?
It should be a tool room.
There's no one here.
Yuka-san, what's the story with this rifle?
The master bought it a few years ago
when some boars tore up the yard.
The lock's been broken.
This smell...
Yuka-san.
Yes?
Could you show me Yuichiro-san's room?
Now this is a problem.
Huh?
I thought one of the three
brothers was the culprit,
but they're all dead now.
Who could the culprit be?
Come to think of it, Oi-san, we weren't
able to confirm your alibi either.
You think I did it?
Give me a break.
I'm a simple lawyer.
I'm pretty sure even a lawyer
is capable of killing a person.
In that case, I believe detectives
are capable of murder as well.
What's all this?
Yuichiro-san had been working on
researching a new flavor for a long time.
The things on that table are
probably research materials.
This is...
black soft serve.
You're right.
Hey, Yuka-san.
What is it?
What do you love most in this world?
Naturally, that would be...
It's you, kid. What is it this time?
I figured out who killed Yuichiro-san.
Oh? How interesting.
So, who did it?
Yuichiro-san was killed by...
Killed by?
Morikawa Yuzan-san.
You did it, mister.
You must be rather certain to
accuse me of being the culprit.
Tell me about it.
But first...
Hey.
You've been using this to watch everything.
Your dead sons and us.
The murders that have been
happening since yesterday
were a series of unfortunate events
caused by your tremendous legacy.
Is that really true?
First, there's Yuzaburo-san's
locked room murder.
Oh? You figured out the mystery
of that locked room murder?
I have no idea.
At first I couldn't believe it,
but I became certain after hearing
what Yuka-san had to say.
Yuichiro-san created that locked room
using the special soft serve machine.
Before the locked room was created,
Yuichiro-san and Yuzaburo-san
were probably chatting
in Yuzaburo-san's room over drinks.
During their conversation, Yuichiro-san
said he'd have some soft serve
and used the special soft serve
machine installed in the mansion.
The machine's temperature
can be set as low as -50°,
and the valve's temperature can be set
as high as 40°, all of it on a timer.
Undetected by Yuzaburo-san, Yuichiro-san
directed the cooling system's vent
outwards and set the
machine to cool the room.
He cleaned up his own glass and left the
room with a cone of soft serve in hand,
leaving the passed out drunk
Yuzaburo-san alone in the room.
Once Yuichiro-san was outside,
he inserted the soft serve into the keyhole.
Before the soft serve could melt away,
the machine cooled the entire room at -50°.
By the time Yuzaburo-san noticed something
was wrong and attempted to exit the room,
the soft serve in the keyhole had frozen,
making it impossible to leave the room.
That's right. Yuzaburo-san froze to death.
It was a trick using
special soft serve machines that could
only be pulled off at this mansion.
After Yuzaburo-san froze to death,
the timer was set to heat the room.
The frozen room itself and soft serve in the
keyhole thawed, creating the locked room.
Yujiro-san was murdered when
Yujiro-san asked to meet Yuichiro-san
in front of the soft serve tanks.
Yu
There was a note written by Yujiro-san
in the trash can of Yuichiro-san's room.
Meet me in front of the tanks at 4PM today
Yu
It probably happened after
their conversation turned sour
and they got into an argument.
No, it was Yujiro who was
trying to kill Yuichiro.
What?
After arguing over their
shares of the inheritance,
a fight broke out, and then this happened.
I see.
Then Yuichiro-san hid the
body inside the tank.
Your deduction was perfect,
but what made you certain he did it?
It was this.
What's that?
Materials for the black soft
serve Yuichiro-san developed.
It's practically jet black.
Ah, it's bamboo charcoal.
That's right.
Jet black chocolate soft serve
made with bamboo charcoal.
It's the project Yuichiro-san
had been working on.
Pieces of bamboo charcoal were
left at both crime scenes.
At one scene, the pieces of charcoal
were stuck to the soft serve machine,
and at the other, there was a charcoal
stain on the floor of the tank room.
And Yuichiro-san's tongue
was black when he was shot
because of this soft serve
made with bamboo charcoal.
That's what you call hard evidence.
So why do you think I killed Yuichiro?
Oh, that?
That was simple.
It's terribly complicated.
There are lots of reasons,
like who knew how to use a hunting gun
or where it was stored in this mansion,
but it was something simple that clued me in.
And what was that?
The Sleeping Kogoro?
Is this that famous phenomenon?
Dad.
After I heard the gunshot and visited
the yard where Yuichiro-san fell,
I went to the room I believed
the shot came from.
In that room with the rifle,
I noticed something.
There was the smell of
gunpowder left by the gunshot
and the smell of the medicines
kept in this room.
And...
There was your smell, too.
My smell?
You mean my old man smell?
Well, you got me.
By using my last bit of strength
to kill him, I dug my own grave.
Why did you kill your own son?
Couldn't you have let the police handle it?
He was blinded by money and
killed his own brothers.
I couldn't trouble someone
else with dealing with him.
As his father, I took
responsibility for what he did.
I originally plotted to
return them to their senses.
Return them to their senses?
I taught my sons to share
since they were boys.
I told them I was planning to rewrite my will
to have one heir so they'd remember that.
It's the willingness to
share with each other.
Don't forget that.
But they didn't remember.
That's right.
In fact, they started
killing each other instead.
You mean Yuzaburo-san tried
to kill someone, too?
Yeah.
He was trying to kill Yuichiro, too.
Yuichiro probably figured
it out and killed him first.
After all my hard work,
I've lost everything on my deathbed.
It's ironic.
The more money I made, the
unhappier my family became.
They used to be so close, too.
Boy, I want you to do something for me.
Tell the police what happened.
And...
Could you make sure Yuichiro's
recipe sees the light of day?
Got it.
That soft serve looked tasty.
Yeah...
Edogawa Conan-sama.
I was instructed by the late Morikawa Yuzan
to entrust you with the
distribution of his legacy.
Me?
Yes.
He said to leave everything up to you.
Take this.
But wasn't Kogoro-no-ojisan hired to do that?
Once the murders happened,
Morikawa Yuzan said he'd entrust the
matter to whoever solved the case.
Who, me?
Yes.
I've been told to leave the entire
matter of the inheritance up to you.
What am I going to do?
As you like.
Also...
This it the recipe for bamboo charcoal
soft serve Yuichiro left behind.
I've also received instructions
to make it public.
Wow, an ice cream cake!
Yuichiro, would you cut the cake for us?
Yes, Father.
Four pieces?
But there's only three of us.
Is one piece for Dad?
No.
Oh, right.
Yuka-chan, come on.
Have some ice cream cake with us.
Okay!
You'd better hurry, or it'll melt.
I understand. I accept.
Good choice.
The case was solved while I was asleep again.
Anyway, is that young lady really
taking over the entire Morikawa Group?
Why not? Shouldn't someone who loves
soft serve inherit his legacy anyway?
Hey, Yuka-san.
What is it?
What do you love most in this world?
Naturally, that would be soft serve.
I guess you're right.
Hey, look at this.
Huh?
Huh? What?!
Whoa.
Did you make those, Ran-neechan?
Yeah, I got good at it after
Yuka-san taught me her trick.
Wow, you did a great job.
Here.
Have some, Conan-kun.
Thanks for the food.
It's so good!
Episode Preview
Tonight we're visiting an abandoned
hospital that was closed a long time ago.
Sadao and Toshiko haven't arrived
yet at this super secret spot.
Oh, yeah?
Looks like the real deal.
It's room 3045, right?
Could it be?
The Detective Boys' Test of Courage
The next episode of Conan is "The
Detective Boys' Test of Courage!"
Cat
Next Conan's hint!
A cat!
Summer is for...
Don't miss the next episode.
Playing chicken!
Gizzards, livers, and intestines!
Gutless...