[op]
[ed]
[eyecatch]
Detective Conan Episode 1052 "The
Detective Boys' Test of Courage"
Softie Sadao and Scaredy-cat Toshiko
Visit
Haunted Locations!
Hello. I'm Softie Sadao.
Softie Sadao
And I'm Scaredy-cat Toshiko.
Scaredy-cat Toshiko
Together we are oh-so-scared!
So Scared
Tonight we've come to an abandoned
hotel rumored to be haunted by ghosts.
It certainly looks haunted.
Hey, wait.
What's that?
Huh?
There's someone there.
But there was no one there a moment ago.
What are you guys watching?
You've never heard of Sadao and Toshiko?
Sadao and Toshiko?
Softie Sadao and Scaredy-cat
Toshiko Visit Haunted Locations!
Don't forget to subscribe
to our channel!
They're a famous duo that visit reputed
haunted locations and film real ghosts.
All their videos are so scary
they'll make you pee your pants.
Sounds fishy.
Fishy or not, apparently you can make
decent money if your videos go viral.
All right!
Then the Detective Boys will film ghosts,
too, and eat our fill of eel bowls!
Yeah!
Seriously?
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
A haunted location teeming with rumors!
The terrifying experience
will chill you to the bone!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Detective Boys' Test of Courage
"The Detective Boys' Test of Courage!"
Maybe we should've had the
professor come with us after all.
What are you talking about?
He definitely would've tried to stop us.
We'll be fine.
If any ghosts show up, I'll knock them out.
I thought you didn't believe in ghosts.
I couldn't let these guys go on their own.
Hey, guys.
The building may be abandoned,
but trespassing is still—
Tonight we're visiting an abandoned
hospital that was closed a long time ago.
Rumors surrounding the place have
only recently begun to spread,
and Sadao and Toshiko haven't yet
visited this super secret spot.
Oh, yeah?
They say a big red oni baby comes
crawling towards you while crying.
No, apparently a mummy chases
after you in a wheelchair.
No, a long-haired lady doctor
charges at you with a scalpel.
Those are some pretty random rumors.
Sounds nice and lively.
Looks like the real deal.
Starting to get scared?
No, of course not.
I-In any case,
there's a locked room on the
third floor inhabited by a ghost.
It's supposed to be room 304, right?
Yes.
Let's film as we head towards the room.
Okay, let's go!
Yeah!
Hey, wait!
Let's go.
What?
Jeez.
Someone's there.
It's just a scarecrow.
And look.
Do Not Enter!
Entering the building without permission
from the administrator is forbidden!
It says right here that entry
is forbidden, so let's get—
If entry is forbidden...
Then maybe it really is haunted.
Let's film some ghosts!
Yeah!
All right!
Hey, you can't go in there.
Careful. Don't run.
Jeez...
Hey, guys. Watch your
step. It's dark in here.
Okay!
We're currently on the first
floor of an abandoned hospital.
Is this abandoned hospital
truly haunted by ghosts?
Ghosts, are you there?
If you're there, give us a sign.
Why would the ghosts respond to you?
Did you hear that voice?
Yeah.
It sounded like a crying baby.
Is this...?
Could it be?
The crying red oni baby!
It could be a blue oni.
Haibara?
It's too dangerous.
You'll be cursed.
I'll be fine.
This must be it.
I knew it.
There's no red oni baby.
Ai-chan!
Haibara!
Haibara-san!
What happened, Haibara?
Haibara?
Haibara-san!
Haibara!
Ai-chan!
Stop, that tickles.
It's just a cat?
How cute.
So this is the red oni baby's true identity.
Okay, get off of her.
You're making me jealous.
What do you think you're
doing to Haibara-san?
This is what most ghosts turn out to be.
Let's get this over with.
Okay.
Here, Conan-kun.
Okay—hey, wait.
Since you don't have a collar,
does that mean you're a stray?
Pretty friendly for a stray.
What are you doing?
Let's go, Conan-kun.
Leave the cat.
Fine.
We've come to the second floor.
I sense a kind of mysterious presence.
It's just cooler because the sun has set.
Haibara-san...
She's rather blunt.
Haibara-san?
Ai-chan.
Was that sound...?
The mummy in the wheelchair!
Whatever. Let's go.
What?
We'll never know what caused the
sound unless we check it out.
This is it.
Conan-kun.
Haibara.
It's too dangerous.
Are you okay?
Ai-chan.
A doll?
But we heard the sound of the
wheelchair moving until a moment ago.
This is what caused the noise.
I see.
That scared me for real.
Either way, this doll looks awfully new.
How long has it been here?
University Hospital Admits to Malpractice
What are these doing here?
Suspects in Robbery and
Murder Escape After Shootout
Dangers Lurking in Everyday Life
Another Home Catches Fire in Haido City!
Eldest Daughter in Her 30s Unreachable
Consensus Among Employees, One
Step Closer to Amicable Settlement
Is something the matter?
There are several newspapers here
from the same day six months ago.
University Hospital Admits to Malpractice
Suspects in Robbery and
Murder Escape After Shootout
Maruo Junji (29)
Onigashira Tomoe (29)
Another Home Catches Fire in Haido City!
Eldest Daughter in Her 30s Unreachable
That's certainly odd.
Hey, Haibara.
Was that doll facing this way?
What?
Oh, come on. Don't you start
saying weird things, too.
Sorry.
Let's get moving.
Sure.
Unbelievable.
What's next, the locked
room on the third floor?
Y-Yes, the room allegedly haunted by a ghost.
Then let's shed light on that rumor.
Okay.
W-We're on the third floor.
This floor is even creepier than the last.
It's room 304, right?
The locked room.
Yes, I suppose.
301.
302.
That's 303.
304—
Ugh, what is that?
Ai-chan.
Oh, please. This is just someone's prank.
Haibara-san?
What's wrong, Ai-chan?
Something just passed by my feet.
Oh, it's that cat again.
Hey, kitty. Come here.
It left.
Hey, what is that?
Could it be?
She chases you with a scalpel.
The ghost of the long-haired lady doctor.
Could it be?
She chases you with a scalpel.
The ghost of the long-haired lady doctor.
It's a ghost!
Hey, guys!
Let's go.
Damn it.
There really was a ghost.
We might get cursed.
Let's get out of here.
Right, Conan?
Hey, Conan?
What are you looking at?
Notice anything interesting?
Yeah.
Take a look at this, guys.
Have the kids left?
Yeah, seems like it.
Did you see the looks on their faces?
Oh, yeah. They were
screaming their heads off.
Hilarious.
Maybe we scared them too much.
It's totally fine. They were
getting in the way of our job.
Come on, let's finish setting things up.
Anyway, those scared expressions...
Quit it. You'll remind me again.
Didn't they close the window earlier?
Yeah.
Then what's this sound?
Don't screw around.
I didn't do anything.
Then why is that doll here?
It's a ghost!
What now?
What is this?
They fell over.
Did we overdo it?
Hey, is everything okay down there?
Both of them passed out.
Do you think they're okay?
It's fine.
They got what they deserved.
That was awful.
Yeah, I can't believe you did that.
You're the ones who scared us first.
All we did was get you back
using the tools you left around.
Anyway, I'm disappointed all those
videos turned out to be fake.
We trusted you.
But how did you know we set everything up?
It was this.
Look.
You're in the edge of the frame.
This is you, isn't it?
Huh?
This person's hand...
What's wrong with this cat?
Hold on. That means...
Hey, did you two come to this
abandoned hospital alone?
What about the actors who
always appear in your videos?
They haven't arrived yet.
We have the actors come once we've
finished setting everything up.
What is it?
It's the ghost that appeared
when we went to the third floor.
Look at her left hand.
Toshiko-san doesn't have this scar.
And that's not all.
The cat that doesn't like either of
them loves whoever's in this video.
Hey, who is this?
It's not me.
You kids ran away before I could scare you.
Th-Then...
Could this be...?
A real ghost?
Don't say that, Genta-kun!
But that's the only thing it could be.
If that really is an actual
ghost, then this is incredible.
We'll definitely go viral.
You kids...
Give that back!
Let us publish it on our channel.
We'll get way more views that way.
No way.
That's our ghost.
How could you take that away from us?
What are you guys doing?
You're dealing with children here.
Give them the camera you took.
Yeah, that's right.
Give it back.
And you kids shouldn't be in here either.
Didn't you see the sign out front?
It says, "Do Not Enter."
We're sorry.
Come on, give me the camera.
I'll erase the video.
But there's a video of a real ghost on here.
You've broken the law.
Aw, man.
Wait.
That cat seems quite attached to you.
Y-Yeah, because I frequently patrol this place.
How'd you get that scar on your hand?
It's the same as the scar on the hand
of the ghost we saw on the third floor.
Then this guy is...?
Yeah, he's the ghost.
What?
I knew it.
Whoa, whoa. What do you mean, I'm the ghost?
From the looks of it, that's
a piercing bullet wound.
In other words, you were shot by a gun.
It doesn't look like it was
properly treated either.
You're the murderer who escaped after
the shootout mentioned in the newspaper.
Suspects in Robbery and
Murder Escape After Shootout
Maruo Junji (29)
Onigashira Tomoe (29)
That's why there were several newspapers
from the same day in that room.
The murderer was trying to get as
much information as possible
on the crime they committed.
Yeah, and there should be something
you're even more desperate
to keep hidden inside the locked room 304.
Like the gun you used in the
crime or the goods you stole.
But the culprit in that case was fat.
And had short blond hair.
He was when he started
hiding here six months ago.
And it wasn't just his left
hand that was injured.
He was covered in blood and writhing in pain.
Like the crawling red oni baby.
It seems like he managed to stop the bleeding
using bandages he found at this
abandoned hospital though.
That must be the mummy people saw.
Hiding here must've been tough.
The hair you dyed black has grown
out, and you've lost a ton of weight.
So that's why people saw the
long-haired lady doctor.
In other words, the rumors surrounding
this building weren't about ghosts.
They were all about the
same flesh-and-blood human.
The fugitive hiding in
this abandoned hospital,
Maruo Junji.
Maruo Junji (29)
They were about you.
A person's appearance changes
as they live in hiding.
That's what you used to look like.
People who came here to
test their courage saw you
and spread those rumors about ghosts.
He might've scared them on purpose
to drive people like that away.
But you couldn't hide the
scar on your left hand.
That's why you came here to erase our video.
Enough.
I'll erase all of you!
Come on,
quit struggling.
Damn.
What?
These idiots...
Conan!
Oh?
Let's flee to the second floor!
Got it.
Where are Conan and the others?
What are we going to do?
Where did they go?
You can't scare me with that.
Why?
Why did you kill me?
Impossible...
I begged you to spare me!
We're saved...
We did it!
The Detective Boys win!
Later, the police who responded to our call
arrested fugitive Maruo Junji.
Furthermore, Softie Sadao and
Scaredy-cat Toshiko were questioned
for unlawfully entering a building.
And of course, we were scolded severely, too.
Aw, man.
I've had enough of tests of courage.
Episode Preview
It's a long story.
I'll tell you the details once we arrive.
What?
Yoshida-san is missing?
A shogi piece?
Hold on.
I've seen this piece before.
What are these skinny things?
Huh?
The Spark That Fell on the Ranch
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "The Spark
That Fell on the Ranch, Part One!"
Chicken
Next Conan's hint.
A chicken!
Restless roosters rarely
reside within their roost!
Don't miss the next episode.
Restless roosters rarely
reside within their roost!
So, where are the roosters?