[ed]
[eyecatch]
Detective Conan Episode 1053 "The Spark
That Fell on the Ranch (Part One)"
[op]
Yes.
I'm sorry, but I don't know where I am.
I was pursuing a man suspected of
stealing a large quantity of explosives,
but I was caught off guard, and
when I came to my senses...
No GPS?
My phone seems to have
been taken by that man.
My only option was to borrow the flip phone
on the body abandoned in this basement.
The body?
Yes, but it doesn't have
much battery remaining.
Was the dead guy killed by that man?
Most likely.
But I'll be fine. I'll find a
way out of this room myself—
Don't do it, Kazami.
If you act carelessly or call for backup,
you could provoke the culprit into
causing the worst possible outcome.
I'll go,
before you end up dead, too.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
A suspicious group of men gather on a ranch!
Amuro leaps into action, and
the case takes a sudden turn!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Spark That Fell on the Ranch
(Part One)
"The Spark That Fell on the Ranch, Part One!"
I'm so excited to see the new chickens.
I hope the new chickens are full of energy.
Yeah.
The two that died the other day were sick
forever, so we barely got to take care of them.
They weren't so much sick
as old and decrepit.
Those two had been around
since I was in first grade.
Since you were in first grade?
You're in first grade right now.
What I meant was...
Are you stupid or something?
Listen up, children.
Make sure you learn proper husbandry from
the ranch that's giving us the chickens.
Okay!
Will they really be okay?
But why did we bring the children?
We could've gone alone if we just
wanted to learn proper husbandry.
Wakasa-sensei, I was planning on taking
this secret to the grave, but...
Yes?
I don't like birds.
Y-You don't?
Ever since I saw a flock of vultures crowd around
and devour a dead zebra on TV as a child,
I've been terrified of their
bulging eyes and pointed beaks.
So even if I can't do it, I thought
it'd be easier to explain their care
if I took a video of the children
looking after the chickens.
But isn't the detective you're dating
named Shiratori (white bird)?
What? That's just his name.
Would you assume someone named
Karasuda-san (crow field) is a crow?
No, but...
If someone had "crow" in their name,
I'd assume they're a dark, cunning,
and unapproachable person
who conspires with others.
But people like that tend to
be cheerful and fun instead.
Yeah, maybe.
Crow...
Karasuma Renya.
The boss of the organization that turned me
into a child using the medicine they made.
And Wakasa-sensei is a suspect for
Rum, the organization's number two.
Come to think of it, the owner of the ranch we're
headed to is Hatoyama-san (dove mountain).
I hope they're peaceful, like a dove.
Are you two headed to Hatoyama Ranch as well?
Hitsuka Junya (34)
What a coincidence.
I'm actually on my way to that ranch, too.
What are you going there for?
I'm gathering a bit of
information for a story.
It's sort of like visiting a power
spot frequented by regulars.
Judging by your appearance,
that's what you're doing, too, right?
Nanbu Takashi (56)
I'm just going to do research.
I'm not like you people who
are in it for the money.
Here we go again.
You're planning to sell
your research, aren't you?
Gathering information? Research? Money?
Hey, he's watching a movie.
Is it science fiction?
Kano Shogo (43)
Quit looking over my
shoulder. Get out of here.
Sorry...
It's all right, though. I took
a video of his phone screen.
Let's look it up online.
Humanity On the Brink of Extinction Again?!
Hey, what do you think you're doing?!
Erase that video right this instant!
What?
Erase it!
Hey!
Hand it over!
Please let go!
The Rum suspect isn't doing anything.
Fine, then. I'll use my
tranquilizer watch to—
Amuro-san!
Who the hell are you?
Why don't we call it here?
And Mitsuhiko-kun, you should erase the
video that upset him in the first place.
Okay.
Are we good?
Yeah.
You're Amuro-san?
Yes.
I'm Kobayashi, their homeroom teacher.
I've heard so much about you.
Amuro-san is apparently a
detective who works at a café.
I'm Wakasa, the assistant homeroom teacher.
Nice to meet you.
Hello.
Amuro-san, where are you taking this bus to?
Like you guys, I'm going to Hatoyama Ranch.
I've got business there.
You do?
It's a long story.
I'll tell you the details once we arrive.
Hatoyama Ranch
There's nobody home.
The gate was left open.
And there isn't a single cow around.
Yeah.
They're planning on shutting down the ranch
and making this area part of a golf course,
so there aren't any employees anymore.
So that's why they're giving
our school chickens for free.
Yes.
They figured they might as well.
Then let's go check out the chickens
we came for until the owner shows up.
What?
You know where they are?
They're probably in the
direction of that arrow.
Chicken Ranch
S-Seriously?
There isn't a single chicken in here.
Why not?
Maybe they've moved the two they're giving to the
grade school elsewhere and sold the others already.
Take a look outside.
Look.
There's a huge hole in
the side of the building.
Maybe they escaped through here.
You're right.
We should check out some
other locations, too.
Yeah.
What's this filled in spot
right next to the hole?
There's a bathroom here.
Lucky me. I've been holding it forever.
Me, too, actually.
Then why don't we take a bathroom
break before we look for the owner?
Yes, let's.
A chicken.
Hey, Conan.
It's time you told me why you came here.
Did I say I'd tell you?
It'll run away if I say something.
Quietly, quietly.
What?
Yoshida-san is missing?
She wandered off somewhere
during our bathroom break.
Let's split up and look for her.
I'll go with Amuro-san,
Edogawa-kun, and Tsuburaya-kun.
Then I'll go with Kojima-kun and Haibara-san.
Bishop
What's that?
A shogi piece?
Hold on.
I've seen this piece before.
Kojima-kun, what are you doing? Let's go.
Right.
I caught it.
Huh?
Where am I?
There are lots of burnt branches
and a weird trail on the ground.
And what's this?
What are these skinny things?
Huh?
Ayumi!
Yoshida-san!
If you're there, say something!
Looking for someone?
What? Yes.
I'm Hatoyama Umisuke, younger brother of
Hatoyama Ranch manager Hatoyama Gisuke.
Hatoyama Umisuke (37)
I haven't been able to get in touch
with my brother since two days ago,
so I came to check on him.
We're looking for the girl we came here with.
She's a first-year grade school student.
Have you seen her?
Oh.
Yeah, I saw her.
R-Really?
Is this the girl you're looking for?
N-No!
Ayumi-chan!
What?
Whoa, there. Don't move.
First, throw your cell phones down here.
Then start walking according
to my directions.
If you try anything, I'll stab this girl.
Hatoyama Ranch
Now go down those stairs.
Goodbye.
F-Furuya-san?
It's you, Furuya-san!
You came to rescue me!
Kazami.
All right! Now I'll be saved!
I've been captured, too, so
your situation hasn't changed.
Isn't this guy Amuro-san's subordinate?
Um...
Who is Furuya?
Oh, it's my alias.
Sometimes they're necessary
when you work as a detective.
This is my detective's assistant.
I'm Hida Danroku.
Hey, more importantly...
There's a corpse on the bed.
What?
And this corpse's face looks just like
the guy who trapped us down here.
You're right.
The body looks a little older,
but they do look rather similar.
That's Hatoyama Gisuke.
He's the manager of Hatoyama
Ranch who was going
to give Teitan Elementary
School his chickens.
You've met before?
No, we just spoke over the phone,
but when I looked him up
online, I saw a photo of him.
Which means that man
doesn't seem to have lied
about being the younger
brother of the ranch manager.
Hey, wouldn't now be a good time to tell
the real reason you came here, Amuro-san?
Hida, tell them.
Yes, sir.
Thirty hours ago,
I learned a large quantity of explosives
had been stolen from a construction site.
I determined there was a
risk of a terrorist attack,
so I followed the footsteps of a suspicious
worker named Hatoyama Umisuke to this ranch.
But he caught me off guard and hit me.
When I woke up, I was in this basement.
I used the dead man's phone
to call Furu—Amuro-san.
I came here to rescue him, but I
ended up getting captured instead.
Really?
So detectives even do things that
sound like secret police work.
Well, yeah. They're with
the Public Security Bureau.
But what was Hatoyama Umisuke trying to do
that required him to kill his own brother?
He even stole all those explosives.
Actually, I think this man killed himself.
A suicide?
How do you know that?
Because even though there are
signs he was strangled to death,
there are no signs he resisted.
R-Really?
If someone strangled you,
you'd fight back hard enough to
leave scratches on your own neck.
It'd be a different story
if his hands were tied,
but there aren't any signs they were bound.
But if he were fed sleeping pills,
had a rope placed around his neck,
and was pushed from a high place...
I doubt that happened.
He probably hung himself next
to the desk in this room.
Since he's not wearing shoes,
he must've been wearing those
boots next to the desk.
I don't know who moved the body to the bed,
but if they removed his boots
when they put him there,
then they'd be next to the bed.
The only conceivable explanation is
that he removed his boots himself
when he climbed on the
chair to hang himself.
But when I woke up, the
chair wasn't knocked over,
and though I brushed them
off when I sat on it,
there were footprints on the seat.
Were they bootprints?
Now that you mention it, they
were leather bootprints.
Then they must've been left by the shoes
worn by that man who trapped us down here.
He was wearing leather boots.
He probably discovered his
brother hanging down here
and stood on the chair and removed
the rope in order to bring him down.
The question is why he killed himself.
He may have been researching something.
See? There are lots of highlighter marks
on his left pointer finger and thumb.
You're right. People often use
highlighters while doing research.
And you often end up with ink on your left
hand when you fail to put the cap on the pen.
What's strange is that the ink on his left
hand is pink, light blue, and yellow,
but there's no yellow highlighter
in his breast pocket.
Since it doesn't seem to be in this room,
he either forgot it somewhere else or something
made just the yellow pen fall out of his pocket.
More importantly, I'm worried about
the others who are still outside.
If your phones were taken, too,
then we have no way to
get in touch with them.
We've got that covered.
We've got these badges
equipped with transceivers.
What?
You've been locked inside the basement beneath
the ranch office by the owner's younger brother?
Yeah.
Not only that, but the ranch owner's body
is down here in the basement with us.
Body?
So, did you find Ayumi?
Yeah, although she's still asleep after the
younger brother made her smell some chemicals.
Then we'll head over to
rescue you right away.
Hold on. Don't be careless.
This guy stole a large quantity of
explosives from a construction site.
Explosives?
There's no telling what he'll
do if we're not careful.
In any case,
it was the ranch owner's younger brother
Hatoyama Umisuke who locked us in here.
He's a thin man in his thirties
wearing a white safari hat.
Try to call the police
without him noticing—
Excuse me.
Are you looking for someone?
Yeah, actually...
We're looking for a group of tourists with
kids like us who were on the bus with us.
I was hoping we could be friends.
Oh.
When I told that family my brother
the ranch owner isn't here right now,
they left disappointed.
Oh, really?
Aw, man. You mean he's not here after all?
No wonder there was no one at the office.
Well, this is my first time in the area.
I just followed this guy here
since I don't know anyone else.
I don't know this area too well either,
so I wanted to ask Hatoyama-san a bunch of
questions since I'd met him once before.
Apparently something shocking happened to
him recently and he ended up in the hospital.
The hospital?
How is your older brother doing?
He seems to be recovering,
but I have a message from him.
A message?
"Go to a certain spot on this mountain."
"If you find it,
secretly bring it home with you and hold
onto it until I'm out of the hospital."
What is "it" exactly?
Who knows? He said I'd know when I found it.
Then let's go there.
Yeah, if that's how we'll know what it is.
Are you and that family the
only ones who came on the bus?
There was someone else.
A big scary dude.
Then let's find him and the
four of us can go together.
Do you think we'll find him?
He went up into the mountains
without saying anything.
Okay, Haibara. Once that man
leaves, call the police.
Sorry, but my phone's out of batteries.
I forgot mine at home.
Then we'll use mine.
Whoa.
Huh?
There's a hole in your butt pocket.
What?
It's not there. It's missing.
Did you drop something?
Nothing significant.
Come to think of, Amuro-no-niichan
picked something up.
Like a piece of wood or something.
The detective did?
Yeah.
More importantly, hurry
up and call the police.
R-Right!
Sensei!
Sorry, we can't call the police anymore.
Seriously?!
In any case, the three of
us will head to the office.
We'll talk again once we get there.
Damn it. Where is it?
Where is this place?!
A beam across the night sky?
That's the movie that guy was watching?
Yes.
But I faintly heard someone say,
"Who's launching bottle rockets
in the middle of the mountains?"
so maybe it was a sci-fi comedy.
Sci-fi comedy?
Um, Furuya-san.
What have you been looking at?
It's a shogi piece.
This bishop with a scratch
on the bottom left side.
I feel like I've seen it before.
Speaking of shogi,
Haneda Shukichi Meijin defended his
title again and kept his six crowns.
It's impressive, isn't it?
Haneda?
17 years ago, shogi genius Haneda Koji died
a mysterious death in the United States.
Bishop
The only one of his possessions
that went missing in the case
was the bishop he always kept on
his person as a good luck charm.
According to the documents I was shown as
part of my PSB training on unsolved cases,
that bishop was the last piece played in
his first victory against a shogi master.
His family said there was no way their
son would've let go of that piece,
and whoever had it must
be the one who killed him.
The shape of the scratch and
lettering on this bishop
closely resemble the photo
of the piece I saw back then.
I can hardly believe it, but are
they really here at this ranch?
The person who killed Haneda Koji?
Hatoyama Ranch
It's no use. The back door is locked, too.
Then we can't get inside.
Sensei, are you okay?
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
But we can probably get inside
now that the glass is broken.
Yeah.
Ayumi-chan.
You're awake.
Huh?
Stay back!
Ayumi-chan.
It's okay.
The guy who kidnapped you isn't here.
What?
Ayumi-chan, can you remember
when you were kidnapped?
Did you see anything strange?
I ended up in a weird place after
I chased a chicken into the woods.
A weird place?
Yeah.
There were lots of burnt
branches on the ground.
Burnt branches?
And there was a long
ditch in the ground, too.
A ditch?
The hole on the side of the chicken coop.
The filled in dirt next to the hole.
The man who became furious
when some children
saw him watching a video of a
beam shooting across a night sky.
The numerous burnt branches and
the long ditch in the ground.
I've finally figured it out why those
three guys on the bus came here.
Episode Preview
All three of them were wearing hiking boots.
I see.
So that's why they had magnets.
You saw their magnets?
Yeah.
But what would we use that for?
You guys are gonna make something for me.
The chance he might be wearing those
shoes is exactly what he want.
The Spark That Fell on the Ranch
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "The Spark
That Fell on the Ranch, Part Two!"
Highlighter
Next Conan's hint.
A highlighter!
Kazami, any summer vacation plans?
Don't miss the next episode.
What? A vacation?
Taking vacations is an
important part of your job.