The Detective Boys and I accompanied
Kobayashi-sensei and Wakasa-sensei
to Hatoyama Ranch to pick up some chickens.
We arrived at Hatoyama Ranch with Amuro-san,
Hatoyama Ranch
who happened to be riding the same bus,
but for some reason,
there was no one at the ranch.
Ayumi became separated from the group
while we were searching the ranch,
so we split up to look for her,
and a man claiming to be
the ranch owner's younger brother
named Hatoyama Umisuke showed up.
Umisuke took Ayumi hostage,
and I was locked inside the basement
along with Amuro-san, Mitsuhiko,
and Kobayashi-sensei.
Amuro-san's subordinate and police officer
was also being held inside,
and the body of ranch owner Hatoyama
Gisuke-san was in the basement as well.
We got in touch with
Haibara's group on the outside,
but Umisuke and the men who rode
the bus with us showed up.
What is Umisuke's objective?
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
The key to solving the
case comes from space!
Expose the truth from inside the basement!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Spark That Fell on the Ranch
(Part Two)
"The Spark That Fell
on the Ranch, Part Two!"
Hatoyama Ranch
What? A meteorite?
The three men riding on the bus
with us came here to find a meteorite?
Yeah.
There was a hole in the wall
of the chicken coop
and a filled-in spot
on the ground in front of it
because someone filled-in the hole made
when the meteorite broke through
the wall and struck the ground.
The large number of burnt branches
and the long ditch Ayumi-chan saw prove it.
Normally when a meteorite
falls, it forms a crater.
But if the meteorite was small
and something changed the angle
of its trajectory when it fell,
then that would explain why
it broke numerous branches
as it passed through the woods
and created a long ditch
until it got stuck in the ground.
Then, that video the large man
was watching inside the bus was...
Probably a video of the meteorite falling
that had been uploaded to the internet.
If there was a voice confusing
the meteorite for a bottle rocket,
then whoever uploaded it probably
didn't realize what it was.
But for meteor hunters, it's a treasure map.
If the location where the video
was taken was uploaded as well,
then they can search for the meteorite.
What? Meteorites are treasures?
Yeah. It depends on the type
and size of the meteorite,
but apparently some have been
valued at tens of millions
or even a hundred million yen.
What? That much?
I see. He got so upset because Tsuburaya-kun
recorded that video using his phone.
Yes. If that video were reuploaded,
then a bunch of other meteor
hunters might come looking for it.
Generally speaking, meteors
are finders keepers.
Judging by their behavior on the bus,
Kano Shogo (43)
the large man is a meteor
hunter in it for the money,
the skinny man is a writer
for an astronomy magazine,
Hitsuka Junya (34)
and the old man with glasses
is a scientist researching meteorites.
Nanbu Takashi (56)
But what does that meteorite have to do
with us being locked in here?
It's up to them to figure that out.
Edogawa-kun, can you hear me?
We snuck into the ranch office and
are standing above the basement door.
But there's a large padlock on it.
I doubt we'll be able to open it.
What about a phone? Is there a phone there?
There are three in the adjacent room,
but they all seem to be disconnected.
I see. Then is there a journal
or notebook around there?
No. All that stuff's probably
on the computer on the desk.
There's also a bunch of things
scattered around the floor.
But it's gloomy in here since it's evening.
Then I'll turn on the lights.
Don't turn on the lights!
Huh?
The man who locked us down here
could be watching from somewhere.
If you turn on the lights, he'll know
there's someone in the office!
Hatoyama Umisuke (37)
Hatoyama-san, isn't it time
we gave up on finding that man
and head to that spot without him?
It's dark out.
No, he could be heading to the same place.
We should keep looking for him.
He might run into trouble.
R-Right.
It's hard to search the office with only
our watch lights when it's so dark out.
Then start by closing the curtains.
What?
If we close the curtains,
it'll get even darker.
Just close them.
They're closed now.
Next, does anyone have
any bottled water and milk?
I have mineral water.
I've got milk.
Okay.
First, add a little milk to the water
and mix them well by shaking the bottle.
Yuck, are we gonna drink that?
Then place the bottle
on top of your watch light.
Wow!
It's so bright.
Now it's bright enough
to look around the whole room.
How does that work?
It's the Tyndall effect.
It's a phenomenon that occurs
due to the properties of light.
When light is shone through water
with milk particles scattered throughout it,
the light is diffused,
making it look brighter.
I see. So grade school kids are taught
advanced physics these days.
What?
Uh, sure.
I didn't teach him that.
The objects scattered across the floor
are documents relating to meteorites.
Someone stepped on a highlighter.
There's ink everywhere.
Any chance that highlighter is yellow?
It is, actually.
If it's been stepped on
and the ink has been spilled,
does that mean there are shoe prints?
There are.
They look like hiking boots.
They're all over the documents on the floor.
All three of them were wearing hiking boots.
There's also a dent in the floor tiles
as though someone hit them with someone.
But what was it?
Maybe it was that weird rock under the desk.
There's a weird rock over here, too.
Huh?
The two rocks fit together perfectly.
Looks like someone smashed the rock
against the floor and broke it apart.
Isn't that a meteorite?
Wow!
But why would someone break one?
Haibara, do you have a magnet?
Yes, I've got a compass.
Try putting that next to the rock.
Nothing's happening.
Then that's probably not a meteorite.
Most meteorites are magnetic.
I see.
So that's why they had magnets.
You saw them carrying magnets?
Yeah, when we were getting off the bus.
The magnets hanging from their
backpacks got stuck together.
Magnets seem like something people
searching for meteorites would carry.
Now that I get a closer look,
I can see the color has chipped
away in a few places on this rock.
Someone probably colored it
to look like a real meteorite.
But who?
Normally it would make sense
to assume it was the ranch owner
who was under such financial distress
that he was selling his ranch.
But there are tons of magnets on the desk.
If it's fake, it wouldn't be magnetic,
so why all the magnets?
Maybe someone swapped it out.
What?
The ranch owner found a meteorite
and had it appraised by an expert,
Pallasite Meteorites
Appraisal Document
but he was told it was an ordinary rock
when it was later returned to him.
The ranch owner insisted that wasn't
possible, but the expert ignored him.
That's probably when the
highlighter fell and was stepped on.
Pallasite Meteorites
When he took a closer look at the
meteorite that had been returned,
he noticed it had been colored.
Realizing he'd been scammed, the
ranch owner killed himself in his despair.
Hida-kun, that deduction...
I-I'm wrong, aren't I? Sorry.
I think you're right.
Huh?
I think so, too.
What?!
There's a bathroom in this basement.
And it's been a while since
you were locked down here,
but you haven't asked us for water or food.
Which means he provided you
with something, right?
Yeah, bread and water.
That means he's not trying to kill us.
T-Then why lock us down here?
He doesn't want us to interfere
with his revenge on the con artist
who drove his brother to suicide.
Revenge? How is he going to do that?
You said some explosives were stolen.
Is he planning to use those?
Come to think of it, I saw a bunch of
long skinny sticks tied around a tree trunk
where I saw all the burnt branches.
Is that true?
Yeah. Something had been
wrapped around them to hide them,
but there were a whole bunch of them.
Could it be?
Is he planning to lure
the meteor hunters there...
And kill all of them?
We finally found you.
So this is where you've been.
We've been looking for you.
Sorry, but I'm not working with you guys.
You're looking for the meteorite, aren't you?
I'll take you to the place where it fell.
Personally, I don't have any
interest in the meteorite.
Ayumi-chan.
Do you know where you saw
the burnt branches?
Yeah.
I entered the woods next to the
building where the chickens were kept
and walked straight ahead.
Come to think of it, I was struck
from behind around there, too.
We've got trouble.
There are four lights
moving through the woods.
It looks like that man is headed towards
that spot with the three men.
Haibara.
Are there blue and red permanent markers
and cellophane tape in the office?
What?
There are markers in the pen holder.
And there's tape in the drawer.
But what would we use those for?
You guys are gonna make something for me.
A magic light that will illuminate the man
who drove the ranch owner to suicide.
First, cover the face
of the watch with tape.
Then color in the tape using
the blue permanent marker.
Next, add another layer of tape on top
and color it using the blue marker.
Add another layer of tape on top
of that and color it using the red marker,
and your knockoff blacklight is complete.
I'm not sure what that was about,
but all it did was turn the white light
into a dark purple color.
Try shining that purple light on the
area the highlighter was stepped on.
W-Wow!
The highlighter ink
and footprints are glowing.
The light of a blacklight is dark,
but it makes fluorescent objects glow.
In other words, if the culprit
stepped on that highlighter,
Pallasite Meteorites
then the fluorescent ink
will be on his shoes,
and you'll know who he is
by shining that light on them.
But wasn't the pen stepped
on several days ago?
I certainly hope he's wearing
the same shoes today.
Don't worry.
The chance he might be wearing those
shoes is exactly what he wants.
Haibara, when you ran
into Hatoyama Umisuke-san,
the guy who trapped us down here,
you said he had his phone
in his hand the whole time right?
Yes, he was holding onto it even
though he wasn't calling anyone.
In that case, this is pretty dangerous,
but I want you to take the things
I just mentioned and head to the area
where Ayumi-chan saw the explosives
wrapped around the tree trunks.
Got it.
Also, Haibara...
What? You're too quiet to hear.
Don't let your guard down
around Wakasa-sensei.
Listen to me, Kojima-kun.
When they give us the signal, I want
you to do exactly as you were told.
Got it.
The four lights are closing in
on the location of the explosives.
Come on, Wakasa-sensei. Let's hurry.
Okay.
I hope they'll be okay.
They will be. Haibara's smart.
And besides, I told them to run
if they feel like they're in trouble.
I feel like I've met that
Haibara Ai girl before.
Y-You have.
You rescued us when we were trapped inside
that refrigerated delivery truck.
Oh, she was there, too?
Since she's always wearing a hat so low
over her eyes, I figured she was shy.
Yeah, I guess.
But Conan-kun, is it true that Umisuke-san
is trying to lure those three men
to the place where he rigged
the explosives so he can kill them?
Yeah.
The video of the meteorite falling
that the large man was watching
was probably a fake video
uploaded by Umisuke-san
after he found it online
and added his voice to it.
Whenever a single meteorite is found,
it's likely there are others in the area.
The con artist who tricked
him out of the first meteorite
would jump at the opportunity.
But why would the con artist
pay another visit
to the home of someone
they tricked once already?
I'd be terrified of being
found out and stay away.
Con artists assume they can trick
a sucker again if they fooled them once.
He might be wearing a simple disguise, too.
Hey, they're a bunch of burnt
branches on the ground.
And there's a ditch over here.
But it stops partway.
Did it bounce away?
Hey, it's the man we met this afternoon.
What are you doing here?
What are you guys doing here?
We came here to give you this.
A badge?
Mister, don't you want to avenge your brother
who was conned out of a meteorite?
I'm one of the kids you trapped
in your basement this afternoon.
Then you should still be down there.
Don't worry about me.
Take a look at the ranch building.
You should be able to see us from there.
We've already escaped and called the police.
Damn it!
Genta-kun.
All good.
Looks like it worked.
Anyway, I've got something
I want to discuss with you.
Before the police arrive, don't you
want to know who tricked your brother?
What?
If the police show up,
only you'll be arrested,
and the man who tricked
your brother will go free.
Don't you want to teach just
that person a lesson?
Yeah. If you know who it is, then tell me.
Remember the footprints
on the floor of the ranch office
made when someone stepped
on and broke a highlighter?
Yeah.
Those were probably the footprints
of whoever conned your
brother out of the meteorite.
In other words, there's fluorescent
ink on the bottom of their shoes.
If you shine the brown-haired
girl's blacklight on it,
the sections stained with ink will glow.
You'll need water, too.
We're using water, too?
Yeah. It'll make it easier to see.
Get the three of them to kneel and
shine the light on the soles of their feet.
Gentlemen.
There's a suspicious-looking
rock in these bushes.
Seriously?
We can finally take a look at it.
Hey, where is it?
I only see ordinary rocks.
It's farther back in there.
So it was you.
Let go!
Damn it!
So you did set your phone as the detonator.
But now you can't use the explosives.
It's true that I can no longer
use the explosives.
But I can still beat him to death.
Now that I know the man who conned
my brother out of the meteorite
was you!
The fluorescent ink that stained the sole
of your boot when you argued proves it!
My brother said in his message to me
that he was trying to sell that meteorite
so he could restore the ranch,
but you broke it!
I-I'm sorry.
I'll return the meteorite.
Don't be ridiculous!
My brother killed himself!
No...
You just wait.
I'll send you to the afterlife
where my brother is waiting.
Hey, that's enough.
Don't touch me!
I was a boxing Inter-High champion!
Sorry, but I'm a professional kickboxer.
Although I quit because
losing weight was too tough.
Look at this silly disguise.
It's guys like you that give us
meteor hunters a bad name.
I'm pretty sure your foul mouth
isn't doing us any favors either.
Shut up.
Go to the police and tell
them the whole truth.
I'll be there with you.
All right.
The police arrived an hour later,
and we were freed from the basement.
You knew who the con artist was
before we shone the blacklight on him?
Yeah. All Umisuke-san said was that his
brother the ranch owner was in the hospital,
but that man pretending to be a scientist
responded with, "How's your older brother?"
Which means at the very least,
he knew the ranch owner Gisuke-san.
But he lied about it being
his first time here
and not knowing anyone in the area.
Furthermore, a meteorite researcher
wouldn't put magnets near a meteorite.
Only plain old meteor hunters
walk around with magnets.
Did I drop something?
What?
Who...
Who is that?
There's someone there.
Amuro-san. Amuro-san.
Amuro-san!
Ow...
You're finally awake.
We thought you were dead.
I can't believe you tripped on the
steps and knocked yourself out.
What?
I-I'm sorry. My hand slipped and
I accidentally shut the basement door.
It's fine.
I tripped on the steps?
Was that an illusion, then?
Or was it something else?
Amuro-san.
Let's go.
Right.