Coffee Poirot
I'm home!
Mori Detective Agency
Is something wrong? You're frowning.
Apparently Suguro Takayuki's
ghost has appeared.
Suguro-san's ghost?
Beika Central Hospital
Two Weeks Earlier
We met Suguro Takayuki-san
about two weeks earlier.
Hup.
I'm glad they don't need surgery.
And they made it sound
like the end of the world.
It was just plain old food poisoning.
I shouldn't laugh out loud at a hospital.
You're the great detective
Mori-san, aren't you?
Suguro Takayuki (42)
Accounting Firm Manager
Are you here visiting someone today?
Yes, I'm visiting an acquaintance.
I see.
Suguro Sayaka (30)
Suguro's Wife
More importantly, honey...
Makiura Tateru (33)
Suguro's Secretary
What were the results of
your exam, Suguro-sensei?
Apparently I've got six months left to live.
What?
Six months to live?
Now that I'm in this position,
I'm glad you insisted I take out
a life insurance policy,
even though I was opposed to it.
As an accountant whose only
strength was his dependability,
I never amassed a fortune,
but I can at least leave my wife
Sayaka with an insurance payout.
Don't look at me like that.
I'll make it all the way through
the remaining time I have left.
He's a strong optimistic man.
Yeah.
However, several days later...
Nobody saw anyone suspicious.
Inspector, good evening.
You again?
I just happened to be passing by.
So, what happened?
Honey!
Sensei!
S-Suguro-san?!
Mori-san?
So this is your home?
By the way, what happened to your husband?
He's been murdered.
What?
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
Rumors about a ghost spread throughout town.
The moment of his revenge
closes in on the culprit.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Ghost's Revenge
"The Ghost's Revenge!"
Suguro-sensei asked me and the missus
to do something this morning at nine.
We left the house, and when
we returned this evening,
he was in the bathroom...
Since he didn't leave a note and
judging by the state of the scene,
it's likely he killed himself.
Perhaps he lost hope because he
was told he had six months to live.
There's no way my husband killed himself.
He wasn't a weak man who would've lost hope.
I got the same impression about him.
Which means the culprit carried
Suguro into the bathroom,
placed his left hand in the filled tub,
and cut his wrist with a razor.
It's likely that this was a murder
made to look like a suicide.
Yes.
Which begs the question, who did it and why?
You can't go in there.
I'm a friend.
Kanda-san?
You know each other?
He's my husband's best friend.
Kanda Yoji (42)
Suguro's Friend
He called me last night to
ask me to come here today.
When I arrived, I was told he'd been killed.
Maybe he ran into some trouble with someone.
During our phone call...
I told him he wouldn't get away with it!
What are you talking about?
Just come over tomorrow!
He sounded so aggravated when he said it.
He was such an earnest guy.
Maybe he couldn't forgive
something terrible someone had done.
Perhaps Suguro-san sent his wife
and secretary away from the house
and invited over that person
to voice his grievances.
Unacceptable! You'll never
get away with this!
But it backfired and they killed him?
That must be what happened.
He couldn't stand any kind
of immoral behavior.
Any idea who that person might be?
I'm not sure.
Not off the top of my head.
Did this fall over during their argument?
Suguro looks so happy in this photo.
He treasured his younger wife Sayaka-san,
and he was proud to call the trustworthy
Makiura-kun his secretary.
Inspector.
The wife and secretary have alibis for
Suguro's estimated time of death of 11AM.
That's what you've been looking into?
When a husband is murdered,
it's normal to suspect the wife
did it for the insurance money.
I doubt that's true in this case.
The money would've been hers
if she waited six months.
More importantly, we need to figure out
who Suguro-san said he couldn't forgive.
Yes, sir.
But they failed to turn up any notable leads.
Mori Detective Agency
And today, several days later...
Suguro-san's ghost?
Rumors that his ghost appeared
have spread throughout town.
He appears before his wife and secretary.
My grudge prevents me from moving on.
I'm taking my murderer with me.
It's ridiculous. Ghosts don't exist.
Who would spread a strange rumor
like that, and for what purpose?
He's right. What do they stand to gain?
Mori Detective Agency
Have they made progress
in their investigation?
It's those two.
Inspector, who is that?
Oshikawa Masato. He was
a suspect in Suguro's murder.
He was a suspect?
We received some information the day
before yesterday pointing to him.
I finally remembered one person it could be.
Six months ago, someone nearly
defrauded a client of our accounting firm
of a large sum of money.
At the time, Suguro-sensei aggressively
told them they wouldn't get away with it.
He was a realtor named Oshikawa Masato.
We'll check him out right away.
Oshikawa Masato (38)
Realtor
Yeah, I resented him.
He suddenly stormed into my office
and embarrassed me.
But apparently someone killed him.
I guess someone resented
him even more than I did.
He was a tough and brazen man.
He seemed plenty suspicious to us.
While we were looking for decisive
evidence, he killed himself.
The estimated time of death
is late last night.
He died after cutting his left wrist
with a razor and sticking in the tub.
That's...
The same way Suguro died.
After killing Suguro,
the police caught up to him.
Believing he couldn't escape, he gave up.
We believe he may have used the same
method as a confession of his guilt.
But would a tough, brazen man kill himself
when the police hadn't found
decisive evidence?
It's our fault.
What do you mean?
We believed Oshikawa Masato was
the culprit, but we lacked evidence.
So we decided to use a ghost.
We'd heard Oshikawa believed in ghosts,
so yesterday, we spread the rumor
that Suguro-sensei's ghost
was seeking revenge on his killer.
You spread the rumors yourselves?
We were certain Oshikawa
would be frightened by the rumor
and turn himself in if he did it.
Does that mean Oshikawa
killed himself to escape
his fear of the ghost?
Manpuku Restaurant
Does that mean it's my fault?
Could you tell us more
about that at the station?
Looks like the answer revealed itself.
Now we know who killed Suguro and who
was behind the rumor about the ghost.
What's wrong?
Did Oshikawa really do it?
What?
He got scared of the ghost and
killed himself because he was the culprit.
Still.
Come to think of it, that guy
said something curious.
Hey, where are you going?
Manpuku Restaurant
Could it have been my fault?
You're the one who told Oshikawa-san
about the ghost rumor, aren't you?
Omori Fukusuke (30)
Restaurant Owner
I-If he killed himself because of it,
then it's probably my fault,
but he didn't seem like he would.
His ghost declared revenge on me, huh?
Maybe he's planning to tear you apart.
I bet the culprit would be
too scared to sleep.
He laughed like it was none of his concern.
He was probably doing his best to act tough.
He wasn't just acting tough.
It probably really wasn't any of his concern.
Because he wasn't the one
who killed Suguro-san.
If Oshikawa wasn't the culprit,
does that mean his death
wasn't a suicide, but murder?
Whoever actually killed Suguro-san
was probably trying to frame him.
Then who's the real culprit?
Oshikawa was the only suspicious person
the wife and secretary could think of.
What about the woman
we met at Suguro's funeral,
who previously worked as their housekeeper?
Hanai Tokuko (38)
Former Housekeeper
As far as I know, there wasn't anyone
who had a dispute with the husband.
You can't think of anyone who found
Suguro's existence offensive?
Is something the matter?
In that regard, those two fit the bill.
Who?
I stopped working at that house
because I felt sorry for the husband.
I first saw it about two years ago.
That's probably when it started.
So those two are a couple.
Kanda Bookstore
Yes, Suguro took out a life
insurance policy about a year ago
at Makiura-kun's recommendation.
I believe it had a special accident clause.
I knew it!
He's right, but there are still
a few things we don't know.
All right. I've figured it all out.
What? All of it?
Mori Detective Agency
Those two definitely killed Suguro.
Tokusa Direct Life Insurance
The fact that Sayaka the wife and Makiura
the secretary have alibis proves it.
They used some kind of trick.
Has he really figured it all out?
Hup.
Oh, jeez. This guy's drinking
all he wants since Ran's not home.
Unbeknownst to Suguro, the two of them
became a couple at least two years ago.
And if Makiura recommended Suguro take out
a life insurance policy one year later,
then it's obvious what he was going for.
He was working with Sayaka
to get Suguro out of the way
and claim the life insurance money.
He'd almost certainly get
the insurance money if he killed him,
but it'd be suspicious if he did it
right after the policy was taken out.
And while he was waiting for his opportunity,
something unexpected occurred...
Apparently I've got six months left to live.
The life insurance policy Suguro
took out had a special accident clause.
If the policyholder is killed
or dies in an accident,
the beneficiary receives double the payout.
In other words, he'd lose money
if he died of an illness.
He needed Suguro to become a murder victim.
About that...
The two of them carried out
the plan they'd laid in advance
before he could die of an illness.
They used a trick to
fabricate their alibis, too.
They needed someone
to play the culprit in their murder.
I finally remembered one person it could be.
He was a realtor named Oshikawa Masato.
In order to conclude the investigation
quickly before they gave themselves away,
they spread that rumor
and made it look like
Oshikawa killed himself
because he feared the victim's
ghost as the culprit.
And that's the truth.
Wow, mister.
I told you I'd figured it all out.
Which means you know how the culprits
fabricated their alibis, too, right?
What? How am I supposed to know that?
Actually, I don't need to know.
Once I name them as the culprits,
they'll confess to everything.
Does that mean you haven't
solved that mystery either?
What mystery?
Normally the culprit would make Suguro-san's
death look like an accident, right?
Like pretending he tripped he or something.
The special accident clause
applies to accidental deaths,
and there would be no need to frame anyone.
It would be way easier, so why didn't
Sayaka-san and Makiura-san go with that?
Huh? It probably just didn't occur to them.
I'm going out for a drink.
I've gotta pump myself up.
After all, I'm revealing my
brilliant detective skills tomorrow.
See you later!
Is he really planning to reveal
that hole-ridden deduction of his?
Whatever.
Life insurance cannot be collected in the event of a suicide within three years of signing the contract.
Could it be?
He sounded so aggravated when he said it.
Is it possible that it wasn't Oshikawa Masato
who Suguro-san said he couldn't forgive?
So that's why his wrist
was cut in the bathroom.
In other words, you're saying the
culprit wasn't Oshikawa Masato.
It was these two.
Sayaka-san the wife and Makiura-san
the secretary killed Suguro Takayuki.
They even killed Oshikawa-san and made
it look a suicide in order to frame him.
No!
You're wrong!
After killing two men,
you should gracefully accept—
Since the situation can be read that way,
it would be wise to fess up.
Otherwise, you'll be held accountable
for the murder of Suguro you didn't commit.
They didn't do it?
What do you mean by that?
You just said yourself
that these two killed Suguro.
You probably have evidence that you
didn't kill Suguro, don't you?
Looks like this is as far as we go.
You're right.
This was on Suguro-sensei's desk.
A letter?
This is...
So Suguro did leave a note.
That's right, Inspector. He wasn't killed.
Suguro committed suicide.
Yes.
Suguro probably figured out
that his beloved wife
Sayaka-san and Makiura-san,
who he trusted completely,
were in a relationship.
He was referring to these two when he told
his friend Kanda-san over the phone
that he couldn't forgive them.
Once he realized they
were in a relationship,
Suguro knew immediately why he was
made to take out an insurance policy.
They planned to kill him
and make it look like an accident
so they could collect the insurance money.
That's why Suguro decided to kill himself.
There would be no insurance
payout if he killed himself
Life insurance cannot be collected in the event
of a suicide within three years of signing the contract.
within three years of signing the contract.
That's right.
We won't even receive the standard
payout, much less double the payout
from the special accident clause.
Suguro-san probably invited Kanda-san
over to the house the next day
so he could see your disappointment.
The day of his suicide, he sent
the two of you out of the house...
You'll pay for betraying me!
...and used a stereotypical method
that could only be interpreted as a suicide.
When you returned home,
you were shocked and panicked.
You could hide the letter, but you
couldn't make it look like an accident.
However, you couldn't let
his death be ruled a suicide.
So we had to make it look like a murder.
But because of that, you needed
someone to be the culprit,
so you were forced to kill Oshikawa-san.
You should've given up on
collecting the insurance money
when Suguro killed himself.
We couldn't. Not after reading
that infuriating note.
What do you mean by that?
Did he describe all resentment
he had against you in the note?
He wrote in his note,
"I'm killing myself so things
don't go your way."
"It must be frustrating
not getting what you want."
Serves you right.
Suicide Note
I'm killing myself so things don't go your way
It must be frustrating not getting what you want
Serves you right.
What are you gonna do, cry about it?
Screw off, both of you.
That's what his note said.
Whatever the reason, you were
manipulated by your own selfish desires,
and ended up killing someone
who had nothing to do with this.
I can only describe your actions as foolish.
Only crooks try to use insurance.
When I bet on horses, I don't buy backups.
I go all in on one horse and win.
He's got no luck with horses or insurance.
I should invest in some insurance...