Detective Conan Episode 1056
"I Want My Husband Back"
[op]
[ed]
[eyecatch]
9AM
Metropolitan Area Kasuba City
Mori Fusae (76)
Is he dead?
He's not breathing.
Inukai Hajime (35)
No way.
I'm sure he'll be fine once
he's treated at a hospital.
Name: Butsumaru Daijiro DOB: February 20th
Address: Tokyo Beika City Haido 1056-9-10
Issued February 12th
Expires March 20th Driver's License
This must be his.
I should report this to the police.
You don't know the license
plate number or vehicle model?
I've got bad news.
Butsumaru Daijiro hasn't
been taken to a hospital.
He hasn't been taken to a hospital?
Then where did he go?
Scene of Accident
Neither the company he manages nor
his home have received any word.
The Kasuba police are searching
for Butsumaru-san's whereabouts,
Missing Person
Butsumaru Daijiro-san (51)
A traffic accident victim just vanished, huh?
and are asking any witnesses
to contact the police.
When he was hit by the car...
He probably died.
The culprit thought they could get away
with it as long the body wasn't found,
so they pretended to take him to a
hospital and hid the body somewhere.
Yes, this is Detective Mori.
Who am I speaking to?
You're the wife of the
missing victim Butsumaru?
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
A missing victim, an unexpected demand,
and the truth that appears on
the far side of negotiations!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
I Want My Husband Back
"I Want My Husband Back!"
Butsumaru
Butsumaru Emiko (46)
Daijiro's Wife
I'm Butsumaru Emiko, the
woman who called earlier.
And this is...
I'm President Butsumaru's secretary Kadokura.
Kadokura Shinya (32)
Daijiro's Secretary
I'd like you to find my husband
and bring him back safe and sound.
The police are looking for him,
but I have no idea what he was
doing in Kasuba in the first place.
He doesn't know anyone there.
More importantly, I doubt your
husband is still with us.
It's my husband.
You want me to buy his body?
I told you, I want you to buy the body
of your husband I hit with my car.
You need it, don't you?
You can't hold a funeral without it.
I'll sell it to you for 10
million yen, so get the money.
If you tell the police,
I'll dump the body in a faraway ocean
where it'll never be found again.
No! Please don't do that!
I'll call your cell phone later.
The two of them seemed somewhat
prepared to hear the news,
but what kind of monster kills a person
and demands money from their relatives?
We should report this to the police!
No.
If I can get my husband's body back for
10 million yen, then I don't mind paying!
Even if we don't tell the police, there's no
need for you to comply with their demands.
The great Mori Kogoro shall take back
your husband's body from the culprit.
If that's possible, Mori-san,
then of course I'd prefer that.
The question is how we'll find the culprit.
We might find some clues if we go to
the scene of the accident in Kasuba.
We'll join you.
I was worried, but they don't
seem to have figured it out.
That's right. I was so surprised.
He came speeding down the street
while I was walking here.
Could it be?
Stop resisting.
That's him.
He's the culprit?
I finally found a new job.
I was afraid of that going
down the drain, so...
But I never demanded any money.
You don't know when to give up, do you?
Quit stalling and return the body.
Of course.
That's odd.
This is where I buried it, but it's not here.
What?
What's going on?
The president's body disappeared.
I don't understand.
Wh-Which means...
Incoming Call
Incoming call from withheld number
Withheld Number Settings
Reject   Answer
Hello?
Your husband's body is crying
about wanting to go home.
This wasn't an accident.
You just stole the body.
Ding ding ding.
It was quicker to say I killed him.
Only one old woman witnessed the accident,
so I figured I could pretend I did it.
More importantly,
I've decided to raise the price
of the body to 30 million yen.
30 million?
30 million is fine, just
give me back my husband.
That's the spirit.
30 million is fine?
This person is weirdly obsessed
with her husband's body.
Um, what's this about the body being stolen?
They're probably an urban
explorer or something,
and saw you hiding the body when
they happened to come here.
Missing: Butsumaru Daijiro-san
Please contact the police with
any eyewitness information.
They got the idea when they saw the news,
dug up the body and took it with them,
and demanded money in exchange for it.
Damn that body thief X.
But they didn't need to move the body.
What if you turned yourself in?
The police would've dug it up.
So that's why they needed to move it.
Anyway, 30 million is an outrageous price.
It's a small price to pay for
the return of my husband's body.
Of course, it'd be best if the great
detective got it back for free.
I don't understand the ransomer either.
Why would they think she'd
be willing to pay that much?
It's Butsumaru-san's study.
What's that?
I see. So that's how it is.
Don't wander into rooms.
Hey, mister. What's this
thing stuck on the safe?
It's an authentication device.
No Match
Could it be?
Looks like you figured it out.
Only my husband can open that.
Inside that safe are our treasures,
tokens of our memories.
That's right.
After all, you can buy memories with money.
Maybe there's actually money in there.
Since she said she's willing
to pay 30 million yen,
there could be several
times that in the safe.
Either way, we have to find the body.
This has nothing to do with X.
Are you sure about that? Doesn't
this narrow down who X could be?
What does that mean?
Who knows about that safe?
Yeah, I was wondering who knows.
Just the three of us. Me,
my husband, and Kadokura.
What? But...
There must be someone else,
and that person is X.
How do you know that?
When you consider X demanded the
high price of 30 million yen
and knows they need the
body no matter what...
Are you saying someone who
knows about their situation
just happened to be there when
Butsumaru's body was being buried?
That's too much of a coincidence.
Yeah, but...
Didn't X say something strange?
Only one old woman witnessed the accident,
so I figured I could pretend I did it.
Not even the news mentioned that an
old woman witnessed the accident.
If they knew that, then maybe X was
there when the accident happened, too.
What would X be doing there?
We have to assume they were, or else—
Well, don't assume.
Someone who happened to get their hands
on the body is just blackmailing them.
I don't think this case is that
simple. I think there's more to this.
I have guests over right now.
Did you notice anything strange?
No, not particularly.
Inspector?
Mori-kun? What are you two doing here?
I see.
So that's what he's doing here.
Yes. He's the one who hid Butsumaru's body.
My name is Inukai Hajime.
You found the culprit and captured him?
I guess there was no point in looking
into Butsumaru's connections to Kasuba.
Mori-kun, why didn't you let us know
right away when you captured the culprit?
I thought I'd question him for clues first.
What are you talking about?
Uh, actually...
The truth is, Inspector,
there's currently another ongoing case
stemming from the accident he caused.
A second case?
I get the picture.
What were the president's connections
to Kasuba you mentioned earlier?
Butsumaru was renting an apartment in Kasuba.
An apartment?
The manager contacted us
after seeing the news.
The name on the agreement is different,
but they said he might be his resident.
When we took a look at the room he
started renting about a week ago,
all we found was video equipment and alcohol.
Since he was renting it under a false name,
we think it may have been a hideout
he used to get away from things.
So that's what it was.
But why did he go to the apartment
in Kasuba that morning?
Was there some reason he had to go?
I don't know why he went, but it's
turned into this pain in the rear.
Kogoro-no-ojisan wanted me to ask you,
yesterday morning, did you notice
anything strange about Butsumaru-san?
He seemed deep in thought,
which was unusual for him.
He received a call from Kadokura.
I see. I'll be all right, though.
I told you, I took measures the other day
so I'll be fine even if they show up here.
He seemed to have something on his
mind and called Kadokura back.
I'm going to be late to work today.
And then he headed to Kasuba.
What is Mori-san trying to figure out?
I wouldn't know.
Has he figured out where this
money actually came from?
Yeah, right.
Suspected of Tax Evasion
President and Chief Executive Officer Arrested
This must be it.
In which case...
I see. So that's how it is.
Let's pretend we're complying with his
demand and arrest X at the location of the deal.
Got it.
There's no room in this plan for
me to show off my detective skills.
Incoming Call
Incoming call from withheld number
Withheld Number Settings
Reject   Answer
In Call
End   Hold
Hello?
Have you got the 30 million?
Put it in a sturdy suitcase.
We'll make the deal at Mt. Zangiyama.
Why do they want it in a sturdy suitcase?
Probably because it'll be
easier to run away with.
I believe there's one in
the president's study.
Mt. Zangiyama? I feel like
I've heard that name before.
Oh, my husband took Kadokura
there once on an inspection.
He wanted to develop the land
at the foot of the mountain.
So that's how you knew.
I know.
What? Mori-san did?
But...
Apparently he got the
inspector's permission, too.
That's fine, then.
Where's Chiba? I don't see him.
He left in a hurry. He said there
was something he had to look into.
What? Why'd he run off without my permission?
That calls for a pay cut.
Crap.
Metropolitan Area Mt. Zangiyama
In Call
End   Hold
A whole bunch of you showed up.
See the shack to the west?
One of you—you with
the suitcase, you'll do.
Bring the money.
The rest of you stay where you are.
Are they watching us from in there?
There's a cliff behind it?
I see.
That's why they wanted the
money in that suitcase.
What?
Kogoro-no-ojisan said not to tell anyone.
If Mori-san says so, then
I'm sure it's a good idea.
You, too, Takagi? Where are you going?
You'll have to cut his pay, too.
I'm counting on you!
He still hasn't come out.
What's happening inside?
Kadokura-san!
He's all right. He's just unconscious.
That's my husband.
I'm glad we got the body back, but...
The moment I entered, I was
suddenly struck from behind.
Damn that X. They took the money
and escaped through there.
No, it'd be impossible to escape from here.
Then where did X go?
Where did...? Where did they...?
Mori-kun?
The culprit didn't disappear.
What's that police officer
doing with the suitcase?
And who's that woman?
So it was a woman.
I don't know who she is either,
but she's most likely X.
What did I do, huh?!
Hakase Mayumi (26)
All I did was pick up
something someone dropped.
That dropped article is the problem.
At any rate, the case has been resolved.
Both the body and 30 million
yen have been returned.
And the culprit was caught.
No, we're only halfway done.
The mastermind who planned everything
and manipulated X still remains.
The mastermind?
By the way, is this woman your
girlfriend, Kadokura-san?
What?
That's right. Kadokura-san is the mastermind.
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Butsumaru kept the money he made
evading taxes in that safe.
However, perhaps because he felt uneasy
about keeping the money at home,
about one week earlier, he moved
it to another hiding place.
Kadokura-san chuckled to
himself when he learned that.
You'd had your eye on that money that
wouldn't be reported to the police,
even if it were stolen, didn't you?
But you couldn't steal it
while it was in that safe.
However, Butsumaru didn't tell you
where his new hiding place was.
So in order to find it,
you came up with the idea of directing Butsumaru
there and having your girlfriend follow him.
You put your plan into
action yesterday morning.
Incoming Call
Kadokura Shinya
Decline   Answer
Suspected of Tax Evasion
President and Chief
Executive Officer Arrested
You told Butsumaru that someone had been
arrested for tax evasion to make him anxious.
He probably wanted to confirm he
wasn't being investigated secretly.
Butsumaru played into your hands,
and your girlfriend followed him.
But on the way there, Butsumaru died
in an accident, and your plan failed.
However, perhaps because you noticed something
suspicious about the man who caused the accident,
you came up with another way to get rich
quick after your first plan failed,
had her move the body...
I'll sell it to you for 10
million yen, so get the money.
...and demand a ransom.
The wife seems to think there's still
a large amount of money in that safe,
so you knew she'd agree to pay a high price.
I don't know what you're talking about.
But it wasn't there anymore.
Then where is the money?!
I told you...
Chiba, where are you?
As Mori-san requested, after thoroughly
searching the apartment in Kasuba,
I found roughly 350 million
yen in the closet ceiling.
That's right.
He was renting that apartment in Kasuba
as a hiding place for the money.
That's why he used a fake name.
350 million...
So that's how much there was.
Don't talk to me, you idiot.
Crap.
There's no point in pretending.
At Mori-san's instructions, I was
waiting at the bottom of this cliff.
I saw with my own eyes the decisive
moment proving you two are accomplices.
In other words, Inspector,
the culprit X didn't vanish.
They were never here to begin with.
It was all an act put on by Kadokura-san.
You probably learned about this shack
when you previously came here on an
inspection and figured you could use it.
I never—
Don't try to make excuses, Kadokura-san.
The numerous calls you made to your
girlfriend today are still in your phone's call history.
I had to keep giving her instructions,
like to raise the ransom to 30 million
because things were going well.
After all, the plan wouldn't work
without specific instructions.
Why did he hide so much
money in an apartment?
It was supposed to work.
What an idiot. This was a huge loss.
They were all motivated by greed.
Mori Detective Agency
Yes. Yes, that's me.
What?
Someone was kidnapped and a ransom has been
demanded in exchange for their safe return?
Tell me more about this pet you were
keeping secret from your landlord.
A pet, huh?
A g-g-giraffe?
Just how large is their place?
Is it even possible to
secretly keep a giraffe?
Mori Detective Agency
Episode Preview
It's an emergency!
There's been an incident!
Who are you kids?
Thief!
What?!
What's with those old ladies?
We aren't thieves. We're the Detective Boys.
Bad Guys
The next episode of Conan is "Bad Guys!"
Sheets
Next Conan's hint!
Sheets!
Why do I keep getting jobs like this?
Don't miss the next episode
Probably because of how you act all the time.
Zip it! Keep your bull-sheet to yourself!