[eyecatch]
[ed]
Detective Conan Episode 1057 "Bad Guys"
[op]
Did you see yesterday's episode of Yaiba?
Yes.
A whole bunch of Kamen Yaibas showed up.
I didn't know who—
What?
Hirasawa Kaori (27)
Wife
Hirasawa Seiko (68)
Mother-in-law
I-It's an emergency!
There's been an incident!
Who are you kids?
Thief!
What?!
Wait, what?!
Who were those brats?
Unbelievable.
What's with those old ladies?
We aren't thieves. We're the Detective Boys.
Honey.
Son-in-law.
Honey, are you really more concerned
about the rug than our injuries?
Honey!
Hirasawa Ryoji (31)
Son-in-law
N-No, I'm very concerned about your injuries.
Son-in-law, hurry up and bring
the first-aid box and treat us.
Yes, ma'am.
Ow, ow, ow.
It hurts!
Ow, ow, ow!
It hurts so much!
Must be tough being their son-in-law.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
A mother, a daughter, and a timid man!
From within their family, a case grows!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Bad Guys
"Bad Guys!"
Aw, man. I've been in a terrible
mood since this morning.
They say it's a quirk of fate.
The entire day might end
up being terrible for you.
What? That would be super terrible.
Supa-ko
It's the Hirasawas' son-in-law.
Ayumi.
You know them?
People were gossiping about
them in my neighborhood.
Gossiping?
The Hirasawas used to own
a lot of land around here.
They still own the Hirasawa Building,
Hirasawa Apartments,
the Hirasawa Parking Lot,
and Hirasawa Farms.
They're a rich family that owns
a bunch of other properties, too.
Their son-in-law originally worked
at an insurance company that did a
lot of business with the Hirasawas.
He married their only daughter
after a formal meeting.
At first people said he
was after their money,
but they still treat him like a servant.
Huh?
Yikes.
Thank you.
Sorry, sorry.
Again, I'm so sorry to make you do this.
Why does he keep apologizing?
All he's holding is a single leek.
Cut him some slack.
I feel sorry for him.
Take care.
Thank you.
I'm back.
Honey!
How far did you go to get groceries?
You're late.
Son-in-law, do the laundry
before making dinner.
Don't forget to clean, too.
Yes, ma'am.
Why are you just standing there?
Hurry up and start dinner.
Yes, ma'am.
We want to go jogging now.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Unbelievable.
What an inconsiderate son-in-law.
Make sure you get everything
done by the time we come back.
Yes, ma'am.
Make sure the curry's sweet.
Make mine extra spicy.
Yes, ma'am.
I feel sorry for him.
Yeah.
Call emergency services and the police!
1-1-9.
I need one firetruck!
Firetruck?
I mean, one ambulance!
I'm going to go tell the son-in-law.
Got it.
It's an emergency, Mr. Son-in-law!
I see. So you kids are the witnesses.
Detective Takagi.
For a Secure Future
Toto Life Insurance
Insurance pamphlets?
Their son-in-law originally worked
at an insurance company that did a
lot of business with the Hirasawas.
He married their only daughter
after a formal meeting.
At first people said he
was after their money,
but they still treat him like a servant.
The insurance company that does business
with the Hirasawas caused the accident?
How are they doing?
I don't know yet.
Is she going to pretend the
accident didn't happen?
At first, people said he
was after their money.
The Hirasawa family's fortune...
H-How are they doing?
Let's see. You're asking
about Hirasawa Kaori-san...
Th-That's my wife.
And her mother Seiko-san.
Yes.
Both of them experienced a close call.
But because the paramedics
did such a good job
and the accident was reported quickly,
we were able to do our best.
That said, they're not out of the woods yet.
We'd like to continue
observing their progress.
Hasegawa Kinue (31)
A Beautiful Woman
Who are you?
That lady was trying to remove her IV tube.
You shouldn't be here.
Get out.
But...
Just get out.
Okay.
I was trying to remove her IV tube.
Is this really the time to close your
eyes and analyze your own behavior?
Or are you closing your eyes so
you can reflect your actions?
No, you're closing your eyes and dreaming.
Dreaming of the day the Hirasawa
family fortune is ours.
Ow!
Kid.
You were eavesdropping on our
conversation, weren't you?
Um, what are you talking about?
You never should have come here, kid.
I hate to do this, but...
Seriously?
What's going on?
Wait, kid!
Who are you?
Shut up!
Crap. The professor's performing
maintenance on my shoes.
What do you think you're doing?
Were you trying to trip me with this?
If you're so desperate to play with
a ball, then I'll play with you!
What?!
Stop, kid!
Come to think of it...
Honey, are you really more concerned
about the rug than our injuries?
Honey!
Could it be?
Brand name track suits are so comfy.
These accessories are so striking, too.
Right?
This should be good enough for
restaurants that have a dress code.
Yeah, yeah.
That wasn't an accident, but a
crime committed by the son-in-law.
What was his problem?
She's awake.
Stop, kid!
Stop!
You little brat.
Kinue!
Ryoji!
Let go of me!
So Conan-kun went after
the culprit's black car?
Yeah.
We haven't heard from him yet, though.
I see.
I'll have to wait for Hirasawa
Seiko-san and Kaori-san
to wake up so I can gather
information from them.
Damn it.
It's that car.
It's the black car.
Conan-kun must be at this hospital, too.
He what?
Genta, Mitsuhiko, Ayumi.
Call the police immediately.
Detective Takagi is right here next to us.
I see.
The Hirasawa family's son-in-law and
a woman from the insurance company
are working together to seize
the Hirasawa family fortune.
They need to be arrested immediately.
Conan-kun, where are you right now?
You're inside some dirty sheets?
I'm in a laundry cart in
the first floor hallway.
It stopped.
Was that a chime?
It's an elevator.
Where are we going?
To the roof.
The roof?
A man and woman believed to be the culprits
have kidnapped a young boy
and are heading to the roof.
They probably intend to...
Conan-kun!
Conan!
Genta, Mitsuhiko, Ayumi!
Detective Takagi!
Don't do it!
They're here!
Conan-kun, do you hear that? Conan-kun!
Conan-kun!
Ayumi, Genta, Mitsuhiko!
Ryoji, the police are down there.
Conan!
Conan-kun!
Crap! Damn these sheets!
We've recovered the boy.
Arrest them.
Conan.
Conan-kun.
Guys...
I see.
They saved my life.
I'm so glad you're all right.
Conan-kun.
Conan.
Beika General Hospital
Captain, we'd like to pack up soon.
It's all right. Leave them be.
Conan-kun, what was it like
to fall from the roof?
It must've been scary, obviously.
It was terrifying.
But you looked really cool
flying through the air.
What?
I'd like to try flying, too.
Don't!
Absolutely not.
What?
Your life is precious.
You shouldn't joke about that.
Okay. I'm sorry.
Bring me down.
You worked real hard, hands.
That was tough.
And...
Thanks, guys. You saved my life.
Let's get out of here.
What?
The cushion's flat as a pancake.
Episode Preview
The time is 17:00.
Katsuki Yosuke, you're under arrest
for the murder of Odawara Shuhei.
Gotcha.
After knocking out the
victim with a metal pipe...
Impossible!
So that's what that was about.
Which means...
The Man Who Camped Out at the Police Station
The next episode of Conan is "The Man
Who Camped Out at the Police Station!"
Window
Next Conan's hint!
A window pane!
Don't miss the next episode.
That's a big house.
Could it be?
Another?
Give me a break, guys.