Detective Conan Episode 1058 "The Man
Who Camped Out at the Police Station"
Sebundai Police Station
MPD Sebundai Police Station
September 29th.
The time is 17:00.
Katsuki Yosuke, you're under arrest
for the murder of Odawara Shuhei.
Katsuki Yosuke (27)
Office Worker
Gotcha!
The culprit was arrested several hours
after the murder was discovered.
At least, that's what we thought.
Two Days Later
Poirot
Ah, Inspector.
Oh, it's you.
I heard you solved the
Sebundai case in record time.
We arrested the wrong man.
What do you mean?
There's no point in telling you about it.
Why don't you tell me what
happened at my office?
Let go of me!
Now, now. Don't say that.
I'll listen to any and all
complaints you might have.
I don't have any complaints to make!
Now, now.
Did you speak sharply to your superior again?
C-Conan-kun...
I shouldn't have come this way.
Come on, come on.
Now, now.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
Someone insists he committed the murder,
but what does the incomprehensible man what?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Man Who Camped Out at the Police Station
"The Man Who Camped Out
at the Police Station!"
The murder was discovered two days ago,
on the afternoon of the 29th.
The victim was Odawara Shuhei, 27 years old.
Odawara Shuhei (27)
Office Worker
We estimated the time of death was the
previous afternoon between one and three.
There were no signs the
room had been searched,
so we believed his killer
was motivated by a grudge.
The body was first discovered
by a woman named Yaguchi Tomoko,
who had just become engaged
to the victim the other day.
Yaguchi Tomoko (25)
Odawara's Fiancée
We found a contusion on the back of the
body's head and rope marks on its neck.
What we believe are the
weapons are over there.
A vinyl rope and a metal pipe, huh?
Also, there was a hole in the window
of that Japanese-style room.
I see.
In other words...
Yesterday afternoon,
the culprit opened a hole in the
Japanese-style room window and snuck inside.
After knocking out the
victim with a metal pipe,
they strangled him to
death using a vinyl rope.
Yes, most likely.
But oddly, while there were
fingerprints on the metal pipe,
there were apparently none on the vinyl rope.
There were only fingerprints
on one of the weapons?
Inspector Megure.
Do you have a minute?
Shuhei-san was so mild-mannered and kind.
He wasn't the kind of the man
who'd incur someone's wrath.
But...
But?
It's possible Katsuki-san resented him.
Katsuki-san?
Apparently he's someone
Yaguchi-san previously dated.
At the time, I found him very attractive.
He was always smiling and had such vitality.
But as I continued dating
him, I came to realize
that he was actually an excessively
self-conscious narcissist.
When I began to think I couldn't
stay with him any longer,
I met Shuhei-san, who was
Katsuki-san's high school classmate.
I see.
So after that, you broke up with
Katsuki and got engaged to Odawara.
Perhaps he resented Odawara-san for that.
When we went to talk to Katsuki himself...
Hey, you got here surprisingly quick.
I was actually on my way to turn myself in.
Then you admit to killing Odawara?
Yes.
I won't run or hide.
Such unseemly behavior doesn't suit me.
Tomoko is the reason I did it.
I don't know why she chose
the dull Odawara-kun over me,
the greatest guy around.
I knew I had to teach her a lesson.
That she'd regret making
such a foolish choice.
So I decided that Odawara-kun had to die.
I wanted Tomoko to lament her actions.
While waiting for the most
effective time to do it,
I heard they'd gotten engaged the other day.
"Now's the time!" I thought.
And as a result, I succeeded spectacularly.
I'm someone who always achieves
every goal he sets for himself.
What's wrong with this man?
In any case, take him to the station.
Yes, sir.
Later, because the fingerprints
on the metal pipe
and Katsuki's were found to be a match...
MPD Sebundai Police Station
Katsuki Yosuke, you're under arrest
for the murder of Odawara Shuhei.
Gotcha!
That's when everything
stopped going smoothly.
What do you mean?
His testimony doesn't match the
situation at the crime scene.
What?
You killed Odawara in the evening?
Yes, that's right.
Yesterday evening, around 6PM.
Are you sure you didn't do it
earlier, like that afternoon?
What are you talking about?
I'm the culprit, and I'm
telling you what happened.
It obviously happened in the evening.
Then where were you that afternoon?
I was in Eito City.
I was harassed by some thugs
and was at my wit's end.
I snuck in through the front door using
the spare key I'd made beforehand.
While fleeing the scene, I
threw the key away in a river.
I pummeled him to death while he was
napping on the couch with a metal pipe.
That's certainly odd.
Yeah.
But once we got the autopsy
results, the mystery was solved.
What do you mean?
The cause of death was suffocation due
to strangulation by the vinyl rope.
The time of death was between 1PM to 3PM,
as we determined at the scene.
But the contusion on his head was
made several hours after his death.
What? You mean...
There were probably two culprits.
A second culprit, X.
What?
X, who?
Yesterday afternoon,
X opened a hole in the Japanese-style room
window while wearing gloves and snuck inside.
Then they strangled Odawara to death.
Several hours later,
you snuck in using your spare key
and struck Odawara with a metal pipe
without realizing he was already dead.
In other words, what you did wasn't
murder but mutilation of a corpse.
That's impossible!
I killed Odawara-kun!
Damn it!
In any case—
I'll tell you everything, Inspector.
I snuck into that house twice.
What?
The first time was during the afternoon.
I snuck in using the spare key and
strangled Odawara-kun to death.
I was wearing gloves at the time.
But by that afternoon, I became anxious.
I was worried he was only unconscious.
So I retraced my steps, opened a hole
in the window, and snuck inside.
Then I dealt the killing blow to Odawara
with a metal pipe as he sat on the couch.
I accidentally forgot to wear gloves the
second time and left fingerprints behind.
That's the truth.
You said you broke in through
the window the second time,
but we didn't find a single one
of your fingerprints there.
And earlier you said yourself
that you were harassed by some thugs in Eito
City that afternoon and were at your wit's end.
I...
In any case, we'll deal with
the corpse mutilation later,
but you're cleared of murder charges.
No!
What?
How could you clear the charges
after arresting me for murder?
X, my ass.
I killed Odawara-kun so that
foolish woman would be miserable.
You have to believe me!
I did it!
S-So, is that Katsuki fellow...
Two days later, he's still
camping out at the station.
I did it! I killed him! It was me!
He's claiming there is
no X and that he did it.
We're currently looking for the
thugs who harassed him at Eito City.
Eito City Shopping Center
If we can find someone to verify his
alibi, then he'll have to admit it.
Naturally, we're looking for
the true culprit as well.
Some eyewitnesses have come forward, too.
Several days earlier, a local resident
saw a man peering into Odawara's home.
Apparently he was rather suspicious.
Hayashi Sanpo (75)
Nearby Resident
Furthermore, according to
his fiancée Yaguchi-san,
several days earlier, Odawara received a
phone call from someone threatening revenge.
From the true culprit X?
Most likely.
In other words, X held a powerful
grudge against Odawara.
So we asked Odawara's old friend about it,
Safety First
but gained nothing meaningful
from the questioning.
Iroha Sushi
Mori Detective Agency
Katsuki's detainment ends this evening.
Ideally I'd like to find X before then.
I don't really understand that Katsuki guy.
Don't understand what?
He achieved his goal of making his
ex-girlfriend Yaguchi-san sad.
Not only that, but since it happened
without getting his own hands dirty,
he should consider himself lucky.
So why is he insisting he did it?
Because he's the kind of person who
wants to take credit for everything.
Is it really just because of his personality?
What else could there—
Huh? What is it, mister?
Katsuki figured out who X is.
What?
And he's camping out at the police
station in order to protect them.
He's right.
That would make it make sense.
In any case, Odawara's old
friend must know Katsuki, too.
And someone with a powerful
grudge against Odawara
who Katsuki would want to protect.
There isn't.
What?
Emoto Koji (27)
Construction Worker
I told the inspector as well, but Odawara
wasn't the kind of guy who incurred peoples' wrath.
I see...
And I can't imagine Katsuki
protecting anyone.
He only loves himself.
W-Well, he is that kind of person.
Then why?
Hey, kid.
We're going to Odawara's house.
We'll visit the scene a
hundred times if we have to.
Hey, wait.
I see.
So he was killed by X who snuck
in while he was sitting here.
But even if X snuck in,
wouldn't the victim have noticed
someone approaching him?
We found that a bit odd, too.
He must've been napping at the time.
Maybe X visited the house as a guest.
A guest would be invited into the living room
and could wait for an opportunity
to kill Odawara-san.
Then how do you explain the hole
in the Japanese-room window?
It's camouflage.
So the police wouldn't realize
they knew the victim.
I see!
Yes.
"I'll pay you back for what
happened all those days ago."
Apparently that's what was said on the call.
I see.
But Shuhei-san couldn't think of
anything they could be referring to.
He thought it was a prank and was
about to hang up, but then...
"Tell those closest to you to be careful
too so they don't get dragged into it."
That's what they told him.
Shuhei-san told me because
that phrase stuck out to him.
He said he wouldn't have told me
about the phone call otherwise.
So I told him to talk to a security company.
But he...
I see.
So you don't recall what he looked like?
Nope.
But you don't often see someone
who looks that suspicious.
Not only that, but when I spoke
to him, he ran off in a hurry.
What's wrong with X?
They're practically going around
announcing how suspicious they are.
He's right.
Both the suspicious phone call and
suspicious man peering into the home
only seem to be drawing
attention to themselves.
But why?
Damn it.
We're almost out of time.
I wanted to find X and free the
Inspector from his troubles
before that police station
camper's detainment period ended.
So that's what that was about.
Which means...
Eito City Shopping Center
What?
You want me to confirm something ASAP?
What exactly is it, Mori-san?
Yes.
Yes, that's correct.
Early in the morning on
the day Shuhei-san died.
I'm sorry for all the trouble I
caused over the past two days.
MPD Sebundai Police Station
Jeez.
If you're gonna apologize, don't camp
out at the police station to begin with.
But there's a reason I claimed to be
the culprit even though I didn't do it.
I'm perfect.
The idea that someone had beaten
me to it frustrated me so much.
I didn't want to admit that I'd lost!
In any case, while you were prevented
from committing a murder by coincidence,
what you did was—
What?
What you... what you did
was... out of line...
M-Mori-kun?
Now? Really?
Don't you find it odd, Inspector?
What's odd?
The phone threat to the victim and the
suspicious man in the middle of the afternoon.
It seems to me like X was trying to
convince everyone of their existence.
Y-You're not wrong, but...
What are you trying to say?
In other words, there is no X.
And the person who killed Odawara
was indeed Katsuki Yosuke-kun.
It was you.
What?
The afternoon of the day of the murder,
you visited Odawara's home as a guest.
You waited for an opportunity to don
gloves and kill Odawara from behind,
and then remained at the crime scene.
That evening, you struck Odawara with a
metal pipe you held in your bare hands.
In other words, X was a fictional person.
A character Katsuki invented
to evade the police.
Furthermore, you took steps beforehand,
hinting at X's existence.
The phone threat to Odawara I
mentioned earlier was one of them.
But since the man who received it would die,
he wouldn't be able to tell the police about it.
So instead...
Tell those closest to you to be careful too
so they don't get dragged into it.
With that single sentence,
you ensured that Yaguchi Tomoko
would tell the police.
You also created a witness
by dressing suspiciously.
It's unnatural for someone
to case a place in the middle of the
afternoon while dressed like that.
You also opened a hole in
the window of Odawara's home
so we'd think there was
another culprit besides you.
You also waited several hours
after killing him with the rope
to hit him with the metal
pipe for the same reason.
And finally, in order to mislead the
police, you had them arrest you.
Mislead us?
"I did it. There is no X."
By convincing the police he was so frustrated
by being beaten to the punch
that he'd make those claims,
he discouraged you from even
doubting X's existence.
You're right.
Oh, excuse me.
Are you listening, Mori-san?
If I wanted to evade the police,
wouldn't it have been far simpler to make it
look like he'd been killed in a random attack?
No matter how careful you are,
you can't reduce the possibility of leaving
some sign of yourself at the scene to zero.
That's why you came up with this plan.
Since you snuck into Odawara's
home to kill them,
it was only natural that
you'd leave something behind.
However, someone beat you to it.
That would allow you to
escape suspicion of murder.
That's ridiculous.
This is all just your imagination, Mori-san.
You don't have a single
piece of physical evidence.
You're right.
By the way, Katsuki-kun,
when did you make the spare
key you used to sneak in?
Who knows?
I think it was a week or two ago.
It was so long ago, I don't remember clearly.
When she was told about the phone
call from the possible culprit,
Yaguchi-san apparently recommended to
Odawara that he talk to a security company.
I confirmed with her that she had the
front door lock changed to be safe
on the morning of the murder.
In other words, even if you
really had a spare key,
it wouldn't have unlocked that front door.
I found it, Mori-san.
Found what?
I asked him to check
the security camera footage
of Sebundai Station.
Sebundai CAM 1
On September 29th at 12:58PM,
Katsuki-san passed through the
ticket gate at Sebundai Station.
For the several hours
between 1PM on the day of the
murder when you exited Sebundai Station
and that evening when you
struck Odawara's body,
where were you and what were
you doing, Katsuki Yosuke-kun?
Well, I suppose I'll head back
into that police cell now.
Struggling in vain doesn't suit me.
Take him away.
Jeez.
What kind of guy camps
out at a police station?
Another beer!
Please just go home, Mori-san.
I've got a group waiting that's
reserved the whole store.
Come on, just one beer!
Half! I'd even take half a beer!
Looks like you're brazenly
camping out at that table.
Just half, okay? Half, please!
Episode Preview
I could never tell her, no matter what!
I've been waiting for you, Okino Yoko-chan.
Hello.
A locked room murder.
Given the blood in the hallway
and the sound of the footsteps...
Okino Yoko and the Locked Attic
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "Okino
Yoko and the Locked Attic, Part One!"
Playing Cards
Next Conan's hint!
Okay, go ahead.
Playing cards!
What? My mug is empty again?
Don't miss the next episode.
This must be a mystery!
You're the culprit, aren't you?
Sure enough.