Detective Conan Episode 1059 "Okino
Yoko and the Locked Attic (Part One)"
[op]
[ed]
[eyecatch]
I don't believe it.
How could I be so stupid?
Normally I could shout at Ran for help,
but Okino Yoko-chan is currently
at the detective agency.
I could never tell her, no matter what!
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
An SOS sent from a locked room!
The truth is in the playing cards!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Okino Yoko and the Locked Attic
(Part One)
"Okino Yoko and the Locked Attic, Part One!"
I can't tell her
we're out of toilet paper.
I know, I'll use my phone.
If I speak quietly over the
phone instead of shouting...
No, wait. If I carelessly call her...
Huh? What?
You're out of toilet paper and
you want me to bring you more?
Can't you speak louder than that?
Wh-What about sending her a message?
Huh? Dad sent me a message.
What? Isn't Kogoro-san in
the bathroom right now?
He says he's out of toilet paper.
I can't do that.
Something terrible is bound to happen.
Since it's come to this,
I'll have to rely on that sort of clever
but insolent kid with the glasses.
At this time, the old man
had no way of knowing
that his decision would be the
key to solving a difficult case.
Mori Detective Agency
2 Hours Earlier
Hey, Dad. Do you know what happened
to the butter sandwiches?
They were in the fridge.
If you're talking about these,
then this is the last one.
What? You ate them?
Yeah, I was feeling a little hungry.
Should I not have?
No. Those were two days
past their expiration date.
I should've thrown them out sooner.
I'm so sorry.
Well, don't worry about it.
Two days is no big deal.
Huh?
Normally he'd be much whinier about it.
His desk is tidy for some reason, too.
Is he a little dressed up?
Is he cheating?
It's probably because of his client.
Client?
After all, Kogoro-no-ojisan is a
huge fan of the person coming here.
Excuse me.
I've been waiting for you, Okino Yoko-chan!
Hello.
Come in, come on.
You came alone today?
Yes.
My manager said I shouldn't get
more deeply involved in the case,
but I can't stop thinking about it.
So I came today without telling my manager.
I don't normally travel by myself,
so I got lost and panicked.
What an incredibly fortunate—
What?
I mean, a rather unfortunate
series of events.
You're okay with tea, right?
Yes.
Ran, serve some tea.
Okay...
So you traveled to a villa in Karuizawa
to scout locations for a TV drama,
even though you're the star?
Yes, with the producer.
It wasn't so much location scouting
as pre-preliminary inspection
to choose one of several candidates.
Since it's my first dark
role, I was excited for it.
What kind of role is it?
I'm playing the ghost that haunts the villa.
Oh, really?
But didn't you say during an interview
that you'd be playing a detective next?
The ghost is a detective.
The lady owner of the villa who has killed
there long ago appears every night as a ghost.
She solves mysteries for
visitors of the villa,
and in exchange, she asks them to find
her scattered bones one at a time.
There's no way I'm watching that.
But we'd been having trouble finding
the right villa for the story.
That's when the producer Heijima
Wanya-san suggested a location.
Heijima Wanya (39)
TV Producer
There's a creepy villa where a woman
actually went missing in real life.
You wanna check it out?
That's what he said.
In real life?
Ow.
It turns out the villa belongs to
the in-laws of Heijima-san's sister,
and it was his sister who went missing.
I see.
So I went to the villa with Heijima-san.
As soon as I saw it, I
knew we had to film there.
It had such an ominous aura.
It was supposed to be a day trip,
but we ended up staying overnight because
there was so much we wanted to see.
Just you and the producer?
Oh, no.
There happened to be others
there escaping the heat.
There was Heijima-san's sister's
husband Baba Nukiyasu,
Baba Nukiyasu (46)
Eldest Son of the Baba Family
Nukiyasu-san's younger brother Baba Fugo-san,
Baba Fugo (44)
Second Son of the Baba Family
and the younger brother's wife Baba Himi-san.
Baba Himi (43)
Fugo's Wife
We had dinner and went to bed,
but just as I was starting to
fall asleep around midnight,
something happened...
That really hurts.
I heard someone groan and then
footsteps running down the hallway.
I was curious, so I went out into the hallway
where I found a trail of blood.
I followed the trail of
blood and turned the corner.
And then...
What's wrong with you, Ran?
Don't scare me like that.
B-But... you saw her, right?
The ghost of the missing wife.
Oh, no. The trail ended,
and there wasn't anyone there.
There wasn't a door leading
outside or stairs nearby?
No, just the bathroom door.
Naturally I turned on the lights
and even checked inside the tub,
but there was no one there.
While I was looking around,
everyone else showed up.
Apparently they couldn't find
the eldest son Nukiyasu-san,
so we decided to split up and look for him.
I say we split up,
but I was the only one who could move around
normally, so we split into two groups.
Everyone else was injured somehow?
Right, I forgot to mention.
The younger brother Fugo-san dislocated
his left wrist and had his arm in a sling.
Himi-san was in a wheelchair due to a hernia,
and Heijima-san sprained his
right foot so he was on crutches.
We thought it'd be dangerous to go alone
if there were any bad guys lurking around.
I see.
So you looked for the eldest
son Nukiyasu-san in pairs.
But just as we started our search,
the young brother Fugo-san received a
strange picture on his phone from Nukiyasu-san.
But just as we started our search,
the young brother Fugo-san received a
strange picture on his phone from Nukiyasu-san.
Playing cards?
Are these poker or blackjack hands?
Some of the piles have duplicate
cards, so I doubt that's it.
You're right.
Even the younger brother who received
the message didn't know what it was?
No, so we decided to think about it
together while looking for Nukiyasu-san.
I had him send it to my phone too, but
in the end, nobody could figure it out.
You tried calling and sending
messages to Nukiyasu-san, right?
Yes, Fugo-san tried several times.
But no matter how many times he called,
Nukiyasu-san's phone was apparently off.
Did you try searching outside the villa, too?
Yes, Fugo-san and I did since we could walk.
We searched the woods around the
villa too, but we didn't find him.
Heijima-san and I couldn't
ignore what happened and leave,
so we canceled our scheduled work so we
could stay at the villa and look for him.
But on the morning of the fourth
day since we started our search,
Fugo-san said, "Come to think of it,
my brother and I used to play cards
in the attic when we were kids."
Why did they play in the attic?
Their parents were strict and
bought them hardly any toys.
He said, "Whenever our parents
brought us to the villa,
we'd secretly play in the attic."
"It's possible he's up there."
But the stairs to the attic were
apparently locked from the inside
and couldn't be lowered.
So we called the police who
broke the attic window,
and when they went inside...
Nukiyasu-san was found dead with
a crossbow bolt in his back.
W-Wait a minute.
If the police broke the window to get inside,
does that mean the window was locked?
Yes.
Which means it was...
A locked room murder.
Right, Kogoro-no-ojisan?
Yeah.
I was gonna say that.
We found the crossbow next to the
house when we searched the woods,
but how did the culprit trap
Nukiyasu-san inside the attic?
What was that strange picture of the playing
cards that was sent to the younger brother?
And why didn't he call the police
if he was able to send that picture?
I have so many questions.
Please, Mori-san, solve these mysteries.
It weighs so heavily on
my mind I can't sleep.
You can count on me. I swear by my name
as the great detective Mori Kogoro...
I-Is something wrong?
Oh, no.
I'm going to the bathroom.
Is it those butter sandwiches?
I knew it was wrong, but I
eavesdropped on your conversation.
A locked room murder sure sounds interesting.
Mori Detective Agency
I see.
So the idol Okino Yoko-san ended up staying
at the producer's acquaintances' villa
she visited while location
scouting for a drama.
When she went to bed around
midnight, she heard a groan
and someone running down the
hallway, so she exited her room
and saw a trail of someone's blood.
She followed the blood around a corner,
but there was nobody there,
and the trail ended.
The only thing there was
the door to the bathroom.
Of course, there was no one
inside the bathroom either.
According to the others, they couldn't
find the eldest son Nukiyasu-san,
so they decided to split
up and look for them.
On the morning of the fourth
day since the search began,
the younger brother said he and his
brother used to play in the attic as kids,
and that he might be up there.
However, the stairs leading to the attic were
locked from the inside and couldn't be lowered.
So they called the police who broke the
attic window so they could get inside,
and there they found the body of the eldest
son with a crossbow bolt in his back.
It was clear that someone had
committed a locked room murder.
Does that sound more or
less like what happened?
Yes.
Though this is technically
a locked room murder,
given the blood in the hallway
and the sound of the footsteps,
it's clear he was shot in the hallway with
a crossbow and ran up into the attic.
In other words,
we need to figure out why
he had to hide in the attic
instead of calling for help.
Not only that, but shortly
after he disappeared
and just as you began looking for him,
rather than contacting the
police or calling for help,
why did he send this bizarre image
to his younger brother's phone?
So, um...
Who are you?
I hadn't introduced myself yet.
I'm Wakita. I work next door at Iroha Sushi.
Last night Master Kogoro
called our restaurant.
He said he might be ordering extra
special sushi for two tomorrow,
and that we'd better have
some fresh fish ready.
I see. He was planning on having sushi
with Yoko-chan if she was hungry.
But he never called no
matter how long I waited,
so I got impatient and brought this over.
Oh, but...
Don't worry about paying for it.
I'll take it out of my wages.
By the way, where is Master Kogoro?
He just went into the bathroom.
Then why don't we eat this sushi together?
Yeah.
I love sushi.
Wow, this looks delicious.
I put enough for three
in there, on the house.
I'll go make some tea.
This is definitely because
of those butter sandwiches.
I knew they tasted weird.
Anyway, is it just my imagination, or is it
lively out in the office for some reason?
It's so good!
I know.
Right, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
It really is extra special.
This chutoro is exceptionally
fatty and exquisite.
That's big-eye tuna.
They're in season right now.
Anyway, Master Kogoro sure
is taking a long time.
There's no point in just
sitting around waiting,
so why don't we get more
details about the case?
In that case, have you got any photos
of the people who stayed at the villa?
I'm having trouble imagining what
happened just based on descriptions.
I had the same thought.
One second.
I think I have a group photo.
Here it is.
This is the group photo we took
of everyone who came to the villa.
Since I took the picture, I'm not in it.
Who's who?
Let's see...
On the left with the crutches is
Nichiuri TV producer Heijima Wanya-san.
In the middle is his sister's
husband and the man who died,
Baba Nukiyasu-san.
The tall man on the right
with his left arm in a sling
.is Nukiyasu-san's younger
brother Baba Fugo-san.
And the woman in the wheelchair
is Fugo-san's wife Baba Himi-san.
Aside from the eldest son, everyone
seems to be injured somewhere.
Yes.
I think it was a coincidence, though.
There were duplicates cards in the photo
Nukiyasu-san sent to his younger brother.
Did he say why?
Yes.
Since they were children,
the whole family would visit the villa
during the summer to escape the heat.
To keep their parents from finding
out they were secretly playing cards,
rather than packing the cards in
their luggage for the trip back,
they hid them in the attic.
Since they bought new cards just in
case each time they visited the villa,
there were about five or
six decks in the attic.
What do you think he was trying to tell
you by mixing together several decks?
It must've been excruciating with
that crossbow bolt in his back.
Speaking of cards, the late Nukiyasu-san
had a strange name for his younger brother.
Huh? What was it?
Ace.
What happened to your left arm, Ace?
I hurt it playing baseball.
Was he a baseball pitcher or something?
I thought so too, but he laughed
at me when I asked about it.
I was often made to play catcher because
I've been on the bigger side since we were kids,
but never in my life have
I ever been a pitcher.
That's what he said.
It sounds like a clue to solving this code,
but I have no idea how.
What kind of person was
the wife who went missing?
You mean producer Heijima's sister.
I've never met her,
but when I told Heijima-san I was
telling Mori-san about the case,
he sent me a picture.
This woman in sunglasses on the left
is Heijima-san's sister Baba Hoka-san.
Baba Hoka
Nukiyasu's Wife
She went missing two summers ago.
Something came up suddenly
for her husband Nukiyasu-san,
who was supposed to go to the
villa with her to escape the heat.
She was supposed to arrive before them,
but when her husband and his younger
brother and wife arrived later,
she wasn't there.
They called the police and searched
for her, but they couldn't find her.
Did she often wear sunglasses?
Yes.
Heijima-san said before she went missing
she'd gotten into them and often wore a pair.
The younger brother and his wife
said they never saw her wear
them in college though.
In college? You mean...
Yes.
They attended not only college together,
but elementary, middle,
and high school as well.
Fugo-san's first love was Hoka-san,
and she and Himi-san were best friends.
I see.
Which means if her husband Nukiyasu-san
is the reason Hoka-san went missing,
then all three of them had
motive to kill Nukiyasu-san.
Episode Preview
So was there anything else
that caught your attention?
I can't do that.
Something terrible is bound to happen.
It's hard to believe he was acting.
No, I think he knew and
was pretending he didn't.
There's no way he doesn't know.
Well, it sure does make you curious
when something isn't where
it's supposed to be.
Okino Yoko and the Locked Attic
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Okino
Yoko and the Locked Attic, Part Two!"
Mahjong
Next Conan's hint!
Mahjong!
Don't miss the next episode.
Sushi is great.
This squid sure is tough.
And I'm in a tough situation.