DETECTIVE CONAN EPISODE 1060 "Okino
Yoko and the Locked Attic (Part Two)"
[op]
[ed]
[eyecatch]
Okino Yoko-san came to the detective agency
to ask the old man about a case.
While location scouting, she visited a
villa where a woman went missing
and wanted him to solve the murder
that happened while she was there.
However, the old man's been holed
up in the bathroom this whole time.
What is he doing in there?
What kind of person was
the wife who went missing?
You mean producer Heijima's sister.
This woman in sunglasses on the left
is Heijima-san's sister Baba Hoka-san.
Baba Hoka
Nukiyasu's Wife
Baba Himi (43)
Fugo's Wife
Did she often wear sunglasses?
Yes.
Heijima-san said before she went missing
she'd gotten into them and often wore a pair.
Fugo-san's first love was Hoka-san,
and she and Himi-san were best friends.
I see.
Which means if her husband Nukiyasu-san
is the reason Hoka-san went missing,
then all three of them had
motive to kill Nukiyasu-san.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
Expose the truth hidden away in the
code expressed through playing cards!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Okino Yoko and the Locked Attic
(Part Two)
"Okino Yoko and the Locked Attic, Part Two!"
So was there anything else
that caught your attention?
The pine trees around the villa, maybe?
What about the pine trees?
Heijima-san said something
when we arrived at the villa.
Heijima Wanya (39)
TV Producer
There were 17 pine trees when he visited
three years ago, and now there were only 16.
When we asked Nukiyasu-san about it,
Baba Nukiyasu (46)
Eldest Son of the Baba Family
he said he transplanted it to his home in
Tokyo because it was a nicely shaped tree.
It's incredible that he remembered
how many pine trees there were.
He's got a very good memory.
He can list off the birthdays of TV staff
and talent after hearing them only once.
Oh, that reminds me!
When we were talking about that pine
tree, Fugo-san told Heijima-san,
Baba Fugo (44)
Second Son of the Baba Family
"You're the true ace!"
What did he mean by that?
I wanted to ask him about it later,
but then the murder happened, and it didn't
seem like the right time to ask anymore.
Just to be sure,
the trail of blood that ended around the
corner didn't end near the attic entrance, right?
No.
The entrance was on the ceiling a short
distance away and around another corner,
and the attic stairs had been stored away.
You tried calling Nukiyasu-san's phone
numerous times while looking for him, right?
Yes, his younger brother did.
He borrowed his wife's phone since
his own was nearly out of batteries.
Everyone really did sympathetically
engage in the search for him.
Naturally, Heijima-san, who was
paired with me, did as well,
but the younger brother and his wife also
called out for him while looking for him.
Mori Detective Agency
I can't do that.
Something terrible is bound to happen.
Even if I call or message Ran about
it, Yoko-chan would probably find out...
that I need toilet paper.
Since it's come to this,
I'll have to rely on that sort of clever
but insolent kid with the glasses.
The old man sent me a message?
What is it, Conan-kun?
Kogoro-no-ojisan just sent me this message.
It looks like a code.
But isn't Mori-san in the bathroom right now?
They're starting to look
like mahjong tiles to me.
What? Ran-chan, you know how to play mahjong?
Yeah, I got into it for
a little while before.
Mahjong...
I see.
So that's how it is.
But why would he bother sending
a coded message to tell me that?
He could just shout for help.
Ah-ha. I see how it is.
But wait a minute.
Aren't these situations similar?
He's trapped inside a certain
location and can't come out,
so he has to send a coded message.
The reason for that and
contents of the message are...
I see. So that's how it is.
That's why Nukiyasu-san didn't call or send a
text but a picture of these playing cards.
He had no idea his code
would be used against him
and keep him trapped inside the attic.
What? You deciphered the playing card code?
Is that true, Conan-kun?
Yeah.
This code using numbers
and kanji Kogoro-no-ojisan
just sent me from inside the
bathroom provided a hint.
Y-You deciphered that code, too?
Even a child could figure it out
with a little bit of thought.
But why did he send you that code?
Probably because he wanted to request
something from inside the bathroom
without the object of his
adoration finding out.
Just as Nukiyasu-san sent his
brother that playing card code
while he was hiding in the attic after
being shot in the back with a crossbow.
Oh?
So, what's the solution
to the playing card code?
You convert the symbols
on the cards into English
and string together the English letters
indicated by the number on the card.
In other words, the first card on
the top left is the ace of hearts,
and the first letter of heart
spelled H-E-A-R-T is H.
The second card is the
two of hearts, so it's E.
The third card is the two of clubs,
and club is spelled C-L-U-B, so it's L.
Conan-kun, you can speak English?
I know. Isn't it surprising?
The fourth card is the two of spades,
and spade is spelled S-P-A-D-E, so it's P.
If you string together the first four
cards on the top left, you get H-E-L-P.
He's asking for help.
Wow!
Conan-kun, you really are a genius.
You might even overtake Dad before long.
It's not impossible.
Crap.
But I forgot how to spell diamond,
so I don't think I can read the rest.
Diamond is spelled D-I-A-M-O-N-D.
He really is just a child.
But if you read the second pile of
cards according to that principle,
you have the three of spades, the five
of hearts, the five of hearts again,
the two of diamonds, and the ace of clubs,
which spells A-T-T-I-C.
What's that?
Who knows? "Attack" as in
assault is spelled A-T-T-A-C-K.
(Assault)
It's "attic," the room beneath
the roof of a building.
Oh, right. Both "help" and
"attic" are English words.
Then the piles of six and two of diamonds
and two of diamonds, four of hearts,
and three of clubs after
that spell N-I and I-R-U.
Those are read normally as
romaji as "ni" and "iru."
NI = in
IRU = to be
All together, they spell, "I'm in the attic."
In other words, he's saying,
"Help me, I'm in the attic."
He only had 16 letters of
the alphabet to work with,
so he probably had no choice but
to mix English and Japanese.
You're right.
But the bottom row of cards seems to
be entirely Japanese written as romaji.
Let's see. That would be...
The culprit is...
Himi?
Isn't Himi-san Fugo-san's wife?
But she was in a wheelchair.
You can fire a crossbow from a wheelchair.
And if you set the crossbow in your
lap and cover it with a blanket,
you can approach your victim
without them suspecting a thing.
In other words, this code says, "My
brother, your wife is the culprit,
so come up to the attic and
help me without her noticing."
Himi-san probably asked to meet Nukiyasu-san
out into the hallway at midnight
and pointed the crossbow at him.
She fired a bolt into his back
while he was running away.
However, he escaped before
she could finish him off,
and though she went after
him in her wheelchair,
she realized you were following
Nukiyasu-san's blood trail.
To keep you from following
the trail any farther,
Himi-san laid the blanket under
the wheelchair's footrests,
held it down with her feet,
and followed Nukiyasu-san while
wiping up the blood in the hallway.
Th-That's why the trail suddenly
stopped when I turned the corner.
Yeah, so you couldn't stop her
from trying to kill Nukiyasu-san.
But the time she spent doing that
allowed him to escape into the attic.
After losing sight of Nukiyasu-san,
Himi-san gathered with everyone else
in front of the bathroom as
though nothing had happened.
B-But after that Himi-san did her best
to search for Nukiyasu-san, too.
She even shouted his name.
It's hard to believe she was acting.
She wasn't looking for him.
What?
She was threatening him.
"Come on down if you can."
"I'll kill you with this
crossbow as soon as you do."
B-But...
Does that mean Himi-san knew
Nukiyasu-san was hiding in the attic?
Yeah.
Since Nukiyasu-san's blood trail stopped
directly beneath the attic entrance,
she could easily imagine what happened.
Then shouldn't he have called
his brother Fugo-san normally
instead of sending the playing card code?
Yeah.
He could've said, "Your wife shot me
with a crossbow. Have her arrested."
But Himi-san still had
the crossbow in her lap.
If he said the wrong thing,
Himi-san might've killed him, too.
Y-You're right.
So that's why he tried to secretly
convey the message with a code.
Then he might've survived if
Fugo-san had deciphered the code.
No, I think he knew and
was pretending he didn't.
Come on, now. What's going on out there?
I sent him a coded message explaining
that I'm out of toilet paper,
so why isn't he responding?
Was that mahjong code too difficult
for a kid to understand?
No, he once made some excellent
plays while sitting on my lap.
There's no way he doesn't know what it means.
Not only that, but I've been hearing the voice
of Wakita from Iroha Sushi for a while, too.
If he finds out about this...
Impressive, Master Kogoro.
You're out of paper, but
your wits are outstanding.
I have to do whatever it
takes to prevent that.
What?
He knew but pretended he didn't?
Why would he do that?
To protect his own wife?
Yeah.
But isn't that just your guess?
Nukiyasu-san called his brother "ace," right?
Since ace is the number one,
if you rearrange the first letters
of spade, heart, club, and diamond,
you get SDHC.
SDHC Card
Add the word "card" to the end of that,
and it means a memory card with
greater capacity than an SD card.
That's why he called his brother,
who'd always been on the big side, ace.
I see.
I'm surprised you knew
about SDHC cards though.
Shinichi-niichan told me about them.
Shinichi's been teaching this
kid tricky concepts again.
But his brother said he didn't
know why he called him that.
No, he probably knew what it meant.
He apparently even told the producer
with a good memory that he was the real ace.
I see.
You're right.
And when his brother was hiding in the attic,
Fugo-san claimed his phone
was running out of batteries,
and deliberately used his wife the
culprit's phone to call his brother.
Why did he use his wife's phone?
If you received a call from
the person trying to kill you,
what would you do?
I wouldn't answer.
What if you were hiding somewhere?
Naturally I'd turn of my phone
so it wouldn't make a sound.
That's right.
By doing that, Fugo-san forced
Nukiyasu-san to turn off his phone,
completely cutting him off from the outside
and trapping him alone in the attic
so he'd die waiting for his brother's
help that would never come.
But why would he kill his own
brother to protect his wife?
Fugo-san probably resented his brother, too.
My gut's telling me Nukiyasu-san's wife
and Fugo-san's first love, Hoka-san,
is dead and buried somewhere near the villa.
What?
In the photo of Hoka-san we saw earlier,
the other four are wearing
breezy summer clothes,
but Fuko-san alone is wearing
long sleeves and sunglasses.
If she started wearing sunglasses a
few years before she went missing,
then it's safe to assume her husband
had started abusing her since then.
Abuse?
So she was wearing long
sleeves and sunglasses
to hide the bruises left by her
husband hitting and kicking her.
It's also a lie that two years ago, her husband
Nukiyasu-san had something come up
and Hoka-san headed to the villa alone.
I'm betting he actually killed her
when he took the abuse too far
at the villa and hid the body.
Then he claimed his wife went missing
when he arrived later with
his brother and his wife.
It's suspicious that he transplanted
one of the pine trees
around the villa to his
home three years ago, too.
Why?
You have to dig all the way down
to the roots to transplant a tree.
If he stopped the workers from filling it in by
claiming he wanted to plant a new tree in the hole,
then he could've secretly buried his
wife's body at the bottom of the hole,
and then said he decided not to plant a new
tree after all and have them fill it in.
That would allow him to hide the body deep
underground where no one could find it.
The culprit Himi-san probably suspected
Nukiyasu-san had killed Hoka-san
and interrogated him while
pointing the crossbow at him.
"Where's my friend's body?"
"You killed her, didn't you?"
I see.
So that's why Nukiyasu-san
couldn't call the police.
That's right.
If the police showed up,
Himi-san would be arrested,
but if she told them the woman
who went missing two years ago
had been killed by her husband,
they might dig up the area around the villa
and find his wife's body.
In other words, Nukiyasu-san sent
that playing card code to his brother
hoping to make it through the crisis
and flee to someplace far away.
Whoops, I got carried away running my mouth.
But all of this is just the
kid's and my deduction.
We don't have any proof.
But if you tell the police, have them
dig up the spot where the pine tree was,
and they find Hoka-san's body,
then Himi-san might admit her guilt.
Okay.
I'll start by talking to
the producer Heijima-san
and have a conversation with the police.
Thank you.
Wow, you solved the case without Dad.
Wakita-san, you're an incredible detective.
Not as good as my master.
Come to think of it, what
was dad's code about?
Like you said, it was mahjong.
The top row is one tile short of
a hand called "thirteen orphans."
The bottom row is one tile short
of a hand called "nine gates."
The "thirteen orphans" hand is
missing a north or "pei" tile,
and the "nine gates" hand is missing
some suit of eight or "pa" tile.
What do you get when you put them together?
He needs...
"Pei" and "pa"...
He wants toilet paper!
I see.
Dad was embarrassed Yoko-chan would
learn he was out of toilet paper,
so he wrote it as a code.
What?
Paper... please!
Anyway, you said that code was
easily deciphered by a kid,
but this one seems way
tougher to crack to me.
R-Really?
Well, it sure does make you curious
when something isn't where
it's supposed to be.
For example...
Like a shogi piece.
Wow, really?
Wouldn't that make you curious?
Not really.
Poirot
Amuro-san, you're looking
at that photo again.
Is that your girlfriend?
No.
We've got orders piling up.
Could you do your job, please?
Got it.