At the police academy,
classmates strengthen their bonds
by competing against
and supporting one another
under class flags they design themselves.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
Dark shadows loom in Morofushi's past!
The truth is uncovered
by the power of his classmates!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Police Academy Arc
Police Academy Arc Wild Police Story
CASE. Morofushi Hiromitsu
"Police Academy Arc Wild Police
Story CASE. Morofushi Hiromitsu!"
C'mon, man.
Matsuda Jinpei (22)
How is the bathroom this dirty?
I told you,
every class got covered in mud practicing
for the sports festival this weekend.
Date Wataru (22)
On top of that, they practiced
in the rain yesterday.
By the way, your design for
our class flag was really cool.
Furuya Rei (22)
Thanks.
Morofushi Hiromitsu (22)
I kind of thought a cherry blossom design
for a police academy would be cliché.
It was finished and delivered
this morning, right?
Hagiwara Kenji (22)
That's right.
As you can see...
Onizuka's Class
Cherry Blossoms in Full Bloom
Tada! I've been keeping it
on me at all times.
The colors are great, too.
Right?
I'm excited for the sports festival.
Huh? What's this?
Cat paw prints?
They kind of stink, too.
I know. I was hanging it out a window so
I could show it off to the other classes.
Not only was it blown away by the wind,
but a stray cat that had stepped
in crap walked all over it.
It pissed me off, so I got Hagi
to help me try to catch the cat.
That's how this happened.
So that's what the cat was about.
And when I sent it to the cleaners,
Onizuka called us into his office.
I'm sure you've noticed,
Onizuka Hachizo (48)
Rookie Class Instructor
but I've received complaints
from the other instructors.
They say that recently the bathroom
has been unbelievably filthy.
But that's not just our—
Because of that,
I've decided that the five of you will be
cleaning the bathroom every day.
What?!
I-Instructor Onizuka...
Don't you think that's a bit unreasonable?
What's that? I thought I'd give you
boys a chance to make up
for all the mischief you've
committed until now.
Mischief?
In any case,
for one week, the five of you will be
cleaning the bathroom and changing room.
You're dismissed. Now get to it.
Missing Person Report
What's this?
Fuchu Police Station
Recipient Number:
Agent:
Community Safety Officer
Yamada Taro
Date Received:
10/28 9:13PM
Missing Person
Name:
Sotsukuri Yoshi
Date of Birth & Sex:
9/21 (7 years old)  Female
Incident Description
Time & Date:
9/21
Approximately 3PM
Location: Home, area around home
Description of circumstances:
Said she was going shopping around three,
left home and did not return
That's a photo of a young girl
who was reported missing
last night in this jurisdiction.
She didn't return home after
going out to run an errand.
What is it, Morofushi?
Do you know that girl?
Oh, no. I've just seen her
around the city before.
May I take this with me?
I might recall something.
That's fine.
Make sure you finish cleaning
by bath time at 7:30.
C'mon,
how long are we going to keep doing this?
Why don't we talk about something
more exciting while we clean?
Exciting?
Come to think of it, Morofushi-chan...
You know something about that missing
girl you were looking at, don't you?
Huh?
He's right.
It doesn't make sense for you to react like
that if you'd only seen her around town.
She looks just like a girl
I used to play with as a child.
She passed away due to an illness, though.
But it caught my attention.
If she was a childhood friend,
does that mean I've met her, too?
No, I knew her when I lived in Nagano.
That sounds interesting.
Tell us about it.
We're all ears.
The truth is...
Oh, but it's not an interesting story.
Oh, c'mon.
Enough of this.
Zero told me to wait until you
brought it up so I'd been holding back,
but you're looking for the guy
who killed your parents, aren't you?
Now you're gloomy because that missing
girl looks like your childhood friend
and reminded you of the murders.
Am I wrong?
I-It's true. You're right, but...
I can't. I have to solve this case.
I don't want to drag anyone else into it.
If anyone else died because of it...
We won't die.
Together we've been through...
Plenty of dangerous situations.
But with the five of us together...
We've made it through somehow.
So tell us, Hiro.
You can trust us.
"You can trust us?"
That sounds like something
a bad guy would say.
Fine, I'll tell you...
about the incident
that took place 15 years ago
that froze the hands of the clock inside me.
That terrifying night
enveloped by the smell of iron.
He arrived around 7PM when I was
eating dinner with my parents.
The visitor apparently knew my father,
and I could hear them speaking
calmly in the entryway.
But the man began raising his voice,
and when my mother went to the entryway
to see what was going on...
I heard my father scream,
and my mother who'd gone pale with fear
returned to the dining room and told me...
"Hide in here for a while."
"Don't come out until I tell you it's safe."
Then she shut me inside
a Japanese-style closet.
I heard her arguing with the man next,
but eventually I stopped
hearing her voice as well,
and the iron-like smell
of blood began to fill the room.
Even I could smell it from inside the closet.
So, what happened next?
I heard a song.
A song?
Yeah. It wasn't my father's
or mother's voice.
In a fake high-pitched and wheedling voice,
he sang the same phrase over and over.
So I cautiously peered through
a gap in the closet door
and saw a man holding
a bloody knife humming,
"It's all right now. Come on out."
What about his face? Did you see his face?
No. I was too scared to look at his face.
But why was he looking for you?
He wasn't looking for me.
He called a girl's name
after he said "come on out."
The name of the girl
I often played with as a kid.
The one who looked exactly like
the girl reported missing last night.
Yuri.
Why would he be looking
for her at your house?
What's her family name?
I only ever called her by her given name,
so I don't remember her family name.
Besides, we were first-year
grade school students.
You didn't see the culprit's face,
but you saw his tattoo, right?
Yeah. He slipped in the blood
and bumped into
the Japanese-style closet
I was hiding inside.
When he moved away from
the closet, for a moment I saw
the goblet-shaped tattoo on his shoulder.
Are you sure that tattoo
was on his shoulder?
Yes, I'm sure.
After he moved away from the closet,
he held his shoulder
as though he was in pain.
I couldn't see the tattoo anymore because
it was hidden behind his bloody hand.
So, what'd he do after that?
I don't know. At some point, I fell asleep.
I was woken by the sound of doors
being opened and closed.
As I was bracing myself
for being discovered,
the closet door was opened...
Hiromitsu, our parents are dead.
Can you tell me what happened?
...by my older brother who had
returned from his camp school.
It was the next afternoon.
I'd been asleep for half the day.
You have an older brother?
He is currently a capable officer
for the Nagano police.
They call him Komei of Nagano.
So, did you tell your brother
about the tattoo?
No. After that, not only did
I suffer some minor amnesia
from the trauma of the incident,
but I also lost my voice.
My brother was taken in by relatives
in Nagano, while I went to Tokyo.
Though I was living somewhere else,
I didn't regain my voice until I met Zero.
So you joined the police academy so
you could catch your parents' killer?
Yeah. Recently I've been remembering a lot.
I've been thinking about
reviewing the circumstances
from the perspective of a police officer
and telling my brother what I know.
And while conducting your search,
you encountered three suspicious men.
Yeah.
We already talked to the
three of them for you.
What?
Right?
Yeah.
We split up and questioned them.
To help you get revenge.
How did you even know I'm looking
for the man who killed my parents?
It's obvious.
You're always looking up the stabbing
deaths of a couple in Nagano online.
This is the first time we've heard details
about the culprit and the tattoo, though.
But it's unlikely the culprit
is here in Tokyo instead of Nagano
and just happens to be in my vicinity.
You're right.
It's also just a coincidence
that the missing girl looks just like
your childhood friend from 15 years ago.
At least, that's what you'd normally think.
So, what's your intuition telling you?
I don't know.
I just feel some kind of uneasiness.
Okay, then it's decided.
Huh?
Team Leader, we'll start with you.
Huh? What?
I had a tough time since
he wasn't much of a talker.
His name is Irie Sumio, 46 years old.
Irie Sumio (46)
He lives with his wife.
He got the tattoo on his
shoulder ten years ago.
It's apparently the champion's cup he won
at a neighborhood association
ping pong tournament.
Ten years ago?
Yeah.
Also, he told his wife,
"hana ya mizu wo kure kure."
Are you sure it wasn't
"hana ni mizu wo kuretekure?"
Yeah, that's it.
That's Nagano dialect. They say "kureru"
instead of "ageru" for watering flowers.
Hey, in that case...
But if he got the tattoo ten years ago,
the math doesn't add up.
Hagi, you're next.
Okay.
Tomori Hajime, 50 years old. He lives alone.
Tomori Hajime (50)
He still operates the cleaning service
he inherited from his uncle.
He got the goddess Kannon tattooed
on his upper arm 20 years ago
for the wife and mother he lost
in a traffic accident.
He graduated with an engineering degree
and often performed repairs
on simple electric appliances.
Because they're from the same region,
he apparently played doubles
in ping pong with Irie-san.
If he got the tattoo 20 years ago,
that doesn't conflict with the murders.
But I'm not sure how you can
mistake a Kannon tattoo for a goblet.
Speaking of things that look like goblets,
the bike shop employee was named
Monobe Shuzo, 35 years old.
Monobe Shuzo (35)
Like Tomori, he lives alone.
He got a scorpion tattooed
on the back of his neck
when he was around 20 years old,
so that's barely 15 years ago.
But it's on the back of his neck.
What is it, you two?
Something doesn't seem right to me.
Me, too.
What is it, Morofushi? You, too?
Yeah. The other day, I called my brother
to tell him what I'd managed to recall...
Seeking quick returns is shortsighted.
Don't call me seeking fast returns
before you have the full picture.
You weren't hiding
in a Japanese-style closet then,
but a Western-style closet
with double folding doors.
That was a western-style house without
Japanese-style closets and sliding doors.
...and remembered that he told me that.
Hiro, are you sure you're not mixing it up
with your home in Tokyo?
That house was old and only had
Japanese-style closets and sliding doors.
Y-You might be right.
Don't you think it's weird, then?
If you were hiding inside a Western-style
closet with double folding doors,
the doors should've closed
when the culprit bumped into it.
He's right.
For you to see the culprit holding his
shoulder, you'd have to reopen the doors.
Did you open the doors
under those circumstances?
Of course not.
Then maybe the gap you were peering
through was wide instead of tall.
You can see what's happening outside
through the slits in a closet door
even when the doors are closed.
That's it. So that's what happened.
I was watching the culprit through
the slits in the closet door.
If I couldn't see up or down
because of the slits,
then Tomori-san's Kannon tattoo
could also look like a goblet.
And if Tomori's from the same place
as Irie, who speaks Nagano dialect,
then it's gotta be him.
The man who killed your parents
15 years ago was Tomori Hajime.
Tomori Yuri.
I remembered Yuri-chan's full name.
Then was she his...?
On a school trip, Yuri-chan
suddenly got a stomachache.
My father, who was a teacher,
rushed her to the hospital,
but her appendicitis was acute
and it was already too late.
If Tomori-san couldn't
accept his daughter's death
and thought my father had
kidnapped Yuri-chan, then...
I knew something was off.
According to Hagi's investigation,
Tomori-san lives alone.
But when we were trapped inside
the convenience store during the robbery...
I-I came to get snacks for my daughter.
Is it possible a similar-looking
girl went missing because...
We'll just have to ask...
Tomori Cleaning
the man himself about it.
Hey, Tomori.
There's no one here.
Is he closed?
What is this?
Don't touch that!
That's a bomb.
A bomb?
Yeah. It looks like it's connected
to the other washing machines,
so it might flatten
the entire shopping center.
This one on the right end
seems to be the source,
so we should be fine
if we can stop this thing.
But why?
In any case, Matsuda, you disarm the bomb.
Zero and Hagiwara,
evacuate the local residents.
Morofushi and I will look for Tomori.
Wait.
My hands are injured, so I can't
do precise work right now.
Hagiwara can take my place.
I wish I could say you can count on me,
but that cat actually scratched me, too.
Seriously?
Sorry.
What? Y-You want me to do it?
You seem like you'd be good with your hands.
I'll show you what to do.
It's up to you guys to disarm the bomb.
Got it.
Tomori-san, are you there?
Tomori-san.
Tomori—
Don't shout. She finally fell asleep.
You and dad are about to go
on a little trip, Yuri.
Wrong.
That wire is a trap.
Don't rush, Zero.
Impatience is the greatest trap of all.
Got it.
That girl isn't Yuri-chan.
What are you talking about?
You're the one who made us meet.
I-I did?
Why do you think I didn't kill you while
you were sleeping in the closet that day?
You were friends with Yuri.
I knew if I followed you, you'd someday
lead me to wherever your parents hid Yuri.
Now step back.
I'd originally intended to depart at 4:30PM
today when Yuri was born, but...
Come to think of it, the day
of the trip, Yuri-chan mentioned
that she'd had an argument with her father.
That she'd told you she was
never going back to that house.
Tomori Cleaning
Nice work.
Wh-Why won't it explode?
They disarmed it in time.
After that, Yuri-chan told me...
"When I get home from this trip,
I need to apologize to my dad."
Looks like it went well.
Aw, man. I wasted my time
evacuating everyone.
Now, now. Don't be like that.
What time is it?
Huh? It's 4:29PM.
Sorry, kid. I'll apologize to your parents
once I'm on the other side.
What?
Crap! He rigged the second floor, too?
Damn it.
Don't, Morofushi!
It's too late!
Come back!
Hiro!
Out front, the cherry blossoms!
Huh?
The next time I inhale,
the smoke will destroy my lungs.
I don't have time to shout a warning
or see what's happening outside, but...
I trust them to do it.
Let me die.
No.
You'll be paying for your crimes.
What?!
You just happened
to find the kidnapped girl,
just happened to arrest her kidnapper,
and he just happened to be the guy
who killed Morofushi's parents in the past?!
Yes, sir.
Don't be ridiculous!
That's an absurd excuse for skipping out
on your cleaning duties to leave campus.
But, sir...
If that bathroom's still dirty...
But it's the bathroom itself
that really matters.
If that's not clean...
You'd better keep this up all week!
Yes, sir!
I bought them time, just like I was told to.
But I would've preferred to do this instead.
Episode Preview
So he has a criminal record.
That's right. He was serving time
in prison until last month.
This belongs to you, doesn't it?
N-No.
In other words, there's a 30-minute
gap between these two.
They're definitely hiding something.
The Spiral of Rain and Malice
The next episode of Conan
is "The Spiral of Rain and Malice!"
Earrings
Next Conan's hint!
Earrings!
Don't miss the next episode.
It's almost Halloween.
Welcome back, everyone.
You get to see each other again.
Yeah.