DETECTIVE CONAN EPISODE 1062
"The Spiral of Rain and Malice"
[op]
[ed]
[eyecatch]
I found it.
What is this?
The license plate has been removed.
Perhaps it was dumped illegally.
Apparently disposing of an old car
is pretty expensive these days.
Unbelievable. What if some kids got into it?
How thoughtless.
Aren't you guys kids?
Let's get back to our game.
Didn't the weather report
say it'd rain this evening?
Yeah!
All right!
What's up?
Onda Tamaki (38)
Design Company Representative
Is that a voice recorder?
Looks like it.
Take this! Explosive Kojima Shot!
Perfect Block!
Watch out!
Watch out, ma'am!
What was that?
You should be more careful.
What's your problem?
That was your fault for
looking somewhere else.
Hey!
It's hopeless.
What?
I can't believe myself.
I get angry so quickly.
It's a bad habit of mine.
I'm sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
Wow!
Huh.
Despite how I seem now, I actually used
to play on my college soccer team.
Here we go.
That doesn't look good.
Should we call it here?
That's probably for the best.
Oh, look at the time.
They're late.
Are you waiting for someone?
Huh? Oh, yes.
I'm going to stick around a little longer.
You kids should go home.
You wouldn't want to get
rained on and catch a cold.
Take care.
Bye, ma'am!
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
Led by the rain that begins to fall,
was it an accident or foul
play? The suspicions build!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Spiral of Rain and Malice
"The Spiral of Rain and Malice!"
The weather's so nice today, you'd
hardly believe it rained last night.
And now for the news.
Body Discovered in Abandoned
Vehicle at Shikigawa River
Early this morning, a woman's body
was discovered inside an abandoned
vehicle by the Shikigawa River.
Based on her possessions, she's
been identified as Onda Tamaki-san,
38 years old, the representative of
a design company located nearby...
Conan.
Conan-kun.
You guys came?
I was shocked to see the news on TV.
Tamaki-san is that woman, isn't she?
What's going on? Why was she inside that car?
You knew the deceased Onda Tamaki-san?
Is that true, kids?
Yeah. She played soccer
with us here yesterday.
She was really good.
What time was that?
For about an hour just after three, right?
That sounds right. Less than 30 minutes
after that, it started raining.
When's the estimated time of death?
Huh?
Uh, um...
Kogoro-no-ojisan saw the
news and told me to ask.
We're waiting on the autopsy
results for the details,
but it was probably between
midnight and 2AM last night.
Is the cause of death still unknown?
Yeah.
We found one contusion on her
head and several on her body,
but she'd been exposed to water, so it's
unclear which of the wounds was fatal.
What about personal possessions?
Her valuables like her phone and
wallet were still on her person.
Oh, right. Do you recognize this?
The deceased Onda Tamaki-san
was holding it in her hand.
An earring?
And only one at that.
Was she wearing this yesterday?
No.
At the very least, she wasn't
wearing that earring.
Perhaps it belongs to the culprit.
Was that lady killed?
No way.
Not necessarily.
It's possible the earrings
were hers even though
she wasn't wearing them
and dropped one somewhere.
What about fingerprints?
She was holding it in her hand.
Forensics just told me only hers were found.
Those are the only possessions found on her?
There wasn't a voice recorder?
A voice recorder?
This type of recorder.
Let me see.
We didn't find one.
Maybe she dropped it somewhere.
Thank you.
We haven't found any witnesses.
Not a single one?
It was pouring rain last night.
Nobody was out walking around.
Do you think it was an accident after all?
It's looking likely.
The question is what did
she do after we left?
Yeah.
To be safe, wouldn't it be best to
investigate this as both a murder and an accident?
I bet that's what Kogoro-no-ojisan would say.
Yeah, you're right. He
always knows what to do.
Let's get to it.
Try not to get in our way, Detective Boys.
Okay.
Cheetah Transport
Refrigerated Transport
What is it?
This is it.
Cheetah Transport
You're useless.
Cargo Reception Desk
When are you going to learn to do your job?
You should be grateful we're
even employing a felon like you.
Wh-What was that?
What? Do you understand
the position you're in?
What's wrong?
You got a problem?
That's enough.
We're the police.
Detective Takagi.
Y-You kids.
What are you doing here?
MPD Beika Police Station
You found a match for the fingerprints?
Yeah.
The fingerprints on the
deceased Onda-san's glasses
matched his fingerprints that
were collected a year ago.
So he has a criminal record.
That's right.
Koyabu Ryuji, 32 years old.
A year ago he badly injured someone
in a fight and was arrested.
Koyabu Ryuji (32)
Transport Company Driver
He was serving time in
prison until last month.
Which means it really was a murder.
Was that lady killed by him
and stuffed into that car?
How awful. I feel sorry for her.
Actually, during the estimated time
of death between midnight and 2AM,
he was making deliveries.
There's even testimony verifying that.
In other words, he has an alibi.
That's right.
Hello?
Chiba here.
I checked out the deceased Onda-san's
company and made an unbelievable discovery.
That's enough gravel.
Try placing the child mannequin on it.
Looks good.
You're Shirosaki Yurina-san, aren't you?
Th-The police?
Yes.
MPD Beika Police Station
This belongs to you, doesn't it?
Shirosaki Yurina (25)
Tamaki's Subordinate
N-No.
That's odd.
We've been told you wore them at your
company's presentation yesterday.
W-Well, someone made a mistake.
What? She has an alibi, too?
Yeah.
During the estimated time of death, she was
supervising a project in that shopping center.
If this were a murder, it's likely
one of them is the culprit, but...
We're stumped.
They both have alibis.
Then we should re-examine the case.
Agree!
Let's head go right away.
You're right.
No, wait.
You can't come with us.
But as the last people who saw her
alive, we might notice something.
You're right.
It makes sense.
All right!
We decided to start by re-investigating
Koyabu Ryuji-san's alibi.
Like I told you before, he
definitely came during that time.
What was the exact time?
Let's see...
He got in at 12:35 and
finished unloading at 1:05.
Could he have slipped out during that time?
No. He would've been with the employees
here the entire time he was unloading.
Did you notice anything
different from normal?
Now that you mention it, I think he arrived
30 minutes later than he usually does.
Does that happen often?
No, that was the first time.
We traced his delivery route and visited
every distribution center he visited.
As we thought, a 30-minute delay
was recorded at several distribution centers.
Cheetah Transport
West Beika Distribution Center
The first delay was recorded here at
the West Beika Distribution Center.
The stop he made before that was at
the North Beika Distribution Center,
North Beika Distribution Center
near the crime scene by the river.
In other words, there's a 30-minute
gap between these two.
Something related to the case
happened during that gap.
All right.
We'll check out the security cameras
between the two distribution centers.
You should probably visit the
local police stations, too.
They might have noticed something unusual.
I'll handle that.
But...
I don't see any security cameras.
Me neither.
Nothing, huh?
Hello?
A minor collision?
It took place last night at 11:30.
But the accident wasn't caused
by Koyabu-san's delivery vehicle,
so maybe it's unrelated to the case.
What? A dash cam?
C-Conan-kun?
Yeah.
Try examining the dash cams of the
vehicles that caused the accident.
You might find something on them.
Look.
Ma'am, where did you get the
earring on your dog's collar?
I found it by a bench
near the river yesterday.
I thought whoever dropped it
might notice if I did this.
What a well-behaved dog.
Did you find anything else, like
this thing that resembles a brooch?
I didn't see anything like that.
Could it be?
They're definitely hiding something.
Takagi, Chiba.
Is it true that Mori-kun
discovered a lead in this case?
Yes, Inspector.
First, look at this.
This is dash cam footage from the two cars
that caused a minor collision last night.
Right here.
Look at this.
What?
And this is footage from the
other dash cam ten minutes later.
What's this? Is he driving back and forth?
But why would he do that?
Koyabu-san, could you explain that yourself?
Th-The rain...
If it hadn't been raining so
hard, I could've avoided her.
Watch where you're going!
I thought I'd run her over, but then...
Take me to the hospital.
What?
Go.
I've got a criminal record, so I figured
it was better than going to the police.
While looking for a hospital, suddenly...
This is the problem.
You can start over if you make a mistake,
as many times as you need to.
It surprised me. I wondered
if she knew who I was.
After getting out of prison, I was
planning to start over this time,
but my old friends threatened me,
and I'd been stealing
valuables from the cargo.
I didn't have a choice.
Go back.
What?
She told me to turn back so she could look
for something important she'd dropped.
I thought she'd go to the police,
but when we returned to the river,
I tried to stop her from getting
out of the truck, and...
She's moving around a lot for someone
who wanted to go to the hospital.
She's probably fine.
After that, the rain started
coming down even harder.
I was worried, but by the time
I arrived in the morning...
Why?
And you, Shirosaki Yurina-san.
Didn't you meet Onda
Tamaki-san here yesterday?
We found the other earring.
Your fingerprints have been found on them.
She rejected my presentation.
She was jealous of my talent.
So she stole my designs and tried
to pass them off as her own.
You've done it again.
This is useless.
You're such an idiot.
Yeah, you're right. It was
stupid of me to show you.
I'm leaving. Give me back my tablet.
What did you say? Who do you
think you're talking to?
Let go.
I'm not showing you the designs on there.
What are you talking about?
Let go, you... you awful...
This is your fault.
But the rain started coming down
hard, and I got worried about her.
I went back a while later,
but no one was there.
I thought it wasn't a big deal
after all and went to work.
So why...?
After that, Onda-san
probably decided she needed
to go to a hospital based
on the pain and blood loss.
She unsteadily made her way to the road,
where she encountered Koyabu-san's vehicle.
I-I had no idea.
Neither did I.
But if she'd never said those
awful things in the first place...
I think you're wrong.
Oh, right.
She was talking about herself.
It's hopeless.
What?
I can't believe myself.
That's...
Detective Takagi,
have you been able to find
Tamaki-san's voice recorder?
No, not yet.
Voice recorder?
We heard from a colleague who's
known Onda-san for a long time
that she used a tiny voice recorder
to record notes for herself.
We still haven't found it yet.
By the way, one of your earrings
was found in Tamaki-san's hand.
So maybe Tamaki-san's
recorder is inside your bag.
Yeah, right.
Impressive work, Conan-kun.
Yurina will be arriving soon.
But I don't think I'll tell
her about it after all.
Until she recognizes her own
mistake and corrects it herself,
I choose to believe in her.
What? She knew?
What are you talking about?
That same colleague told us
that she was considering
you for her successor.
It's the reason she was so hard on you.
You're kidding.
Tamaki-san...
I was the thief.
I stole anonymous designs from the internet.
Then what about when I saw her?
She was probably disoriented
and didn't know who you were.
She entered the abandoned
vehicle to get out of the rain.
And then...
She lost consciousness.
The truth captured by the two
recorders wasn't murderous intent,
but a spiral of misfortune
that led to her death.
Either way,
both of you were concerned for her
well-being after you parted ways with her.
If you'd looked for her or turned back then,
she may have survived.
It's a shame.
After that, Onda Tamaki-san's
cause of death was determined.
Together the wounds from the
tablet and car were too much,
and she died from blood loss due to being
left untreated for a prolonged period of time.
If she'd suffered only one or the
other, it wouldn't have been fatal,
but how those two who caused her death
will be punished by the law is
another story for another time.
Episode Preview
So, what does a chicken
sexer like you want from me?
It seems like someone is trying to kill me.
Can you think of any reason
someone would want to kill you?
No, so I thought you could
start by investigating that.
Watch out!
The Targeted Chicken Sexer
The next episode of Conan is
"The Targeted Chicken Sexer!"
Hand
Next Conan's hint!
A hand!
Super Elegant Pass!
Don't miss the next episode.
Hyper Ultra Hand!
You can't use your hands.