Kusano Eggs
A request from National Chicken
Sexing Champion Nanba Hitoshi-san
Nanba Hitoshi (45)
Chicken Sexer
brought us here to the Kusano Egg factory.
You're very fast.
I'm determining if they're male or female
by looking at slight
differences in their behinds.
So, what does a chicken sexer
like you want from me?
It seems like someone is trying to kill me.
What?
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
Every second counts when sexing chickens!
It's a race against time
when his life is in danger!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Targeted Chicken Sexer
"The Targeted Chicken Sexer!"
For the past few weeks, strange things
have been happening around me.
While I was walking outside,
a rubber ball came flying at me.
While I was napping,
someone burned my hand using
a magnifying glass from a distance.
A phone that had been placed
near me at some point exploded.
A ball...
A magnifying glass...
And an exploding phone?
I'd like you to investigate why this is
happening while acting as my bodyguard.
Can you think of any reason
someone would want to kill you?
No, so I thought you could
start by investigating that.
President's Office
A grudge?
Nanba-san is a star in this industry.
Kusano Saburo (61)
Kusano Eggs President
There's no way anyone would want to kill
someone so accomplished and personable.
Is it possible someone has some
unjustified anger against him?
No, I've never heard of anything like that.
Fresh and Safe
When it comes to eggs,
nothing beats
Kusano Eggs
Chicken Sexing World Monthly Magazine
November Issue
Direct Sales of Eggs
Someone has a grudge against Nanba?
I don't know about that,
Nakamura Takashi (29)
Chicken Sexer
but I have no comment regarding whether
or not he's deserving of people's respect.
He seems like a nice person
outwardly, at least.
Aren't you a chicken sexer as well?
Yes, but to be honest, I'm aiming
to become Nanba-san's successor.
Steroid Cream
You're asking about Nanba-san?
He's a good person.
Hirasawa Mamiko (22)
Kusano Eggs Accountant
At the very least, he's kind to me.
That said, I just recently
joined the company.
So you're a new employee.
Why did you choose to work here?
I'd like to become a chicken sexer someday.
The way he handles chicks
with his graceful hands is so cool.
Does that mean you joined this company
because you admired Nanba-san?
Yes, that's right.
Hey, mister.
Shouldn't we talk to people
who don't work here, too?
Huh?
Yeah, I guess.
In that case, the perfect person
is here gathering information.
Huh, so you're the famous detective.
I'm a journalist-slash-cameraman-slash-errand boy
for Chicken Sexing World Monthly Magazine.
Kitazawa Kazumasa (29)
Magazine Journalist
My name is Kitazawa Kazumasa.
Nice to meet you.
Rolled
Omelets
Hello.
Cutting to the case, do you know anyone
who might have a grudge against Nanba-san?
Who knows? It's not as though
I'm particularly close to him.
I heard that Nanba-san is a champion.
Is he really that amazing?
It's not that he's bad,
but he's nowhere near as good
as Okabe-san at his peak.
Okabe-san?
What? You've never heard
of Master Okabe Yuji?
National Chicken Sexing Tournament
Seven-time national champion,
no mistakes four years in a row,
Okabe Yuji (52)
Chicken Sexer
record-breaker for speed!
Things were so exciting back then.
I see...
Ah, Mori-san. There you are.
Let's go. I've been asked to give
a lecture this afternoon.
A lecture?
The Future of Chicken Sexing
Lecturer: Nanba Hitoshi
There are several ways to sex chickens,
Lecturer Nanba Hitoshi
The Future of Chicken Sexing
but the vent sexing technique
was developed here in Japan.
Because it requires a delicate touch,
Japanese people and their small hands
are suited to using this technique.
There's more to this industry
than meets the eye.
Y-Yeah...
I've developed my own personal
techniques for this method
to increase my speed
while maintaining accuracy.
Those techniques are—
Watch out!
Hey, what was in that liquid?
According to forensics,
it was a chlorine-based detergent.
Those can cause blindness
if they get in your eyes
or cause severe chemical burns
if they get on your skin.
It's not as though having detergent poured on
you poses an immediate threat to your life,
but it's clear that someone is harassing you.
It would seem that way.
In any case, I appreciate you
investigating this case.
I'm going to get back to work.
See you later.
Okay...
I guess I already got everything
out of him that I could.
Mori-san, I got some great information.
Kusano Eggs
I'll give you the information for free
if you'll give me an exclusive
interview once you solve the case!
That's fine.
The information I've got for you
is that there are money troubles
between Nanba-san and President Kusano.
Apparently Nanba-san's been
demanding half of the profits
Fresh and Safe
When it comes to
eggs, nothing beats
Kusano Eggs
because the company's been doing so well
since he became its poster boy.
Wouldn't he be fired
for making demands like that?
But if he hasn't, then that would mean...
Perhaps it's because Nanba-san's
not entirely wrong.
Then... let's go see if that's the case.
There's no way I could accept that,
so we're currently in talks to find
a compromise that satisfies both parties.
So it's true that he
demanded half of the profits?
What? Well, uh...
Money troubles would be a motive
to target Nanba-san's life.
How dare you. I would never—
Then why haven't you fired Nanba-san
for making such threatening demands?
B-Because...
Does he have dirt on you?
Leave me alone!
We have our own way of doing things here.
Get out!
Hey, Hirasawa-san.
You're in charge of accounting, right?
Yes. What about it?
Is this a good company?
Of course it is.
I see.
By the way, do you think
Master Okabe is the best, too?
What?
Actually, I don't know much
about that time period.
Kusano Eggs Co., Ltd.
When it comes to
eggs, nothing beats
Kusano Eggs has been
in business for 24 years.
Since making Nanba Hitoshi
its poster boy six years ago,
the business has been steadily improving.
Kusano Eggs Co., Ltd.
President and CEO Kusano Saburo
President and CEO
Kusano Saburo
began working in the egg industry
when he graduated university.
After leaving Miura Foods,
he founded Kusano Eggs.
National Chicken Sexing Tournament Judge
He was a national tournament judge?
Is this...?
What are you doing here?
Mori-san was looking for you.
Nakamura-san, were there any
contests you found strange
among the tournaments
Nanba-san participated in?
Contests I found strange?
Yeah.
Well...
It's not as though Nanba-san did
anything strange, but there was one.
It was the national tournament
seven years ago,
the contest that made
Nanba-san the champion.
The contest ended when the reigning
champion ruined his own chances.
I thought it'd be a closer contest,
but the title changed hands easily.
By the way, what's the name
of the former champion?
You don't know?
It was egg industry legend
Master Okabe Yuji.
Is something wrong?
Is there anywhere I could
still see that contest?
Kusano Eggs
I see.
Name
Time
Accuracy
Okabe Yuji
4:36
Nanba Hitoshi
4:50
This certainly is a strange contest.
Chicken Sexing World
Supplementary
Volume
Hello, Detective Takagi?
I'd like you to look into something.
I see.
Yes, I see.
Got it, thank you.
Interview 1
Nanba Hitoshi vs Okabe Yuji
So that's how it is.
I'm starting to see the whole
picture of this case.
This is footage of the national chick
sexing tournament held seven years ago.
Defending champion Master
Okabe advanced to the finals.
His opponent was promising
new star Nanba Hitoshi-san.
Let's have a fair fight.
I've heard you've got a lot of potential.
You'll be competing for speed and
accuracy in sexing a hundred chicks.
That's President Kusano!
What's going on here?
The judge and a competitor
currently run a company together.
Don't you think that's too much
to be a coincidence?
It's time to begin the National
Chick Sexing Tournament Finals.
Ready, go!
72nd National Chicken Sexing Tournament
Everyone seemed to think Master Okabe
had an overwhelming advantage, but...
It's time to announce the results.
72nd National Chicken Sexing Tournament
Nanba had a time of four
minutes and 50 seconds.
His accuracy was 100.
Okabe had a time of four
minutes and 36 seconds.
His accuracy was 83.
What?
It was a crushing victory for Nanba-san.
The winner is Nanba.
72nd National Chicken Sexing Tournament
Let's have a round of applause
for our new champion.
W-Wait a minute.
There must be some mistake. This isn't—
72nd National Chicken Sexing Tournament
If he was working with the judge,
then there's no way he
would've lost to any opponent.
If that's true, that means
Master Okabe has motive.
But why would he do something
now after seven years?
No, that's not possible.
What?
Chicken Sexer
Master Okabe
The Truth About His Retirement
After the contest, Master Okabe
made a fuss about unfair judging,
but his actions earned him
a negative reputation in the industry,
and he ended up leaving the public eye.
Six months later, Okabe-san killed himself.
Suspect in Serial Murder Case Arrested
Chicken Sexer Kills Himself?
No...
Then that means we're back to square one.
That's not true.
Huh?
There's someone who's been lying
to us this whole time.
Lying? You mean President Kusano?
Not him.
Huh? What are you trying to say?
People are normally under
a lot of stress when they lie.
Crossing Arms
The actions and defensive posture
they unconsciously take when lying
Looking Away
can be a sign of their dishonesty.
Re-crossing Legs
Defensive posture?
That's what Shinichi-niichan
told me the other day.
Shinichi did?
Yeah, so I confirmed for myself
that there was someone hiding their
vulnerable neck while they were lying.
That's right. The culprit is...
Hirasawa Mamiko-san.
The number you are trying to reach
is either outside the service area or—
Damn. He's not answering.
He should still be at the office.
Let's search the area.
Wait, Conan-kun.
You're going to get what you deserve.
Dad, isn't this Nanba-san's phone?
This isn't good.
It was in that inconspicuous
field over there.
Sounds like we can assume he was
dragged off by Hirasawa-san.
But where?
We won't find him in a random search.
We should contact the police
and have them look for his car.
But mister, won't that take a long time?
Then what are we supposed to do?
I wonder what Hirasawa-san plans
to do to Nanba-san.
If she bothered to kidnap him,
then she's probably taken him
someplace secluded.
She said she'd only joined
the company recently.
If she doesn't know the area,
then she'll take him someplace
that means something to her.
Which means...
Wow, while listening to your
reasoning, I had an epiphany.
What?
Maybe it's this place.
This is it.
Yeah, the place where everything started.
Authorized Personnel Only
It's where the national chick sexing
tournament finals were held seven years ago.
Hold it right there!
Stop what you're doing, Hirasawa-san.
Don't throw your life away for revenge.
Don't come any closer.
I'm impressed, detective.
How did you know I'd be here?
How? Uh, actually...
I knew you'd be here because...
Dad?
How, how?
Because this is where it all started
and where your father chose death.
That man ruined your life.
Your father was set up and
killed himself in his despair.
You were apparently sent
to an orphanage after that.
That's right, your former name is Okabe.
You're the beloved daughter
of Master Okabe Yuji.
How did you figure that out?
I was tipped off by your expression
when you described a chicken sexer's hands.
When I saw your expression,
I thought you must have some
connection to chicken sexers.
Also, only one of your hands was chapped.
Steroid Cream
There was hand and
steroid cream on your desk.
And immediately after our conversation,
Nanba-san was attacked using
a chlorine-based detergent.
This hand gave it away?
Yes. Then there's the lies you told us.
You clearly hated Nanba-san.
Furthermore, you said you
didn't know your father.
You do exactly what your
father did when you lie.
So I had someone look into it.
After entering the orphanage, you
were adopted by the Hirasawa family.
But why did she need to get a job
at Nanba-san's company?
Because she wanted to see for herself
if Nanba-san engaged in match fixing.
Am I wrong?
That's right. I went to eat with him.
When I presented him with an opportunity
after he'd had something to drink,
he started spilling his guts to me.
So...
You're asking if I was trying to kill him?
No, you haven't plotted to kill him.
When you threw the ball at him,
burned him with the magnifying glass,
tampered with the phone,
and tried to throw detergent on him today...
All those crimes targeted Nanba-san's hands.
Why would she do that?
Because a chicken sexer's hands
are everything to them.
The job requires a delicate touch
and subtle movements of the fingertips.
If an injury to his arm left him
with the slightest aftereffects,
it would end his chicken sexing career.
No...
That's right.
I was going to take everything from him,
just like he took everything from my father.
Don't do this. Doing this wouldn't
make your father happy.
Nanba-san and Kusano-san's
corruption will come to light
if the tournament footage is analyzed.
I guarantee it.
It's too late now.
That's not true.
Leave me alone! He's going to
get what he deserves!
Stop.
Aren't you going to become
a chicken sexer, too?
A truly great chicken sexer
like your dad was.
Up you go.
Your hands are so pretty.
Your hands are pretty, too.
Which means you'll be a chicken
sexer in the future, too.
Yeah. I'm gonna be a chicken sexer, too.
The best in Japan.
No, the best in the world.
Then I'll be the best in the universe.
No...
The police arrived shortly afterwards
to take Hirasawa-san away.
72nd National Chicken Sexing Tournament
With help from Nakamura-san
and Kitazawa-san,
Nanba and Kusano's evildoing
was brought to light.
Nanba was stripped of his title
and chicken sexing license,
and Kusano was dismissed
from his job as president.
After exposing each other's evil deeds,
Kusano Eggs
they were arrested for
embezzlement and tax evasion.
What? It's a guinea pig sexer this time?
I've never heard of that.
Petting Area
Are you sure it's not a request
from a caretaker?
Yup.
They want me to find a guinea pig
that got mixed into this bunch.
Lost Guinea Pig
Mofuo 2 Years Old
His name is apparently Mofuo-chan.
Petting Area
Out of all of these...
You're looking for one specific guinea pig?
Hey, wait!
Petting Area
Let's become professional
guinea pig sexers together.
Hey!
I'm sure the three of us can do it.
Don't leave and go home without me.
Hey!
Episode Preview
This is Kazama Joji-san.
I met him at a matchmaking party.
He's my boyfriend.
Enough already.
Huh?
This guy is definitely a gold-digger.
I'm his daughter Yuki.
I think my father was probably afraid.
The Dreamy-Eyed Woman's Last Shot at Love
The next episode of Conan is
"The Dreamy-Eyed Woman's Last Shot at Love!"
Limousine
Next Conan's hint!
A limousine!
Have you found Mofuo-chan?
Don't miss the next episode.
I'm sure I will eventually
as long as I keep sleeping.
There's no way you'll find him while asleep.