DETECTIVE CONAN EPISODE 1064 "The
Dreamy-Eyed Woman's Last Shot at Love"
[op]
[ed]
There's definitely something
wrong with that old woman.
You think so?
Look around you, Ran.
This is the new date spot
everyone's talking about.
All the people around us are young couples.
There's clearly something odd going on here.
It's not like we're a couple.
Maybe she's senile and got lost.
Kamogawa Haru (78)
I'm gonna go talk to her.
Wait, Sonoko.
Are you all right, ma'am?
Sorry. Have you been waiting long?
No, not at all.
Oh, so you're meeting your son.
That's great.
We were worried you might be sen—
We thought you might not be feeling well.
Oh, my. Is that so?
Anyway, your son seems awfully gaudy.
Hey, Sonoko.
Seriously?
Oh, this isn't my son.
This is Kazama Joji-san.
Kazama Joji (44)
Haru's Boyfriend
I met him at a matchmaking party.
He's my boyfriend.
What?
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
An old lady's last shot at love
makes her heart burn with passion
as she is encircled by lies and love!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Dreamy-Eyed Woman's Last Shot at Love
"The Dreamy-Eyed Woman's Last Shot at Love!"
Like this, darling?
Perfect, honey.
Say cheese.
Incredible.
Modern phones can even
take pictures these days?
Amazing. I'm impressed.
They can do more than take pictures.
Could I get this, please?
I'd like to pay using this.
If you could tap here, please.
My, you can even pay for things?
Now try this on.
Hey, you.
See? I knew it'd look great on you.
Joji...
Enough already.
Huh?
How could you trick an old lady who
doesn't even know what smartphones are?
Don't, Sonoko.
Am I wrong?
Look at how she's dressed.
Her whole outfit is high-quality
designer products.
She must be pretty wealthy.
Could you please call me
Haru-san instead of "old lady?"
In any case...
This guy is definitely a gold-digger.
Poor girl.
You must be lonely because
your boyfriend ignores you.
What?
I see. So she's jealous of us.
H-He doesn't ignore me!
I mean, Makoto-san hasn't been back in
forever because he's off training...
And he writes astonishingly curt replies,
even when I send him really
long messages, but...
Poor girl. I thought so.
That's not the point.
I really am worried about
you, old—Haru-san!
What?
He's obviously going to fleece you
for a ton of money for his
"sick daughter" or whatever!
Huh?
What's wrong, Joji?
Kazama Yuki (23)
Joji's Daughter
I'm his daughter Yuki.
He really did have...
...a sick daughter.
Kazama Yuki-sama
Yuki has a one-in-a-million heart condition.
Entrance Ceremony
We're barely keeping her condition stable
by providing her with cutting-edge treatment.
I had no idea.
Why didn't you tell me?
I was going to tell you eventually,
but I didn't know how to bring it up.
I'm sorry, honey.
I think my father was probably afraid.
Until now, he's has lost numerous girlfriends,
who left him after they found out about me.
But don't worry about me.
I just want my father to be happy.
Yuki...
Don't think so poorly of me.
Honey...
I'm not leaving you over that.
I'll make all of us happy.
Haru-san...
So don't cry anymore.
I won't. Thank you.
I'm sorry I doubted you!
Jeez, Sonoko. You're crying
harder than everyone else.
I can't let you pay her medical bills.
That's not why I had you meet my daughter.
I once had someone I wanted to save,
but I wasn't able to.
I've always regretted that.
Is that a memento of that person?
Please. Let me do this, for me.
Now that that's decided, good
deeds should be done quickly.
Oh, is something the matter?
No, it's nothing.
I'm impressed.
She really was wealthy.
That's one crazy car.
Take care, everyone.
I was kind of moved by all of that.
Shall we head home, too?
Something's not right.
Ow, ow, ow.
Ugh, I got a blister.
Well, they are new. Are you okay?
That's it!
Huh? Conan-kun?
I'm too late.
What is this?
What's going on here?
I didn't see any shoes or slippers
you'd expect to find on the floor.
Yuki-san was wearing shoes in bed,
so she could flee right
away if she was found out.
You mean Yuki-san isn't...
Yeah.
She's not his sick daughter.
She's an impostor.
What?
Yuki-san?
That's Yuki-san!
What?
Hold it right there!
Calculated.
Nice throw.
Joji is primarily responsible.
He's made a ton of money
using similar methods.
Which must mean Joji-san
is pretty wealthy, too.
What? Yes.
More importantly, we need to
let Haru-san know right away.
But how?
She doesn't even have a phone.
They can't have gone too far.
That car would stand out around here.
I'm sure a bunch of people have seen it.
We'll find them if we follow their stories.
I told that woman to message
me once she was out of there.
Is something the matter?
No.
You look handsome when
you're discontent, too.
Thank you.
Just to be safe, maybe I
should speed things up.
It sure is hot.
I'm sorry.
Perhaps it's my age, but I get cold easily.
I'll take your coat.
That's all right, honey.
Thank you.
This is why I can't stand old women.
No, calm down. I need to
naturally bring it up.
Anyway, honey, when can you give
me money for the medical bills?
Huh? Is that...?
It's a check.
I'm sure it seems analog to you,
but this is what I'm used to.
Will you forgive me?
Of course. Don't worry about it.
Here. Is this enough?
Check
Teito Bank Co., Ltd.
Amount
Th-This much?!
Well? Is that enough, darling?
Of course, honey.
Ones, tens, hundreds,
thousands, ten thousands,
hundred thousands, millions,
ten millions, hundred millions...
Teito Bank
Go on, darling. Go cash that check.
I'll be waiting here.
I can't believe she gave me 300 million.
Lonely old women make great marks.
Haru-san!
What? Who are you kids?
Sorry, wrong car.
One moment, please.
300 million, huh?
How am I gonna spend all of that?
How rude.
Ugh, no. Where did we go wrong?
It's probably too late by now.
Don't give up yet.
Haru-san said "good deeds
should be done quickly."
She's probably planning to
give him a lot of money,
which means they most likely headed to...
A bank!
But which bank?
Let's split up and check them out.
You're right.
Why do I still feel like
something's not right?
These glasses block 80% of blue light
produced by computers and phones
I see. So that's how it is.
They're taking a while.
I guess it takes time to get
300 million in cash ready.
Ah, they're here.
Come in!
Uh... Oh, right.
I see.
It takes a lot of people
to carry 300 million.
Huh? What?
Wait, what? Why?
I knew you'd be here.
Great. I've been waiting for you.
What do you mean?
What are you doing here?
I'm here to stop you from
escaping, obviously.
Don't worry. Joji-san was arrested,
thanks to a tip from someone.
You gave Joji-san a fake check, didn't you?
What are you trying to say?
That bag contains the money you
conned from Joji-san, doesn't it?
Oh, please.
How would an old woman like me—
I thought it was strange.
Remember?
Your car was awfully hot inside.
That was probably so Joji-san
would remove his coat,
allowing you to take his phone.
That way you could hack into his
bank accounts tied to his phone.
Then you withdrew money
from Joji-san's accounts.
Haru-san, you weren't being fooled.
You were fooling him.
Isn't that right, Haru-san?
You must be joking.
I don't even know what smartphones are.
I couldn't pull off a high-tech—
Those reading glasses block
blue light, don't they?
People who use digital
devices often wear those.
Then when you were looking
at my face earlier...
Yeah, I thought something was odd.
Also, the police are already outside.
How did you know we'd come here?
Because that car stands out
too much to make a getaway.
I knew you'd swap cars.
And where can you inconspicuously
park an empty car
and change cars without attracting attention?
An underground parking
garage is the perfect spot.
In this area, there are
three underground garages.
But one is at that hospital, and one
is across from the police station.
That just leaves this one.
Who are you?
Edogawa Conan.
I'm a detective.
A detective.
You were just doing as I said, got it?
Six months ago my friend
passed away and left me this.
She was a kind person.
And it was Joji who tricked my friend
and took everything from her.
My friend died after that.
So you were getting revenge.
"An eye for an eye, a scam for a scam."
I studied so much to prepare for this,
like how to scam someone and how to
use a computer for the first time.
What?
Haru-san, is this your first scam?
Oh, please.
Did you think I was a veteran con artist?
You mean...
Of course this is my first crime.
Until now, I'd never even run a red light.
But at some point, I started
having so much fun.
I practically forgot I was
doing this for revenge.
I probably fell in love
with the joy of tricking someone with a scam.
But I found love too late.
When you said the police were outside...
Sorry. I was bluffing to
keep you from leaving.
In other words, I lied.
You tricked me?
Sounds like you've got some potential.
If you ever get tired of being a detective,
you should become a con artist.
I'm sure you'd be good at it.
I'll never get tired of it.
After all, I'm in love
with being a detective.
I'm sorry I ended up fooling you girls, too.
By the way, what's going to happen
to the money I took from Joji?
The officer said it would probably
be returned to Joji's victims.
I see.
That's good.
Maybe that's actually what Haru-san wanted.
I wonder.
Maybe she always wanted
to try scamming someone.
She might be right.
But don't you think it's nice
that you can fall in love
with something no matter how old you are?
It makes me kind of excited to get older.
Try not to fall in love
with anything questionable.
Episode Preview
You're familiar with Nishiwaki Kae-san
who lives on the first floor, aren't you?
I adored my sister, but she was hit by a car.
There are too many other
things pointing to him,
including the items left at the scene.
Could it be?
Wouldn't that mean they saw something?
Detectives Don't Sleep
The next episode of Conan
is "Detectives Don't Sleep!"
Thursday
Next Conan's hint!
Thursday!
All done!
Don't miss the next episode.
Done with what?
My list of things I want
to do when I turn 100.
How optimistic of you.