[eyecatch]
DETECTIVE CONAN EPISODE 1065
"Detectives Don't Sleep"
[op]
[ed]
Coffee Poirot
It was a Thursday morning
when classes were canceled.
Mori Detective Agency
Someone occasionally sneaks into
my apartment while I'm at work.
Nishiwaki Kae (24)
Office Worker
And they steal something every time?
No, it's the opposite.
Huh?
It started about a month ago.
When I came back from work...
What is this?
The item that wasn't there
when I left that morning...
Masakariya
was a box of Masakariya chocolates.
The next time it happened was the week after.
It was a Skeleton V album.
The third time it was a bouquet of roses.
They're all things I love.
So rather than sneaking into your
apartment to steal something...
They're leaving behind what seem to be gifts.
I understand what you want from me,
but have you contacted the police?
I didn't think they'd believe
such a strange story.
Not only is it strange, but it's also creepy.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
The client's so anxious she can't sleep!
Can he solve the case without falling asleep?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Detectives Don't Sleep
"Detectives Don't Sleep!"
Since you're locking the door when you leave,
whoever it is must have a spare key.
Have you thought about changing your locks?
I was going to,
but then I remembered you
and thought I'd ask for your help first.
If they're leaving gifts,
perhaps they're trying to tell you
that you have a secret admirer.
Can you think of anyone like that?
No, not at all.
What's this suitcase?
It's not mine, and this
wasn't here when I left.
If there's a ribbon on it...
Then it must be the fourth gift from
whoever's sneaking into your apartment.
It's pretty heavy. What did
they give you this time?
Hup.
Kusakabe Ryuko (31)
Kae's Boss
What's my manager doing in there?!
That's my manager Kusakabe Ryuko.
She's my direct superior at my job.
What?
So you didn't like Kusakabe-san
because she was a strict boss?
Honestly, I even hated her a little.
I'm telling you, Inspector, this is
another gift for Nishiwaki Kae-san.
The sender got rid of the
person their beloved hated.
I never asked for this!
But why did they bother
to bring the body here?
Because they thought it would please Kae-san.
Nobody enjoys receiving a dead body.
Inspector Megure.
The victim died immediately when she was
struck on the head with a blunt object.
We believe she died around 1AM last night.
She was stuffed inside the suitcase
immediately following her death.
I see.
Inspector.
A listening device, huh?
That must be how they
learned your preferences,
and that you hated Kusakabe-san.
Can you think of any clues that would
help us determine their identity?
They always snuck into
my apartment on Thursday.
It's Thursday today, too.
Maybe they're an office worker
and Thursday is their day off.
Anything else?
I'm not sure...
In the middle of the night last night?
It was apparently around 2AM.
When she got up to use the bathroom
and was having a cigarette,
she saw someone carrying
into this apartment building
a large suitcase they presumably
had loaded into a car.
It must be that suitcase.
But it wasn't brought into
my room during the night.
It's not mutually exclusive.
They brought it to this apartment building
with the intention of waiting until you
left today to sneak into your room.
They temporarily hid it in
the building—but where?
They'd have to be careful
about where they hid it.
If someone saw it and reported a
suspicious suitcase, they'd be screwed.
Is there such a thing as a
totally secure hiding place?
What about inside their own apartment unit?
Which means they're a
resident of this building?
It's certainly possible.
Then maybe it's them.
I once dropped my apartment
keys about a month ago.
I wondered where I'd lost them and came home.
Bulletin Board
One of the residents must have found it.
I was grateful at the time.
It's possible whoever found
her keys made a spare.
The question is who are they
and how will we find them.
Maybe Kinoshita-san saw them.
She's someone who often
hangs out at the entrance.
Oh, it was Tsukumo-san who
lives on the third floor
Kinoshita Kino (70)
Resident of Kae's Apartment Building
who left the key on the bulletin board.
What?
What is it?
I know him.
He looks at me meaningfully.
Tsukumo Hisashi (28)
Resident of Kae's Apartment Building
Honestly, it creeps me out.
He's probably been secretly in
love with Kae-san for some time.
He started sneaking into her apartment when
he happened to find her key, and then...
It's too soon to say for certain,
but we should try to meet him soon.
Tsukumo-san's probably home.
I just saw him.
Thursday is my day off.
You found a key about a
month ago, didn't you?
Yes, that did happen.
Do you recall creating a copy
of the key at that time?
What?
Why would I do that?
You're familiar with Nishiwaki Kae-san
who lives on the first floor, aren't you?
What do the police want with me, anyway?
We'd appreciate your assistance
with an investigation.
Tsukumo-san, where were
you last night around 1AM?
In other words, you suspect me.
It's just like he said?
What?
Yes.
Between midnight and just after 2AM,
he was drinking at that bar by the station.
He has an alibi?
It seems like Kae-san assumed
Tsukumo-san was the culprit.
Anyone would.
Inspector, there isn't anyone else who
has as many clues pointing to him.
But not only is there no physical evidence,
but he has an alibi for the
time the crime took place.
It's me.
I'll be right there.
We've determined where she was killed.
In Hidora City, where the victim was from.
Hidora Park
On nights before her day off, Kusakabe
Ryuko-san often stayed out late drinking.
As usual, last night she
took the last train home.
While cutting through this
park on her way home...
She was attacked by the culprit.
Most likely.
This was found here.
Forensics determined that the blood
and hair on it was Kusakabe-san's.
What's that?
Since it was found here,
we examined it and discovered the
fingerprints of someone with a record of theft.
His name is Tsukumo Hisashi.
Tsukumo?
If my fingerprints are on that
lighter, then I must've used it.
Someone must've picked it up
after I dropped or threw it away.
After all, I've never been to Hidora City.
More importantly, wasn't my alibi airtight?
We found his lighter at the
crime scene. He must be guilty.
In other words, he faked his alibi.
And we should be able to take it apart.
Indeed.
His lighter was at the crime scene,
and it's possible he used
a trick to fake his alibi,
but something doesn't feel right.
What doesn't feel right?
I wonder.
Jeez.
I promise I'll expose the trick
he used to fake his alibi.
Okay.
I wonder what's bothering me.
Since Tsukumo-san's a regular,
it's hard to believe the employees
could've made a mistake.
I'm telling you, he used a trick.
What kind of trick, though?
What do you mean by trick?
What are you investigating? I'm curious.
So that's why you've been
secretly watching us.
You noticed?
Tell me, Mori-san. Come on.
I'm dealing with a difficult case
and don't have time for you.
But I helped you!
She's scary.
So Kae-san suspected Tsukumo-san
because not only did he find her key,
but Thursday is his day off.
That's right.
We found out about his day off later, though.
That's not right.
I already knew Tsukumo-san has Thursdays off,
and I've told Kae-san about it.
Then Kae-san knew.
Apparently so.
Those two must be connected in some way.
Tsukumo-san once said seeing Kae-san
reminds him of his sister and saddens him.
What do you suppose that means?
How should I know?
But he doesn't seem like a bad guy to me.
In any case, let's head
back to the apartment.
You're still lurking around here?
It'd be quickest to ask him directly.
What kind of trick did you
use to fake your alibi?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Nobody's going to answer that question.
More importantly...
Hey, Tsukumo-san.
Why does looking at Nishiwaki
Kae-san remind you of your sister?
Kinoshita-san told us about it.
That Nishiwaki woman looks a
little like my younger sister
who passed away when were little.
They have similar eyes and the
same mole beneath them, too.
I adored my sister, but she was hit by a car.
Forget your story. Tell me
about the trick you used!
Try figuring it out.
You're a great detective, aren't you?
Crap.
I'm going to be late for
the limited-time sale.
Oh, I'll figure it out, all right.
If that's true,
then he wasn't looking at Kae-san
meaningfully because he's in love with her.
That casts doubt on one of
the reasons we suspected him.
There are too many other
things pointing to him,
including the items left at the scene.
That's it!
That's what was bothering me.
But what does it mean?
We're heading back to the apartment.
Could it be?
Wouldn't that mean he saw something?
Hey, the apartment is this way.
When I picked up the key?
Yeah.
What time was it when you stuck it on
the bulletin board in the entrance?
It was when I came back from work,
so it must've been around six in the evening.
Thanks.
What time do I come back from work?
He told me to come ask you about it.
Kae-san said she comes back
from work around six every day.
Tsukumo-san stuck the key on the
bulletin board around the same time.
So, what?
I'm trying to figure out the
trick he used over here.
Stop bothering me.
I'm not getting through to him.
Well, no matter.
Hello, Inspector. It's Mori.
Catch.
If you've figured it all out,
then you must know the trick he used.
What?
Inspector, you asked me to meet you here.
Crap.
Sorry.
Thank you.
What's the matter, Mori-kun?
Quit putting on airs and
solve the case already.
I'm not putting on airs.
This isn't good.
Maybe we should have this
conversation another time.
When he invited us here?
Did I?
I don't remember that, but if I did, then...
He doesn't seem well.
It's a little odd that I don't
feel drowsy like I normally do,
but I have to get started.
The trick he used to fake his alibi was...
You're not sleeping today?
I can do it without sleeping.
You've got an identical twin brother.
That's news to me.
Then you hired your doppelgänger
to stand in for you.
I was drinking with my best friend.
He'd know immediately if I used a substitute.
I can't think of anything else.
I knew this would happen.
Are you sure you don't have to sleep?
Ow, ow!
I wanna see the Sleeping Kogoro!
Go to sleep!
Shut up! I don't feel sleepy today!
I guess there's no point in doing that.
What should I do?
Right, I just have to lead him to the truth.
If a great detective like
him can't figure it out,
then maybe he didn't use a trick.
That would be what that means.
Which means Tsukumo-san
really does have an alibi.
So you're innocent.
I knew it.
No way.
So why was his lighter at the crime scene?
Because he was framed by the true culprit.
The true culprit?
Oh, right.
Didn't you say there were too many
clues pointing to Tsukumo-san?
That's right.
I already knew by that point.
Wait a minute, Mori-kun.
The culprit needed a spare key to bring
that suitcase into her apartment.
How did the true culprit get that?
Well, uh...
Did the culprit really use a spare key?
Nobody can get into a
room without a spare key.
Quit making up nonsense and stay out of this.
He's not getting it.
This is annoying and a lot of work.
Then I'll try a different angle.
By the way, you said something
about two birds with one stone,
but what did you mean by that?
Did I say that?
Of course.
After all, he didn't say that.
Two birds with one stone...
Come on, figure it out.
Come to think of it, earlier this kid said...
Kae-san said she comes back
from work around six every day.
Tsukumo-san stuck the key on the
bulletin board around the same time.
So that's how it is!
That would explain everything.
We should be focusing our
attention on only two things.
Who benefits from Kusakabe Ryuko-san's death,
and who benefits from framing Tsukumo-kun?
When it comes to who found
the two of them disagreeable,
it truly is two birds with one stone.
Nishiwaki Kae-san, you're the true culprit!
Wait a minute.
What do you mean, she did it?
You wanted to kill the boss you hated.
But naturally, you didn't want to get caught.
While trying to come up with a plan,
you happened to lose your keys.
The moment you learned they
were found by Tsukumo-kun,
whom you also found unpleasant,
you came up with this plan.
You'd kill Kusakabe-san and frame
Tsukumo-kun for her murder.
Naturally, Tsukumo-kun has
no motive to kill her,
but you just needed to fake one.
You would make us believe he killed the
boss you hated because he loved you.
In other words, you used his
numerous break-ins against him.
I didn't break into anyone's apartment.
What he's trying to say is that's what
the culprit wanted us to believe.
No one actually snuck into
her apartment every Thursday.
That's right!
That was a lie told in order to frame you.
The culprit needed a spare key
to sneak into her apartment,
and you were the only one who
had the opportunity to make one.
She knew Kinoshita-san's
testimony would support that.
You were the one who found it.
She even bugged her own apartment to
make us believe someone was breaking in.
Last night she carried out her plan.
She knew Kusakabe-san had a habit of coming
home late on nights before her days off,
so she waited for her.
She killed her, stuffed her in the suitcase,
and left Tsukumo-kun's lighter that
she'd acquired beforehand at the scene.
She brought the suitcase into her apartment
and tied a ribbon on it
so it'd look like a gift.
Her one miscalculation was assuming
Tsukumo-san wouldn't have an alibi
for the middle of the night when he did.
He has an alibi?
But because we insisted his alibi was fake,
she hoped we'd scrape something together.
Isn't that right?
Do you have any proof that I did it?
Not right now.
But if we search your car,
I'm sure we'll find signs that you
used it to transport that suitcase.
I despised you.
You apparently fell in love
at first sight with me,
but how dare someone as gloomy
as you develop feelings for me.
What Kusakabe did was even worse.
You're so useless and incompetent.
Take her away.
That was perfect.
M-Mister?
I'm all out of steam.
I'm exhausted, too.
That was even more work than usual.
Coffee Poirot
Yes, hello.
Mori Detective Agency
Actually, I'm not longer the Sleeping Kogoro.
I've decided to solve cases without sleeping.
It's all right. I've already
managed to solve a case.
Give me a break.
It's way more work when you don't sleep.
Episode Preview
Thank you for waiting.
It's time for the bride
to make her appearance.
Making you drink water is part of my job.
Do you have business with me?
I actually hired a detective
to conduct an investigation.
There were so many, I have no idea.
They must've pointed them!
You're the only one who
could've seen what was inside.
'Til Death Do Us Part
The next episode of Conan
is "'Til Death Do Us Part!"
Schedule
Next Conan's hint!
A schedule!
Don't miss the next episode.
A detective who doesn't sleep, huh?
How strange.
No, that's normal.