[eyecatch]
DETECTIVE CONAN EPISODE 1066
"'Til Death Do Us Part"
[op]
[ed]
Hey!
That was a cute incident,
but let's pull ourselves together
and proceed with the ceremony.
Yokoyama Shinpo (28)
Office Worker
Thank you for waiting.
It's time for the bride
to make her appearance.
Imamura Sayoko (24)
Housekeeper
I can't breathe!
What?
Sayoko?
Sayoko! Sayoko!
Calm down, Shinpo.
Sir, call an ambulance.
Got it.
It's no use. She's dead.
The time is 13:22.
Sayoko...
Why?
Nagashima Hiroko (23)
Wedding Planner
Why did she have to die now?
Kawasu Alex Harutoshi (58)
Priest
It's too soon. She's too young.
Perfect.
Yamada Gakuto (27)
Officer Worker
In that case, me, too.
They got what they deserved.
Mizuguchi Naho (23)
Office Worker
If anything, this should've happened sooner.
If only I'd noticed sooner.
Yokoyama Nobuteru (57)
Executive
I knew it. This marriage was cursed.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
During the highlight of a happy day,
why did their vows disappear?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
'Til Death Do Us Part
"'Til Death Do Us Part!"
So, how did you end up at the
scene of the murder this time?
I met the groom's father at a bar I frequent.
He ended up inviting you to the wedding
because you were having so much fun.
And yet another incident
occurred at the ceremony.
Something always seems
to happen around you.
Yeah, sorry.
I don't see any obvious injuries.
The victim is Imamura
Sayoko-san, 24 years old.
She was a housekeeper.
As you all witnessed, her time
of death was 13:22 today.
According to forensics, the
cause of death is poisoning.
What kind of poison was the bride given?
Matter from poisonous mushrooms
were found inside her body.
Ingesting even a small amount paralyzes your
entire body and causes death within an hour.
An hour?
Then anyone who gave her something
to eat or drink is a suspect.
Wedding Party Waiting Room
This is Nagashima Hiroko-san,
the wedding planner.
You apparently gave
Imamura-san water to drink.
Supporting the bride is my job.
Making her drink water is part of my job.
I stuck a straw in a bottle so
her makeup wouldn't be ruined
and had her take frequent sips of water.
We heard a lot of demands were made of
you while preparing for this wedding.
I'll admit they were such difficult
clients I wanted to kill them.
They planned their schedule down to the
minute and kept trying to squeeze in everything.
Just look at this. There isn't
even room to take a breather.
13:25 Bride's Entrance
13:30 Scripture Reading
13:40 Vows Exchanged
13:45 Kiss
13:50 Ring Dog's Entrance
The day after criticizing the planned
reception and changing the color of the napkins,
I was told to change it back.
Being self-centered came naturally to her.
When you said you wanted to kill her...
But I didn't do it.
That would ruin the wedding
ceremony I put together.
Although, ultimately, it was ruined anyway.
You said, "Why now?" What
did you mean by that?
A spectacular fireworks display was
planned for after the bride's entrance.
Getting that authorized was a lot of work.
By the way, whose dog was it
that interrupted the ceremony?
That was Yokoyama-san's dog.
It was supposed to be the ring dog.
Ring dog?
They carry the wedding rings.
These days some couples have a dog do it.
Do you have business with me?
This is Yamada Gakuto-san.
He's a friend of the groom.
They work at the same company.
You went to the bride's room
just before the ceremony began.
What did you do there?
I'm both the groom's friend
and Sayoko's friend.
I went to congratulate her personally.
Did you give her anything to eat?
No, nothing.
But I did give her something to drink.
From this.
That's liquor, isn't it?
That's right. I always carry this with me.
She asked for a drink to pick her up.
Could we examine that flask?
Yeah, of course.
Hey, mister.
When the bride collapsed,
you said, "Perfect."
What did you mean by that?
You were listening?
What did you mean?
It's not something we should
discuss in front of children,
but Sayoko and I were...
Conan-kun, my pen ran out of ink.
Could you borrow one from
someone in the hall?
Yeah, sure. I'll be back.
Oh, uh... Please continue.
Sure.
Don't tell Shinpo, but she and I were dating.
I knew she was getting married.
So she was two-timing.
She's the two-timer.
I said it was perfect because
now that she was gone,
I was free to find a new love.
Is this guy for real?
This is Yokoyama Nobuteru-san,
the groom's father.
My deepest sympathies.
Unbelievable. How did this happen?
Before the ceremony, you
went to the bride's room.
Yes.
I heard her parents weren't around,
so I thought I could be there
for her in place of her family.
I heard she loved chocolate,
so I brought her some.
I wish I could eat them
now, but I put my nails on.
Could you feed me, Dad?
But...
Oh, come on. We're father and daughter.
Ah.
Her cause of death was poisoning.
You can't be serious.
I didn't poison the chocolates.
We're still just talking to everyone.
Don't worry about it.
Hey, mister.
You said, "If only I noticed sooner."
"I knew it. This marriage was cursed."
You were listening?
I actually hired a detective
to conduct an investigation,
and the results weren't very good.
What do you mean?
Sayoko-san had quite a history
with men since she was in school.
I told my son about it,
but he wouldn't listen.
They say love is blind.
I didn't do it.
Mizuguchi-san, when the bride collapsed,
you said, "They got what they deserved.
This should've happened sooner."
Sayoko and I had been friends since school,
but she'd been jumping from one
man to the next since then.
I said that because I knew something
terrible would happen to her eventually.
Can you think of anyone who may
have held a grudge against her?
There are so many, I have no idea.
Right?
I saw the groom's father feeding
chocolate to the bride.
The door happened to be open when
I passed by the bride's room.
I saw what was going on inside.
What time did you see them?
I believe it was around 12:45.
Nagashima-san last had
her drink water at 12:50.
But since she was frequently hydrating,
it'll be difficult to determine
exactly when that happened.
She drank Yamada-san's liquor around 12:20.
I believe you said the poison...
According to forensics, the poison comes
into effect within an hour and kills the victim.
It was the liquor that she
drank an hour earlier.
It's possible, but Yamada-san
willingly handed over his flask.
Hey, Father.
What is it?
You said something when the bride collapsed.
I meant exactly what I said.
She was too young to die.
Yeah, you're right.
I've uploaded the data.
Takagi-san, we have the
results from forensics.
What are they?
They found nothing in the
plastic bottle and flask.
But mushroom poison was
found in the chocolates.
B-But...
Why did you give the bride chocolates?
W-Well,
because Sayoko-san said she loved Mativa
chocolates during the wedding rehearsal.
I bought chocolates at a department
store and gave them to her.
Why was there poison in chocolates
you bought from a department store?
Don't ask me.
Does this settle it, then?
Hold on.
What is it, kid?
Would he really poison the chocolates he
gave her when he knew he'd be suspected?
If the groom's father was
against the marriage,
he would've found another way to oppose it.
Looks like we'll have to keep investigating.
This was the act of someone who
had a grudge against the victim.
I'm going to the bathroom.
Wedding Party Waiting Room
This is the bride's room.
Left of the bride's room is an elevator hall.
Past that is the guest waiting room.
Guest Waiting Room
There's nobody here.
Poor dog. You're all alone.
What's this?
The leash has been cut.
Wedding Party Waiting Room
That must be it.
Hey, miss.
Do you need something?
Can I see your ceremony schedule?
Sure. Here.
Thanks.
13:25 Bride's Entrance
13:30 Scripture Reading
13:40 Vows Exchanged
13:45 Kiss
13:50 Ring Dog's Entrance
Let's see...
I knew it.
The ceremony started at a different time
from what's listed on this schedule.
Why is that?
I know.
One of the groom's shoes went
missing right before the ceremony.
It was ultimately found in the bathroom,
but it delayed the start by five minutes.
Huh.
That's not much of a reaction.
You were ready by early this morning, right?
I got here at six this morning.
I had so much to do, I had
no idea what was going on.
Anyway, between the dog running away
and someone's shoe going missing,
nothing went according
to plan at this wedding.
The ceremony was interrupted, too.
The key to solving this case
is that precise schedule.
I see. So that's how it is.
I've figured it out. They're the culprit.
Detective Takagi,
Kogoro-no-ojisan wanted you
to look into something.
Mori-san, we've gathered the
wedding party as you requested.
What? I never said—
I guess I must've said that.
So this is the Sleeping Kogoro.
I've never seen this before.
The key element in this case
is the culprit's powerful thirst for revenge
against the victim Imamura Sayoko-san.
A murder on the day of someone's
wedding is shocking enough on its own,
but the culprit intended to take her life
at the most dramatic moment possible,
probably when the couple kissed.
Is that even possible?
In fact, they failed.
However, the culprit had calculated
backwards so that would happen.
So that's why they used
the poisonous mushroom.
Yes.
Consuming even a small amount
of the poisonous mushroom
used in this case causes
death within an hour.
So that's how it is.
A fall from the height of happiness
is the perfect revenge.
Isn't that right, Kawasu Alex Harutoshi-san?
What?
No way. The priest?
I don't know what you're talking about.
But you're the only person who
knew about the Mativa chocolates
and could've swapped out their contents.
Nobuteru-san learned the bride liked
chocolates during the wedding rehearsal.
You were at the rehearsal
as well, weren't you?
In that case, Nagashima-san the
wedding planner was there as well.
Nobuteru-san, when did you
purchase the chocolates?
I bought them today at a department
store in Beika City before coming here.
I see.
He knew the brand, but in order to
purchase the exact same chocolates,
he needed to see the moment you bought them.
So you followed Nobuteru-san.
After watching Nobuteru-san
buy the chocolates,
you purchased the exact same product.
You poisoned the chocolates
using the poison you brought
and waited for an opportunity to
swap yours with Nobuteru-san's.
Then you watched Nobuteru-san
feed the chocolate to the bride
and attended the ceremony.
Isn't that right?
Take a look at this.
Conan.
Here.
The wedding schedule?
It really is amazing.
It's such a precise schedule.
The victim ate the chocolate at 12:45.
The groom lost his shoe and the
chihuahua interrupted the ceremony,
delaying the schedule by roughly ten minutes.
Which means if you add ten
minutes to this schedule,
one hour after when she consumed
the poison at 13:45...
That's when the couple kisses.
Kiss
Then the shoe was hidden by...
It was also Kawasu-san who manipulated the
leash so the dog would interrupt the ceremony.
By delaying the schedule
a little bit at a time,
he made it match up with when
the bride would collapse.
And why would I do that?
At Mori-san's instruction,
I looked into something.
You apparently had a son.
He attended the same
university as Sayoko-san.
Not only that, but your
son was dating Sayoko-san.
In his fourth year of university,
they had a terrible breakup.
Several months later, he
died in a traffic accident.
When you take into account the
testimony concerning the victim,
it's to easy imagine the difficult
time your son must have had.
That's an adequate reason to seek revenge.
You even looked into that?
I sensed the motive in this case
was a powerful desire for revenge.
Furthermore, you're the only person
who could have swapped the chocolates
and could've seen Nakajima-san's schedule.
I see.
So that's how it is.
And one more thing.
You still have some chocolates, don't you?
It's hard to imagine someone like
you would've thrown them away.
Kawasu-san, you've hidden them in what you
believe to be the safest hiding place.
You're a clergyman.
You must've been supremely
confident that your profession
would shield you from being searched.
After toying with my son and
driving him to his death,
that woman didn't even come to his funeral.
I couldn't allow that she-devil to happily
get married after the evil she committed.
I poisoned her so she'd die
during her happiest moment.
But she died before their kiss.
The poison was supposed to
take effect after an hour.
You said initially that it was too soon.
It's too soon.
She's too young.
You quickly added more to what you said,
but by "too soon," you meant
that she collapsed too soon.
When I realized what you meant,
I became certain you were the culprit.
I am amazed by how perceptive
you are, Sleeping Kogoro.
And thank you.
"Forgive us our sins, as we forgive
those who sin against us."
Don't!
Is he trying to kill himself?
Parents can't help
but to care about their kids...
If Ran ever gets married...
I'll probably cry.
You would?
Yeah.
While bawling my eyes out, I'll
beat the groom into a bloody pulp!
Another beer!
Ran!
I'm never letting you get married!
I'm never gonna be nobody's father-in-law!