During this time of year
when the city is full of cheer,
there's one place that's not...
Cheery Shopping With a Smile!
Bondo Shopping Center
This place is gloomy.
Cheery or not, that's got nothing to do
with how good these pickles taste.
Boss, I'll take two of my
usual malted miso pickles.
Cheery Vegetables
Boss?
Huh?
Are you asleep?
Cheery Vegetables
This is the busiest time
of day for merchants.
Oh, it's you, Mr. Detective.
I see. It's already that time of day, huh?
Cheery Vegetables
No wonder I'm so tired.
Liar!
You still haven't opened
these boxes of vegetables?
If there's anything you want,
you can open them yourselves.
Self-checkout is all the rage these days.
That's not the same thing.
Hey, kid. Could you put this out front?
I'll give you a discount.
Gladly!
Cheery Vegetables!!
He's so unmotivated.
This is why this place is so gloomy.
Hey, isn't it time to put this away?
Hello, shop owners of Bondo Shopping Center!
Madam Gaga
Shopping Center Producer
Thank you for waiting!
Godlike producer Madam Gaga has arrived
to bring your exhausted shopping
center the gift of cheer!
Godlike producer?
Madam Gaga?
Huh?
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
A mysterious Christmas gift
has arrived at the shopping center?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Shopping Center In Love
"The Shopping Center In Love!"
Mori Detective Agency
You agreed to referee a pro
wrestling event at a shopping center?
But why?
I didn't have a choice.
I go shopping there all the time.
We're talking about Bondo
Shopping Center, right?
You don't even go there once a month.
Y-Yeah, but giving them a hand regardless
i-is what you calling helping people, right?
It's a pro wrestling event, right?
And the participants are the shop owners.
You will be revitalized!
Cheery shops make for a cheery town!
Cheery owners make for cheery shops!
And Gaga Pro Wrestling,
or GGP, is here to help!
Pro wrestling?
Yamazaki Yoshinobu (51)
Owner of Green Grocer "Yaoyoshi"
What do healthy bodies make?
Fujinami Hajime (52)
Hardware Store Owner
Pro wrestling's supposed to energize us?
Tenryu Ichiro (53)
Sushi Shop Owner
Is she telling us to wrestle?
That's right, a healthy business.
There's no way.
We'd fall over dead before
we got any energy from it.
Definitely.
Huh? Icchan, don't you go to the gym?
I've never used the machines or pool.
Then what do you go there for?
To use their sauna, obviously.
That's what you'd expect to happen.
But if you're refereeing, that must mean...
Don't look at me.
Don't say a word
Conan-kun, you're a good boy
who doesn't tell any lies.
Ran-neechan, why are you s-so mad?
It's just an event to
revitalize the shopping center.
Lie to her
It's not like they'll be
pro wrestling for real.
Wow, these malted miso pickles are so good.
They wouldn't stand a chance against
actual professional wrestlers.
Right? It would suck if we
couldn't eat these anymore.
Female pro wrestlers!
Huh?
With nice bodies!
Ding ding ding.
You can't get anything past my daughter.
Your opponent will be GGP's
idol wrestler Cutie Mimi!
Cutie Mimi
Gaga's Daughter
Mimi-chan.
A female pro wrestler?
She's so cute.
There's only one thing you need
to do to seize victory!
The moment you take the Victory Diamond
glittering on her chest, you win!
Think you can take this?
The winner will receive
the official GGP champion's belt!
Hello. I'm GGP manager Rabbit Suzuki.
Rabbit Suzuki (32)
Gaga's Son
An official GGP champion's belt?
Where are they even from?
All right.
Don't underestimate us.
We'll be taking that belt.
Huh?
We'll show them the skills we acquired
playing pretend pro wrestling as kids.
Pretend skills?
They've inspired me to give my best effort.
I've never seen you try
your best at anything.
What do you think I've
been going to the gym for?
Didn't you say it's to use their sauna?
Who is that?
I-It's the association president!
Sh-Shouldn't you be resting?
But your health.
So, when are you holdin' this event?
There's lots to do, like constructing
the event space and printing pamphlets.
Three days from now?
There's no way they'll win a pro
wrestling event in just three days.
Don't tell me that association
president is participating.
He said he'd referee
instead of being a wrestler.
Referee?
Yeah, but his family insisted
he couldn't do that either.
The association president is legendary
referee Yamamoto Tetsusaburo.
Legendary referee?
Long ago, when people still watched
pro wrestling on TVs in the street,
everyone looked up to the man when there
was little other entertainment to be found.
He refereed with unwavering righteousness.
Even when crooked
wrestlers tore up his shirts
and tried to throw him out of the ring,
he raised the winner's hand up high.
To this day, his rousing legend is still—
Did you think you could trick me
with an impassioned story?
No, of course not.
Fine. I'm going to Bondo Shopping
Center tomorrow to check things out.
Mori Detective Agency
B-But why?
I need to warn people what happens
when they underestimate combat sports.
Just don't participate, okay?
Bring it on!
In 3 Days
When: 13:00~
Where: Shopping Center Plaza
Pro Wrestling Event
Huge Super Cheery Sale!
Bondo Shopping Center
I can't believe how lively it is.
Cheery Shopping With a Smile!
Conan-kun.
Sorry. Were you waiting long?
No, I just got here.
Bondo Shopping Center
Cheery Shopping With a Smile!
It seems pretty cheery.
It wasn't like this yesterday.
Welcome. Half off for everyone.
Come and get it.
Welcome.
He actually unpacked his produce.
Cheery Vegetables!!
Is this really the shop?
Are you jogging?
Yeah, I completed three laps to the station.
The station's right around the corner.
If you suddenly push yourself too hard...
Hey, Hajime. Don't tire yourself out.
Shut up. I'm not tired.
Where are you going?
Isn't it obvious?
I'm going for a swim.
I'll take it easy today and
only swim three kilometers.
Won't it be your first time swimming?
Isn't three kilometers
too much to start with?
Mori Detective Agency
Sounds like a good thing to me.
The shopping center
is suddenly full of life, right?
This is exactly what Gaga-sama had in mind.
She really is a godlike producer.
I'm telling you, it's dangerous.
I hate to be rude,
but they're all pretty old.
They can't just jump into pro wrestling.
Don't worry about them.
Pro wrestling has always been
about putting on a show, too.
It's not like Mimi-chan will go all out.
That's what I'm saying is dangerous.
Even if Mimi-san holds back,
it only works between opponents
who have trained for it.
Dad, I bet you don't even know
how hard the mat is.
I don't care to know that.
It's always exciting when the referee
gets thrown down on the mat.
Totally.
Hold on. Were the other
old guys working out?
Well...
The ramen shop owner and real
estate agent attempted bouldering.
Attempted?
They barely got off the ground.
The butcher played tennis.
He was more interested in chatting
with young women than playing tennis.
The futon shop owner went bowling.
He spent most of his time
polishing the bowling ball.
They each spent twice as long enjoying—
I mean, training really hard.
I'm starting to get worried.
Additionally, the association president
is feeling very refreshed
after his aromatherapy massage.
I don't care about that!
See? Aren't you starting
to think they can't do it, too?
As long as you've got the energy,
you can do anything!
Let's go!
Bondo Shopping Center
Pro Wrestling Event
Huge Super Cheery Sale!
Where: Shopping Center Plaza
When: 13:00~
Bring it on!
In 2 Days
Th-They're sore?
Unbelievable, right?
What a bunch of wimps.
You're not in any pain?
I'm not like them.
I'm built different.
Welcome back.
Why are so many stores closed?
Did they take the day off?
They're seeing chiropractors
and getting massages.
Massages?
What'd you expect to happen
to guys your age?
You must be idiots.
It's a good thing you came the next day.
Bondo Chiropractor
Massages
Quick massage
30 minutes
2,000 yen
We Accept Insurance
As you get older, you experience
the worst pain after the second day.
Bondo Shopping Center
Pro Wrestling Event
Huge Super Cheery Sale!
Ow, ow.
Where: Shopping Center Plaza
When: 13:00~
Bring it on!
Tomorrow
Kid, I'll pay you to open the boxes
and put out my banner.
Did you hurt your back?
It's your fault for pushing yourself
to do things you don't normally do.
But at least you're trying to open shop.
Just pathetic, Yaoyoshi.
You can take the day off tomorrow
and leave the wrestling to me.
You're walking weirdly
and your legs are shaking.
Pathetic. You guys take it easy.
Tomorrow the main event will be my
60-minute match against Mimi-chan.
A no time limit electric cage
death match would be great.
That jerk's surprisingly youthful.
I'm not so sure.
It's possible he used the sauna and got
a massage instead of going swimming.
Oh, right. It's not that he's standing
up straight, he just can't bend forward.
Shut up.
Not there!
What? Isn't this the center?
It's over there, next to our car.
That's where we're putting
the red corner post.
Are you sure?
It'll be hard for the audience to see.
It's fine.
From here to here.
The event will be a dud
unless the center is over here.
We won't be able to put on a spectacle.
Okay, okay. Got it.
I see you're using a generator.
Yeah. Even in the afternoon,
we'll want lights on the ring.
You couldn't borrow power
from the shopping center?
It seems like you could
use those over there.
Electricity isn't free.
We'd be imposing on the shops.
Our goal is to energize the shopping center.
Oh, right.
What are we going to do, mom?
I heard there are only three participants.
You should be glad we even got three.
They're not three normal
participants either.
They're decrepit old men.
They can move. It'll be fine.
No matter how you look at it,
it'll be over in a second.
You can't do that.
You have to drag it out
for an hour and a half.
30 minutes per challenger, huh?
I'll have to try not to kill them.
I know you can do it, Mimi-chan.
Why is it 30 minutes per person?
Who are you?
Are you with one of the shops?
Since you're so strong, you can't help
beating a bunch of old men quickly.
Y-You're right.
But the audience who came
to see pro wrestling
would be disappointed
if the match ended quickly.
Yeah.
What I really want is to go all out
against a strong opponent, but...
Conan-kun.
Sorry. Practice ran late.
Hey, you!
Yes?
Mori Detective Agency
Why are you wrestling?
Don't say it.
Can't you tell I'm depressed right now?
Hey, kid. You were watching, right?
Explain.
Well...
Huh. So you do karate.
Yes. I love being active.
Are you strong?
What?
It's not about strong or weak.
I practice karate to—
Why don't you dance instead, then?
Amateurs are lucky.
They get to pretend fight for fun.
Have I done something to offend you?
Impressive. She manipulated
her by making her angry.
Ran-neechan did her best to resist.
She kept provoking her
by saying all kinds of things.
If she knew what was happening,
she should've been able to resist.
But in the end...
Wow, it's never okay to say that!
Right?
It seems like words aren't enough
to get you to understand.
Do you know what the difference
is between a professional and an amateur?
As far as I am concerned, I regret nothing.
Chest!
She's quoting Musashi.
Hello? What do you want?
You've got good timing.
I just closed my laptop.
And?
Uh huh. Uh huh.
Hold on. I'm putting you on speaker
phone so I can use both hands.
Wait, no. I'll use this.
Okay, go ahead.
What?
I'm using earphones instead.
Because he'll hear you.
No, you'll wake the professor.
You never consider the time or place.
Don't laugh.
I found GGP.
What is this? Comedy pro wrestling?
They operate around the country.
Yeah. Yeah.
A jewelry store?
Wait, is this...?
Yikes... A bad feeling, huh?
Every time you get a bad feeling
about something, it turns into a case.
Yes. Yes. Okay...
Detectives must all suffer from that illness.
Where: Shopping Center Plaza
When: 13:00~
Bring it on!
Today
Huge Super Cheery Sale!
Thank you for waiting, everyone!
GGP Bondo Shopping Center
The Bondo Shopping Center Pro Wrestling
Event presented by GGP will now begin!
Wow. She must be pretty popular.
Cutie Mimi is a popular Tuber
with over 500,000 followers.
Huh? Haibara, did you come alone?
You didn't tell Genta and the others?
It's not like you told them either.
Something inappropriate
for them might happen.
Our first challenger is the owner
of Yaoyoshi, Yamazaki Yoshinobu!
His opponent is GGP champion Cutie Mimi!
The referee is Mori Kogoro!
Both wrestlers, step forward.
It's time to search your
bodies before the match.
Is this why he volunteered
to referee the event?
See? Hardly appropriate for children.
Have you got any dangerous
weapons on your person?
That won't be necessary.
I'm sorry.
This is your chance.
You could do the Sleeping Kogoro now
without using your tranquilizer watch.
It's not time for the fall yet.
Just fight, damn it!
Go, Yaoyoshi!
It'll all work out!
Mimi-chan, do this.
I'm scared!
It's okay!
It's okay! She's cute!
What does that mean?
Do they mean that getting hit
by a cute girl doesn't hurt?
That's it, Mimi-chan.
Keep doing that to buy time.
All right! Yaoyoshi, tag me in!
Tag?
Oh, my! It's suddenly turned into
an irregular three-against-one match!
What do you think you're doing?
I'll allow it!
Try not to let this scare you.
A bottle opener!
Oh, no! He's got a weapon!
Hey, what are you thinking?
What's wrong with a hardware
store owner having a bottle opener?
You did good, hardware store owner.
Leave the rest to me.
Hey, you didn't even tag in!
This stuff is brutal, Mimi-chan.
Freshly grated honwasabi!
That's nothing!
It burns!
I can't watch anymore of this.
Haibara, would you?
A wooden mallet?
Strike when I give the signal.
It's so strong!
Of course it is.
Don't underestimate my shop's wasabi.
Hup.
It's strong! It's strong!
Oh, so strong!
Jeez...
Don't you dare give me a thumbs up.
That's enough of this.
I'm glad nobody got hurt.
We've only used half of the time
allotted, but we've seen enough.
Unfortunately, Gaga-san,
the GGP has lost this match.
What are you talking about?
Was that wasabi too strong for you?
You're a truly delightful person.
But stealing jewels is a crime.
Oh, please, Kogoro-san.
Do these look real to you?
Oh, no. Is this stolen, too?
Using the decorations on the
champion's belt is an interesting idea.
They're hollow on the inside, like capsules.
You could certainly
hide jewels inside those.
How many times have you
successfully fooled people until now?
No, nobody even noticed you
were up to anything.
GGP has held pro wrestling
events all over the place,
but for some reason, a few
conditions are always true.
The location of a manhole.
A generator.
And a jewelry store's
subterranean storehouse
at the end of an underground passageway.
Every jewelry store has reported a theft.
The generator hides the sound of the drill,
and these pro wrestling events
create numerous witnesses.
The manhole is hidden beneath the ring.
The cord extending down into it
is longer than it needs to be
for the ring lights.
But I can't deny that it's
all just my theory.
Th-That's right. None of that
amounts to any evidence at all.
Too bad, Mr. Detective.
Mom, what's going on?!
There were cops waiting for me
when I broke through the wall.
This time you're being arrested for
property damage and breaking and entering,
but I'm sure your previous thefts
will be thoroughly investigated.
I'm the one who called them.
Okay.
What the hell is this?
Wow... she was totally ready to fight.
I guess you'll have to fight her now.
What?
Episode Preview
Sherlock
Holmes
It smells good, doesn't it?
But I can't give you any of this.
Sherlock
Holmes
We are...
The Detective Boys!
Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko's Detective Notes
The next episode of Conan is
"Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko's Detective Notes!"
Pizza
Next Conan's hint.
Pizza!
Thank you for another year!
Don't miss the next episode.
Have a Happy New Year!