Happy New Year!
We've made it to 2023 thanks to all of you.
And we'll be kicking off the year
with a story about me.
What? No fair!
What about me?
We don't have a story about me?
Onizuka's Class
What? We already did yours.
Seriously?
We haven't done mine yet.
This is my year.
Anyway, once again, Detective Conan...
The Detective Boys!
And Haibara Ai.
...appreciate your continued support.
Win 1 Extra Pizza!!
Campaign On Now
The last question's a little difficult.
O-Okay.
This is enough dough for one pizza.
How many grams is it?
215 grams!
Oh, yeah? Let's see.
You're correct!
Congratulations!
You've won a free pizza.
Yeah!
All right!
Nice work, Genta-kun.
You're exceptionally skilled
when it comes to anything food-related.
Be careful taking them home.
Thank you!
Later, guys.
See you tomorrow.
See you later.
Okay, see you tomorrow.
Huh?
What?
Book Fair
Sherlock
Holmes
Holmes Fair
Huh? Hey, what are you...
It smells good, doesn't it?
But I can't give you any of this.
Nope.
What?
Wash your hands
until they're nice and clean.
You just wait, my little pizza.
All right.
Huh?
Thief!
Open
I see. They're watching a child
complete their first errand.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
Detective Mitsuhiko is on the case!
Is it a challenge from Holmes himself?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko's Detective Notes
"Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko's Detective Notes!"
I see. So they escaped.
Yeah, all I found was this box.
Me, too. Mine was on the ground
a few steps away.
So did I. The contents
were untouched, though.
They won't get away with this.
What do you suppose is the meaning of this?
It doesn't seem as though
the culprit was hungry.
Maybe the culprit was after the boxes.
Yeah, probably.
Book Fair
Sherlock
Holmes
The police just came to ask if we'd
seen anyone suspicious in the area.
Makishima Chuya (35)
Pizza Store Manager
Last night a jewelry store was robbed.
A jewelry store robbery...
According to the police,
they chased after the culprits
as soon as the alarm sounded,
but they escaped as they were
just about to arrest them.
Was something stolen?
I think they said ten diamonds were taken.
Do you know how big the diamonds were?
I don't know. I think they
said they were for rings.
I see.
If they're one carat diamonds,
that'd be 6.5 milligrams.
Mr. Manager, do you know
where the robbery took place?
Huh? Oh, yeah. Give me a minute.
Let's see...
Yup.
This is the jewelry store,
and our store is here.
I knew it. It's possible they fled this way.
Yeah, and they found this store.
It was the middle of the night,
so no one was around.
They probably decided to temporarily
hide the jewels here and flee.
What? Are you saying the jewels
are in here somewhere?
No, we already know where they are.
Take a look at this.
After we left the store...
That's what happened?
But why did the thief hide
the jewels inside pizza boxes?
There was a benefit to doing so.
I see. They were going to have it delivered.
And they'd get a pizza, too.
They were probably watching from nearby.
I see. That's why you kids were chased.
In other words, this case is the same
as "The Adventure of the Six Napoleons."
"The Six Napoleons"?
What's that? Can you eat it?
Genta-kun, I don't think it's a food.
It's a Sherlock Holmes story
written by Conan Doyle.
According to canon...
Canon?
That's what Sherlockians
call the Holmes series.
Huh.
Several Napoleon busts
are stolen from around town
and smashed in this mysterious case.
Why would someone break
the stuff they stole?
The culprit hid jewels inside the plaster
before it dried to trick the police.
When they went to retrieve them later,
the busts had already
been sold to various buyers,
and the culprit had to
collect all six Napoleon busts
that had been made at the same time.
But there were no signs that
anyone broke into this store.
Hey, what's that notebook?
21:30
Finished closing
Leaving key in mailbox
and going home
Yesterday, the manager left work before me,
so I locked up, put the key
in the mailbox, and went home.
Since my shift started this afternoon today,
I left notes for the next person.
Finished closing
Leaving key in mailbox
and going home
I knew it.
The culprit read the notebook
from the outside
and took the key out of the mailbox.
Then they put it back.
That's why there were no signs
anyone had broken in.
But the mailbox is locked.
Look closely at the padlock.
Could it be?
What?
Hey, that's careless of you.
You should replace the padlock
as soon as you can.
Also, instead of using your mailbox,
you should get a spare key made
and keep proper track of them.
Yeah, I will.
I see. Because of this...
That's amazing! Who are you kids?
I'm glad you asked.
We are...
The Detective Boys.
Hey, look.
Are all your boxes gone?
You had so many.
Yeah. Unusually, we had
three big orders this morning,
and they were just delivered earlier.
According the the deliverymen,
it was around here.
The deliverymen said the three large orders
were seven pizzas for Tanaka-san,
seven pizzas for Kato-san,
and seven pizzas for Yamada-san.
I still think it's weird to
accept pizzas outside your house.
Well, the thief placed the orders
so they could retrieve the jewels.
All three orders?
Yeah, probably.
Perhaps they thought ordering so many pizzas
at once would leave a lasting impression.
The pizzas were probably
ordered under fake names, too.
They apparently requested
the orders use the campaign boxes.
It must be the culprit.
Hey, look.
In there.
First the thief accepted
the pizzas here as Tanaka-san
and checked the contents
of the boxes inside their car.
What about that car?
There are regular boxes, too.
One, two, three, four, five.
They must have run out of boxes
because they used them for our pizzas.
Huh? There's no car here.
You're right.
Edogawa-kun, look.
You guys stay here.
Haibara, call an ambulance.
Got it.
So, you discovered a connection between
your stolen pizzas and the jewel theft,
and were visiting the drop-off locations...
And we found that person.
Isn't that last night's jewel thief?
There was cardboard from the pizza
boxes stuck beneath his nails.
Probably.
He matches the description of one
of the thieves spotted last night.
Were there two thieves?
Yeah.
Do you think they had a falling out, then?
Probably.
I imagine the case will be
solved once he wakes up.
I'm sure we'll find the diamonds, too.
Thanks for talking to us.
You kids can go home now.
Okay.
Be careful on your way home.
It really was just like "The Six
Napoleons" until partway through.
I see.
Sometimes things don't follow the mold, huh?
Well, it sounded like
the thieves didn't have a plan.
What's wrong, Mitsuhiko-kun?
Are you too hungry to move?
The mold...
Huh?
There's something I'd like to confirm.
Conan-kun, I've made a terrible discovery.
The thieves may not have
acquired the jewels yet.
What do you mean?
I remembered something.
When we checked the pizza boxes,
the sample box was missing, too.
Since the bookstore's Holmes Fair
display was also using an easel,
it caught my eye.
So we went back to the pizza shop
and asked about the sample.
The sample box was one they had
on the counter this morning
that they chose at random
to display on the easel.
Where is that box now?
Today's the last day of the campaign,
so they used it to make a delivery
since they were short on boxes.
There was still one more box left.
You guys can't seriously be...
We're currently on our way
to the home that placed that order.
Don't! It's too dangerous!
It's okay, Ai-chan.
We're just going to beat the thief there
and retrieve the jewels.
You can count on us.
You kids...!
We're almost there, so I'm hanging up.
This is the place.
Yes?
Sakuragawa Mariko (40)
Pizza Store Customer
What is it?
We came from the pizza shop.
It's about the pizza you ordered today.
I already ate it.
Was something wrong with it?
No. Could you let us take the box?
Why do you want the box?
Please.
Give me a minute.
So, what about this?
Don't move!
Hand over the box.
O-Okay.
Please let him go.
This kid is my hostage. He's coming with me.
No way!
This has been a pain in the butt.
I was convinced he cheated me out of
my share and was just playing dumb.
But thanks, kids. You led me right to them.
So they really hadn't
retrieved the jewels yet.
This is the greatest mistake of my life.
Someone help.
Stay where you are.
You're not getting away.
I know who you are. Prepare yourself.
Conan-kun...
What can a kid do?
Take this!
Wow...
Conan-kun!
You guys...
We're sorry!
Are you really sorry about what you did?
Yes, terribly.
Oh, right.
They're not here.
What's going on?
That can't be right.
She hasn't even broken down the box
even though it's been a while
since she finished the pizza.
Huh? You're right, now that you mention it.
Normally you throw it away
as soon as you're finished.
I crumple mine up
and stuff it in the garbage.
Could it be?
I'm sorry. I couldn't resist.
This man robbed a jewelry store last night.
We came to your house to retrieve the box
because he'd hidden diamonds inside it.
I see. Well, crime never pays.
Saying I couldn't resist is just an excuse.
I'll never consider doing anything
like that again. I promise.
Anyway, I helped make
breakfast this morning.
Oh, yeah? Did you burn the toast?
What? How did you know?
Because you've got burnt crumbs on you.
Conan-kun was as impressive as always.
His detective skills and initiative
were like Holmes himself.
Really? Wow.
However, it was my flash of inspiration
that led to us solving this case.
Of course, I've helped solve numerous cases
until now with my brilliant intellect.
This was the case that made me
start keeping Mitsuhiko's Case Files.
What's that?
It's a secret.
Mitsuhiko-kun, Genta-kun.
Hurry up.
Okay.
Coming.
I hope I'll have the chance to show you
all the cases inside this file someday.
Episode Preview
Hello?
Mori-san, I'm...
...currently at Kuran Park.
Kuran Park?
What was that?
Mayako-san!
Nagamine.
Hey!
The Sweet Voice Heard Through the Phone
The next episode of Conan is "The Sweet
Voice Heard Through the Phone!"
Pay Phone
Next Conan's hint.
A pay phone!
What's this year's Chinese zodiac?
Don't miss the next episode.
Ra—
It's eel!
No, it's rabbit.