[eyecatch]
DETECTIVE CONAN EPISODE 1069 "The
Sweet Voice Heard Through the Phone"
[OP]
[ed]
Café Poirot
Mori Detective Agency
Hello, Mori Detective Agency.
Ah, Nagamine-san.
We're meeting today at three, correct?
I'll be waiting for you.
Actually, I got lost on my way there.
I'm going to be about five minutes late.
There's no rush.
I've cleared my schedule for you today.
Posts 27   Followers 31   Following 64
Posts   TMSTV   Saved   Tagged
Actually, Mori-san, I have a request.
What is it?
Please call me Mayako.
What?
But we've never met before. Are you sure?
Yes. I think it'll help me be more honest.
Very well. In that case,
I'll call you Mayako-san.
The old man always fawns
over his female clients.
It's rare that I don't, but I've got
a bad feeling about this client, too.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
The client has a beautiful voice
and sweet whispers call forth a case!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Sweet Voice Heard Through the Phone
"The Sweet Voice Heard Through the Phone!"
Mori Detective Agency
It's been 30 minutes since then.
Nagamine Mayako-san is late.
Yeah.
Maybe she got lost—
How do you know the client's name?
I know more than just her name.
One year ago, Nagamine Mayako-san married
her former boss Nagamine Haruhiko-san.
Posts 27   Followers 31   Following 64
Self-improvement   Loves Cute Things   Read More
Translate
Now she's a housewife.
Her husband's been divorced once, and rumors of his
infidelity have continued even after their marriage.
How do you know all that?
Because you were speaking loudly
on the phone yesterday, too.
She's coming today about
her husband again, right?
Yeah...
But not about his infidelity.
She's worried he might be involved
in some criminal activity.
Criminal activity?
She recently saw Nagamine-san bring home
a suitcase in the middle of the night
and hide it in their garage.
Nagamine Haruhiko (40)
Office Worker
After he left,
she got out the hidden suitcase and
attempted to examine its contents,
Nagamine Mayako (31)
Housewife
but it was locked.
However...
However?
However, the suitcase was
apparently quite heavy.
Excuse me, but are you looking for someone?
Hello, Mori Detective Agency.
Oh, Mayako-san.
I'm sorry. I know I'm nearby, but...
I'll go meet you.
What can you see from there?
Let's see...
What's the matter?
I just spotted my husband.
Your husband?
It is him. He followed me.
Mayako-san, stay where you are.
No, I can't.
It would be disastrous if he
found out I was visiting you.
I'll head to your office once I've lost him.
Please wait a little longer.
She's in trouble.
Nagamine-san is following her.
Then you should've stayed on the
line with her instead of hanging up.
I can't, because Mayako-san
called me from a pay phone.
A pay phone?
Apparently her husband has a short temper.
There's no telling what he'd do to her if
he found out she was meeting a detective.
He also thoroughly checks her phone,
so she always uses pay phones to call me.
I'm home.
What's the matter, Ran-neechan?
I just saw a pretty lady
who looked lost, but...
A pretty lady?
Was this her?
Yeah, that's her.
What?
A suspicious man wearing
a hat was following her.
Was that this guy?
Since he was wearing a hat,
I couldn't see his face.
If the woman you saw was Mayako-san, then the
man wearing the hat must've been Nagamine-san.
Hello?
Mori-san, I'm...
currently at Kuraun Park.
Kuraun Park?
My husband is still nearby.
If he finds me, he might kill me.
What was that?
Mayako-san!
Mori Detective Agency
Mayako-san is at Kuraun Park.
I'm going to help her.
Mister!
Dad!
Kuraun Park
Mayako-san!
Dad!
Ran, help her.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Mayako-san!
Who's there?
Is that you, Nagamine-san?
Hey!
Nagamine!
Mayako-san.
Ran, don't touch that.
Okay.
Ran-neechan, there's blood on your hand.
Huh?
You're right.
Are you okay, Ran?
Yeah. I don't seem to
be injured, so I'm fine.
I wonder when this happened.
The culprit seems to have gone looking
through her bag for something.
The victim is Nagamine
Mayako-san, 31 years old.
She's a housewife who lives
rather far away from here.
Mori-san can explain what she was doing
at this park so far away from her home.
You again?
Inspector, Mayako-san—rather, she was...
Someone rifled through the victim's bag.
Was anything taken?
Her wallet and valuables were still
there, so I doubt anything was taken.
What about her phone?
We didn't find one inside her bag or pockets.
You should search her bag more thoroughly.
Hey! The adults are talking.
MPD
I see. I understand what happened.
The culprit is undoubtedly her
husband Nagamine Haruhiko.
I got a clear look at his face.
Was it also Nagamine who knocked
over that woman's bike and fled?
No, that was someone else.
Someone else?
I believe that man was following Mayako-san.
I saw him.
Then it's possible that man is the culprit.
But based on our phone conversation,
the culprit could only be Nagamine.
What about the woman on the bike?
She suffered minor injuries.
Yufunezawa Kyoko (31)
I'm thinking about her asking her
if she can provide any clues regarding
the man who bumped into her.
Inspector.
Nagamine!
He was wandering around wearing bloody
clothes, so we brought him here.
I didn't kill her! I'm here
because Mayako invited me here.
Liar! Mayako-san just happened to flee here.
It's true.
We got into a little argument
over my relationships with women.
She asked me to come here so
we could discuss a divorce.
When I arrived, Mayako was on the ground.
Let's go over it one more time.
The man who bumped into you
was wearing a black felt hat,
and his mouth was hidden behind his clothes.
Who are you?
You!
You know him?
I'm Aragaki Ippei, his junior coworker.
Aragaki Ippei (25)
Haruhiko's Junior Coworker
Why were you following Mayako?
The president ordered me to.
What?
What do you mean by that?
The company discovered that he embezzled
roughly 100 million yen from the company.
100 million?
Since it would affect the
credibility of our company,
I was ordered to recover the money he
embezzled before we reported it to the police.
I visited his home, but
only his was wife there.
Did you tell Mayako-san
about the embezzlement?
I did.
She didn't seem to know anything about it,
but while staking out their
home, I saw her leave.
I thought she might be meeting him.
So that's why you followed her.
Mayako-san was coming to discuss
the embezzlement with me today,
so you decided to shut her up.
Wait a minute!
If I'm going to be accused of murder,
then I'll tell you everything.
It's true that I embezzled
money from my company.
Where is the money now?
I packed it in a suitcase and hid
it in my garage, but it's gone now.
What do you mean by that?
Mayako-san said she gave it
to a friend to hold onto.
She was probably planning
to split it with them.
You're lying!
I see.
So you and Mayako were working together.
What was that?!
Mister, do you have a minute?
What is it?
Did you know the name of this park?
Come to think of it, I learned
today that it's called Kuraun Park.
Everyone calls it Jizo Park
since it has jizo statues.
Kuraun Park
Earlier I saw the name of the park
engraved in a pillar at the entrance,
but at a glance, you wouldn't be
able to read it as Kuraun Park.
I doubt Mayako-san would've
known the name of the park
if it was her first time
in this part of the city.
But the woman on the phone
clearly said Kuraun Park.
Mori-san, I'm currently at Kuraun Park.
Y-You're right...
Conan-kun, what does that mean?
It means the woman who you spoke with
over the phone wasn't Mayako-san.
Wh-What?
You've never met Mayako-san before, right?
That's true, but we've spoken
over the phone several times.
I was talking to her moments
before she was killed.
You know that.
But since you've never met,
you wouldn't know if that
was really her voice.
But Conan-kun, I saw Mayako-san
when she was lost.
I believe the woman you saw was Mayako-san,
but she wasn't on her way to
the detective agency then.
She was probably looking for Kuraun Park.
Wait a minute. Then who
have I been talking to?
Probably Mayako-san's murderer.
The murderer?
Are you saying I've been talking to
Mayako-san's murderer this whole time?
Looking at it that way might
allow us to solve the case.
N-No way.
I see. I've figured it out.
What?
Mayako-san and the culprit
closely resembled each other.
In other words, they're twins.
Twins?
You're way off the mark, old man.
Twins are identical in appearance and voice.
It wouldn't have been impossible to
fool the great detective Mori Kogoro—
No, no!
I can't help if it's
happening at Kuraun Park!
Mori-kun?
Excuse me, Inspector.
I've finally solved the case.
Solved the case?
The person I'd been speaking to over the
phone was probably Mayako-san's killer
and not Mayako-san herself.
The culprit planned to kill Mayako-san
at this park from the start.
Why at this park?
Because my detective agency is nearby.
What?
The culprit spoke with me
over the phone numerous times
and created the impression that
they were Nagamine Mayako-san.
And then...
They killed Mayako-san with a knife
after inviting her to the park,
and pretended they were calling to say they
were about to be killed from the crime scene.
Mori Detective Agency
Then they left the park
and Nagamine-san arrived.
Mayako-san!
Mayako-san! Mayako-san!
Then I arrived and discovered Mayako-san.
Even though I hadn't witnessed the murder,
I'd be convinced Nagamine-san killed her.
I see.
They attempted to frame Nagamine-san
by having a detective like
you testify that he did it.
Conan, could you ask Detective Takagi
to do what I told you earlier?
Okay.
Detective Takagi.
Yeah?
Listen...
Can I leave now?
Thank you for your cooperation.
You can leave for today.
Takagi-kun, what's that sound?
It's Mayako-san's phone.
While thoroughly searching her bag earlier,
I found this beneath the false bottom.
Conan-kun just told me to make a call.
The culprit used pay phones to call me, but
they sent directions to Mayako-san's phone.
The last call she received today
must have been from the culprit.
That's why I had Detective
Takagi call back that number.
I had nothing to do with this.
I found this phone in the area.
I recognize your voice.
And the sound of the bells on your earrings.
It wasn't Mayako-san I was speaking
with over the phone, but you.
Detective Takagi, don't let her leave.
Stop her!
You!
Who is she?
Kyoko, the woman I was
married to before Mayako.
What?
So you're Mayako's friend?
That's right. Surprised?
When Mayako learned you were
hiding 100 million yen,
she asked me for advice.
So I instructed her to
invite you to this park.
Then you killed Mayako-san
and framed Nagamine-san in an attempt
to keep the money for yourself.
That's right.
I thought a famous detective
would back me up.
Actually, Mori-san, I have a request.
What is it?
Please call me Mayako.
Kuraun Park is right at the next corner.
I'll be there soon. Wait for me.
Haruhiko doesn't know you're coming.
He'll be so surprised.
You're right.
Let's teach him a lesson together.
See you later.
Everything would've gone according to plan...
if you hadn't followed Mayako.
That ruined everything.
Anyway, I'm impressed, Detective.
How did you know?
There was blood on Ran's hand
even though she hadn't touched
anything at the crime scene.
Conan, explain.
Okay.
Ran-neechan got blood on her hand
when she grabbed your bike's
handlebars to pick it up.
The blood that got on the culprit's hands
when they stabbed Mayako-san
was on the handlebars.
Why would you do this?
I hated Mayako for taking
my happiness from me.
And you, too.
Enough that I wanted to kill you.
Do you remember?
When I called you back
when we were married...
Mayako?
Don't worry. I told my wife
I'm on a business trip.
You mistook me for Mayako and lied to me.
You told me all about your
plans to go on a trip with her.
So I figured you wouldn't notice
if I pretended to be Mayako on the phone.
Mori Detective Agency
Anyway, Nagamine-san really
screwed up by mixing up
his wife's and mistress'
voices over the phone.
You thought it was Mayako-san's voice, too.
I'd never met her before. You can't blame me.
I'd never confuse the voice
of a woman I'd met with—
Hello, Mori Detective Agency.
Hello, darling. It's me.
Me who?
Is that you, Eri?
It's me, Dad.
Ran?
I can't believe you thought
I was Mom. Are you okay?
You impersonated her on purpose.
It's only natural for a daughter
to sound like her mother.
Don't play dumb pranks on me. Hmph!
He's hopeless.
Episode Preview
Is someone there?
At first glance, this seems
like an unfortunate accident.
But all of this was planned
without your knowledge, Mai-san.
You're kidding, right?
Riko, how could you make
me kill Yusuke over that?
The Surprise That Leads to Tragedy
The next episode of Conan is "The
Surprise That Leads to Tragedy!"
Handkerchief
Next Conan's hint.
A handkerchief!
Hello, this is Takagi.
Don't miss the next episode.
I bet you like eel bowls, don't you?
You're not wrong.