[ed]
[eyecatch]
DETECTIVE CONAN EPISODE 1070 "The
Surprise That Leads to Tragedy"
[op]
Takigawa Mai (25)
Office Worker
Is someone there?
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
A surprise is accompanied
by the sound of screams!
Behind the tragedy is a shocking truth!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Surprise That Leads to Tragedy
"The Surprise That Leads to Tragedy!"
That chameleon sure was cute.
Yes.
I'm not surprised your friend
likes weird animals like that.
It's quite late, isn't it?
It's already eight.
Huh?
That came from downstairs.
Hey!
Where did that come from?
Probably the room at the end.
What happened?
Are you all right?
It's Yusuke...
Yusuke! Yusuke!
Tsuda Yusuke (25)
Mai's Boyfriend
Totsuka Riko (25)
Mai and Yusuke's Friend
I... I killed him.
Let me make sure I've got it straight.
When Mai-san came home from
work around eight tonight,
she saw someone moving around
inside her apartment,
which should have been empty.
Thinking she was being robbed,
she grabbed the golf club
she kept for self-defense.
And then...
However, that person was actually
her boyfriend Yusuke-san,
who appeared out of the darkness
to surprise her with a party.
Have I got that right?
Yes.
It's my fault.
I'm the one who suggested we throw
a surprise party for Mai's birthday.
That's why...
No, it's my fault.
If only I'd called the police when
I thought I was being robbed.
All three of you were close
childhood friends, correct?
Yusuke and I have always been mischievous.
We got in trouble with honor student
Mai all the time for pulling pranks.
I checked the third floor hallway
security camera footage.
It's exactly as they described.
So no one's at fault. It was
an unfortunate accident.
Don't you think it's weird, though?
Normally you wouldn't keep a
golf club in an umbrella stand.
You're right, not even if
it was for self-defense.
Mai had just started living on her own.
She was really paranoid about security.
Really? So you decided to throw a
surprise party for someone like that?
We wanted to cheer her up!
Mai's been having trouble at her new job.
She seemed really down.
I see.
What is it?
I was wondering why they chose this spot.
Isn't this the only spot where Mai-san would
be able to see anyone on her way home?
This is where you were hiding, right?
So what if I was?
If you wanted to surprise her,
why did you hide by the window
where you'd be easily spotted?
So I could see Mai coming home.
I moved over there right after that.
Did you loosen the light bulb
as part of your surprise, too?
It did seem to be loose.
So it wasn't broken.
Did you do that, too?
I admit I took it too far.
But it was for the surprise!
I didn't mean any harm!
Give me a break! This is hard for me, too.
Riko...
I feel sorry for them.
They're all victims here.
Give it a rest, Conan.
So these are the victim's belongings.
This is everything.
History
Takigawa Mai
Totsuka Riko
Call
There are a lot of calls here from Mai-san.
Listening to Yusuke's voice
always helped me feel safe
when I felt anxious or was having a bad time,
so I couldn't help myself.
But he'll never answer my calls again.
There are a lot of calls
from Riko-san recently, too.
Look. He only received
calls from Riko-san today.
It was for the party!
I called him a bunch of times.
I'm hungry. Let's go.
You're right. Come on,
Conan-kun. Let's get going.
I'm starving.
Hey, wai—
What's this?
This thing is cool.
Don't touch people's things without asking.
That's pepper spray.
Mai-san.
Why didn't you use that spray?
Kids don't know anything.
Pepper spray can make someone back off,
but it's relatively harmless.
Right?
Well, it's not a weapon
designed to hurt others.
It's just for self-defense.
You need to get close to
someone to use it, too.
When you're really in trouble,
a long-reach and highly
damaging weapon like—
So you recommended that
Mai-san use a golf club?
It's true.
A handkerchief?
Is this blood?!
It's mine.
Must've dropped it.
That's odd. I thought I put it away.
That's Yusuke-san's blood, isn't it?
I was so focused on trying
to stop the bleeding.
But why is your lipstick on it, too?
From some other time I used it.
Huh? Detective Takagi, do you
have lipstick around your mouth?
Huh? What?
Wh-What are you talking about, Conan-kun?
That's not possible.
Is that what happened?
Can I leave now?
I have work tomorrow.
Riko...
Wait.
At first glance, Yusuke-san's death
seems like an unfortunate accident.
But all of this was set up by Riko-san,
who planned this surprise party.
You made sure Mai-san would
see you on her way home.
You loosened the light bulb
so the light wouldn't turn on.
And you encouraged Mai-san to switch to using
a highly damaging golf club for self-defense,
all so Mai-san would mistake Yusuke-san
for a burglar and hurt him.
Isn't that right, Riko-san?
I'm telling you, it was just a
series of unfortunate events.
It's too many to be a coincidence, though.
You're right.
Riko would never do that.
Mai.
Besides, she has no motive.
Why would Riko do that?
Excuse me.
This is Yusuke-san's blood and your
lipstick on this handkerchief.
I told you, I was trying
to stop the bleeding.
Then you would've held it against his head.
But only the victim's mouth had been wiped.
Why did you only wipe the victim's mouth,
and what was your lipstick doing there?
You were kissing, weren't you?
In the darkness, as you waited for Mai-san.
When the lights turned on, you noticed
your own lipstick on Yusuke-san's lips,
so you rushed to wipe his lips clean.
You and Yusuke-san were dating, weren't?
Without Mai-san's knowledge.
You're kidding, right?
Riko, how could you make
me kill Yusuke over that?
That's awful.
It's not like that!
I just wanted Yusuke to be seriously
injured so you'd break up.
I really didn't think he'd die.
We know the truth now,
but it's heartbreaking.
What are you glaring about?
I gotta pee! One second!
Where are the bathroom lights?
Crap, crap.
Which one is it?
Well, whatever.
Hey, Genta-kun.
Sorry. Must be this one, then.
Turn the lights on already.
But I can't see the switches. Where are they?
Wait. I'll do it.
I'm sorry. Are you okay?
Yeah, but I can't see anything.
Hold still for a second. You'll be fine.
Your eyes will get used to the darkness.
You're right. I'm starting to be able to see.
Me, too.
See?
Wait a minute. Could it be?
Are they both going to be arrested?
Mai-san will probably be
able to come home soon.
I'm sure it'll be recognized
as an act of self-defense.
But Riko-san...
I'm telling you, I didn't
think he'd actually die.
You can tell us more in the interview room.
Huh? Where's Conan-kun?
Takagi-kun, he's not with you?
N-No.
He was reviewing Yusuke-san's phone
and the security camera footage
at Agasa-san's request.
I-Is that right?
He's playing with fire inside my apartment!
What?
But...
Open the door!
I knew it.
Hey, no fair!
Wh-What are you doing?
I wanted to confirm something.
But now we know exactly what happened.
Right, Professor?
Uh, yeah.
Know what?
Who the true culprit is, of course.
The true culprit?
Though we believed Mai-san
was Riko-san's pitiful puppet
manipulated into killing her own boyfriend,
she's actually the true culprit,
who was manipulating everyone involved.
What?
Mai-san knew what Riko-san was planning
and pretended to be tricked
so she could kill Yusuke-san.
She'd be found innocent due to self-defense,
and Riko-san would be
held wholly responsible.
Is that what you're saying?
Yes. It was probably also Mai-san who led us
to discover the handkerchief
used to wipe Yusuke-san's mouth
so we'd realize what Riko-san did.
A handkerchief couldn't happen
to fall out of that pocket.
Riko-san was on her guard.
Only Mai-san, who had been
by her side the whole time,
had the opportunity to take it.
What?
You're lying. I really didn't know anything.
Then why didn't you call Yusuke-san
when you entered your apartment?
You thought there was a burglar inside.
You said you've always called Yusuke-san
when you felt anxious.
Yes, Mai-san herself said that, and it's
clear from his call history as well.
But tonight, when you should've been
feeling more anxious than ever,
you didn't call him,
when normally you would've
kept him on the line.
You're right.
He only received calls from Riko-san
today and not a single one from Mai-san.
Of course, it's because calling
him would've ruined your plan.
Furthermore, check the
security camera footage.
Takagi-kun.
Yes, ma'am.
Don't you think there's something strange
about the way Mai-san walked down the hallway?
She does seem exceptionally careful,
but it doesn't seem odd for someone who
thinks there's a burglar in their apartment.
It's slight, but she appears to
be touching the wall as she walks.
If you zoom in on Mai-san's face
as she enters the apartment,
you'll understand why.
She's closing her eyes?
I've got it.
She's adjusting her eyes to the darkness.
Like we did earlier.
Its effectiveness differs
for everyone, though.
But why?
So she could accurately strike
Yusuke-san in the head
with the golf club in the
dark right after that.
There's no other plausible explanation.
So you knew everything.
Th-That's just conjecture, isn't it?
Not evidence.
Go on.
If you're so sure I did it,
then show me the evidence.
You've already shown us the evidence
through your own actions, Mai-san.
What?
Don't you find it strange?
When Conan-kun went missing earlier...
He's playing with fire inside my apartment!
You're right. How was Mai-san
the only one who knew that?
She couldn't see inside
the apartment from there.
This is the answer.
Is this a camera?
That's right.
It's probably a baby monitor,
the type that detects movement
and sends video to your phone.
Excuse me.
Naturally, it's also an infrared camera
that takes clear video even in darkness.
You're right. You can see in the dark.
Mai-san probably used it to determine
what was happening inside,
including where Yusuke-san was
hiding and where he'd come from.
Then when Conan-kun lit the candle earlier...
I asked him to do it.
Because she accurately described
what Conan-kun was doing,
it proves Mai-san used a baby monitor
to deliberately kill Yusuke-san.
Looks like I lost.
You knew about me and Yusuke?
Of course I did.
The three of us had been
together since we were kids.
I knew you two better than anyone.
That's why you knew which
conditions were necessary
to plan this murder.
You chose this timing to begin living alone.
You exaggerated your security concerns.
And Riko-san and Yusuke-san
had mischievous personalities.
It's too perfect a combination of factors.
We should assume Mai-san
made them happen on purpose.
Furthermore, Riko-san's plan
seems a bit too elaborate for her
to have come up with on her own.
It was probably Mai-san
who gave her the idea.
Well? Does that sound familiar?
Look, Riko.
Someone overseas mistook their husband
for a burglar and shot him dead.
Scary, right?
What? Seriously?
Wow, that's crazy.
It's your fault.
I trusted you two more than anyone.
But you...
By the way, Takagi-kun,
what was that lipstick?
That was a misunderstanding.
Oh, really?
Conan-kun!
Crap, I forgot to explain myself.
Episode Preview
I haven't identified the culprit yet,
but I believe I'll know by
this weekend's TV special.
That's why we invited you, Shin-chan.
Could it be?
Found it.
This is a series of murders
committed by the same killer.
They used the same locked
room trick all three times.
Kudo Yusaku's Detective Show
(Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "Kudo
Yusaku's Detective Show, Part One!"
Live Broadcast
Next Conan's hint!
A live broadcast!
Detective Takagi, you smell like perfume.
Don't miss the next episode.
No, wait. This is just—
Wow, you're right! Just kidding.