[eyecatch]
DETECTIVE CONAN EPISODE 1071 "Kudo
Yusaku's Detective Show (Part One)"
[op]
[ed]
World-renowned mystery author Kudo Yusaku has
just exited the Metropolitan Police Department.
Sensei! Kudo-sensei!
Impressive as always, Kudo-sensei!
They say you were the first to determine
the victim faked being robbed by Kaito Kid.
Not at all.
Metropolitan
Police Department
I simply offered some advice at the
request of a police inspector I know.
The letter and robbery itself
were far too sloppy for Kid.
I'm sure the museum owner who was arrested
for fraud this morning
will confess to everything.
He pretended the jewels he
sold were stolen by Kid,
and he planned to collect the insurance
money for the jewels as well.
Did you come to the MPD
today to confirm that?
No, actually.
I was asked by a different inspector
for advice on another matter.
Another case?
Regarding the locked room murders that
have taken place over the last month.
There're no apparent connection between the
ages and professions of the three victims,
and they were killed by different methods,
so I was told they're unsure if they
were killed by the same culprit.
Those murders everyone's
talking about right now?
You're involved in that as well?
As an advisor.
I actually returned to Japan to
take on less work and recharge,
but I have absolutely nothing to do.
Do you think you'll be
able to solve the case?
Yes.
I was just given a summary of the
case and shown crime scene photos,
so I was able to solve the locked room
trick by the time I got down here.
What?
What?!
I haven't identified the culprit yet,
but I believe I'll know by
this weekend's TV special.
What?
T-TV special?
You mean you don't know?
Next Saturday at 8PM,
I'll solve the mystery on
"Emergency Live Broadcast!
8PM | [Emergency Live Broadcast!]
Locked Room Murders Solved!
Locked Room Murders Solved!"
broadcast by Toto TV.
Until I saw the crime
scene photos at the MPD,
I planned to deduce what might be
possible based on the information I had.
Th-That's not my station,
but I'm looking forward to it.
Oh, you're from Nichiuri TV.
Nichiuri TV
Excuse me.
It's fine.
Well, I should get going.
Wait, Sensei.
One last question.
This time you proved Kid
had been falsely accused,
but do you have a message for him?
Well...
If you're grateful for what I did,
I'd appreciate it if you could buy my novel.
If you gave me your address, I
could deliver you a copy myself.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
A locked room mystery has
the world in an uproar!
The mystery will be solved on live TV!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kudo Yusaku's Detective Show
(Part One)
"Kudo Yusaku's Detective Show, Part One!"
Beika Pharmacy
3 Days Later...
What?
He dramatically announced during a TV
interview that he'd solve the case,
but he's stuck in bed with a stomachache?
Yup. Yu-chan isn't feeling any better.
Did he eat something bad?
Well, last night Yusaku and I
visited the Italian restaurant
that left a flier in our mailbox.
He's been feeling under
the weather ever since.
Then he should go to the hospital.
He's planning to go if he's still
not feeling better tomorrow.
Don't blame me if his stomachache
gets worse because he took his time.
But the TV staff are coming over tonight.
For the program he mentioned on TV,
"Emergency Live Broadcast!
Locked Room Murders Solved!"
You should turn them down.
Dad's not feeling well.
But the producer is the person who
first adapted Yu-chan's novel for TV.
It's hard to say no to him.
That's why we invited you, Shin-chan.
What?
How does that follow?
Wait, could it be?
Are you going to disguise yourself as Dad
and have me provide his voice
using my voice changer?
Yu-chan was supposed to go
to the MPD this afternoon
and explain the truth behind the case,
but he got sick before then.
I see.
Since Dad hasn't told you the solution yet,
you invited me over to
show me the case documents,
so I could solve the case for the show.
Ding ding ding!
I knew you'd figure it out.
You're absolutely correct.
Unbelievable.
Fine.
So, when do the TV staff arrive?
The broadcast starts at eight, but they
said they'd come over around six to set up.
That's four hours from now.
It's all right.
It should be a piece of
cake for you to solve.
You're really not worried about this.
Yu-chan solved the case in three minutes,
so four hours should be plenty for you.
Yeah, yeah.
Kudo
Wow, you're right.
Dad's really out of it.
Right?
At least he's hydrating.
You better go to the hospital tomorrow
even if he's feeling better.
We will.
By the way, where's
Subaru—I mean, Akai-san?
He had some kind of FBI business to
take care of and isn't here right now.
If he were here, I might not have
bothered to invite you over.
Why don't you summarize the serial
locked room murders for me, then?
The first murder took place 20 days ago.
As you know, the body was discovered
by that new announcer...
Yumekawa Saiko, who frequently conducts
interviews using a pink mic, right?
Yumekawa Saiko
Newbie Announcer
That's right.
She's coming tonight for the special.
The murder victim was her friend
Morita Atsumi-san, 24 years old,
Morita Atsumi (24)
Clothing Making Employee
who worked for a clothing maker.
The day she found the body,
Yumekawa-san suddenly received a message
from Morita-san asking for help.
She rushed to Morita-san's apartment,
but no one answered when
she rang the doorbell.
Since the door was locked,
she explained the situation to the
property manager and had him unlock it.
That makes this a locked room? Maybe
she gave a spare key to someone.
Yumekawa-san had a spare key,
but the locked room wasn't the entryway.
It was the bathroom where she found the body.
The bathroom?
Yeah.
Morita-san died when someone pushed her
and the back of her head hit the sink.
The bathroom door was locked.
The door could only be
locked from the inside.
Here it is.
So it's a thumb-turn lock.
The scene looks like a mess.
Yeah.
Most of the items on the
shelf had been knocked down,
and on the floor there was a bag containing
lotion, a hairdryer, a toothbrush,
makeup, hair clips, and a bath brush.
When the police broke down the door,
the items on the floor
were pushed to the side.
The next murder happened ten days later.
Kiryu Taiji-san, a 31-year-old
permanent part-timer,
was killed in his apartment.
Kiryu Taiji (31)
Permanent Part-timer
I say part-timer,
but he was a recluse living off
the money his parents sent him.
The body was found just inside the entryway.
Apparently the place was so full of trash
that it was hard to tell
where the entryway ended
and where the rest of the apartment began.
There's a lot of stuff on the floor in
front of the door at this scene, too.
Yeah.
Convenience store bags, half-empty plastic
bottles, empty cup noodle containers,
and disposable chopsticks.
Huh?
There's a photo of his apartment
after the entryway photo.
It looks pretty tidy.
Well, there are empty cup
noodle containers on the table
and garbage bags scattered around,
but the figures and games
on the shelf are organized.
It feels like someone opened a
garbage bag and threw trash around.
Oh, right.
He made all the dolls on the shelf himself.
They're characters from
some kind of online game.
Look.
See the photo on the shelf?
He won a silver medal at a figure-making
contest with that doll.
That's Rock, a character from
online game Dungeon Holmes.
What? Shin-chan, you know what that is?
Yeah.
You enter dungeons as a group
and solve mysteries with Rock.
Huh.
So, how was he killed?
There was a small burn
on the back of his neck
and signs that he'd been
strangled with a rope.
It seems like he was knocked
out with a stun gun
and then strangled from behind.
But he regained consciousness
during the attack and fought back.
There were bits of the culprit's
skin stuck under his fingernails.
They found that kind of evidence?
Yeah, but they still don't
know whose skin it is.
The third murder took place the next day.
The victim was Kanzawa Koretsugu-san,
47 years old, who runs a bakery.
Kanzawa Koretsugu (47)
Bakery Manager
He was killed in the kitchen
of a house in Beika City.
He was stabbed to death.
After stabbing him in the back with a knife,
the culprit stabbed him again in
the stomach when he turned around.
Did he live alone?
No?
He was married, but they were separated.
His wife went back to her
parents' house in Kyushu.
When his wife visited to discuss
divorce, she found his body.
Whoa!
There's junk in front of the door again.
There's the knife used as a weapon,
a ladle, tongs, a spatula,
and a frying pan.
They're all cooking utensils.
Kanzawa-san baked test products at home
and had all kinds of utensils.
You're right.
There are several frying pans and
other utensils hanging on the wall.
It looks like a restaurant kitchen.
Was this kitchen locked from the inside, too?
Yeah.
Like the first case, the room
couldn't be locked from the outside,
but he'd been stabbed to
death inside the kitchen.
The second victim Kiryu-san
also wasn't the kind of person
to hand out spare keys except to his parents,
so Yu-chan said the police thought all
three cases were basically locked rooms.
Well, the media are just saying
these three cases were committed
by the same culprit to stir up excitement.
They might just be three similar cases
that happened to occur one after another.
No.
This is a series of murders
committed by the same killer.
They used the same locked
room trick all three times.
No way.
You figured out the trick, too?
Yeah, it was easy.
If you solved the locked room trick,
then even if we can't identify the culprit,
we can still keep up appearances.
Huh?
Oh, I guess...
Then I'll go disguise myself as Kudo Yusaku.
There's more information in there,
so skim it while I'm gone.
Yeah, sure.
I'm pretty sure I know
who the culprit is, too.
Hey, Mom.
How long does it take you
to disguise yourself?
Hurry up. The TV staff will be here soon.
Hey, Mom.
At least answer me.
What's wrong, Mom?
Are you okay?
I'm fine. I was just taking a nap.
Could it be?
Did you eat the same
thing Dad had last night?
Of course I did. We're married, after all.
This is definitely food poisoning.
I need to turn down the TV show
and get them to a hospital.
Crap, the TV staff are here.
My voice changer's not done charging.
I'll have to explain the situation
and ask them to leave.
S-Sorry, but today we're...
What?
Y-You...
Could it be?
I'm home.
Mori Detective Agency
Sorry I'm late. I'll get
dinner ready right away.
There's no rush.
Yeah, but I want to take my time watching
the special that starts at eight.
Special? Oh, the one about
the locked room murders.
Yeah, "Locked Room Murders Solved!"
Shinichi's dad is going to solve
the case, so I can't miss it.
I'll make something right away.
Why did they reach out to a novelist
and not a great detective?
A-Are you...?
Come on, now.
I came to help because I couldn't
ignore the trouble Kudo Yusaku was in,
and this is the welcome I get?
I'm here to repay him for clearing the
false accusations made against me.
I knew it. You really are Kaito Kid.
Well, if I'm not welcome,
then I'll be leaving.
No, wait!
I-If you want to repay the favor,
then I'm not opposed to the idea.
You tsundere brat.
In any case, the TV staff will be
arriving in less than ten minutes.
I'll explain the case to you. Come inside.
Roger that.
By the way, how'd you know my dad is sick?
I happened to overhear your
conversation at the pharmacy,
while I was following you
so I could repay the favor.
I didn't think his wife would be ill, too.
Yeah. It seems to be food poisoning, so
I'm having them rest in their bedroom.
Crap, the TV staff are here.
The case documents are in
the tablet on the desk.
Read those while I deal with the staff.
Say, do you live here?
In that case, I don't
mind receiving the staff.
Whatever you do, don't say
anything uncalled for.
Sure thing. You can count on me.
Good evening.
I'm Yumekawa Saiko of Toto TV.
I'm looking forward to this
evening's live broadcast.
Well, well. So you're Yumekawa-san?
You're beautiful.
Didn't we meet the other day when I came
here to discuss the program schedule?
Ah, I meant I hardly recognize you.
Young women grow more beautiful by the day.
Oh, my.
Let's have them start getting ready
for the broadcast, Yusaku-ojisan.
Ah, yes.
We'll be borrowing your study.
Go right ahead.
Don't do anything uncalled for.
Kudo-sensei.
It will take some time to finish
setting up the equipment.
Could you get your makeup
done in another room?
Actually, I did my own
makeup. I'm good to go.
Y-You did?
His disguise will be exposed if
someone tries to do his makeup.
By the way, Kudo-sensei.
I've been wondering about something.
I feel like I've seen this boy before.
Oh, he's...
I'm Edogawa Conan, the famous Kid Killer.
He's an acquaintance's child.
He wanted to see how the
program was broadcast.
I see.
By the way, where's your wife?
She said she wanted to make an appearance
during our meeting the other day.
Oh, uh...
Yukiko-obasan is sick in bed.
Sh-She is?
That's too bad.
Please tell her I hope she gets well soon.
Thank you.
I'll let you know once we're ready.
Understood.
How are they?
They seem to be doing better, but I
need to get them to a hospital soon.
The quickest way would be to skip the
TV broadcast and call an ambulance.
That said, I can't allow the
man who saved me to lose face.
Why don't you summarize the case for me?
Sure.
The first victim was
clothing maker employee...
Mori Detective Agency
Episode Preview
At the first crime scene, there was a bag
containing something in front of the door.
At the second crime scene, there was a
convenience store bag containing something.
But there was no bag at
the third crime scene.
We have no choice. We'll do it live.
I'll transmit my voice to this earphone.
Don't play dumb.
After all, the culprit behind
these serial murders is...
Kudo Yusaku's Detective Show
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is "Kudo
Yusaku's Detective Show, Part Two!"
In Front of the Door
Next Conan's hint!
In front of the door!
Dad, you've had too much to drink.
Don't miss the next episode.
Who cares? It's New Year's.
Actually, it's almost February.