[op]
[ed]
[eyecatch]
DETECTIVE CONAN EPISODE 1072 "Kudo
Yusaku's Detective Show (Part Two)"
My dad was supposed to solve a series
of locked room murders on a TV special,
Nichiuri
Metropolitan Police Department
but he got sick and stuck in bed.
My mom who planned to
disguise herself as my dad
and solve the mystery in his
place ended up stuck in bed, too.
This is definitely food poisoning.
I need to turn down the TV show
and get them to a hospital.
Crap, the TV staff are here.
My voice changer's not done charging.
S-Sorry, but today we're...
What?
Y-You...
Could it be?
Come on, now.
I came to help because I couldn't
ignore the trouble Kudo Yusaku was in,
and this is the welcome I get?
I knew it.
You really are Kaito Kid.
Well, if I'm not welcome,
then I'll be leaving.
No, wait!
I-If you want to repay the favor,
then I'm not opposed to the idea.
You tsundere brat.
Why don't you summarize the case for me?
Sure.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
Solving a case on live TV!
Dark shadows approach behind the scenes!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Kudo Yusaku's Detective Show
(Part Two)
"Kudo Yusaku's Detective Show, Part Two!"
The first victim was Morita Atsumi-san,
who worked for a clothing maker.
Morita Atsumi (24)
Clothing Maker Employee
She was killed in the
bathroom of her apartment.
She died when someone pushed her and
she struck the back of her head.
Yikes!
This is pretty brutal.
The body was discovered
by Morita-san's friend,
the announcer you just met,
Yumekawa Saiko-san.
What? She found the body?
Yeah.
Yumekawa-san received a message from
Morita-san asking for help
and went to her apartment.
She found her murdered in the bathroom,
which was locked from the inside.
I see.
So it's a thumb-turn lock.
Most of the stuff on the shelf next
to the sink has been knocked down.
Makeup, hair clips, and a shopping bag
are scattered in front of the door.
Notice anything?
What?
Didn't you say you're good at solving
cases involving contraptions?
The only question I have
is why are there hair clips
on the floor when the
victim's hair is very short?
What's the matter?
Have you lost your touch?
Shut up. Show me the next one.
The next victim was permanent
part-timer Kiryu Taiji-san (31).
Kiryu Taiji (31)
Permanent Part-timer
He was killed in the
entryway of his apartment.
And this room full of
garbage was locked, too?
This door also uses a thumb-turn lock.
Huh? But the other rooms are pretty tidy.
You noticed that, too?
Yeah.
Maybe someone deliberately opened a garbage
bag and scattered trash around the place.
Judging by how tidy the
dolls on the shelf are,
the victim seems like he
actually kept things clean.
He seems to have made those dolls himself,
so it's possible he just kept those tidy.
They're figures for an online
game called Dungeon Holmes.
The giant magnifying glass she's
carrying is her trademark.
Huh.
So, have you figured it out yet?
Well, the disposable chopsticks on top of the
trash bags in the entryway caught my attention.
They're upside down in their pouch,
and the bottom of the pouch is folded oddly.
That's all?
I'm telling you, I'm a
thief, not a detective.
So, who's the third victim?
Kanzawa Koretsugu-san, who ran a bakery.
Kanzawa Koretsugu (47)
Bakery Manager
He was killed in the kitchen
at his home in Beika City.
His wife, who he's separated
from, came to visit.
She discovered the body in the kitchen,
which was locked from the inside.
And of course this kitchen
has a thumb-turn lock, too.
The victim's clothes are covered in blood.
Was he stabbed?
Yeah.
See the bloody knife on the
floor in front of the door?
First he was stabbed in the back with it.
When he turned around, he
was stabbed in the stomach.
How was the second victim killed?
He was strangled.
After knocking out the
victim with a stun gun,
the culprit strangled him from
behind using some kind of rope.
But he regained consciousness
during the attack,
and fought back so hard the culprit's
skin got stuck under his nails.
I see.
So, notice anything?
At the first crime scene, there was a bag
containing something in front of the door.
At the second crime scene, there was a
convenience store bag containing something.
There were bags containing
something at both scenes,
but there was no bag at
the third crime scene.
But you could say in its place,
there's a frying pan instead.
Strangely, the pan on the floor is black,
but for some reason all the cooking
utensils hanging from the wall are silver.
And?
Huh? That's all I've got.
Seriously? So you can't solve it?
Who cares? You already know the answer.
Tell me the culprit's
identity and trick already.
First, the culprit is...
Huh?
Come in.
Excuse me. Kudo-sensei, we're ready.
Could you come out here, please?
Sure. I'll be right there.
Thank you.
We have no choice. We'll do it live.
I'll transmit my voice to this earphone.
Just say what I tell you to say.
Roger that.
Mori Detective Agency
The mystery deepens in this
series of locked room murders.
It's started.
Tonight we're broadcasting with
the special advisor on the case.
Reporter Yumekawa-san.
Yumekawa Saiko
Newbie Announcer
Hello.
I'm currently at the home of world-renowned
mystery author Kudo Yusaku-sensei.
Conan-kun said he'd be staying
over at the professor's house.
He's not watching this in person, is he?
Why in the world would they ask a writer to
solve a case instead of a great detective?
Let's get Kudo Yusaku-sensei's thoughts
on the series of locked room murders.
People are calling this a serial murder case,
but the victims were killed
using different methods,
and there's no connection
between any of the victims.
Were they really all killed
by the same person?
Yes, certainly.
After all, the same locked room
trick was used in all three cases.
Furthermore...
Furthermore, all three victims
were in fact connected.
What? Th-They were?
Yes. Since they're police
photos, I'm unable to show you,
but there was a logo featuring
a magnifying glass
printed on the towel hanging from
the shelf at the first crime scene.
At the second scene were several figures
holding magnifying glasses
made by the victim himself.
The same magnifying glass design
was on the third victim's watch.
This magnifying glass is the trademark
of online game Dungeon Holmes.
All three victims probably
played the game together.
R-Really? I had no idea that game existed.
Oh? I doubt there's any way
you're not familiar with it.
After all, you suddenly swapped
your mic to your other hand
so you could hide your left wrist
and the very same watch that's on it.
Th-This watch was a gift from Atsumi.
I'm just wearing it because
the design was interesting.
Don't play dumb.
After all, the culprit behind
these serial murders is you,
Yumekawa Saiko-san.
What?
Mori Detective Agency
Th-This watch was a gift from Atsumi.
I'm just wearing it because
the design was interesting.
Don't play dumb.
After all, the culprit behind
these serial murders is you,
Yumekawa Saiko-san.
What?
What?!
Toto TV
Please Stand By
It cut out.
Um, Kudo-sensei? You're joking, aren't you?
What? Oh, um...
Excuse me.
You should've told me from the
start that she was the culprit.
What was I supposed to do?
The show started before I
had the chance to tell you.
In any case, just say what I tell you to say.
Fine.
Excuse me.
I suddenly hid this watch because I
didn't want you to unfairly suspect me.
If you're accusing me,
then show me the evidence.
Let's put a pin in the culprit's identity.
I'll begin by proving this
series of locked room murders
were committed by the same person
by explaining the locked room trick.
Toto TV
Please Stand By
I wonder what happened.
The higher-ups probably
shut down the broadcast
when one of their employees
was accused of murder.
Yeah...
We apologize for the inconvenience.
The show has been interrupted
by technical difficulties,
so the live broadcast will be ending.
What?
Seriously?
Or so I thought, but...
Keep going!!
We will continue the broadcast as scheduled.
These are sets of the
area in front of the door
at the three crime scenes
I had set up beforehand.
As you can see, all three are rather untidy.
Besides that, the three crime scenes
have three things in common.
First, there's a thumb-turn lock
above the handle of each door.
Second, there's a hair clip,
chopsticks upside down
inside an oddly bent pouch,
and tongs at each scene.
They're all things that can be used to
grip something and hang something off of.
And finally,
there's something bag-like that
could be attached to those
and filled with something with some weight.
B-But there's no bag in the kitchen
at the third crime scene.
Believing it would be suspicious if bags
were present at all three scenes, you—
Rather, the culprit used
a frying pan instead.
As proof,
the other cooking utensils
in the photos are all silver,
but the one on the floor in
front of the door was black.
Unlike the bags, the length of
the pan couldn't be adjusted,
so the culprit purchased a pan of the exact
right length as well as tongs beforehand
and brought them to the crime scene.
But don't take my word for it.
Allow me to demonstrate how you can
actually lock a room using these objects.
What do you think, Dad?
Will it really work?
Who cares? If it doesn't,
he'll embarrass himself.
First, attach the hair clip, chopsticks,
and tongs to the thumb-turns on the doors.
Hang the handles of the bags off their
ends and place them on top of the handles.
Hang the ring on the end of the pan
off the tongs, and you're ready.
Carefully exit the rooms so the objects
don't fall off the handles and close the doors.
If you turn the handles,
the objects on top of them fall, causing
the thumb-turns to rotate, and...
Wow.
The doors actually locked.
A-And?
Why do you think I did it?
You made several mistakes.
The black frying pan is one,
but you also ransacked the room to camouflage
the bag and hair clip you used in your trick.
However, even though the second
and third shelves were ransacked,
for some reason the first shelf wasn't.
There was a bath brush on the floor.
I can easily imagine a short person using it
to make it look like the work of a tall person.
Scattering trash around Kiryu-san's apartment
to camouflage the bag and chopsticks was fine,
but you went too far when
you opened the trash bags
to put empty cup noodle
containers on the table.
All the chopsticks in the containers were
leaning on the left side of the cup.
This is something left-handed people do,
but Kiryu-san was right-handed.
You're left-handed, aren't you?
What?
Most announcers use their dominant
hand to point their mic at someone.
That watch on your left hand
is also for left-handed people.
The crown is on the opposite side that
it would be for a right-handed watch.
Furthermore, most people wear watches on their
non-dominant hand so it doesn't get in the way.
Additionally, judging by its size,
it's unnatural for even a woman
to wear it facing inwards.
You probably did that because Kiryu-san
fought back during the second murder.
Yes, that's right.
If only he'd died while still
passed out from the stun gun.
But he fought back so fiercely.
I thought a bandage would seem suspicious,
so I used my watch to hide
it, but it was still obvious.
I killed them because I told
them through in-game chat
that I wanted to test the locked
room trick I'd come up with.
All three of them said it worked on their
doors at home and complimented my idea.
A scriptwriter was having
trouble coming up with a trick,
so I thought it was an opportunity
to make a name for myself.
But Atsumi used the trick in the online
novel she'd been writing for fun.
I asked her to delete it
right away and pushed her,
but she hit her head on the
sink and stopped moving.
I used the locked room trick
because I had no other choice,
but the other two began to
suspect my trick had been used,
so I told them, "If it's not you or me,
then the culprit must be the other guy."
"Let's meet up to discuss it."
Then I met them at their
homes and killed them.
Oh, you're quite prepared.
More importantly, why did you
agree to report on this case?
You could've said you weren't over
the shock of losing a friend.
I couldn't sleep because I was
worried I'd be found out eventually.
I thought I'd be able to sleep soundly
if I could fool Kudo Yusaku face to face.
I was shocked when I received
your call, Yusaku-kun.
This afternoon your wife called to say you
couldn't come to the MPD because you were sick.
As you can see, I've recovered,
but now my wife's stuck in bed.
Section 2's Nakamori actually said he
wanted to come so he could thank you.
But he doesn't have time for that anymore.
Did something happen?
Oh, right. You haven't seen the news.
Kaito Kid just appeared in Shibuya earlier—
What? That's not possible.
C-Conan-kun? What are you doing here?
I just happened to stop by.
Anyway, the Kid spotted in
Shibuya was an impostor.
Right, Kudo Yusaku-san?
But Nakamori-kun said tonight's
Kid was definitely him.
Seriously?
If that was the real Kid, then who's
been disguising himself as Dad?
You're late, Vermouth.
Sorry.
Rum asked me for a favor.
Someone who might become a
threat to the organization
is staying in Japan for some reason,
so I went to investigate.
So, what was he like?
Disappointing.
We could kill him anytime.
You didn't kill him?
No, not today.
But if necessary,
I'll kill him anytime.
Hey, wake up!
Vermouth might've been
here until a moment ago!
It's possible you got sick because
Vermouth poisoned you with something!
Huh?
Akai-san?
Dad? Mom, too? Why?
Jodie and Camel, status?
No bugs or hidden cameras in the study.
Nothing in the other rooms either.
I knew we could count on a
best-selling author's plan.
We managed to fool her.
We can't let our guard down yet.
What's going on?
When I told Yusaku someone's
been watching us lately,
he suggested we do something to attract
attention to see how they'd respond.
Then a suspicious flier for an Italian
restaurant showed up in our mailbox.
We went to check it out, and sure enough,
the food tasted a little
odd, so we had it examined.
There was distigmine bromide in the food.
So you didn't eat it?
No, we pretended to eat
it and stuffed it my bag.
Because of it, my favorite bag was a mess.
The symptoms of distigmine bromide
consumption resemble food poisoning,
nausea, vomiting, stomach pain,
diarrhea, and perspiration.
So we pretended to have those
symptoms to lure in their allies
and showed them we're completely
unguarded and have nothing to hide.
You should've told me that.
"To fool your enemies, you
must first fool your friends."
And Sharon seems to like you.
At least the fear they'll
attack this place is gone now.
Yeah. Now just have to prepare
for them to make a major play.
Episode Preview
You got here quick.
I was in the area gathering
information when I heard sirens.
Someone was robbed.
A man's body was found nearby
at an izakaya in Haido City.
Does that mean he's the purse-snatcher?
Could it be?
Yeah, this case didn't just happen.
It was a premeditated murder.
The Detective Boys' Pursuit
of the Purse-snatcher
The next episode of Conan is "The Detective
Boys' Pursuit of the Purse-snatcher!"
Apartment Complex
Here's the next Conan's hint!
An apartment complex!
Mystery writers are amazing.
Don't miss the next episode.
But great detective are a world "apart."
I think you might be confused.