Beika Bakery
Aw, darn.
They didn't have it here either.
Huh?
I wonder why he was in such a hurry.
10 Minutes Later
Someone help!
Thief!
Kume Shosaku (68)
I just saw someone
in a red jacket run that way.
That way?
What's wrong?
Someone stole a bag containing
the 300,000 yen I'd withdrawn.
I chased after the culprit
as quick as I could,
but I lost sight of them.
I ended up here after asking
people if they'd seen them.
You called the police, right?
Oh, right. I should call the police.
I know. I'll call the others, too.
Metropolitan Police Department
Detective Takagi?
You got here quick.
I was in the area gathering
information when I heard sirens.
Someone was robbed.
What?
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
The Detective Boys chase
after a purse-snatcher,
only to discover a shocking truth!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Detective Boys' Pursuit of the Purse-snatcher
"The Detective Boys' Pursuit
of the Purse-snatcher!"
The culprit who stole the bag
from Kume Shosaku-san
apparently fled into an apartment complex.
Did they really run in there?
Maybe they ran through it to a side street.
Officer, help!
There's s-someone on the ground over here!
Samura Koichi (33)
Yes, we're almost certain it was murder.
Yes, sir.
Hey, that's my bag.
And that's the red jacket
the culprit was wearing.
Does that mean he's the purse-snatcher?
I don't think so.
He couldn't have run on that leg.
And I think the culprit had longer hair.
Could you confirm this is yours?
T-The envelope containing 300,000 yen
and my wallet aren't here.
Does that mean the purse-snatcher
was someone else who murdered that man,
abandoned their conspicuous red jacket,
removed the money and wallet
from the bag, and fled?
Probably, but why did they
come to this apartment?
February 11th
Management company coming in AM
So he had guests coming over today.
Samura Koichi,
the resident of this apartment,
appears to have several
previous extortion offenses.
So he was a serial blackmailer.
How is the murder of this scoundrel
connected to the purse-snatching incident?
This is Megure.
At Haido City?
Understood. I'll be right there.
A man's body was found nearby
at an izakaya in Haido City.
Next to the man's body were
an envelope containing 300,000 yen
and Kume Shosaku's wallet.
Does that mean he's the purse-snatcher?
Izakaya Toriko
Izakaya & Yakitori Toriko
Could you confirm this is yours?
That's definitely mine.
So he really was the purse-snatcher.
This store is closed today,
but an employee who came to get
something they'd forgotten found the body.
Togane Katsumi.
This man was quite the scoundrel as well
and a friend of Samura Koichi.
He died after consuming a poison.
Togane Katsumi (32)
Based on this note he left
with the stolen money,
I killed my friend
for betraying me.
Farewell to this
cursed life!
we can guess what happened.
Togane Katsumi robbed the victim
near an apartment complex
in Beika City and fled.
He went to his criminal friend
Samura Koichi's apartment
in hopes that he would harbor him.
He became angry when
Samura rejected his request,
and Togane killed Samura
using a knife at the scene.
He abandoned his bloody jacket,
removed the envelope and wallet
from the bag, and came to this izakaya.
Betrayed by his friend Samura Koichi
and having now committed murder,
he killed himself here out of desperation.
That's probably what happened.
Let's get this body autopsied.
Thank you for walking me home.
You've been through a lot today.
First you were robbed,
and then you saw a corpse.
Your family will be shocked
to hear the story.
Oh, I don't have any family.
Kume
I lived in Tamage City forever until
I moved here to Beika City five years ago.
Six months ago, my wife
passed away from an illness.
Be careful on your way home, kids.
Kume
So Kume-san is all alone.
Seems like it.
Sounds like there's still
something bugging you.
Why did he decide to kill himself
at a closed restaurant
instead of his own home?
You're right.
That poorly-written suicide
note seems off to me, too.
Maybe he wrote it
with his non-dominant hand.
He could've tripped while fleeing
and hurt his dominant hand.
Arms up.
That's possible, but the note
wasn't so necessary
that he'd need to write one
with his non-dominant hand.
You're not wrong.
Right?
A murder?
So that's why there are
so many police cars around.
I might have to reduce the rent
on Building B Room 301 because of it.
Are you from the management company?
Do you manage this apartment complex?
Y-Yes, I do.
You're lucky you didn't get involved.
What?
You were supposed to visit Samura-san
in Building B Room 301, right?
What? No, I wasn't planning on doing that.
What?
B-But...
What about that?
Management company coming in AM
Someone pretended to be from the management
company and contacted Samura-san.
Probably so he wouldn't leave his apartment.
And Samura Koichi-san was murdered.
Could it be?
Yeah, this case didn't just happen.
It was a premeditated murder.
Eliminate fraud!
Crackdown in effect
Prevent Traffic
Accidents
MPD Beika Police Station
I see. I suppose that's possible.
You're right.
This is Megure.
Yes. Yes.
What?!
I see. Understood.
According to the autopsy,
Togane's time of death was
an hour earlier than Samura's.
They died in the opposite order?
Then Togane didn't kill Samura.
So who killed Samura-san?
That question needs answering, too, but...
Huh? Then what about
that note Togane-san wrote?
It said he was killing himself
because he killed Samura.
So that's how it is.
Togane didn't commit suicide. He was killed.
Most likely.
Samura's death was a premeditated murder.
Togane's death was a murder
made to look like a suicide.
Both deaths need to be re-investigated.
Yes, sir!
Made to look like a suicide?
That would explain what was bugging me, too.
The culprit must've needed that suicide note
to make the murder look like a suicide.
The culprit deliberately wrote
with terrible handwriting
to disguise their handwriting.
The culprit wanted the body to be discovered
so the investigation would
conclude it was a suicide.
But if it was found too soon, the precise
time of death would be determined,
ruining the idea that
Togane-san killed himself
because he murdered Samura-san.
That's why they chose
to kill him at that izakaya.
Izakaya Toriko
Izakaya & Yakitori Toriko
Since the store was closed today,
the body would be found tomorrow.
They were supposed to
have a whole extra day.
Yeah.
But because an employee came
to get something they'd forgotten,
things didn't go as planned,
and Togane-san's body was discovered.
I see.
So that's what happened.
Then the person wearing
the red jacket that I saw
wasn't actually that Togane man.
That's right.
By the time you saw them,
he was probably already dead.
If we review the culprit's actions,
we may find a clue leading to them.
First the culprit poisoned
Togane-san at the izakaya.
Then they stole the bag from Kume-san.
They visited Samura-san pretending to be
from the management company
and killed him.
Then they took the money and wallet.
And left them next to Togane-san's
body alongside the suicide note.
What we don't know
is why the culprit killed Togane
Katsumi-san before Samura Koichi-san.
Even though their times of death
would create an inconsistency.
There must've been some
reason he needed to do it.
Was there a related incident?
You've got a keen eye, Conan-kun.
It's an extortion incident
related to Samura Koichi.
A young woman killed herself because
she was being blackmailed by Samura.
I'm re-investigating this case.
I see. Good luck with that.
What?
Setoguchi Asako-san
was the victim in that case.
Victim Name: Setoguchi Asako (24)
Address: Tamage City North Ward 1073-151
It happened five years ago in Tamage City.
Isn't that...
Yeah. It's where Kume-san used to live,
and he moved away five years ago.
It might be a coincidence, but...
He's involved in the case, after all.
Setoguchi
Hello.
We're looking for the home of Kume-san.
Setoguchi Sakie
What? He moved away a while ago.
So he did live around here.
You must've been close
since you were neighbors.
I'm sorry, but I'm in
the middle of something.
She avoided talking about Kume-san.
Kume-san and her daughter's
tragedy might be related.
We'll just have to ask the locals.
What? We're walking more?
This is exhausting.
I see. Thank you.
So that's how it is.
Kudo-kun.
How'd it go?
The daughter was engaged.
I didn't learn anything else.
It's hard to believe they're unrelated.
Kume-san and his wife moved away
immediately after the daughter's suicide.
Suddenly, as though fleeing from something.
But what does that have
to do with this case?
I don't know the motive yet, but I have
a rough idea of what happened.
But why did the culprit kill Togane
Katsumi-san before Samura Koichi-san?
What?
You went all the way to Tamage City
to investigate Kume-san?
You think he did it?
You think he was working with the culprit?
Rather than explaining it to you,
there's something I want to check.
Hey, what's that?
Building B
Where the culprit went
after killing Samura-san.
The culprit entered Building B from
the location where Ayumi-chan saw them
Building A
Building B
Sidewalk
Main
Street
Side
and then headed to the exit.
Building B
They left Building B, entered
the side street from here,
and then headed towards Haido City.
Building B
Side
Street
Building A
What are you looking for in here?
Whoa! The floor looks like
it's going to fall through.
Be careful.
I thought they might've hidden
something here on the way.
Hidden what?
A yard...
A fresh mound?
What's this?
They used this to bury it.
Which means...
The culprit's jacket?
And this is Kume-san's bag, right?
But the police currently have those
in their possession as evidence.
Why is there another set of those here?
What's that shaggy thing?
Is this it?
Looks like a long-haired wig.
Is there a mask and sunglasses, too?
Yeah, they're probably buried here.
Call Detective Takagi right away
and explain the situation.
I've got somewhere to go.
What?
Don't touch the evidence.
Kume
What is it that you figured out?
The culprit had to kill Togane-san
before Samura-san, right?
If they waited until after they
were robbed and called the police,
they'd be stuck with the police
and wouldn't be able to do anything.
They'd have to explain
how they were robbed, too,
and once the bag was found,
they'd be asked to confirm it was theirs.
Pretending to be a victim is hard, isn't it?
There never was any robbery.
I went to Tamage City, too.
Having decided to kill the two of them,
you took Togane Katsumi-san
to that restaurant
so the body would be discovered the next day
by saying something to lure him there.
Then you poisoned him.
You wedged an envelope containing
300,000 yen, your wallet,
and a suicide note beneath
the body and left the place.
Then you pretended to be
with the management company
and killed Samura Koichi-san.
You left a bag and jacket there.
Then you donned a second
matching jumper, wig, and mask
and carried a second bag to disguise
yourself as a purse-snatcher.
You ran into the apartment complex
as though fleeing a robbery,
ran through the complex
and onto the side street,
and buried the things you'd used
at an abandoned house.
Thief!
Then you showed up as a robbery victim
chasing after a thief and
re-entered the apartment complex.
In other words, you played two roles.
By acting as both the culprit and victim,
you convinced the police
that you'd been robbed
and made it seem as though
Togane Katsumi-san was the thief
and killed himself after killing
his friend Samura Koichi-san.
That was your plan, right?
Playing two roles requires a tight schedule.
You prepared a second jacket
and bag to leave behind
and killed Samura-san before you ran into
the apartment complex as the culprit, right?
But I still don't know your motive.
It's probably related to the incident
with Setoguchi Asako-san.
Five years ago,
my wife and I saw Asako-chan
arguing with a man.
Setoguchi Asako (24)
My wife was concerned,
but I figured it was just an argument
between a married couple.
I calmed her down, and we walked away.
Several days later,
Asako-chan killed herself.
When I heard from her parents
that she was being blackmailed,
I regretted my actions.
If I'd noticed then, she wouldn't have died.
You left Tamage City because you
couldn't bear to stay any longer.
The other day, I saw
that man—Samura Koichi.
Anyway, the girl I snared
the other day at the club is rich...
He was plotting something evil with Togane
Katsumi, who seemed to be his friend.
They were planning how to take advantage
of the young woman who was their next target.
I thought more victims would appear
if they were allowed to live.
But you still shouldn't have killed them!
We've collected the evidence buried
at the abandoned house.
Kume-san was about to turn himself in.
Oh, right. Ayumi-chan, what
were you doing here this morning?
I heard they sold them around here,
so I wanted to find them
and let Genta-kun know
that I'd found the eel bowl buns.
What?
Eel bowls baked into bread?!
Eel bowl buns?
Where are the eel bowl buns?!
He sure has a weakness for eel bowls.
But eel bowl buns...?
What?
The eel sauce would seep into the bread.
Does this food actually exist?
It might actually be pretty good.
The bread seems kind of unnecessary.
Huh?
Episode Preview
Thank you for coming,
Detective Mori, Ran-san,
and Edogawa Conan-kun, the little detective.
We'd like your help with the boiled fugu pot.
The pot was stolen the other day.
Please find our family treasure
and bring it back to us.
The next episode of Conan is "The Boiled Fugu
Mystery Tour Showdown, Mojiko & Kura Part!"
The Boiled Fugu Mystery Tour Showdown
(Mojiko & Kura Part)
Kanmon Straits
Next Conan's hint.
The Kanmon Straits!
Wh-Where are you, eel bowl buns?
Don't miss the next episode.
Next week we're having boiled fugu.