DETECTIVE CONAN EPISODE 1074 "The Boiled
Fugu Mystery Tour Showdown (Mojiko & Kura Part)"
[ed]
[eyecatch]
Wasn't this job referred
to you by the lawyer Oi,
who we met during Morikawa-san's
inheritance dispute?
Yeah.
Like last time, I'm being paid a fortune.
The client is a long-standing restaurant.
They're in Shimonoseki.
And it's a long-standing
restaurant, which means...
Fugu sashimi and boiled fugu.
Whitebait and jellied fish.
Porridge to round it off.
And fish fin sake.
I'm so excited!
JR Shin-Shimonoseki Station
Oi Hiroki (36)
Lawyer
Thank you for coming.
I've been waiting for you.
Hello.
Detective Mori, Ran-san,
and Edogawa Conan-kun, the little detective.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
Exquisite delicacies and mysteries,
swirling around the Kanmon Channel!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Boiled Fugu Mystery Tour Showdown
(Mojiko & Kura Part)
"The Boiled Fugu Mystery Tour
Showdown, Mojiko & Kura Part!"
Shimonoseki.
The largest city in Yamaguchi, located
on the westernmost end of Honshu.
As everyone knows, it's the home
of Japan's greatest fugu dishes.
The Kanmon Channel dividing
Shimonoseki from Northern Kyushu
is known as one of Japan's
three great tidal currents.
The tide's speed reaches ten knots,
Hinoyama Park Summit
making it difficult to navigate
boats through the channel.
The tides are surging like crazy.
What a magnificent sight.
Apparently ten knots is about
18.5 kilometers per hour.
Conan-kun, this time the
client is a fugu restaurant
that's been in business in
Shimonoseki for over a century.
He's the fourth generation owner
of the Izumiya restaurant,
and he's requested that...
Could you describe the nature
of the job to me, please?
Oh, excuse me.
This is organic boiled fugu from Shimonoseki.
I heard fugu is called "fuku" in Shimonoseki.
Ah, you know your stuff.
Go ahead.
Thank you!
So good!
It's delicious.
Organic food sure tastes different.
It tastes so clean and refined.
We'd actually like your help
with the boiled fugu pot.
What?
Izumiya Makoto (58)
Restaurant Owner
The Izumiya family has been operating
this restaurant since the Tokugawa Era.
There's a special pot we've been using
since the restaurant was founded.
It was made by a celebrated potter
and is valuable as a work of art.
Recently we'd been storing it in our vault
outside of special occasions, but...
The pot was stolen the other day.
Izumiya Kaede (22)
Makoto's Daughter
Please find our family treasure
and bring it back to us.
I see. I understand.
You can count on me.
Thank you.
This is a photo of said pot.
I see. So this is the pot.
The pot was stolen on February 19th.
We believe it was stolen
between 19:00 and 20:00,
when the restaurant is busiest
and nobody is at home.
The thieves destroyed the
safe and stole only the pot.
By the way, what is the
approximate value of this pot?
Works made by the same potter are worth
no less than several million yen.
But its value isn't the reason
we're determined to get it back.
Then why?
Because of the broth.
The broth?
The umami of the fuku has seeped
into the surface of that pot
that's been used to cook only the finest
fuku since the restaurant was established.
Even if the same ingredients were used,
the depth of the flavor would
be different in another pot.
That pot is steeped with
flavor and tradition.
We're lost without that pot.
Additionally, Izumiya-san
will be participating
in this weekend's "Boiled Fugu Grand Prix,"
with his fourth consecutive
championship on the line.
"Boiled Fugu Grand Prix?"
Famous restaurants from Tokyo, Osaka,
and all around the country get
together to compete at this event.
Those within the fuku culinary scene believe
winning this event to be the highest honor.
Do you have any idea who
might've stolen the pot?
Allow me to explain.
The police investigation identified
four possible suspects.
The first is Kobayashi Yasushi,
who works in a restaurant.
Kobayashi Yasushi (27)
Part-time Employee
He was arrested two years
ago when he robbed Izumiya.
The second is Fujii Shinichi, who manages
a Japanese restaurant chain called Kan.
Fujii Shinichi (43)
Restaurant Chain Company Manager
He previously failed to buy out Izumiya.
The third is Daiehara Satoru, who runs
the restaurant King Arthur in Moji.
Daiehara Satoru (34)
Restaurant Owner and Chef
He's a business rival.
He knows of the Izumiya's treasured pot.
Finally, there's Ban Keisuke.
Ban Keisuke (24)
Former Izumiya Restaurant Employee
He previously worked at
Izumiya, but was fired.
That pot is our family's treasure.
My father can't confidently compete in
the Boiled Fugu Grand Prix without it.
Mori-san, please help us.
I see. In that case, you can count on me.
The great Mori Kogoro shall
recover your treasured pot.
Dad, you said they could count on you,
but do you know who the culprit is?
We're on our way to investigate
that now. Right, mister?
Yeah.
Anyway, just how well-prepared
is that lawyer?
Shimonoseki Marketplace
Lively Karato Marketplace
He even acquired police documents and
personal information on the suspects.
That's Kamon Wharf.
Kamon Wharf
Kobayashi Yasushi, the man who robbed
Izumiya two years ago, works there.
Are you the one who wanted to see me?
You're Kobayashi Yasushi-san, correct?
Y-Yes.
A detective? I wish you hadn't
bothered me at my job.
I already talked to the police.
Don't worry, I'll leave as soon
as you answer my questions.
Make it quick.
Then allow me to be direct. Did you do it?
I was arrested two years ago when
I broke into that restaurant.
Why would I do something so
risky when I'm on probation?!
Do you have a verifiable alibi
for when the crime took place?
I was with my coworker Kato!
He even testified to the police!
What were you doing with your coworker?!
Shopping!
Damn it!
I've been stuck living this life ever
since that incident two years ago!
Because of the information I was
fed then, my life has been...
What information?
Mind your own business.
We're done, right?
If you've got no other questions,
then get out of here.
Hey, Kobayashi.
Coming!
JR Kokura Station
The next suspect runs a
company near Kokura Castle.
Since Kokura Castle is right next
to the station, we can walk there.
Kokura Castle
Japanese Restaurant Kan
So you're the famous detective.
Kan
You're restaurant chain Kan owner
Fujii Shinichi-san, correct?
Yes, that's me.
I heard you failed to purchase Izumiya.
Yes.
I thought I made them a good offer,
but they rejected the deal.
Why did you try to buy Izumiya?
The restaurant industry is like
the late-Tokugawa Era revolution.
Just as former rivals Satsuma
and Choshu formed an alliance,
true victory awaits beyond our expectations.
Boiled Fugu Grand Prix Open!
Huh?
Your restaurant's participating in
the Boiled Fugu Grand Prix, too.
You've got a sharp eye, kid.
I thought it'd be better to
win over my rival Izumiya-san
rather than make an enemy out of him.
By the way, what's your alibi for
between 7PM and 8PM on February 19th
when the theft took place?
I was entertaining guests that night.
The restaurant staff and company president
I was hosting should be able to verify that.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Japanese Restaurant Kan
Not at all. Don't worry about it.
Where are we going next?
To the King Arthur restaurant.
It should be nearby.
Is Daiehara-san a suspect as well?
Do you know him?
Yes. We work in the same industry, after all.
Oh, right.
If you suspect us,
then you'll have to solve the
mystery of the Kanmon Channel.
The mystery of the Kanmon Channel?
Apparently the police examined
the security camera footage...
...of the Kanmon Tunnel footpath, roadway,
Kanmon Tunnel
Shin-Shimonoseki and Shimonoseki
station platforms,
Mojiko Retro
and ports from the day of the theft.
We didn't appear in any
of the camera footage.
In other words, if you want to arrest us,
you'll have to explain how
we got to Honshu from Kyushu,
without appearing on any security cameras.
It's me, Kobayashi.
I was just visited by a detective.
Yeah, I know.
I'm counting on you.
You'd better not betray me.
Kanmonkaikyo Museum
King Arthur
Wow, what a stylish restaurant.
Thank you.
Here we develop new dishes that are a
fusion of Western and Japanese cuisine.
Daiehara-san, forgive me,
but you apparently asked Izumiya-san
to give you his family's treasured pot.
Yes.
I was impressed by the boiled fugu
dish I ate that was made in that pot.
Did you think he'd give it to you?
No, I expected him to say
no, which he did in fact do.
By the way, what's your alibi
for the day of the theft?
My restaurant was closed that day.
I was visiting my contracted farmers in
Northern Kyushu in search of new ingredients.
I'd like to get the contact
information of those farms later.
Very well.
Also, do you have anything that would
prove you were visiting the farms?
In that case, how about this photo?
You can see this photo was taken in
the evening of the day of the theft.
I see. That's what you call a perfect alibi.
I needed photos for a magazine article.
You injured your foot.
It's embarrassing to admit,
but I carelessly broke
my foot three months ago.
I just got the cast off the other day.
I see. Could I get a copy
of this photo as well?
Yes, I'll send it to you right away.
I'll send you the medical certificate
for my injury later as well.
Thank you.
Well, excuse us.
King Arthur
I hope you'll stop by to eat next time.
We will.
I'd love to eat at a stylish
restaurant like this one.
Another time.
Jeez.
Chofu Moritei
Yes, I was fired from Izumiya,
but that doesn't mean I would rob them.
By the way, why were you fired?
Izumiya didn't tell you?
So, what was the reason?
K-Kaede approached me.
What?
She wouldn't leave me alone.
When I told her I couldn't go out with her
because it would interfere with my job,
for some reason I was fired.
Is that really true?
I doubt Kaede would say that.
By the way, what's your
alibi for February 19th?
I was drinking at an izakaya
called Uzushio that day.
I'm a regular there, so the
staff would remember me.
Hello?
We talked to all the suspects.
Did you figure out who did it?
Not yet. First we're going
to verify their alibis.
I see. I appreciate your continued efforts.
Got it. See you later.
What are you doing? We'll leave you behind.
Mister, where are you going
to start your investigation?
Isn't it obvious?
At the izakaya.
Izakaya Uzushio
Ban-chan, huh?
He was here that day.
I remember it well since he
kept buying expensive drinks.
He said his friend won some money
at the races and was treating him.
Do you remember what time he arrived?
What time was it?
Do you remember, Eri-chan?
I'm not sure. I know it was at night.
It's pretty important that
we know what time he arrived.
Since you came all the way from Tokyo,
why don't you stay for dinner?
Today's specials are Spanish
mackerel and monkfish liver.
The problem is their alibis.
Even an alibi that seems
perfect at first glance...
could be using some kind
of trick to hide a lie.
I see.
That's an astute observation, Mr. Detective.
Mister, what kind of reputations
do Fujii-san and Daiehara-san have?
Fujii-san's place is pretty successful.
If he wins the Boiled Fugu Grand Prix,
his profits will probably increase even more.
Daiehara-san's restaurant is stylish.
It'd be a great place to go on a date.
Izakaya Uzushio
In other words, the alibis are the key.
I see. Of course, Mr. Detective.
Honshu's here, and Northern Kyushu is here.
Kobayashi, Fujii, Daiehara, and Ban are here.
And Izumiya is here.
Kobayashi
Daiehara
Fujii
Ban
Izumiya
These are the places they claimed
to be on the day of the theft.
Though they all have alibis,
they also all have motives.
The old man is right.
There are two culprits on either
side of the Kanmon Channel,
and there's something suspicious
about each one of them.
Was it Kobayashi, Fujii, Daiehara, or Ban?
But perhaps there's another possibility.
What?
Izumiya could've faked it himself,
or it might've been his daughter Kaede.
Really?
I'm just saying it's possible.
So, who did it?
I wanna know.
Izakaya Uzushio
My detective skills are
telling me the culprit is...
Mumble, mumble.
What?
He named the culprit in
his drunken ramblings.
This fried fuku is so good.
Thank you for coming.
I think our hotel was that way.
Kaikyo Yume Tower
Hello, Oi-san?
I thought I'd report on a development.
Apparently Izumiya received an anonymous tip.
A tip?
Yes.
According to the tip,
the coworker who verified
Kobayashi Yasushi's alibi lied.
You're saying they received a phone call now?
Yes, that would seem to be the case.
Oi-san, I actually have a request.
Go ahead. I'm listening.
What was that?
Hold it right there!
Hey, Ran!
Is something the matter?
The culprit might've approached us.
Sorry. I'm hanging up.
Stop!
Where did they go?
I shouldn't have run right after a meal.
Damn it.
Where did they go?
Don't go sticking your nose
any deeper into the case.
Dad!
Dad? Dad?
Damn.
Episode Preview
By the way, are you glad Izumiya-san's
special pot went missing?
I'm not a good man.
He's probably heading towards...
As long as I'm participating,
of course I don't want to lose.
"Soon you shall learn that beneath
the waves of the Mimosuso River
there lies another city."
The Boiled Fugu Mystery Tour Showdown
(Shimonoseki Part)
The next episode of Conan is
"The Boiled Fugu Mystery Tour
Showdown, Shimonoseki Part!"
Battle of Dan-no-ura
Next Conan's hint!
The Battle of Dan-no-ura!
They say eating fugu is good luck.
Don't miss the next episode.
But it's also like playing
Russian roulette...