DETECTIVE CONAN EPISODE 1075 "The Boiled
Fugu Mystery Tour Showdown (Shimonoseki Part)"
[op]
[ed]
[eyecatch]
We accepted a job for a restaurant
in Shimonoseki through the lawyer Oi.
The client hired us to find their
treasured cooking pot and get it back.
During the investigation,
we encountered someone who might be
the culprit in the city at night.
We thought the case would
be solved instantly,
but instead, the old man was
attacked by the culprit.
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
The boiled fugu smells awfully suspicious!
What secrets are hidden
in the Kanmon Channel?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Boiled Fugu Mystery Tour Showdown
(Shimonoseki Part)
"The Boiled Fugu Mystery Tour
Showdown, Shimonoseki Part!"
In order to disprove the testimony of
Kobayashi-san's coworker and the izakaya owner,
as well as the alibis of
Fujii-san and Daiehara-san,
we need to prove how they
crossed the Kanmon Channel.
How did they cross the surging Kanmon Channel without appearing on any security cameras?
Doctor.
Is my father all right?
He's got a large bump on his
head, but it's not serious.
He'll make a full recovery in two weeks.
Dad...
Hey, Ran. Sorry for making you worry.
I was so worried about you.
You're not seriously injured?
As you can see, I'm completely fine.
I shall continue my investigation.
Um, Mori-san.
Izumiya Kaede (22)
Makoto's Daughter
Izumiya Makoto (58)
Restaurant Owner
There's something I need to tell you.
What is it? Is it related to the case?
Yes. The truth is...
Dad, are you sure you're okay?
Of course I am. A little
spit's enough to fix this.
And besides...
The attack proves our investigation
is headed in the right direction.
That's right.
So, what are you going to do now?
Well...
Why don't we get something to eat first?
Good idea.
What?
There's a restaurant I want to visit.
Kokura Castle
Hello, Detective. It's good to see you again.
Fujii Shinichi (43)
Restaurant Chain Company Manager
This kid insisted on coming here.
Thanks for the food.
What do you think, Ran-neechan?
It's good.
The ponzu is mild, and the grated daikon
and pepper serves as a nice accent.
You're right, but it doesn't
compare to Izumiya-san's dish.
Hey, don't be rude.
I don't doubt it.
I know I don't stand a chance against
him at the Boiled Fugu Grand Prix.
If I want to win,
I'll have to choose my ingredients
carefully and modify my recipe.
By the way, are you glad Izumiya-san's
special pot went missing?
I'm not a good man.
I prefer having an advantage
over a fair fight.
That said, I'm not so desperate to
win that I'd break the law to do it.
King Arthur
Here's the medical certificate.
I see. It clearly says "full
recovery expected in three months."
I hope it helps clear me of suspicion.
Hey, mister. Does this
restaurant serve boiled fugu?
Not boiled fugu, but we do
serve something similar.
Daiehara Satoru (34)
Restaurant Owner and Chef
Thank you for waiting.
This is acqua pazza made with channel fuku.
Wow.
What a luxurious dish.
Have a taste.
It's our specialty.
Thanks for the food.
It's so good.
Normally fuku has a fresh clean
taste, but the flavors are so deep.
It's like the umami of the fuku and
vegetables are layered or blended together
in a complex manner.
Daiehara-san, why didn't you
enter the Boiled Fugu Grand Prix?
What?
Why?
Because this isn't a Japanese restaurant.
I see.
But if you did enter...
If I were participating, of
course I wouldn't want to lose.
Of course.
Mojiko Station
Hello?
What? Kobayashi fled?
Kobayashi Yasushi (27)
Part-time Employee
He packed his things and
is trying to go somewhere.
Oi Hiroki (36)
Lawyer
I confirmed with his employer that
he skipped work without notice today.
He's probably heading towards...
Driver, take us to Shin-Shimonoseki Station.
Hey, kid.
You're not in command here.
What are you talking about?
I'm just doing what you told me to do.
Oh, I know.
Your memory must be fuzzy because
you hit your head yesterday.
Dad, I'm impressed you knew
Kobayashi-san would try to run.
Anyone would want to flee if
their alibi were disproven now,
especially if they had a criminal record.
Isn't that what you said, mister?
Uh, yeah.
Wait!
Mister!
Stop!
Take this!
Dad!
Dad, you're still injured.
Don't push yourself. Wait here.
Ran!
Wait!
You don't have to run.
Of course I do. If I don't
run, I'll be arrested.
That's not true. Kogoro-no-ojisan will—
You don't know that.
But I do.
After all, you're just
being used by the culprit.
What?
You received a phone call, right?
Telling you to flee because we
figured out you faked your alibi.
How do you know that?
Izumiya-san received an anonymous
tip claiming your alibi was a lie.
Then I really am screwed.
But don't you think running would
be playing into the culprit's hands?
The culprit probably committed the crime
on a day they knew you'd have no alibi,
and expected you to fabricate
one because you're on probation.
Conan-kun?
That's what Kogoro-no-ojisan said.
He also said that the same
person instigated you
to commit theft two years ago.
It's highly probable that
was part of this plan, too.
Then what should I do?
It's simple.
Trust Kogoro-no-ojisan.
He'll solve the case with
his great detective skills.
That said, I can't identify the culprit
until I solve the greatest mystery in this case.
Akama Shrine
Is that Ryugu Palace?
No, that's Akama Shrine.
It's a famous power spot.
Emperor Antoku is enshrined at Akama Shrine.
It's also famously the setting of
the tale of Hoichi the Earless.
Emperor Antoku?
He's the 81st emperor and
a mere eight years old.
He was the shortest-lived emperor and
the only one to die during battle.
In the Battle of Dan-no-ura, he drowned
himself in the sea with Nii no Ama
and the three sacred emblems
of the Imperial Family.
"Soon you shall learn that beneath
the waves of the Mimosuso River
there lies another city."
They say she recited those words to the
young Emperor Antoku out of sympathy.
I see.
So that's how it is.
What? Did that help you figure something out?
Yeah, something Kogoro-no-ojisan
secretly told me.
Oi-san, could you gather all the suspects?
It seems Mori-san identified the culprit.
Also, there's something he'd like confirmed,
and he has a request for everyone.
That's what he told me.
Understood.
One more thing. He'd like to meet at...
If memory serves, the Boiled Fugu
Grand Prix final is this weekend.
I asked that you come here today
at Detective Mori-san's insistence.
This is rather theatrical, isn't it?
What are we planning on doing here?
Why, naturally...
A cooking showdown, of course.
I asked everyone to make the
necessary preparations beforehand.
I'm sure each of them has
their own culinary secrets.
I see.
Ban Keisuke (24)
Former Izumiya Restaurant Employee
What am I doing here?
But will this help us identify the culprit?
You have ten seconds remaining.
Nine, eight, seven, six, five,
four, three, two,
time's up.
All their dishes look so good.
Now that they're done
cooking, it's time to taste.
My memory is so fuzzy.
The Sleeping Kogoro...
Now that the dishes have been completed,
let's get to solving the case.
The theft of Izumiya-san's cooking pot begins
with the attempted robbery
that happened two years ago.
After successfully inciting Kobayashi-san
into committing the crime,
the culprit planned this
theft after his arrest
and carried out their own crime
after making careful preparations.
Not only did they steal the pot,
but they also framed Kobayashi-san.
They thought everything had
gone off without a hitch,
but they actually dug their
own grave by over-preparing.
What do you mean by that?
In this case, all the suspects had alibis,
though Kobayashi-san's turned out to be fake.
Kobayashi-san was removed
from the list of suspects
because he was accused of faking his alibi.
This was a mistake on the culprit's part.
After all, only the culprit would have
left an anonymous tip at this time.
Furthermore, Ban-san can also be
excluded from the list of suspects.
Me?
You stalked Kaede-san so persistently
that you should've been
arrested by the police.
What?!
You took advantage of Kaede-san's kindness
not to turn it into a police matter.
You're lying!
That's bullshit!
Kaede loves me!
She belongs to me!
I never stalked anyone!
Kaede is—
I should've done this from the start.
She began going to a boxing
gym to learn self-defense
after Ban-san was fired.
I see.
I doubt a man as impulsive as him
could've carried out this theft.
Exactly, which leaves only Fujii-san
and Daiehara-san as suspects.
And it was you who stole Izumiya-san's pot.
Isn't that right, Daiehara-san?
This is no joking matter.
I wasn't captured by any of the
cameras in the Kanmon Channel.
Correct.
You weren't on the footpath, road,
station platforms, or ports.
Then how did he get to Honshu?
It's simple.
Daiehara-san swam across the Kanmon Channel.
Nobody can swim across the Kanmon
Channel in the middle of winter.
That's right.
Not only that, but I can't swim.
Even a poor swimmer can do it.
With a drysuit, you can even
swim in the Antarctic Ocean.
And with the suit's buoyancy and fins,
even a poor swimmer can swim across.
That photo you sent me of you
at the contracted farm...
You were wearing not a watch but a
dive computer on your right wrist.
I was able to confirm that
you have a diving license.
Even so, it's impossible for someone
to swim across such rapid currents.
Do you know why the Heike were
defeated at the Battle of Dan-no-ura?
The Battle of Dan-no-ura?
I know.
The tides changed, didn't they?
That's right.
The superior Heike forces
were counterattacked
by the Genji when the tides turned.
Their forces were utterly destroyed.
Daiehara-san, you waited for the tides to
turn and swam across the Kanmon Channel.
The tides change four times a day.
A quick search would reveal
when the tides would change.
Isn't that right?
I'm impressed.
But it's impossible.
After all, my foot was broken.
According to your medical certificate,
it's been two months and 15
days since you suffered a break
that would be fully healed in three months.
I'm currently on the second day of
my own two-week recovery period,
but as you can see...
In other words, your medical
certificate isn't an iron-clad alibi.
Maybe my alibi isn't iron-clad,
but there's no conclusive
evidence that I did it.
Are you sure about that?
Oi, if you would.
Please taste his dish.
Hey, nobody told me Izumiya
would be tasting my dish.
Dad.
There's no mistaking it.
This dish was cooked using that pot.
Using that pot?
There were many conceivable motives,
but what would the thief do
once they acquired that culinary
treasure with such an elaborate plot?
They wouldn't be able to resist using it,
especially not when their
dish would be evaluated.
I knew someone like you
would bring that pot here.
Only because that lawyer
said there'd be a contest.
It's here.
Sounds like there was conclusive
evidence after all.
What will you do?
Will you confess?
Fine. I did it.
But if it won't be mine,
then I'll destroy it.
Daiehara-san was ultimately
arrested for theft, right?
Yeah, sounds right.
I doubt he'll be able to get out
of prison that easily, though.
That's what Oi-san told me.
Well, in any case...
That was close.
It's a good thing the pot didn't break.
Yeah.
Episode Preview
A dying message?
Perhaps Komoto-san made a
living by blackmailing people.
And he attempted to blackmail someone, but...
Does this Innami Juichi-san fellow have
anything to do with Utagawa-san's blackmailing?
Maybe Komodo-san was trying to
say something about Innami-san.
Someone that would make him a lot of money?
The Charismatic CEO's Secret Plan
The next episode of Conan is "The
Charismatic CEO's Secret Plan!"
Putter
Here's next Conan's hint!
A putter!
Don't miss the next episode.
I'd love to go on a trip
that doesn't involve a case.
Don't be ridiculous.