Utagawa Corporate Headquarters
At this rate, I'll be forced into bankruptcy.
Utagawa Tosuke (42)
Utagawa Corporation CEO
It's time to go big or go home.
10 Days Later
You're here again?
We couldn't help it this time.
We're the ones who discovered the body.
I see.
We've identified the victim
based on his license.
Komoda Akira-san, 25 years old.
Komoda Akira (25)
He was a resident here in Beika City.
So his name was Komoda.
You knew him?
Not really. He visited my
apartment yesterday morning.
Izumi Tomoe (70)
Apartment Landlady
Okay, okay. We're going.
He was struck once on the head
with this metal pipe.
The estimated time of death
is around 9PM last night,
but this is the most notable detail.
A dying message?
Normally a victim writes the culprit's name.
But it also looks like the numbers 1-1-2.
It could also be read as
the hiragana for "i" or letter "z".
We have no idea what it means.
What was he trying to tell us?
Mysterious clouds block your field of view!
Clear them away with deductive
reasoning and the sky sparkles!
A charismatic CEO's sweet seduction!
His life depends on this performance!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Charismatic CEO's Secret Plan
"The Charismatic CEO's Secret Plan!"
Was there anyone who hated Komoda-san?
I don't know much about him.
Otake Minoru (60)
Apartment Manager
He didn't seem to be working.
Komoda-san didn't have a job?
He just hung around every day
at the big park down the street.
How did he pay for his living expenses?
Who knows? He was behind on rent, too.
Come to think of it,
yesterday afternoon he said...
I'll pay off all my unpaid rent tomorrow.
I found a way to make some big money.
Perhaps Komoda-san made a
living by blackmailing people.
And he attempted to blackmail someone, but...
His would-be victim killed him.
If that's the case, then who did he blackmail?
Oh!
Did something come to mind?
He looked at the magazine
I was reading and said...
Hey, there he is.
Who?
He's filthy rich. He should
expect to be a target.
I believe this was the article.
Showing off his treasures
Utagawa enjoys tuning up antique music boxes
"CEO of the Utagawa Corporation, which
engages in a broad range of business,
Utagawa Tosuke."
Maybe Komoda-san tried to
blackmail this Utagawa-san.
He must've sniffed out some dirt on him.
Let's go check it out.
Yes, sir.
Komoda Akira?
I don't know him.
That's a suspicious laugh.
And it sounds like he's lying.
Once again, last night around 9PM
you were alone at your home.
In other words, you have
no one to verify your alibi.
I'm single, after all.
Sir, you shouldn't keep them
waiting any longer.
What am I supposed to do?
These officers won't let me go.
Excuse us for interrupting
your busy schedule.
Come back any time.
He certainly feels suspicious.
But since we don't know what
Komoda-san was using to blackmail him,
we can't ask him about it.
Come to think of it, Komoda-san said he
found the information yesterday, right?
Maybe it has something to do with
that person we met at the crime scene.
What does? Hey!
What's going on?
Hey, wait. Hey.
Okay, Sally-chan.
I've been looking for you.
Oh, the boy from this morning.
You said earlier that Komoda-san
visited you yesterday morning, right?
Why did he come to visit you?
He came to ask about Innami Juichi-san,
one of my former residents.
Come to think of it,
I'd forgotten to take it down.
Innami Juichi...
What did you two talk about?
Let's see...
Innami-san had been gone for about ten days.
When he finally came back last night,
he said he was moving.
Did he say where he was moving to?
He said he'd let me know later.
The company he worked for
previously went bankrupt,
so maybe he found a new job
with an employee dorm.
And now he's disappearing, huh?
Does this Innami Juichi-san fellow have
anything to do with Utagawa-san's blackmailing?
I wonder what kind of person Innami-san is.
Would you like to see? I have video of him.
There was a big accident
in the neighborhood last month.
I was interviewed for TV
because I happened to witness it.
Look, that's me.
Could you tell us what you saw?
I was so shocked.
It suddenly came speeding through,
and then there was a terrible crash.
But the real trouble started after that.
This is Innami-san.
What?
If there's a man who looks
exactly like Utagawa-san,
and Komoda-san was looking for him...
You said Innami-san
suddenly moved out, right?
Yes, the other night.
You can dispose of all my belongings.
That's fine, but this is rather sudden.
And nobody knows where
Innami-san's been since.
So that's how it is.
He really does look just like him.
Maybe Komoda-san was using
Innami-san to blackmail him.
What do you mean?
Utagawa-san hired this man
who looks just like him
to be his substitute to fabricate alibis.
Utagawa-san must've been up to no good.
And Komoda-san somehow found out
about it and blackmailed Utagawa-san.
It's certainly possible.
Since he was being blackmailed,
it must've been something criminal.
If that's the case, then Utagawa-san
must be a pretty terrible person.
Not only was he committing crimes,
but he killed his blackmailer Komoda-san.
Were those the only things he was doing?
What do you mean?
Once Utagawa-san was through using
Innami Juichi-san as his substitute,
he became a nuisance.
Perhaps he secretly killed him.
But if he suddenly went missing,
it could spell trouble for him.
So he disguised himself as Innami-san...
You can dispose of all my belongings.
And told the landlady he was moving.
It doesn't make sense for him to suddenly
move without telling her his new address.
Then I feel sorry for Innami-san.
Utagawa-san might have a hand
in three different crimes.
If we can prove he did even one of them,
it might lead us to proving the other two,
but we don't have any evidence.
Wouldn't using a substitute leave some
kind of suspicious evidence behind?
But we don't know when and where
Utagawa-san used his substitute.
We can probably narrow it down.
He told the landlady he was
moving two nights ago,
so it would've been that day
or the day before.
And when using a substitute, the more
people to verify your alibi, the better.
He would've made him appear
in front of a bunch of people.
Contact the Utagawa Corporation.
See if the CEO attended any large
events on the 9th or the day before.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Only one event fit the description.
On the evening of the 9th,
there was an award ceremony
for a photo contest held by the Utagawa
Corporation which Utagawa attended.
An award ceremony...
That must've been when it happened.
He had his substitute Innami-san attend
while Utagawa was off getting up to no good.
But we need evidence that
he fabricated his alibi.
The event sponsors hand the winner
their award at award ceremonies, right?
That's it.
Forensics Department
Thumb               Index              Middle                Ring                Pinkie
Right Hand
Fingerprints
Left hand
We'll compare Utagawa's fingerprints...
Award Certificate
Tsukinari Toshiya
Utagawa Corporation
CEO Utagawa Tosuke
Against the sponsor's fingerprints on
this award we borrowed from the winner.
If they belong to different people, then
we can prove he fabricated his alibi.
It's a match.
What?
So the award ceremony was attended
not by the substitute Innami-san,
but by the real Utagawa.
We narrowed it down to the wrong event.
Are you sure about that?
But the fingerprints were a match.
So he didn't use a substitute? Then...
Could it be?
That would explain everything.
Komoda-san's message was
a person's name after all.
And it was probably...
Komoda-san's apartment is this way, right?
You want to visit it again?
Maybe Komoda-san's dying message is
the number 11 and the kanji "otsu".
11 refers to Innami-san.
11 = ju-ichi = Innami Juichi
Maybe Komoda-san was trying to
say something about Innami-san.
What does "otsu" mean, then?
Remember what the manager said earlier?
He just hung around every day
at the big park down the street.
This must be that park.
Otohime Park Map
He was trying to write "Otohime Park".
In other words, while hanging
around this park as he always did,
Komoda-san witnessed an event
that had something to do with
Innami-san and Utagawa-san.
That might be what he used to blackmail him.
Someone that would make him a lot of money?
Could it be?
Looks like someone filled in a hole.
Hup.
I knew it.
Komoda-san was trying to tell us
that Innami-san was killed
and buried at this park by Utagawa-san.
No, actually—
He happened to witness the murder
and blackmailed Utagawa-san.
I'll let him talk for now.
Get him autopsied.
Chiba, go with the body.
Yes, sir.
What? The Inspector did?
Yeah. He asked you to look into that, too.
We found the body, but we don't have
any evidence proving Utagawa-san did it.
You're right.
In that case, I've got a good idea.
Utagawa Tosuke
I apologize for bothering you again.
I think I dropped something
when I was here earlier.
Hello? Yes?
The information Komoda Akira
was using for blackmail?
You might know where it is?
I'll head back right away. Excuse me.
That's not good. Before they find it...
You're too late, Utagawa-san.
I'm sure you planned to hide it elsewhere,
but we've already retrieved
Innami Juichi-san's body.
I visited you so you'd rush off to the
crime scene known only to the culprit.
And you led us right to it.
Innami-kun had to die.
But why?
Mori-kun?
He's already confessing.
You don't need to sleep.
Listen to me, Inspector.
It was ten days ago that Utagawa
Tosuke-san conspired to commit a crime
and carry it out.
He even planned how he'd get away with it.
He learned there was a man who looked
just like him through that news story.
He scouted Innami Juichi-san,
who happened to be looking for work.
He invited him to stay
at his house for training.
He had him copy his voice,
the way he spoke, and his mannerisms.
He had him memorize
information about himself
and had Innami-san attend
the award ceremony on the 9th
Utagawa Corporation
Photo Contest Award Ceremony
as his substitute
while he carried out his plan.
Wait a minute, Mori-kun.
The fingerprint analysis
proved that wasn't possible.
Everything went according to
Utagawa-san's plan up until that point.
His plan ended there.
Immediately afterwards, Utagawa-san
was killed by Innami Juichi-san.
He what?
What are you talking about, Mori-san?
I'm Utagawa.
Hello?
What?
It's Chiba, who's attending the autopsy.
Dental records showed the body
belongs to Utagawa Tosuke-san.
What?
That's right. He's Innami Juichi-san.
He used Utagawa-san's proposal to act as his
substitute to claim his wealth for himself.
He's still continuing to
pretend to be Utagawa-san.
What are you—
You gave yourself away.
I'm talking about your dominant hand.
Utagawa-san was right-handed,
and Innami-san was left-handed.
Utagawa-san was right-handed.
You pretended to be right-handed,
but during an emergency...
He used his left hand.
I see.
In other words, we never
met the real Utagawa-san.
You'd already swapped places.
I see. If he's Innami-san...
Then of course the fingerprints matched.
You probably plotted to take
Utagawa-san's place since he scouted you.
After acting as his substitute,
you asked Utagawa-san for a ride and
dragged him into this park on the route.
You killed him and buried the body.
And Komoda Akira-san, who happened
to be here, witnessed the event.
Two guys with the same face? But why?
Komoda-san, who had witnessed a murder,
followed you.
And now he's disappearing, huh?
When he learned Innami-san suddenly
moved away, he figured it out.
Innami-san erased his own existence
so he could become the wealthy
businessman Utagawa-san.
Komoda-san decided to blackmail you.
You pretended to comply with his
demands, but killed him instead.
Thank you.
Ow...
Komoda-san tried to tell us
the name of Utagawa-san's murderer
and the body's location.
In other words, Komoda-san
blackmailed not Utagawa-san,
but Innami-san instead.
And Utagawa-san didn't kill Innami-san.
It was the other way around.
That leaves just one mystery.
What did Utagawa-san do when he
had you fabricate an alibi for him?
Nothing at all. After all...
At this rate, my busy
schedule's going to kill me.
I need time off.
I'd like you to act as my substitute
every now and then so I can take a break.
So I said...
I'll give you the eternal break you desire.
And I became the top
executive of a corporation,
like I'd dreamed of becoming
since I was a kid.
It was give and take.
You think that excuses what
you've done? You killed two men.
He was killed by the substitute he hired
so he could have time for himself.
Poor Utagawa-san.
It's impossible to live someone else's life.
It'd be convenient if I had a doppelgänger.
I'd make him solve cases
while I got all the credit.
Just kidding.
You're already doing that.
I'm not your stand-in, though.
Episode Preview
Graduation Ceremony
MPD Police Academy
It's time to present the diplomas.
Graduating class representative Furuya Rei.
Yes, sir.
Police Academy Arc Wild Police Story
CASE. Furuya Rei
The next episode of Conan is "Police Academy
Arc Wild Police Story CASE. Furuya Rei!"
Next Conan's hint!
Onizuka's Class
Cherry Blossoms in Full Bloom
Instructor Onizuka Hachizo
Assistant Instructor Matsumoto Naota
Cherry Blossoms in Full Bloom
Cherry Blossoms in Full Bloom!
Conan-kun, next week...
Don't miss the next episode.
Those guys are coming back.