Furuito City 2nd Street
October 2nd 20:30
Tony sure is late.
He better not be stuck in line
at a popular ramen spot again.
O-Or maybe...
Did I read this code wrong?
You're finally here, Tony.
Sorry, but Tony said he can't make it anymore.
Damn it.
G-Gin...
Will you tell us where your hideout is?
I see. You won't.
Then you're useless to me.
Beyond detective skills
capable of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
The Black Organization closes in on the FBI,
while we get closer to the truth about Rum.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Black Organization's Scheme
(Hunt)
"The Black Organization's Scheme, Hunt!"
Wow, the bodies of two more
unidentified foreigners were found today.
Sounds scary.
Yeah. They found two yesterday, too, right?
I wonder why they can't
identify them, though.
The culprit probably took whatever
could've been used to identify them.
Since the bodies found yesterday
still haven't been identified,
those foreigners probably
entered the country illegally
or entered using fake names and identities.
I'm more interested in the fact that two
victims were found yesterday and today.
Yeah. Is it just a coincidence,
or did the culprit know where
they were meeting and attack them?
What?
Huh?
B-But we're on our way to meet
the professor at the park.
Will we be all right?
We'll be fine. It's got nothing to do with us.
Th-That was really loud.
Yeah. Did something fall?
It sounded like it came
from the next street over.
Conan-kun!
A foreigner.
Is he another victim in the foreigner murders
that have happened two days in a row?
Hey, Conan.
What happened?
We can't see.
Let us through.
No. Don't come any closer.
What?
Haibara, call the police and
an ambulance, just in case.
Got it.
If he's another victim in the serial killings,
then there must be another nearby.
Is he on top of the building?
Vodka.
He probably didn't want to
end up like his friend,
but I never thought he'd jump.
Maybe that FBI pest thought he could fly.
Haibara, take these guys back
onto the street we came from.
What?
Got it.
No fair, Conan-kun.
Just do as he says. Come on.
And Haibara...
Whatever you do, don't let your face be seen.
You know what that means, don't you?
Yes.
Come on, let's go.
Hey, let us see what's going on.
What did he mean by that?
It's a kid.
A kid wearing a hood approached the body.
What should we do?
I've got the shot.
Should we kill him, Gin?
Yeah. One shot, one kill.
Wait.
Crap, he's dead.
More onlookers have shown up.
No way.
The police arrived rather quickly.
We should give up on silencing
witnesses and get out of here.
But, bro, we still haven't taken his ID.
It's fine.
They've entered this country without
authorization to hunt us down.
I doubt they'll want to make
our existence known to the public
and get investigated themselves.
Though I'm sure it'll cause
quite the commotion.
You're right.
Let's get out of here.
Roger that.
Roger.
Hey, kid.
Should you be touching the body?
You'll get in trouble with the police.
How's it looking, Edogawa-kun?
Have you figured out who he is?
Yeah.
His name is Jim Mason.
Looks like he's an FBI agent.
FBI?
Yeah.
Is that for real?
No way. It's like a movie.
It must be a toy, right?
What's that?
It's a phone.
Was he typing a message just before he fell?
Huh? Is this a message?
Edogawa-kun, the people who killed him...
We'll discuss the details later.
Haibara, take the kids to
a nearby convenience store
and have the professor
pick you up in the Beetle.
What are you going to do?
I've got to make a stop someplace.
I'm going now. Bye.
Hey, wait.
Edogawa-kun.
Damn it. What's going on?
Akai-san's been busy, and my
parents won't answer their phones.
Did they come to my home?
The entryway looks normal.
I hear voices I don't recognize.
Not just one or two, either.
They're coming from the study.
What's going on?
We've tried getting in touch, but
we haven't received a response yet.
I see.
Oh, Cool Kid. You came, too.
Jodie-sensei and Camel-san.
Are these people...?
Yeah. They're all FBI agents.
What? But why?
Three days ago, an agent
named Aaron disappeared
while tailing a member of the Organization.
He was found dead the next day.
Then yesterday and the day before,
our agents were ambushed by the Organization.
We use a code to arrange meetings.
We think Aaron might have
told them how to decipher it.
We're staying here at the
Kudo house temporarily.
If he told them how to decipher the code,
it's possible he told them
the location of our headquarters.
I see.
It's only until we establish
a new headquarters.
Where are Yusaku-san and Yukiko-san?
They went shopping to feed us.
Ordering delivery for this many
would attract attention.
Some of our agents are skilled cooks,
so we'll manage as long
as we've got ingredients.
I see. No wonder no one
answered the land line.
But did Aaron really tell them
how to decipher the code?
I don't want to believe that, but...
No.
That's looking unlikely now.
I'm having someone watch
the hotel we were based out of,
but no one's surveying the hotel
from within a half-kilometer radius.
They would've gotten the location of
our headquarters and rounded us up
before asking him how to decipher the code.
Y-You're right.
Anyway, have you heard from Jim and Chen
who volunteered to go to the meeting spot?
Not yet.
The agent named Jim fell from
a building and died earlier.
Since Vodka was on the roof,
he may have been pushed.
What?
I just happened to be there.
I came here to let Akai-san know.
But if Aaron didn't tell them how to
decode it, then how did they know?
Maybe they de-encrypted
the coded messages normally.
After all, that code described the
location, time, and date of the meeting.
What?
Does that mean you were able to
read the code we're using?
Yeah. I took a picture and
was able to figure it out
this code that was on Agent Jim's phone.
That's hard to believe.
Can you print this out?
Yeah.
Could you print it on two B5 sheets, then?
Make one mirrored, please.
Ready?
This is the original code,
and this is the mirrored code.
On their own, they're indecipherable,
but when I looked closely,
even when mirrored,
I found a few characters that looked
like numbers or letters of the alphabet.
These slightly offset dots
made me think the lower half
of each line might be mirrored.
So if you remove the bottom half of
mirrored code, including the center line,
and lay it over the original code...
See?
It's a combination of upper and lower
case letters, but it seems legible.
The first thing that stood out to me
was this letter on the first row
between the I and A.
But since the abandoned building
he fell from was in Beika City,
judging by the letters around it,
you can tell this letter is K.
Beika
The next thing that stood out was this
little u and big U on the second row.
On the first floor of that abandoned
building was a store called "Cafe Guava,"
Cafe Guava
that served guava juice as their specialty.
If these letters spell guava,
then it's spelled g-u-a-v-a.
In other words, a small u is the
letter u, and a big U is the letter V.
If the numbers after Beika on
the first row express the address,
and the third row is the date and time,
then the code reads, "Beika
City 3rd street, lot 5."
"Cafe Guava, October 3rd, 16:00."
And that's the location
and time of the meeting.
Incredible. You're right.
So you printed the code earlier, and...
No, I put it together in my head
and thought that might be it.
What?
We'd been using a specialized tool to
mirror it, but you did it in your head?
Impressive, kid.
Then you could write messages in code.
I doubt he could handle the entire alphabet.
Sure I could.
What?
There were other coded
messages on Jim's phone.
One said, "Furuito City 2-1,
taxi stand, October 2nd, 20:30,"
so I know how you write an X, too.
In other words, the 26 letters
of the alphabet...
look like this.
It's scary how perfect it is.
If Jim and Chen saw you
solve the code so easily,
they would've have acted recklessly.
You mean the man who fell
from the abandoned building?
Those two came up with the code.
They wanted to prove it
couldn't be solved easily,
so they arranged to meet using the code.
I see.
In any case, we need a new code in a hurry.
W-Wait.
This might be an opportunity.
We could use this code to draw them out.
You're right.
If we surround the meeting place, we
could flank whoever takes the bait.
Isn't that right, Shu?
It's not a bad idea.
What do you think, kid?
I think it's a good plan.
I wish we could wait for Yusaku-san
to return and get his opinion, but...
But Jim and Chen's deaths
haven't been reported on the news.
This is our best chance, while
they think we still don't know yet.
The problem is, what
should we do about the code?
Jim and Chen had been making them until now.
I'll make them. I know how to do it.
All right. That leaves who we'll
send to the meeting point.
If we're not careful, they could end up
surrounded. It's a dangerous job.
E-Excuse me.
Could I do that?
At this rate, my brother
won't be able to rest in peace.
You're the late Tony's brother Mark.
I'm not a fan of acting on personal grudges.
It should be fine if I go with him.
If it comes to it, I'll shake them
off with my driving skills.
Camel.
Camel, if you're going,
take this hat with you.
What? I'll pass. It would look terrible on me.
Have you forgotten?
You drove the CIA's Mizunashi Rena, who's
currently undercover in the Organization.
They think you died in an explosion
when they got her back.
If one of them remembers what you
look like and learns you're alive,
Mizunashi Rena will be killed.
Don't forget that you and I aren't
supposed to be alive anymore.
Right.
What? You intercepted
another coded FBI message?
We just killed the FBI agents.
It'd better not be fake, Vermouth.
No. It looks like they haven't
noticed their agents were killed.
The location is Kadefu City 1-4,
parking lot, one hour from now.
It'll take less than 30 minutes
in your Viper, Chianti.
I'll be there in less than ten.
I'll head there with Kir.
Gin and Vodka, do what you always do.
Roger that.
We've got something big coming.
We should eliminate as many
pests as possible before—
Wait.
Th-That voice...
He's using a voice changer, but...
That's definitely him.
Our Organization's number two...
Rum.
Camel here.
Per the code, I'm waiting with Mark
in an underground parking lot
in Kadefu City 1st street, lot 4.
We're five minutes past the meeting
time, but they still haven't shown up.
Jodie-san, you didn't write
the code wrong, did you?
That's not possible.
I checked it numerous times.
Outside teams watching the
parking lot, what's the situation?
Bill and David here.
Zero people have approached
the parking lot building.
Jodie-san, are you sure you
didn't write the code wrong?
I vote for that, too.
Did something happen?
Bill, David. Please respond.
That's the sound of bullets
striking their target.
David's been shot. He's badly injured.
Shot? From where?
I don't know. We're getting out of here.
George here. They've got us surrounded, and—
The FBI agents are terrified.
Rum was right.
They've got another thing coming
if they think they can set us up.
George here. They've got us
pinned down. We can't get out.
Daniel here. I'm going to help George and—
Camel here. I don't understand what's going.
The outside teams getting shot one by one.
Understood.
We'll leave, too.
Be careful.
Wait, Camel.
Don't leave yet.
Target is fleeing southeast.
Don't let him escape, Chianti.
Gotcha.
Camel, Mark. Please respond.
Please respond, both of you.
Um, we bought ingredients.
It sounds like something happened.
Kudo
I see.
So you attempted to use this code
to lure out the Organization.
Yes.
But they knew what we were up to.
But how?
Who wrote this code?
It was Jodie-sensei.
Sensei? Jodie-san?
Since he called you sensei,
does that mean you previously
worked as a school teacher?
Yes.
I was an English teacher
at Teitan High School.
Not a grade school teacher?
No.
Though I do have a friend, Shibuya
Natsuko, who teaches grade school.
Did she teach you a lot of things?
Naturally, like Japanese.
I learned most writing skills
like kanji and hiragana from her.
I see.
A grade school teacher
taught her to write?
So that's how it is.
They knew because of what Jodie-sensei
learned from Natsuko-sensei.
Damn it. I can't believe I didn't notice.
Episode Preview
Where are they?
Where did they go?
A-A Porsche 356 A.
Gin.
At this time during this season,
the currents in the Tokyo Bay...
It must be Umizaru Island.
The Black Organization's Scheme
(Landing)
The next episode of Conan is "The
Black Organization's Scheme, Landing!"
Romaji
Next Conan's hint.
Romaji!
This is becoming a disaster.
Don't miss the next episode.
The sea is starting to look dangerous.
Seriously.