When I came across the
murder of an FBI agent,
I headed to my house to notify Akai-san.
A large group of agents
had sought shelter there.
The Black Organization had cracked the code
they'd been using to arrange meetings.
The decision was made to use that
against them and lure them out,
but we were ambushed
by the Organization instead.
Shots were fired on Camel-san's car.
Beyond detective skills
capable of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
A chase takes place
in the darkness of night!
What is Rum thinking as he goes for the kill?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Black Organization's Scheme
(Landing)
"The Black Organization's Scheme, Landing!"
That's it, Mark. Tie it tighter.
Damn.
We've got a problem on our tail.
The code I wrote revealed to the Organization
that the FBI had laid a trap for them?
You probably used kunrei-shiki romanization.
It's a system that prioritizes
consistent spelling,
and as such is taught in elementary schools.
Were you not taught this system
by your grade school teacher friend?
I was, but what did I get wrong?
The romaji for "fu."
What?
Kunrei-shiki romanization uses
the H-U spelling you wrote,
but in the Hepburn romanization
system used by the guys
who'd been writing the codes
until now, it's F-U.
The town name Furuito City that
appeared in the previous code
was spelled F-U-R-U-I-T-O.
In other words, Kadefu City
had to be spelled K-A-D-E-F-U,
but you spelled it K-A-D-E-H-U.
N-No...
And that raised their suspicions,
so they realized it was a trap.
I'm sorry. It's my fault.
You're not the only one to blame.
We didn't notice when we checked the code.
More importantly, is the agent
acting as a decoy all right?
Camel-san, was it?
It sounded like he'd been shot.
Judging by their voices, it was the agent
in the passenger seat, Mark, who was shot.
Camel's car is currently
heading south towards Kanagawa.
He can't shake his tail.
Hey, Camel. Can you talk?
Yes, I think so.
But we're being pursued by a Viper, so
I don't have much attention to spare.
It sounded like you'd been shot.
We were. A rifle bullet passed
through the right-side door
and became embedded
in the driver's-side door,
but it's not affecting my ability to drive.
However, the bullet struck
Mark's thigh when it passed through.
He's bleeding badly and urgently
requires medical attention.
Turn right at the next intersection,
left at the one after that,
and get onto Otaru Street.
But there's a lot of cars parked on that road.
It'll be harder to get through.
Understood.
Damn them, scurrying around like that.
Where is it? Where is it?
Where is it?
Found it!
Th-They disappeared?
Where did they go?
We seem to have lost them.
Camel here. I'm leaving Mark on Otaru Street.
Please pick him up later.
Damn it. Where did they go?
Japanese people are strange.
What?
A car was parked against
the direction of traffic. Strange.
You mean they hid among
those cars parked on the street?
You should've said so sooner.
Gin, we lost them. They're
probably headed your way.
No problem.
They just passed us.
I've got a new tail.
What's the make of the car?
A-A Porsche 356 A.
Gin.
There's a T-intersection up ahead.
Charge into it at full throttle
before he builds speed.
Turn either left or right.
Don't let him follow your trail.
Got it.
Bastard.
They accelerated.
A T-intersection?
Damn it. Which way are they going?
Left.
Turn left.
Left?
They're not here.
Go faster.
Damn.
That's them. They're up ahead.
But how?
When people are being chased,
they tend to turn left.
So do pests in a rush to get away.
I-It's no use. I can't shake him.
Stay calm, Camel.
Trust your skills.
Got it.
The bastard's entering Umibotaru.
Kir and Vermouth, they're in Umibotaru.
Enter from the Chiba side
and block their escape.
I've just exited the Umibotaru Tunnel.
I should be able to escape through Chiba.
Those FBI guys are a bunch
of disgraceful losers.
I think I've seen that guy before.
Is that true, Korn?
Yeah. I could remember
if I saw his face again.
I see...
Interesting.
Then we'll do whatever it takes
to find the body of that FBI agent
so we can see his cold, dead face.
Camel. Please respond, Camel.
Andre Camel!
J-Jodie-san?
Camel, you're alive.
I drove off Umibotaru in my car.
I'm currently underwater,
but I'm hanging in there.
For now, I'm going to exit my vehicle and...
Th-The door won't open.
The power windows aren't working either.
The water's already right beneath my chin.
What...
The door won't open because
of the water pressure.
The power windows aren't working either
because the electrical system is flooded
or because the water pressure is
pressing the glass against the frame.
I wouldn't bother trying to
escape by opening a window.
B-But...
Then break the window, Camel.
Is there anything in the glove compartment?
O-Only maps.
Then undo your seat belt and float.
Keep breathing the air
near the roof of the car.
But I'll run out of air eventually.
It's just until you have
about 20 centimeters of air.
I see.
Like the boy said, wait
until you have 20 centimeters.
I'm already way past 20 centimeters.
A-Akai-san!
Okay, Camel. Take a deep breath
of the air from the roof,
open the door, and escape.
It's open.
They're probably still watching the water.
Get as far away from the car as you can
and stick your face out of the water.
I just passed beneath Umibotaru
and exited onto the south side.
Good.
All right. Keep swimming
until you reach the shore.
Got it.
But why did the door suddenly open?
Once the car fills with water
and the pressure on the outside
and inside are the same,
the door opens easily.
But extracting him while he's surrounded
by them will be next to impossible.
You're right.
We should've waited to hear
Yusaku-san's advice before we acted.
I'm not certain I would've noticed
if you were using kunrei-shiki
or Hepburn romanization.
But they have someone on their
side who instantly noticed.
It would seem that we underestimated them.
The shore?
You've reached some kind of
shore, right, Camel?
Yes, somehow.
Do you know where you are?
Your phone's GPS is broken
from being underwater.
I didn't see any lights.
Do Not Enter
I think I'm on a small island in the Tokyo
Bay, but I don't know where exactly.
I see some sturdy stairs.
There must have been some
kind of facility here.
Any identifying structures?
There's something that looks
like the remains of a battery.
A battery?
Then he might be at Fort No. 1 or 2.
What fort?
They're ruins of marine fortresses once
constructed in the Tokyo Bay for defense.
I've found a brick structure.
Could you describe in detail
how those bricks are laid?
Y-Yes.
Every row alternates large and small bricks.
Then you must be on Umizaru Island.
Umizaru Island?
English style alternates rows with only
the long or short side of the bricks showing.
French style alternates showing
the long and short sides within each row.
The bricks Camel-kun saw
were laid French-style.
The only place with French-style
brickwork in that area is Umizaru Island.
Camel, wait for us at Umizaru
Island until we can come get you.
Roger that.
Who should we send for him?
I'll go.
But, Akai-kun, if they see you...
Naturally, I'll go wearing this face.
I've made it waterproof so
it'll resist the rain and wind.
I made you even more handsome than usual.
Thank you.
Of course, he's super handsome to begin with.
Shu is coming for you.
Wait there until he arrives.
Are you all right, Camel?
Yes.
My clothes are just soaked.
But they'll dry eventually
while I'm walking—
Don't!
What?
You need to remove your
wet clothes immediately.
They'll rob your body of its heat.
There's a campsite at Umizaru
Island. Head there first.
If you don't find something to start a fire
and warm up there, you'll be in trouble.
Wow, I actually got a fire going.
I didn't realize you could create a spark
using a battery and chewing gum wrapper.
If you wrap your clothes in the towel you
found at the campsite and step on them,
they'll dry faster.
I'm heading out now.
Could I take Conan-kun with me?
Why are you asking me that?
It just seemed like the right thing to do.
He's a relative's boy,
but I'm sure it'll be fine.
He looks like he wants to go.
I see. Understood.
Get out of there before the police arrive.
Got it.
Did they find anything in their car
that fell from Umibotaru?
Another group dove down to investigate.
As we thought, the driver wasn't there.
Don't you think he handled
that a bit too adeptly?
We're talking about a guy who
let himself get surrounded
and drove his car off Umibotaru.
I think it's odd, too.
Maybe he was just that good.
Didn't he throw you off his trail once?
Or else the FBI are putting their
heads together to help him escape.
What? Why?
Who knows?
Maybe it has something to do
with Korn recognizing him.
Maybe it would be bad for them
if we found out who he is.
Well, that's not good.
Now I won't be satisfied until
I see that FBI agent's face.
Amazing.
Conan-kun was right.
My clothes dried quickly after I wrapped
them in a towel and stepped on them.
They're almost completely dry
after holding them over the fire.
That's good.
Since there were cold packs
in the abandoned cooler,
you can use them as heat packs
by boiling them in water.
You know everything, kid.
It's kind of weird hearing Akai-san's
voice coming from Subaru-san's face.
In that case...
I'll use this voice.
How's your arm doing, anyway?
I've performed first-aid.
The bullet's out, so I should be fine.
I felt awful when I arrived on this island,
but now the salt breeze feels good to me.
Salt breeze? You mean you're on the beach?
Y-Yes?
Put out your fire immediately.
It's clearly visible from across the water.
I-Is something the matter?
A fire.
The fire that was burning on
Umizaru Island just went out.
I knew it.
Rum.
At this time during this season,
the currents in the Tokyo Bay
flow towards Umizaru Island.
I've heard stories of bodies
washing up on Umizaru Island,
carried there by those currents.
There's a cruiser waiting for you.
Go to the island and hunt down
the FBI agent who escaped.
Sorry.
I should've warned him when
I told him how to start the fire.
Don't worry about it.
I'm also at fault for not checking in.
Have you finished putting out the fire?
Yes. I buried it all in sand.
I'm in the woods now.
Did you bring the olive oil you
said you found at the campsite?
Yes, but what are we going to do with this?
Pour it onto your clothes
and rub dirt on yourself.
What? But I just dried these.
You're making a camouflage suit.
The Native Americans used to
do it when they went hunting.
It helps you blend in with nature,
making you harder to spot.
You'll have to use the heat packs the kid
taught you to make to withstand the cold.
G-Got it.
I-It's them!
They're coming to the island on a boat!
They must've seen your fire.
Wh-What should I do?
Calm down, Camel.
They only saw your fire. They're
not certain you're on the island yet.
Don the scout suit you just made,
rub mud on your face,
and blend into the woods.
They'll leave before dawn when
the Umizaru Island staff arrive.
As long as you're not found before then,
you win.
G-Got it.
Why'd you send the boat back?
I'm just having it wait somewhere else.
It'd attract attention if
we left it tied to the pier.
Welcome to Umizaru Island
But, bro, did you really
see a fire on this beach?
Yes, I'm certain.
I don't see the remains of a fire.
There are plenty of campers'
footprints, though.
How long ago were the campers here?
The last boat was at 4PM.
It's currently 3AM, so that
would've been 11 hours ago.
Did you know the risen edges
of footprints on the beach
become rounded in about half a day?
But these footprints still have sharp edges.
And yet we haven't found the
remains of a fire, which means...
Look. He used this stone for his fire.
It's still slightly warm.
If he bothered to bury it in the sand,
then he must've known we were coming.
Split up and look for him.
Roger that.
We haven't heard from Camel-san in a while.
Do you think he's all right?
Is it him?
No, it's not Camel.
It's codename Kir, currently
undercover in the Organization.
CIA agent Mizunashi Rena.
What?
Akai here. Can you talk?
Yes.
We've arrived on Umizaru Island
and have split up to look for Camel-san.
I'm the one who shot him at
the Umibotaru Tunnel exit.
I didn't shoot to kill then, but
the next time I'm told to shoot him,
I'm sorry, but I'll be aiming for his face.
There's a member of the Organization
who remembers Agent Camel's face.
You good with that?
Yeah.
No problem.
Bastard!
Episode Preview
You're not getting away!
If you come quietly,
we'll give you a painless death.
The Black Organization's Scheme
(Identity)
The next episode of Conan is "The Black
Organization's Scheme, Identity!"
Next Conan's hint.
Rum!
Don't miss the next episode.
The identity of the number two man
of the Organization will finally be revealed!