When I came across the
murder of an FBI agent,
I headed to my house to notify Akai-san.
A large group of agents
had sought shelter there.
The Black Organization had cracked the code
they'd been using to arrange meetings.
The decision was made to use that
against them and lure them out...
Did something happen?
...but we were ambushed
by the Organization instead.
Agent Camel was cornered on Umizaru Island.
Don't you think he handled
that a bit too adeptly?
We're talking about a guy who
let himself get surrounded
and drove his car off Umibotaru.
I think it's odd, too.
Maybe he was just that good.
Didn't he throw you off his trail once?
Or else the FBI are putting their
heads together to help him escape.
What? Why?
Who knows?
Maybe it has something to do
with Korn recognizing him.
Maybe it would be bad for them
if we found out who he is.
Well, that's not good.
Now I won't be satisfied until
I see that FBI agent's face.
We haven't heard from Camel-san in a while.
Do you think he's all right?
Is it him?
No, it's not Camel.
It's codename Kir, currently
undercover in the Organization.
CIA agent Mizunashi Rena.
What?
Akai here. Can you talk?
Yes.
We've arrived on Umizaru Island
and have split up to look for Agent Camel.
I'm the one who shot him at
the Umibotaru Tunnel exit.
I didn't shoot to kill then, but the
next time I'm told to shoot him,
I'm sorry, but I'll be aiming for his face.
There's a member of the Organization
who remembers Agent Camel's face.
You good with that?
Yeah.
No problem.
Beyond detective skills
capable of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
Black hunters close in on their prey.
Rum finally shows themselves.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Black Organization's Scheme
(Identity)
"The Black Organization's Scheme, Identity!"
Damn. Damn, damn.
Damn.
I don't see him anywhere.
Maybe he already fled the island.
I kind of think that, too.
It's certainly possible.
It's 1.2 kilometers from here
to the Yokosuka coast.
You could swim that distance.
No. If he did,
I doubt he would've bothered to hide
the traces of his fire in the sand.
Making us believe he's still here
would cause his pursuers to focus
their attention on the island.
We'd turn our attention away from
the sea, giving him more time to swim.
You're right.
Then why didn't he do that?
He can't swim yet.
Huh?
He probably used all his
strength swimming to this island.
Even if he tries to wait and escape by sea,
our boat's keeping an eye out for him.
Either way,
there's nowhere for an
out-of-breath FBI agent to run.
Right.
Camel, were you able to acquire
the things I told you to find?
Y-Yes.
I entered the café on Umizaru Island and
acquired three hemp sacks for coffee beans.
One still contained beans,
so I emptied the bag.
I also acquired adhesive tape
and a box cutter
Umizaru Island
Tourist Information Center
from the tourist information
center next to the café.
The café should have straws.
Borrow some of those, too.
Got it.
But what am I going to do with these things?
You'll need them to blend
into nature even more.
O-Okay...
Could you tell us what items
you have on you right now?
I-I don't have much.
I've got a penlight,
my FBI badge, a phone with a broken GPS,
and the headset linked to it.
Come to think of it...
I've still got the cap Akai-san
gave to me before I headed out.
I felt like I should return it later.
Akai-san, is that hat...?
Yeah. Like my wool hat, it's one
of Professor Agasa's inventions.
Good work, Camel.
That might come in handy.
Th-This thing?
There's no way he'd be hiding
in such an obvious place.
We're just making sure.
They just entered the café.
Do you have an escape route?
Yes.
Then leave immediately.
Your scout suit will make you
stand out indoors.
Roger that.
Anyway, I'm surprised by Rum.
He suddenly butted into our
conversation to issue instructions.
And he's been right about everything.
"He?" Have you seen Rum's face?
That's just how I imagine him.
Some say he's a big man, some
say he's a masculine woman.
Some say he's an old man,
some say he's got a false eye.
The rumors about him are all over the place.
But according to Gin, the only rumor
that's true is the false eye.
The rest are lies Rum himself spread.
Then Gin's met Rum before?
Yeah. He says he knows where
he is and what he's doing, too.
Oh, yeah? I wonder what Rum's up to.
Camel, have you moved?
I wasn't told, but Gin told me...
No, I'm in the middle of something.
These days he wears a disguise
and goes by a ridiculous name.
A ridiculous name?
Crap!
Bastard!
You're not getting away!
What are you doing?
He got away.
Sorry.
What are those dark things
scattered on the floor?
Coffee beans?
I see.
You got away because you spread
coffee beans on the floor.
In reality, they're just the beans
that scattered when I opened the bag.
Anyway, what should I do with these bags?
Right. First, use the box cutter
to cut open the bottoms of the bags.
Chain the bags together using
adhesive tape to create a long tube.
Lay the bags in a depression in the woods
and cover the bags with dirt, leaves, and
branches until they're no longer visible.
Then you can enter the bags and open
a hole for the straw so you can breathe.
It's the classic doton-no-jutsu.
Yeah. It makes you difficult
to find and keeps you warm.
Can you do that, Camel?
I think so.
You slipped on some coffee beans?
Yeah. I wasn't expecting a trap like this.
No, it wasn't a trap.
Huh?
If the hemp bags are gone, then he
must plan to bury himself in the dirt.
Search the whole island before dawn—
Wait.
Huh?
There's a better way.
He used hemp bags to bury himself in the dirt?
Like a ninja.
Yeah. Searching all of the dirt on
Umizaru Island would take a long time.
In two hours, the sun will rise, and
the Umizaru Island staff will arrive.
If he can make it until then,
Camel will be saved.
Let us know if the situation changes.
Roger that.
Yusaku? Is something the matter?
If I were them...
Namikaze Park
Camel, can you hear me?
We just arrived at Namikaze Park,
which has a view of Umizaru Island.
Has your situation changed?
Right.
It's quite comfortable underground.
Actually, it's a bit hot.
Hot?
Akai-san!
Umizaru Island...
It's on fire.
Camel, unbury yourself immediately.
What?
You'll burn to death.
What?!
Akai-san, we'll have to use that.
When did this fire start?
Camel, you got the adhesive
tape and box cutter
from the tourist information center, right?
Yes.
Was there a copy machine there?
I think so.
I know it's dry this time of year,
but it's burning quite nicely.
But if we don't hurry,
the fire boat will show up.
You're right.
There he is.
He's running down the pier.
He actually came out of hiding.
Rum was right again.
Don't praise him for every little thing.
You think that barricade will stop us?
If you come quietly,
we'll give you a painless death.
Akai-san.
Wait, Camel.
Draw them closer to you.
1,334.2 yards to target.
Wind blowing from the left, plus one degree.
Okay, Camel.
Run.
Got it.
He's running.
I've got the shot.
As usual, aim for the head.
No, go for the back. Aim for his heart.
What?
Got it.
Akai-san!
What should we do, bro?
Should we dive in and bring his body up?
Yeah, of course.
After using this to make sure he's dead.
A grenade.
I dragged this out
in case he fled into the sea.
What are you going to do with that?
Throw it into the ocean.
What?
When thrown on dry land,
during the several seconds until a grenade
explodes, you can get five meters away,
point your feet at it, and get on the ground,
which gives you some chance of survival.
But when a grenade explodes underwater,
the pressure waves crushes lungs and organs,
which means certain death
for living creatures in the area.
That's how dynamite fishing works.
Yeah.
I'm looking forward to seeing
what kind of fish come floating up.
A-A grenade?
Akai-san!
I know.
I see it.
Wha...
What?
Someone's shooting at us
from the opposite shore.
Someone's at Namikaze Park.
Then they must be 1,300 yards away.
You're saying they shot the grenade
Gin threw from that far away?
It's not as though they're Akai.
Their random shot just happened to hit—
Get down.
What should we do about the body
of the FBI agent we shot?
We can't leave it.
If we dive in, find the body, and
bring it up beneath the pier...
I-It's the fire boat.
Bring the cruiser around
opposite the fire boat.
We're getting out of here.
Got it.
They're leaving.
Yeah.
Officer, hurry.
I heard something that sounded like
gunshots coming from over there.
You sure about that?
Yes, really.
Well, that's not good.
We didn't catch anything this time, Dad.
I can't believe we caught nothing.
I thought it was around here.
Too bad, though.
We never saw the face
of the FBI agent we killed.
Who cares?
He's dead.
If you mean the man we shot
earlier, I know who he is.
What?
Andre Camel. A skilled driver
and one of Akai's pets.
I once worked with Bourbon
to get information out of him.
Korn, who is this guy?
Where did you meet him?
I definitely saw him.
Two years ago.
Rum sent me a photo of this guy.
Two years ago? Photo?
What? Why would Rum send you his photo?
I was watching the warehouse
where they were meeting.
But the meeting was canceled.
Then Rum sent me a message
with the photo attached.
"Rye and this guy are FBI agents."
"Shoot them if you see them."
That story brings back memories.
Rum.
He reprimanded me for this incident.
We attracted too much attention.
Though he applauded you for killing the man
the FBI were desperately trying to protect,
personally I would've liked to have taken
him alive so I could ask him some questions.
Sorry, Andre Camel.
Sacrifices must be made
for the sake of progress.
No hard feelings.
Yes, sir.
But you look so neat and handsome this way.
It's like you're a different person.
But they're all laughing.
I'm amazed you're all right.
Weren't you shot in the back?
It was the copy paper.
What?
I taped two reams of copy paper from
the tourist information center to my back
like a bulletproof vest.
But there are holes on the front
and back of your bloody clothes.
That's fake blood.
Fake blood?
Camel-san had the professor's
bleeding cap with him.
He split the fake blood inside into two bags
and stuck them to his back and chest.
The mechanism used to burst the bags
broke when it fell into the water, though.
What?
The blood on his back must've
sprayed when he got shot,
but what about his chest?
I shot him.
What?
Immediately after Camel was shot in the back.
I had him tape his penlight over
the bulge created by the fake blood
so it'd be easier to target.
The blood sprayed out of his chest
at exactly the right time.
I even thought their bullet
penetrated the copy paper.
I thought I'd been shot, too.
The blow to my back made me
actually spit up blood.
I see. You knew they'd shoot him
in the back instead of the head
because they wanted to see his face.
Yes.
I even had him close the gate so
they wouldn't fire at his legs.
But if you'd shot them before
they fired on Camel-kun,
wouldn't they have left without
needing any kind of ruse?
If he'd done that, they would've done
whatever it took to kill Camel-kun.
Though Akai-kun had his rifle trained on them,
the people standing near Camel-kun
were the far greater threat.
Apparently they even had a grenade.
For them to leave, they had to be
made to believe Camel-kun was dead,
and for none of them to be injured.
If you'd pinned them there by firing on them,
they would've gotten into a fight
with the approaching fire boat,
possibly resulting in casualties.
It was the optimal strategy.
Impressive as always, Akai-kun.
Actually, Conan-kun helped me come up with it.
I'm glad I took him with me.
Nice one, Cool Kid. I'm impressed.
Thank you for saving me, Conan-kun.
Don't thank me. It was all Akai-san.
I still haven't received a response
to the late-night tea party.
Right.
Tea party?
They killed seven of our agents,
and others were gravely injured.
But we only chased them off
and have nothing to show for it.
Come to think of it,
Vodka mentioned something.
Some say Rum is a big man,
some say he's a masculine woman.
Some say he's an old man, and
some say he's got a false eye.
But aside from the false eye, the
rumors are lies Rum himself spread.
He also said these days he wears a
disguise and goes by a ridiculous name.
A ridiculous...
...name?
Sir. Sir.
Sir.
You can't stay here. It's too dangerous.
We've arrived.
Thank you.
Irohazushi
Mori Detective Agency
Hey, boss, let me help you prep!
Episode Preview
Does that mean we can't
withdraw money from this ATM?
I can't see her face.
Let's give it a try.
They're using software
to check Haibara's face?
Could it be facial recognition?
Hey, what was that for?
The Cameras Targeting Haibara
The next episode of Conan is
"The Cameras Targeting Haibara!"
Next Conan's hint.
Black Cash Card
A black cash card!
Are you sure this haircut looks okay?
Don't miss the next episode.
Yeah, you look great.
Really?