Grand Prize
And the grand prize is...
Hachijo-jima Whale Watching Tour
A Hachijo-jima Whale Watching Tour!
Groups of Two
Ten Winners
Up to ten pairs could win.
This winter, come play the lottery at the Beika
Department Store and meet some whales.
Any purchase will earn you a chance to play.
One play per customer.
Get yours soon!
Beika Department Store Winter Mega Sale!
Winter Mega Sale
Win a whale watching tour in a lottery?
Come to think of it, those kids
wanted to go on this tour.
They invited me to go with them.
You, too?
They invited me to go with them
to the department store today, too.
Oh, you're not going?
Nah. I'm not interested.
I'll pass, too.
Well, I should get going.
I want to go.
Huh?
Every man dreams of seeing whales.
Th-They do?
All right. The three of us are
going to the department store.
We're going, too?
They said each customer only
gets to play the lottery once.
We'll have better odds if more of us go.
I'll get my wallet.
Hey, wait. Isn't your scheduled
delivery arriving soon?
Oh, right. The tools I need
for inventing are arriving.
You can play the lottery tomorrow.
But...
If we don't go soon, they might
run out of whale watching tour slots.
You're hopeless.
We're going?
Yes.
Oh, right.
Could you withdraw cash for me
like you always do?
Agasa Hiroshi
Got it.
Let's go.
What? Me, too?
You'd better win that tour.
I'll get some beach toys ready while I wait.
Hey, that card looks new.
It is. I recently swapped it
out for my old card.
Agasa Hiroshi
Huh.
Beyond detective skills
capable of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
A whale watching tour and
an international organization!
A dark shadow closes in on Haibara!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Cameras Targeting Haibara
"The Cameras Targeting Haibara!"
What? Now?
The department store is
holding a sale right now.
You sure do love sales.
Ran.
Huh?
Every woman loves a good bargain.
Th-They do?
Meiwa Toto Bank ATM
Could I withdraw some cash first?
Are you going shopping for sales, too?
More like I have to go shopping for dinner.
Must be tough cooking every day.
I'm used to it.
I bet you'll make a good wife.
Don't tease me.
Huh?
Oh, no. Why?
What? What's wrong?
I don't know, but the machine
suddenly stopped working.
Oh, come on.
Meiwa Bank ATM
Took you long enough.
Let's get over to the department
store so we can play the lottery.
You can't play unless you buy
something at the department store.
Don't worry.
We brought our allowances.
After all, you can buy anything
for a chance to play once.
I'm gonna buy Kamen Yaiba chocolate.
Let's go, Ai-chan.
Hold on. I have to withdraw some money first.
Huh?
What's the matter, mister?
I'm not sure what happened, but
when I tried to make a withdrawal,
the machine suddenly stopped working.
The machine ate my card
and won't give it back.
Bank ATM
PIN Code
Please enter PIN code
Cancel
Damn it. The next race is starting soon.
Mister, are you betting on the horses again?
You'll get in trouble with Ran-neechan.
Shut up! You kids shouldn't be here anyway.
Get out of here.
Mister, have you forgotten?
Several years ago, in just three hours,
1.8 billion yen was withdrawn
from ATMs all over Japan.
1.8?!
It was because a South African
bank was hacked.
Hacked?
That's when bad people steal
information from computers.
The stolen personal information
was used to create fake cards.
The incident occurred when
those were used, so maybe...
Has my personal information
been stolen, too?
Maybe.
With the skills of an international hacker,
apparently it's possible to hack
into a security camera system
and observe you from overseas.
Be careful you don't get caught up
in any international crimes.
What happened to that international hacker?
I think that Interpol is
still investigating the case.
Interpol?
It's an international police organization
with members from all over the world.
The ATM is currently...
Huh? Haibara-san, you're not
going to make a withdrawal?
Oh, right.
Haibara...
Hey, what was that for?
Huh? That man's card...
It's black.
Toto Meiwa Bank ATM
Hey, wait.
I'll go after him, too.
That man used a weird
card to withdraw money.
Could it be?
Huh?
It must be, right?
What?
The international hacker will be captured...
By us.
The Detective Boys!
Wait, guys.
This is your fault for mentioning
that in front of those kids.
Yeah, but...
Thank you for waiting.
Are you Mori-sama? We received your call.
What's going on here?
I can't withdraw any money,
and I can't get my card back.
I'm sorry. Several ATMs in
this area are out of service.
For now, we'd better find that man.
You think he's an international hacker, too?
No, but he was surprised
when he saw your face.
What? Well, it did seem that way.
But he was a total stranger.
He's not a member of the
Black Organization, is he?
No, he didn't seem like it.
You're probably overthinking it.
In any case, you should go home.
You're letting it bother you too much.
Just do it.
Hey, guys.
Where are you now?
Toto Bank
We're pursuing the international hacker.
He's entering the bank.
The bank?
So they're near Beika Park.
Huh?
There's nobody here.
But this is the only entrance.
Window Service
Suspended
And the bank is closed.
Could it be?
He vanished?
Mori Ran
I'm sorry for the inconvenience.
Does that mean we can't
withdraw money from this ATM?
I'm terribly sorry.
It's possible all the ATMs
in this area are out of service
We apologize for the inconvenience
This ATM is currently out of service
What?
I can't see her face.
Let's give it a try.
It's not working.
This camera's position makes it difficult.
Damn. We won't be able to make our report.
Conan.
The international hacker disappeared.
The bank closes at three.
It should already have been
closed when that man arrived.
What could have happened?
What is it, Genta-kun?
If we keep hanging around here, they might
run out of whale watching tour spots.
But what about the international hacker?
The whales are more important.
Huh? Where's Haibara?
Oh, she went home because
she had something to do.
What? Why?
Does it have something to do
with the international hacker?
No, of course not.
Haibara-san, where are you right now?
Unfortunately...
Now this is a problem.
What am I going to do about dinner?
Oh, well. I'll have to make do
with whatever we've got left.
Nice thinking, Ran. You're
the perfect housewife.
There you go again. Don't flatter me.
I'm going to pass on playing the lottery
and go home today since
I can't withdraw any money.
Aw, darn.
The international hacker!
Toto Bank
Hey, wait. What about the whales?
Ai-kun, do you mind?
Oh, right.
Coming.
Yes?
Cheetah Delivery
Package for you.
Haibara!
Haibara-san!
Ai-chan!
Haibara...
Haibara, are you okay?
Y-Yes...
Ai-chan.
Are you all right?
Hey, he's getting away.
Stop!
You're...
We'll go after him.
Ai-chan, stay there.
We're going to play that lottery later.
Don't! Wait...
Haibara.
Stop the kids.
Does that mean he was...?
I don't know.
It didn't feel like he was, but...
You don't know every member
of the Black Organization.
Go back to the professor's house.
Got it?
Edogawa-kun!
What did that guy do?
I'm not sure, but I do know that
Haibara-san was afraid of him.
For Haibara-san.
I can't keep running.
Me neither.
I won't let him escape.
He's entering some kind of building.
Wait, Mitsuhiko. Stay there.
He opened the door. He's going inside.
Whatever you do, don't go in there.
Conan-kun, I'm sorry.
Mitsuhiko!
Um...
Yeah, I found her.
I've acquired some photos.
Bring up those images again.
This should work.
Now we can use facial recognition.
He's using some kind of software
to compare photos of Haibara-san
against security camera images.
They're using software to
compare images of Haibara's face?
Could it be facial recognition?
Will Haibara's identity be exposed?
When I tried to make a withdrawal,
the machine suddenly stopped working.
Haibara...
The bank closes at three.
It should already have been closed
when that man arrived.
It is. I recently swapped it
out for my old card.
Could it be?
Ah, Shinichi. What is it?
No, isn't Ai-kun with you?
I see. She's not back yet.
Did something happen to her?
No, it's nothing.
Haibara said you replaced your cash card.
That's right. When I went
to the bath the other day...
I'm sorry.
Your card was slightly cracked,
which prevented the machine from reading it.
We'd appreciate it if you could replace it
with a new card as soon as possible.
In that case, could I get a replacement today?
Also, we checked for
unauthorized uses on your card,
and found that a grade-school-aged girl
used your card to withdraw money.
I told them I had my daughter
use my card to make a withdrawal.
I see. So that's how it is.
Professor, come to the following
location right away.
What are you doing here?
What's the matter?
It's a child.
There's a child in the building.
Hey, wait!
How'd you get in here?
Hey.
Help me!
Mitsuhiko!
Mitsuhiko, are you okay?
What's going on?
What? A bank?
That's right.
Toto Bank
This is the Toto Bank Beika Park Branch,
and these guys are bank employees.
That's right. We're this branch's
technical staff.
And this is where we view
security camera footage
from the Toto Bank branch in Beika City.
The technical staff checks the footage here.
More importantly, you tripped.
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine.
I'm sorry for entering the building
without your permission.
There's nothing wrong with playing detective,
but you shouldn't follow people around.
We're sorry.
Why were you looking at images of
Haibara-san on the monitors in this room?
Probably because they noticed
she was trying to use the professor's
card to make a withdrawal.
That's right.
We were notified that a young girl
was using Agasa-sama's card.
We thought the girl and Agasa-sama
might have committed
or gotten involved in some kind of crime.
I jumped to conclusions.
That's why you took photos of Haibara
to run facial recognition on here.
We went too far. I'm sorry.
Come to think of it, you used a
black card to withdraw money.
Oh, that?
At our bank, whenever there's a problem,
we use that card to examine
the ATM where the error occurred,
and share the information on these devices.
Hello? Yes.
Yes, understood.
Your ride is here.
We've confirmed the card you handed over
is linked to Agasa-sama's bank account.
We're terribly sorry for doubting you.
I said this girl was my daughter
when asked about our relationship,
but she's actually a relative's child.
You were allowing a relative's
child to use your cash card?
When I can't be bothered to
go withdraw money myself.
Is that against the rules after all?
But even grade school kids can open
bank accounts and use cash cards.
As long as its their account.
At our bank, we allow children
to use their parents' cash cards
at ATMs with their consent,
but we'd appreciate if you didn't allow
your relative's child to use your card.
But...
She's a relative's child, but she's special.
She's not my child, but she's more
important to me than anyone.
She's the only family I have.
Ai-kun.
I'm sorry. I'll be more careful in the future.
We're sorry for the trouble we caused.
Sorry for scaring you.
It's fine.
Besides, it's our fault
for breaking the bank's rules.
How mature of you.
The ATM error that occurred
earlier has been resolved.
We appreciate your continued patronage.
Toto Bank
We were able to make our withdrawals.
Now we can finally go
to the department store.
All right. Let's win a whale
watching trip in the lottery.
Yeah!
I'll be sure to play for you, too,
my dear professor.
Ai-kun...
So be a good boy and wait at home.
Sure. I'm looking forward to it.
What? We can use the bank's ATMs, too?
Yes. Apparently even grade school children
can have bank accounts and cash cards.
Really? I had no idea.
I can't, though.
Not in your current condition.
Not until we take down the Black Organization
and return to our original forms.
But I never thought that would happen
to Haibara because of said organization.
Episode Preview
Pan-kun!
Help! Someone help!
Do you know why you were attacked?
I'm not rich or anything.
There's no time. I must do
something before it's too late.
My Beloved Dog Pan-kun Is a Good Boy
The next episode of Conan is "My
Beloved Dog Pan-kun is a Good Boy!"
Apple Pie
Next Conan's hint!
Apple pie!
What's going to happen with
the whale watching tour?
Don't miss the next episode.
Come see us at the movies!