Here it comes, Mitsuhiko.
Try catching my full-power pitch!
I'll catch it with all my might!
Go!
Good luck, both of you.
Thanks.
Down, down.
Be a good boy and quiet down.
What's going on?
Pan-kun?
He ran away.
That dog abandoned his owner.
Beyond detective skills
capable of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
A dog with too much freedom
runs towards a surprising truth!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
My Beloved Dog Pan-kun is a Good Boy
"My Beloved Dog Pan-kun is a Good Boy!"
Pan-kun?
Guys, make as much noise as you can.
Someone help!
He's gonna kill us! Help!
Pan-kun...
Thank you so much for saving me.
That was so scary.
I'm glad you weren't hurt.
Yamada Sachiko (28)
Housewife
I know. It's all thanks to you kids.
He came back.
Pan-kun, you're all right.
I'm so glad.
That dog does whatever it wants.
Miss, do you know why you were attacked?
I have no idea.
I'm not rich, nor do I
have any special skills.
The only reason I can think of
is that I'm just so attractive.
Just kidding.
She just looks like an
ordinary dog person to me.
Anyway, I'm glad you're all right.
Thanks to us.
We'll report this to the police,
but you should be careful, too.
I will. Thank you.
But next time, this boy will protect me.
After all, Pan-kun is a good boy.
Well, goodbye.
Too fast!
Goodbye.
There's no time. I must do
something before it's too late.
I wonder why that lady was attacked.
Her attacker was wearing a ski mask, and
it didn't seem like a crime of opportunity.
It's obvious.
The culprit wanted her brooch.
It did look like a large emerald.
If it's not fake, it would
be pretty expensive.
It was fake?
We can safely assume a flawless
emerald that size is fake.
Then he must've been her stalker.
He was wearing a ski mask because
he was waiting for her there.
When the victim herself didn't
realize she has a stalker?
Don't you think that's a little far-fetched?
You're right. She didn't seem anxious
at all or like she was being followed.
Then it must be the dog.
What?
It's really cute, so maybe
a thief wanted to steal it.
It didn't seem like a breed
you'd bother to steal.
It's unlikely to be stolen without a pedigree.
Then why was she attacked?
Huh?
It's curious, isn't it?
Then let's look into it.
Yeah!
Hurry. She can't have gone far yet.
Since she was walking her dog in this park,
she must not live too far away.
Where did she go?
Look.
Pan-kun, don't go up there.
Okay, okay.
Looks like her name is Yamada-san.
Now, now. Don't bite the sofa.
Yamada Goro, Sachiko,
and Pan
Nothing seems out of the ordinary.
Looks like that dog misbehaving
is business as usual.
Huh?
Pan's Profile
Favorite foods:
"Magical Smith Apple Pie"
Yamada Sachiko-san's Posts
Yamada Sachiko
Oh, is that Yamada-san's
social media profile?
Pan-kun jumping on
a Magical Smith Apple Pie
Nice [heart]
Most of her newest posts are about Pan-kun.
He's learned to destroy
Daddy's pillow [heart]
Nice work, Pan-kun
The yard is full of holes!
(Good job digging them [heart])
I found Pan-kun's treasure inside,
as well as Daddy's shoes.
And she calls him a good boy?
Cleaning together [heart]
That dog gets away with everything.
The dog food...
Pan-kun, those are Daddy's shoes.
But he's cute.
Y-Yeah...
Huh?
What?
Get the dog.
G-Got it.
Pan-kun!
He ran away again.
He wouldn't make a very good guard dog.
Why don't you guys give up?
Give up? What are you talking about, kid?
Don't underestimate us!
Guys.
Make any noise, and you'll pay for it!
Don't bother. We've already called the police.
If you don't calm down, you'll regret it.
Damn it! You'll be the ones
who will regret doing this!
Do it.
No hard feelings.
Mister, your shoes are untied.
What? Seriously?
They're not untied.
Try catching my full-power pitch!
And mine!
Hey, don't let a couple
of kids take you down.
What will you do now?
Y-You'll pay for this!
Now then.
Who are these guys?
Takahashi Hajime (22)
Unemployed
Takahashi Hajime, 22 years old, unemployed.
A minor criminal with
three previous offenses.
Takagi-san.
This man's ski mask resembles
the ones worn by the culprits who
robbed the jewelry store two days ago.
Is that right?
A gem-studded tiara and armband were stolen.
They're worth several million yen.
Kaneko Jewelry Store
These are the items.
Kaneko Jewelry
Store Camera 1-7
Look at this.
This is footage from the Kaneko
Jewelry Store security cameras.
They certainly do look similar.
So do their builds.
Later, a passerby, who heard the owner
shouting, attempted to catch the culprits,
and was stabbed with a knife instead.
The Kaneko Jewelry Store was robbed again?
Yeah. Apparently they've tightened security.
I wonder why they keep getting robbed?
Wait, you kids again?
What does that mean?
We're the ones who caught the culprit.
Yeah.
Not only that, but we
chased off the thieves twice.
At the very least, we've
been more useful than Pan-kun.
Good work, kids.
Thanks for everything.
You're welcome!
So, do you think he'll talk?
He hasn't said anything so far, but
we'll take our time questioning him.
Like Mitsuhiko-said, Yamada-san
has been attacked twice today.
I wonder why she was attacked.
You're right. We'll put a
security detail on Yamada-san.
So she might be connected
to the jewel thieves somehow.
Do you think the culprit
who fled will be back?
They say things come in threes, but
I doubt he'd do anything that reckless.
I made some tea. Would you like some?
Uh, this is a crime scene.
Good boy, Pan-kun.
We should be fine out here. Have some.
Thanks for the food!
Miss, are you sure you don't know
why you were attacked?
Well, my husband runs a normal company,
and we haven't won the lottery.
I wonder why?
And you haven't been followed
recently or anything like that?
No, I haven't received any
weird silent phone calls either.
Does Pan-kun have any special talents?
Of course. After all, Pan-kun is a good boy.
What exactly does he do?
He wags his tail whenever
you call him a good boy.
This doesn't seem to be it.
Did anything unusual happen two days ago?
Two days ago? Not especially.
Come to think of it, Pan-kun took
his own leash and went missing,
but he came back right away.
What time was that? For how long?
It was around 2PM, for about ten minutes.
But he always goes missing, so it
didn't feel out of the ordinary.
That's the same time the
jewelry store was robbed.
What are you thinking?
That Yamada-san has nothing
to do with the case after all.
Like Ayumi-chan said, the culprits
are probably after Pan-kun.
Then...
He doesn't have a pedigree and
can't perform any special tricks,
but considering Pan-kun's personality...
He ate something he shouldn't have?
But the items stolen from the jewelry store
weren't things that could be swallowed.
Then what do they want?
Is something wrong, Pan-kun?
Pan-kun's escaped!
Pan!
Pan-kun!
Pan-kun! Pan-kun!
What are we doing to do?
He's been dognapped.
The thieves were after Pan-kun.
What's this?
It's apple pie.
Pan-kun...
They say third time's the charm.
If they were that desperate to steal the dog,
then we should assume
he swallowed the jewels.
Pan-kun! Oh, Pan-kun!
The culprits acquired what they wanted.
Your dog might be...
Pan-kun! What's going to happen to Pan-kun?!
If the culprits suspect he
swallowed something, then...
You mean Pan-kun's not coming home? No...
That won't happen.
Huh?
Conan-kun will rescue Pan-kun. Right?
Oh, right.
Conan-kun.
We shouldn't give up yet.
You mean...
Detective Takagi, I'd like you
to look into something.
Bow-meow Animal Hospital
I don't see any foreign objects.
That can't be!
It should be in his stomach!
You keep saying that, but...
It should be inside this boy.
What's going on?
Looks like you didn't
find what you expected.
What? You're that kid.
How'd you know I was here?
Because you kept attacking her.
There was a reason you kept attacking her
despite her being on her guard.
But no matter how much
Yamada-san thought about it,
she couldn't figure out
why she was being attacked.
So what if it was Pan-kun?
But we had nothing conclusive pointing to him.
That's when these attacks were
linked to the jewelry store robbery
you and your accomplice
committed two days ago.
You have a dog and a jewel heist.
Anyone's first assumption would be
that the dog ate the jewels,
but all the stolen jewels
were too large to be stolen.
So was there something else?
Something you were willing
to take risks to acquire.
It's your knife, isn't it?
H-How did you know that?!
The switchblade in the
security camera footage
and the knife you used to
attack Pan-kun were different.
Also, the footage showed
you cutting your own hand.
That means your blood is on the knife.
But the knife wasn't in Pan-kun's stomach.
Where could it have gone?
How strange.
Who the hell are you?
How do you know all that?
It wasn't me, it was the great detective
Kogoro-no-ojisan who figured it out.
He's certainly a great detective.
Come to think of it, I hadn't told you yet
how we knew you were here.
It's because you're a dog person.
H-How do you know that?
You used a net for capturing animals.
You bought specialized equipment
so you wouldn't hurt the dog.
In other words, you never
intended to use violent methods.
You even used apple pie, Pan-kun's
favorite food, to lure him to you.
You can imagine what a culprit would
do with a dog after stealing him
if he thought he swallowed something.
An owner would take their dog
to the vet immediately
if they thought they swallowed something.
So we had the police look for an animal
hospital with a blue car parked outside of it.
So you know everything, huh?
Then did you expect this?
Nobody move!
You, officer! Get me a getaway car!
Don't do anything stupid!
You'll only regret this!
Shut up! My life is full of regrets!
I've been desperate from the start!
I know, why don't you get me
some getaway cash, too?
A million yen in cash, with
non-sequential serial numbers!
I feel like I've heard all those lines before.
He watches too many cop dramas.
Hurry up!
He ran away again.
Come on, officer. Give me your keys.
And I want everyone outside.
You're such a good boy, Pan-kun.
Don't do anything stupid.
I can't use my tranquilizer
watch with these two around.
What should I do?
Pan-kun!
He's back.
Quit it! Stop! Down!
Be a good boy! Down!
All right!
Detective Takagi.
Got it.
By the way, I love dogs, too!
Thief apprehended red-handed at 14:53.
By the way, I'm a cat person.
Nobody asked.
Good boy, Pan-kun.
Wow, Pan-kun. You did great.
I told you so.
My dog is a very good boy.
Could you ask him to let
go of that shoe, then?
That's evidence.
Come on, Pan-kun.
Be a good boy and let go of the shoe.
Come on.
Come on, Pan-kun. Be a good boy.
He's definitely not letting go.
Pan-kun never changes.
That's case closed.
No, not yet.
What's he doing?
Just watch.
What's that?
It's a bunch of junk.
But to Pan-kun, they're treasures.
So you knew.
He's learned to destroy
Daddy's pillow [heart]
Nice work, Pan-kun
Yeah, because there were photos of him
stealing shoes and digging holes on social media.
And Yamada-san's yard had a wooden floor.
I figured you installed it to stop Pan-kun.
Wow, how did you know?
Pan-kun would dig holes elsewhere
once he couldn't dig holes in the yard.
And he chose this park.
That's right.
Let's go.
There's no knife.
Look.
Okay.
It's not here.
Pan-kun, come here.
We found it.
Looks like the knife in question.
Third time's the charm again.
Okay.
Dig here, doggy.
This dog's always causing trouble.
Later, the knife was collected as evidence,
Tanaka Ichiro (24) Unemployed
and all the stolen jewels were found
at the culprit Tanaka Ichiro's home.
Awoo!
Look at this.
Huh?
Pan-kun is a Good Boy.
Wow, genius dog!
So cute! Pan-kun is great
What?! He attacked a
knife-wielding criminal!!?
What is this?
Comments
People are calling him the great dog
who solved a tough case.
So cool
Nice [heart]
Super awesome
Pan-kun the Great
They're calling that Pan-kun great?
Well, it's true that he helped.
It's not clear if he was helping the vet
or just wanted the shoe, though.
My Pan-kun is a good boy.
Episode Preview
Bon appetite.
To you, this might be
a dingy old-fashioned alley,
but it's an important place to us.
Whoa!
This wasn't an accident.
It was a crime targeting Kusumi-san.
What?!
The Alley of Sad Betrayal
The next episode of Conan is
"The Alley of Sad Betrayal!"
Medals
Next Conan's hint.
Medals!
We have Pan-kun to thank
for solving this case.
Don't miss the next episode.
What a good boy.
Shut up.