Italian Izakaya RESO
Sakura Sushi | Creative Cuisine Seventy-Seven
Beika Gourmet Restaurant Street
RESO Italian Izakaya
Bon appetite.
Wow.
That's the stuff.
This is what I wanted to eat.
Yamaura Takashi (53)
Italian Restaurant RESO Owner
Fantastic. Bon appetite!
Mister, "bon appetite"
means "enjoy your meal."
What? Is that right?
The wine is great, too. Bon appetite.
Since you haven't been here in a while,
make sure you eat your fill.
Sorry I haven't stopped by.
It's fine. You're busy, right?
I've seen you on the news, Sleeping Kogoro.
Oh, please.
I heard you solved another
difficult case the other day.
You're doing great work.
I don't remember any of it, though.
The great detective once caught someone
who dined and dashed at this restaurant.
Wow.
And he threw a rampaging
drunk waving around a bottle.
At least, that much was okay.
But he threw him so hard,
he destroyed the wall.
What was that?
Beyond detective skills
capable of identifying the truth...
...is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
Sadness hangs about this retro alley.
They key to solving the case
uses a medal system.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Alley of Sad Betrayal
"The Alley of Sad Betrayal!"
Hey, you.
What do you think you're doing
knocking down the wall while we're open?
I was hired by the owner of this place.
Him again?
He's not getting away with this today.
Disgusting - Do Not Enter
Close Your Shop!! / Coward Soba
Kusumi!
Do Not Enter
You jerk!
Domestic Soba Flour
I've had enough of your crap.
Yama-chan.
Violence is wrong.
Hey!
Nakano Fumio (42)
Sushi Sakura-ya Owner
Why are you causing a commotion
outside my store?
Yonezawa Yuji (37)
Creative Cuisine "Seventy-Seven" Owner
This goes way beyond simple harassment.
Words weren't enough to
make some people move out.
So now you're using force.
If you don't like it, then why don't you
give me your signatures already?
Kusumi Hiroyuki (29)
Alley Owner
Actually, I wouldn't mind if you
went ahead and dropped dead,
like that soba shop owner.
What?
You killed him, didn't you?
That's right.
Your harassment made the
old man's health deteriorate.
He always drank with his customers
until he was in a stupor.
He was a total alcoholic.
Some people looked forward to
drinking with the old man.
Not that you'd understand.
No, I don't understand people who
get drunk in this old-fashioned alley.
Oh, forgive me. I meant "dingy alley."
To you, this might be a
dingy old-fashioned alley,
but it's an important place to us.
There you go again. Are you
playing the sympathy card now?
I can't stand it.
Now, now. Out of respect
for the Sleeping Kogoro...
What? This is none of your
business. Stay out of this.
Not even the owner should be demolishing
a shop that hasn't been vacated.
Oh, please.
I simply mistook it for
an empty shop at the end.
You think the police will believe that excuse?
You've been harassing them
until now, haven't you?
Who the heck are you?
I am...
The great detective Mori Kogoro-sensei!
Fine, fine. I'm out of here.
We'll just be moving stuff out today.
Bring the light truck around.
Yes, sir.
Nice work, Mori-san.
We got to see you show off your skills again.
You're our hero.
O-Oh, yeah? Well, you know,
you can count on Mori Kogoro
when you're in trouble.
I need to go to the bathroom.
In that case, take this with you.
What's this?
One of this alley's medals.
The bathroom's back there.
Take a right at the dead end.
Insert the medal to unlock the door.
Huh.
Hup.
RESO Italian Izakaya
Beika Gourmet Restaurant Street
It's not even six yet.
Ow!
Oh, you're awake.
I bought some wine.
This is what I've been waiting for.
But first, I'm going to take a leak.
Let's see...
Whoa!
Hey.
Wake up.
Someone call an ambulance!
They say he tripped and hit his head.
Again? I told him the tiles here are slippery.
What's that smell?
Toto Fire Department
Sorry for scaring you.
Shall we head back to the restaurant
and have some dessert?
Okay.
Sorry, Yama-chan. You got a medal?
I've got one.
What happened to the one you took earlier?
Huh? I used it, obviously.
He what?
Don't go in there.
What? But I'm about to wet myself.
This wasn't an accident.
It was a crime targeting Kusumi-san!
What?!
Metropolitan Police Department
I see. This bathroom unlocks
when you insert a medal.
It automatically locks
when the door is closed.
And medals can't be inserted
while someone is inside.
Yeah, but I thought it was odd
that he was able to insert a coin
while Kusumi-san was inside.
Which means...
The only conceivable explanation is that
someone was with him and left the bathroom,
leaving the unconscious Kusumi-san inside.
In other words, this wasn't an accident,
but a murder plotted
by someone at the alley.
B-But...
He was apparently making unreasonable
demands for you to move out.
That sounds like a motive.
W-Wait a minute.
You can't be serious.
A member of our alley would never do that.
That's what we're going to investigate.
During the 15 minutes between 5:30
when Conan-kun went to the bathroom
and 5:45 when Mori-san
discovered the falling victim,
where were you and what were you doing?
I was at my restaurant with Mori-san.
After Conan-kun returned from the bathroom,
I went shopping at a nearby liquor store.
While your restaurant was open?
Yes. Mori-san drank all our house wine.
You were drinking since early in the evening?
Oh, you know...
I've got the receipt.
I was placing orders for
ingredients over the phone.
That was a rather long phone call.
I buy meat, fish, alcohol, and vegetables
from their respective producers.
I see. That sounds like it would take a while.
It's in my call history.
You can go ahead and check it now.
What about you?
I was prepping before opening my shop.
Is there anyone who can corroborate that?
No. It's a small shop,
so I obviously run it alone.
Which means you're the only one
without an alibi.
It wasn't me!
If anything, don't you think it's strange
that you have an alibi for that hour?
What?
Kogoro-kun, say something.
Where are you going, Mori-kun?
Well, you know...
What is it?
I'm going to the bathroom.
I've been holding it this whole time
since I can't use this one.
What?
Inspector, Chiba called me from the hospital.
The victim had a contusion
on the side of his head.
I knew it.
After knocking out Kusumi-san by
striking him on the side of the head,
perhaps the culprit struck the front
of his head against the door
so it would look like he tripped.
It's likely.
Excuse us, but we'll be
checking the inside of your shop.
If you're the culprit, you'll have
hidden the weapon somewhere.
Sakura Sushi
Sakura
Something's not right.
Creative Cuisine Seventy-Seven
If Fumio-san is the culprit,
why did she close the door?
Do Not Enter
If she hadn't closed the door,
Kusumi-san's murder might've
been written off as an accident.
What's this?
It's the soba flour that
was on Kusumi-san's jacket.
What?
But why?
I see. I've figured it out.
I know what the weapon is
and who's the true culprit
who tried to frame Fumio-san.
Inspector.
There isn't a speck of dust on it
even thought it was in the back.
Like it's just been wiped clean.
It's possible someone wiped
away the sweat and hair
that may have stuck to it
when they struck Kusumi-san.
You can't be serious.
Wait.
What? Mori-san said someone else did it?
There's something I'd
like to discuss with you.
Huh? Mister...
I thought he found the culprit.
Well, I guess this is convenient.
Why the formality?
Curry, huh? Brings back memories.
You fed me curry often
when I didn't have money.
Yeah, back when this was a board house.
Now it's on your menu.
It smells as amazing as ever.
It's not ready yet.
I'm about to put the roux in.
Speaking of smells, didn't Kusumi-san
smell like rotten vegetables?
I didn't notice.
Maybe he was cleaning up
some rotten ingredients.
It was pretty strong, but I guess you
wouldn't notice if you smelled the same way.
What?
If you're making curry, then
you must've used some, right?
Asafoetida, a spice that
smells like rotten vegetables.
You said it's such a powerful spice
people call it "devil's dung"
and let me take a whiff.
And when heated, it becomes the
delicious smell of cooked onions.
You're the one who was in the
bathroom with Kusumi-san, aren't you?
Tell me the truth about what happened.
Impressive, Detective. You remembered.
Is what I'd like to say, but you saw
the argument I had with Kusumi.
The smell got on him then.
Besides, I've got an alibi.
You used to do it all the time
while accepting reservations.
Three people an hour from now?
Yes. Yes.
You'd hold your phone between
your shoulder and cheek.
If I did it, then what's the weapon?
That's right, Mori-kun.
Inspector?
You weren't there, but we found a bottle we
believe is the weapon in Fumio-san's shop.
I didn't do it!
What's going on, Detective?
What? Well, uh...
I don't have a choice. Sorry, old man.
Asafoetida!
He's sleeping now?
The bottle isn't the weapon.
Then what is it?
It's right in front of you.
What?
It's hard frozen bread dough.
Though it's beginning to thaw.
What?
Even if fingerprints get on it,
nothing will be left once it's baked.
That's why you took it to the bathroom
without even wrapping it in plastic.
Where's the proof?
Oh, I've got proof.
You left behind a huge piece of evidence
by trying not to leave any behind.
Look. This powder was on
the ground near the bathroom.
Powder?
You mean there was flour typically
sprinkled on bread dough on the ground?
Unfortunately, I think that's soba flour.
Kusumi's jacket was covered in soba flour,
so of course it was on the ground.
There was soba flour everywhere,
but this is different.
Different how?
Watch this.
There.
What? So, what?
I see. Since you only knead
bread dough, you don't know.
Soba flour doesn't become sticky even
when you knead it with cold water.
That's why they use hot water to make soba.
Tell me.
Why was there wheat flour mixed in with
the soba flour on Kusumi-san's clothes?
I can't believe some flour did me in.
It wasn't just the flour.
I thought it was strange from the start.
Why did the culprit close the door?
If the door hadn't been closed, this case
likely would've been treated as an accident.
Closing the door was necessary because
the culprit wanted to frame Fumio-chan.
You knew all that?
You certainly are a great detective.
Yonezawa...
That's right. I killed him.
I killed the jerk who harassed
the soba shop owner to death.
I told Kusumi I wanted to speak to
him where we wouldn't be seen.
After striking his head,
I hit his head against the door
for the old man,
went outside, and closed the door.
You mean...
That's right. I'm the one who
put the fake weapon there.
But why frame our friend Fumio-chan?
Probably because he heard I was
moving to the train station building.
What?
After saying we'd protect the old man's
alley together, I betrayed the group.
Both you and I got our start here.
The old man taught us everything
we know about business.
How could you face the old man
after being first to leave?
But the one who disgraced himself most is...
Yeah. That's right, Detective.
It's me.
So this is it.
I used to come here when I was broke.
They fed me oden all the time.
Oden-den-den, Oden-den-den!
Here, too?
How many alleys does
the old man remember fondly?