Iwasada Yasuaki (45)
J League Staff
Have fun today.
Okay!
Let's go!
It's the J League 30th anniversary match.
Kawasaki Frontale are attempting to
reclaim the league championship title
from FC Tokyo, who cannot possibly lose at
the National Stadium, in this fantastic game.
Kageyama Yuka-san of Hinatazaka46
is here as today's guest.
I'm Kageyama Yuka. Thanks for having me.
Kageyama-san, what should we
pay special attention to today?
Kageyama Yuka (22)
Hinatazaka46
The match up between Oshima and Matsuki.
I've also got high hopes for Tachibanada.
For today's special event,
the children chosen by lottery
will play a mixed special friendly match
with players from both teams.
Let's do this!
Yeah!
How cute!
How will the kids do?
It's time for the kick off.
The ball is passed from
Yoshida-san to Kojima-kun.
He's trying to dribble through.
Mitsuhiko!
Got it!
What a beautiful coordinated play.
Go!
Will the shot go in?
Matsuki has childishly blocked the shot.
Goal!
Tachibanada forces the ball in.
All right!
Nice goal, Tachibanada.
Tachibanada Kento (24)
Kawasaki Frontale
Thanks.
We're lucky you were there at that moment.
You really are amazing.
What's your secret to success?
My secret? First, relax and calm down.
And...
Keep a broad field of view.
That's what Oshima always says.
Matsuki Kuryu (19)
FC Tokyo
Broad field of view?
Look at not just the ball,
but the entire pitch.
Oshima Ryota (30)
Kawasaki Frontale
Look at not just the pitch,
but the entire stadium.
And everywhere else, too.
Impressive.
Yeah. People who compete
internationally are on another level.
Aw, shucks.
You're all embarrassed? How cute.
Let's go!
Beyond detective skills capable
of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
The J League celebrates its 30th anniversary.
A case begins behind the scenes.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Behind the Scenes of the J League Finals
"Behind the Scenes of the J League Finals"!
It's time for the J League 30th
anniversary match to kick off.
Inspector, where are you
going all dressed up?
Do you have a date?
Nothing like that. Just some minor business.
I'll be back.
See you later.
I'm hungry.
Matsuki was so cool.
So were Oshima and Tachibanada.
We're so lucky.
We certainly are.
Lucky, huh? Yeah, I guess we are.
Yeah.
This wasn't supposed to happen.
I was supposed to hold hands with my
beloved Higo when we entered the pitch.
Yesterday's Big Osaka match was amazing.
I'd forgotten Haibara gets
emotional when it comes to Higo.
Sanada made a ton of mistakes.
Yeah.
Give me a break.
That's right. Sanada missed a huge
opportunity, and Big lost the game.
It was awful!
Sorry about that.
Sanada!
Hey, keep your voices down.
What if the other fans notice?
What are you doing here?
You're here to scout out the enemy, right?
That's right. I thought I'd give them
a thrashin' the next time we play them.
I hope you do.
After all, Tachibanada gave you a
thrashing in your match the other day.
It's not surprising.
He's the captain of a team that's
produced one great player after another.
Spirits gave you a thrashing
in yesterday's match, too.
It's a fierce scramble for the ball.
Which team will seize the initiative?
Wow!
Their intensity is on another level.
Something's not right.
Look. Behind the Frontale goal.
What's going on?
There aren't any fans.
Maybe they couldn't sell the tickets.
That's impossible.
National Stadium tickets
are really hard to get.
What's going on?
Look at this.
It's a livestream on social media.
There's an argument happening
outside the National Stadium.
What? Why?
Hey!
I'm sorry, but that ticket
seems to be invalid.
What does that mean?
Do you have any idea how hard
it was to get this ticket?
What do you mean, it's invalid?
Takeuchi Ryo (35)
J League Staff
I understand, but...
You can't be serious!
Let us in!
That's not good.
Not good? They're about to explode.
Does it have something to do
with those empty seats?
Almost!
They were so close.
Aw, man.
What's his deal?
Over there. That man.
What about him?
He hasn't been watching the match at all.
That's ridiculous. No one comes all the way
to the stadium to not watch the match.
That's why Edogawa-kun said
it doesn't make sense, right?
It's suspicious.
Yeah.
The mysterious empty seats,
the supporters not allowed entry,
and the mysterious man
who's not watching the match...
This calls for an investigation.
Hello?
Oh, Conan-kun.
Detective Takagi, I need a favor.
I'm going to send you a photo.
I'd like you to find out what you can
about the person in the photo.
Is there something the matter with them?
I'm just curious about something. Thanks.
Let us in!
Yoshikawa Mitsutoshi (33)
J League Staff
We're currently looking into the cause.
The supporters denied entry
and the mysterious man...
I wonder what's going on.
Maybe someone made a bunch of fake tickets?
Ah, I see.
Paper tickets aren't the only kind of tickets.
There are smartphone codes
that can be scanned, too.
Besides, the seats behind
the goal are still empty.
Did the FC Tokyo supporters do it to
give their team an advantage in the match?
That must be it.
That would take too much effort,
and it's too roundabout.
Why would someone go to the trouble
of hacking the system
to invalidate a bunch of tickets
so FC Tokyo will win?
Maybe they bet a lot of money on the match.
That's what I thought, too.
If they were willing to do all that work,
I'd expect them to choose
a more certain method.
Then why?
Well...
Hello?
I ran the photo you sent through the facial
recognition software and got a match.
The man in the photo is
Fukunaga Yuzo, 55 years old.
Comparing
Please select image
to compare
98.3% Match
He's the leader of a terrorist organization
who hasn't done anything major recently.
In the past he was the mastermind
behind large-scale terrorist plots.
Fortunately, his plans were stopped
before they could be carried out,
and his entire organization was arrested.
He was found guilty and served time.
He just completed his sentence
the other day and was released.
So he's a former terrorist.
What?
He's at the National Stadium?
Some supporters have been denied
entry to the stadium as well.
There must be something going on.
What? Why—
Give me that.
Hey, wait!
Ow...
We'll head there right now.
What are we going to do now?
We need to keep our eyes on that man.
I'm also curious about
what's happening outside.
Haibara, I'm going to go check it out.
Keep an eye on him.
Got it. Be careful.
Goal! Matsuki of FC Tokyo
scores the first goal.
I came all the way here from Osaka,
and now I can't even watch the match.
You don't have to come with me.
You expect me to casually
watch a soccer match
while makin' a kid to handle
a terrorist? Yeah, right.
It's not as though adults are always useful.
In that case, what do you think of this?
What? Hey, wait!
Hup!
We'll jump right over the entry gate!
This isn't safe. Please stop pushing.
Crap.
Not even an unstoppable J Leaguer
can do anything about this.
Unstoppable? What would Haibara
have to say about that?
Hey, look.
All the fans should want to get in,
but there are some people who don't.
Huh? What do you mean?
The real fans are interested
in the match happening inside,
but the fake fans only care about
what's happening behind the gate.
Are they that guy's accomplices?
Looks like that Fukunaga guy
hasn't learned his lesson.
We have activity.
Someone who's probably his accomplice
handed him a large case.
Could it be a bomb?
No, the shape of the case was more like...
A sniper rifle?
For real? Are we in a Hollywood movie?
Come to think of it,
Fukunaga's past terrorist plots
involved the assassination
of a VIP with a rifle.
What should we do?
We can't just keep watching
him from a distance.
Yeah.
Did he cause this commotion so
he could sneak in a rifle, or...?
In other words, it's time for us to act.
Don't! It's too dangerous!
Don't worry. We'll make sure
we're not spotted.
We'll be fine as long as we split up.
Detective Boys, move out!
Yeah!
Hey, wait.
Jeez. We'd better hurry.
Hello, Detective Takagi?
Could you head to the
Sendagaya gate at the stadium?
Got it.
He should be on the other side of this area.
The suspect is on the move.
Don't do anything reckless.
Got it.
There aren't too many people, so we
should be able to follow him easily.
The first half is over.
It's now halftime.
Yeesh...
Where is it?
The professor is looking around, but
so far he hasn't found any explosives.
Then we should assume
he's trying to shoot someone.
What? There are thousands of people here.
There's no way to know who he's after.
Do you give up in the middle of matches?
And you call yourself
Higo's partner? What a joke.
I'll check the news and social media
to look into every VIP and
celebrity at the stadium.
Thanks. I'm going to review
the documents again.
Both parents died of illnesses.
No relatives. Never married.
No information about friends or acquaintances.
His terrorist organization repeatedly
attacked the government and police.
Is he doing that again? But that's not enough.
Have you found anything?
No. There are a lot of celebrities here,
but I'm not seeing any
connections to the suspect.
Let's see...
I wonder where he is.
It's no use. I don't see him anywhere.
Don't give up, Mitsuhiko.
I know.
Who is his target?
Ow! What was that for?
Who's givin' up?
I'll keep runnin' until the very end.
What? Whoa!
Hey, kid. Start by calmin' down.
Take some deep breaths.
What?
Come on.
You're torturing me! Ow, that hurts!
Inhale.
And exhale.
Ow, ow, ow!
Start by calming down?
First, relax and calm down.
And keep a broad field of view.
A broad field of view...
It's not here.
What?
There are homes of important political figures,
and government, police, and
Self-Defense Force facilities
near the National Stadium.
I see. The stadium is just
the shooting location.
The target is somewhere else.
Goal! That's FC Tokyo's second point.
That second point puts them
in a strong position to win.
Nichiuri NEWS
Fukunaga Yuzo (55)
Inspector Megure of Division One
stops large-scale terrorist plot
and arrests entire terrorist group!
What's this?
What could they shoot from here?
It's no use. I don't see any likely targets.
I don't think so.
Conan-kun, I just arrived at the gate.
Detective Takagi, is the government,
police, or Self-Defense Force
holding an event near the National Stadium?
An event?
Turn on your speakerphone.
Okay.
A lecture on white collar crime is being held
at the National Stadium's
Umayado Memorial Auditorium.
That's it. Is Inspector Megure
attending that lecture?
How do you know that?
He headed out pretty dressed up today.
It must've been to give a lecture.
But does that have anything
to do with this case?
Absolutely. It was Inspector Megure who
arrested Fukunaga Yuzo a long time ago.
Fukunaga Yuzo (55)
Inspector Megure of Division One
stops large-scale terrorist plot
and arrests entire terrorist group!
This is terrible.
Also, Fukunaga's accomplices are among
the supporters shut out of the stadium.
What?
Instruct the staff to allow
people with tickets inside.
Whoever's left outside is a terrorist.
Given the auditorium's location, the shooting
location must be near the Aoyama gate.
Takagi-kun, contact Inspector Megure.
Got it. Wait, Sato-san?
Hold onto my shoes.
What?
I'm heading to the Aoyama gate.
Sato-san!
Ticket holders, don't push.
Please enter one at a time.
They hacked the system and shut out a bunch
of supporters to make it easier to escape.
I see. It's harder to catch the culprits
when they're blendin' in with a crowd.
Fukunaga planned his attack
when he got confirmation Inspector Megure
would be coming to the auditorium.
He caused the commotion at the
National Stadium to distract the police.
And because this...
is the perfect place to
shoot Inspector Megure from.
Hey, you.
Yes?
I'm Takagi of Division One.
Could you take this car to a parking lot?
What?
I'll explain the situation
when I come back for it. Thanks.
Yes, sir.
Sato-san!
Frontale are finally starting to look lively.
Tachibanada's combo plays with
Oshima are heating up, too.
This attack isn't for his ideology
or any great purpose.
It's simple revenge.
His accomplices are
probably all hired men, too.
I can't believe he did somethin' so elaborate
just to get back at someone
for arrestin' him.
He must be totally twisted.
You're right, so...
We can't allow him to succeed, no matter what.
You're right.
Here we go.
He's really here.
You're too late.
Stop. Get out of the car.
Get out of here.
Drop your weapons.
Police! You're under arrest.
What's going on?
You, too! Drop your weapon!
Takagi-kun.
What's going on here?
Inspector, get down!
What?
No, you don't!
Stand back!
I simply did what any J Leaguer would do.
It's true, then?
Did you really stop an assassination attempt
on the Division One police inspector?
I simply did what any J Leaguer would do.
It's not fair. You solved
most of the case, Conan-kun.
It's fine. Sanada worked really hard.
The entire criminal group and principal
offender Fukunaga were arrested.
His terrorist plot was stopped
before it could happen again.
Thanks to Sanada's shot.
Anyway, Frontale was amazing after that.
Two fierce goals in a row.
What a sight worth seeing.
I thought they'd make a comeback,
but FC Tokyo was impressive, too.
In any case, it was a good match.
Yeah.
I'm excited for the next one.
The next one, huh?
I'm kind of worried, actually.
Next time I'll enter the pitch
holding hands with Higo...
Episode Preview
Sir!
You're not going to yell
like you always do? Creepy.
How odd. It's as though
someone trapped you inside.
Could it be? I know, I must've
hit the floor when I fell asleep.
The Freezing Cold Men
The next episode of Conan
is "The Freezing Cold Men"!
Next Conan's hint!
Bag
A bag!
30 years? Wow.
Don't miss the next episode.
You know, we're actually—
Don't say it.