Ai
Aizawa Foods
Safety First
Aizawa Kenzo (72)
Aizawa Foods Company President
Sir, are you in here?
S-Sir?
Are you all right, sir?
Your body's freezing. We need
to get you to the hospital.
Bando Masaru (69)
Aizawa Foods Managing Director
Sir?
S-Sir!
Beyond detective skills
capable of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
A rift forms between a father and his sons.
Trapped within are love and hate.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Freezing Cold Men
"The Freezing Cold Men!"
Beika Chuo Hospital
Kadome
I'm glad it wasn't serious.
Wash your hands!
I can't believe you made such a fuss
over a little cut from a knife.
It's embarrassing.
You can't be serious, bro!
Hey, what are you doing?
Hey.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
Aizawa Ryoichi (33)
Kenzo's Older Son
You resort to violence the
moment you get upset, huh?
Reiji, are you the one
who attacked our father, too?
I thought you'd finally done something.
Aizawa Reiji (29)
Kenzo's Younger Son
Both of you, the president
is still being treated.
Treatment Room
What exactly happened?
This man is the great detective Mori Kogoro.
You can tell him anything.
Just discussing what happened is free, right?
Well, yes.
Why not, Bando-san?
He's rather shrewd.
But...
Tell him. I don't mind.
And he reeks of liquor.
We work for a small food company
called Aizawa Foods.
Our father is the president.
Bando-san, who's been his right-hand man
for years, is the senior executive director.
My brother and I are managing directors.
Why are you going on about titles
when we're the only employees?
After all, somebody fired all the others.
I simply removed what we didn't need.
I had today off, so I spent
the whole day sleeping at home.
I think it was around 7PM
when noticed I'd forgotten my phone
at the office and went to get it.
The president's briefcase was still there,
and when I went to the refrigerated
warehouse to check on him, he was...
Refrigerated warehouse?
The refrigerated warehouse
we use to store products.
Even the safety features are
rusted on that run-down thing
because my brother's so stingy.
We don't have the money to buy a new one.
In any case, the president has always
inspected the office and locked up
after everyone else has gone home.
And during his inspection—
Doctor, how is he?
I was just taking a nap.
Kadome
A nap, huh?
Yes. It was an accident.
Doctor, how is our father?
He's fine. He should be able
to go home tomorrow.
That's great.
I must've been tired.
I only meant to take a quick
break during my inspection.
How embarrassing.
Please be careful.
Ten minutes later, and
it would've been too late.
You saved me again, Masaru.
Sir...
You took a break inside
the refrigerated warehouse?
Y-Yes.
This has made things clear.
We can't have a senile president.
You have to quit. You're causing problems.
I agree. You were napping?
It would've been better if
you'd stayed asleep forever.
You shouldn't say that.
Boys.
What?
You're not going to yell
like you always do? Creepy.
I'm tired. Please leave me alone, everyone.
I should go.
Is your hand okay?
I bang on the bathroom door in the morning
when the old man is inside so he'll open it.
That's how you got that, right?
How odd. It's as though
someone trapped you inside.
As if. I know, I must've hit it
on the floor when I fell asleep.
Wow, you broke your fall with your
hand even though you were asleep?
It certainly is strange.
Maybe you didn't actually take a nap.
Why would I lie about that?
Kadome
Because you don't want this
to become a legal case.
That's nonsense!
Mori-san, I have a request.
Aizawa Foods
Ai
Safety First
I see. So this is the refrigerated warehouse.
As you said, we've kept everything
the same as it was yesterday.
Didn't you just get out of the hospital?
You should be resting.
I can't.
That's odd, though. My stingy
brother hired a detective?
What are you planning?
When it comes to risk management,
you end up paying for it later
if you're stingy to begin with.
You're a perfect example.
If you'd been disciplined
properly as a child—
What does that mean?
Hey, look at this.
Is this the only lock?
Yes. It can only be locked from the outside.
Was it locked when you found the president?
I see. If this was an accident,
then it shouldn't have been locked.
But if someone locked it, then...
Let's see...
I don't remember.
Bando-san, be honest.
It was locked.
So someone locked the president inside?
Where's the key to this padlock?
In the office. Anyone from our company
would have been able to use it.
So the culprit is one of you.
What about former employees?
They were all fired, right?
Maybe they resented that.
That's impossible.
Why?
Because...
It sounds like you know who the culprit is.
Are you all right, sir?
Yeah. I just felt a little dizzy.
It's freezing.
Someone must've done it on purpose.
Dad, we should call the police.
Don't!
For our small company, trust is everything.
We're already in debt.
The police merely showing up
would destroy us.
But you got lucky when
you were rescued yesterday.
The next time...
The president has labored for decades
trying to protect the company
the previous president gave to him.
I've watched him this whole time.
Please take his feelings into account.
You're doing it for the company?
Is that really the only reason?
Are you sure you're not protecting
something more important than the company?
Our dad doesn't have anything like that.
He's only ever cared about the company.
When our mother collapsed...
Maybe that's why he's protecting
his family this time.
Come to think of it, you got into a shouting
match with Dad yesterday afternoon.
I wouldn't go this far over an argument.
And I've got an alibi.
I was drinking all evening
at a place called Club L.
That's a high-class club
with beautiful women.
I'm so jealous.
Dad.
You perv.
I've made a reservation
again today. I gotta go.
Reiji-san, please tone down your partying.
Out of my way!
Ryoichi-san, is the door left open when
the president conducts his inspection?
No, he closes it so the cold air
doesn't get out.
It really is freezing.
Come on. Haven't you seen enough?
But...
Get out of here.
Aizawa Foods
The case is coming into focus.
Reiji-san is most suspicious.
But he has an alibi.
Reiji goes there all the time.
I'm sure they'd help him fake an alibi.
Then...
Ryoichi-san, what's your alibi?
We haven't heard yours yet.
After leaving the company at five,
I was working from home the whole time.
Can anyone verify that?
No.
Why didn't you work at the office?
Because...
It doesn't matter.
Besides, if I were the culprit,
I wouldn't have hired a detective.
Isn't that right, Detective Mori?
That's right. And you stay out of this, kid!
Okay...
Well? Do you think it'll work?
Tonight's the night.
If it comes to it, I'm prepared
to do what I have to do.
What? What time did Ryoichi-san
arrive at the hospital?
Come to think of it, he arrived pretty early.
He didn't come from home?
No. That would've taken him longer.
Does Mori-san suspect Ryoichi-san?
But he doesn't have a motive.
Actually, Ryoichi-san is eager
to take over the company.
He'd mercilessly get rid
of anything in his way,
even if that's his father.
Aizawa Foods
I can't believe those adorable
children ended up like that.
Oh, I'm sorry. I couldn't help myself.
Wow, these look good!
Hey.
Sorry. The kid wouldn't listen.
Where did these come from?
They're from my former employees.
Even though you fired them?
They were all picked up by Kadome.
Kadome? That's a major company.
They've got a factory next to the hospital.
I'm surprised they hired all of them.
The president's got a lot
of personal magnetism.
That's it.
Ran-neechan, earlier Kogoro-no-ojisan said...
Sure, but Dad could've asked me himself.
Is that your briefcase?
Yeah. I remembered I forgot to inspect
an area and left it there in my rush.
It's still new.
My birthday was two days ago.
It was a gift from my sons.
Your brown briefcase was run down.
The president's briefcase
is the company's face.
You need to look sharp for the rest of us.
Sorry.
Did you throw a birthday party two days ago?
Yeah, with just the three of us
for the first time in a while.
He's got a short temper,
but he's a good guy at heart.
So why did you think
Reiji-san is the culprit?
I mean, just look at
how he dresses and speaks.
Why don't you come clean?
So you saw Reiji-san lock you in
and heard his voice, too.
Was that really Reiji-san, though?
Ryoichi-san.
I'm going to go look for Reiji.
Aizawa Foods
Ryoichi-san.
Even in that cold refrigerated warehouse,
you're so proper you never put
your hands in your pockets,
but you just left with
your hands in your pockets.
What are you hiding?
Who exactly are you?
You're still here, kid?
Reiji.
Let's all head back. The old man says—
I know who the culprit is?
You don't?
What's going on here?
That kid said you were calling us.
Actually, I...
Who is the culprit?
You figured it out, didn't you?
I figured it out...
Yes, I finally figured out who trapped the
president inside the refrigerated warehouse.
What?
Sir, you saw Reiji-san close the door.
What? Are you serious?
And you've been protecting Reiji-san.
But it's strange.
The door should've been closed during your
inspection so the cold air wouldn't escape.
He could've just locked the closed door.
But the culprit chose to open
the door so he'd be seen.
Why is that? So you'd see him, of course.
When the crime occurred,
the strong light from the setting sun
was shining in through the door.
In other words, you couldn't see the
culprit's face because it was backlit.
All you saw was a silhouette
with a distinctive hairstyle.
Th-That's exactly right.
I see. Since they have similar builds,
he could disguise himself as Reiji-san.
But didn't the president
hear Reiji-san's voice?
Ryoichi-san can explain that.
Later, Dad! I never want
to see your face again!
That's probably an edited
version of a secret recording
of Reiji-san's argument with the president.
Bro...
No, you're wrong.
I thought about it again,
and both Ryoichi and Reiji
have flaws, but it wasn't them.
They aren't the kind of people to do this.
It's impossible!
Dad...
I'm impressed. You're absolutely right.
Ryoichi-san was framed as well
by the person who hid that in his desk.
If he were the culprit, he would've
tossed it in the river earlier,
but he didn't because it proves
Reiji-san's innocence.
Bro...
It's evidence that will lead us to the truth.
Then who did it?
The culprit went through all this
effort to convince the president
that Reiji-san is the culprit.
His plan assumed the president would survive.
In other words, the culprit is Bando-san,
who rescued the president.
You're far apart in age, but your build
is roughly the same as Reiji-san's.
That's your only reason?
You can't be serious.
How can you assert I did it?
The briefcase.
The briefcase?
You claimed the following.
The president's briefcase was still there,
and when I went to the
refrigerated warehouse...
Wh-What's wrong with that?
That really was the president's briefcase.
Yes, but when and how did you learn that?
The president just received
that briefcase two days ago
at a party attended only by his family.
In other words, since you were sleeping
at home yesterday on your day off,
you never had the opportunity
to learn that it was his.
You'd only know if you were the culprit
and saw the president carrying it
before you attacked him.
That's right. I'm responsible for everything.
But why?
It's your fault for saying you'd
leave the company to your sons.
You even tried to get me to retire.
We're both getting too old.
It's time for us to retire.
They'll be fine—
They won't be fine!
That's what I tried to show you.
That's why you came up with this plan?
The president thought this
company would run smoothly
with Ryoichi and Reiji running it together.
But if either one lost his trust,
neither one would take over.
I'd be the only one
the president could rely on.
Then the company would be mine.
So you were trying to take over the company.
You make it sound so awful.
I did it for the company.
This company would do so much better
if I took control and not these youngsters!
So when I first suspected
Reiji-san and then Ryoichi-san,
you tried to frame Ryoichi-san.
But if an employee were
arrested, the company—
You're wrong about that.
Ryoichi the heartless
and Reiji the delinquent.
Getting rid of those two would
improve public trust in the company.
I did it because I care about
this company more than anyone else.
Even though you nearly killed the president?
You did it for your own ego.
Damn it.
You're not the one who truly
cares about the company.
What?
I had Ran confirm that Ryoichi-san visited
the Kadome factory yesterday evening.
And not just yesterday evening.
You've been going there since before
they accepted your former employees.
So it wasn't because of the
president's personal magnetism.
That's the kind of man Ryoichi is.
But what about Reiji?
Reiji-san, your coat.
That outfit...
You were entertaining clients.
And the grime on your forehead...
Groveling before clients is no big deal.
I got a huge contract for us.
Don't worry, Dad.
We promise we'll restore this
company to its former glory.
Yeah.
Looks like the president's
judgment was correct, Bando-san.
Aizawa Foods
I think I caught a cold.
That refrigerated warehouse sure was cold.
Here.
Thanks.
Hot!
Here.
I'm thirsty after working up a sweat.
She's got all the energy you'd expect
from a karate club captain.