Mori Detective Agency
In the recent string of murders
of seven foreigners,
a culprit still has not been apprehended,
and none of the victims have been identified.
No progress in foreigner murder investigation
We received an unverified tip that
one of the foreigners was an FBI agent,
but when asked about it, FBI headquarters
said the information was groundless.
There's no way they're FBI.
This isn't a movie or TV show.
Right?
Even if they were FBI, what
would they have been up to?
They really were FBI, though.
Swiping the FBI badge from the body
that fell from the building in Beika City
and handing it over to James-san's
group was the right call.
If people learned the victims were FBI
agents, it would become a huge deal.
It'd be difficult for Akai-san
and the rest to remain in Japan.
Though since there have been
more than ten casualties,
FBI headquarters ordered them back home,
and most of them have returned
to their home country.
Two things still weigh on my mind.
Dad and Akai-san were discussing something
when we returned from Umizaru Island.
I still haven't received a response
to the late-night tea party.
Right.
Tea party?
Then there's the information concerning
Rum's identity Camel overheard.
They killed seven of our agents,
and others were gravely injured.
But we only chased them off
and have nothing to show for it.
Come to think of it,
Vodka mentioned something.
Some say Rum is a big man,
some say he's a masculine woman.
Some say he's an old man, and
some say he's got a false eye.
But aside from the false eye, the
rumors are lies Rum himself spread.
He also said these days he wears a
disguise and goes by a ridiculous name.
A ridiculous name...
None of the FBI agents said they
had any idea who he could be.
I could ask Amuro-san, but he'd
probably dodge the question.
Who else can I discuss this with?
Get lunch with Conan-kun at Poirot, okay?
Come to think of it, they're coming
from Osaka today, aren't they?
Hattori!
That must be them.
Perfect timing!
I'm here, Ran-chan.
Welcome, Kazuha-chan.
Huh?
Huh? What?
If you're looking for Heiji, he's not here.
It's just me.
Oh, really?
Today us girls are going on a secret trip.
Secret trip?
Should we take Conan-kun with us?
Sure. Wanna go to Haido Shrine with us?
Uh, okay...
I guess it's better than eating
at Poirot with the old man.
Beyond detective skills capable
of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
The case begins with matchmaking!
Who's that detective wearing a mask?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Inauspicious Matchmaking
(Part One)
"The Inauspicious Matchmaking, Part One!"
Wow, that's a long line.
I've never seen this many people
at this shrine before.
Today's the 15th. It's a special day.
Special how?
It's supposed to be lucky,
so they sell matchmaking charms
and stamps just for today.
Everyone's talking about how great they are,
so I'm gonna buy one and
capture Heiji's heart.
Right.
I'm pretty sure it's already yours.
Does that mean everyone in line
is interested in matchmaking?
Yeah. Everyone, including
those schoolboys and ladies.
Huh?
Does that guy looking at his flashcards
want a matchmaking charm, too?
He should buy one for academic success
if he's studying for entrance exams.
Maybe he's hoping he'll be "matched"
with the schools he's applying to.
Oh, right. That's one
old-looking student, though.
He looks like he's failed
his exams ten times already.
Well, some people don't start
attending college until they're older.
Wait a sec, Ran-chan.
Did you not know about this shrine
even though you're local?
I'm familiar with Beika Shrine, but
I only ever passed by this place.
How'd you learn about it?
From Heiji.
The other day he was staring at
his phone, so I asked him about it.
What are you looking at?
He was so surprised, he dropped his phone.
When I picked it up, I saw the words
"Haido Shrine" and got curious.
Haido Shrine
When I looked it up online later, I learned
it was a shrine famous for matchmaking.
Haido Shrine
Heiji was probably looking
into something else, though.
Actually, judging by how
he's been acting recently...
What you said over the phone
had better be true.
The view is magnificent.
Better than the view of
Big Ben in the evening?
Of course. It doesn't even compare.
Hey, Kudo.
Huh?
If you're planning on asking why we came...
I'm not.
I already know.
Who comes all the way to Tokyo for that?
Shut up, idiot.
You went all the way to London
to tell her how you feel.
I-In my case...
W-We just happened to be in London.
Oh, yeah? I'd like to say
a line as cool as that.
"I shall come to take the fairy's lip."
To take the lip...
Heiji, you're staring at my mouth again!
Heck yeah.
If I beat Kudo, I'll ride that
momentum to the lovely spot
and confess my feelings to Kazuha!
It'd make sense if he wanted to get
his hands on a matchmaking charm.
Wait a minute.
If today's the only day those charms
and stamps are available,
Haido Shrine
then he might be...
Conan-kun?
Is something the matter?
Uh, no...
I'm tired of standing in line.
Could I go walk around the shrine?
Sure, go on.
Be careful.
Okay.
Which charm do you want?
Anything's fine.
What's this about, Heiji?
What are you wearing that mask for?
It's not what you think.
There's a reason I'm doing this.
Huh? K-Kazuha?
This jerk used his voice-changer
to imitate Kazuha's voice.
Anyway, I didn't think you
were one to turn to prayer.
Wh-What am I supposed to do?
During the Nue case at Kurogane Lake...
Listen, Kazuha.
I didn't realize it until the
incident at the Ebisu Bridge,
but it seems I...
have...
Evacuate the civilians to a safe area!
Huh?
Wh-Wh-What?
...the self-defense force interrupted me.
When Kinza Block 4 was lit up for Christmas...
No...
You should've tried talking
to him before stabbing him.
Wait, I don't have time for this!
I've gotta get to Kinza Block 4!
We're not going to Kinza.
We're going to Tokyo Station.
K-Kazuha!
...another case interfered with my plans.
When the two passenger ships
moored in Haido Harbor...
Heiji!
Wow, what a pretty sunset.
You dummy.
Look closely at the two passenger
ships in front of the setting sun.
The white ship in front and the
ship with the red chimney behind it
are only both at this harbor once a year.
In other words, today's the only day
those ships line up to form a heart.
Which makes today a heart's day to remember.
Kazuha, I'm about to spill my
heart to you, so listen closely.
K-Kazuha?
Wh-Where did you go, Kazuha?
Hattori.
K-Kudo?
Kazuha-chan just headed down the stairs
after that Iori guy whispered
something in her ear.
...Momiji's butler got in my way.
During the Fairy Lip case...
Enough already.
Everything you've been saying is ridiculous.
Looks like I'll have to cover
that ridiculous mouth
in order to keep you quiet.
Wha...
Wh-What's all the noise for?
...you guys interrupted—
I mean, I appreciated you interrupting me
since that was Kid disguised as Kazuha.
I finally realized
what I'd been missing wasn't
beautiful sights or situations, but luck.
So I came to receive the blessing
of the matchmaking gods.
I thought I'd improve my luck.
Wouldn't you benefit more
from warding off misfortune?
But when I got here, I was surprised
to see you guys with Kazuha,
so I put on this mask.
I see.
In any case, you're screwed
if you run into those two,
so I'll tape my voice-changer
to the inside of your mask.
If you turn the dials to change
your voice, they won't figure it out.
You're right.
Huh?
Conan-kun, who are you talking to?
Oh, uh, he's...
I'm, uh...
That voice... Could it be?
Are you Komoto Hyoga-kun of the Naniwa Kids?
What?
I'm a huge fan.
Uh...
You're dark-skinned and kinda look like Heiji.
Oh, right. You're wearing a mask
because you're here in secret.
Y-Yeah, that's it.
The voice I got after randomly turning
the dials sounds like his, then.
Come to think of it, I heard on the news
that Komoto-kun's been missing since his
relationship was discovered yesterday.
He's involved with TV
personality Mikage Usagi,
and her agency denied their relationship,
so he must be desperate to get
a matchmaking charm so he can be with her.
Don't worry.
We'll make sure your identity isn't exposed
until you get your charm, Komoto-kun.
Th-Thanks.
Were you two able to get yours?
Yeah.
While you were off exploring the grounds,
we got our charms and stamps.
Come to think of it, something odd
happened just before we bought ours.
Something odd?
Yeah. Just before we bought ours,
that old exam student left the line
and chased after someone
while saying something strange.
What'd he say?
"This really is a matchmaking shrine."
"That's three of them in one place."
Three of them...
...in one place?
That scream...
It might've come from the rear steps.
Hey, wait.
Aw, come on!
Are all boys like that?
He's just like Heiji, always
all over any kind of case.
She's right.
He's just like Hattori-kun.
It's no use. He's dead.
No way.
It's the old exam student.
Maybe he slipped down the steps.
There's a lot of snow.
No.
If that were the case, he
would've used his elbow or hand
to break his fall and protect his body,
but there's no sign of that.
Which means after knocking him out,
someone pushed him down the stairs.
It was murder.
Wow, Komoto-kun really is just like Heiji.
Judging by this bloody flag
abandoned on the steps,
the culprit probably struck the victim
with this flag at the top of the steps,
pushed him down, and killed him.
Since a flag would attract attention,
he removed just the pole and fled.
But who would do that to an exam student?
He's not an exam student.
What?
Look at these flashcards he had.
They're all photos of people.
What does it mean?
He was probably memorizing
the faces of wanted criminals,
looking for them in the city,
and questioning and arresting
them if he found any.
He was a police investigator.
Shinichi-niichan told me about it once.
Shinichi's been teaching
kids that stuff again?
In that case, does that mean
the "three of them" he mentioned
were three wanted criminals he spotted?
Yeah, so I need you to call Detective Takagi
and tell him not to let
anyone out of the shrine.
Okay.
Tell him those three bad guys
might still be at the shrine.
So after receiving your call
and the investigating shrine grounds,
we found that all three
of them were still here.
What? Really?
That's them.
Shamoto Tsurumi (30)
Pickpocket and Shoplifter
Pickpocket and shoplifter Shamoto Tsurumi.
Kawano Torahiko, who drove without
a license and committed a hit-and-run.
Kawano Torahiko (38)
Driving Without a License and Hit-and-Run
Marriage fraudster Jinnai Kyoma.
Jinnai Kyoma (29)
Marriage Fraudster
And one of you may have added
murder to their list of crimes.
Matchmaking Prayers
The victim was MPD Investigation
Assistance Police Lieutenant
Hidaka Soshi, 31 years old.
Given the contusion on the back of his head
and no evidence that he broke his fall,
we believe he died when he was knocked out
by someone at the top of the steps,
fell down the steps, and struck his head.
We can't say for certain until forensics
examines the contusion on his head,
but judging by the bloody flag
abandoned on the steps,
the culprit probably struck the victim
on the head using a flag,
knocked him out, pushed
him down, and killed him.
Since a flag would attract attention,
they likely removed the pole
from the flag and fled with it.
Officers are currently searching the shrine
grounds, but they haven't found it yet.
I see.
According to testimony from
Ran-chan and her friends,
the victim Lieutenant Hidaka was in line
to purchase a matchmaking charm.
He said, "This really
is a matchmaking shrine."
"That's three of them in one place,"
and then left the line
to chase after someone.
Right?
Yes.
That's definitely what he said.
His job was to memorize the faces of
wanted criminals and find and arrest them.
If he said "three of them", then that
means there were three wanted criminals.
Which means it's safe to assume one of you
three wanted criminals here at Haido Shrine
killed Lieutenant Hidaka.
But why would a police officer want
matchmaking charms and stamps?
Maybe his daughter asked him for them.
It was probably because
he was an investigator.
I've heard some investigators
buy matchmaking charms
in the hopes that they'll
encounter criminals.
Komoto-kun, you're amazing.
What those police officers just said
matches what you deduced earlier.
I bet you'd make a good detective.
Yeah, you can count on me.
I doubt you could beat Heiji, though.
Idiot, I'd never lose to him!
Shouldn't you, though?
Anyway, judging by the situation, it seems
certain the culprit is one of those three.
But why did all three of them
stay at the shrine?
Was there some reason they had to stay?
Then there's the flagpole
thought to be the weapon...
Matchmaking Prayers
Since there was blood on the abandoned flag,
it's not wrong to think that was the weapon.
Matchmaking Prayers
You might be able to knock
someone down the steps with a pole
that seems neither hard nor heavy,
but could you hit them hard
enough to knock them out?
And how has something that
large not been found yet?
The shrine grounds may be vast,
but it's still only a shrine.
They should've found it by now.
Is that flagpole really the weapon?
One more thing...
Ran may not notice, but Kazuha-chan's
been with Hattori since they were kids.
Does she really not realize it's him
just because his voice is different?
Or if she has noticed, then why?
Talk about scary.
Conan-kun?
What are you scowling about?
Are you thinking about the case?
There's that, too, but I was just
wondering what Heiji-niichan is up to.
That dumb mystery nerd is probably
drooling in his sleep while he naps.
Um, Kazuha-chan?
Yeah, it seems pretty likely that she knows.
What are you going to do about it, Hattori?
Episode Preview
The question is, where's that flagpole
that still hasn't been found?
Yes.
The blood matched the victim
Lieutenant Hidaka's.
What was that thudding sound?
Which means it isn't missing.
We just didn't notice.
Yeah.
The weapon's right in front of our eyes.
The Inauspicious Matchmaking
(Part Two)
The next episode of Conan is
"The Inauspicious Matchmaking, Part Two!"
Ready, and...
Snowman
Next Conan's hint!
A snowman!
That looks good on you.
Don't miss the next episode.
That's hardly a compliment.
Hey, masked detective.
Shut up.