Ran and Kazuha-chan
brought me to Haido Shrine.
Haido Shrine
While waiting in line to receive stamps,
I spotted Hattori hiding
his face with a fox mask.
Apparently he came to receive
his own matchmaking stamp.
Having purchased their charms and received
their stamps, the girls met up with us.
Using my bowtie voice changer,
Hattori managed to fool them, but...
That scream...
It might've come from the rear steps.
Matchmaking Prayers
The victim was MPD Investigation
Assistance Police Lieutenant
Hidaka Soshi, 31 years old.
His job was to memorize the faces of
wanted criminals and find and arrest them.
If he said "three of them", then that
means there were three wanted criminals.
Which means it's safe to assume one of you
three wanted criminals here at Haido Shrine
killed Lieutenant Hidaka.
Beyond detective skills capable
of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
Heiji exercises his detective
skills from behind a mask.
What is the truth about
the disappearing weapon?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Inauspicious Matchmaking
(Part Two)
"The Inauspicious Matchmaking, Part Two!"
Anyway, why did the three of them remain
at the shrine instead of running away?
It seems that each of them
had a reason for staying.
Shamoto Tsurumi the shoplifter was tied
to a lamppost at the bicycle parking area
using handcuffs and a bicycle cable lock.
Shamoto Tsurumi (30)
Pickpocket and Shoplifter
She was tied up with a bicycle cable lock?
Yes. The bicycle lot is just over there.
Would you like to take a look?
Sure.
I see.
The handcuff chain was passed
through the cable lock, like this.
Both the handcuffs and cable belonged
to the victim Lieutenant Hidaka.
But he could've handcuffed her
directly to the lamppost.
Why did he use the cable?
That police officer did it
out of consideration for me.
At first he handcuffed me to the lamppost so
he could pursue another wanted criminal,
but some kids who came to
park their bike mocked me.
This lady's handcuffed to the lamppost!
Did you do something bad?
So he used his bicycle cable lock instead.
If I leaned against the lamppost
with my arms crossed,
it'd look like I was waiting for someone.
Then you were handcuffed here
when the murder took place?
Yeah, that's right.
There's a police box across from the bike
lot exit, so I didn't feel like trying to run.
Haido Shrine Police Box
But why didn't Lieutenant Hidaka
ask for backup from the police box?
He did, but on their way here, the officer
was instructed to go somewhere else.
There was a fight at the shrine entrance.
I'm the one who started that fight.
While hurrying through this torii gate,
I bumped into some thugs
and got into a fight.
The police box officer showed up
while we were going at it.
Kawano Torahiko (38)
Driving Without a License and Hit-and-Run
You were in a hurry because you realized
Lieutenant Hidaka spotted you, right?
Yeah. I got the sense he was a cop when
I saw him chasing after that shoplifter.
Then why didn't you sidestep
those thugs and leave?
Aren't you a former boxer?
Those thugs got cheeky with me.
I blew my top.
You weren't trying to use the thugs'
blood to hide the police officer's blood
that got on you when you
struck him, were you?
What did you say?
Why would I use a flag, anyway?
I'd hit him with my fists.
Maybe you've lost your boxing skills
and couldn't land a punch on him.
I'll smash your face and that stupid mask.
Hey, don't provoke him.
Huh?
I see.
Ow, ow, ow!
Do you understand the position you're in?
More importantly, who is he?
Why is he still wearing a mask?
He's my friend.
He burnt his face badly,
so he can't remove his mask.
I see.
I didn't run. Or rather,
I didn't think a cop had found me.
I was wandering the temple grounds
looking for my wallet I left somewhere.
Jinnai Kyoma (29)
Marriage Fraudster
Your wallet?
Yes. I had cash, my cash card,
and car keys in there.
But then this police officer stopped me.
I see.
In other words,
there's another wanted criminal
Lieutenant Hidaka found at this shrine,
and you just happened to be caught?
Yes. They may have already fled, though.
You've got an awful lot of mud
splattered up your pant legs.
You're right. This is what happens when
you run through a street with melted snow.
Why'd you have to run if you were just
wandering around looking for something?
Because...
Oh? You've got something on your
face beneath your right eye.
What?
Oh, that's a mole.
By the way, why did you come to this shrine?
For work, you could say.
I came to purchase a matchmaking
charm to use as a fraud tool.
People open their hearts to you
if you give them one as a gift.
This guy sucks.
Yeah.
I bought my charm, but as I was leaving,
I noticed my wallet was missing.
I think I had about 100,000 yen in it.
Yeah, right.
You only had 3,000 yen in there.
What? How do you know that?
Because I swiped your wallet.
I threw away your wallet and cards,
but I kept the keys in my pocket so
I could break into your car later.
I'm admitting it now
before I'm found out later.
You bitch. I couldn't leave even though
I wanted to because of you.
You couldn't leave even though you wanted to?
Uh, I mean...
But according to police records,
I thought you quit pickpocketing.
Yeah. I hadn't shoplifted in a while either
because I found a good man
to take care of me.
But he broke his leg in a traffic
accident and can't work anymore.
I came to this shrine that
attracts lots of people
to pick a few pockets and make some money.
Where did that traffic accident take place?
At an intersection in Toriya City Block 1.
Then the person who ran over
your man was probably this guy.
Wait, no—
What?!
It's your fault this is happening to me!
Hey, wait. Shamoto-san, don't do that.
Sorry about that.
How dare you!
Ow, ow, ow!
Why are you kicking me?
So, why did you come here?
I came to get a stamp for my little sister.
A young man cast her aside
after she spent a fortune on him.
She was pretty down about it.
Wait a minute. You're that guy!
You look exactly like the guy in
the photo my sister showed me!
I-I don't know what you're talking about.
You need to take responsibility
for what you did to me first!
Don't act so self-important!
Give me back my car keys!
You'd better take responsibility,
you marriage fraudster!
I-It's a three-way deadlock.
Their conversation is like a
game of rock-paper-scissors.
They're right.
Haido Shrine
Matchmaking Prayers
The question is, where's that flagpole
that still hasn't been found?
Yes.
Matchmaking Shrine
The blood on the discarded flag
matched the victim Lieutenant Hidaka's.
If the culprit is one of those three, then
it should be somewhere around the shrine.
M-Maybe there really was another culprit.
If they took the flagpole with
them, that would make sense.
Maybe they put it in this box
next to the snowmen.
Look. There's a bunch of unassembled
poles and flags in here.
We had forensics examine that right
away, but they didn't find any blood.
I see.
But why were these things left here?
Because Kawano started a fight at the
entrance while they were being assembled,
the workers left to watch the fight.
That's why no one saw Lieutenant
Hidaka fall down the steps.
I see.
Anyway, it's cute how there are
little snowmen all around the place.
Maybe the neighborhood kids made them.
It's a capsule toy capsule.
When we were kids, we'd use
oranges for our snowmen's eyes.
What was that thudding sound?
It sounded like something
falling on the snow.
Whoa! Be careful.
The ground's still frozen here and there.
Frozen?
Thank you.
There was a tap at the
top of the steps, right?
Yes, I believe there was a faucet.
Which means it isn't missing.
We just didn't notice.
Yeah.
The weapon's right in front of our eyes.
These two definitely feel like them.
This person is Hattori-kun.
Haido Shrine
Give me a break.
Matchmaking Prayers
We might be wanted criminals
that murdered cop was pursuing,
but you still haven't found the weapon
used to strike and knock
him down the steps, right?
It's a flagpole, right?
Then—
Nah.
The flagpole was a red herring
planted by the culprit.
A deception?
After Lieutenant Hidaka
fell down the steps and died,
in order to hide the actual weapon,
they removed the flag
from a nearby flagpole,
rubbed the lieutenant's blood
on it, and left it on the steps.
Then they put the flagpole in the box
filled with other identical poles and fled.
It'd look like the weapon used to strike
the lieutenant was a bloody flagpole.
And if there were no bloody poles in the box,
it'd look like the culprit
fled with the weapon.
Wow, Hyoga-kun. It's a waste of
your talents for you to be an idol.
Kazuha-chan, he's probably...
That masked man is Heiji, right?
What?
Wh-When did you notice?
From the start.
His voice may be different,
but I recognized him instantly.
But you said he sounded like
Komoto Hyoga-kun of the Naniwa Kids.
I don't know how he's changing his
voice, but that's not Hyoga-kun's.
I'm pretending I haven't noticed
so he'll let his guard down and
do whatever he was going to do.
I see. Kazuha-chan's doing this so
Hattori-kun will tell her how he feels.
Heiji...
Then where's the real weapon?
Huh? You didn't hear that?
Huh?
Didn't you hear that thudding noise?
What noise?
And after that, the snowman wearing
the bucket lost one of its eyes, right?
Which means whatever was inside that
bucket fell on the snowman's head.
Whatever was inside the bucket?
A-A bucket-shaped block of ice?
Which means a bucket full of frozen
water was placed on its head,
and the block fell on its head
once the ice melted.
No one would put a bucket
like that on a snowman's head,
so it was probably originally
left by that faucet.
The culprit was nearly caught by the
lieutenant at the top of the steps
and swung around the bucket
they grabbed without thinking.
It hit the lieutenant's head,
and he fell down the steps.
Realizing they had to hide the weapon,
they put the bucket on a snowman,
and made it look like
the weapon was a flagpole
using the method I described earlier.
But any three of them
could have done that.
I couldn't have done that.
That was only possible
because people gathered to see the
fight I started at the shrine entrance
so there was no one left here.
Yeah.
You're innocent. Besides, you're left-handed.
Left-handed?
The contusion on the victim's forehead
ran from top right to bottom left.
Y-You're right.
Which means it's likely
the culprit is right-handed.
When I provoked you, you entered
a southpaw boxing stance.
And you, marriage fraudster.
Haido Shrine
So are you.
When I said you had something
beneath your right eye,
you reached for it with your left hand.
In other words, you're left-handed.
Which leaves you, the
right-handed pickpocket
who touched her glasses with her right hand.
You're the only one left.
What? The world is full
of right-handed people.
How does that make me the culprit?
Besides, I couldn't have done it.
I was handcuffed to a lamppost
at the bike lot the whole time.
I couldn't move.
But if you're lying, you could've swiped
Lieutenant Hidaka's handcuffs after he died
and cuffed yourself to the lamppost.
Maybe if I'd only been
handcuffed to the lamppost,
but the handcuffs on me were passed
through the cop's bicycle cable lock.
I was tied to the lamppost
when you arrive, right?
Yes...
Then tell that masked man
that I couldn't have done it.
It's not impossible.
Want to see if it really can be done
using that cable lock at the bike lot?
This is how she was tied to the post, right?
Y-Yes.
Now take the gap in the cuffs, and...
Pass the cable up through the bottom.
Pass your fist through the loop in the cable,
and simply pull the cable through.
Simply pull it through?
What? Wow, it came off.
I'm impressed you knew about this, Conan-kun.
I saw it on a magic show on TV.
Haido Shrine Police Box
Since there was a police box
right across from the bike lot
and Lieutenant Hidaka had notified
them, it was risky to use that exit.
So you walked across the
shrine to another exit,
but Lieutenant Hidaka found you.
You ran up the steps to get away
from him, but he nearly caught you.
In order to escape, you used the bucket full
of frozen water at the faucet by the stairs
to strike Lieutenant Hidaka, knocking
him down the steps and killing him.
You could've fled then, but it was probable
Lieutenant Hidaka had informed
someone he caught you.
You'd inevitably be wanted for murder.
So like this boy said, you hid the weapon
and returned to the bike lot.
You thought you wouldn't
be suspected if you claimed
you were handcuffed to
the lamppost the whole time.
But if the contusion on Lieutenant Hidaka's
forehead matches the shape of the bucket
and his blood and fingerprints
are found on the bucket,
you won't be able to
talk your way out of this.
Prepare yourself.
Damn. Damn, damn.
I should've just run.
If I'd have run away instead of pulling
this stunt, I'd be—
It would've ended the same way.
These days everyone carries a tiny
camera in the form of a smartphone.
You'd end up arrested after someone
took a picture and reported you.
You can try to sneak around, but
you'll be discovered right away.
There's nowhere for you to run.
No one wants to hear that from a guy
wearing a mask to run away from Kazuha-chan.
Now that the case has been solved,
I'd better get my stamp.
More importantly, Hattori.
Huh?
What kind of name do you think
a "ridiculous" name would be?
A ridiculous name?
I know one guy who's got one.
Who?
Edogawa Conan. It's you.
Not me.
If not you, then there's that guy
you mentioned before, Doito Katsuki.
When you rearrange the letters,
it spells Kaito Kid.
That's a ridiculous name.
An anagram, huh?
Hyoga-kun, you're getting
along great with Conan-kun.
You'd better get in line soon, or you
won't be able to get your stamp.
Y-You're right.
It's Komoto Hyoga-kun of the Naniwa Kids!
No way!
What?
Did you come to get a stamp so
you'll end up with Usagi-chan?
Oh, no.
I've always enjoyed collecting stamps.
I just secretly came to get one.
He sounds different.
You're right.
No, wait. I can explain...
Give it up.
The jig was up from the start, Heiji!
Yeah, that's right. I came to get a stamp.
I need the matchmaking
gods' help with someone.
Help with...
who, exactly?
What?
Who are you trying to get matched with?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
It's obviously you, Kazuha-chan.
I'm like your older sister.
I-I think I've got a right to know.
Sister? Don't be gross, idiot.
You're not my older sister.
You're the gross one.
What were you doing sneaking
around with a mask on?
I-I'll do what I want.
Oh, come on. We're at a matchmaking shrine.
Yeah, what you really need is
something to ward off misfortune.
Episode Preview
It's no use. He's already dead.
As fellow bodybuilders, we spoke sometimes,
but we weren't especially close.
It's not as though Nishitani-san
was particularly promising.
I'll win the next one.
I see. So that's how it is.
The Case of Ayumi's Illustrated Diary 3
The next episode of Conan is
"The Case of Ayumi's Illustrated Diary 3!"
Teeth
Next Conan's hint!
Teeth!
He's so aggravating!
Don't miss the next episode.
I don't think you need to be...
...mad about it.