June 15th. Today I went shopping
with the Detective Boys.
Suddenly, out of nowhere...
Help!
And that's how the third case
of my illustrated diary began.
Beyond detective skills capable
of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
Ayumi's drawings document the case!
The pursuit of beauty leads to tragedy!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Case of Ayumi's Illustrated Diary 3
"The Case of Ayumi's Illustrated Diary 3!"
Tanning Salon Kurosawa
Someone come quickly!
Tanning Salon
A tanning salon?
S-Someone help!
Ayumi-chan!
Tsunoda Yasuo (18)
Salon Employee
S-Sorry, miss. Are you all right?
Yeah.
Did something happen, mister?
Nishitani-san is dead in the back!
Haibara, call the police and an ambulance.
Got it.
Take me to him.
What? Hey, wait.
It's dark in here.
We can't see anything like this.
Mister, where's the light switch?
Is this...?
Oh, sorry.
Nishitani-san's dead back there.
Room number nine, third
from the back on the right.
You guys wait here.
Aw, what?
Nishitani Shin (19)
Beika International University Student
It's no use. He's already dead.
But what's this?
There's something all over his body.
What is this?
It's called tanning gel.
You apply it to get a nice even tan.
Hey, what's that glowing machine?
That's a tanning machine.
It's used to artificially tan.
Huh...
I told you guys to wait.
But why would someone bother getting a tan?
Because being tan makes you look healthy.
And judging by the dead man's build,
he was probably a bodybuilder.
A bodybuilder?
That's someone who builds
their muscles, like us.
A dark tan makes the shadows
beneath your muscles more visible.
And a nice dark tan makes
your muscles look more defined.
Why do they have to be well-defined?
Well, because bodybuilders compete
in contests overseen by judges.
They all go to tanning salons to make
themselves look as good as possible.
I see.
Tanning Salon Kurosawa
Including the victim Nishitani Shin-san,
there were four people at the salon
when the incident occurred.
There was store employee Tsunoda Yasuo-san,
and customers Ozawa Masaru-san
and Nagano Takeshi-san.
They were all very tan and very muscular.
After receiving Ai-chan's call, Detectives
Takagi and Chiba came to the salon
and began investigating the case.
Ozawa-san, what's your relationship
with the late Nishitani-san?
Ozawa Masaru (21)
Student Champion
As fellow bodybuilders, we spoke sometimes,
but we weren't especially close.
So you wouldn't know if anyone resented him
or he was involved in any kind of trouble?
I'm not sure. I never heard
anything like that.
Not to be tasteless, but Ozawa-san is a
three-time student bodybuilding champion.
It's not as though Nishitani-san
was particularly promising.
I see.
Why do you guys pose every
time you say something?
Oh, this? Because there's a
bodybuilding contest coming up.
Our minds are totally occupied
with last minute checks.
Though I'm sure Ozawa-san
will win, of course.
We won't know that until the contest.
Nagano Takeshi (20)
Student
Nice to meet you. I'm Nagano Takeshi.
Nagano-san is said to be Ozawa-san's rival.
Ozawa-san is a great athlete,
but I'll win the next contest.
Did you know Nishitani-san?
Yes. He was my junior at school.
He was a good guy.
Which university do you attend?
Beika International University.
The school's bodybuilding club
is called "Beikoku Body".
It's famous in the bodybuilding community.
Did you notice anything unusual
about Nishitani-san recently?
Well...
Come to think of it, he
recently said he was broke.
Apparently he made a rather large purchase.
A large purchase?
Did you hear what he bought?
No, I wasn't told.
I see.
Anyway, I can't believe it.
Everyone liked Nishitani.
I can't imagine anyone hating him.
Takagi-san, do you have a minute?
Sure.
The cause of death was poisoning.
Poison was found in the gel
rubbed on his body.
We found poison in the gel container, too.
What about the containers
in the other rooms?
We found nothing unusual in them.
Then how did the culprit poison the gel?
What do you mean?
When we arrived, this hallway was dark.
What?
It certainly is dark.
It would be difficult to see
someone's face in this darkness.
Right?
Since there's only one entrance,
it would've been difficult
to enter before Nishitani-san
and poison the gel without being noticed.
But even if the culprit
waited for him in this hallway,
there would've been no point
if they couldn't see his face.
You're right.
In other words, in order
to poison Nishitani-san,
the culprit had to know beforehand
which room he would enter.
I see! So the culprit can see the future.
No, the culprit can move very quickly.
I think the culprit can turn invisible.
Seriously?
There's one person who knew which
room Nishitani-san would enter
without using a superpower.
Yeah.
I don't know anything about that.
But you showed customers
to their rooms, didn't you?
That doesn't mean I did it.
Then why was there poisoned
gel only in that room?
Don't ask me. Maybe it was a coincidence.
That would make this
an indiscriminate murder.
Scary. I was in the room next door.
Maybe they were trying to kill me.
Mister, are the rooms at this salon
different from each other in any way?
Rooms seven, eight, and nine in the back
have high-powered machines
meant for advanced tanners,
but the remaining rooms are the same.
But Nishitani typically used
standard machines to tan.
That's right. He suddenly asked to start
using the high-powered machines today.
Why didn't you mention that?
Because you didn't ask!
Now, now.
Excuse me.
Do you think we could leave soon?
We need to hit the gym.
But...
The contest's in two weeks.
All we do is go back and forth
between home and the gym.
Very well, but make sure
you're reachable at all times.
Thank you.
Excuse us.
Chiba, you're in charge here.
I'm going to ask around the university
the victim attended.
Got it.
So, kids...
Why exactly did you come with me?
What's the problem?
But...
Are you sure you want us to leave?
Ayumi-chan is logging this incident
in her illustrated diary again.
What? Really?
Yeah, look.
Ayumi's illustrated diary
once helped you solve a case.
Try to be as quiet as possible.
Bodybuilding Club
What?
Nishitani-san is dead?! How?!
Randy Moore (33)
Coach
He was poisoned.
What?!
So I have a few questions for you
since you were his coach.
Very well. Ask me anything.
Do you know if anyone resented Nishitani-san
or if he was involved in any trouble?
No! He was a nice guy.
Everyone loved him.
The idea that anyone hated him is nonsense.
I heard Nishitani-san wasn't
a very high-level bodybuilder.
It's not fair to compare him
to the champion or Nagano-san.
What's so different about them?
Oh, are you detectives as well?
We're the Detective Boys.
Nice to meet you!
What was Nishitani-san and
Nagano-san's relationship like?
Nishitani-san looked up to Nagano-san.
Whenever Nagano-san started a new
training program, he seemed to copy it.
Excuse me, Coach Moore.
What is it?
Just to confirm, it's unlikely anyone
would've tried to kill Nishitani-san
over his bodybuilding capabilities, right?
It's true that some people are willing
to take out the competition to get ahead.
But I'm talking about top-level competitors.
He wasn't at that level yet.
Excuse me.
Hello, Chiba?
What?
Got it. I'll head back right away.
Did something happen?
They found new evidence.
Something really significant.
We received a call saying there was
a huge development in the case.
Who was the culprit?
What was going to happen
to our investigation?
Beika Police Station
MPD Beika Police Station
I told you, it wasn't me!
How many times do I have to tell you that?
So you say,
but given how dark that hallway is,
you're the only one who could have
shown the victim to the poisoned room.
I-I'm being falsely accused. I just...
You were just embezzling
the salon's profits, weren't you?
It's obvious when you compare the salon's
books against your bank account balance.
If anything, I can't believe
it wasn't discovered sooner.
B-But I didn't kill Nishitani-san.
Then how about this?
Th-That's tanning gel, isn't it?
Yes, poisoned tanning gel.
What?
We found it in your bag.
You're lying!
It's true.
But...
That's impossible! I didn't do it!
In any case, I've already reported
your embezzling to division two.
They should be arriving with a warrant soon.
You should confess to
the murder before then.
I guess the case is solved, then.
I'm telling you, I didn't kill anyone.
But he says he didn't do it.
You have to believe me.
But we've got all the evidence.
I guess we didn't need Ayumi's
illustrated diary this time.
It's a little disappointing.
Is it? Isn't this how most cases go?
And so, it seemed as though the
case had been solved all too easily.
But Conan-kun seemed dissatisfied
with how it turned out,
Illustrated Diary
so I'll keep writing in my diary.
Conan-kun reviewed the case.
There's no motive. Why would
someone kill Nishitani-san?
What about the lights in the hallway?
Is there some meaning behind that?
It Tsunoda-san isn't the culprit, then
how did the culprit poison the gel?
Conan-kun.
Ayumi-chan.
Conan-kun, look at this.
Sure.
June 15th.
Today I went shopping
with the Detective Boys.
Come to think of it, you're right.
We were going shopping then.
Tanning Salon Kurosawa
We never got to complete
our shopping trip, though.
Yeah.
Anyway, they were all so muscular.
I know. Not only that,
but they were all so tan.
I'd definitely mix them up if I saw them
standing next to each other from behind.
You'd mix them up?
Huh?
Yeah...
Mix them up...
What's this?
Weren't the body's teeth...?
And those lights...
I see. So that's how it is.
Looks like you figured something out.
Yeah. There's still a lot I need
to confirm, but I'm certain of it.
Thanks, Ayumi-chan.
Your illustrated diary helped me
make a breakthrough.
Sure!
But this case isn't over yet.
Bodybuilding Club
Changing Room
Nagano
I figured you'd show up soon
since the contest is coming up.
It's too bad, though.
Did you really have to do all of this?
Three-time student bodybuilding champion,
Ozawa Masaru-san.
What are you talking about?
I just came here to see Nagano-kun.
With a poisoned bottle?
I-I don't know what you're talking about.
Ozawa-san, being a three-time
champion must be hard.
Huh?
Remember what tanning salon
employee Tsunoda-san said?
Our minds are totally occupied
with last minute checks.
Though I'm sure Ozawa-san
will win, of course.
He made it sound like
you were expected to win.
Ozawa-san is a great athlete,
but I'll win the next contest.
You've got a rival claiming
he'll beat you, too.
You must be under a lot of pressure.
Well, yeah.
So you decided to take your rival out.
That day, you waited in one of
the three advanced tanning rooms
for your target to arrive.
After confirming he arrived, you entered
the two vacant advanced tanning rooms
and swapped out the provided tanning
gel with your own poisoned gel.
You waited for your target to enter a room
and retrieved the poisoned gel
from the vacant room.
While Tsunoda-san was panicking
over finding a dead body,
you slipped the poisoned gel bottle
you retrieved into Tsunoda-san's bag.
W-Wait a minute.
There was no way for me to know when
Nishitani-san would come to the tanning salon.
You couldn't know exactly,
but if you were both regulars,
you could guess approximately
when he'd arrive.
According to the salon's records, you
visited the salon three days in a row.
M-Maybe so, but you're the one who said
you couldn't see people's
faces in that dark hallway.
Besides, I don't have a motive.
Nagano-kun might've made sense, but
there's no reason for me to kill Nishitani-kun,
who still had a long way
to go as a bodybuilder.
That's right.
That was the biggest question.
You don't have a motive
to kill Nishitani-san.
The black lights.
What?
Because of the black lights
illuminating that dark hallway,
you mistook Nishitani-san for
Nagano-san, your actual target.
Hey, Haibara. What's a black light?
It's a kind of light that emits light
that's mostly invisible to humans.
When you shine a black light on
fluorescent objects, it makes them glow.
During the meteor hunter case,
Edogawa-kun instructed us
on how to make a light that
would make fluorescent ink glow.
Oh, right.
Two years ago, Nagano-san replaced most
of his teeth with hybrid ceramic implants.
The resin used in hybrid ceramic implants
sometimes glows under a black light.
So you attempted to identify
Nagano-san by his teeth,
but you didn't know...
Nishitani-san, who looked up to Nagano-san,
recently had most of his own teeth replaced
with hybrid ceramic implants recently.
The big purchase he made was those implants.
So you made a mistake.
You saw Nishitani-san's teeth
glowing in the darkness
and thought he was Nagano-san.
You kids don't get it.
You don't know how hard it is
to have people coming for you.
The fear of being ousted.
It makes you willing to do anything
to stay on top!
Look out!
You're right. I don't understand...
how a killer feels.
And so, the case was solved.
Detectives Takagi and Chiba
arrived to arrest Ozawa-san.
Poirot
Today we had Detective Chiba treat us
since it must be hard on Detective
Takagi's wallet to treat us all the time.
Thanks for waiting. This
is what we're having today.
Special high protein low calorie
chicken, broccoli, and egg whites.
It's a bodybuilder approved muscle-building
meal that's good for losing weight, too.
Muscle-building meal?
Then if we eat this,
will we end up looking like this?
Nice bulk!
Washboard abs!
Episode Preview
Hand over your money!
Hand it over!
Shrine
What happened?!
Someone pushed this man
down the stairs and fled.
What?
The next episode of Conan is "The
Unfortunate and Suspicious Victim!"
The Unfortunate and Suspicious Victim
Daypack
Next Conan's hint.
A daypack!
I have my illustrated diary.
Don't miss the next episode.
I have Holmes.
And I've got the eel bowl case.
Yeah, that never happened.