Doterasu Shrine
Okamoto Jupita (20)
Student
I'm really looking forward to it.
Me, too!
Hand over your money!
Hand it over!
What happened?!
Someone pushed this man
down the stairs and fled.
What?
You guys call an ambulance.
Call the police, too.
Got it.
Beika Central Hospital
My younger brother will be
all right, won't he?
I can't say for certain yet,
but we'll do our best.
Okamoto Juria (26)
Rising Songwriter
Thank you for calling an ambulance.
It's fine. I'm worried about your brother.
They caught the culprit, didn't they?
Yes, but I don't know why my brother
came to Beika City in the first place.
Is there something wrong with that?
When I spoke with Jupita on the phone
just before he was mugged...
JUPITA
I'm in Waiha City right now.
Waiha City and Beika City are
in complete opposite directions.
Right, so why did he lie about
coming here of all places?
Of all places?
Juria-kun.
Oh, Saimon-sensei. Thank you for coming.
Saimon Kotaro (71)
Veteran Songwriter
What's going on?
What was Jupita-kun
doing here of all places?
Him, too?
Why do you two hate Beika City so much?
What? Because...
Beyond detective skills capable
of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
Suspicious actions and
a suspicious phone call.
Despite him being the
victim, the suspicion deepens.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Unfortunate and Suspicious Victim
"The Unfortunate and Suspicious Victim!"
Two people we're connected
to live in this city.
One is my ex I broke up
with despite being engaged,
and the other is our
infuriating pest of an enemy.
Enemy?
Kariba Yuzuru the songwriter.
He's a super successful songwriter
who's written a bunch of hits.
Publicly, yes.
I'm a rising songwriter who's
studying under Saimon Kotaro-sensei.
And Kariba Yuzuru used to be
one of his students, too.
I dismissed him because
he was rotten to the core.
But somehow he became a hit maker,
and was even appointed chairman
of the Japanese Songwriters Association.
Kariba Yuzuru (36)
Songwriters Association Chairman
I won't name names, but the walking
corpse taking up space on the board
despite not writing a hit
in years is shameless.
He's been slandering Saimon-sensei
because he was dismissed.
I can ignore his slander,
but I can't forgive him
for plagiarizing lyrics.
Plagiarizing lyrics?
Despite being accused several times,
he's always gotten away with it.
What's even scarier is there are members
of the association copying his methods.
And that Kariba Yuzuru
lives here in Beika City.
I broke up with my ex Mizutani
Ren-kun because of it, too.
When I learned Kariba was
constructing a home in Beika City,
I told Mizutani-kun...
A nasty pest has taken up
residence in this area.
You need to move immediately.
Mizutani Ren (28)
Juria's Ex-fiance
We'll be moving once we get married anyway.
Why bother moving twice?
It's not about the effort.
It doesn't matter who lives here.
We're both stubborn, so
we ultimately broke up.
And Mizutani-kun still lives
here in Beika City, too.
We understand your
connections to Beika City,
but does your brother Jupita have
any connections to Beika City?
No, absolutely none.
Maybe he came to visit Mizutani Ren.
Since you were engaged, Jupita-san
must have met him too, right?
Well, yes...
Jupita-kun seemed to like Mizutani-kun.
He once let slip to me...
I think they make a good couple.
Do you think it's impossible
for them to get back together?
Why is he discussing that with you?
Why don't you ask Mizutani-san
if Jupita-san came to see him?
Okay.
Hello? It's me.
I've got a strange question to ask,
but did Jupita visit you today?
Of course not.
Why would your brother visit me now?
Right. Sorry. Thanks.
Then why did he come to Beika City?
We'll find out why
Jupita-san came to Beika City.
You can count on us, Juria-san.
The Detective Boys seem
like a dependable bunch.
First, we need clues.
Did Jupita-san have any possessions on him?
The nurse's station has
the clothes he was wearing.
All we know right now is that Jupita-san
came to the shrine for some reason.
Was there any reason
for his visit besides praying?
Nurse's Station
They're a little dirty.
It must've happened when
he was attacked and fell.
There's a receipt inside his pocket.
Seems like he bought something
after coming to Beika City.
Yeah. This is from the general
store near the station.
A young man?
Oh, you mean the man
who purchased a knife earlier.
I believe he put the knife
he bought in a daypack.
Why did he buy a knife?
And where did it go?
He wasn't carrying a daypack.
And the mugger only took his wallet.
Did he drop it during the attack?
It's not here.
Let's ask the people at the shrine.
Yes, this was turned in as a lost item.
This is definitely it.
A knife?
Why would he buy a knife?
We don't know yet.
But this might serve as a clue.
I noticed he didn't have his.
It was in his bag all along.
It might help us figure something out.
Could you show us his call history?
I'm not sure we should do that
without his permission.
It's all right. I'll apologize to him later.
The last number he called is our association.
Huh? His phone is set to
withhold his own number.
History
Unknown
Okamoto Juria
Cell phone
Why would Jupita call the association?
I'll ask them.
Hello, this is Okamoto Juria.
I believe my brother called
you. Do you know why?
I'm not sure if it was your brother,
but we did receive a disturbing
anonymous call from a withheld number.
Kariba Yuzuru will suffer the wrath of god!
Th-Thank you.
If that was Jupita, then
why did he place that call?
He threatened Kariba Yuzuru
with the wrath of god.
Could it be? But...
Was Jupita trying to kill Kariba Yuzuru?
He came to Beika City where
Kariba lives to kill him.
He bought the knife he planned to use,
made a threatening call to the association,
and prayed for success at the shrine.
Is that really what Jupita-san was planning?
What?
If he was, then that means he lied about
being in Waiha City to fabricate an alibi.
You'd be able to speak in his defense
if he was suspected of murder.
But that testimony
wouldn't count for anything,
and it's strange that
he announced his intent.
Withholding his number
wouldn't stop the police
from immediately figuring out
who the caller was.
I appreciate your consideration,
but my brother isn't the brightest.
I can't believe Jupita was plotting a murder.
I'm going to leave this
at the nurse's station.
I'll carry it.
Let's go.
Thank you.
Shall we go, too?
Conan-kun?
I don't get it.
He'll be in the hospital for several days.
We'll need to make sure
he has everything he needs.
You're right.
If that really was his plan, then
his behavior was inconsistent.
Wait a minute. When you
think of it that way...
What are you talking about?
Either way, that's our only clue.
All right.
Conan-kun!
Here we go again.
This bandanna wasn't in his daypack
when we brought it back from the shrine.
If something that wasn't here before
is here now, then... Could it be?
Then that bandanna is...
Yeah. The true culprit took it once but
returned it because they didn't use it.
When you assume that, it explains
the threatening phone call.
You mean the true culprit placed the call?
Probably. But there's too much
we don't know, so we'll split up.
Does Jupita-san cook?
Yes, he seems to enjoy cooking.
What about it?
Kariba
So Kariba-san hasn't been back
since he left this morning.
So that's why.
It would be impossible if he's not here.
What are you talking about?
Oh, what is that?
That wasn't here when
I cleaned the place this morning.
Do you think that metal pipe might be...?
Where was that daypack found?
Behind the main shrine.
But what was it doing there?
The daypack was left around here, right?
Look at these leaves and grass.
Could it be?
They were on Jupita-san's clothes.
Which means this is probably the place.
Yeah.
You're right.
What? Who are you kids?
Jupita-san won't show up
no matter how long you wait.
There's a reason he can't come anymore.
What do you mean?
What are you even talking about?
My brother wasn't plotting
to kill Kariba Yuzuru?
If he were, then his actions
aren't consistent with that.
He withheld his number when
he made the phone threat,
but he allowed the store clerk to see
his face when he bought the knife.
There's another individual, person X,
involved in this incident,
and they were the one actually
plotting Kariba-san's murder.
While thinking of a way
to get away with murder,
they happened to learn Jupita-san
was going to Beika City.
X must have realized then that
they could frame Jupita-san.
Jupita-san loved his sister.
He might do something like that.
In other words, he seemed like the
perfect patsy because he had a motive.
Today, X approached Jupita-san in
disguise as he left the general store,
came up with an excuse to lead
him to that deserted shrine,
drugged him with sleeping pills, and
carried him behind the main shrine.
By hiding Jupita-san from sight,
they denied him an alibi.
Then X took Jupita-san's bandanna
so they could leave it at the scene
of Kariba-san's murder and frame him.
Furthermore...
This is the Songwriters Association.
Kariba Yuzuru will suffer the wrath of god!
They left the phone threat
in Jupita-san's call history.
Then X took a metal pipe and
headed to Kariba-san's home,
but when learned he was out,
they hid in his yard
so they could attack him when he came home.
Then Jupita was set up by X?
But perhaps the sleeping pills
were ineffective,
as Jupita-san eventually woke up.
What am I doing sleeping back here?
When he saw the shrine, he must have prayed.
Realizing his daypack was missing,
he returned to the shrine
and was unfortunately
attacked by the mugger.
Meanwhile, X, who was still waiting for
Kariba-san, couldn't carry out the murder
because they received a call saying Jupita-san
had been taken away in an ambulance.
My brother was attacked by a mugger
and was taken away in an ambulance.
Because Jupita-san was transported
by ambulance, he had a perfect alibi.
So X gave up on framing him for Kariba-san's
murder and rushed to the hospital.
Could it be?
Yes. Saimon-san is X.
But despite not carrying out his plan,
he left behind evidence of his scheme.
The phone threat in
Jupita-san's call history.
He failed to erase that,
so he at least returned the physical evidence
that was the bandanna to the daypack.
The only person who had
the opportunity to do that
was Saimon-san, who took
the daypack to the nurse's station.
You mean then?
I'll take this. You go on ahead.
Okay.
I can't believe you were willing to
frame Jupita to kill Kariba Yuzuru.
I would've done anything to
stop the evil he was spreading.
As his former teacher, it's my duty.
And Jupita-kun had to do
something useful for once.
The reason you're not hugely
successful despite your talent
is because of your superficial
and irresponsible brother.
Irresponsible?
You're awfully biased.
But I couldn't even frame him.
I should've found another patsy.
What? Say that again.
It's from the association.
Apparently, Chairman Kariba was
called in by the police this morning.
Association Office
He was arrested for tax evasion.
They're going to thoroughly reexamine
the accusations of plagiarism, too.
He's not getting away with it this time.
I wanted to let you know right away.
He's evil.
But now I don't have to kill him.
But you need to turn yourself in
and atone for what you've done.
Turn myself in?
You drugged Jupita-san, placed a
disturbing call to the association,
and stole a metal pipe.
None of those are forgivable actions.
That's right.
Could it be?
Did you already solve it?
Yeah, mostly.
Did you figure out why Jupita-san
came to Beika City, too?
He's explaining that now.
You figured that out, too?
Jupita-san lied because he
couldn't tell you the truth.
After all, he was going to visit your ex
who you'd broken up with after an argument.
What? But Mizutani-kun said...
When Jupita-kun called me two days ago,
he asked me not to tell his sister.
I had to play dumb.
But why would Jupita visit you?
He didn't buy a knife to use as a weapon.
He was planning to cook with it.
Yeah. He said he came up with
a tasty recipe and wanted me to try it.
He must've bought one because I told him
I didn't have a decent knife at home.
But why would he ask you to try his cooking?
It was probably just an excuse to visit him.
Maybe he actually wanted to ask
Mizutani-san to get back together with you.
After all, Jupita-san said
you make a good couple.
That's why Jupita-san prayed.
Please let things between my
sister and Mizutani-san work out.
It's all speculation, though.
Jupita-san probably genuinely
wished for Juria-san's happiness.
He's not irresponsible at all.
I made so many mistakes.
I should turn myself in.
Please apologize to Jupita-kun for me.
I'm sorry to you, too.
I'll make you something tasty.
Okay, we'll be waiting.
I want an eel bowl!
I can't do that, but I'll still
make something tasty.
Okay!
Episode Preview
Plums, huh?
Conan-kun, don't they call
people like you arrogant?
Don't turn your back on the elderly!
I'll have the same omurice you're having.
It's showtime!
A long-haired high school girl in overalls?
Welcome to special kid's lunch hell.
The Genius Restaurant
The next episode of Conan
is "The Genius Restaurant!"
Next Conan's hint!
Flag
A flag!
Next time we're having kid's lunches.
Don't miss the next episode.
Hooray!
Sounds like a whole lot of trouble.