Celebration
Candy Shop
Put out your hands.
Here you go. For you.
You, too. Here you go.
Plums, huh?
Jurakudai Grand Opening
They must've given us these to
celebrate the opening of the candy shop.
I've never had anything like this before.
Me neither.
Sour!
Jurakudai Grand Opening
So good!
Yummy!
It's delicious!
These are addicting!
Yeah!
They're actually not too sour.
Yeah.
Beyond detective skills capable
of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
The world's greatest kid's
lunch is a dangerous dish!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Genius Restaurant
"The Genius Restaurant!"
You're not going to eat yours?
I'm not into candy.
Conan, are you looking down on candy?
It's not that I'm looking down on it.
It's just that candy is for kids.
Don't pretend you're all grown up!
Jurakudai Grand Opening
Conan-kun, don't they call
people like you arrogant?
What? I'm not being arrogant.
No, you're totally being arrogant.
Celebration
Grand Opening
Genta-kun.
Conan-kun.
I'm leaving.
Why'd they get so worked up
over some candy? It's exhausting.
I'm sorry.
Are you all right? Here.
I saw something.
I saw a corpse.
An omurice corpse.
An omurice corpse?
This guy seems exhausting, too.
Don't turn your back on the elderly!
Let go of me!
This way.
This is the place.
Where's the omurice corpse?
Here.
It's gone?
It's gone? It's gone?
I know.
You ate it, didn't you?
What? What's wrong with this old man?
Don't turn your back on the elderly!
Wait!
What's this doing here?
Jurakudai
I've been to this restaurant before.
Welcome
Jurakudai
The restaurant's name is
Jurakudai. Three months ago...
This is the restaurant.
It serves western food.
Meal Tickets
Menu
This aquarium serves
as the restaurant's menu.
Huh.
Meal Tickets
Be careful when using fire
That's the chef-owner.
Jurakudai
Chef-owner
The genius chef Jurakudai-san.
His name is the same as the restaurant's?
That's right. He's internationally famous.
Jurakudai-san's special kid's lunch
is a world-class five-star dish.
Be careful when using fire
His kid's lunch?
That's his special kid's lunch.
Looks like we have to buy meal tickets.
Meal Tickets
I'm going to have the omurice.
Conan-kun, you'll have
the special kid's lunch, right?
I'd rather have something else.
It's no ordinary kid's lunch.
It's a special kid's lunch
made by the genius Jurakudai.
No matter how special it is, a kid's
lunch is still just a kid's lunch.
Conan-kun, sometimes you
say such grown-up things.
I know you're a smart kid,
but if someone who doesn't know
you well heard you say that...
Arrogant.
Yeah, they'd think you're arrogant.
That's the same thing Mitsuhiko
and Genta said earlier.
Jurakudai Grand Opening
Don't they call people like you arrogant?
What? I'm not being arrogant.
No, you're totally being arrogant.
The same thing happened then.
I'm not arrogant!
You can't seriously expect me to
eat a kid's lunch in front of you.
Sorry, sorry.
It's fine.
I'll have the same omurice you're having.
So you're not going to have
the special kid's lunch?
No.
Mixed Fried Platter
Hamburg Steak
Tonkatsu
Special Kid's Lunch
Napolitan
Gratin
These must be the ticket vending machines.
Steak
Curry Rice
Hayashi Rice
Where's the omurice ticket machine?
Omurice
Here it is.
0 people
How many?
We want two, so...
Omurice II
It's showtime!
Where should we sit?
How about over there?
This parachute turns into a bib.
The restaurant seemed so fun.
How did this happen?
That's...
Did genius kid's lunch chef
Jurakudai-san take that?
But what's it doing here?
Could it be that Jurakudai-san was angry
I wouldn't eat his special kid's lunch?
Which means the kid's lunch
flag stuck in my omurice...
And the staff's violin performance...
Come to think of it, those
staff members looked similar.
Is it possible
that what you saw inside the omurice was...
...me?
Then was it a long-haired high
school girl wearing overalls?
What?
This mysterious and exhausting
old man is actually...
Genius kid's lunch chef Jurakudai.
I see. He used his restaurant staff.
Jurakudai Grand Opening
He opened a candy shop
and had them lead us there.
Put out your hands.
They handed out some candy...
Don't pretend you're all grown up!
You're totally being arrogant.
...and made us get into a fight.
In the meantime,
Jurakudai the genius kid's lunch chef
disguised himself as a mysterious
and exhausting old man.
He claimed to have seen
an omurice corpse that didn't exist.
Don't turn your back on the elderly!
Then he took me to this back alley
and showed me his shut down restaurant.
Jurakudai
Are you saying it was my fault
the restaurant shut down?
Child, your arrogance shattered my
pride as a genius kid's lunch chef.
I heard what you said.
It's no ordinary kid's lunch.
It's a special kid's lunch
made by the genius Jurakudai.
No matter how special it is, a kid's
lunch is still just a kid's lunch.
I'll have the same omurice you're having.
You're not going to have
the special kid's lunch?
No.
My rage wouldn't subside.
Thanks for the food.
After that, my shattered pride
began to affect my cooking slightly.
The quality dropped slightly, and my
booming restaurant began failing slightly.
Both my restaurant and I crumbled.
I'm not letting an arrogant
child like you off the hook!
I'll teach you a lesson!
Welcome to special kid's lunch hell.
You're not going to have
the special kid's lunch?
I never thought the costume I made
for the third anniversary festival
of my creative special kid's lunch
would come in use now.
Special Kid's Lunch!
Third Anniversary
Festival
Menu
Wow, I wish I could've caught
a special kid's lunch, too.
Catch that kid.
Catch that kid!
Child, today's special kid's lunch
comes with free cream soda.
And it's extra spicy for you.
What's that?
Damn it.
Crap!
Damn you, child.
Help!
"The next time I'm here, I promise I'll order the special kid's lunch."
"A genius always becomes too proud. And pride comes before the fall."
Candy Shop
Conan-kun sure is taking his time.
Celebration
What is he doing?
Hey!
Conan-kun.
Conan.
I'd like one plum, please.
Anyway, that was a weird dream.
It's good.
Hey, wanna get special kid's
lunches together sometime?
Yeah!
Yes!
Episode Preview
White clothes...
The man dead at the top of the stairs
is Yuki Hideto-san, 34 years old.
He helped found the company
and was my dearest friend.
In other words, today is the day she died.
I see. Does that mean...?
The next episode of Conan is "The Culprit
Who Disappeared Into the Sleeping Town!"
The Culprit Who Disappeared Into the Sleeping Town
Bouquet
Next Conan's hint!
A bouquet!
We'd like kid's lunches, please.
Don't miss the next episode.
Actually, could I get an eel bowl?
Seriously?