Ouch...
Wow, look at the time.
I'm glad we found the lost cat, though.
It's thanks to you, Conan-kun.
Stop! Murderer!
It came from over there.
He's still alive!
Ran, call an ambulance!
Got it.
Nezu Goro (52)
Security Guard
Hang in there!
A security guard was stabbed.
His life is in danger.
I'm at a business district in Haido City.
Hideto? Don't die!
Ran-neechan, there's someone
at the top of the stairs, too.
Get here as quickly as you can.
Who did this to you?
Wh-White clothes...
Damn it.
I'm too late.
What's going on?
Beyond detective skills capable
of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
Missing footprints and invisible traces!
Pursue the culprit lost in the darkness!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Culprit Who Disappeared Into the Sleeping Town
"The Culprit Who Disappeared
Into the Sleeping Town!"
The man dead at the top of the stairs
is Yuki Hideto-san, 34 years old.
Yuki Hideto (34)
IT Company President
He was stabbed in the chest.
Yuki Hideto? As in the Yuki Hideto?
Yes. He was the gifted
president of an IT company.
He was frequently criticized by the media
for his aggressive business practices.
He had a lot of enemies.
So that's his company's building, huh?
It's right next to the murder scene.
We believed he was attacked
as he was exiting the building.
Someone left flowers already?
They were already there before the murder.
We don't think they're related to the case.
The blood stains end abruptly.
The victim's blood must
have gotten on the culprit.
A considerable amount, too.
Did she discover the body?
She's Yuki's wife and
his company's number two.
Yuki Keiko (34)
Yuki Hideto's Wife
Her name is Yuki Keiko-san.
She was clinging to her husband's body.
By the time we saw them,
they were already like that.
We'll wait to question her until later.
"White clothes," huh?
A stun gun?
Yuki carried one for self defense.
Judging by the voltage, there must be
a stun gun burn on the culprit's body.
Security guard Nezu-san arrived at the scene
and got into a tussle with the culprit.
These flat ones belong to the culprit,
and these patterned ones are Nezu-san's.
Despite his injuries, Nezu-san
desperately pursued the culprit.
But during his pursuit, he was
stabbed in the stomach.
Based on the shape of their injuries,
we believe the same knife
was used to stab both men.
There are a lot of cuts concentrated here.
He must've fought with the culprit here.
How awful.
The culprit's footprints end at
the entrance to the main avenue.
It's possible he changed shoes
or fled in a vehicle.
We're currently searching the area,
but we've found no signs of the culprit
fleeing, much less witnesses.
Business districts are
practically deserted at night.
Which is why the culprit would've stood out,
seeing as they were covered in blood.
But if there's no sign of them, then...
He's right. It doesn't make sense.
Or maybe they're right here,
feigning innocence.
I was talking to my husband in a
third-floor meeting room until a moment ago.
After that, I stayed behind to work,
and heard the alarm whistle.
Stop! Murderer!
Did you see the culprit?
Does that mean the culprit returned
after leaving the scene once?
So you didn't realize your husband had been
attacked before you heard the whistle?
I was in the room in the very back.
It's true that people hated my husband.
But he was actually a
sensitive person, and I truly...
But only you wore a wedding ring.
Now that you mention it, you're right.
So, what?
Perhaps you were unhappy
with your husband as well.
That's right. My husband
was asking for a divorce.
He also said he'd sell the company.
We'd finally made it this far together, too.
Keiko-san didn't do it.
If it'd been her, Nezu-san
would've pointed up the stairs,
instead of towards the main avenue.
Besides, she's wearing heels.
The culprit's footprints
look nothing like hers.
Impressive work, Detective.
I get that a lot.
The old man's right, but...
Which means the prime suspect is...
Ichinose Kaoru (25)
Hideto's Secretary
You think I killed the president? Why?
My husband told you off all the time, and
I sometimes saw you glaring daggers at him.
Oh, please. This is a misunderstanding.
You weren't working today, were you?
What were you doing here?
I just happened to pass by.
Wh-What is it?
You smell like coffee and cigarettes.
You were at the smoking area
across the street, weren't you?
You must've been there for quite a while.
I like having a smoke there.
The other buildings would've blocked
his view of Yuki-san's building.
It's a strange place to wait for him, but...
You're the only one who was on
the avenue Nezu-san pointed at.
Didn't the culprit flee that way?
Then you must've seen them
running down the avenue.
I just didn't notice.
But Nezu-san said white clothes.
Takagi-kun, get forensics over here.
Yes, sir.
Excuse me.
I'm not seeing anything.
No bloodstains, huh?
See?
Huh? These clothes are reversible.
What?
Ichinose-san.
I see. So it's a black
and white reversible vest.
There's a stain on the white side.
We'll find something this time.
What?
There's nothing there.
Then what's that stain?
It's coffee.
My shoes are totally different
from the culprit's anyway. See?
You're right.
Is this...?
Thanks, kid.
In that case, go ahead
and search my entire body.
There's a stun gun burn
on the culprit's body, right?
Search me, too.
Then I'll search Keiko-san.
Dad!
Good grief. They're both innocent.
Does that mean there was
someone else at the crime scene?
A culprit X we haven't been able to spot?
Then how did they disappear?
Let's begin our search for X.
Yes, sir!
But why did the culprit attack
Yuki-san in front of a security guard?
Why can't you just keep your mouth shut?
Wasn't the security guard over there?
True. Why didn't he wait until
he was alone to attack him?
That would be more certain and less risky.
Was Yuki-san really the culprit's only target?
Could it be?
I'll look into it immediately.
I found that four years ago, Yuki's company
was suspected of unlawful conduct.
There was a woman who
assumed all responsibility
and killed herself by
jumping off this building.
That was Sachi. Shirai Sachi.
She helped found the company
and was my dearest friend.
Then those flowers...
I put them there.
I didn't know about that.
It was before you joined the company.
The suspicions ended with her death.
Foul play was suspected at the time,
but a security guard testified that
Sachi-san threw herself from the building,
and the case was determined to be a suicide.
And that security guard was...
It was Nezu-san, right?
Yes.
After that, Nezu began paying off
the debt he'd accumulated.
If Yuki-san bribed him into
giving false testimony, then...
Nezu-san was a target from the start?
Not only that, but Sachi-san
died four years ago today.
In other words, today's
the anniversary of her death.
Were these murders revenge against
the two men involved in Sachi-san's death?
Ran-neechan.
What is it?
An image I found on SNS.
Is that Sachi-san?
It's still online.
Christmas With Sachi
She looks so happy.
Huh? Is this...?
I'm going to tell Inspector Megure.
No, it's not enough.
We still don't know anything.
What's this?
Oh, it's over here.
Huh?
Is this... blood spray?
It's pretty far from the body.
What's this doing here?
These footprints...
I see. Does that mean...?
Hey, kid.
I get it now.
What's the meaning of this, Ichinose-san?
It's true that I was Sachi's boyfriend.
Then you joined our company...
To determine the truth.
But I didn't kill anyone.
You can't expect us to believe—
You already know that, don't you?
We proved that earlier.
W-Well, yeah.
But why did you bring that pen?
It's a recording device, right?
What?
And it wasn't a coincidence
that you came here.
The president asked me to come here tonight.
He said he had something
to tell me about Sachi.
What? Did my husband know who you were?
I think he figured it out,
which is why I brought this.
If anything happened to you, the audio
you recorded would serve as evidence.
Yes. We were supposed to
meet at the smoking area,
but he never showed up, so
I headed towards the office building.
But there were already
bloody footprints there.
Stop! Murderer!
There wasn't time to clear
up the misunderstanding,
and I was focused on running,
so I don't if someone stabbed
Nezu-san behind me.
By the time I turned around,
he was already on the ground.
You already know the rest.
So you turned your clothes inside out
and pretended you happened to pass by?
I was afraid of being framed, so...
My husband probably wanted to tell
you he planned to turn himself in.
What?
Selling his company and filing for divorce.
Everything Yuki was doing sounds
like putting his affairs in order.
Keiko-san, the meeting
you had with him tonight...
Yes. My husband told me
everything for the first time
about the unlawful activity, about
Sachi, and about turning himself in.
He was always like that.
When it came to this kind of thing, he
always tried to do everything himself.
Which means he never trusted me.
Are you sure about that?
What?
Couldn't you think of it this way?
He didn't want to drag you into this mess.
Did Keiko-san kill him to stop him
from turning himself in?
I don't think so.
We disproved that earlier, too.
Then who's the culprit?
It must be a third party, the true culprit X.
The culprit... culprit is...
No, there's one more person.
Someone with motive to kill Yuki-san
for trying to turn himself in
who's never run or hidden
from us from the start.
You mean...?
Indeed I do. The true culprit is
Nezu-san, the dead security guard.
What?
It's true that Nezu-san's false testimony
would be exposed if Yuki turned himself in.
He'd be fired from his job.
And at his age, with a criminal record,
he'd never find another job.
That sounds like motive to me.
But wasn't he killed?
Nobody saw who killed him.
Not Keiko-san. Not even Ichinose-san,
who was only a short distance away.
It doesn't make sense.
He fought with the culprit,
who was armed with a knife,
but Nezu-san's nightstick
was still on his hip.
But there were two sets of footprints.
Even if he used a second pair to
make them, where did the shoes go?
It's a simple trick.
The bottoms of Nezu-san's
shoes had two surfaces.
Takagi-kun.
What we saw was the rubber sole
mask he attached to his shoes.
If you remove them...
their unsettling flat face is revealed.
Nezu-san's plan was probably as follows:
First, he'd stab Yuki-san to death
when he exited the building.
Next he'd use his flat soles
to create footprints left by X
leading to the main avenue.
Then he'd glue the soles he brought
to his shoes and climb up the stairs,
step in the blood, and this
time create his own footprints.
Then he'd have made two sets of footprints.
Next he'd cut the front
of his body using a knife
to imitate defensive wounds.
Finally, he'd perform chest
compressions on Yuki-san
to hide the blood that had gotten on him.
He'd blow his alarm whistle so Keiko-san
would witness what happened.
The non-existent X would be framed,
he'd be a heroic victim
who suffered injuries,
and Nezu-san would have
pulled off the perfect crime.
But nothing ever goes according to plan.
When he stabbed Yuki-san, he was
met with unexpected resistance.
The stun gun!
At this rate, it would be clear
that Nezu-san killed him.
While creating the fake
footprints, his mind raced.
He realized the best place
to hide a leaf is in a forest,
so the best way to hide a burn
was with another injury.
Then those wounds were...
Defensive wounds should be
on the front of the body.
It's hard to believe he'd suffer
multiple injuries like that.
Nezu-san inflicted them on himself
to hide the burn from the stun gun.
Once he was finished, while performing
chest compressions to hide the evidence...
I showed up.
Nezu-san must have been
surprised, as well as confused.
He thought you'd seen everything.
Stop! Murderer!
Because I was too far away,
I couldn't see what he was holding.
And I turned around and ran.
If he wanted to apprehend you,
he would've drawn his nightstick.
Nezu-san intended to stab you to death
and make it look like self-defense.
But Nezu-san had cuts all over his side.
He was also panicked by
the unexpected development.
And the soles of his shoes
felt different from before.
When he raced down the stairs at full
speed under those circumstances...
In other words, it was an accident.
It's the only conceivable explanation.
Then Nezu-san was pointing at...
Until the very end, he was still
trying to frame Ichinose-san or X.
He didn't think he would die.
But that's just conjecture.
That's not enough.
But there is evidence.
How did Nezu-san hide the stun gun burn?
It would be difficult to
see a burn on his side.
He needed a mirror.
Kid.
Here.
Right here.
Is this blood?
There's blood and footprints
on the ground, too.
There's no other reason
for these things to be here.
Call forensics over right away.
Yes, sir.
Dad, you ate my kinako mochi, didn't you?
I-I'm sure I'm being framed by X.
That's impossible!
Just look at all this evidence!
Crap. I should turn myself in soon, too.
Episode Preview
Is something wrong?
Yeah. Don't you think
that guy's acting weird?
He's not looking at any clothes.
We saw someone like that, too.
He kept looking at the walls
instead of the paintings.
I might've seen someone acting strange, too.
He was mumbling to himself
while pushing a stroller.
I see. So that's how it is.
Girls Day Mystery
The next episode of Conan
is the "Girls Day Mystery!"
Hairstyle
Next Conan's hint!
Hairstyle!
Don't miss the next episode.
He's the true culprit!
You too, Conan-kun?
I'll go buy some kinako mochi.