Now Open
World Mask Exhibition
From non-woven fabric masks
to gas masks
Until 7/23
Located on 6F
Harry Murzabayev
Diamond Collection
Starting 8/1
Wow!
Bei
The Beika Department Store
never fails to impress.
Unlike other department stores,
it's crowded with people.
Yeah.
By the way, where's the kid today?
I invited him, but he said
he's meeting the professor.
Hey, Professor!
It's starting!
Thank you.
I'll be right there.
Should you be eating pizza?
You know what they say.
"When the cat's away, the mice will play."
Episode 1
Oh, yeah?
Then us two girls should enjoy
today to our hearts' content.
Yeah.
Department stores are awesome.
Wait. Huh?
Is something the matter?
Look over there!
Ayumi-chan! Ai-chan!
Ran-oneesan and Sonoko-oneesan.
Hello.
What are you two doing?
Yoshida-san said she wanted to check
our clothes for her piano recital.
I'm here as her guardian and advisor.
Look at that.
Beyond detective skills capable
of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
The girls get together,
but there's trouble brewing!
Unlike desserts and candies,
there's nothing sweet about it!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Girls Day Mystery
"Girls Day Mystery!"
Beika Department Store Restaurant
Anyway, what a coincidence.
Summer Afternoon
Tea Available Now
I know. We rarely run into
each other unless there's a case.
Detective Sato, what are you doing
at the Beika Department Store?
I'm obviously here to get limited edition
pear sweets from Tadano Fruits Parlor.
Detective Sato, you like cakes?
Not really, but when I saw them
featured on a morning TV show,
I got the urge to try them.
I know what you mean!
Don't food reports make your stomach growl?
And the harder a place is to visit,
the hungrier it makes you.
Exactly.
In other words, everyone loves tasty foods.
That's right.
Wow, so Inspector Megure has a playful side.
Funny, right?
Speaking of funny, we saw
someone weird earlier.
Someone weird?
Yeah. While we were checking out
clothes on the third floor...
Excuse me.
No, excuse me.
Is something wrong?
Yeah. Don't you think
that guy's acting weird?
Weird how?
He's not looking at any clothes.
Hey, you're right.
He's looking at the ceiling
while mumbling to himself.
I wonder what he's doing.
Maybe he was checking the AC.
We saw someone like that, too.
Right, Ai-chan?
Yes.
We saw him at the art gallery by the
children's clothing section on the sixth floor.
Art Gallery
Huh?
What is it?
Children's Clothes
Don't you think that guy's acting weird?
He keeps looking at the walls
instead of the paintings.
You're right. That is weird.
He's muttering, too.
Maybe he's really into walls.
Well, there's no accounting for taste.
There's nothing wrong with liking walls.
You're right.
A wall fanatic, huh?
Now that I think of it,
there was that guy, too.
Oh, the guy on the roof.
The roof?
Yes.
Just before we ran into each other,
there was a man looking up the sky
and mumbling to himself.
There's another weird guy over there.
Another one?
Look. It's like he's measuring the direction
of the wind while muttering to himself.
I might've seen someone acting strange, too.
You, too?
Yes.
I saw him while getting in line
for the limited edition sweets.
He was mumbling to himself
while pushing a stroller.
But that alone doesn't sound strange.
I know, but when I got a closer look,
I noticed the stroller was empty.
Yikes.
C-Coincidences sure can be unsettling, huh?
Is it really a coincidence?
What do you mean?
One or two might be a coincidence,
but we've seen four people muttering
to themselves while looking around.
Do you really think that's a coincidence?
Maybe their muttering was them
communicating with each other over the radio.
They could be casing the place.
What? That man wasn't a
wall fanatic, but a thief?!
Yeah, right.
M-Maybe those thieves' target is this.
Starting 8/1
at Beika Department Store 6th Floor
"Harry Murzabayev Design Diamond
Collection Special Exhibition."
Apparently they're displaying diamonds
over 100 carats not for sale in stores.
Seriously?
Isn't that exhibition on the 6th floor,
where Ai-chan and Ayumi-chan saw
the weird man at the art gallery?
This must be their target, then.
We can't say for certain
that it's not a coinci—
In any case, let's conduct
a proper investigation first.
If this really is just a coincidence,
then we can laugh about it later.
Yeah.
Really?
What are you doing?
I thought I'd let Shinichi know.
We should call Conan-kun, too.
What? Uh, sure.
Yoshida Ayumi
Incoming Call
Mori Ran
Miss, are you all right? Miss!
He's not answering.
Conan-kun's not answering either.
Why don't you send them a message instead?
Good idea.
Now Open
World Mask Exhibition
From non-woven fabric masks
to gas masks
Located on 6F
Harry Murzabayev
Diamond Collection
Starting 8/1
I see.
Well...
There certainly are several valuable
diamonds in the Murzabayev Collection.
Takahashi Kazuo (28)
Security Guard
It'd make sense if someone
were trying to steal them.
There's a mask exhibition on right now,
but after this, this entire floor will be
filled with Murzabayev diamonds.
Let's check the security camera footage.
Okay.
Detective?
Has something caught your attention?
No, it's nothing.
You're certain it was these four?
Yes.
That's definitely them.
That guy's the wall fanatic.
These men...
We shouldn't judge customers by their
appearances, but they do look suspicious.
How's security here?
During business hours, there are 40
guards on duty watching every floor.
After business hours, the exits are locked,
and only the service entrance remains open.
It goes without saying that every
visitor is checked thoroughly.
The six guards on duty keep an eye
on the monitors at all times.
Once every three hours,
they patrol the building.
Furthermore, during the Murzabayev exhibition,
we plan to double the number of guards.
Are these all the security camera feeds?
Yes. There are no blind spots.
We won't miss a thing.
If the sensors installed on every
door detect anything unusual,
backup is called right away.
Where is the security footage stored?
On the cloud.
Even if this room is attacked, the data
isn't here, so there's nothing to worry about.
What about the roof?
The roof is locked, too.
That man seemed to be measuring
the wind direction on the roof.
It was around here.
Does he mean to fly here from that building?
It's not like he's Kid-sama.
Understood. I'll tighten
security on the roof, too,
and send images of the men to all personnel.
Thank you.
Hey, that's him.
It's the suspicious man Detective Sato saw.
That's not all.
The rest of them are here, too.
What should we do?
Let's arrest them.
We can't.
They're certainly suspicious, but
they haven't done anything yet.
You're kidding, right?
Are we really going to let them go?
We can question them, but that's it.
Should we follow them?
How? We don't have a car.
We really can't do anything even though
those suspicious men are right in front of us?
I know.
I've got a good idea.
I see. So that's how it is.
Did you figure something out, Shinichi?
Yeah. Both the culprit
and the trick they used.
All of it.
But episode five just ended.
Next Time, Episode 6
There are still five more episodes.
Hey, that's him.
It's the suspicious man Detective Sato saw.
That's not all.
The rest of them are here, too.
What should we do?
Let's arrest them.
We can't.
They're certainly suspicious, but
they haven't done anything yet.
You're kidding, right?
Are we really going to let them go?
We can question them, but that's it.
Should we follow them?
How? We don't have a car.
We really can't do anything even though
those suspicious men are right in front us?
I know.
I've got a good idea.
Karaoke Torigami
A rehearsal?
That's right.
What does that mean, Ayumi-chan?
Well, we'll imagine how we think
those men will rob the exhibition,
and tell the department store man
what we come up with.
I see. If we know what
they'll do beforehand,
then it's easier to come up
with countermeasures.
It's a good way to review the case, too.
Either way, I'm surprised karaoke shops
rent out white boards these days.
Apparently, they rent their rooms out
for meetings on weekday afternoons
and when they have fewer customers.
Huh...
Okay, everyone. Try to remember
everything you can about those men.
I'll write it out on the white board.
Since that man was looking at
the ceiling while muttering...
Oh, right. Security cameras.
I see. If he was checking
for security cameras,
it's likely they were scoping out
the security systems, too.
There was a man looking at the walls.
Looking at walls.
The head of security said there were
sensors installed on every door.
Man looking at ceiling
I see. Maybe they intend to avoid the sensors
by breaking in through the wall.
There was a man measuring
the wind direction on the roof.
Then we should assume they'll
try to sneak in from above.
Since all four of them left in a car, maybe
they plan to make their getaway in a car?
You're right.
Man looking at ceiling
Man looking at walls
Man measuring wind
direction on roof
Man pushing stroller
Which means the man pushing the stroller
was checking out local traffic conditions.
They all had a nasty look in their eyes.
They were wearing flashy clothes!
They had weird hairstyles!
They had weird stickers on their car!
What?
Also, he said all the security camera
footage was stored on the cloud.
Yes, that's what he said.
In other words, the building is secure,
but it's connected to the outside
through the internet.
I see.
In other words, it's possible to sneak in
through that connection and hack the system.
How does a grade school kid know that?
It's common sense.
Man looking at ceiling → might be checking security cameras
Man looking at walls → might break in through a wall
Man measuring wind direction on roof → sneak in from above?
Man pushing stroller → checking traffic conditions for getaway?
Scary expressions  Flashy clothes
Unique hairstyles  Weird stickers on car
That should do it.
Then let's rehearse.
We'll pretend we're those thieves
and let our imaginations run wild.
Okay.
Fine.
Let the rehearsal begin.
The thieves attempt to enter from the skies.
First they hack into the security
system and turn off the alarm.
They incapacitate the guards.
They avoid the sensors on the doors,
destroy a wall, and enter the building.
They acquire the diamonds
as quickly as possible and flee.
And the jewel heist was a huge success.
W-We actually succeeded.
Now we need to come up
with a way to stop that.
If they mean to enter from the skies,
couldn't security guards be posted on the roof?
That's it. We'll stop their
scheme before it starts.
Either way, that diamond is amazing.
It'd be hard to play the piano wearing that.
Special Exhibition
A large diamond...
That's it.
What is it, Ai-chan?
What do the thieves intend to do
with the diamonds they steal?
What?
Sell them for money, right?
But wouldn't it be easy to track them down
if they tried to sell such famous diamonds?
I see. That said, if they got them
re-polished so they're harder to track,
it would reduce their value significantly.
Right. And remember what
the head of security said earlier?
Furthermore, during the Murzabayev exhibition,
we plan to double the number of guards.
In other words, checking current
security conditions is pointless.
Which means they're after
what's on display now.
But...
The current exhibition is
the World Mask Exhibition.
Masks?
Scary expressions
Unique hairstyles
I see. So that's how it is.
What is it?
Did you figure something out?
Yes. I know what they're after.
They're the culprit.
What? Really, Shinichi?
Yeah. I'm sure of it.
B-But that's not who you said it was earlier...
Hold it right there.
All three of you are
under arrest for burglary.
Your friend downstairs in the getaway
car is being arrested now, too.
B-But how?
We saw you guys casing
the store this afternoon.
Yeah, but how'd you know
we'd be coming tonight?
Because you're after the pro
wrestling mask on display
at the World Mask Exhibition
that ends tomorrow.
Once the exhibition ends, you'll
lose your chance to steal it.
That mask is a masterpiece made by
the famous Mexican mask-maker Morela.
Legendary Mexican pro wrestling champion
El Desto wore that mask in his title match.
It's priceless.
But how'd you know we were after that?
Because of your hair.
All four of you have your hair
styled like pro wrestlers.
We knew right away that
you like pro wrestling.
I actually thought it was
a bit of a stretch.
That said, when it's all four of you,
it can't be overlooked.
And besides...
There were stickers on the car you got into
after you finished casing the building.
"Beware of Bears" and "I Love Caras".
"Caras" refers not to karasu, or crows,
but the Spanish word for face.
Face
Mask
In other words, the masks
worn by pro wrestlers.
The only thing pro wrestling mask
fans would be after is Morela's mask.
Now give yourselves up and come quietly.
We did it!
The Five Detective Girls have won!
A later investigation revealed
they were the Masked Leotards crime group
that had been causing a sensation.
Danny's Restaurant
Now then.
A toast to us for stopping the mask theft
on our own before it happened.
Cheers!
Anyway, I'm amazed we prevented a
crime without Shinichi or my dad's help.
Conan-kun wasn't here either.
You're right.
Either way, Ai-chan, I was
impressed by your insight.
It was just a coincidence.
Are you sure about that?
Should the five of us get together again?
Great idea. That sounds awesome.
What if there's another case?
Then we'll solve that one, too.
Danny's Restaurant
Don't underestimate a detective.
Shinichi, the culprit in this drama
isn't who you said it was.
What?
Episode Preview
Another stakeout?
Wh-What are you doing here?
We saw a window with open blinds.
So, what's the case about?
Someone exited the building.
Oh, no.
Stakeout 2
The next episode of Conan is "Stakeout 2!"
Cake
Next Conan's hint.
Cake!
Next time let's go to a cake buffet.
Don't miss the next episode.
I'm in!
I pray that nothing happens.