You think Fujiki Kazuma will show up?
Yeah.
I'm sure he'll show up at
Yoda Satomi-san's place.
Yoda Satomi (25)
Office Worker
Another stakeout?
Wh-What are you doing here?
We saw a window with open blinds.
How did you know it was a stakeout?
Call it a hunch.
We're in the same business, after all.
Same business?
Is this him?
What?
They're looking for this guy.
You can't just take that.
Aww...
Which building are you watching?
Stop that.
Aw, man.
So, what's the case about?
We can't have them wandering around.
If we want them to leave,
we'll have to make them realize
there's nothing for them to do.
Someone was injured during
a robbery this morning.
Beyond detective skills capable
of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
The Detective Boys show up at a stakeout!
Will they work together
to arrest the culprit?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Stakeout 2
"Stakeout 2!"
Not much was taken, but...
The victim was a middle-aged man.
He was knocked unconscious when struck
on the head with a rod-like object.
We immediately determined the culprit was
Fujiki Kazuma, 25 years old, unemployed.
But he hadn't returned home, and we
couldn't determine where he had fled to.
BAR Fukunishi
That's when we got some useful information.
Fujiki is a self-centered guy.
No matter who he dates, they
always get sick of him eventually.
But...
Yoda Satomi...
She was probably the best woman for me.
She loved me so much,
she bawled when I left her.
I see.
Fujiki Kazuma (25)
Unemployed
I know. She's probably still waiting for me.
I'll get back together with her.
What?
It was two days ago that he said that.
So if he's wanted by the law...
Inspector Megure thought it was
likely he'd go to see her,
so we visited Yoda Satomi-san.
Kazuma was involved in a robbery?
You want to know if he's contacted me?
He hasn't even called.
If he shows up here, I promise I'll call you.
There's no point in running forever.
But we can't take her word for it.
Which is why we're conducting this stakeout,
but there's no telling when
Fujiki Kazuma will show up,
and there's no guarantee that he will at all.
There's nothing for
the Detective Boys to do this time.
There's no mystery to solve either.
Are you sure about that?
Huh?
It's possible he won't show up in the future.
He could've already fled here
and be hiding inside.
Yeah.
Naturally, we considered that possibility.
But when we visited, there were
no signs of anyone hiding.
Huh.
That makes it even stranger.
Yeah. Fujiki-san seems like he'd immediately
run to his ex Yoda Satomi-san for help,
so why didn't he do that?
We can't leave now.
After all, there's a mystery here.
Yeah.
So you're staying, then?
What should I do?
She looks like she's
desperately trying to stay calm.
Her ex committed a crime, after all.
It's been three years since they broke up.
Does she still have feelings
for Fujiki Kazuma, or...
She's going out.
Hold down the fort!
Got it.
I'll go with you.
She exited the building.
She went that way.
She's heading towards the station.
I wonder who called her.
Yeah. It might've been Fujiki Kazuma
asking to meet her somewhere.
Give me back my money!
I'll pay you back double, so go home!
You're gonna lose it all
playing dice again, aren't you?
Stop that!
You shouldn't fight, and
you shouldn't gamble either.
Shut up!
What?
He's a cop?
Did I say dice? I meant nice!
Oh, no.
Lucky us.
Unagi
Broiled in Sauce
Broiled Without Sauce
Unagi
So she left the house to go shopping, but...
High-grade steak, assorted sashimi,
and top-quality broiled eel.
All portions for one, too.
Now she's bought wine and two shortcakes.
Then it's decided.
She's smiling happily, too.
What are they doing?
It must be hard carrying all that stuff.
We'll help you carry it home.
Help me?
We're not suspicious children.
We're just considerate passers-by.
What do you think you're doing?
It's a clever strategy.
The presence of children will
create a genial atmosphere,
increasing the chances Fujiki
Kazuma-san will show up.
I'll carry the eel.
Don't eat it.
I'll carry the wine.
I'll be careful not to break it.
Toto Meiwa Bank ATM
Meiwa Bank
Toto
ATM
Thank you, kids.
Think something of it.
You mean, "Think nothing of it."
Yeah, that.
Well, see you later.
Bye!
Fujiki Kazuma will show up soon?
That call was from Fujiki.
He probably said he'd visit soon.
Yoda Satomi-san still has feelings for him.
If he was so desperate for cash
that he robbed someone,
then he must not be eating properly,
so she prepared a feast for him.
She even withdrew a large amount of cash.
She probably intends to give
it to him as getaway money.
But we just need to apprehend Fujiki Kazuma
before she does anything
stupid like aid his getaway.
Yeah, but maybe Yoda Satomi-san
has realized she's being watched.
What?
Don't you think it's too convenient?
We nearly lost her while following her,
but we found her again.
And...
You're overthinking it, Conan-kun.
It's our turn now.
Why won't Fujiki Kazuma show up?
It's been three hours since
she got the food and money.
It certainly is strange.
Yes, this is Takagi.
Oh, Yoda Satomi-san.
What?
Did Fujiki contact you?
There's something I'd like to
tell you. Could you come here?
What?
I'd like to discuss the details in person.
Your little friends can come with you.
She invited all of us.
What?
The truth is, just after
you left this morning,
I got a call from Kazuma.
It's me. Haven't talked to you in three years.
He'd committed a crime and came to my
apartment in hopes that I'd hide him,
but the police happened to be
there, so he fled in a hurry.
I wanted to get back together with you,
but I guess things didn't go my way.
I hope you find happiness, Satomi. Goodbye.
Kazuma!
So Fujiki Kazuma came to
this apartment building.
But he saw us and fled
and called to say goodbye,
which means he won't be coming back.
Then what was that food and money for?
Oh, right. There was no need to get those.
I'm sorry for tricking you.
When I realized I was being watched,
I decided to use that against you.
By letting you observe me
getting the food and money,
I made you believe Kazuma
was trying to come here.
But I've realized allowing Kazuma to
stay on the run isn't good for him.
I decided to tell you everything and ask you
to please find Kazuma as soon as possible
and make him atone for his crimes.
We understand. In any case, we've
realized it's pointless to continue.
We'll call off our stakeout and
follow Fujiki Kazuma's trail.
Thank you.
There's something off about Yoda Satomi-san.
She even cried tears
as she made that confession.
It smelled like an act to me.
Smelled like an act?
Yeah.
Those tears may have been over the top.
That's because she still has
feelings for Fujiki Kazuma-san,
and they're deeply in love.
Are you sure about that?
They're looking for witnesses.
Fujiki Kazuma-san came all
the way to this building,
saw the police, and fled in a hurry.
And they'll go farther and farther away
as they expand the area of their search.
What is it, Conan-kun?
What's up?
Did you discover a new fact?
Her confession was an act after all.
But why?
What happened as a result of it?
The stakeout ended.
Yeah.
There's a reason Yoda Satomi-san was
inconvenienced by being watched by the police.
What's that?
What is it?
Fujiki Kazuma-san is
actually on his way here.
Either way, there's no understanding women.
What?
Why can't they cut ties with bad men?
Uh, yeah...
This isn't a conversation grade
school kids should be having.
That's Detective Takagi's car.
Welcome.
Hello. Is your office in the back?
Uh, yes.
We're helping Detective Takagi with his work.
Sure, go ahead.
We're the Detective Boys.
Don't run.
This is footage from this morning
of the front of this store.
The people are small, so
I'll enlarge the image.
It's Fujiki Kazuma.
It looks just like him.
That's really him.
Um, based on the timestamp,
we know he headed to Yoda
Satomi-san's apartment this morning.
But the cameras only captured him arriving.
Whichever way he ran,
I doubt he's still around here.
Yes. So, Inspector, we're
going to look for places
Fujiki Kazuma might go besides
Yoda Satomi-san's apartment.
Yes, roger that.
Okay, let's go.
Okay.
See you later, kids.
Head directly home.
Now then, should we go home?
Yeah, right!
Figures.
The police don't seem interested,
but let's look into Yoda Satomi-san.
Yoda Satomi-san used to be
a really cheerful person.
But around this time three years ago,
she fell into a deep depression.
She probably took it hard when
Fujiki Kazuma-san dumped her.
I have some surprising news!
She's currently seeing someone!
He runs a store on the other side
of the station, so I went to check it out.
Ishinabe
Discount General Store
Discount
The owner is a good honest man
named Ishinabe-san,
Ishinabe Daisuke (30)
Store Manager
but the shocking part is he got engaged
to Yoda Satomi-san last month.
What?
An engaged woman wouldn't trick the police
to help a man she got over a long time ago.
That confession must have been a lie.
But why did she need to lie?
Could it be?
The only trail the police have on Fujiki-san
is him heading to Yoda
Satomi-san's apartment, right?
Yes, it was captured on a security camera.
What about it?
Being watched is inconvenient both
when you're secretly receiving a guest
and when they're leaving, too.
I had no idea books could be so heavy.
You should've had them pick them up.
Used bookstores pick up? I had no idea.
Thanks for the help.
Well, I've got work, so
I'm heading back to the store.
Here's your key.
Thank you.
See you later.
You scared me.
Hey, Yoda Satomi-san. Could you show us
that box you loaded into your car?
They're just books I finished reading.
Hold it. Don't lock the trunk.
Stand back.
B-But...
Hup.
Don't!
Huh? But they're just books, right?
I knew it.
Stay back, guys.
Fujiki Kazuma-san, who injured
someone in a robbery this morning,
fled to your apartment.
He didn't want to be arrested,
so he asked you to hide him.
But you couldn't forgive him for selfishly
begging for help after dumping you...
so you killed him.
When you returned to your senses, you
realized the gravity of what you'd done.
If your crime was discovered, your
engagement would be called off.
So you decided to abandon Fujiki-san's body.
Even if it were discovered, your
relationship ended three years ago.
You figured the police wouldn't suspect you.
But...
Yes?
Excuse me, but we're with the police.
B-Be right there.
Then they began their stakeout.
You were aghast.
The police were watching you at all times,
so you couldn't move the body.
What should I do?
That's when you came up
with the fake confession.
You had two goals in doing that.
First, to make them call off their stakeout,
and second, to avoid suspicion.
You were willing to deceive
the police to help him escape.
It would convince the police
that someone who loved Fujiki-san that much
wouldn't kill him or dump his body.
You probably meant to leave
Fujiki-san's body somewhere
and lead them to believe he got involved
in some kind of trouble while on the run.
You're mostly correct, but you
got one important thing wrong.
I didn't kill Kazuma.
When he came to my place,
Kazuma said something.
You can't seriously serve water
to a man you haven't seen in years.
Bring me beer.
You're as inconsiderate as ever.
Treat your guests better.
Yeah, that's the stuff.
I finally realized something.
You were my bluebird of happiness all along.
Aren't you glad you waited three years, too?
Just thinking I once loved
this man made me feel pathetic.
But I'd grown over those three years.
Huh?
I'm not some innocent girl anymore!
Get out!
You can't be serious, you bitch!
Fine.
You'll never see me again.
If a neighbor heard us shouting,
the police would suspect
I killed him during an argument.
So I felt I had to do
something about Kazuma's body.
If that's truly what happened, we'll
treat this as an accidental death.
Thanks for calling us.
Is this man involved in the case?
Ishinabe-san.
I came back because I forgot my lighter.
It's over.
But you didn't kill him.
A man died, and I didn't call the police.
Instead I hid the body and
planned to get rid of it.
You're under arrest for
attempting to abandon a body.
I'll wait for you to come back.
Aw, man. I'm hungry.
Come to think of it, all we had to eat
were those snacks during the stakeout.
Hey, wasn't she arrested?
What's going to happen to
the top-quality eel she bought?
What?
And the shortcake.
But she was arrested, so
wouldn't those be evidence?
Yeah, they were probably collected
as evidence of her deception.
Aw, man. My eel.
Genta-kun...
And the cake.
Let's have the professor treat us.
Yeah!
Good thinking, Haibara-san!
Episode Preview
Miyano Akemi-san was...
You're her younger sister Shiho-chan, right?
Yeah, right.
You're a smart kid.
Yeah, I'm with the Beika Fire Station.
She was the better...
Here's what it looks like.
We'll help you look for it.
Miyano Akemi's Time Capsule (Part One)
The next episode of Conan is "Miyano
Akemi's Time Capsule, Part One!"
Next Conan's hint!
Class Reunion
19th Graduating Class
Reunion
A class reunion!
We'll see you again!
Don't miss the next episode.
In "Stakeout 3!"
See you then!
Give me a break...
Huh?