Aw, darn.
I really wanted to keep that chicken.
You mean that chicken you caught
at the ranch the other day?
It's not like we had a choice.
Its owner died, after all.
Come to think of it, the new black
rabbit doesn't seem very energetic.
Yeah, it's not eating much.
Perhaps it's sick.
It'll be fine.
Rabbits are sensitive to
changes in environment.
It's probably just not used
to its surroundings yet.
It might greet us with an energetic
face when we go to see it today.
Face...
Haibara, don't show your face.
You know what that means, don't you?
Well? Feel like going to
a tanning salon, too?
I dunno. That's too dark for me.
Dark...
That cake was so good.
The secret ingredient was probably sherry.
Sherry...
It's an organizational...
Organization... Betrayal... Gin...
Betrayal is...
That ginger dish...
The pursuer is...
Pursuers... Rum...
Actually, I'm a fan of rum...
Haibara? What's the matter?
What?
It's nothing.
Beyond detective skills capable
of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
We're deciphering a code
at the elementary school!
A message is delivered to Haibara!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Miyano Akemi's Time Capsule
(Part One)
"Miyano Akemi's Time Capsule, Part One!"
Oh, wow!
It's eating a ton.
I'm glad it's feeling better.
We're heading back to the faculty office.
Could you change their water
and clean the shed?
Okay!
What are Kobayashi-sensei and
Wakasa-sensei doing at school on a Sunday?
Right?
We're here to take care
of the animals, but...
The said they had to look
after the guests coming today.
Huh.
What guests?
I don't know. I didn't ask.
What's wrong, Ai-chan?
Oh, sorry.
I felt like someone was watching me.
By the way, Haibara...
Didn't I tell you the other day that you don't
have to worry about the Black Organization?
They just clashed with the FBI.
You're not in any danger.
Besides, there's no way they'd find out
you're ex-organization member Sherry,
or that your real name is Miyano Shiho.
You're right.
Hey, you.
You're Shiho-chan, right?
Miyano Akemi-san's younger sister.
I didn't expect to run into you here.
I'm surprised.
N-No, I'm not...
Who are you?!
Who the hell are you?!
"Who the hell?"
Who's Shiho?
Her name is Ai-chan.
You're some kind of pervert, aren't you?
No, I was just—
Murata-kun.
What are you doing?
Who are you people?!
This is an elementary school.
It's not open to outsiders.
But we're not outsiders.
Then who are you?
Oh, there you are. Those people are...
They're graduates of this school,
and they came to hold a class reunion?
In a classroom here at
Teitan Elementary School?
Yes.
I'm surprise you got permission to do that.
We were given permission on the
condition that we don't drink alcohol.
Weren't you one year behind me
in the 19th graduating class?
Yes.
I'm Murata Sho. I was the class president.
Murata Sho (25)
Former Class President
I'm Yanagimachi Gaku.
I was the class vice-president.
Yanagimachi Gaku (25)
Former Class Vice-President
I'm Ichihashi Seiko.
I was the class secretary.
Ichihashi Seiko (25)
Class Secretary
It looked like you were arguing
with the children earlier.
There was a girl named
Miyano Akemi in our class.
That brown-haired girl looks just
like a photo of her younger sister Shiho
that she showed me, so I approached them.
How long ago was that, though?
I think it was over winter
break during our sixth year.
That's 13 years ago.
Oh.
Then there's no way it's her.
You're right.
Unbelievable.
You never told me your
sister graduated from here.
I just found out, too.
I heard the Organization frequently
made her change schools, though.
In any case, act like you're unrelated.
I know.
Miyano Akemi...
Miyano Shiho...
This girl is the fallen angel who
took over research for that drug
and betrayed the organization?
Yeah, right.
Shall we go, then?
The rest of the class is in classroom 6-A.
Oh, actually, they're lining up the desks.
They're probably setting up the space.
We have something we need to dig up.
Class 6-A
19th Graduating Class
Class Reunion
That should do it.
Yeah.
That just leaves the food.
It feels like something's missing.
I know. Why don't we order sushi
and make our homeroom
teacher Kunigami pay for it?
Good idea.
I see. A time capsule.
You're going to dig up the time capsule
you buried the day before your graduation
as entertainment for the party.
Yeah.
I don't know what I'll do if we're all expected
to share something in front of the others.
Why?
I'm sure I wrote something embarrassing.
Well, it doesn't bother me.
I became a firefighter just like I wanted.
I'm fine, too. Becoming
a doctor was my dream.
It's what my parents wanted for me, too.
What about you, Murata-kun?
You don't work in art?
You won some kind of award
for your watercolor painting.
That was a fluke. I work
part-time these days.
You still haven't found the time capsule?
Yeah. We're currently waiting
for the person who buried it.
It was buried by the person we were
just discussing, Miyano Akemi-san.
My sister?
Are you sure you sent her
an invitation to the class reunion?
I know I did.
I told her to meet us in
front of the animal shed.
The location of the shed
hasn't changed, right?
No.
Sounds like they don't know
your sister's dead.
Well, the news reported that
her body was unidentified.
We need her to come, though. She's
the only one who knows where it is.
Seriously?
What are we going to do?
Don't worry about that.
She apparently wrote down
the location where it's buried
and gave the note to Kunigami-sensei.
Really?
Oh, but it's not a map of the location.
Here's what it looks like.
Librarian Miyano Akemi
Show me a Monet
Plane attack
Artist don't go
Doctor don't lie
Don't burn charm 89
See?
A code?
Librarian Miyano Akemi
Show me a Monet
Plane attack
Artist don't go
Doctor don't lie
Don't burn charm 89
Why is it in code, though?
Maybe she wanted her friends
meeting for the first time in a while
to have fun solving it together?
Like the "Fiend with 200 Faces"
you put on for us the other day.
Right. When she gave it to Kunigami-sensei,
she apparently told him that it
includes a message for everyone.
There's a message for her younger
sister who she rarely got to see, too.
What?
What should we do? Should we show
the others and search together?
N-No, let's try looking
for it ourselves for now.
Y-You're right. We wouldn't want to
interrupt their preparations...
Um, Kudo-kun—
In that case...
We'll help you look for it.
What?
After all...
We are...
...the Detective Boys!
We can't do that. If we find it while the
others around, I won't be able to read—
Don't worry.
I'll find it before these guys
and secretly deliver it to you:
Librarian Miyano Akemi
whatever message your sister
left for you 13 years ago.
In that case, should we split up
and try to find the time
capsule based on this code?
Right. We can share the code
by taking pictures with our phones.
Excuse me.
Now we can search in several groups.
If anyone finds the capsule first,
why don't they use their phone
to notify the other groups?
Got it. No looking inside until notifying
the others and everyone else gets there.
Haibara, Ayumi-chan, and
I will go with Murata-san.
Okay.
Kobayashi-sensei and Mitsuhiko will go
with Ichihashi-san the doctor.
Okay.
And Wakasa-sensei and Genta will go
with Yanagimachi-san the firefighter.
S-Sure.
We're good with searching as teams, right?
No.
I'm against the idea, too.
Why are you the only one
who gets to go with the girls?
That's not fair.
That's the problem?
But we're girls, too.
We can change teams later.
There's actually a reason I put Haibara
and Murata-san on the same team.
But the moment those three saw
the code, they all turned pale,
as though they knew what the
code said just by looking at it.
It seems like there's more to
this code than meets the eye.
Edogawa
Hup.
This place hasn't changed at all.
Yeah.
You're right.
What's the matter?
Oh, sorry.
Just spacing out.
There you are. Shall we go?
Principal's Office
We'll start in the principal's office.
What? Why?
Because the first code says
"show me a Monet," right?
Our principal loves the painter Monet
and bragged about having a
replica of his work in his office.
So there must be a clue on that painting.
Class 6-A
Murata Sho
Oh.
Looks like he's displaying a
student's work and not a Monet.
There's a name on it.
Class 6-A Murata. That's...
Yeah, this is my work that won an award.
This brings back memories.
If there's something written
on the back of the Monet...
We'll have to ask where it is.
But the principal has the day off.
Let's look everywhere
that catches our attention.
Yeah.
Right.
Kids, you'll get in trouble for doing that.
It'll be fine. We'll explain
the situation later.
More importantly...
What was the girl who wrote this code like?
Well...
She was cheerful, kind, and considerate.
Everyone in our class adored her.
All the boys were probably in love with her.
Is that true?
Yeah. I was actually one of those boys,
and she politely turned me down.
Really?
Ai-chan, you seem kind of happy.
You'd better thank me later.
The same goes for this
painting. It's actually...
It's actually...?
She was the better...
E-Er... Nothing.
Nurse's Office
You're currently in training, then?
Yes.
Japanese Language 6
I'm rotating between all kinds
of departments. I'm so busy.
Sounds difficult.
By the way, what are you doing?
I'm searching the sink.
The "tell a lie" in "doctor don't
lie" sounds like "tearai" (sink),
Tell a Lie
so I thought there might be something
in the sink at the nurse's office.
I haven't found anything yet, though.
You're a smart kid.
You must be, too, as a doctor.
Huh?
Were your grades always top of the class?
Sure...
Luck seems... to have been on my side, too.
Seriously?
Home Economics Room
You're the ones who put out that fire
at the apartment building in Beika City?
Yeah, I'm with the Beika Fire Station.
That's amazing. That was a huge fire.
I even saved two kids who hadn't escaped.
Wow, you're a real-life hero.
Well, it's my job.
Anyway, the "don't burn charm 89"
at the bottom of the code...
Since it says "burn",
I thought we'd find something
in the home economics room
where students use open flames.
But there's nothing here.
Come to think of it, Kobayashi-sensei said
the music room nearly caught fire once.
Oh, right. The thousand cranes
in the music room
that were folded for the choral
contest got a little burnt.
I believe it happened 14 or 15 years ago.
Do you remember that?
A fire in the music room?
I don't remember that.
We've searched the principal's
office, the nurse's office,
the art room, the home economics room,
the science room, and the roof,
and have nothing to show for it.
Us, too.
Since we didn't see any of the other
groups, we must've missed each other.
Yeah.
Why don't we show the code
to the rest of the class
and search together after all?
Why don't we keep looking by
ourselves just a little longer?
Yeah. Besides, I remembered something.
I feel like we can figure it out.
Then the teachers and I
will help you look for it.
You guys handle the rest of
the chores at the animal shed.
Aw, what?
The first part of the code
is "show me a Monet."
Monet makes me think of...
The principal's office.
But my work is hanging there now.
Did you call the principal
to ask about the painting?
Yes. He said he has the painting at home,
but there's nothing written on it.
That's too bad.
If it's not on the back
of the painting, then...
Maybe it's on the wall.
Yo
I knew it.
There's something written on
the wall behind the painting.
Seriously?
I didn't notice.
Yo
Look. It's the hiragana symbol "yo."
We've made progress.
Yes.
Maybe we'll be able to
solve the rest of the code.
Yeah.
Episode Preview
It's dark and hard to see, but...
There's a "gu" on the bottom of
the doorknob of the door to the roof.
Next is the fourth code, "doctor don't lie".
Be brave.
Damn it.
Where is it?
Onee-chan...
Beika
Irohazushi
That's Teitan Elementary School, right?
The next episode of Conan is "Miyano
Akemi's Time Capsule, Part Two!"
Miyano Akemi's Time Capsule
(Part Two)
Keyboard
Next Conan's hint.
A keyboard!
A time capsule, huh?
Don't miss the next episode.
What should we put inside?
I—
Anything but food.
Never mind.