We arrived at school to
take care of the animals,
Murata Sho (25)
Former Class President
where we met three members of Teitan
Elementary School's 19th graduating class.
Yanagimachi Gaku (25)
Former Class Vice-President
Ichihashi Seiko (25)
Class Secretary
The three of them were
searching for the time capsule
left behind by their classmate
Miyano Akemi-san, but...
Librarian Miyano Akemi
Beyond detective skills capable
of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
The code Miyano Akemi left behind
travels across time to reach Haibara!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Miyano Akemi's Time Capsule
(Part Two)
"Miyano Akemi's Time Capsule, Part Two!"
The next part of the code is "plane attack."
An attack on a plane is called a hijacking.
Since that's a jack that
happens at high altitude,
I thought it might mean the power
jack for the clock in the auditorium.
Oh, right.
I see.
Are you okay?
Don't fall.
High places are no problem for firefighters.
Well?
Is there anything written up there?
It's hard to read because of
all the dust, but there's an "u."
Combined with the first letter
we found, we have "yo-u."
What does that mean?
We'll know once we have
the remaining three letters.
The third code is "artist don't go,"
so we came to the art room.
But where should we look?
What is it, kid?
Oh, you know.
Oh, right.
Speaking of "don't go," we were prohibited
from drawing landscapes on the roof.
I remember that.
Someone nearly fell when the wind
caught their drafting board.
If the code's telling us not to
go up to the roof to draw,
then maybe there's something
written on the door to the roof.
Let's go, Yanagimachi.
Sure.
Come on, Conan-kun.
Gu
There's a "gu".
There's a "gu" on the bottom of
the doorknob of the door to the roof.
I'm surprised it wasn't
scrubbed away after 13 years.
After that incident, the door was locked,
and hardly anyone was
allowed on the roof anymore.
Maybe it's because nobody
touched the doorknob anymore.
Oh, right. Akemi must've known that.
Smart girl.
Next is the fourth code, "doctor don't lie."
I think I might know what that means.
Hey, Ichihashi.
Is there really something down there?
Shi
Found it.
It's dark and hard to see,
but there's a "shi" written
behind one of the legs of the bed.
But how'd you get under the bed
from "doctor don't lie?"
Lots of kids faked being sick so
they could lie in bed and skip class.
I see. So it means "don't lie
to the school nurse."
Shi
When you string together the four letters
we've found so far, you get "yougushi".
Even if we can't figure out
the last code about charm 89...
It's obviously tool shed (yougusitsu).
Yeah.
Then let's head there and
look for the time capsule.
Oh, but...
I believe that tool shed was...
Library
Just like I thought.
The tool shed that was
located on the edge of the yard
was removed ten years ago due to
deterioration and replaced with a bathroom.
What?
Seriously?
Does that mean the time
capsule is gone, too?
Probably.
But why did we look that up
on the computer in the library?
There are other computers
with school documents on them,
but this is the only one that
doesn't require a password.
I see.
Either way, that's a rather old computer.
Yes.
Though it was brand new back
when I was a school librarian.
This reminds me of how
I used to organize books here.
I see. That's why "Librarian Miyano
Akemi" was oriented that way.
Librarian Miyano Akemi
Show me a Monet
Plane attack
Artist don't go
Doctor don't lie
Don't burn charm 89
I figured it out. I know
where the time capsule is,
and that they've been
interfering with our search.
Be brave.
Mori Detective Agency
Coffee Poirot
Okay, that's ten standard combos.
Beika Irohazushi
To Teitan Elementary School, right?
It's unfortunate, but we'd better
report this to the rest of the class.
The tool shed where the time
capsule was hidden was removed,
so we can't find it anymore.
Then why don't we try to remember what
we put in it and tell the rest of the class?
That's a good idea, even
if it is a little embarrassing.
We'll head back to the classroom
where the reunion's being held.
It's a shame, though.
What?
About the tool shed.
This computer is old, but it's still useful.
It's a shame to get rid of
something just because it's old.
Look. The positions of the keys on
this keyboard are mostly the same,
so you could use it for years
without replacing it.
The keyboard!
Well, the tool shed leaked
and was in terrible shape.
Oh, I see.
Why don't you return to your
friends at the animal shed?
Okay.
They contacted me using our
detective badges earlier.
They're almost done caring for the rabbits,
so they suggested we go home together.
See you later, Sensei.
Okay!
Kids these days carry detective badges?
Just those kids.
It's me. How are things over there?
We finally heard from Conan-kun.
Took you long enough.
We finished caring for
animals a long time ago.
So, where's the time capsule?
We haven't found it yet, but...
You guys are going to look for it.
Class 6-A
19th Graduating Class
Class Reunion
Damn it.
Where is it?
Where should I look?
I knew it was you.
Our search was being obstructed by
Yanagimachi Gaku-san the firefighter.
O-Obstructed? What are you talking about?
I just realized where the time
capsule's actually hidden.
But you did obstruct our search
by planting a bunch of fake answers.
What?
The third code is "artist don't go."
Because drawing on the roof was prohibited,
there was a "gu" written on the
doorknob of the door to the roof.
But there was also a "gu" written next to
the number seven on the clock in the art room
so we'd find it even if we thought the answer
was 197 (i-ku-na, "don't go"), or 19:07.
The same goes for the fourth
code, "doctor don't lie."
Because some students faked being sick so
they could lie in bed at the nurse's office,
there was a "shi" beneath the bed.
But there was also a "shi"
on the back of the scale.
I'm sure some students stretched as tall
as they could to lie about their height.
Class 6-A
Murata Sho
The first code is "show me a Monet,"
and we found a "yo" on the wall behind
the painting in the principal's office.
But there wasn't anything written
there when I looked earlier.
In other words, you left fake answers
in all the places you thought
the code could refer to
when we first split up and
searched around the school,
knowing someone would find
them on our second search.
That's why you didn't write an
answer for "don't burn charm 89."
Since the previous letters were yo-u-gu-shi,
you figured we'd assume
it meant the tool shed.
And once we learned that shed
was torn down ten years ago,
you expected us to give up the search.
But there was one place where you couldn't
write a letter during our first search.
That's the hijack that could be deduced
from the second code, "plane attack."
In other words, a power jack located up high.
The power jack for the clock
in the auditorium.
If you'd climbed a ladder to write
something up there during our first search,
someone would've found it suspicious,
but if you climbed the ladder yourself later
and said there was an "u" written there,
it's unlikely anyone would
climb back up to check.
But you couldn't have
planted these fake answers
unless you knew Miyano Akemi-san, the
person who wrote this code, wouldn't show up.
If she revealed the real answer,
you'd be exposed.
Since you're the one who sent out the class
reunion invitations, you knew, didn't you?
That Miyano Akemi-san
wouldn't be able to attend.
Yeah...
Since Akemi didn't respond,
I visited her apartment.
Miyano
It looked like she hadn't been home in days.
But why would you do this?
I was scared.
I was scared Akemi would reveal that I
snuck into the school with some local punks
and caused the fire in the music
room by playing with fireworks.
Is that true?
Yeah. Akemi happened to be at
school and discovered us, so we ran.
The music room next door
probably caught fire
because we didn't extinguish
our flames properly.
So there's probably a
note in the time capsule
about how a current firefighter
is actually an arsonist.
On the day of our graduation,
Akemi told me...
Be brave, Yanagimachi-kun.
That's what she said.
She was probably telling me
to turn myself in.
And that's why you
interfered with our search?
I was planning to swipe Akemi's message
if we found the time capsule, too.
Ichihashi...
I once copied Akemi's answers
for a Japanese language test
because she sat in front of me.
A teacher asked to meet with us over it.
Me, too, actually.
Akemi-chan painted the same location
as my painting that won an award.
Even though hers was clearly
better, only I won an award.
She probably wrote about
that in her message.
There's no way she'd do any of that!
She was kind, considerate, and
popular with the whole class.
She'd never leave a negative
message like that!
But we won't know unless we
find and open the time capsule.
We've already found it.
What?
Unlike the rest of the letters,
Librarian Miyano Akemi
Show me a Monet
Plane attack
Artist don't go
Doctor don't lie
Don't burn charm 89
"Librarian Miyano Akemi" was
oriented differently, right?
That's meant to represent herself
doing her job as a school librarian.
So her name is the chair,
and the code is the keyboard.
If you rotate the keyboard
90 degrees clockwise
and connect the keys for
mo-ne-mi-se-ra-re-ru (show me a Monet),
you get "shi."
Hi-ko-u-ki-o-so-e (plane attack)
is "i."
If you read the last bit of e-ka-ki-i-ku-na
(artist don't go) as yu-ku-na,
you get "ku."
The fourth code, I-sha-u-so-ko-ku-na,
is "ko."
The 8 and 9 in 8-9-no-o-ma-mo-ri-ya-ku-na
(don't burn charm 89) are the function keys.
When compared against the library's computer,
you get "ya."
String them together, and you get
animal shed (shiikugoya).
I see.
And you came here because
you figured that out, right?
Yeah.
So, where's the capsule?
We found it.
It was taped to the roof of the shed.
It was hidden behind a false roof.
And just in case it fell...
This note was taped to the lid of the box.
This is the 19th graduating class' time capsule! Please contact a teacher if found.
Th-Then what about Akemi-chan's message?
It was written right here,
on the back of a group photo.
I hope all our dreams come true
Class 6-A Miyano Akemi
It says, "I hope all our dreams come true."
Akemi...
Akemi-chan...
Be brave, Yanagimachi-kun.
Akemi...
I hope all our dreams come true
Class 6-A Miyano Akemi
Come to think of it, the teachers
said the fire in the music room
was caused by the old
AC unit short-circuiting.
What?
Then why did Akemi tell me to be brave?
Maybe she was telling you to find
the courage to stop hanging out
with the bad influences you
lit those fireworks with.
I see. Sounds like something she'd say.
Now that I think about it,
after we met with the teacher,
Akemi frequently invited me to
study with her in the library,
and my grades improved.
Then maybe she didn't submit
her own painting to the contest
so I'd gain confidence.
I'd better tell her the next time I see her
that I'm taking another shot
at becoming an artist.
19th Graduating Class
Class Reunion
When I grow up,
I want to be Japan's first... president.
19th Graduating Class
Class Reunion
Are you kids getting enough to eat?
Don't be shy. You guys found
the time capsule for us.
Okay, thank you.
Well? Hand over my sister's letter.
You swiped it, didn't you?
Actually, we searched the time
capsule pretty thoroughly,
but we didn't find a letter.
What?
There was a photo, though.
I love you Shiho
It's just a joke.
If you remove the sticker on the back,
you'll see what your sister said 13 years ago.
Dear Shiho, my younger sister.
Since you've got such a high IQ, I'm sure
our parents will make you study abroad,
and take over their research someday.
But remember this.
Even if we can't be together,
Dad, Mom, and I all love you.
Mom said a silver bullet
is the bullet of justice.
So like that bullet, I hope
you fly straight and true
toward whatever you think is right.
I hope these words reach my sister someday.
Akemi.
Onee-chan...
Hey.
Someone's there...
Someone's outside the classroom.
Is something wrong?
D-Did you see someone
suspicious here just now?
We didn't see anyone like that. Right?
Yeah.
Maybe Haibara imagined it.
She's been on edge since this morning.
I guess there was a pizza delivery guy.
And a sushi delivery guy.
Ah, here they are.
Here's the extra food we ordered.
I'm so hungry.
Yeah, I've been craving that stuff.
Miyano Akemi was part of Teitan
Elementary School's 19th graduating class.
But the dead don't attend parties.