Mori Detective Agency
Your husband is missing?
Yes. I suddenly stopped
hearing from him three days ago.
Nakajima Takako (30)
Housewife
I checked everywhere I could
think of, but couldn't find him.
I see.
Nakajima Hiroshi (36)
Salaryman
We've been married for four years.
He's a very earnest man.
I can't believe he'd
disappear without a word.
Have you contacted the police?
Of course, but they said foul play seemed
unlikely and didn't take me seriously.
So that's why you came to me.
Yes.
I heard there's no case the great
detective Mori Kogoro-san can't solve.
Won't you please find my husband?
I'm so worried about him.
Where is he now, and what is he doing?
Just thinking about it...
I couldn't turn down a request
from such a beautiful lady.
You mean...
Yes. I'll take on this job!
Thank you!
Beyond detective skills capable
of identifying the truth
is the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
We're suddenly hired to
find a missing person.
There's a truth to this husband
not even his wife knows about.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Missing Man's Dream
"The Missing Man's Dream"
Nakajima Hiroshi, 36 years old.
Works at an apparel company.
But his clothes are kind of drab.
His wife left some things that
might serve as clues, right?
Yeah.
Business cards, three framed photos, a
laptop, and a note written by his wife.
Is this photo from their honeymoon?
Dive Shop
Ocean Blue
This photo is from went they went diving.
Who's this person next to Nakajima-san?
According to the wife's note,
that's his coworker Nishimura-san.
And this is Nakajima-san's
younger brother Ryu-san.
Huh.
Let's see what's on his computer.
Nakajima Hiroshi
Let's see. The password is...
"HIRAKE_50."
We got in.
What's in his email?
Inbox
Drafts
Sent
Spam
Trash
Outbox
Seriously? He doesn't use it at all.
Then what about his browser history?
Right.
His history's totally empty, too.
All History
The most recent item is from six months ago.
An online cruiser store, luxury cars,
luxury watches, and cottages.
Nakayama Oi Construction
All luxury goods a regular
employee couldn't afford.
Well, looking is free. Now then.
Let's visit his office.
This is it.
Let's see.
Lyphard & Roberto, Inc.
9F (Ltd.) Eclipse Arabian
8F St. Simon Corporation
7F Lyphard & Roberto, Inc.
6F Godolphin & Mitcham
5F Tsukitomo Man o' War, Inc.
4F TPD Sunday Holdings
3F Halo
2F Tag Diary, Inc.
1F Entrance
Found it. It's on the seventh floor.
What?
What do you mean by that?
Like I said, there's no one named Nakajima
employed in our accounting department.
Kasai Junko (24)
Receptionist
That can't be right. I know
I was told he works here.
I don't know what to say to that.
This is your company's
business card, isn't it?
Yes, but...
Then let's ask to talk to
his coworker Nishimura-san.
Yeah, you're right.
Oh, Nakajima-san?
Nishimura Masa (35)
Salaryman
Nakajima-san quit six months ago.
What?
He quit? Is that true?
Yes.
I wasn't told anything about it.
I first learned about it when he left.
I thought you were close with Nakajima-san.
He taught me a lot when
I joined the company.
But recently, he'd been busy.
We hadn't kept in touch.
I can understand why he'd want to quit
with no managerial position at his age,
and no real work to do.
Do you have any idea where he might be?
I don't know.
In any case, he's an earnest guy.
All he did was travel between
home and work every day.
What do you think this means, Mister?
Who knows?
This was supposed to be a plain old search,
but it's becoming a pain in the rear.
Excuse me.
You're the great detective
Mori Kogoro-san, aren't you?
Well, yes.
The receptionist from earlier?
There's actually something I wanted to
tell you regarding Nakajima-san.
Then you knew Nakajima-san.
Y-Yes.
The truth is, six months ago...
Nakajima-kun, calm down.
I'm always calm.
Then why?
I can't work at a company
that's this exploitative!
What?
I quit!
So that happened?
Yes. I couldn't officially say anything
that would hurt the company.
Was it useful, though?
Yes, of course.
Great. Then I can brag to everyone
that I helped solve the case.
See you later.
We haven't solved it yet, though.
An allegedly earnest man spoke sharply
to his boss and suddenly quit, huh?
What are we going to do next?
I don't know where to begin.
Then why not make a phone call?
A phone call?
To Ocean Blue.
Dive Shop
Ocean Blue
The dive shop Nakajima-san and
Nishimura-san visited together in that photo.
Dive Shop
Ocean Blue
Hello?
This is Dive Shop Ocean Blue.
Yamauchi Isao (56)
Dive Shop Manager
What? A detective?
What does a detective want with us?
I believe someone named Nakajima
Hiroshi was one of your customers.
Oh, Hiro-chan. I remember him well.
After all, he used to work for us.
He loved sharks.
Every year when he came to our shop, he told
us to take him someplace there were sharks.
Has Nakajima-san visited you recently?
No. The last time he
came was four years ago.
Diving is expensive.
He complained it's tough to keep diving
as a salaryman with only 2,000 yen to spend.
I see. Thank you for the information.
Hey, Mister. Something's not right.
The wife acted like it was totally natural
to know her husband's computer password,
and 2,000 yen for spending
money seems a little stingy.
Yeah. We'll need to look into it.
Yeah.
I haven't spoken with my
brother in several weeks.
Nakajima Ryu (28)
Self-employed
Since Takako-san reached out
to me, I'd heard he was missing.
Have you heard from your brother?
No. I tried calling him,
but he didn't answer.
You don't seem that worried.
I'm not worried exactly.
I just figured it was possible.
What do you mean?
Takako-san is stricter than she looks.
My brother had been under
her thumb for some time.
She held the purse strings, and my brother
was only given 2,000 yen a month to spend.
Whenever he went out, he
told her where he was going,
sent photos of whoever he met with,
and contacted her every two hours.
He said there were a bunch more rules, too.
I see. In other words, you're not
surprised your brother went missing.
No. If anything,
I'm surprised it took this long.
It's sounding less like something happened
to him and more like he ran away.
Yeah.
Nakajima-san had a reason to do that.
What do you mean by that?
In other words, six months ago,
your husband quit his job.
No...
No, that can't be possible.
But it's the truth.
You're lying!
I know everything about him.
He always went to work at the same time
and came home at the same time.
His salary was deposited
same as always, too.
He was definitely going to work,
and he'd never doing anything
without my knowledge.
It's impossible!
Forgive me, but an unemployed person can
leave the house according to schedule.
It's even possible to make deposits
under a different name, too.
But it doesn't make sense. After all,
he was going to the office.
How do you know that?
Were you keeping an eye on your husband?
Yes, I was. I was tracking
the GPS on his phone.
So I know he'd been going to
the office until three days ago.
But three days ago, his phone
lost power in the evening.
That had never happened before.
I see. So that's why you hired me.
That's right!
Now that you know, get out of here.
Hurry up and find him.
By the way, what will you do
once you've found your husband?
Get out!
Nakajima-san used his controlling wife's
habits against her to lead a double life.
He quit his job six months ago,
and continued depositing his
salary into his wife's account.
She hadn't found out until now
because he planned it very carefully.
I wonder what he was doing.
I don't know.
But it seemed to be going well, so why
did he turn off his phone three days ago?
Either he didn't need to hide it anymore,
or something unexpected happened.
Yeah. It's a mystery.
Then let's go find out.
You already know where Nakajima-san was
going without his wife's knowledge, right?
What? Well, yeah.
Normally a GPS only displays a flat map.
So by placing the device on a different
floor in the same building as his office,
he made her believe he was at the office.
In other words, Nakajima-san
was going to the basement
of the building where
his office was located.
Wh-Why would he go to the basement?
What?
Because only the basement floors
were blank on the directory,
but there was no space for rent sign.
In other words, someone is renting them,
but there's no company there.
You'd need a really good reason
not to rent out space
in an office building located
in such a nice district, right?
But an ordinary salaryman couldn't
afford something like that.
That's why we're going to check it out.
This is it.
It's not locked.
Wh-What is this?!
Wh-What is this huge aquarium?
Mister.
A video camera and phone.
The phone's broken.
So that's why the power turned off.
What about the camera?
Huh?
My name is Nakajima Hiroshi.
I just became unemployed two days ago.
But I believe this is my first step towards
living my one life without regrets.
Behold.
In this empty space, I'm about
to create my very own secret base.
I need to start with the foundation.
I'll reinforce the frame so the weight
of the water doesn't destroy it.
Then I'll install the acrylic panel walls.
I'll need to carefully consider the layout.
I'll add water while keeping
a close eye on salinity.
I'll install filters and heaters, too.
Isn't this taking the idea a bit too far?
Finally, I'll add the fish.
Don't forget the hammerhead
sharks. I love those.
Now my secret aquarium is complete.
After six months, it's finally done.
I bet people will be surprised
when they see this.
Where'd he get the money to build this?
Let me explain.
I put all my allowance from every month
towards the year end lottery.
And last year, I finally won.
My winnings totaled...
one billion yen!
What?
S-Seriously?
After carefully considering
how to spend the money,
I decided to build a personal aquarium
in the same building as my former office.
One that would allow me to swim
with the fish, not just observe them.
I'm recording the process in hopes
of someday releasing it publicly.
See you later.
I see. So he made his fading
dream a reality in this place
while avoiding his wife's hounding.
He built the palace of his dreams.
Mister, look.
That's Nakajima-san. Damn it.
This is amazing. It's like a proper aquarium.
It's what's left of a
middle-aged man's dreams.
You know what happened to the victim?
Yeah, more or less.
Do you even know who killed him?
No, not even I—
Not even I know that.
Mori-san?
Please have Nishimura Masa, who works on
the seventh floor, come here immediately.
He's the one who killed him.
G-Got it.
You're identifying the culprit
right off the bat today.
I'd like you to confirm a few things, too.
Why was I suddenly called down here?
What is this place, anyway?
Why don't you drop the act?
We already know you killed
Nakajima Hiroshi-san.
Wh-What are you talking about?
At first you supported
Nakajima-san's proposal.
Of course you did.
You loved diving, and you'd
get to do it for free every day.
But then you learned Nakajima-san won
a massive fortune and wanted a share.
You probably threatened
to expose him to his wife.
The discussion went south from there,
and you attacked Nakajima-san
inside this aquarium and killed him.
That's just speculation.
I didn't know about his secret base,
and I've never been here before.
If you still insist I did it,
then show me the evidence.
The evidence is right there
on that video camera.
On the video camera?
Look closely.
At first, he's filming with a tripod.
But by the end, see?
Someone's holding the camera.
Y-You're right.
In other words, it was filmed by
someone who helped build this place.
Nishimura-san, by your hands.
I'm being falsely accused.
I've never seen this video before.
Then how did you know
this was his secret base?
That's just speculation.
I didn't know about his secret base,
and I've never been here before.
Only someone who saw
that video or filmed it
would know this was
Nakajima-san's secret base.
I don't know what you're
talking about it. It wasn't me.
I didn't do it!
Then what is that?
That's your earring.
You dropped it when you
tussled in the water.
It seems you hadn't noticed.
According to this building's
security camera footage,
three days ago when you took paid time off,
you came to this building for some reason.
You had earrings in both ears
when you entered,
but one was missing when you left.
Furthermore, you arrived before and left
after Nakajima-san's estimated time of death.
What that signifies is plain as day.
You can't talk your way
out of this, Nishimura-san.
It's his fault.
He could've helped me a little.
One billion yen...
One billion yen.
I'm a billionaire!
Hey, Mister.
Huh?
Nakajima-san's secret base
was pretty expensive.
Yeah. He managed to use
up all one billion yen.
Then his wife...
...won't get a single penny.
That's too bad.
Yup.
I'm hungry. Wanna get
some conveyor belt sushi?
I don't feel like fish right now.
Then let's get ramen.
I'd rather have yakiniku.
We can pick up some instant
noodles on the way home.
I'd rather have yakiniku.
You must really love Holmes.
Episode Preview
I know. Let's investigate
the burglary ourselves.
The person I just spoke to said they go
to the park to play the trumpet every day.
Then Kimishima-san would've known
exactly when they'd be out of the house.
Pigeons?
Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko's Detective Notes 2
The next episode of Conan is "Tsuburaya
Mitsuhiko's Detective Notes 2!"
Birdhouse
Next Conan's hint!
A birdhouse!
If I won a billion yen, I'd keep it
a secret from Ran, and...
Don't miss the next episode.
She'd find out in ten seconds.