Up we go.
All right.
Kimishima Satoshi (32)
Park Warden
The birds really like you kids.
They're very friendly.
You can tell they're well taken care of.
This park gets a lot
of visitors who like birds.
I frequently receive food for them, too.
Is there anything else we can do to help?
Thanks, but you've already done enough.
Then is there anything else
you need help with?
What do you mean?
Well, to tell you the truth...
We help people solve any and all problems.
We take on and solve all cases.
We are the Detective Boys!
I see.
In that case, could I ask you
Detective Boys to do something for me?
Could you find the owner of this hat?
It's a lost item that's going
to be disposed of soon.
I see.
Very well. You can count on us.
Yeah.
Then it's up to you now.
What team does that hat belong to?
It's probably for an amateur baseball team.
Since it's big, it must be an adult's hat.
You're right. It's even big for my head.
Huh? There's something written on it.
Izumiya Hayato (42)
Park Visitor
What?
What is this?
Is it the name of a company?
All right. Let's go find
the owner of that hat.
Yeah!
Me, too?
You're a member of the Detective Boys, too.
Come on. Let's go.
Okay.
Beyond detective skills capable
of identifying the truth
sis the power to lead us
to what we should believe.
Our search for the owner of the hat gives
Mitsuhiko the chance to flex his detective skills.
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child
and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko's Detective Notes 2
"Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko's Detective Notes 2!"
Beware of Burglars!
Be On Alert!
This is it.
It sure is dangerous out there.
Absolutely.
There have been no eyewitness reports so far,
so the best we can do is
tell people to be careful.
There's a new burglar in the neighborhood?
Yes. Recently there's been a rash of
burglaries targeting jewels in the area.
Katsumi Nozomu (28)
Amateur Baseball Team Member
I don't have any jewels here.
But I'm planning on buying
some soon, so I'll be careful.
Please do. The burglar breaks in
exactly when homes are vacant.
They research their targets thoroughly.
I understand. I'll be careful.
Well, I should go.
Um... hello. We're here to deliver something.
Thanks for coming all the way here.
The park warden asked us
to find the hat's owner.
I see. Going running in the park
used to be my routine.
Does that mean you haven't gone recently?
I've been busy with work.
But how'd you find me?
We started by questioning
people at the park.
Then we carefully examined the hat.
Examined?
Our examination revealed the hat was
custom-made for an amateur baseball team,
got the team name from the manufacturer,
learned about you from your
teammates, and ended up here.
You kids went all out. I'm impressed.
Yes. After all, we're the Detective Boys.
We did consult the canon a little, though.
The canon?
Oh, it's...
It's what Sherlockians
call the Holmes stories.
Sherlockians? As in Sherlock Holmes?
What story did you consult this time?
"The Adventure of the Blue Carbuncle."
Huh. Never heard of it.
What?
Sorry. I haven't heard of it either.
What's a carbuncle, anyway?
It's a gemstone. A kind of ruby.
Yeah. It's also known as "The Blue Garnet."
"The Blue Carbuncle"
begins on Christmas morning
when a goose and hat
are delivered to Holmes.
A man takes home the goose,
and Holmes takes the hat.
Holmes deduces the owner's
characteristics from the hat.
While Holmes follows
the trail to the hat's owner,
just as the man carves up
the goose to eat it,
he finds a gemstone inside the bird.
Why was there a gemstone inside the goose?
Because the jewel thief fed the gemstone
to the goose as a temporary hiding place.
The culprit went to retrieve the gemstone,
but the goose had already been sold.
Huh...
You must really love Holmes.
I know. Let's investigate
the burglaries ourselves.
Fine, but don't get up to anything dangerous.
I know.
I have a friend who I go walking with.
Some of her jewelry was taken.
It must've been that new burglar.
Is your friend's home around here?
It's a bit closer to the park.
Did you know there's a big park
a short distance from here?
We go walking there all the time.
Someone broke in through the window.
What was taken?
My wife's jewels.
It must've been the new burglar.
What is this?
Cute.
I heard a dog owner I frequently see
on my walks had their home broken into.
Do you know where their house is?
I'm sorry. I only ever see them
in the park I stop by with my dog.
I don't know where their home is.
I see. It seems the culprit really
doesn't leave behind any evidence.
You kids are still here?
We're investigating the burglaries, too.
What? But that's dangerous.
Huh? What's that?
An artist gave it to us while we were
asking people about the hat in the park.
Midorikawa Sumie (72)
Park Visitor
I don't know.
Oh, right.
I thought it might be in one
of my drawings, but I guess not.
Thank you. Your drawings are lovely.
You're welcome to take this, if you'd like.
Are you sure? Thank you.
Could I take a look at that?
What's the matter?
I've actually questioned this man
on the left about three times.
I thought he seemed suspicious
but never found anything on him.
Thanks for showing me.
You thought there was
something suspicious about him?
I was probably overthinking it.
See you later.
Don't wait too long to go home.
I wonder what it means.
He probably just lives around here.
But the police officer
said he seemed suspicious.
Is something the matter?
The person I just spoke to
said they go to the park to
play the trumpet every day.
You mean all the victims
frequently visit the park?
Then Kimishima-san would know exactly
when they'd be out of the house.
But the police officer said he
didn't find anything on Kimishima-san.
Pigeons?
Could it be?
What is it, Conan-kun?
Did you figure something out?
Kimishima-san came up with the idea
of burgling the homes of people
who habitually visit the park.
But the neighborhood is
on alert for burglaries,
so he wanted to avoid
fleeing with the stolen goods.
So he decided to use pigeons.
He could attach the stolen goods to the
pigeons' legs and retrieve them at the park.
That way, no matter how thoroughly
he's searched, nothing would turn up.
I see. He used their homing instinct.
Homing what?
It's their ability to return to the nest.
Pigeons can find their way home
from over a thousand kilometers away.
Pigeons are so smart.
You're right. That would force him
to steal only jewels, too.
Pigeons can't carry anything too large.
Yeah, that's right. Kimishima-san
is definitely the burglar.
There must be evidence
somewhere in that shed.
Let's go.
Kimishima-san.
Hey, Kimishima-san!
Kimishima-san!
What's wrong?
What happened?
Kimishima-san.
Call an ambulance and the police.
Got it.
The culprit is probably long gone,
and we'll be leaving once we're
finished examining the crime scene.
Be careful on your way home, kids.
Okay...
How is Kimishima-san?
They said he'd survive. He'll be fine.
I told the police about the burglaries, too.
But what's going on here?
Did someone who figured out Kimishima-san
was the burglar come for revenge?
Maybe. There were leather
shoeprints on the floor.
Kimishima-san was wearing sneakers, so...
Were those the culprit's footprints?
Yes. The culprit probably
looked inside through the window
with drawn shades from the flowerbed.
But wouldn't they have brought
something with them, then?
Wasn't the weapon a bat left
in the lost and found box?
You're right.
Wait, does that mean
Kimishima-san didn't act alone?
It's possible.
What do you mean, Conan-kun?
I also think Kimishima-san
was attacked by an accomplice
or someone connected to
the burglaries somehow.
Maybe they had a falling out,
and the culprit tried to retrieve
evidence of their involvement.
Does that mean the room was
a mess not because of a tussle,
but because the culprit
was looking for something?
Yeah. Kimishima-san had
clearly just been attacked.
The culprit had to flee because we showed up.
Then is the culprit still in the park?
Yeah. They might be waiting
for another chance to search the shed.
If we see someone wearing muddy
leather shoes, they must be the culprit.
All right. Let's split up and look for them.
Got it.
You're only looking for them.
If anything happens, contact Edogawa-kun.
Okay!
Don't worry about us!
You can count on us, Ai-chan!
The sun's starting to set.
I need to use the bathroom.
Huh?
I didn't find anyone.
Maybe they already left.
Do you remember the man with
the purse who visited Kimishima-san?
Yes. He appears several times
in the artist's drawings.
He's probably the guy he was talking about.
The man who gives him bird food.
That's it.
It seemed awfully heavy for bird food.
Kimishima-san gave us
the hat so we'd go away.
They were making a deal.
What?
Kimishima-san retrieved the jewels
and was selling the stolen
goods right here in this park.
There was probably money in that purse.
The man visiting Kimishima-san was wearing...
leather boots.
Mitsuhiko sure is taking his time.
The noise must've surprised you.
It's just like I thought.
It's really here.
So that's where it was hidden.
You're...
How'd you know they were in there?
Answer me!
It was the weight of the birdhouse.
I thought it was strangely
heavy when I lifted it.
Huh.
I didn't know what you were looking for,
but it seemed like you didn't
search around the birds.
I see. You're a pretty smart kid, too.
I hate birds, you see.
You visited Kimishima-san
this afternoon, didn't you?
Yeah, that's right. To make a deal, as usual.
But he said he didn't want to
do business with me anymore.
I left once, but returned
to talk him out of it.
I told you, I'm done with you.
What?! But we came up
with this idea together!
No, I'm the one who realized
we could use the information
the park visitors carelessly spilled.
So this was my idea.
I've trained the pigeons
to fly longer distances.
I could establish additional bases
and find better business partners.
What?
See? I'm a bad guy.
Now hand them over.
Okay.
Hey.
I'm sorry.
You can't be serious, kid.
Hurry up and hand them over!
Okay.
Here.
This'll teach you to play detective.
I did it. I can't believe I really did it.
I...
Mitsuhiko, are you okay?!
Conan-kun, guys! What took you so long?!
I told you to contact us
if anything happened.
I'm sorry.
I thought the culprit might've realized
the jewels were hidden in the birdhouse
and came back to check.
But you tried really hard, Mitsuhiko-kun.
Oh, right. The jewels.
They're in here.
What do you mean?
I filled the purse inside the lost and found
box with marbles and handed it over.
I was worried he'd open the purse.
Wow, Mitsuhiko-kun.
Yeah, sounds like something
out of a Holmes story.
I'd hardly call that a success.
I let the culprit who attacked
Kimishima-san get away.
Don't worry about that.
We had the police surround the park.
They'll have arrested him by now.
Yeah.
Impressive as always, Conan-kun.
Don't do anything this reckless again.
I won't. I'm sorry.
I don't want to go through anything
that scary again. I'll be careful.
But you did a great job.
You were awesome.
Sheesh.
You're under arrest!
That brat tricked me!
Let me go, damn it!
Katsumi-san, you can do it!
And so, my epiphany
solved the case once again.
I had quite the scare, too,
Team Name
Beika Miracles
Beika Galaxy
Total
but you can't make an omelet
without breaking a few eggs.
I'm one step closer to becoming Watson.
See you next time, everyone.
I plan to write much more in this notebook.
Mitsuhiko-kun, are you watching the game?
Huh? Uh, of course.
You won't want to miss it.
Episode Preview
Um, did I do something?
What?
I have a bump on my head, but
no other injuries on my body.
In other words, this is someone else's blood.
Please. Will you find out where
I was and what I did last night?
Eden?
Did I Do It?
The next episode of Conan is "Did I Do It?"
Dressing Sharp
Next Conan's hint.
Dressing sharp!
September is time for...
Don't miss the next episode
Black "Crow"sing!
For two weeks in a row!
We'll see you on Friday, too.