Ladies and gentlemen!
I bring you marvelous illusions that
make this town sparkle at night!
What miracle is going to happen
under the moonlight tonight?
Huh... So you know the owner, Kaito...
It looks like his name should be "Terai,"
but it's pronounced "Jii." Weird, right?!
I'll call him Jii-san!
Still, Saturday afternoon
and the place is dead...
Huh?
You're good, Kaito!
You're really good, Kaito!
Jii-chan! Coffee!
I'm just gonna serve myself.
Good!
What's that, getting me back?
No, I mean this coffee's good!
You're worse than me, Kaito!
I'm not a hustler.
I'm a magician.
Don't give me "magician"!
You've never beaten me!
Shut up!
You shut up!
You been yakkety-yakkin' since comin' in here!
Brats shouldn't be shootin'
pool to begin with!
What?!
I can't have this, sir.
This is a place to hit balls.
Not a place to hit people.
If you want to hit somebody, do it elsewhere.
Y-You won't be givin' me
the high hat much longer.
This place is deserted with all your
customers flockin' to the boss's pool bar!
What about it?
The boss has the Legendary Cue
at his place.
That's why nobody's comin'
to your hole in the wall!
Get lost, punk!
Yeah, I'll do that.
The next time I come, it'll be to
buy this place from you dirt cheap!
Are you okay, Young Master?
Yeah. But what was he saying
about some "Legendary Cue"?
The Legendary Cue is inlaid with
countless diamonds and emeralds,
and it's said that only
a champion can wield it.
Diamonds and emeralds?!
I know about the place that has that cue.
It's the pool hall called American
in front of the train station.
I hear you have to be 18 or over
and dressed up to get in.
Billiards should be fun to play.
Age and clothes have nothing to do with it.
Still, I'd like to get a look
at an awesome cue like that.
I used to own it.
Then why don't you have it now?
I played a game of pool,
with that cue as the stakes.
And I lost.
This was a long time ago.
Before I met your father, Young Master...
Hustler vs. Magician
Back then, I used to rake
it in as a pool shark.
A pool shark?
Nowadays, pool is an
enjoyable pastime for me,
but back in the day, it was
all about the gambling.
I was a lone wolf who never lost, but
some people didn't take kindly to that.
Hasura Tsujiro worked for the syndicate.
He was a sharp hustler
at the top of his game.
We were tied.
But I made just one error.
From that point on,
Hasura had control of the game,
and I never got another turn.
But you were an expert, right, Jii-chan?
How could you have blown it like that?
Unbeknownst even to Hasura,
the syndicate boss doctored my chalk.
That's cheating!
You didn't object?!
A showdown is a showdown.
I didn't notice it then, and I lost.
Besides, Hasura really was talented.
This is unacceptable.
You've done a lot for me,
so I'll get that Legendary Cue back for you.
Tsujiro, come here a minute.
I got somethin' interesting to show you.
To Hasura-sama:
I'm going to take
the Legendary Cue
at 10:00 tonight!
Kid the Phantom Thief...
Boss, should we call the cops?
Idiot! They're already keeping
an eye on us these days!
Like I'd ask them for even more attention?!
Man, Aoko is always late!
Here she comes.
Sorry I'm late!
What kind of outfit is that?!
Is it cute?
You look like a middle school student!
At least...
What are you doing?!
H-Hey!
Presto!
...you gotta wear something like this.
Come on, let's go!
Wait a minute!
You touched my butt back there, didn't you?
You always have to act like a perv!
How else was I supposed to dress you?!
Then you did touch me!
Th-Three...
Are you two really college students?
Y-Yeah! We're married!
That's right, honey!
P-Please come in...
Chocolate ice cream. Make it a double.
Y-Young Master!
They'll know you're still a kid
if you order stuff like that!
I like it! What can I say?!
I'll have a chocolate parfait.
Aoko-sama...
How about ordering an adult-like cocktail?
Cocktail? With alcohol? Is that okay?
Leave it to me!
Martini, please.
Skip the alcohol.
This is yummy!
Good grief. But maybe she at least
looks like she belongs here...
Hey, where's that Hasura guy?
I believe Hasura-sama is
playing in the secret room.
Secret room?
Sorry, sir, but there's a 50,000 yen charge
just for being a spectator in that...
Three... two...
One!
I'm with Weekly Magic Sunday,
and we want to publish an article in next
week's issue, called "Just Like a Magician!"
"The Cool Techniques of a Brilliant Hustler."
It's for an article?
Then follow me.
Aoko, wait here.
You're leaving me?!
Sheesh!
Nine ball in the corner pocket.
That's definitely Tsujiro.
What the hell? That was a lousy shot.
Young Master!
You're gonna make the Legendary
Cue cry with skill like that.
Jii, huh? He comes in here
after all this time...
We were just supposed to observe tonight...
That's a pain!
As long as I get it, right?
You're from a magazine, I take it?
Why don't you play against Tsujiro once?
Sure, I'm game!
It's been a long time, Jii.
Tsujiro...
Which one should I go with?
Jii, is he a hustler?
I-I don't know...
One game, 10,000 yen.
Let's go with nine ball.
Nine ball?
I know straight pool, but...
Young Master, you're at a disadvantage
if you don't know the rules.
Don't worry, Jii-chan! It's still just a
matter of knocking the balls in, right?
That's right.
Except in straight ball,
you can target any of the balls,
whereas with nine ball,
you have to sink them in order.
Even if you brilliantly knock in the
eight ball, miss nine and you lose.
If you knock the nine ball in
during the opening break, you win.
Heck, it sounds easy.
You can go first.
Thanks.
There we go!
Huh?
Uh-oh!
You did know that sinking the cue ball
is a foul?
I'm unlucky!
You certainly are.
However...
Hasura-sama is amazing!
Incredible!
...nine ball is a game of luck.
And drawing the luck to you...
...is a type of skill.
That's it! He doesn't only have talent.
He's got guts that attract luck.
Oh, boy. This is a match
between an adult and a child.
Do you wanna quit while you're behind?
Up yours...
Tsujiro won this set, too.
That's 100,000 in losses.
Young Master, I can't afford...
W-Wait a second!
Let's raise the stakes. We'll put the
Blue Parrot pool hall on the line!
And for your side,
you put up the Legendary Cue.
Y-Young Master! How am I supposed to
make a living if I lose my place?!
Oh, come on! What's a business or two?
Besides, that place
is Kid the Phantom Thief's headquarters!
I'll figure something out!
I refuse.
I can't play, knowing that I would
take away Jii's business.
Do it. We can make good money
with that place.
But, Boss...
Zip it. Your job is to hit
the balls in like a machine.
What?!
I'm not askin' you.
It's an order, Tsujiro.
He accepts the challenge!
Oh, no...
I'm just a tool to him?
When did that happen?
Still, a showdown is a showdown.
Sorry, Jii, but I'm gonna win this game.
Sink the one, then a two-nine
combination to finish it.
Hey, open up!
Miss, I can't do that!
Kaito! I'm here to cheer you on!
I missed!
A nuisance got in...
The balls are fickle.
Why are you playing this slow crap?!
Kaito can't win with music like that!
I'll play!
Um, something that Kaito likes...
W-What the hell is that?!
All right, now we're talkin'!
Seems like Lady Luck's on my side now!
Kaito, you're so cool!
He looks like he's having so much fun...
Do I enjoy myself like that
during matches these days?
Would you cut the noise when it's his turn?
I can't have him getting distracted.
Billiards is a game you play for fun.
And besides, as for his turn...
He ain't gonna get one!
We'll see about that.
You can't even sink the easy shots, so
there's no way you can handle this setup.
Is that position...?
Toichi-sama...
Kaito, who do you think is the
most important person in a circus?
The person on the flying trapeze!
That's not it.
The clowns are the most important.
Clowns are lame!
Sometimes, to satisfy the audience,
they have to fail deliberately.
That's even more difficult than succeeding.
But clowns have to laugh the whole time.
That's to catch the audience off guard
and heighten their amusement.
That's their poker face.
Dad...
I nailed it!
What?!
The cue ball made two jumps?!
Come on, a little more...
Good job!
I-It can't be...
You did it, Kaito!
Just dumb luck.
S-Son of a...
You're not gettin' that cue!
What?! You said you'd give it if I won!
As always, adults are liars!
And lying is the first step
to becoming a thief!
After learning the secret, you have to die!
What the...?!
What happened?!
K-Kid the Phantom Thief!
I hope you like the flavor
of my paralyzing powder.
I-I can't move!
Kaito! You can't die on me!
As promised, I'm absconding
with the Legendary Cue.
Wait! Your advance notice is nullified.
Your note said you were going
to steal the cue from me,
but now it belongs to him!
That cue can only belong to a true champion.
I've been protecting it for 20 years,
and now I want to give it to that
young man with all my heart.
I see.
In that case, I'm embarrassed for my actions.
Acting outside the bounds of my advance notice
would bring shame to my good name.
Therefore, I shall take my leave.
Farewell!
We're the Organized Crime Task Force!
Nobody move! You're under
arrest for gun smuggling!
Will you come with us down
to the station voluntarily?
You're very talented.
Nah. I was just lucky.
Huh? There are two Kaitos?
It seems you can use magic
to manipulate luck.
But no matter what happens,
a showdown is a showdown.
I lost this time.
But if you don't mind, I'd like to
play against you again sometime.
Sure, I'd like that.
Huh?
Where did Jii-san go?
Honestly, Young Master works
this old man too hard!
Blue Parrot
I had no idea you were
a hustler, Young Master.
Shut up. I told you that was just dumb luck.
Boy, you suck!
You'll never beat me like this!
You relied on luck with my business at stake?
What's the difference? I won!
Look at this shot!
Besides, I'm not a hustler.
Um...
Yay!
I'm a magician.
I win again!
You're on a lucky streak!
The battle between a hustler and a magician.
Was it luck or the poker face
of a clown that won the match?
Or maybe...?
Well, see you next illusion!
I'm devoting myself to stealing as usual
when an arrogant guy just back
from England appears before me.
Detectives are a phantom thief's rivals,
but I haven't met one yet
who's a match for me!
So, you wanna show me what you've got?
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
A Great Detective Comes to Light!
A Great Detective Comes to Light
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion!