Ladies and gentlemen,
I bring you marvelous illusions that
make this town sparkle at night!
Please enjoy the last miraculous
present of the year!
K-Kid the Phantom Thief!
Where are you going?!
Inspector Nakamori.
Unfortunately, I don't have time
to toy with you anymore.
W-What?!
Stop!
Drink. Drive. Lose Your License.
Take Precautions Against Fire
Inspector!
D-Dammit!
He's been gone for three months!
The Phantom Thief Has Vanished
Three months since
Kid the Phantom Thief's last crime
Retired?
Where the hell is he? Where?!
Where did he go?!
It's just been three months.
Maybe he hasn't gone anywhere...
Idiot!
Has he ever taken this much time off
between robberies?!
Well, no, but...
Something's strange...
There must be a reason.
Three months since
Kid the Phantom Thief's last crime
But, Inspector, isn't it a good thing that
Kid the Phantom Thief isn't busy stealing?
That's not what I'm saying!
I'm gonna catch Kid with my own hands...
But it sounds like you want
Kid the Phantom Thief to commit crimes.
Maybe I should tell the commissioner...
Nah, I don't think you need to go that far.
Yeah.
Well, say what you will.
We owe Inspector Nakamori a lot.
When we switched shifts on that
last stakeout, he brought me ramen.
He brought me a beef bowl.
That's enough, you guys!
I want you to give serious thought
as to why Kid hasn't shown up lately!
Well, that's, uh...
He probably has a cold.
Drink. Drive. Lose Your License.
Take Precautions Against Fire
Are you guys morons?!
Holy Night: Two Kid the Phantom Thieves!
Sheesh. First I get a cold, then finals...
This sucks.
It's strange...
I thought idiots were too slow
to catch a cold.
Don't touch me!
What?! I was worried about you!
Don't make me laugh, jackass!
Jeez! You're in a bad mood, Dad's in a snit
because Kid's been a no-show lately...
I have to worry about both of you.
He's mad about Kid's absence?
I'd think the cops would have no
problem with a thief not stealing.
Dad thinks it's weird that Kid hasn't
been around for three months now.
Sounds like your old man's the weird one.
I'm sure even Kid the Phantom Thief doesn't
feel like stealing from time to time.
Man, I've got my own problems to deal with.
Jii-chan, who always gathers
intel on the Big Jewels,
was bedridden after straining his back.
Kaito, blow your nose.
Here.
Thanks.
Still, I wonder where that
sneak thief is hiding...
Then, right when Jii-chan got better,
I get hit with a cold and tests.
Given all that, was I supposed to keep up
my end and pull off regular robberies?
That third-rate inspector...
What does he think I am, a weekly
manga magazine or something?
I've got it!
I bet he's dead!
That's gotta be it! Yeah!
Talk about no tact...
I've finally got my health back.
All right. Time to look into
what the Young Master requested.
I see. That is indeed a valuable jewel...
...but at best, it's a gem
worth tens of millions,
not a Big Jewel.
Young Master seems to be busy at school,
so I can save this report for another day.
E-Everyone! It's Kid!
Kid the Phantom Thief Has Issued a Notice?!
Kid the Phantom Thief has released a notice!
At 6:54 pm this evening, Christmas Eve,
Kid the Phantom Thief stole
the Star of the Giants that was decorating
Tofu Department Store's Christmas tree!
There it is! He finally struck!
The star is inlaid with emeralds
worth several billion yen.
It's meant to be donated to
a museum after Christmas.
Now that's what I'm talkin' about, Kid!
Inspector! Don't talk like that in public!
Drink. Drive. Lose Your License.
Take Precautions Against Fire
All cars, mobilize!
Get to the Tofu Department Store!
R-Roger!
What's all the fuss about?
Something must've happened.
Maybe a crime.
Come on, we have to get to my house.
Customers are coming in droves,
just like I thought!
With this many people,
sales should double... no, quadruple!
Releasing a fake letter
was a stroke of genius.
B-But, sir...
If Kid doesn't actually show up,
we'll lose face and sales afterwards...
Kid the Phantom Thief wouldn't
let his prey escape.
He's coming?
Don't you get it yet?
Excuse me?
You're gonna play Kid the Phantom Thief!
M-M-Me?!
Relax. I'll prepare your escape route.
B-But I don't know if I can
do something so outrageous.
If you steal that Star of the Giants,
we can hold onto it and reap the huge
reward of the amount it's insured for.
And the whole thing will be pinned on Kid!
Succeed, and I'll make you my vice-president.
V-Vice-president?!
Special Bonus
I don't think it's a bad deal.
Here.
I-I'll do it, sir!
I-Isn't that enough, Aoko?
Hang in there! You're so impatient.
Th-This spot?
A-A little to the right...
Th-Then here?
Jeez! That's left, right?!
You suck at this, Kaito!
If we don't hurry, everyone
will be here before it's done!
You hurry!
And you're heavy...
For cryin' out loud, it's not
like you're a little kid.
Why do you gotta hold a
Christmas party every year?
I can do what I want!
You and your parties...
There's excitement in the air
at Tofu Department Store.
There are two more hours
until the appointed time.
Come on, quit being lazy and help me!
Okay, okay...
Will he really come?
Kid the Phantom Thief Sent Advance Notice?!
Fork and spoon go opposite!
How the hell should I know?!
Well, let's interview Inspector Nakamori,
who's in charge of security.
Inspector, Kid has made a move at last.
Kid! I'll pulverize you!
Just you wait!
That was Inspector Nakamori, in high spirits.
You can see all the people gathered
down below from our chopper camera.
I'm sure you viewers at home
know what this is about.
This crowd of onlookers has Kid fever!
It's no understatement to say that Kid is
the greatest phantom thief of this generation!
Coming!
Welcome!
Thanks for the invite!
You came too, Akako-chan!
I just thought it would be immature
not to come after you invited me.
Well, I'm glad you all came. Come on in!
Hey, did you hear? Kid is appearing tonight!
That's Kid for you, showing up
on Christmas Eve! That's awesome!
Oh. All that brouhaha was over
Kid the Phantom Thief.
We'll get to see your dad all hot and
bothered with frustration again, Aoko!
Cut it out!
What are you talking about?
Nothing!
What's with her?
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
The Kid calls have begun!
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid!
Come on, Kid! I'm gonna be
the one who captures you.
You don't skip town on me
without previous notice!
Merry Christmas!
Yay!
Come on, I've got a lot of food over here,
so everyone eat your fill.
Wow! It looks delicious!
She just put out store-bought stuff!
No need to tell them that!
We've got cake, too!
Yay!
Flutter-flutter-flutter! And...
...look!
Now who would be calling at a time like this?
Does anybody have a lighter?
No, nobody here would have a lighter...
I guess we'll just have to
borrow one from Aoko's dad...
Huh?
And I thought I'd have Dad sing us a song...
He said he's gonna be late tonight
because of Kid the Phantom Thief.
Well, good for him...
What?!
He scared me...
I'm right here, so how could Kid...?
We're at Tofu Department Store.
Emergency live broadcast!
The appointed time is nigh!
Kid T-shirts, sweatshirts, and other
merchandise are selling like hotcakes!
This is Mr. Zaizen, the owner
of Tofu Department Store.
Emergency live broadcast!
The appointed time is nigh!
What are your thoughts on the advance
notice you received from Kid today?
Well, I was shocked.
I don't recall sending out
any advance notice!
What's this about?
Don't ask me!
And... why are you asking me?!
Kaito and Akako-chan!
What are you whispering about?
Nothing!
Really?
But what about this
unexpectedly huge sales boost?
If they just got notice today,
why do they have all those Kid goods?
Emergency live broadcast!
The appointed time is nigh!
It's like Kid is everywhere!
It just goes to show that even a sneak
thief like that can do some good!
We're waiting for you.
Good grief...
Kid is bad, but this owner is no better!
Right, Kaito?
Kaito?
Well, he couldn't just stand here.
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Emergency live broadcast!
The appointed time is nigh!
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Listen to those cheers.
But Kid isn't here yet.
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Dammit! What's he doing?!
It's already past the appointed time!
It's Kid! Kid the Phantom Thief is here!
Kid!
What are you waiting for?!
S-Sir!
This is too much for me...
Idiot! Vice-president!
You can be vice-president!
Of course, that includes a major raise!
Plus a chauffeur and flexible working hours!
But that's not all! The vice-prez gets
to take home food from the gourmet floor!
I-I'll do it!
I'm going to take the Star of the Giants!
Kid! Kid! Kid!
Kid! Kid! Kid! Kid!
I knew he could do it.
I just had to hold his hand most of the time.
Farewell!
Give up, Kid the Phantom Thief!
S-Sir!
W-What?! I've never seen
you before in my life!
D-Don't do this to me!
You don't know when to give up, Kid!
Kid the Phantom Thief, you're under arrest!
I don't believe it!
What?! Kid isn't all he's cracked up to be!
Everyone, please continue to shop at
Tofu Department Store!
K...
Kid the Phantom Thief?!
Merry Christmas, Inspector Nakamori!
Good luck, Kid!
W-Which is the real one?!
I-It can't be!
I came, just as the advance
notice stated, Mr. Zaizen.
And it's Christmas Eve.
A night when miracles can happen.
Kid-sama!
Give me a miracle, too!
I'll climb the tree, so wait
for me up there, Kid-sama!
W-With a suave line like that,
this must be the real Kid!
Get him!
Uh-oh. But first, how about I
give you a Christmas present?
M-M-My department store!
Well, I'm off...
W-Wait, Kid!
Do you intend to vanish again?!
Kid, back then...
...you suddenly disappeared
without any warning.
And eight years passed like that.
If you're going to do it again...
I'm not going to run or hide,
Inspector Nakamori.
Let's meet again!
Kid...
"Let's meet again," he says! The idiot!
The next time we meet, I'll tan your hide!
You look happy, Inspector.
Welcome home, Dad!
Yeah. Start to wind it up, you guys,
before it gets late.
Aoko, I'm starving!
K-Kaito?! Where were you?!
Sorry! I had to run an errand.
And on the way back, I bought an ornament
for your tree, so cut me some slack!
So how about some grub?
I'm runnin' on empty here!
We finished everything already!
Seriously?!
You have it rough.
Couldn't be...
The program you witnessed this evening
was the miracle of a holy night.
Truth that sprang from a lie.
If you enjoyed it, then I'm
satisfied as a magician.
Well, see you next illusion!
Hi, Nakamori Aoko here!
I'm doing the preview today!
In the next episode, we all go skiing!
Akako-chan puts the moves on Kaito
on the pure white ski slope!
That Kaito is pretty popular.
I wonder what'll happen with those two.
And what'll happen with me?
Come to think of it, we enjoy
a hot spring bath, too!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Get Away from Him!
Get Away from Him
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion!