Ladies and gentlemen,
I bring you marvelous illusions that
make this town sparkle at night!
I hope you enjoy the miracle of seeing
the true face of a hated villain.
Find him!
Kid the Phantom Thief has to be
hiding somewhere around here!
This is finally the night I'm gonna
slap iron bracelets on those wrists!
This isn't good...
The forecast called for rain, but I didn't
know it'd be too heavy for my hang glider!
It sounds like you're in a spot
of trouble, Phantom Thief.
U-Um... And who might you be?
Me?
My name is Nightmare.
I'm on your side.
Dark Knight
Nightmare?
You're saying he helped Kid escape,
Superintendent Chaki?
Yes.
The Second Investigation Division
just got a mail about it.
It said, "This time, I'm meeting
Kid the Phantom Thief as a friend.
On next Friday night, the 13th, at 8:00,
the two of us will show you a
nightmare at the Shuho Art Museum."
Who is this "Nightmare"?
A weird guy who wears a mask.
But he partners up with thieves
from all over the world.
He's a mysterious mastermind who takes half
of the loot as his reward for coming up with
the perfect methods and escape route.
Why would Kid team up with him?!
The good news is that any thief who
cooperates with him is invariably caught by
the local police before dawn,
and some have even been
shot trying to escape.
Still clutching their half of the spoils...
So there's a rumor going
around among thieves.
Anyone who works with Nightmare and
safely makes it through the night
will be able to shake off any nightmares of
this world and attain endless good fortune.
I'm sure Kid the Phantom Thief is
blinded by the promise of good fortune.
This way, you'll finally be
set free from Kid.
I mean, right?
Thieves who are singled out by Nightmare
either end up caught or dead.
Although, as a representative
of Japanese law enforcement,
I hope to catch both of them alive
by any means possible.
Japanese...?
Nightmare is an international criminal
who wreaks havoc all over the world.
Naturally, agents will be
coming here with a Red Notice.
Red Notice?
An international arrest warrant seeking
custody of a fugitive criminal,
demanding we turn him over.
You didn't know that?
Then don't tell me these agents
that are coming over...
Yeah. The international police organization.
Interpol.
136 officers in front! 103 officers in back!
185 officers in the main building!
47 officers on the roof!
Six helicopters! Everyone is in place!
All right! Stand by in position
until it's time!
Keep your eyes open!
Excuse me...
Glad you could make it, Interpol!
I'm Nakamori, the guy who's
got this place locked down!
Uh... Kaito-kun?
Right. You called me here...
Oh, right. I wanted you take a look
at my security system here later on.
Like Kid, you're good with tricks.
Check it out with an illusionist's eyes,
then give me your opinion.
Okay...
See you later, then.
I'm counting on you!
Well, that suits me.
Since he's willing to show Kid how his
tricks are done before the show starts.
And what do you find so amusing,
Kid the Phantom Thief?
Just kidding!
A-Aoko?!
What's with that uniform?
I told a member of the riot squad
that I wanted to try on the uniform
sometime, and he lent me a spare!
Don't tell my dad, okay?
I actually wanted to show him, too...
Him?
Hey!
Are you gonna fight the bad guy, too?
Yes, that's right.
I'll capture him, then
pound some sense into him.
Because evil musn't be
allowed to prosper!
Then you're on the same side
as Papa! Good luck!
"Papa"? Who are you?
I'm Kenta Connery.
Papa is Chuck Connery.
He's been on the trail of that bad guy,
Nightmare, for the longest time!
He's got an important job with Interpol!
I apologize for arriving late.
This is the additional material on Nightmare
I was telling you about on the phone.
B-But I didn't think you'd be coming alone...
I have people standing by outside.
We're just here to cooperate
with you, the local police.
We don't have the right to make an arrest.
At any rate, you speak Japanese very well.
My wife is Japanese.
Although she passed away three years ago...
Papa!
K-Kenta!
Shoot! Dad!
What are you doing here?
I slipped out of the home since I knew
you were coming back to Japan!
"Home"?
Ever since my wife passed, I've had
an orphanage take care of him.
I travel all over the world for work,
so I can't raise him properly.
Kenta, you "slipped out"?
I'm sure they're worried about you!
It's fine! I said I was gonna
stay with you at your hotel.
But I don't know what to do.
I don't have time to drop him
off at the home.
I have to go back?
Then shall I take him back?
She's a quick-change artist now?!
Um, who is this?
My daughter, Aoko!
She sometimes brings me dinner
when I'm on the job.
Then please take care of my son.
Sure!
And I'm leaving Nightmare in your hands.
Okay. I'll arrest him, along with Kid.
We've both been carrying heavy baggage for
years, so it'll be nice to finally set it down.
It will.
Well, then...
One question. Frankly speaking,
what's Nightmare like?
That's a good question.
If we're to believe the words
of all his arrested partners,
Nightmare is a cunning demon
who gets into a person's mind,
sees through everything,
and manipulates them.
That's about it.
A demon who manipulates people's minds...
That may be true.
What do you think, Kid the Phantom Thief?
How is the escape route I selected for you?
Worthy of your reputation, Nightmare.
Well, if you know my name already,
that saves us some time.
Next Friday the 13th...
Sorry, but I'm not teaming up with you.
Oh? So this is how you're going to play it?
The rumors were right. You're a lone wolf.
Or actually, you have one associate.
A loyal old man who sometimes
impersonates you and helps you escape.
What?!
Maybe now you understand?
Nothing can escape me.
You are under my constant surveillance.
That's right. Even now.
Nightmare!
So what's the prey?
Nightmare and Kid are after
these earrings, which have
black opals embedded in them.
Dark Knight!
And the jewel is contained in
what I developed to stymie Kid.
My security system!
To open the lid of that hard glass case,
you'd have to remove
these electrified chains.
It's simple yet impregnable, don't you think?
I see.
And what's the liquid in the case?
Water! Black opals' weakness is dryness.
Right, Director Kondo?
Oh, the director said he can't fight on an
empty stomach, so he ducked out for dinner.
The outside length and height are 48 cm.
The diameter inside is 16 cm.
So what do you think of
this system, Kaito-kun?
Well, I don't think it can be stolen.
You'd have to open the lid.
Huh?
Aoko? You're still here?
Well, he insists on "taking down
the bad guy with Papa."
Come on, let's leave this
to your papa and my dad.
Forget it! I'm gonna fight, too!
I'm gonna be like Papa!
Hey, what's wrong?
Are you okay?
I-I'm fine. I have my medicine.
That's a painkiller!
The doctor said I have a
bad guy living in my head
and I need to have surgery...
Surgery?!
But it's all right.
Papa said!
If Nightmare goes away, then he'll be able to
drive off the evil, wild horse in my head!
Then we'll be able to live
together forever, he said!
Oh, are you hungry?
Then why don't we get curry and rice
at a family restaurant?
If you eat some carrots,
maybe the bad horse will quiet down.
O-Okay.
Speaking of horses, did you see him in there?
Who do you keep talking about?
That's strange...
I got a mail saying to let you know
he'd be coming back today.
He said he's looking forward
to seeing you at the scene.
Hey, you don't mean him?!
Are we really going there, Young Master?
It's not only Kid who's showing up tonight,
but I hear some scoundrel with a
dreadful name is also connected.
Did you know this, Baaya?
The symbol of a nightmare is a black horse.
Yes, I knew that.
In chess, the black horse is
a knight that moves second.
So if the starting white knight
doesn't stand on the board,
the game can't begin.
I mean me, Hakuba Saguru.
Between the front, back,
in the main building,
and on the roof, there are
472 riot police officers.
On top of that, there are six
helicopters watching from above.
Yeah, I know.
But where'd you get that information?
Surveillance cameras.
I intercepted footage from the cameras
in the art museum,
and was just going over it now.
Yes. You could say I possess the power to
see all the information the police have.
Normally,
I guide my partner through the
escape route I've pre-selected,
but perhaps you don't need that.
That's right. While I do the stealing,
you can pile up the pillows and take a nap,
Nightmare-san.
Inspector! Director Kondo is back!
Good grief. You're late, Director.
My apologies.
So how are things going?
We were just about to place
Dark Knight into that case.
Wait a moment!
Just in case, I want to
check this one last time.
It looks like there's no problem.
Now I just put the lid back on,
and then we attach the high-voltage
electrified chains.
Whoops! I bumped it.
Maybe it's my age.
Sheesh...
All right! After you attach
the chains, hang it up.
It's all set.
Now, if I can just keep
Hakaba out of the way...
Baaya, why are we taking this street?
Just before, Inspector Nakamori told me this
street was the fastest way to get there.
Baaya, that was Kid the Phantom Thief.
He used the inspector's voice to lead us
to a busy street in order to slow me down.
I was such a fool!
It's okay. He knew the situation wouldn't
be good if I arrived before the crime.
Young Master!
I'll run the rest of the way!
Hello, Nakamori here.
Inspector Nakamori, it's Hakaba Saguru.
H-Hakaba-kun!
Inspector, please tell me
what the situation is there.
Situation? Nothing has happened yet...
Isn't this room a little too dark?
I just adjusted it.
Opals contain around 6-10% water,
and if they dry out, cracks form,
so you have to avoid bright lights.
But like this...
Certainly, when it's dark like this,
you're practically begging
for the opals to be stolen.
Inspector, the lights!
Calm down! Switch to reserve power!
Th-The jewels are gone?!
H-How can it be?!
It's fine. I'm sure they're still inside.
Look. They've slid down the pedestal
and are floating on the water...
They're floating?!
What's going on here?!
An opal's specific gravity
is between 2.10 and 2.13.
There's no way they could be
floating in the water.
Are you telling me they're fakes?!
A-Anyway, I'll examine them, so let's
remove the chains and the lid...
Wait! Don't touch anything
until I get there...
I can't wait!
Dammit!
Th-This is a fake!
D-Damn you, Kid!
Chief Connery! We just received
word that Kid stole the jewels.
No problem. I know Nightmare's pattern.
After running off, the two
of them will rendezvous.
Everyone, follow my orders and act quickly!
Hunt them both down!
Roger!
It's Papa!
Papa was in that car!
Driver, follow that car!
W-What's wrong?
There's something I have to tell Papa!
Someone from the home found a
nice doctor who'll fix my head!
So he doesn't have to worry about me.
He can concentrate on fighting the bad guys!
Please! Let me just tell him that!
Please!
There's no point in investigating now.
Before the theft, Kid switched
the jewels with fakes,
tilted the case when the lights were out,
and made us look like fools
for protecting junk jewelry!
Still, don't you think it's strange?
Normally, with this much
water inside, if you tilt it,
it should leave grime from the center of the
surface to the side where the water rose.
And yet, there's only grime
on the edges of this case.
In other words, the amount
of water was very low.
Hey!
That's...
A transparent acrylic panel.
He attached a small stopper to
all four of the case's corners,
sunk an acrylic panel that would get caught
on them, keeping the depth of the water low.
A depth that would make the jewels look like
they were floating after he tilted the case.
Then the fake jewels the director
examined were actually real...
Inspector! The director is
unconscious in the bathroom!
It's the director!
Kid disguised himself as the director
and made off with the jewels!
Don't let him out of the art museum!
He's probably already discarded that disguise
and flown off somewhere on that
white wing in the night sky.
Crap! Another miss.
That was brilliant, Kid the Phantom Thief.
Oh? I thought we were splitting it 50-50.
Unfortunately, they're not
the jewel I'm looking for.
What do you think of the escape
route I selected for you?
Selected, huh?
You had tons of choices, right?
Because you heard all of the Japanese
police security measures directly.
What?
Isn't that right, Jack Connery of Interpol?
Idiot. I told you already...
I learned of all the security measures
from tapping into cameras
and the police network...
If that's true, why did you
make a counting error?
Counting?
Of the riot police:
136 in front, 103 in back,
185 in the main building, 47 on the roof,
for a total of 471 officers.
You were one over.
That's right. Because you included the
girl who put on the uniform as a lark.
You didn't intercept the
surveillance cameras.
You counted with your own eyes
right there on the scene.
I come across them occasionally
while traveling all over the world.
Stupid local cops
who purposely misreport their numbers to
Interpol out of pride or burning with rivalry.
That's why I always confirm
the numbers with my own eyes,
but it seems that backfired
on me this time.
Wait!
I see.
Any partners who figured out your real
identity were rubbed out by you yourself.
Yeah. But my partners are always thieves,
a plague on their respective countries.
I give credit to the local cops, ensuring
there's no mention of my gun being fired.
Oh.
It seems my people blindly followed my orders
and brought your local police here.
To find your corpse.
You want to help your son so badly
that you would kill for it?
Your son has a complicated cranial disease.
You need money.
When you told him "If Nightmare
disappears, so will your disease,"
you meant you would retire as Nightmare
once you saved up enough for the surgery.
It must be frustrating to have
to give up half every time.
And yet, if you kept all the treasure for yourself,
no one would team up with you again.
You're right!
That's why I have to continue
giving nightmares to thieves!
Wearing this mask!
Papa!
K-Kenta!
That was Papa! I heard Papa's voice!
What are you two doing here?
He said he saw...
Kenta-kun!
Let them go!
Let the jewels go and grab
my arm with both hands!
I can't! This is Kenta's...
Kenta's surgery!
Papa!
I'm gonna be like Papa!
Ken...
What the hell?
He fell trying to protect the jewels?
Given that he's holding Kid's glove,
it looks like Kid was trying
to save him from falling.
The two of them had a falling out
and escaped, huh?
Throwing the treasure aside...
No. He stole it.
For his son's sake.
That's the nightmare called truth.
A sad man who lost his life for
the sake of his beloved son.
But the ironic thing is this finally
freed him from that nightmare.
I wish you happiness, Kenta.
See you next illusion.
Old man Jirokichi from the Suzuki Group
has challenged me again because
he never learns his lesson.
The treasure's location is the
middle of a pedestrian mall!
All right, how can I steal it?
Of course, that pint-sized
detective will be on my case,
so I'll have to knock his socks off with
magnificent magic while I steal it!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Kid Versus Conan:
Teleportation Under the Moonlight
Teleportation Under the Moonlight!
Step right this way. Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion.