Ladies and gentlemen,
I bring you marvelous illusions that
make this town sparkle at night!
Tonight, please enjoy the miracle of
the princess who was like a caged bird!
Welcome to Japan, Princess Anne.
You brought with you a marvelous painting
and jewel from the Duchy of Sabrina.
Yes. I would like to
show them to everyone.
Of course, that includes
Kid the Phantom Thief...
Somebody stop my Belmonde!
Leave it to me!
Shouldn't have run away, Belmonde.
Are you all right, Inspector Nakamori?
Nakamori?
I'm in charge of the princess's
security, so why did you fire?!
Are you the one?
The bumbling inspector who Kid the
Phantom Thief runs rings around.
W-What's that?!
Who the hell are you?!
Europe's number one detective, Delon.
Hey, I've heard of him.
If it looks like the bad guy's
gonna get away, he shoots 'em dead!
Europe's murderous detective, Delon!
Are you listening, Kid the Phantom Thief?!
If you want to have a showdown
with me, steal that jewel!
Th-That's Europe's biggest diamond!
"Lots of Sunshine in Paris"!
Our own Sabrina police will provide
security for the princess.
A-Are you trying to say Japan's
police can't be trusted?!
You want me to trust police who let him
slip through your fingers time and again?
I don't know if he's Japan's Lupin or what,
but watch me catch that sneak thief!
D-Dammit...
The Princess and the Thief's Improv
What?!
Kaito?
Oh...
What are you doing?!
Sometimes you embarrass me.
Why?! There's nothing for you
to be embarrassed about!
What?! Reading the news in class!
You look like an idiot!
I'm sure you were just staring at
the princess from Sabrina, anyway!
The Friendly Princess Anne and Her Cat,
Belmonde, at Press Conference
Wow!
S-She's cute!
You're totally insensitive.
Aoko-kun...
Maybe you're jealous?
N-No! It's my dad...
He's been feeling down lately.
"You got the jewel back,
but Kid got away.
When are you gonna be
able to catch him?"
That's what his boss says.
Dad told me if Kid beats him again,
he may be taken off the task force.
That's why...
A third-rate inspector like your
old man couldn't catch a cold!
Excuse me?! I'm seriously worried here!
Kai-troll!
What, Ass-ko?!
How dare you?! Kai-troll! Kai-troll!
Ass-ko!
Stupid Aoko! Where'd she
get "Kai-troll" from?
You looked bummed out, Inspector.
Oh, Kaito-kun...
As expected, Kid the Phantom Thief
sent an advance notice.
Oh, about the duchy of Sabrina's
jewel exhibition, right?
I saw it on the news.
The Sabrina police have taken
charge of providing security.
If that Detective Delon
makes me look like a chump,
I may be pulled off of Kid's task force!
I see...
If they pull me off his case, I'll... I'll...
But I will get a grip on him!
His activities! His methods! Everything!
Inspector...
I'm sorry, Kaito-kun.
Why am I complaining to you when you
don't have anything to do with it?
That's right! Kaito-kun...
Will you show me a magic trick?
A-A magic trick?
Aoko is always bragging about those.
I have no tricks up my sleeve.
Oh, how amazing!
But it's not, really.
I have no idea how you did that.
You focus attention on your
left hand like this...
...while your right hand is
setting up the next trick.
You do it fast so your audience won't notice.
Basics of being a magician.
Come to think of it, Kid the Phantom Thief
is a magician too, isn't he?
I-I see...
If he's a magician, then he'd also make
everyone look in the wrong place...
Magic tricks aren't sorcery.
There's always a trick to it.
But...
...your feelings of surprise and delight
are genuine, aren't they, Inspector?
Here.
That's a lucky rabbit.
I'm sure something good is
waiting in the wings for you.
Brilliant...
Inspector Nakamori, everyone's in position.
Okay, good work.
But it sticks in my craw.
The Sabrina cops are providing security
inside the building, while we're in the street.
And we're posted in front of a building
that has nothing to do with the exhibition?
This is how I want it.
Okay...
Magicians draw people's
attention to one place...
...while they set up the trick in
another place that no one notices.
If Sabrina's finest police officers keep
security tight like this, he'll never have a chance.
I beg your pardon! My umbrella
flew out of my hands!
Jerk!
Who's the old man?
He gave his name as Count Clover.
They sure shipped enough stiffs in.
Oh, well, that's what I wanted anyway.
Welcome...
...Count Kid the Phantom Thief.
H-How rude!
I'm Clover! And who might you be?!
I beg your pardon.
I'm Delon with the Sabrina Police.
Look at this smug bastard...
Well, go ahead and check me out!
Well, make sure you do your job.
Keep an eye on him.
Yessir!
Inspector Nakamori, maybe we
should get more people out here?
Inspector?
No, we're fine like this.
Don't call for reinforcements.
Y-Yes, sir...
Having more people than we need
is just what he wants.
With fewer people, it'll be harder
for him to pull off a trick.
Could you direct me to the restroom?
What are you doing?!
Help!
Is something wrong?!
It's Kid the Phantom Thief!
Kid the Phantom Thief is here!
It's him! Count Clover!
He changed into my uniform
and went to the exhibit hall!
Dammit! I knew he was that old man...
The exhibit hall! Hurry!
Yes, sir!
Dopes.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I'm gonna borrow this for a bit.
Excuse me.
Crap! He's disguised as a police officer?
This room is full of them!
Emergency! Kid the Phantom Thief is here!
What?!
Detective Delon has ordered everyone
to gather in the exhibit hall!
All right! Got it!
He went to the exhibit hall!
Assemble in the exhibit hall!
Something's strange about this...
It feels like the guards are
multiplying in here by the minute.
Wow, like a cop convention...
Then the princess must be over there...
D-Detective Delon!
What are you doing over here?
He showed up!
I'll watch the princess while you
get over to the exhibit hall!
Yes, sir!
Have a good trip!
We came all this way to Japan, but I
can't even see the sights in Tokyo?
It's no different than being
locked up in a prison cell!
And it's not like anyone
pays me any attention...
Who's there?!
What?! Nobody's here,
not even the guards!
This is negligence on
Detective Delon's part.
I'm gonna tell Dad
when we get home.
Given the circumstances, I wouldn't even mind
a visit from Kid the Phantom Thief.
White, are they?
Who said that?!
A thief.
Kid the Phantom Thief!
Why are all of you in here?!
And you guys, too?! I ordered you
to guard the princess!
But Detective Delon, you said to...
H-Huh?
Dammit! He got us!
Upstairs! He's after the princess's jewel!
I'm glad you could make it.
You're just like Arsene Lupin.
The rumors about you have even
made it as far as my Sabrina!
Please stay a while!
We can play a game!
Hey, hey...
Princess!
I don't have much time.
I must leave after my work is done.
Oh. What kind of work is that?
A one-night-only magic show.
Yes! I know about that.
You're also a magician,
Kid the Phantom Thief.
I wonder what kind of magic
you'll show me.
Oh, you're not the audience
for tonight's show, Princess.
What do you mean?
I would like you to be my assistant.
Assistant? Me?
Yes. I'm sure we could put on a brilliant
performance together, Princess.
What do you say?
Yes! I'd love to!
Then, as the key item
for this magic show...
...I'd like to borrow the jewel you're
wearing as a necklace for the time being.
This?
I'm just going to borrow it
for a little while.
After the show is over,
I'll return it to you.
But my father entrusted me
with this precious diamond.
Please have faith in me.
Thieves don't lie.
Sometimes magicians fool people,
but we don't make people unhappy.
Oh!
Bad kitty!
Get down, Belmonde!
You like cats, huh?
Yes. We even go out
and have meals together!
Fools! We can't all ride at the same time!
So just do it as we prepared.
I'm so excited!
Let the show begin!
It's Kid the Phantom Thief!
That's the princess screaming! Princess!
Delon! Q-Quick!
He jumped out that window!
What the hell?!
Kid's made his move.
Inspector, let's head over there!
Don't lose your nerve! Just make
sure everyone stays in position!
Got it? Two people at every exit.
We can nab him like that,
even without a small army!
R-Roger!
Scary dude...
You messed up, Kid the Phantom Thief.
That jewel shines even in the darkness.
Delon, you're a beast! How could you
shoot someone right in front of me?!
It's okay, Princess!
I'm immortal!
I probably hit the diamond, didn't I?
Well, that does prove my aim was right on.
Crap...
All right, you men leave the room.
He has a talent for blending
into a crowd of police officers.
I'm going to take my time with you.
What's this?
There?!
H-How...?
Do you know which is the
real one, Detective Delon?
Dammit! I don't know which one
is coming from him!
W-What is this?
Kid!
Shhh!
I've achieved a wonderful illusion
thanks to you, Princess.
It's our co-production, right?
By the way, Kid, what is this?
Cyalume.
It glows green when you bend it.
By the way, Princess, what's that?
I think it looks cute.
Making a fool out of me!
You have wonderful taste, Princess.
Wait. That diamond...
I'll share something before I finish this.
That diamond has a special cut.
When light hits it, it reflects
the shape of a cross!
Idiot.
Princess, please hide in here for a while.
I won't see you again, will I, Kid?
The curtain has closed.
But it was a fantastic show
thanks to you, Princess.
It looks like we both have the
talent to entertain people.
I can... entertain people?
Yes. It's a waste of your talent to
just leave people waiting to be entertained.
The next time we meet, I'd love
to perform together again.
Sure!
Oh, that's right.
White is nice and pure, Princess.
Oh!
Princess!
Detective Delon fell out the window!
Where's Kid?!
He ran off that way! Please catch him!
I'm pretty good at this, even on my own.
This isn't the one, either.
Inspector! We can't let them
get ahead of us...
Calm down! Charging mindlessly
is what he wants us to do!
They're focusing on the floor with Princess Anne's
bedroom and the surrounding floors.
That means he's already out of there.
Because he's a magician!
I saw Kid the Phantom Thief!
Princess Anne! Where is he?!
In my room!
I'm going to take shelter in the annex!
He's up there?
Well, I'll be going...
Wait!
Princess, what happened to your cat?
You're famous for being a cat-lover,
and for always having your cat with you...
Strange, isn't it?
Please, let go of my arm.
Princess Kid!
Grab him! This is Kid!
Everyone! In front of the annex!
Idiot! That's my head!
Impressive, Inspector Nakamori.
I didn't know the princess was fond of cats.
Damn you, Kid!
And on top of that, you ambushed me here.
Unlike another detective I know,
who uses his gun instead of his brains.
You're making my job a lot harder
than it should be.
I hope they take you off my case.
Yeah! I'll catch you right now
and end the case tonight!
That's not gonna happen! Farewell!
He disappeared!
Dammit...
It must've fallen out of
my pocket in the crush...
Th-That's "Lots of Sunshine in Paris"!
You grabbed it away from him
during the pile-on, huh?
That's our Inspector Nakamori.
Y-Yeah...
Kid the Phantom Thief Goes Empty-handed!
Our Own Inspector Nakamori Recovers the Stolen Jewel
from Kid the Phantom Thief!
That damned dirty old man!
Kid got away, but Dad managed to
corner him and take the diamond back.
He says they're treating him like a hero!
Shut up! The truth is, I...
I...
You're what?
I... I...
Kuroba Kaito
I'm Kuroba Kaito.
What an idiot...
Did you enjoy tonight's show?
The exploits of my charming assistant
were a highlight, weren't they?
Well, see you next illusion.
Nakamori commandeered
the last preview,
which was totally out of line!
I'm back in the saddle this time,
though, so you can relax.
Anyway, my next heist is a challenge from
Jirokichi of the Suzuki conglomerate.
Of course, I have no choice
but to take it on.
I'm positive he's involved
in it some way, too.
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Kid vs Conan: Miraculous Airwalking
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion!