This is one of Kid's announcements?
Go ahead and rack your brains,
you modern-day Sherlock Holmes.
Kid, Conan, and the Ryoma Treasure Illusion
Kid the Phantom Thief announced that he'll
return Ryoma's treasures at 8:00 pm tomorrow.
Already, over a hundred people are
gathered outside the Suzuki Museum,
hoping to catch a glimpse of him!
Suzuki Museum
Wow! I wanna go there, too!
Kid                                                               Kid
Forget about it. It's dangerous.
I agree. Stay away from there.
Well, that's unusual.
For you to be worried about me...
I-I never said I was worried!
Still, it's a chance to see the genuine
Kid the Phantom Thief in the flesh.
Suzuki Museum
Will Kid really show up tomorrow?
Why is Kid, a phantom thief,
going to return stolen treasures?
And why is he going to do it tomorrow?
Space reserved for Kid the Phantom Thief
to return treasures
The mystery just keeps getting deeper.
It really is a mystery.
But if he's going so far out of
his way to return what he stole,
maybe it means he regrets the theft.
There's no way that villain
feels a shred of remorse!
I'm gonna catch that bastard
for sure this time!
And why does it have to be tomorrow?
At first, he just said it would be "soon."
Then he suddenly announced
it'd be tomorrow, right?
The reason, Aoko,
is that it's going to rain tomorrow!
He was waiting for the rain!
Did you really come up with
that yourself, Inspector?
O-Of course!
That's what my instincts as a detective say!
So Kid was waiting for the rain
before setting the day and time?
Yeah! It looks like it could rain any minute now,
and tomorrow's forecast calls for rain.
That's amazing, Dad!
So why does it have to be a rainy day?
W-Well, maybe it has to do with the
"washing" he mentioned in the letter.
Or maybe because it's easier to blend in
with with an umbrella and raincoat?
I dunno...
So it was just a gut feeling, huh?
N-No! That boy...
I-I mean, boy, a crimefighting
pro like me knows...
Boy...
So it did come from him...
But I don't know if Kid would base the date
and time of a crime on something so simple.
I pointed that out, too...
And there's one more thing.
I can't believe Kid would do this
just to return the treasures.
What do you mean?
Tarumi, the exhibition sponsor,
and Hanamura, the appraiser, had an idea.
They suspect Kid will make it look
like he's returning the treasures,
only to steal Ryoma's gun belt,
the main attraction of the exhibition.
If it's such a pain, you should just
have them cancel the exhibition.
I can't do that.
Why not?
That Tarumi guy is strongly
opposed to the idea.
Why?
When it means Kid could steal the
most important treasure of the bunch?
Isn't that weird behavior for a sponsor?
Yes, it is...
Especially since their exhibits have apparently
been plundered by thieves several times.
I see. So Tarumi and Hanamura are disciples
of that Gozu guy who tried
to kill me last time.
But I hope you'll finally be able
to catch him this time, Dad!
Yeah! Leave it to me!
I've got a gas mask prepared just in case,
and we've decided on a code word
that'll trip Kid up if he's in disguise.
We even installed metal detectors,
since Kid will be carrying that pistol.
We'll be celebrating by this time tomorrow!
Thanks for the precious
info as always, Inspector.
But I still wonder what he meant
by "washing" in his notice.
That's probably just a play on Ryoma's words.
I don't know about that.
I don't think Kid the Phantom Thief
is that simple.
I don't think a pro thief would go to all
the trouble just to return stuff, either.
My guess is that
he's got some other purpose.
Another purpose?
Rain... washing...
Maybe they're hinting at something.
Although I'm not Kid, so what do I know?
One at a time!
Please step through the gates one at a time.
Next person, please!
Don't push!
Look!
Kid?!
Isn't that Kid?!
It's Kid!
Kid-sama!
Hey, Sonoko!
Ow!
What's the problem?! I should be able
to wear what I want!
Creep...
He doesn't look anything like the real deal.
In the first place, Kid would never
just stroll through the gates.
Don't be too sure.
But anyway, I'm not that fat.
Where's Kid?!
Okay...
Let the game begin.
Space reserved for Kid the Phantom Thief
to return treasures
Sheesh. They sure were polite
to reserve me a space.
Like the moniker goes,
Kid is a "phantom" magician.
Space reserved for Kid the Phantom Thief
to return treasures
I'm not gonna follow your guidelines...
There's no way he'll show up, right?
Space reserved for Kid the Phantom
Thief to return treasures
What's wrong, son?
I'm talking about Kid the Phantom Thief.
A phantom thief wouldn't appear
where they tell him to.
I'm sure you're right about that.
Damn cosplayer.
Thinks this is a convention...
Conan-kun, there's something that bothers me.
What is it?
I can't picture Kid, a thief, just coming
to return treasures that he stole.
I suspect he has some ulterior motive.
An ulterior motive?
Rain... washing...
Maybe those are major clues.
Did you really come up with
that by yourself, Inspector?
O-Of course!
Little bastard...
Don't tell me he's on to me!
Phantom Lady...
The length is 17 centimeters,
so that's about...
About this size?
June 24th, 1867.
Ryoma mentioned this pistol in a
letter to his older sister, Otome.
"It's 17 centimeters and holds five bullets.
It's smaller than a dagger, but can
kill a man from 90 meters away."
K-Kid!
Dammit!
How'd you smuggle that in?
Did you go through the gates?
Yeah. All I had to do was remove the lead
from the grip and waltz right through.
It's really light this way, too!
Although lugging this many of them
was a pain in the neck.
I'll tell you one thing. This time, I really
did come just to return the stolen goods.
So don't get in my way, Great Detective.
See ya!
Hey, wait! Dammit!
Please don't push.
Walk slowly.
Where's Kid?
Hey!
R-Ran-nee-chan!
Sorry.
I thought you could get crushed
in this crowd, Conan-kun.
Imagine what it'll be like
by the time Kid announced.
Huh? There's something on your right arm.
No way!
It looks like writing.
"Iron One"?
Is that some kind of secret code?
Say, did you bump into something
in the exhibit room?
Yeah. I was pushed against the
case of the gun belt exhibit.
Hey, come on. Give me a
little more time here.
Still, I wonder how
Kid the Phantom Thief will appear.
Well, it's something to look forward to.
He isn't our enemy.
He's a colleague.
Since he's an accomplice...
You two look really happy.
Even though Kid may be coming to
steal your precious treasures.
W-What are you talking about, young man?
We're not happy at all.
That's right. And besides, he's not
coming to steal treasures tonight.
He's coming to return them.
I wonder if that's really it.
What else would he do?
If he stole something, the police would
be on him like that and it'd be over.
Maybe Kid won't be the one
who's arrested this time.
Take good care of that ring.
Handicraft Corner
Who is that brat?!
Little turd...
Looks like he's figured it out, too.
Just you wait.
I'll give your filthy natures
a good washing!
How's the entrance?
Sir! Nobody's turned around and left
when they saw the metal detectors.
Are there any problems
at the metal detectors?
No. And no one's come through
carrying that pistol.
What's going on in the
Ryoma exhibition room?
At the moment, no one who
looks like Kid is around,
but I wonder if he's even
going to show up at all.
Dumbass!
Kid has never announced an
appearance and then blown it off!
Five more minutes until
the time he announced...
When the show starts, I'm counting on you...
...Jii-chan.
It's just too bad that I won't
get to see the wonderful show.
Well, ladies and gentlemen...
It's showtime!
It looks like Kid did have
another motive, after all.
What do you mean?
I think you'll find out soon.
Hey! Where are you going?
Kid may show up any time now!
I'm just an elementary school student.
I'll leave Kid to you police.
Besides, I don't wanna get wet.
Get wet? What is he talking about?
Anyway, there are too many people in here.
Security isn't worth a damn
when it's like this.
H-Hey, ma'am!
Cut it out! Don't touch me!
Oh, my! I'm sorry!
You look like my deceased husband!
What the hell was that?
K-Kid the Phantom Thief!
Kid-sama, you're so cool!
He's standing on the gun belt case!
What were you talking about, "washing"?!
We'll catch you and wash you to the bone!
That's the idea. But to wash
something, you need water.
Observe as I make it rain in this one room!
R-Rain?!
Son of a... He used fire
to activate the sprinklers!
And now I shall take my leave.
Hey, wait! I thought you were
gonna return those three items!
This shower will make everything clear.
Just as rain washes away muddy water.
C-Can't see him with the steam...
That villain! He must have tampered
with the sprinkler's water pressure!
Kid...
...disappeared.
The exit is this way.
It's very crowded, so please
proceed slowly towards the front.
Footprints!
Follow wet footprints
that go through the gate!
B-But there are wet footprints
all over the floor!
W-What?!
I see...
That's why he waited for a rainy day.
Well, that's not the only reason.
Then what about the three items
he said he was gonna return?!
He left them on top of the gun belt case.
Oh, this is no good. My blood got on it.
But it seems that all three were just
replicas, so there's no problem.
The problem is this gun belt...
Wha...?!
The security system inside
the case has been destroyed!
Then the gun belt inside is a fake that
Kid switched out with the real one?!
Dammit!
He got us!
The explanatory plaque on that case...
Something's dripping from it.
Paint...
I see!
This gun belt was a fake all along.
They made a large quantity of them on
the assumption that they would be stolen.
He stuck a duplicate plaque with the same
message in watercolor paint over the original,
so when water hit it, the paint would run,
revealing the secret message underneath.
All right, Inspector. After
the washing comes the drying.
So put these two clowns out
to dry! I'm counting on you.
I see! My sleeve was wet
from the rain outside...
So the watercolor letters on the gun belt
explanation plaque came off reversed on you!
So? What's this secret message underneath?
Let's see...
"This gun belt was a fake all along..."
They made a large quantity of them on the
assumption that they would be stolen. Right?
The important part was that the thefts
made news and got a lot of attention.
Ryoma Relics Stolen!
So they mass-produced replicas
of the items beforehand
and used third parties to sell them
to wealthy Ryoma fans,
who were all told they were getting the item
that was stolen the other day.
The beauty of this scheme is that even if
the buyers realize later they bought a fake,
they can't report it.
If they filed a complaint, they'd have to
admit they secretly bought stolen merchandise.
That's why Phantom Lady's crime didn't come
to light after those three items were stolen.
Then she entrusted you with all
the replicas she'd collected
and asked you to expose
those two con men, right?
The crime would need both an exhibition
sponsor who knew they were fakes
and a crooked appraiser who would claim
those replicas were the real thing.
Isn't that right?
Ryoma poseur phantom thief!
Hey! Is the message on this plaque true?
N-No! It's bull!
In the first place, where is this
so-called "large quantity" of fakes?
All I see are this light
pistol made out of plastic,
a counterfeit sake cup,
and a phony letter!
I-Inspector!
I-I just noticed I'm wearing
this gun belt with the pistol!
M-Me too!
A card on the belt says, "Borrowed
from Tarumi-shi's warehouse"!
Blast you, Kid! He used the crowd
to slap belts around all our waists!
I see...
You sabotaged the security system yourself
to make it look like the belt was stolen
and then afterwards sold copies of it.
No...
Inspector!
This exhibit also has a plaque with a
message under the washed-away paint.
What?!
The materials used are new and the method of
production is modern, so in conclusion, this
hanging scroll can't be from the Bakumatsu period.
- Kid the Phantom Thief
"Pull," it says...
He wants me to pull on this scroll?
W-What's this?!
Ryoma's letter!
And they're all multiple
copies of the same one!
They look exactly the same as the
one left on the gun belt case.
I-It's a setup!
Kid set us up!
That's right! There's no proof that
we made and sold these forgeries!
Hey, Sonoko!
I just did what Kid's plaque said.
The materials used are new and the method of
production is modern, so in conclusion, this
vase can't be from the Bakumatsu period.
- Kid the Phantom Thief
"Crush."
Hey. There's a ton of sake cups inside.
It looks like each one
of them has blood on it.
If we run a DNA test on the blood, it will
become obvious who fabricated these cups.
Will you lie like before and say you
touched them all with a wounded finger?
You wiped your own blood
on all of these cups.
Well, I'm sure we'll find plenty of evidence
when we search your warehouse.
Probably a mountain of unsold fakes.
I'm surprised you figured out I was Kid.
I look like a middle-aged guy
you'd see anywhere.
It was simple.
Even fake plastic pistols take up a lot
of space if you carry them together.
And even more so if you've also got
a bunch of letters and sake cups.
So I looked for somebody in the crowd
who had an especially slim lower half
compared to the rest of their body.
I found you, pretending to be fat so
you could hide all those replicas.
And of course, you're in disguise,
so there's no sweat to be seen.
So I stuck this button-sized transmitter
sticker to your skinny ankle.
I located your position with my tracking
glasses and called out to you.
So? Are you gonna turn me over
to the police?
No.
This time I'll let you go,
out of deference to Ryoma.
Are you a Ryoma fan?
My mom is.
She once played Ryoma's big sister, Otome,
and fell madly in love with Ryoma.
But the reviews called her too cute to play
Otome, which turned out to be a career boost.
Well, it sounds like we're
both no match for our moms.
See ya.
Both?
Hey, don't tell me...
Is Phantom Lady...
Sorry, Aoko.
Thanks to me getting the runs, I was holed up
in the museum bathroom the whole time.
And you stayed with me, so you didn't get
to see Kid the Phantom Thief, either...
That's okay. Anyway, he's probably just some
middle-aged fat guy who looks like a thug.
I'm not that fat!
I can say that now, at least.
Well, until we meet again.
Be sure to follow the adventures of
that pint-sized great detective, too.
See you next illusion!
That means it's almost Christmas!
I intended to spend a quiet
Christmas Eve at home,
but Aoko's gonna have a party and
wants me to help her with it!
And what's this? Kid has sent out
another advance notice?
It sure as hell wasn't me!
I wanna take a break that night!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Holy Night: Two Kid the Phantom Thieves
Holy Night: Two Kid the Phantom Thieves!
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion!