Thank you, everyone, for your
support of Magic Kaito last year.
Now then, ladies and gentlemen...
Best wishes for a...
...Happy New Year!
Please keep watching this year, too!
Move!
Hey!
Yahoo!
Ow...
Idiot!
Would you knock it off, already?!
How many times have you
crashed into me today?!
I'm not doing it on purpose!
I'm a beginner!
Then ski over there!
Jeez, you suck!
Why'd you even come?
Excuse me?! I'm trying my best here!
Whoop it up while you still can,
Kuroba Kaito!
This is the day you become my captive.
But still, Nakamori Aoko...
...is a nuisance.
Get Away From Him
Welcome
Everyone from Egota High School
All right, everyone.
Welcome
You have half a day left to ski.
A fun event awaits you this evening!
A "fun event"?
Nobody said anything about that!
It's a masquerade ski tournament!
You find a partner and
ski together as a couple!
No way...
Are you serious?
Sensei, can't girls partner with girls?
Forget it!
When I say "couple," I mean a boy and a girl!
On the slope at twilight,
making trails side by side...
In your own little world...
Konno-sensei, did you eat a
mushroom you found on the slope?
Shush. You can't interrupt
at a time like this.
That's right. Girls hold on to an innocent
romantic streak, no matter how old they get.
Cold snow all around you...
But the light of love that flares up
between the two of you melts it all away!
Snow White Paradise
I understand, but you can be
romantic without being delusional!
W-Well, I admit she is
going a little too far...
I have a feeling Konno-sensei was
really lonely in high school.
I bet this will be the first page
in the springtime of your life!
How romantic!
I can't believe I came up
with this brilliant idea!
What's with the "masquerade" bit?
Just skiing is no fun, right?
Of course I've prepared a delightful
present for the best couple.
Now she's talkin'!
What?! We get a prize?!
Really?!
You might want to spend some time
working on your costume,
and that's all I have to say!
A partner...
A partner?
Hey, I heard the hot spring here is co-ed!
I know, I know!
Like I'm gonna pair up with a
crappy skier like you, dumbass!
Nakamori-san, got a minute?
Akako-chan?
Nakamori-san, you've got a
crush on Kuroba-kun, don't you?
N-Not especially!
Is that right?
I like him.
Kuroba-kun isn't the
simpleton you think he is.
He's more mysterious, more...
The point is, he isn't a good
match for your mediocrity.
Why don't we make a bet?
Which of us will he pair up with for this
evening's masquerade ski tournament?
Whoever loses has to keep away from...
N-Nakamori-san?
After all, it's ridiculous!
A beautiful girl like you
with a crush on Kaito!
I can't figure out why he's so popular.
Tell me, what do you like about him?
You can tell me!
There's nothing in particular...
Anyway, it's on!
Akako-chan is cute when she blushes.
I see. So she likes Kaito...
I had no idea.
I envy Akako-chan...
She can ski with Kaito...
Fujie-kun?
Akako-sama!
Fujie-kun, you like Akako-chan, huh?
She sure is a beauty.
But I don't stand a chance with her.
I'm a fat wallflower who can't ski.
Akako-sama can only be
the girl of my dreams...
In fact, I doubt there's
anyone out there for me.
That's... That's not true!
But...
Okay, then.
Why don't we ski together?
We're both lousy, but let's
do our best. All right?
B-But what about Kaito?
He's got nothing to do with it.
I'm sure he'll be with Aka... I mean...
He'll pair up with a good skier.
You're as good as ever, Kaito.
Eat my dust!
See you!
What the hell?
Oh, Kuroba-kun.
Hi, Akako.
I'm not surprised.
You're a wonderful skier.
This girl rubs me the wrong way...
Ouch...
I wiped out again.
Hey, Aoko...
Kaito...
I see you're as uncoordinated as ever.
Oh, shut up!
By the way, you haven't decided yet, right?
Decided what?
You know, for that pair
tournament thing this evening.
I can't leave you out in the cold.
So I'll pair up with you.
Oh, I heard that Nakamori-san
is going to be with Fujie-kun.
Akako-chan...
Is that true, Aoko?
Th-That's right.
Then I guess that's out...
Yeah.
The lift's here.
See you later, Nakamori-san!
It couldn't be helped.
What's the matter? You've been
sulking since we got on here.
I'm not sulking.
You will pair up with me, won't you?
Yeah, whatever.
Look! This ski outfit is cute, isn't it?
Say, Kuroba-kun...
Yeah, whatever.
Getting caught up with that girl would ruin
even Kid the Phantom Thief's reputation!
I don't know what you're talking about.
We could always pair up for good, you know.
Is this girl serious?!
Okay, okay!
We'll be partners, all right?
You're cute.
It seems the heart sticker
I slapped on his back is working.
It's a charm that makes the person
you put it on be your partner.
Eventually, you'll be mine, heart and soul.
This girl's got a screw loose...
Boring...
Just sitting around...
Nobody else is here!
That's great! Like it's reserved for us.
Yeah!
But this is a mixed hot spring, right?
It's okay!
When I checked before, it was empty.
It's so big!
Aoko, I see you're still
flat as two pancakes up top.
Oh, leave me alone!
A-Aoko! Th-This isn't good!
Don't worry about it! A lot of guys
actually have a flat chest fetish.
What?!
Hey, somebody's over there!
I think you mean me!
How cute! A husky voice!
Oh, it's a girl!
Thank goodness!
I just got an eyeful...
Yeah, right?
Come to think of it, why
didn't you and Kaito pair up?
Well, after all, I'm terrible at skiing.
That's your reason?
Kaito hates being around incompetent people.
If we skied together, I'd only embarrass him.
Kaito is always clowning around, right?
So as his childhood friend,
I want to make him look cool once in a while.
So this way is fine.
No, it's not!
It ain't fine!
It's not fine!
Okay, everyone!
Are you ready?
What?!
Kid the Phantom Thief?!
Does it look good on me?
Then I'm sure Aoko is...
Kid and Inspector Nakamori
are gonna win for sure!
Nyuk nyuk nyuk!
That's how your Dad laughs?
Yep.
Like you would know.
Oh, Kaito-kun...
Cute sticker.
Dammit! Akako must've stuck it on me!
Akako-sama's...
Lucky...
Don't tell me you've got a thing for Akako?
Huh?
Yay!
Okay!
All right, let's get started!
Everyone, line up!
Kannou-san is into it more than anyone.
Even though she doesn't ski herself...
And who are those people?
Asuka Barber
A-1 Women's Club
Yuhi Liquor Store
Mato Orthopedic Clinic
The judges of this masquerade
ski tournament are
local merchants I found
walking around town!
I'm impressed she snagged them.
Hey! Keiko!
What kind of costume is this?!
Your ribbon is crooked!
They'll think I'm gay!
So what?
She's impressive, too.
Idiot!
And now, let's begin the
masquerade ski tournament!
Entry number one!
Mr. and Mrs. Polar Bear!
So-so.
Not enough tricks!
3, 1, 3, 2...
That's 9 points!
Next up, entry number two!
The One-inch Boy!
Oh, dear...
Asuka Barber
A-1 Women's Club
Yuhi Liquor Store
Mato Orthopedic Clinic
The bowl overturned.
Unfortunately, only 5 points!
Entry number three!
Astronauts!
The Town Musicians of Bremen!
Titanic!
Ikkyu-san and the Folding Screen Tiger!
Masked Yaiba and Laser Police!
Alice Through the Looking-Glass!
Go!
Huh?
Where did Fujie-kun go?
Nakamori-san...
It seems I've won.
Entry number 83!
The Snow Queen and the Abominable Snowman!
Good luck, Kaito.
Let's go, Kuroba-kun.
Observe our magnificent skiing!
Kaito, why?
Why didn't you ask me earlier?
10, 10, 9, 10!
An impressive 39 points!
This could be our winning duo!
K...
Kaito, you're an idiot!
Sorry about that.
I mean, for being an idiot.
Kaito...
Where's Fujie-kun?
He's with the object of
his affection, Akako-sama.
We got an amazing score, Kuroba-kun!
A-Akako-sama and I...
But can't you do something
about that outfit?
At least...
...do something like this!
Come on!
Kaito, you're like the real Kid...
Dumbass! I'm cooler than the real deal.
But what are we gonna do? I can't ski.
Don't worry. You don't have to.
Hold still.
Okay.
Entry number 84! Kid the Phantom Thief
and Princess Nakamori!
All right, here we go!
That's...
...Kuroba Kaito!
He's dressed up as his alter ego...
That boy knows no fear!
Th-Then who are you?
Akako-sama!
Okay, here we go!
Heave-ho!
Now!
One more!
Oof!
10, 10, 10, 10!
A perfect 40 points!
The winners, from class 2-B,
Kuroba Kaito and Nakamori Aoko!
You really are clumsy!
Well, excuse me!
You'll never be able to catch me like that,
Inspector!
He did it to me again!
But I won't give up!
Dad, I'm home!
Here's your souvenir from the ski lodge.
Winning Prize
Masquerade Ski Tournament
What the hell is this?
Winning Prize
Masquerade Ski Tournament
In a winter wonderland, a witch used
a spell to bind people's hearts,
while an illusionist presented
identity-switching magic tricks.
But was the illusionist who made
a deep impression on the girl
under the moonlight
real or an impostor?
Well, see you next illusion!
I let Aoko narrate last episode's preview,
but she did a terrible job!
I've really gotta do it myself.
So the next setting is aboard a train.
I'm after a queen's jewel,
but she's a formidable opponent.
And her son, the prince,
is pretty sharp for a squirt!
He reminds me of someone else I know!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Crystal Mother!
Crystal Mother
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion!