Ladies and gentlemen!
I bring you miraculous illusions
that will make the night sparkle!
Tonight, I present to you one of my days off.
The Angel's Crown is mine tonight.
Kid the Phantom Thief!
What are you doing?!
Shine it in his face!
C-Crap!
Y-You're...
It's bright!
D-Dammit!
Inspector! There's a note on your back!
When did he...?
"For tonight, I bid you adieu.
However, I shall return
next Sunday at 8:00 pm
to abscond with the Angel's Crown.
Kid the Phantom Thief."
M-Make a monkey out of me, will he?!
Still, I know that face...
Yeah. I'm sure of it!
Kaito Kuroba's Busy Day Off
Stare...
Both of you, stop eating so sullenly!
The least you could do is tell me
if the food is any good!
If it wasn't any good, it's not like
I could just come out and say it.
So you're trying to tell me
it isn't any good!
Well, your hamburger steaks always...
Look!
They always crumble into little bitty pieces!
That's an awful thing to say!
After I cooked dinner for you!
I'm gonna tell Chikage-san what you said!
Um, do I have something on my face?
Oh, Kaito, you're like a little kid.
What is it?
N-N-Nothing...
Thanks for dinner.
Hey, you've still got food on your plate!
I'll have it for breakfast tomorrow.
Jeez. What's he talking about,
"crumbling into pieces"?
You two are like a married couple.
Don't say that!
What makes me seem like
that jackass's wife?!
Don't tell me you two
go out on dates?
Huh? Of course not!
What, you're suspicious of us, Dad?
So that's why you were
staring at Kaito tonight.
That's not it.
Then why?
Kaito-kun is...
Kaito is...?
...Kid the Phantom Thief!
That's just silly!
No, I'm sure of it. I saw his face!
And Kaito-kun performs magic, too...
All the more suspicious...
Dad...
Kid the Phantom Thief's note claims he'll
appear again next Sunday. I'll prove it then.
Shut up!
There's no way Kaito is
Kid the Phantom Thief!
On what grounds?
Grounds?
After all, Kaito is...
Kaito-kun is what?
...going on a date with me next Sunday!
W-W-What?!
What?! Are you gonna
make me say it again?
Go on a date with me!
What is this? Some kind of gag?
Do you accept or not?
W-Who would go out on a
date with a dog like you?
I know... I know that...
But please!
S-Sure...
Really?! Then let's make it next Sunday!
At Tropical Land!
That's a promise!
W-Wait a second!
I shall return next Sunday at 8:00 pm
Sunday's when I'm supposed to appear...
I can't believe you asked him
out on a date, Aoko!
You must really like Kaito-kun.
As if I like that jerk!
I didn't do it because I want to
go on a date with him!
It's my dad...
That's right. This is Dad's fault.
Suspecting Kaito of being
Kid the Phantom Thief...
That's not possible... right?
You were peeping in the girls' locker
room again, weren't you, Kaito-kun?!
Gulp!
You pervert!
You shouldn't use such a cheap lock!
It's not like I was peeping.
I heard somebody saw a rat, so I thought
I'd hunt it down for you, is all!
Come back here!
You're the rat!
He is suspicious...
Blue Parrot
The inspector suspects you?
Yeah!
I think he saw my face when
I was on the job last night.
He was staring at me all
through dinner this evening.
I see...
And maybe it's not only him,
but Aoko, too...
Aoko-san too?
After all, she suddenly insisted
that we go on a date next Sunday!
Next Sunday is when...
...I said I'd steal the Angel's Crown!
I see. I'd be careful if I were you.
They say there's nothing scarier
than a woman's intuition.
That's a pretty heavy remark
coming from you, Jii-chan.
Are you speaking from experience?
I'll tell you about it someday.
More importantly, Young Master,
I've prepared the props you requested
for your next magic show.
Thank you.
And this, too...
What is it?
Gotcha.
With that, you should be able
to make it through the night.
I just hope I can pull it off.
Hey, Dad, what do you think I should do?
Listen, Kaito,
and listen well.
As the famous magician Al Baker once said,
"Don't run away before they chase you."
"Don't run away before they chase you"?
What does that mean?
If given a chance, the audience
will begin to doubt us magicians.
However, if you fear their gaze,
you'll definitely make a mistake.
A first-rate magician never
fears being scrutinized.
I see.
You can trust in your own ability.
Do you understand, Kaito?
Loud and clear, Dad.
No matter what happens,
I won't lose my nerve.
After all, I'm the son of Kaito Toichi,
the greatest phantom thief in the world!
Kaito's late...
It's okay. Aoko doesn't suspect me.
"Don't run away before they chase you."
All I have to do is act normally.
Hi!
Sorry to make you wait.
Kaito...
I knew you would come.
Well, I promised, didn't I? Idiot...
Let's go!
S-Sure!
Look! Those elephants are amazing!
Right?
They're robots.
Oh...
The elephants are welcoming you.
Let's go in here.
You people will never leave this room again.
The painting is stretching!
The room is just being lowered.
Oh...
Welcome to Tropical Land!
How cute!
You smell sweaty!
Kaito...
W-Wait!
Wait up!
Why are you being so mean?!
Look at me!
Here.
Now that's the Aoko I know.
This way is more natural.
Ow!
Yeah, right! You were just being mean.
Why, you...
Nyaah!
D-Dumbass! You gotta eat fish
right in front of me?!
What can I say? I like it!
Take that!
I'll get you for that!
I can't wait to see it!
It's almost time for me
to put in an appearance.
This is the perfect chance to slip away.
The movie's 40 minutes.
As long as I'm back by the end...
Hey, 3D movies give me a headache.
I'll wait outside.
Hold on.
Sorry.
Stay with me... for just a little bit longer.
Aoko...
Come on, let's watch the movie!
Does she know about my other identity?
So the inspector did see my face then.
I'm so excited!
Chill out. Have faith in your own ability.
And now, please enjoy Adventures.
He should be here in ten
minutes! Stay focused!
I've got 34 minutes!
That much time to do the job and get
back by Aoko's side! I've gotta make it!
One more minute!
Hey, do you know where the inspector went?
No...
I-I'm sleepy...
Hurry up! You've got 18 minutes!
Inspector?!
You walked right into it,
Kid the Phantom Thief!
You walked right into my trap!
And now I'll reveal your true identity!
And now I'll expose...
...your real identity!
A-Aoko!
My true identity is... Captain Japan!
I'm a master of disguise!
I can look like anyone!
Inspector Nakamori, I know
everyone who's close to you.
Then you impersonated
Kaito-kun last time...?
And I think I'll be you next time,
Inspector Nakamori.
See you, Dad!
W-Why, you...!
Get him!
Crap! That ate up too much time!
The movie's gonna be over in nine minutes!
If I'm not back by then,
Aoko will realize I'm Kid!
This is the end of you, Captain Japan!
Three minutes!
I'll show you my true power!
90 seconds!
And it's two kilometers away!
I won't make it in time!
Tropical Land Map
3D Movie Adventures
You Are Here
Dragon Coaster Waiting Area
Dragon Coaster...
Turbo Beam!
That's it! Get him!
Yeah! Get 'im!
Enjoy the ride!
30 seconds!
W-Wait a second...
Ow!
Wasn't that exciting?!
Yeah...
Dad?!
Inspector Nakamori,
Metro police fail to capture
Kid the Phantom Thief again...
Oh, just on TV...
what can you tell us about tonight's theft?
Are you watching this,
Kid the Phantom Thief?!
I swear I'll arrest you next time!
I'm glad.
Kaito, you're just Kaito, right?
Wait here a minute.
So to prove my innocence, Aoko,
you put me through the wringer.
Here.
Your favorite ice cream.
Don't act out of character!
Even if this isn't like me, I'm me!
Jeez, you're so cold.
Like ice cream!
But ice cream...
...is sweet.
Kaito, Aoko-chan told me what you said.
That was a very cheesy line.
W-What are you talking about?!
"But ice cream is sweet."
I-It wasn't that bad...
I can't help it. It's funny.
You've reached the age where
you say things like that.
Quit bustin' my chops, Mom!
That reminds me of the first time
your father and I went on a date...
More of your nostalgia?!
Gimme a break!
It was on the Champs-Élysées in Paris.
Your father made reservations
at a very fancy restaurant...
Mom, sorry to interrupt, but there's
a show I wanna catch on TV.
Can we wind this up?
Listen to me! I'm almost done.
I doubt that very much.
Talk to you soon. Goodnight!
Hey! Everything has to be
done at your pace, huh?
Who do you get that from?
From you, Mom, from you...
So anyway, at that restaurant,
the wine was the finest I'd ever tasted...
Well, let's meet again
under the sweet night sky.
See you next illusion!
For some reason, schools at night
have a really creepy atmosphere.
But even though everyone's like,
"There's a ghost!", I don't take it seriously.
So this Phantom will get to
the bottom of that ghostie!
It's childish to try and
expose a ghost story?
Well, see for yourself and decide
whether I'm a kid or an adult!
Adult's Charm
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
Adult's Charm!
Step right this way! Watch carefully!
Don't miss the illusion!