Ladies and gentlemen,
I bring you miraculous illusions that
make this town sparkle at night!
Tonight, please enjoy a different kind
of ending featuring mother and son!
This is Japan's foremost luxury train,
the Royal Express.
Yes. I quite like it.
To be honest, I wanted to reserve the
whole train for you, Your Majesty...
Not at all. I wanted to come in
contact with the Japanese people,
if even just a little bit.
I'm glad I was able to
meet that famous person.
What?! You contact Superintendent
Chaki directly yourself!
Do you mean Inspector Nakamori,
who is in charge of your security?
This is no time for that!
I'm busy! Get it done!
No.
Tell Superintendent Chaki that, too!
I mean the visitor I had
in my private room earlier.
The bandit known as Kid the Phantom Thief.
Crystal Mother
Is that true, Your Majesty?!
Yes.
He appeared to steal the treasure
of the Principality of Ingram.
Europe's biggest topaz,
this Crystal Mother.
Good lord!
Then the advance notice sent
to the embassy was genuine!
But why didn't he take off
with that jewel?
I'm sure he realized it at the first glance.
That this is only a replica.
A replica?!
Yes. I've got the real one
hidden elsewhere.
W-Where is it?!
I can't even tell you that, Inspector.
He could be listening in from
somewhere on this train.
All right! Kid is on this train!
Check every passenger from head to toe!
Yes, sir!
No!
I cannot subject everyone else to
trouble for the sake of Ingram.
But, Your Majesty...
This is a showdown between him and me.
This train will reach Osaka
in two and a half hours.
Will he be able to steal the jewel,
as stated in his notice?
Or will I be able to protect it?
It's a duel with the honor
of my country on the line.
Say, Mother...
Your necklace is a little strange, isn't it?
Phillip!
What a naughty boy!
I told you to stay in the room!
And I've instructed you countless times...
Address me as "Your Majesty"
in front of other people.
Who's this kid?
Prince Phillip.
The son of Queen Selizabeth and King Henry,
who passed away from illness two years ago.
He is the next king of the
Principality of Ingram.
But...
...this replica is different
from the last time I saw it.
Excuse me, Your Majesty...
This is a listening device!
Kid must have planted it in
Her Majesty's room when he slipped in.
Are you listening, Kid the Phantom Thief?!
As long as I'm around, you won't
lay a finger on that jewel!
Well, you certainly have sharp eyes, Prince.
What's wrong, Kaito?
You have a weird expression on your face.
Th-That third-rate inspector...
It's nothing!
Your old man just reamed me!
What are you mad about?
You're the one who wanted to
ride this train, remember?
That's why I asked my dad
to get us tickets...
I know, I know. I'm always
grateful to your old man.
Sheesh! You need an attitude adjustment.
And do it before we meet Her Majesty.
After all, we're on the
same train as a queen!
Aren't we lucky?!
So we'll pay her our respects!
I'll introduce myself as the daughter of
Inspector Nakamori, who always stymies Kid!
Seriously?
What?!
Kid has ignored our warning again
and is targeting another Big Jewel?!
Yes, Boss.
And thanks to his advance notice,
there are even more security guards.
Under the circumstances, I believe it'll
be tough getting the gem before him.
In that case, just steal it from him!
Kill him if you have to!
Understand?
But whatever you do, be careful
how you handle that jewel.
After all, it may contain...
...the stone of life, Pandora,
which can grant immortality!
Yes, sir!
Your Majesty...
Now will you tell me where
you're keeping the jewel?
Without knowing the location, I don't
know where to focus security efforts...
If you're that worried about it,
then stay by my side and protect me.
Let me pour you a drink.
N-No thank you, I can't
drink while on duty...
Oh. This is the first time anyone's
turned down a drink from me, Inspector.
W-Well, in that case,
I'll indulge in just one drink.
European liquor is tops, Your Majesty!
D-Dad?!
He's drinking booze!
Hey!
Your Majesty, this is my daughter,
Aoko, and her classmate, Kaito-kun!
Charming!
I-It's a pleasure to meet you, Your Majesty!
What are you two doin' over here, anyway?
K-Kaito said he really wanted
to meet Her Majesty, right?
That's you...
Don't innerfere with security
by wandering aroun'!
We won't...
Is he supposed to be protecting her?
Ah, well, I've managed to infiltrate
Her Majesty's salon car,
so now I can search
for the jewel all I want.
But where the heck could it be?
I was just in Her Majesty's room a little
while ago, so I doubt she left it in there.
Then maybe it's near her...
In her bag or under her hat...
Or maybe...
The cat?
Don't tell me it's in that cat's eyes?!
Well, well, Kaito!
You've been gazing at Her Majesty!
Idiot! I was looking at the cat!
Her Majesty's cat!
You mean Caesar?
Cute, isn't he? He'll be two this year!
Who're you?
Phillip Maximilian du Ingram!
You mean you're...
...the prince?!
Come here!
Come on!
Here, Caesar.
You wanted to see him, right?
Yeah...
Let me hold him!
Does he hate me?
I guess that's not really possible...
Enough?
Sure...
That's a cute teddy bear.
This?
It was a present from my father!
Huh? One eye is about to fall off.
Let me see it...
Doesn't feel like it's in here, either.
Hey, Mister.
I think you're...
...Kid the Phantom Thief, right?
D-Don't even joke about
something like that!
What, I'm wrong? Too bad, since
I know where the jewel is hidden.
But I'm not gonna tell you!
Little brat...
Prince Phillip, it's dangerous
for you to be out here.
Return to your room, please.
Go on. You heard the man.
I'm not going anywhere!
I'm gonna help Mother
protect the jewel from Kid!
So you're doing it out of
love for your mother...
No, I hate Mother!
She changed after Father died.
She used to be so kind...
...but now, she gets angry and yells
every time she sees me.
She says I never listen.
I know she doesn't love me anymore.
But I made Father a promise.
I promised to protect
the country with Mother.
That's why... That's why...
Mother!
Not "Mother"! You call me "Your Majesty"!
Let go of me! Mother!
Y-Your Majesty!
Mother!
I'd better not see you
out of this room again!
Did you have to be so harsh with him?
It's none of your concern!
This is the only way to
get through to that boy!
Mother!
Wait! Mother!
We'll be arriving in Osaka in ten minutes.
It seems I've won, Inspector.
So where is the jewel hidden?
I'll tell you when we reach Osaka.
I think you'll be surprised,
though, Inspector.
Where is it? Where the hell is it?!
Dammit! If I don't hurry,
I'll miss my chance!
Here, one more.
Oh, boy. Thank you.
Huh? That's strange...
It hasn't changed one bit...
Normally, the form changes...
Thanks a lot!
I've got it! I know where the jewel is!
Where are you going, Kaito?
The bathroom.
See you in a bit!
Sorry, Aoko.
I need you to take a little nap.
I can't be Kid the Phantom Thief
in front of you.
What's going on?!
I-It's a blackout!
It must be Kid!
He's finally showin' up!
Your Majesty!
Don't get the wrong idea!
I was just tryin' to protect Her Majesty...
Forget that, Inspector. Where's your glass?!
My glass?
My glass is over there...
W-What?!
Which one is your glass?
I don't know...
Everyone!
Start looking for it!
Yes, Your Highness!
Y-You mean the jewel was
in my glass with the ice?
That's some audacity...
There!
Crystal Mother is safe!
Kid the Phantom Thief!
It's an honor to see you again, Your Majesty!
Fool.
We're on a train. There's
nowhere for you to escape!
Your Majesty, please remember this.
Kid the Phantom Thief
is an elusive rogue.
And as for you...
Don't forget that you're a mother
with a heart before you're a queen!
Farewell!
W-Wait!
Come back, Kid!
All right, get on the phone and have the
police set up a cordon around the whole area!
We can't let him get away!
Yes, sir!
It sounds like you've still got the
booze in your brain, Inspector.
To be fooled by that dummy...
How gullible can you get?
You're the one who's gullible, Mister!
Give me back the jewel.
The people in my country need it.
So give it back!
You know, brat,
I am impressed you managed
to climb up here by yourself.
I didn't do it by myself.
A man helped me.
He said you were sure to be here
and carried me up.
A man?
Look, the nice man standing
right behind me...
Long time no see, Kid the Phantom Thief.
You!
Unfortunately, I don't have
time to play with you.
Put the jewel down and turn around.
Unless you want me to blow
this kid's brains out...
Don't do it, Mister!
Don't give it...
Quiet! Keep your mouth shut!
This isn't the Pandora jewel you
and your pals are looking for.
What?!
It's true.
I held it up to the moon a minute ago.
Shut up! I'm gonna check it out myself!
Now, turn around!
It's the end of the line for the
immortal Kid the Phantom Thief.
We'll see about that.
Don't underestimate me!
Negishita Tunnel
Hey, are you okay?
Give me back the jewel.
What?!
Is that the attitude you take
with the guy who saved your life?
Without that jewel,
the people in my country will...
Forget it! I'm not giving
it back to any liar.
You're really doing it for
your mother's sake, right?
You wanna return the jewel in
the hope that she'll praise you.
So, am I on the mark?
Yeah...
Then I've got a better way.
A way to confirm your mother's feelings...
I can't believe this is happening...
My country's precious treasure
was stolen because of me.
What will the people say?
Y-Your Majesty...
Mother.
Phillip!
I'm sorry, Mother.
I chased Kid the Phantom Thief onto the
roof and tried to take back the jewel...
...but he got it away from me.
Mother...
Why won't you ever listen to me?
Why do you always pull
dangerous stunts like that?!
What's the point?
With your father gone, why did I harden my
heart and try to give you a strict upbringing?
But...
But thank goodness!
Thank goodness you're safe...
Mother!
Good for you, Prince.
Your mom is the genuine Queen of Hearts.
Listen, a boy mustn't bawl his eyes out.
And as I keep telling you,
refer to me as "Your Highness"!
A magic trick that unlocked
Her Majesty the Queen's heart.
But tonight, I was
no more than the assistant.
The star was a brave little boy.
Well, see you next illusion!
I'm Nakamori with the Metro Police!
And I'm in charge of this preview.
So as for next week's plot,
a Detective Delon from Europe goes over
my head and claims he's gonna arrest Kid!
Of course, this means I've gotta go all out!
Next time on Magic Kaito 1412:
The Princess and the Thief's Improv.
The Princess and the Thief's Improv
Step right...
What is it? I don't get it...
Well, anyway, don't miss my exploits!