Who are you?
It's a secret. A secret.
I can't tell you.
A secret makes a woman, a woman.
Daddy's glasses.
I'm sorry.
Daddy. What's the matter?
Is he already asleep?
He promised to read me a story before going to bed and yet...
Then, will you stay by your father until he gets up?
Okay!
Then, you set fire to my house
and burned everything down to ashes.
All of what my father, as an FBI agent,
gathered behind closed doors,
the investigation data on all of you.
But, I was saved
because after that...
I remembered that there was no more orange juice
that father always drinks upon getting up
and since he was lying down from exhaustion from afternoon
taking care of my mother who wasn't feeling well.
I wanted to be of help and went out shopping.
Oh, so you're the little girl I saw back then!
I really went all out looking for you,
because all that was left from the remains
were the bones of your parents.
My father's colleagues protected me.
They applied for the witness protection program for me.
That stupid system of changing the name and address of a witness
whose life is in danger in order to protect that person
under a different identity.
It must've been really restricting, right?
To live away from your hometown, as a different person.
You went through hard times, didn't you?
And?
You took after your father, and came after me?
FBI agent Jodie Starling?
Just as expected of a witch with a thousand faces, Vermouth.
With your ability of disguise, you can sneak in anywhere
and check on things to your heart's content.
I'm amazed that you saw through the disguise of Dr. Araide.
It's obvious.
Despite of not having that bad of an illness,
you keep frequenting Araide Hospital with no makeup.
You were planning to kill him and become him!
Then you mean that...
the time his car passed right before me with his family
and crashed through the guard rail
eventually sinking into the sea...
was all set up by you?
Yes!
I made it look as if he died of an accident
before you got to kill him.
Because if the car was left at the bottom of the sea
and if nobody knew that he was dead,
it would make it easier for you to go around
acting as Dr. Araide.
Of course,
the people in the car were my colleagues equipped with air pumps.
The real Dr. Araide is living in peace in a place far away.
Then just as we expected,
you established yourself in Araide Hospital
and began checking on something.
It was obvious what you waiting for
the moment we snuck into your room in that hospital.
A picture was poked all over with darts.
The picture of a girl in her 20's with reddish brown hair.
You were planning to find her and get rid of her!
Now I have a question!
The picture of the woman you were trying to get hold of and kill
and this girl that looks just like her.
Of course the witness protection program
will be applied to her but...
Is she really the woman in the picture?
There's still more!
The two pictures that were below her picture,
with the words Cool Guy and Angel that are written on the pictures.
That boy is unmistakably sharp,
but he's more a "kid" than a "guy," isn't he?
Yes. That boy called Conan.
Until that boy left the girl's side,
you didn't do anything.
Inside the bus that was jacked too.
Please don't!
It's just the mischief of a child, isn't it?
Will tell me why you went all out to protect that boy
to the point of almost risking your own life?
If she didn't come around,
things wouldn't have turned out like this.
So...
Nab that person called Vermouth too!
And?
So that name Vermouth, that sounds like the name of some liquor
is probably a fake name, right?
Do you know the person's identity?
You haven't seen that person yourself, either?
No.
Then, what about the receipts of the things
that you received that she used to blackmail you?
Well...
What? No way!
You threw them away?
The address is probably a phony one too.
I guess for now...
until we arrive at the harbor, we'll have to keep him tied up somewhere.
So now, the case is closed.
Come on.
Will you tell me?
Okay!
I'll tell you.
That's...
Don't move!
Gosh.
What a dangerous thing you have there.
Did you get permission from the police in Japan?
We'll request joint investigation
from the police here after we nab you!
Of course, I'm willing to take full responsibility for this.
But before that I have something I want to ask you!
And what may that be?
Why don't you...
Why don't you age at all?
You caught my attention because of what you said
in front of my mother's coffin.
A secret makes a woman, a woman.
I was really excited and started investigating,
then sure enough, there was a perfect match.
Remember back when you killed my father
making it look like he committed suicide.
You picked up his glasses trying to replace it
because of the way it lay unnaturally on the floor.
The fingerprints that were on the lens of the glasses
and yours matched perfectly!
But, I had my doubts.
You were too young to be a suspect of an incident
that had happened 20 years ago.
I didn't think it possible at first,
but when I matched your prints with a certain person's,
I got results that made a shiver go up my spine.
You're the one and the same as your mother, Sharon Vineyard!
And, I finally found the witness
that could explain the mystery
of what was keeping you from being arrested!
You guys! Come out and hold this woman!
When I get custody of you from the Japanese police,
I'll make you spit it out.
You'll tell me everything.
Well, even if you insist on saying nothing,
she will eventually.
Thank you, Calvados.
Don't kill her yet.
I've still got something I want to ask her.
Why?
You all staked out here
and figured you lured me out but...
I came here once already two hours ago,
disguised as you.
And this is what I said in your voice.
This is it tonight! Come back tomorrow!
Didn't you realize?
There was another reason as to why the papers of the cases
that Detective Mouri was involved in were stolen.
All of the documents were stolen
so that the papers we actually needed would not be specified,
however, all of the documents were sent back to the MPD in one batch
because I wanted you people to think that my stay in Japan
had something to do with Detective Mouri
so that you would stake out the detective agency.
Which as a result, it would help me figure out who the FBI agents are.
Just as expected, I figured out how many of you there were,
the place you were all staying
and the way you were all communicating.
I also knew that you were trying to trap me here.
Then, you knew that we snuck into your room too?
Yes. I was just playing dumb.
I thought that if you saw that picture,
you would find her for me.
But you surprised me twice already.
The first is that you are the girl
that I met 20 years ago.
The other is that
you knew what went on behind the scenes regarding Dr. Araide.
How did you get information on it
when nothing about it was spoken to anyone?
I didn't hear about it from anyone.
I was asked to do so by someone.
To corner you and disclose your identity,
and in turn for doing so, she said that she would trust me.
This girl over here.
Oh, I see.
She said so.
Anyway, let's hear the whole story
when we get to the police station!
He solved the case in such a short time!
Just as expected of Shinichi Kudo!
Fantastic!
It's nothing...
The reason I got to solve it right away
is because I used the same trick as the killer.
Just what does that mean?
What?
The same trick that Werewolf over there used!
So, this is it, for our re-encounter after 20 years.
It's time to say goodbye.
Come on and smile
because you're going to get to see your father in heaven.
What?
The same trick as Werewolf used?
The killer put a mask over the victim, who was already disguised.
Which means he double disguised the victim.
Don't you only have bandages wrapped around you?
Just what do you mean by that?
Don't tell me that you're...
Yeah.
So this...
is what I mean!
What?
You're...
Heiji Hattori?
Cool kid?
Conan Edogawa.
A detective!
He wasn't Shinichi.
Heiji Hattori?
Disguise?
It's a disguise?
But his voice and tone were just like Shinichi.
Yes.
Of course.
It's my masterpiece that took me six hours to put him on this disguise.
As for his voice, the microphone on his collar
picks up the deduction that Heiji whispers into it,
then Shinichi says it through the microphone on his mask.
That voice output is the speaker on Heiji's necktie.
How do you like it?
A perfect collaboration by Dr. Agasa and I.
Okay! We're okay on this side, Kudo!
Do your thing on your side too, now!
Don't move!
Your body's the blind spot for the rifle.
Now...
get in the car after Ms. Jodie.
Let's take a drive to the police!
Ms. Jodie.
Quick and get in the car!
Ms. Jodie! Are you all right?
Yes.
Don't tell me that?
Shinichi Kudo?
Remember? The kid that you poisoned to death
with the drug made by the organization back then!
Sorry, Vodka.
I make it a policy to forget the name and face...
of the ones I get rid of.
And?
Are you saying that the kid rose from the dead
and appeared as a ghost?
Yeah, I mean no.
Something strange is happening.
Why are you disguised as Shinichi Kudo in the first place anyway?
Sorry! Pops!
I haven't seen Kudo for some time,
so I got kind of lonely.
I figured that if I came out looking like him
and made a deduction, maybe he just might pop out too.
But maybe he's dead, just as rumor has it, don't you think?
Darn it! Kid from Osaka,
this is the second time you're pulling this trick!
If Ran were here,
you'd be way gone by now!
Scary. Give me a break.
I had no choice.
After all, Kudo e-mailed me asking me to do this.
He told me that those guys are trying to pull him away from Ai
and do something,
so he wanted me to disguise myself as him and find out about it.
That's why I'm on board this ship!
But, it sure freaked me out
when I got to his house
and found his mother there.
She seems to have been worried about him,
and hiding for a while in the house watching him.
Mother?
Hey...
I didn't think she had a special talent to disguise people
but she would even freak Arsene Lupin out too!
Thanks to her,
I didn't have to complete my deduction all bandaged up.
The only one I'm worried about is
the little girl that is left sleeping
and confined in the basement of Dr. Agasa's house.
Kudo says she'll be fine
if she doesn't have the pursuit glasses
hidden somewhere with her.
But, if I were her...
knowing that he would be meeting someone dangerous disguised as me,
I wouldn't be able to wait for him just like that.
I would break the door open
and go after him no matter what.
No matter what, Kudo!
I'd go after you.
Haibara. You...
Haibara?
Darn it!
Don't come!
Stay away!
Go back!
You idiot!
No, Kudo.
This is my problem!
This had nothing to do with you.
That's why...
Don't die!
I don't want you to die!
So you had the spare pursuit glasses
hidden after all.
Kudo.
Run for it, Haibara!
Hurry!
Just what are you doing?
Get out of here, Haibara!
Hurry and get out!
Quick!
Goodnight, baby.
And...
Welcome...
Sherry!
The only reason I can think of
for Vermouth to go after Haibara's life
and want me to stay away from her
is because of her identity as actress Chris Vineyard
as well as Sharon since she is both of them.
She was probably acting out two roles under disguise.
If she knows mom,
she would've probably seen pictures of me as a kid,
so she would've easily made out who I am
and I also understand why she wouldn't want
to be messed up with a scandal.
I'll be fine!
Don't worry because I promise to make it back alive!
Is that really true,
Sharon?
Stupid woman.
Screwing up this little boy's plan,
and coming out here on your own initiative to die.
I didn't come here just to die.
I came here to end everything.
Even if you were to be arrested,
as long as I'm alive,
you guys will never stop pursuing me.
But, I'd like you to give me your word.
That you will not lay a hand on anyone else except me.
Will you promise to give me your word?
Okay.
I'll save all the others
except for this woman FBI agent here.
But first, I'll get rid of you, Sherry.
If you want to hold a grudge on anyone,
hate your parents for starting
such a stupid research in the first place.
Cool kid.
No way!
How?
Stop! Calvados!
Could it be...
she saw everything?
Stop! Calvados!
Stop!
Can't you hear I'm telling you to stop?
So...
Get away from that brown-haired girl!
If you don't want to die, you'd better hurry!
No! Don't move!
Come on. Hurry! Get out of the way!
Stop it!
I called the police.
So just put up with this a while longer. Please!
Big sis.
Silver hair?
The story was meant to end this way.
Hate God for what is happening to you.
What are you doing?
Hurry and hang on to my arm!
Hurry or my arm will get slippery from the rain.
Why'd you save me?
Why on earth?
Who needs a reason?
Who cares what the motives are
for a person to want to kill another person?
Why would a person want to save another then?
There is no logical reason for that either, is there?
Get out of the way!
What are you doing?
Hurry and hang on to my arm!
Move it, Angel!
What?
This is a blind spot for the rifle.
When did you...
Throw your gun down.
Throw your gun down!
If not, I'll aim for your head next.
The sound of a pump?
A shotgun?
Okay! Calvados.
We'll attack them from both sides!
This is bad.
He's coming from behind.
Come on, Calvados.
Use that dear shotgun of yours
and blow up the little kitty FBI agent, will you?
So, his name is Calvados.
A rifle, a shotgun and three guns.
I thought he was a weapon vendor or something.
Shuichi Akai?
Shu!
But with two broken legs,
I don't think he'll be doing business for quite some time.
Well, Calvados is like a strong apple spirit.
So, I guess he's just right
for the partner of a rotten apple like you.
Rotten apple?
That's the name we call you by.
Golden Apple was the stage
in which the great actress Sharon stole the limelight.
You're just as beautiful now as you were back then but...
Inside, you're a wrinkled up rotten apple.
A really rotten apple!
Don't, Shu!
Don't worry.
I can tell from the way she moves
that she's wearing a bullet proof jacket
and layers of bullet proof pads all over her body.
I think she'll get two or three broken ribs at most.
Moreover, look.
Look at her face that tore apart with the shot that was fired.
That's the face of that woman with no make-up after all.
The brats are a nuisance!
Cool kid.
To think she can blow up the gasoline tank
by looking over the mirror in that situation.
She's pretty good.
Shu!
This is no time to be amazed by her!
She took a child hostage and got away, you know?
Then why didn't you take the key out of the car?
Well, I'm sorry.
We did get our share though,
because that woman's comrade is...
Hey...
Don't tell me he still had a gun on him?
Could it be that he killed himself?
Look at that.
The Japanese police are here.
This girl must've called them.
Inside the trunk,
it's hard to make out conversation
but bullets can be heard.
I'm sure
she saw the pictures in my room and got suspicious,
and snuck inside my car
in order to investigate me.
She heard the bullets and came outside.
Then protected the brown haired girl, who had a gun pointed at her.
They probably thought they were shot
and both passed out.
Geez.
I don't know if you can say they got guts or not.
Then, I'll leave the rest up to you.
Just go ahead and explain to them that
you're an FBI agent on a long leave of absence came to Japan
and got mixed up in a child kidnapping case.
Since that woman got away,
nobody would believe anything we say anyway.
The big guy behind all this hasn't come up front yet.
And besides I can't have
that girl with the brown hair see me yet.
"Seems that I gave you too much freedom before."
"Return to me immediately, Vermouth."
Okay, boss.
Now...
This child.
What shall do with this child who thinks
he is capable of doing everything?
The electrodes of an ECG monitor?
There is a tracing device as well as a recorder.
Don't tell me that
the sound of the telephone I made just a while ago was.
Don't.
If you pull that out,
it means that my heart has stopped
and the mail address of the boss you sent an e-mail to
will be disclosed to my friend.
The telephone company must protect the privacy of their clients.
But the police
can get that information if they fill out a special form
and have one of the higher-ups put a seal on it,
then have the information disclosed before several witnesses.
If the call that was received was not from a cell phone,
but a regular home phone, even the address would be disclosed!
In other words,
if the sound just now is recorded
and analyzed to decipher the alphabets and number,
the name of your boss, as well as his whereabouts can be tracked down!
That is, even if I were to be killed!
Well,
I did figure that if you found Sherry,
who you guys are going nuts looking for,
you would unmistakably contact your big boss.
Since things began to look dangerous for Ms. Jodie,
I had to change my plans.
So, what are you going to do now?
My friends are waiting for contact from me
at a distant place from here.
If you don't want this to go out,
take me to your boss!
Let's get things over with once and for all, Vermouth!
I want to stop playing hide-and-seek already!
Okay.
I lost.
I'll give up going after Sherry.
It's mere sleeping gas.
You idiot!
If you do something like this, you'll suck in the gas too.
Yes. This is a gamble.
If you get up first,
you go ahead and call the police and have me arrested,
then go raid the boss along with them.
You already know what happens
if I get up first, don't you?
Bad news!
I've got to go wake him up right away.
Shinichi!
Shinichi...
You guys were blasted by Shuichi Akai?
Yes.
He just happened to find us by,
and Calvados ended up with three broken ribs.
You mean that FBI agent that you failed to get rid of
back in New York a year ago,
when you disguised yourself as serial killer.
I thought he'd be off his guard if he figured
I was just an ordinary killer, but...
I should've gotten rid of him back then
even if I had to risk being killed myself.
Our boss said that
that person
could be our silver bullet.
He is to be feared.
A silver bullet that capable to kill us in one shot
doesn't exist.
At any rate, I'm in a phone booth on route 20,
so can you come pick me up?
I got into a bit of trouble,
and can't move.
Before that, I have something I want to ask you.
Do you know a kid by the name of Shinichi Kudo?
No.
I don't.
Why did you save me?
Who needs a reason?
Why would a person want to save another then?
There is no logical reason for that either, is there?
Yes, it's him.
He, the one who pierced through our heart,
could prove to be him.
The one that we have long awaited,
the silver bullet.
"Next Episode."
At any rate, we'll have to figure out
what this mark that Ayumi drew is.
Hey!
The mark on Genta's butt sure looks familiar.
Next Conan,
"Look for the Mark on the Buttocks (Part 1)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"Emblem."
How did you like the first two hour and a half special?
It's been nine years since the Detective Conan series has been aired.
Keep tuning in on us, okay!