The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
The deduction catches fire on the line to the heart.
Deciphering codes together with Heiji.
Tokyo-Osaka large scale mystery solving.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
"Conan and Heiji, Code of Love (Part 1)"
Bummers, this rain sucks.
Just when we were thinking of playing soccer in the park.
But it started raining the minute we got there.
But there was 50% chance of rain,
so we did right to bring umbrellas.
Why don't we play games at Doc's house then?
Yeah! Let's!
Speaking of games, how far did you get in "Titan Hunter"?
I got to rank 7.
I got the Haoken!
No joke?
-Really? -Yep!
-And? What did you want to talk to me about? -Oh, right.
Do you understand...
what "Younger sister from another domain" means?
What?
Is that a setting for a late night anime or something?
No.
Masumi seems to be hiding an intermediate school aged girl,
who looks just like her at her hotel.
It bothered me so much that I texted her about the girl yesterday.
She texted back, "She's my younger sister from another domain."
Then, she's her younger sister, no?
But she said she had no younger sister.
And what does "from another domain mean?
Besides, I feel like I've met her somewhere before.
I guess you'll have to start from remembering where it was.
I was thinking the same thing. But all I remember is her snaggletooth...
Ouch...
You brat! Watch it!
What's this?
Tea leaves?
Don't touch it!
There he is!
Hold it!
Who are those men?
-Probably cops. -What?
Judging from his appearance,
the one they were chasing is probably a drug dealer.
The tea leaves like stuff that you picked up is dried weed.
Probably marijuana.
What?
Marijuana?
Oh, no! I touched that bag, you know?
Maybe your fingerprints got on it.
Your fingerprints on the bag is no big deal!
-You sure? -Yeah.
If you explain what happened to the police...
A pocketbook?
That man must've dropped it.
Yeah.
But nothing seems to be written inside.
No. There's something small written on the edge of the page.
There's an "E" and "2" and a "circled 2".
The character "ma" for drugs.
Drugs?
Something else seems to be written after the "ma",
but unlike the letters and numbers on the side,
it's written in water-based ink,
so it's smeared by rainwater.
There's something written on the next page, too!
Yeah. On the next
and the next page, too.
A total of 12 lines.
All that can be barely read of the blurred words are...
"ma" on the 1st line,
"tsuki" on the 3rd line, "nihon" on the 5th line,
and "kyobashi" on the 9th line.
I wonder what they are?
Codes, right?
Maybe they're code numbers for members of a drug smuggling organization!
Like E22 and S10.
What about the circles?
And "tsuki" and "nihon" written after that?
And? Did you figure it out?
I don't have the slightest idea.
No use hanging on to it, so let's take it to the police box.
-You're right. -Yeah.
Yeah.
See you officer!
We're counting on you!
-Thank you! -Not at all.
What now?
It stopped raining.
Shall we go back to the park to play soccer?
Sorry.
I just remembered I had something to do so I'm going home!
Okay!
Bye!
See you later!
Conan's a crummy liar.
It's so obvious!
We've learned over time.
So...
Ai, let us use the you know what!
Please!
Yes, yes.
Well, I got here.
But there's nobody here.
Just as I thought, it's no good unless I know what time.
The only ones here are the kids...
who secretly came after me.
Oh, what a coincidence.
Do you have business this way, too?
Coincidence my foot!
You followed the location of my detective badge
using those spare tracking glasses!
Because...
No fair!
You're investigating something, right?
Yeah. The stuff that's written in this pocketbook
is probably the place, dates and time of various drug deals.
Drug deals?
How do you know?
The clues are the notes written in water-based ink
next to the letters and figures.
The finger of the drug dealer was soiled
with the same color ink as the smeared letters.
So the letters were written by the drug dealer.
If so, the codes written by permanent marker
were written by someone else.
It's only natural to think that the other party wrote it, right?
The other party probably sent the drug dealer a pocketbook
of codes designating the places, dates and time of the deals.
He taught only the drug dealer how to decipher the codes,
so no one else could figure it out even if they saw the pocketbook.
What about the letters in water-based written by that man?
Yeah. He wrote the answers to the codes next to it!
He was probably planning to burn or trash them later.
In other words, E22 to "ma",
Y21 to "tsuki", G11 to "nihon". Each symbolizes a Chinese character.
With these clues, you can tell right off
that they are subway routes and station numbers!
What?
So, E22 refers to the 22nd station on the Oedo Line, Azabu Juban.
Y21 refers to the 21st station on the Yurakucho Line, Tsukishima.
G11 refers to the 11th station on the Ginza Line, Nihonbashi.
Station numbers?
What's that?
Well, let me tell you.
They're the circled letters and numbers
displayed next to the name of the station.
Really?
Which means, you only remove the circled number
or letter of the station and read it?
Since in E22 of Azabu Juban, the 3rd number is circled,
so the 3rd kanji character "ju" is chosen.
Using this rule, if you read up to the 5th line of the code, E22 is "ju"!
C10 is Nijubashimae on the Chiyoda Line,
the 1st letter is circled so it's "Ni"!
Y21 is Tsukishima on the Yurakucho Line, so it's "tsuki"!
M09 is Shinjuku Sanchome on the Marunouchi Line, so it's "san"!
G11 is Nihonbashi on the Ginza Line, so it's "Nichi"!
If you line everything up, it comes out "December 3rd"!
Hey! Isn't today December 3rd?
Yeah. So the deal's supposed to be today.
I can't solve the lines below the date from the 6th line!
The dates, location and time should be written, but...
Since in N11 of Korakuen on the Namboku Line, shown on the 6th line,
the 2nd number is circled, so the 2nd kanji character "raku" is chosen.
In Y12 is Edogawabashi on the Yurakucho Line. Shown on the 7th line,
since the 2nd number is also circled here, "do" is chosen.
It reads, "Rakudo".
It's totally Greek to me.
If so, why did we come here?
Since HO2 on the 8th line, is Ebisu on the Hibiya Line,
and there's a circle around it entirely, it's chose as is.
Since on the side of N22, there is a written note "Kyobashi",
and the 2nd number is circled, "bashi" is chosen.
In other words, "Ebisubashi".
That's why I took a guess that this would be the place.
But I could be wrong.
I can't figure out why N22 is Kyobashi to begin with?
"N" stands for the Namboku Line, but there's no 22nd station.
Kyobashi is on the Ginza Line and right next to Nihonbashi
so it should be G10.
Besides, what is that arrow on the circle around Ebisu?
Does it mean the next station?
Naka-meguro and Hiroo are the stations on either side of Ebisu.
If so, why isn't it written H01 and H03? Gosh!
Even the last three lines,
I02 is Shiroganedai on the Mita Line, so "Shiro" is chosen.
T22 is Baraki-Nakayama on the Tozai Line, so "Bara" is chosen.
But I can't make out C22.
The Chiyoda Line ends at the 20th station, Kitahayase.
Hey, show it to me, will you?
That code, hurry, show it to me!
-Hattori? -Yeah!
The kids called to tell me that you were on the verge of tears
because you can't decipher the code.
So, I, a much wiser great detective than you
shall help you out if you want, you know?
I'm gonna hang up.
Sorry, really!
Please let me help you, all right?
I'll forward it to you now, so hang on.
Why did you have to call him?
Because he's your detective master, isn't he?
-Huh? -He told us to call him anytime you needed help.
He's not my master.
Well, it's true that I needed help, though.
I see.
Codes using subway lines and station numbers.
Interesting!
Hey, just whose cell are you talking on?
Oh, Inspector Otaki's!
We just closed a murder case at Shinsaibashi.
You're talking on my cell phone too, Conan.
And? Anything?
Is this G11 really Nipponbashi?
Yeah, it's the station next to Kyobashi.
The alphabet and numbers are all correct, you know?
Well, since both Nihonbashi and Kyobashi are subway stations in Tokyo,
it's no surprise that you don't know them.
What're you talking about?
Nipponbash and Kyobashi are both names of stations in Osaka!
Besides, there are many stations between them
and they aren't next to each other?
What?
Moreover, it's pronounced "Kyobashi",
with the accent on the first syllable.
Hey. You've got a station called Kyobashi over there, too?
The code says so too, N22!
The "N" stands for Nagahori Tsurumi Ryokuchi Line.
The 22nd station on that line is Kyobashi!
Which means... Don't tell me that this code...
"Ebisubashi" -What?
You acquired a clue to deciphering the codes?
Yeah.
If there are stations in Osaka with station names, Nihonbashi and Kyobashi,
the code using line and station numbers
aren't limited to one specific district.
And, if so, the codes that I deciphered
from the 1st to the 5th lines to be December 3rd,
may be wrong, too.
Could be.
There are stations with numbers in their names like.
Higashi-Mikuni, Yotsubashi, and Tanimachi Rokuchome.
It seems that Osaka and Tokyo are the only cities
with the station names Nihonbashi and Kyobashi.
Some of these codes are written to the left
-and others are written to the right, aren't they? -Huh?
True, it looks to be so.
Then! Maybe one side are the stations in Tokyo
and the other in Osaka?
If so,
the codes that you deciphered,
until the 5th line
are all written on the left side, so they're all no good.
-But Nihonbashi in Tokyo is G11, right? -Yeah.
The Nipponbashi in Osaka isn't G11, is it?
No, it isn't.
The Nipponbashi in Osaka is K17 on the Sakaisuji Line,
and S17 on the Sennichimae Line.
If there is a note "Nihon" written beside G11,
it's the Nihonbashi in Tokyo.
Hei-chan, I went and got it.
A book that has information of the subway lines
and station numbers in Tokyo.
Oh, I don't need that anymore.
I searched online and found it.
What?
Oh, come on!
I went all the down way to the kiosk in Shinsaibashi Station to buy it.
The escalators were under maintenance, so I had to use the stairs
and I'm pooped.
What? Escalators?
-That's right! Escalators! -What?
When riding escalators,
in Osaka people move to the right and open the left side,
while in Tokyo it's the other way around, right?
That's why the stations written on the right are stations in Osaka
and the ones on the left are stations in Tokyo!
I see.
That's why the page was divided
and the codes were written on the edge of the pages.
If you take an overall look, it looks like stairs.
So, let's say that "December 3rd" is correct.
What stations in Osaka are N11 and Y12?
N11 is Taisho Station on the Nagahori Tsurumi Ryokuchi Line,
and Y12 is Higobashi, on the Yotsubashi Line.
Both have circles around the 2nd number, so "sho" and "go" are chosen.
In other words, "shogo", meaning 12:00 noon!
Twelve noon!
Only 10 more minutes to go.
No joke?
If the drug deal's going to be here at Ebisu Bridge,
-we better hide quickly, or they'll be here! -Yeah.
H02 is written to the left, so it's "Ebisu"!
If N22 is Kyobashi in Osaka,
I think that the deal will be at Ebisu Bridge.
I don't know why there's an arrow attached to the circle encircling H02.
Hey, Hattori. Is there a bridge called Ebisu there, too?
Huh?
Hattori?
There is, here in Osaka.
The kanji characters are different,
but there's a bridge that people often use to meet each other!
Is that right? This arrow indicates...
-that it's the Ebisu Bridge in Osaka. -Yeah!
I'm running over right now. I'll get there in two to three minutes!
-Wow! -He's good!
He's unmistakably Conan's master!
I feel sort of vexed.
By the way, what is "shiroihara"?
I want the answers to the three remaining lines
under the location of the deals.
I02, C22 and T22...
C22 that is written to the right is.
Takaida on the Chuo Line of Osaka, so it's "i".
I02 and T22 that are written to the left,
are Shiroganedai and Haraki-Nakayama in Tokyo.
So, you take "Shiroi" and "hara".
If you join them together, it reads "Shiroihara (White belly)".
I hope it doesn't mean that they'll be waiting
sticking their white bellies out.
No, it should be read "Baraki-Nakayama",
not "Haraki-Nakayama"!
In other words, if you join them together, it reads "shiroibara".
It probably means a "white rose" will be the sign!
Hattori? What's up? Hattori?
-You can't hear him? -Maybe something happened?
Don't tell me he got caught trying to get the dealers.
He's so hot-blooded. It's possible.
Hey, Hattori? Answer me, Hattori!
-Hattori! -There're three.
I'm looking around Ebisu Bridge,
and I see three people with a rose on, holding it,
or waiting for somebody.
Gosh.
-At least tell me that you're at the bridge. -Sorry.
I got carried away watching them
because they look so authentically suspicious.
But, is it true that they're going do the drug deal here?
Yeah, most likely.
The owner of this pocketbook of codes
had at least 4 large bags of marijuana.
Even if one bag were to be about 500 grams, 4 bags would total 2 kilograms.
The street value would be exorbitant.
They weren't packed in small packages
so he was probably gonna sell the entire batch at once.
The deal may have already gone through, but...
If the time arranged was noon,
they'd be meeting each other from now.
And? How did the drug dealer look?
He was unshaved, wearing a knitted cap and a parka.
The typical drug dealer type.
He was being chased by men who looked to be cops,
so they may already have arrested him, though.
He could've fled and headed over that way, so be careful!
-I will. -By the way, where's Inspector Otaki?
He went back to the headquarters to get backup.
After all, I'm using his cell phone now.
-There's only 5 minutes to go before noon! -Yeah.
I guess we'll have to narrow down the target
to one by then.
Just the two of us!
"Next Episode" -Isn't he the one? The bad guy?
I think so, too!
Me, too!
It's one minute past the time of the deal.
That guy...
Hey, what's with you? What do you think you're doing?
Kazuha!
I'll throw you all over down Dotonbori!
Bring it on!
Hey, Hattori!
Next Conan, "Conan and Heiji, Code of Love (Part 2)"
Next Conan's Hint:
"White rose."
-Huh? New Year's monetary allowance? -Please give us!
Big brother, give me some, too!