Aiko...
From: Aiko Subject: Goodbye
Damn!
This is their fault!
Their fault!
The rhythm on my lips is footloose!
The rhythm of my detective skills is perfect!
While love blossoms at the MPD, black malice approaches!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Target: MPD Transportation Department (Part One)
I'm late!
This isn't good! Yumi-san's going to be mad!
I'm sorry!
Huh? You...
What? No way! Chiba-kun?
Are you...?
Y-Yes?
Yes?
Are you maybe...?
Oh, no!
I'm actually late!
See you later!
The light's always so long when you're in a hurry.
I can't be late.
No one's looking.
There aren't any cars. Maybe I'll cross.
The light is red!
Who cares? There isn't a single car.
No one's watching.
I'm watching.
And you're watching, too.
Once you go easy on yourself and break the rules, it becomes a habit.
Habits are hard to break even if you want to.
Do you not even understand that?
No, no. Be patient.
Hey, you're the mini patrolwoman's henchman.
It's Naeko-san.
Henchman?
You're up early.
We're up early because it's our turn to feed the rabbits.
Is something happening?
It's traffic month at the MPD. We're tightening supervision.
All right.
Don't! The light's still red.
But there aren't any cars.
Doesn't this symbol mean kids can cross?
No, this sign is a warning to drivers to be careful
because there's a school, kindergarten, or nursery school nearby.
Most road signs are divided by color and function.
Yellow signs like this one are warnings.
Red means danger or prohibition.
Easy-to-read blue signs are for directions.
Calming green signs that are easy on the eyes are used to guide people to emergency exits.
Think of it as the same as a traffic light's red, yellow, and green.
Huh.
You certainly are a female officer of the traffic department.
The shapes have meaning, too.
Circles that appear larger than they are for prohibitions or regulations.
Triangles or squares with points at the top look unstable and draw your attention,
so they're for warnings and regulations.
Solid stable-looking squares are for direction and guidance.
I'm sure you'll learn about it at school soon.
Make sure you follow traffic rules.
Okay!
The rules...
Everyone should follow them! Follow the rules!
The rules!
What? You got hit on again?
During a stakeout?
Yeah.
Apparently the clothes I always borrow from your friend make me look easy.
You're right.
The clothes you wear to stakeouts always have a kind of devilish aura about them.
Well, as long as I don't look like a cop, it's okay.
So, what'd you do with the guy who hit on you?
Naturally, I drove him off by secretly showing him my badge.
I told him, "Don't you think you're hitting on the wrong woman?"
But weren't you on a stakeout with Takagi-san at the time?
Yeah.
Then couldn't you have chased them off by saying he's your boyfriend?
Oh, well...
You're not wrong,
but I once actually did that to tease Takagi-kun, and...
Oh, uh, it's not that I'm her boyfriend,
but we're actually here on a stakeout...
He panicked, and everyone in the area figured out that we were cops.
So we can't use that strategy.
Oh, Takagi-san.
I know.
Takagi-kun's always so fun to tease.
Speak of the devil.
Sato-san!
What are you doing here?
Inspector Megure was looking for you.
Ch-Chiba-kun!
Oh, no! I had pot stickers for lunch today, so my breath might stink!
By the way, is the newbie who went out on the stakeout with you feeling better?
No, his allergies have gotten worse since then.
He's at home asleep today.
Well, I can conduct a stakeout on my own.
If you're short a man, how about her?
Y-You...
Y-Yes?
You wouldn't be good on a stakeout.
You'd just look like a middle schooler being admonished by an officer.
A middle schooler? But we're the same age.
Chiba, what are you doing?
Let's go.
Coming.
Chiba-kun...
Jeez.
Miwako proudly declares her love, but you're absolutely hopeless.
Yeah, but...
Feel like singing, Miike?
At karaoke, after work.
I'll sing! Let me sing with you!
All right. Toko, will you come with us?
You bet I will.
Yumi, how about you?
I'll pass. I've got stuff to do tonight.
Is it your shogi master boyfriend again?
Yeah, something like that.
They added the new Eio title,
so I have to talk Chukichi into getting it so he can be a septuple crown master.
Eio
For now I don't really want to think about the future
No one can be greater than you
Even though you're [important]
Hey, Shiori.
Anything strange happen to you lately?
Anything strange?
Like being followed by someone.
Come to think of it, since about a week ago.
Seriously? You, too?
But we'll be fine. We're strong.
Besides, you're a third dan judoka.
Well, yeah.
And I'll go running to you now
Are you okay? Can you handle her?
I'll be fine.
Chiba-kun... You big dummy...
Hey, Miike. Miike!
Come on, Miike.
Can you walk home? Can you make it?
I'm totally fine!
Excuse me.
I've been hearing the sound of a small girl crying in the park bathroom for a while.
Could you go check it out?
I wanted to ask the police,
but there isn't a police box in the neighborhood.
Got it.
Could you take me to that park?
Beika Higashi Park
I don't hear anything.
It was coming from the women's bathroom in the back.
Hello?
Is someone there?
I knew it. I'd sensed an odd presence recently.
I'm a cop.
Looks like you chose the wrong target for your trap.
I didn't choose wrong.
I didn't choose the wrong target!
Hey, kids.
Yumi-san!
You're such good kids to raise your hands while you walk in the crosswalk.
Naeko-san told us about traffic rules yesterday.
So we did a bunch of research.
Kids are hard to see because they're small, so they raise their hands, right?
Really? Miike, huh?
Japanese road signs are based off of English ones, right?
What?
Is that right? Miike, did you know that?
Yes. That's what I learned.
Anyway, you guys are working early.
It's traffic month, right?
Yeah, something like that.
We're looking out for your safety.
Thank you for your service, boss!
This is nothing!
I'm the boss!
Hey, we should get going.
MPD to all stations.
The body of a woman bludgeoned to death was discovered at Beika Higashi Park.
All patrols in the neighborhood, please head to the location.
No way. That's nearby.
Let's head there to preserve the crime scene.
Right, like controlling curious onlookers.
Don't be late, kids.
It's at Higashi Park.
We still have time before first period, right?
Should we go, too?
Let's go.
Hey, guys!
Man, you're hopeless.
We're just going to check it out, okay?
Yeah!
You're the one who wants to go the most, Kudo-kun.
It's obvious.
Sato-san!
It's no use.
We didn't find anything in the area that would help us identify the victim.
Maybe the suspect took it.
Does that mean this was a robbery?
N-No!
M-Momosaki-san! Momosaki-san!
Momosaki-san...
You knew her?
She's a colleague.
I thought I recognized her.
So she was a cop.
Momosaki Toko.
Like us, she worked for the MPD Transportation Department as a sergeant.
But she was a third dan judoka. How could this happen?
Come to think of it, weren't you going to karaoke with Momosaki and Yagi last night?
Miike!
Yes, but I got drunk.
I only remember Yagi-san, who went with us, walking me home.
Where was the karaoke box?
Karaoke Beika on fourth street, across from the planetarium that's being remodeled.
That's right over there.
Then maybe she was attacked while trying to use the park bathroom.
But if the suspect bludgeoned a third dan judoka to death,
it's possible they're quite strong as well.
Or they knew she was a cop and planned a countermeasure.
What?
This bent 100 yen coin next to the body...
What if it wasn't a coincidence, and the suspect left it there deliberately?
So it was a premeditated crime.
Maybe it was the work of someone who bore some financial resentment.
We'll have to canvas the area to gather information,
but for now, our only clue is this 100 yen coin.
No...
There are other clues, too.
Conan-kun?
Look at her left hand.
There's nothing on her pointer finger,
but there's a scrape along the first joint of her middle, ring, and pinkie fingers.
And...
Hey, wait.
If you flip it over, there's a scrape along the bottom of her palm, too.
But there aren't any signs that her body was dragged.
Which means her left hand was actually shaped like this
and placed against the ground like this.
What you doing?
She probably got these scrapes
when someone kicked it towards her feet.
So she was trying to tell us something by pointing somewhere?
At what, though?
Look at the tip of her pointer finger.
See the little bit of blood on it?
You're right.
Maybe that means she knew the culprit would move her hand
no matter what she pointed at,
so she used her own blood to leave a fingerprint.
Look!
There's a stain from where her bloody finger scraped against it.
In other words, she was actually pointing in that direction.
A swing set?
Yeah.
What does that mean?
What? Uh...
Yumi.
Who else was with the victim at the karaoke box last night?
Lieutenant Yagi Shiori also of the Transportation Department was with them.
Right?
Yes.
Where is she now?
Yagi's got the day off.
Since it's still early, she's probably at home.
I see. Got it.
Someone go to Lieutenant Yagi's place immediately.
Yes, ma'am.
Oh, uh...
By the way, what are you kids doing here?
We ran into Yumi-san and Naeko-san in their mini patrol car while on our way to school.
We heard about the case on the radio.
How did you get here?
We came immediately when we heard the radio,
but you were already investigating the crime scene.
Sato-san and I happened to be conducting a stakeout in the area.
We'd just finished when we got the call.
So you were with Detective Sato all night last night.
We were working, okay?
I know...
Yeah, that's right.
Last night, Toko, Miike, and I went to karaoke.
I said I'd walk Miike home since she was drunk and parted ways with Toko in front of the store.
I had no idea this would happen afterwards.
It looked like she was trying to stop by the park bathroom.
That's odd.
Toko used the bathroom just before we left the karaoke box.
Then what was she doing in a park?
Was there anyone who resented her?
Last night she said she felt like she was being followed starting about a week ago.
And?
But that was the only time we discussed it.
I see.
Do you know anything about a swing set?
A swing set?
She pointed at that swing set just before she died.
What? Did you remember something?
I don't know.
I could be wrong, so I'll call you once I'm sure.
Well, I need to tell Toko's friends about what happened.
Yagi!
You've got the day off. You should stay home.
Yeah, I know.
The body discovered in the park belonged to Sergeant Momosaki Toko,
a member of the Transportation Department like Yumi-san and Naeko-san.
The evidence left behind included a bent 100 yen coin
thought to have been placed next to the body by the culprit.
There's also the park's swing set the dying Momosaki-san indicated with blood.
The culprit and the victim both left separate messages.
But we still haven't found the clue
to decipher what either of them mean.
And later,
we'd learn this was only the beginning of this case.
Three of the traffic violators they fined
made a bunch of complaints.
Very nice.
I'm impressed you found this place.
I knew it.
You're the one who killed Toko.
What? Wait a minute.
This alleyway and the park...
The next episode of Conan is "Target: MPD Transportation Department, Part Two!"