Sergeant Momosaki and Lieutenant Yagi were murdered
one after another in the policewoman serial murder case.
It was determined that the dying messages they left behind pointed to no parking signs.
And that signified...
I had no idea Japanese road signs were based off English ones.
England...
Japanese road signs are based off English ones...
That's it! So that's how it is!
Listen, Detective Chiba...
Oh, sorry. Someone's calling.
Hello? Hello?
Hey, what are you doing?!
Damn! You had two phones?
Ch-Chiba-kun...
The rhythm on my lips is footloose!
The rhythm of my detective skills is perfect!
The culprit's identity is becoming clear!
Hurry to Patrolwoman Miike, Detective Chiba!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Target: MPD Transportation Department (Part Four)
Hello, Sato-san? It was a week ago after all.
One week ago, there was a woman who committed suicide
by jumping from the roof of an office building on Second Street in Haido City.
Her name was Midorikawa Aiko.
Since she worked at the building she jumped from,
her colleagues were able to confirm her identity right then and there.
She resided in room 702 of the apartment building.
Left at the scene were her shoes and phone.
Later, a suicide note was discovered in her desk as well.
And, in fact...
You know who the culprit is?
You know who killed Sergeant Momosaki and Lieutenant Yagi?
Yeah.
The culprit is one of the traffic violators
they arrested one week earlier, right?
Yeah.
They were extremely angry when they were brought into the police station,
so that's the lead we're following.
They were Aono, who forgot his license and was using his phone while driving,
Akamine, who was riding a motorcycle against traffic without a helmet,
and Shiroyama, whose inspection was expired and forgot to wear his seat belt, right?
And most likely, both the first victim Sergeant Momosaki was pointing at
and the second victim Lieutenant Yagi was facing a no parking sign.
Do you know why signs prohibiting something are a circle with a diagonal line?
N-No, I don't.
Because the shape is combination of the letters N and O.
In other words, it means "no" in English.
No parking signs are a "no" layered on top of a blue sign.
Which means blue (ao) plus "no" is ao-no.
The culprit is Aono-san.
Blue plus no makes Aono?
Do you really think they made a lame pun with their dying messages?
That's what I thought at first,
but if that's the only thing you saw in the vicinity, wouldn't you do the same?
Dying messages can't be noticed by the culprit,
but it's also not good if no one understands them.
Most people don't know the history of road signs,
but it's likely an officer of the Transportation Department would notice.
It's the perfect message.
Then there's 7155.
Huh?
The number Lieutenant Yagi left on her phone that doesn't connect to anyone.
It probably refers to road traffic law article 71, section 5-5.
While operating a vehicle, drivers must not hold their phone in their hand
or look at its screen.
In other words, I think we can assume it refers to Aono-san,
who was using his phone while driving.
We just received word from Sergeant Chiba.
We've received information identifying Aono Kengo
as the suspect in the policewoman serial murder case.
I'm ordering the emergency deployment of police forces
in a wide area to search for Aono Kengo.
He's a dangerous criminal who has murdered two of our own.
For the dignity of the police, we must arrest him!
Yes, sir!
Yes, sir.
Oh, but...
It was Conan-kun who figured all of this out.
The Sleeping Kogoro's adviser...
I suppose I'm not surprised.
Aono hasn't returned to his home.
According to his neighbors, they haven't seen him for several days.
According to Aono's coworkers,
this afternoon they told a woman who came to ask about his whereabouts
that he was probably at his girlfriend's place if he wasn't at home.
Yes, it was definitely Lieutenant Yagi.
I confirmed her identity using a photo.
Sato-san, look!
It's so noisy.
There are a lot of patrol cars driving around.
Of course there are.
They're looking for the suspect who murdered two police officers.
So I recommend you release me immediately and turn yourself in!
I told you...
If you want me to release you, just tell me already.
She's in here, isn't she?
That damn woman named Yumi.
Why do you want to know?
I'm going to tell her I found your phone and have her come here to get it.
Then I'll push her out the window and break her head open,
just like my girlfriend Aiko.
Though she might trigger a trap first and end up skewered instead.
In that case...
I wouldn't tell you even if I knew!
What?
Aono Kengo's girlfriend killed herself by jumping off the building she worked at?
One week ago?
Yes.
Apparently she couldn't take the power harassment
she was suffering at the hands of her bosses.
Aono received a text from his girlfriend that said "goodbye."
He rushed out of work, got into his car without his license,
and was caught by Sergeant Momosaki and Lieutenant Yagi while he was on his way to her.
So he resented them for stopping him.
He believes he could've prevented his girlfriend's suicide if that hadn't happened.
But according to the local jurisdiction,
she called Aono immediately after texting him, right?
Yes, but Aono didn't answer,
so she left a voicemail instead.
She was using a recording app on her phone,
so they were able to confirm the message's contents at the scene.
Her phone, huh?
Speaking of phones, they received a phone call while questioning Aono,
and he was extremely upset.
Yes.
The officers who came to help question them heard what he said.
You're seriously talking about karaoke?!
Someone might die, and you're talking about karaoke?!
The two of them had a mutual friend named Yumiko who they went to karaoke with.
But both of them called her Yumi.
Yumi?
Did Aono hear that name then and plan to kill Yumi-san next?
If you're looking for someone named Yumi among their acquaintances,
it's certainly possible.
Where is Yumi-san now?
I've been calling her, but she won't answer.
A text?
Conan-kun just sent a message to Takagi-san's phone.
Conan-kun did?
Due to certain circumstances, I'm driving him home right now.
Is the number I just sent him Yumi-san's number?
What? Yumi called you?
I don't know if it was Yumi-san,
but I heard four sets of a fingernail tapping a phone seven times.
After that, I heard a male voice say, "Hey, what are you doing?!" before they hung up.
I thought it might be...
What? Wait.
This is Miike's number.
What? Miike, Yumi-san's subordinate?
Come to think of it, we can't get in touch with Miike either.
It's possible the culprit figured out she's a police officer
and kidnapped her so he can lure Yumi-san to him and murder her!
What?
If he plans to call her to him, then he can't be that far.
What places are nearby that the culprit would be familiar with?
Do you know what Aono does for work?
Y-Yes...
I think he was a remodeler.
An English school, an out-of-business arcade,
a planetarium, a sports facility, a restaurant...
It's no use.
There are more places being remodeled than I expected.
The only clue we have is the four sets of seven taps that Detective Chiba heard.
Damn it! Where are they?!
A remodeler...
Four sets of seven taps...
What does it mean?
By the way, Chiba-kun, how did the sound you heard go?
I believe it was...
Tap tap tap tap tap tap tap,
tap tap tap tap tap tap tap.
Huh? That sounds familiar.
It's "Twinkle Twinkle Little Star!"
What?
Twinkle twinkle little star, how I wonder what you are.
Up above the world so high, like a diamond in the sky.
The lyrics are four phrases of seven syllables each.
She could only communicate using sounds because her mouth is covered!
The culprit works as a remodeler, and then there's "Twinkle Twinkle Little Star!"
In other words, she's being held in the planetarium that's being remodeled!
The planetarium is near the park we were just at that was the scene of the first murder.
Hurry!
Damn it. You're determined not to talk, aren't you?
Forget it, then.
Instead, I'll make it so you can never speak again!
Chiba-kun!
Twinkle, twinkle, little star,
how I wonder what you are.
Up above the world so high,
like a diamond in the sky.
Twinkle, twinkle, little star,
how I wonder what you are.
A-A kid? What is this? Why are you here?
I brought him here so he could distract you.
Aono Kengo, you're under arrest for the murders of two female police officers.
Chiba-kun!
22:54, suspect arrested.
Damn it!
Damn, damn!
So you do have your phone with you.
The police have been calling you over and over.
It's not on.
This phone is full of memories of Aiko.
I never let it out of my sight.
But since that day, that moment, I haven't looked at the screen!
I can't look at it anymore!
Since that moment Aiko died,
no matter how often I look at it, Aiko never says anything to me!
I heard about your girlfriend.
What happened was tragic.
It's your fault!
Because you police wouldn't let me go, Aiko is...
Weren't you driving without a license while using your phone?
It's only natural that you were arrested.
Those are the rules.
There it is. The rules.
They could've quickly written me a ticket!
But they wasted my time by talking about karaoke on the phone
and slowed me down!
I wanted to get to my girlfriend to convince her not to do it!
The police killed Aiko!
The police didn't kill your girlfriend.
It was a coincidence that they received a call.
Even if it hadn't happened, they wouldn't have let you go.
It was clear from your behavior that you were out of your mind.
They thought you needed time to calm down.
No one can remain calm under all circumstances,
especially not if their loved ones are involved.
Not even me.
It's the reason the policewomen you killed did their jobs.
So a driver like you
who's lost their cool won't take the life of someone else's loved on.
You're lecturing me?
Talk all you want, but Aiko still died because you guys stopped me!
If that hadn't happened, I could've saved Aiko!
Besides, I was calm!
They had no reason to keep me there!
No.
You weren't behaving normally.
You weren't there. How would you know?
I do know.
Your girlfriend left a voicemail on your phone.
A voicemail?
I knew it.
You haven't heard your girlfriend's message.
No, you don't even seem to know that she called you.
She called you a minute after she sent that last text.
Because you were hurrying to your car,
it's possible you didn't notice she was calling.
But you were looking at your phone while driving after that.
You were so preoccupied that the police stopped you.
You should've seen this notification on your screen then.
Aiko, Voice Message Missed Call
This important notification was visible to you, but you didn't notice.
I know exactly how shaken you were.
Aiko...
Let me hear it.
Let me hear the message Aiko left for me.
Aono-kun.
Just sending a text seems bland, so I'll tell you directly.
Thank you for everything.
Someone fell!
Call an ambulance!
Do you understand now?
You were too late.
You're lying!
Aiko...
You're Yumi-san's subordinate...
Don't!
How could you be so reckless?
It's only natural! After all, I...
I...
Chiba-kun, you're...
After all, I...
I'm a police officer.
It's only natural.
I parked my car far away so the suspect wouldn't notice.
I'm going to carry you to a nearby hospital.
Do your best to bear it.
Okay.
Chiba-kun!
Sorry. Could you handle the rest?
It should be around here somewhere.
There it is. Beika University Hospital.
For Pedestrian and Cyclist Use
Damn. The light's taking forever.
There aren't any people or cars.
Maybe I'll cross.
You shouldn't cross.
What?
You may think no one's watching, but I'm watching.
You're watching, too.
Once you go easy on yourself and break the rules, it becomes a habit.
Habits are hard to break even if you want to.
Do you not even understand that?
Y-You...
It's not superheroes that I like.
Don't make me say it, dummy.
Thanks, Kamen Baiya.
Chiba-kun, you idiot. I hate you!
A-Are you really my childhood friend Naeko-chan?
You idiot.
Took you long enough.
The light turned green a while ago.
Oh, right.
Uh, oh! I forgot to return Naeko-san's phone after I picked it up.
Hey, while I was sleeping at Chukichi's place, Miwako called me 54 times.
I've been trying to call her back, but her line's been busy.
Did something happen?
Yes.
As you said, I gave all the information I could to that boy.
Though my information didn't do much to help him solve the case.
It's a minor matter.
It's better not to have to put out unnecessary fires.
More importantly, how is that going?
Nothing yet.
Don't neglect to make your reports, Bourbon.