"Saturday, December 5th.
Today Conan-kun caught a jewel thief.
When I asked him how he did it, he said it was thanks to my illustrated diary.
But I don't remember figuring anything out.
I wonder why he said that."
Find the question that solves the mystery!
Apply miraculous detective skills to the secrets of the heart!
Hints from Ayumi's illustrated diary save the day!
Catch that jewel thief!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Case of Ayumi's Illustrated Diary
Conan-kun noticed the jewel thief
while walking through a shopping area on the way to school.
Is something wrong?
Is it your illustrated diary?
Yeah.
I'm never sure what to write each day.
What do you guys do?
Just write about whatever you want to eat that day.
Like grilled eel in a bowl, or grilled eel in a box, or quartered grilled eel.
That can't be right.
When I can't decide, I go for a walk.
Don't you end up writing the same thing every day?
I suppose.
As long as I can write something.
Seriously?
What about you, Ai-chan?
It's easy.
A quick search online yields plenty of ideas, like the weather or whatever else.
You simply have to choose whatever you like from among the options.
That doesn't sound right either.
Aw, jeez. What should I do?
Carefully observe all kinds of things,
and you'll discover the truth.
Huh?
You should observe your surroundings in your own way.
I'm sure you'll find something to write about.
Got it. Thanks, Conan-kun.
Hey.
There's a bunch of people over there.
Huh?
What are they doing?
What does Kaneko-san plan to do by stocking something this nice?
He said he hoped it would revitalize the town.
What if someone steals it?
I'm not certain, but it's probably insured.
Right. Of course.
Then it'd be no skin off Kaneko-san's nose if it were stolen.
I don't know about that.
But I wonder how much that watch would sell for.
Even if you sold it so it couldn't be traced, it'd probably go for at least 70 million.
70 million?
No way.
I heard you can get several times the market price if you sell it to a collector.
If I got that much money, I'd take my family to Hawaii.
So this is what drew the small crowd.
It's a big watch.
It's so shiny.
I wonder how many eel bowls this is worth.
Come on, kids.
Isn't it almost time for school? Get moving.
Okay.
According to Conan-kun,
the jewel thief was trying to steal the big shiny watch from Jewelry Kaneko.
Blue Diamond Limited Tourbillon Cage No. 3.
Made by renowned watchmaker Soumillon, there's only five of them in the world.
No wonder the grocer was so excited.
It's quite the luxury watch for a small town jeweler.
Enough to create a commotion among ordinary people.
I hope it doesn't become the target of any ill-intentioned people.
Did you beat that game?
Yeah, I did.
Huh?
It's Detective Takagi.
Hey, you're right.
Make sure you lock your doors.
Will do.
Detective Takagi.
Conan-kun, you kids.
What are you doing here?
Is it about the luxury watch at the store next door?
Not exactly.
Then what it is?
There have been a lot of burglaries in this area lately.
I'm handing out these fliers to alert the locals.
Anyway, that's why we're handing out these fliers.
Thank you, I appreciate it.
Hey, Mister. We heard the watch in your store window is really expensive.
Would you like to take a look?
Can we?
Yeah. After all, you seem to be friends with this police officer.
Soumillon's masterpiece from the height of his career.
Blue Diamond Limited Tourbillon Cage No. 3.
Well? Beautiful, isn't it?
Wow!
It looks different up close.
It's so sparkly.
Kaneko-san, how's your security?
Don't worry.
My security is absolutely secure.
I have security cameras covering every inch of the store.
The footage is stored on the cloud,
so you don't need to worry about intruders erasing it.
Outside of business hours, I keep the sturdy shutters closed.
I also have infrared and pressure sensors installed.
The store window where the watch is displayed is made of tempered glass,
and a code is required to open this door.
All of these systems are monitored by computer.
If anything happens, the security company will come running.
I see. With security this tight, it's not possible for your average burglar to break in.
Indeed.
But nothing's for certain.
Please be careful.
Understood.
Excuse me.
Now then.
Hey, kids—
Detective Takagi.
Don't you think that watch is at risk?
But security is tight,
and it's hard to imagine jewelry theft going well in this day and age.
Hey, kids.
If you're not busy, could you help me hand out these fliers?
Bye!
Hey, w-wait!
Nothing of note happened for several days after that.
But one day...
Cafe Haronbo
Hup.
Good morning, kids.
Good morning!
Don't take any detours. Head straight to school.
Okay!
What's that sound?
Maybe it's construction work.
Looks like they're renovating.
Yeah.
I don't see anything suspicious.
Suspicious? Like what?
Like pretending to do construction work so they can rob the jewelry store?
What? Is that true, Conan-kun?
I don't know that yet.
Let's check it out for ourselves.
Conan-kun?
Excuse me.
What is it, kids?
As you can see, I'm renovating my store.
The president of the engineering firm over there is named Kumazawa.
We've known each other since middle school, so he's given me a special discount.
Um, is it possible that...
That you're pretending to renovate your store
so you can steal the watch from the jeweler next door?
What?
Don't be rude, you two.
Marvelous.
If I punched a hole in that wall and stole some jewels, I'd be rich.
Then I could open a store overseas.
What a masterpiece.
Maybe I'll become a professional thief.
I'm joking.
I may not look like it, but the only thing I can do is make coffee.
I'm too clumsy to be a thief.
Who are they?
They're Kumazawa's sons.
I've known them since they were in diapers.
You suspect them, too?
Well, uh...
Hello.
Cheetah Transport here.
Hello again.
Could you sign or stamp here, please?
Sure thing.
Thanks for the food.
Come back once we've finished renovations.
Okay.
Well? You heard what he said.
He's a little suspicious.
He didn't seem like a bad person.
The juice was good.
It's certainly risky to rob the jewelry store next door.
But he made jokes about it earlier.
I'm not sure what he actually thinks.
What's got you kids down?
Ma'am.
Here.
Oranges?
On the house.
Have some oranges and cheer up.
Head home once you finish those.
Okay.
Welcome, ma'am. What can I get you?
Then nothing in particular happened for several days.
But while Conan-kun thought hard about it,
the culprit's plans were steadily advancing.
Jewelry Kaneko
Does this mean there wasn't anyone
who thought about stealing that watch?
Maybe.
You think so?
I think the owner of the café is suspicious.
I think the contractors are suspicious.
What if it's actually the lady from the produce store?
You should also consider the possibility that the jeweler might pretend to rob himself.
He might do it for the insurance money.
You're right, Haibara-san. It's certainly possible.
Let's all keep an eye out so there is no burglary.
Yeah!
With no crime, there wasn't anything Conan-kun could do,
but several days later, that fateful day would come.
Conan-kun.
Ayumi-chan.
Conan-kun, read this.
Your illustrated diary?
Thanks, Conan-kun.
Huh?
Thanks to you, I think I got better at keeping an illustrated diary.
Because of me?
Did you forget what you told me?
Carefully observe all kinds of things, and you'll discover the truth.
Huh?
You should observe your surroundings in your own way.
I'm sure you'll find something to write about.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Since then, like you said, I've been carefully observing my surroundings every day.
When I started writing exactly what I saw and felt, I got better at it.
What's this?
Is something wrong?
Did something happen, Conan-kun?
Found it.
What about that drawing?
Didn't Michiyo-chan from the class next door—
Ayumi-chan, what's Michiyo-chan's family name?
I think it's Ogino.
All right.
Conan-kun?
Where are you going?
Ogino Produce Store
What's gotten into you, Conan-kun?
Seems like you figured something out.
Yeah.
Thanks to Ayumi-chan.
Huh?
There's still a lot I need to confirm, though.
But that's definitely it.
Almost. I'm almost there.
You just wait, my little jewels.
Hold it right there.
You nearly pulled it off. Too bad.
You can't escape.
We've already called the police.
Damn it.
You heard an expensive luxury watch was on display at Jewelry Kaneko.
While waiting to see what would happen,
you heard Café Haronbo was renovating its store and came up with your plan.
Isn't that right,
Cheetah Transport courier Fujioka Yuji-san?
This was the plan you came up with.
The renovation work being done at the café next to the jewelry store
would generate a lot of noise.
You decided to use that noise as a camouflage
to enter the jeweler from the produce store on the opposite side.
As long as the cafe was undergoing renovations,
no matter how much noise you made, no one would suspect you.
Then you just needed the produce store workers to go away.
You probably learned the grocer loves prize contests from that conversation
and invited her and her family to Hawaii by lying and telling her she'd won a prize.
Even if you sold it so it couldn't be traced, it'd probably go for at least 70 million.
70 million?
No way.
I heard you can get several times the market price if you sell it to a collector.
If I got that much money, I'd take my family to Hawaii.
Speaking of which, did you win that trip to Hawaii you mentioned the other day?
I don't know yet.
I hope you win.
I'd like to win a trip to Hawaii.
H-How do you know that?
What's wrong with you?
You mean you didn't see that note she posted?
What?
It says the shop is temporary closed because they're on a family trip.
That must've been a lot of work.
You've been digging for five days since they went on their trip, haven't you?
Damn it!
Who are you kids?
Edogawa Conan—
Yoshida Ayumi.
Huh?
Kojima Genta.
Tsuburaya Mitsuhiko.
We are the Detective Boys!
That's us.
And so, the case was solved.
The culprit Fujioka-san was arrested by Detective Takagi.
Conan-kun said he figured out the culprit's trick
from my illustrations of Michiyo-chan and the three buildings in a row.
He deduced that the culprit must know a lot about the area
and began to suspect Fujioka-san the courier
who was having a conversation in front of the jeweler.
Apparently the deciding factor
was that he accurately named the black market price.
Conan-kun called the Cheetah Transport company
and determined that Fujioka-san had missed work for five days.
Conan-kun said he couldn't have solved this case
without my illustrated diary.
Yay!
In other words, this was my first big success as a member of the Detective Boys.
Victory!
And that's how the Detective Boys
prevented a burglary before it happened.
Detective Takagi treated us to lots of tasty food at Poirot to thank us for preventing a crime.
Thanks for the food!
Hey, wait. This isn't an all-you-can-eat restaurant, kids.
But can't Ayumi-chan eat all she wants?
I suppose so.
Ahem.
He's really a great detective who can solve any case, right?
Why don't you show a little more consideration for your family?
You mentioned something about the gears of tragedy.
It wasn't you who turned them, but the culprit.
That must be it.
The next episode of Conan is "The Automatic Tragedy, Part One!"