Hired to find the culprit who killed Oide Fusaya-san's father,
the old man and I tracked down the thief who burglarized the Oide family home
around the time of death of Fusaya-san's father Raita-san, Taira Yasushi.
However, Taira claimed he only burglarized the house while Raita-san was asleep.
Was it Taira who murdered Raita-san
and set the gears of tragedy in motion for the Oide family?
Or was it...?
Ah, Fusaya.
Fusaya, where have you been?!
We're almost there, Fusaya.
Where do you think you're going, Fusaya?!
Fusaya, come here.
Don't laugh at me.
I'm pretty serious about this.
I'll be back, Dad.
Find the question that solves the mystery!
Apply miraculous detective skills to the secrets of the heart!
A series of tragedies befall a family!
Identify the culprit and stop the gears from turning!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
The Automatic Tragedy (Part Two)
If this case was the premeditated murder of Oide Raita,
that would make what Taira said rather curious.
He was snoring in his sleep.
Right on the floor here.
That testimony.
That's it!
All right!
Did you figure something out?
I haven't figured anything out, so I'm going back to the Oide family home.
I see.
Inspiration will surely strike if we go to the crime scene,
the same way we figured out Taira Yasushi was the burglar.
So, why are we taking the train instead of a rental car today?
Because today, taking public transportation is good luck.
We're relying on fortune telling now?
Wait, is this what he was reading so intently earlier?
If we'd taken the train yesterday, we might've solved the case already.
Now then.
Fusaya-kun.
Mori-san, what are you doing here?
I thought I'd examine your place again today.
I see. In that case, my sister went to the hospital.
I'll give you the key.
Thank you.
Fusaya-san, you're dressed rather formally.
Do you have a date or something?
No. I've got an interview.
Your necktie is crooked.
My father was worried that I couldn't find a job until the very end.
I thought doing whatever it takes to get one would be a good way to honor his memory.
They're closed today, but I asked them to make some time for me.
I'm sure they'll understand if you explain your feelings to them.
They surely will.
Thank you.
All that's left is to find my father's killer.
Leave it all to me, the great detective Mori Kogoro, to handle the case.
You should focus on your interview.
Mori-san.
So, we came all the way here...
But I'm still not getting any ideas.
It's strange, isn't it?
What is?
When Taira snuck into the house to steal the money,
Oide Raita-san was sleeping on the floor around here, right?
Huh?
They have a sofa, so why was he sleeping on the hard floor?
He was probably overcome by extreme sleepiness.
When I've had a lot to drink, I end up sleeping wherever when I come home.
But Raita-san was looking for Fusaya-san that day, so that couldn't have been it.
Maybe he drank his cares away.
He's not you.
In that case, he must've been really tired or...
Sleeping pills.
In that case, the culprit
secretly drugged Raita with sleeping pills before Taira snuck into the house.
After confirming they'd taken effect, they tried to kill him.
But then...
Taira snuck into the house.
The culprit hid somewhere and watched to see what he'd do.
After watching Taira burglarize and flee the house,
they killed Raita as planned.
In that case, why did the culprit bother putting him to sleep?
Because he would've resisted otherwise.
In other words, the culprit is a weak person.
Like a woman?
I hate to imagine it,
but is that a possibility?
A woman? Could it be?
All right. In that case...
Mister?
We'll have to go to the hospital to check.
Sounds like he's zeroed in on the culprit again.
What? A woman?
Yes.
Did Raita mention having problems with anyone?
She's a young woman.
Who are you talking about?
She was there yesterday by the station.
A very suspicious-looking woman.
Oh.
Oh, that's who you meant.
Who did you think I was talking about?
Nobody.
She's around your age, wears sunglasses, and has a mole right here.
What?
Do you mean Kuremi?
So you know who she is?
Y-Yes.
Soho Kuremi-san.
She was my classmate in middle school.
Last night she came here to visit us.
She's your friend?
She was here last night?
Yes.
When I ran into her the other day, I told her I'd gotten engaged.
She seemed very happy for me.
Where can I find this Soho Kuremi-san?
H-Hold on.
She gave me her business card the other day.
This is it.
Thank you.
She's a pharmacist?
In other words, she could've acquired some sleeping pills.
Thank you for your help.
Now then.
Excuse me.
Wait, Mister.
Does Kuremi know something?
Maybe there's something he wants her help with.
On the day of the incident, when the two of you returned home,
Raita-san was in the living room angry about Fusaya-san running away from home, right?
Not in the living room.
He was at the bottom of the stairs just inside the entrance.
Yeah.
Dad was really angry while he was fixing the shelf.
Fusaya leaving home must have really come as a shock.
Remember that last phone call he made to you?
Did something happen?
Yeah.
He called to ask if we'd found Fusaya.
I see.
You haven't even found anyone who's seen him.
I'm sorry. I suddenly feel sleepy.
The rest is up to you.
Hey, Dad?
Since his voice was so indistinct, I thought it must have really gotten to him.
What time did you receive that final phone call?
Around 3:30.
Is something the matter?
No.
I'll pass on your story.
Bye.
Tebai West Pharmacy
Take care.
Thank you.
Next customer, please.
You're Soho Kuremi-san, aren't you?
You seem to recognize me.
You know who I am, don't you?
Soho Kuremi-san, after running into your former classmate,
you heard about her engagement.
She was engaged to the son of a wealthy family.
Jealous that she was marrying into money,
you plotted to inflict misfortune upon her.
Huh?
There's something odd about this culprit.
By making her father Raita a murder victim.
That day, you visited the Oide family home
and secretly drugged Raita using sleeping pills you procured from your workplace.
The sudden sleepiness Raita mentioned
was due to the sleeping pills he was given taking effect.
In other words, Raita must've fallen asleep immediately afterwards just past 4 PM.
But he was killed 30 minutes later at 4:30.
They successfully put him to sleep as planned,
so why didn't the culprit act right away?
That 30 minute delay.
What does it mean?
I'm beat.
I can't believe I got injured after getting caught up in that accident.
Although I did receive a bunch of money in compensation.
That kind of thinking will get you killed.
Your injuries may not have been serious, but it's still a concussion.
That's what you thought of me?
Huh?
It's true that I was jealous.
I think she got what she deserved with this case.
When you started showing up everywhere I went, I laughed.
I thought they must really be struggling if they hired a famous detective.
But it sounds like you're actually a hack.
Wh-What?
I haven't fallen so low that I'd commit murder over something like that.
Could you not make a fool of me?
Then why did you keep showing up wherever that family went yesterday?
Is watching them from a distance and pretending to visit them
so I could laugh at them a crime?
It's certainly true that you're behaving suspiciously.
Don't treat me like a criminal when you don't even have any evidence.
Then at least help me with my investigation.
You're so persistent.
I'll give you some special information if you'll leave me alone.
Wh-What is it?
I saw a suspicious person exit that house
on the day of the incident when the 4:30 PM notice played.
What? What kind of person?
A short man wearing a hat with shaggy hair and a prominent nose.
Shaggy hair, prominent nose, wearing a hat,
and short.
That's Taira.
What? He's not the culprit?
I held onto that information so the family would owe me a favor.
Hold on.
Was he carrying a large bag of some kind?
A bag, huh?
I think all he had with him was a small shoulder bag.
Which means Taira didn't take the weapon with him.
He's starting to sound innocent.
Satisfied?
Good luck finding the real culprit, Mr. Great Detective.
Later.
Damn it!
What? From the autopsy?
Yeah. He asked me to check in a hurry.
If it was Mori-san's request, then I suppose I can show you.
But will you understand what you're looking at?
I'll tell him exactly what I saw. Don't worry.
Will you?
Single blow only
I knew it.
The person who set the gears of tragedy in motion for the Oide family was...
Really?
Yeah, I really got the job.
That's great.
Now Dad can rest in peace.
You came, Fusaya.
Sorry, Mom. Did I wake you?
It's fine.
I was just dreaming about you.
We were all celebrating you landing a job.
Mom, your dream came true.
What? You mean...
Yeah. They're going to hire me.
That's great. That's so great.
Hello? Yes.
Really? Yes.
Yes, I'll head back immediately.
What is it?
That was Mori-san.
He figured out who the culprit is.
Hiring him was the right choice after all.
You're getting married, and I got a job.
The gears of tragedy will finally stop turning now.
I'm going to go hear what he has to say.
Is it true?
After all, it's only been a day.
Well, he is a great detective.
You're right.
There's no harm in praying to god or asking great detectives for help.
What does that mean?
I'll meet you at your home.
Oide
Where have you been?
What about you?
How did things go with the suspicious woman?
She was just suspicious, nothing more.
I didn't find a single piece of evidence.
I see. Speaking of evidence, they didn't find any sleeping pills in Raita-san's body.
No alcohol either.
What?
That means my deduction is fundamentally wrong.
Wait, how do you even know that?
Lieutenant Tagiri asked me to tell you.
Mori-san.
You truly are the country's greatest detective.
Who is it? Who's the true culprit?
What?
Actually, I, uh—
I'm still working on that...
Mori-san?
Let's figure that out together.
Is this the rumored Sleeping Kogoro?
Allow me to describe my reasoning.
The culprit thought to have snuck into this house and killed your father
never existed in the first place.
What do you mean, Mori-san?
Before I explain the truth, I'd like to confirm something with you first.
The morning of the incident, Raita returned just as you were leaving the house
in order to avoid troubling your sister and her fiancee.
He returned to speak with you about your future, but the two of you got into a fight.
That's right. Why are you bringing that up now?
Was your fight with your father rather intense?
For example...
Yeah. Dad was really angry while he was fixing the shelf.
Your sister was referring to the hanging shelf up there.
And your fight was violent enough that it broke.
We got into a scuffle, and I threw my father off of me.
His back struck the wall, causing the shelf to fall.
I left while that was happening.
And that was around 10 AM.
Yes. More importantly, what do you mean, there's no culprit?
My father is—
Dead. You've heard the cause of death, haven't you?
Yes, but I'd never heard the term before.
Acute epidural hematoma.
Yes, I believe that's what it's called.
They're quite tricky.
Often the moment a person strikes their head and their time of death don't match.
What?
People who strike their head and fall unconscious due to a concussion
often recover quickly and appear totally lucid as though nothing happened.
This is known as a lucid interval.
The state can persist for three to six hours.
However, they then rapidly lose consciousness and die shortly later.
You're saying that's what happened to my father?
Most likely.
You mean...
Why don't you show a little more consideration for your family?
You and Raita got into a scuffle here.
The hanging shelf fell, and its corner struck Raita on the head.
That's when the acute epidural hematoma developed.
Raita probably lost consciousness for a moment,
but once the lucid interval began,
he got up as though nothing had happened.
Fusaya!
After that, he fixed the shelf,
and helped your other family members look for you,
but eventually he was overcome by fatigue as he lost consciousness.
Unaware that a burglar had entered his home...
The time is 4:30.
Please be careful as you return to your homes.
...he died.
But that's just one theory, right?
There could be a true culprit who snuck in after that burglar fled
and bludgeoned my father to death!
That's not possible.
There were no wounds on Raita's head aside from the one caused by the fatal blow.
And when the shelf was examined earlier,
it matched Raita's injury.
That's the truth, Fusaya-kun.
Which means my father died
because of me.
I prayed at this shrine yesterday evening and this morning, too,
for Mori-san to find the culprit.
Your prayers were answered.
Now we can finally begin preparing for your wedding.
Fusaya has found his way, and you'll be able to leave the hospital tomorrow.
The light has finally fallen on our family.
Yeah.
You can count on me, Fusaya-kun.
I promise I'll save the entire Oide family.
I, the great detective Mori Kogoro, so swear.
Mori-san, it's my job to stop the gears of tragedy from turning.
Fusaya-kun, you should decide how you'll live for yourself.
Thank you.
For my dad, my sister, my mom.
For my entire family.
I...
Tebai Police Station
After all, I'm the country's greatest detective.
Hey, Mister.
It's time for the last train.
Come on, old man. Wake up already.
Taking public transportation is good luck? Yeah, right.
We've arrived.
Well? Pretty tasteful, right?
I had a bite, but it's good.
Say, "Ah."
What was that?
What's wrong?
I-It's an emergency.
The manager...
The next episode of Conan is "Murder at the Townhouse Café!"