Smile Village
Welcome to the high-class resort-style nursing home "Smile Village!"
What?
Find the question that solves the mystery!
Apply miraculous detective skills to the secrets of the heart!
The Detective Boys are everyone's idols!
What plot is hidden behind their smiles?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
Intrigue at Smile Village
Come on. Everyone is waiting, Edogawa-sama.
Everyone?
Sakura-sama, Sumire-sama,
Botan-sama, Azami-sama, and...
Hey, Conan!
Conan-kun!
You're late.
Guys.
Those ladies over there are devoted fans of the Detective Boys.
D-Devoted fans?
It happened two weeks ago.
We were on a luxurious sightseeing bus tour of Beika City.
An acorn rolled down and down
and fell into a pond.
A loach swam up and...
Oh, my!
These are delicious.
Since then, the Detective Boys have become Sakura-sama,
Sumire-sama, Botan-sama and Azami-sama's idols.
They even formed a fan club.
Now then.
Since all the members of the Detective Boys are here...
Azami-sama.
Yes.
Botan-sama.
Sumire-sama.
Yes.
Sakura-sama.
Imagine that the Detective Boys are your own grandchildren
and show them to your rooms.
Actually, I'm not so sure about...
Edogawa-sama.
Think of them as your grandmothers, okay?
B-But...
Ondo.
Ondo?
Shibuzura Ondo (30) "Smile Village" Employee
Lay him down on that bed over there.
Thank you.
Anyway, this room is really luxurious.
I had it remodeled in a Baroque architectural style.
I see.
It was my dream to sing lullabies to my grandchildren.
Was it?
Hushabye, hushabye.
My good baby, sleep.
My good baby...
She put herself to sleep with her own lullaby.
Um, where's the bathroom?
Gotta go, gotta go.
Gotta go.
You guys, too?
I was with Botan-obaasan.
It was my dream to peel fruit from around the world for my grandchildren.
Say ah. Eat up.
Say ah.
Ah.
Excuse me for a moment.
I was with Azami-obaasama.
This is my collection.
What?
I especially like these dentures decorated with diamonds.
I'll show you some ventriloquism.
Ventriloquism?
Please tell me your name.
It's Ayumi.
My name is Azagami Azami.
Nice to meet you.
As soon as we entered Sumire-baachan's room...
Ow!
My butt, my butt!
You pinched me!
What are you doing, Grandma?
Pain, pain, fly away.
Hey, w-w-wait.
Crap!
Are you okay?
Oh, no. Oh, no.
So all the old women are insanely wealthy.
Indeed.
I guess we can let it slide since they're our fans.
It's the married couple Chief Director Hohoemi Waltz-san
and Administration Manager Tango-san that creep me out.
They're always smiling.
Yeah, they've been smiling since we met.
All right.
1 Million Yen Savings
They're smiling.
Maybe they have to smile because they're the chief director
and administration manager of Smile Village.
Isn't that what they call a customer service smile?
They're right.
Were those old hags...?
Yes, those old hags.
Smile Village
I never imagined that those old hags
would be scouted by another nursing home.
Considering how much money they have,
I understand why other nursing homes would want them to move in.
By letting them meet their idols the Detective Boys,
they'll stay at Smile Village.
We should thank the Detective Boys.
Indeed.
They appreciate us.
They used us.
What?
Waltz.
What is it, Tango?
We need to buy a high-class hotel in Dubai before those old hags catch on.
Using their money that we've been managing.
This is the list of high-class hotels Dubai we'll purchase.
If those old hags learned we're planning to buy a high-class hotel in Dubai,
I'm sure their blood pressure would rise.
What's Dubai?
A world famous resort city in the Middle East.
Middle East?
They said they're planning to buy a hotel using the old women's money.
They're using their money without their knowledge.
Those poor old ladies.
Tango, you decide which hotel we'll buy.
Waltz, you decide.
Darling, you're my husband. You should decide.
Oh, Waltz. You're my wife.
You should decide.
Tango.
Waltz.
They're dancing even though they're bad guys.
It's not pretty at all.
In fact, it's unsightly.
Waltz.
Tango.
I'm sick of taking care of wealthy old Japanese people.
So we'll use their money to buy a high-class hotel in Dubai
and open a Smile Village there.
Smile Village Dubai.
We'll care for the world's wealthy old people and use their money
to build a Smile Village in space.
I'm thinking about making Cosmic Smile Village Japanese style.
Japanese style.
And once we do,
I'll devote my heart the Manyoshu and wear a twelve-layered ceremonial kimono.
Devote your heart to the Manyoshu.
More importantly...
What is it, Waltz?
We need to make those old hags sign an exclusive contract
so they can't be scouted by another nursing home again.
You're right.
Exclusive contract!
Guys.
The Detective Boys?
Ondo!
Chief Director's Office
Let go of me!
Let go of me! Hey!
Let go! Let go!
Please let go!
Let me go!
Let us go!
Lock them in the basement.
What are you doing?
Where are you taking us?
Stop it! Stop!
Let us go!
Ow!
Hey, let us out! Let us out!
Ow. I hurt my teeth biting him as hard as I could.
Guys.
Conan?
Conan-kun?
They've installed multiple solid locks on the door.
Stand back. I'll break it open.
All right.
Please sign the contract.
By the way, where are the Detective Boys?
How many times do we have to tell you?
The Detective Boys left.
Oh, that's right.
Now sign the contract.
Okay.
Is there something else?
We were just wondering...
...what our idols...
...the Detective Boys...
...are doing right now.
We told you, they decided to leave.
You don't need to smile like that when you're angry.
We just need to sign, right?
Just need to sign, right?
Yes, please.
No, you don't!
The Detective Boys haven't left yet!
It's our idols, the Detective Boys!
Ondo!
Ondo?
Ondo-san says he likes working at Smile Village.
So he finds your plan to use the old ladies' money
you've been managing to buy a high-class hotel in Dubai...
Unforgivable.
Ondo-sama!
You're so wonderful!
Ondo-sama! Ondo-sama!
Everyone, we've almost arrived at the butcher's storefront.
The Detective Boys are eating croquettes.
So cute!
Chief Director Ondo-sama!
After all that time you spent, this is what you made?
We're unsuccessful because of your incompetence.
Why did the president and head of R&D have such a tense relationship?
I thought they were friends who shared the same ambition.
The next episode of Conan is "The Frying Pan of Hatred!"