We received a letter from someone named Nichihara Taisei-san
asking us to investigate why his friend committed suicide,
and came to an abandoned church deep in the mountains of Nagano.
However, Nichihara Taisei-san was the man who killed himself at the church.
At the instructions of the culprit who gathered us here,
we searched the abandoned church for codes.
But Wada-san was murdered,
followed by Kawasaki-san.
A journey of a thousand miles starts with the first step!
Solve 1,000 mysteries and enter a new world!
A snowy mountain lodge mystery!
Amuro and Wakita work together to solve the code!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
"The 36-Cell Perfect Game, Part Three!"
Which letter are we supposed to start with?
I have no idea.
If only we had a hint.
A hint?
There's nothing like that.
(Fujide Raito (27) High School Teacher)
You know, it's kind of annoying.
If you'd tell us about the club you've kept secret from us,
I think it might help us solve the code.
We don't mind telling you.
Just don't laugh.
Most people make fun of us when we tell them about it.
Sounds like your phone has service.
Hello? Hello?
It's Yamato with the Nagano police.
It'll take another hour to clear the tunnel of snow.
We'll be able to come get you in three more hours.
Sit tight until then.
Hey, wait!
He said they'll be here in three hours and to sit tight until then.
Three hours...
You can't be serious!
How are we supposed to sit tight for three hours
when there might be a murderer lurking in the area?
Someone else could be killed somehow during those three hours!
Maybe so, but the first victim Wada-kun headed to the toilet
where the crossbow trap was set because you drew his name.
And when Kawasaki-kun was poisoned in front of the bath
because he went to investigate a suspicious noise,
you're the one who decided how we'd choose which pair would go.
You think I'm responsible?
Was it Nishino-san who suggested the method used
to choose Nishino-san and Kawasaki-san's pair to investigate?
Yeah.
He emptied two out of three mint cases.
The pair that drew the case with mints would go check things out.
Naturally, with his ability to pick out losers,
Master Kogoro selected an empty case right off the bat.
About that...
I felt like no matter which case I picked, none of them would be losers.
What?
You mean it was a sham?
I didn't say that.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Are you trying to frame me?
I can't trust any of you anymore!
I'll protect myself!
Wait, Nishino-kun!
Let's go.
Nishino-kun, open the door.
We don't think you did it.
Shut up!
I'm not opening this door until the police arrive!
I'm going to survive!
Nobody's going to kill me!
Well, he'll be safe locked inside the study.
As long as the murderer isn't already hiding in there.
Anyway, don't you think it's odd?
Why was the detective Master Kogoro invited here?
If the culprit wanted to avenge Nichihara Taisei who killed himself here,
they only needed to invite you guys.
Inviting a detective here would get in the way of their own plans.
Now that you mention it, the letter said to bring a group of four, right?
Including us, nine people were invited here.
Perhaps the number nine has some significance.
One of the benefits of the number nine is that it's easier to create lots.
Compared to five or seven,
it's easier to create nine equally-sized pieces from a single sheet of paper.
It's the same if you use two sheets to make lots.
What else is related to the number nine?
Mahjong's nine gates.
Beethoven's 9th.
The nine-tailed fox.
Nine-ball pool.
Nine!
That's it. So that's how it is.
The culprit wanted nine people to show up for a variety of reasons.
Which means that fourth code indicates where the next crime scene will be.
I see exactly what's going on now.
I know whose life will be ended next,
and the identity of the murderer who intends to kill them.
Nishino-kun.
Come on out.
Don't stay locked up inside the study.
It's safer for all of us to stick together.
Nobody thinks you did it, Nishino-kun!
Of course I didn't do it.
I'm the one who drew the lot that sent Wada to the toilet where the crossbow was rigged,
but I couldn't have cheated.
When we went to investigate the strange sound,
Kawasaki's expression changed when he received a text from someone,
and he ran off to the bath where he was poisoned,
but that wasn't my fault.
So I'm not leaving this room until the police arrive.
You guys will try to pin it on me.
Huh?
A text? From Nishino, who's holed up in the study right now?
He figured out who did it?
I think...
the study should be around here.
You came.
I'll bring some tables and chairs over so it's easier for you to get down. Wait there.
So, who's the culprit?
First, take a look at this paper.
You found a new code?
Unfortunately, I can't read it.
Huh?
What are you doing?
Don't poison me!
Hey.
I don't want to die!
Don't kill me!
Then don't swallow it.
Huh?
That capsule in your right hand.
That poison.
Wh-What?
That's the plastic bottle you got from Fujide-san's bag.
Naturally, Fujide-san's fingerprints are on it.
If we testify that we heard your screams from outside the room,
the police would probably think
that Fujide-san snuck in here through the ceiling and poisoned you.
Even if Fujide-san claims that he received a text from you telling him to come here,
if you leave the phone used to send that message in this room,
they'd assume he sent that text to himself.
No, you're wrong.
I just panicked because you all came down from the ceiling.
And like I said earlier, it was a coincidence that Wada and Kawasaki were killed.
No, it was inevitable.
You made Wada-san head to the toilet
where the crossbow was rigged using a trick.
A trick?
When you don't have scissors,
cutting one sheet of paper into nine equal pieces
creates one piece with four torn edges in the center.
By giving that piece to Wada-san and making him write his name on it,
even after putting it inside the tissue box,
you could identify it using the torn edges.
I thought he drew them relatively quickly, though.
Since eight out of nine sheets have untorn edges, he prioritized choosing those,
and left the person he wanted to send to the bathroom for last.
But what about the mint cases?
Because the last remaining case happened to contain mints, Kawasaki and I were chosen.
Hey, Mister.
You said you felt like all the cases were losers, right?
Yeah.
None of the cases gave me a bad feeling.
Of course they didn't.
After all, all the cases were empty then.
What do you mean?
It's a simple trick.
If I shake the case using my left hand,
it doesn't make a sound, but when I shake it with my right...
See? It makes a noise.
You're right.
It's because I have a spare case with mints tucked inside my right sleeve.
Since Nishino-san said he brought plenty of snacks, he probably had spare mints, too.
K-Kawasaki and I only went to check things out
because we heard the sound of glass breaking.
If you set the ringtone of a phone you hid in this abandoned church beforehand
to the sound of breaking glass,
you could've made it ring anytime.
Maybe so, but it's true that when we went to investigate,
Kawasaki's expression changed after seeing a text from someone, and then he ran off.
When Kawasaki was poisoned in the bath and shouted,
I was with you guys.
You swiped Kawasaki-san's phone and poured honey on the screen,
so that Kawasaki-san would remove his gloves
and touch it when he received a text.
With honey on his fingers,
he'd be forced to run into the nearby bath and wash his hands.
Come to think of it,
Kawasaki-san held his handkerchief in his mouth when he washed his hands.
By swiping that handkerchief and applying poison to the section he'd bite,
since Kawasaki-san drank water after every activity he completed,
he'd swallow the poison on his lips along with the water.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You guys have been going on about tricks, slight of hand, and swiping objects,
but it's not like I'm a professional pickpocket.
You're a magician, aren't you?
Huh?
A magician-turned-pickpocket I arrested long ago happened to say the same thing.
Hold on.
There's an odd stain on the top card.
When holding a deck of cards face down,
he referred to the deck's "top" and "bottom" cards.
I'm sure a magician could swipe a phone or handkerchief.
While receiving a drink from Fujide-san,
you apparently put a stack of blank code sheets in his bag.
I don't know what you're talking about.
You invited nine people to this abandoned church
because you wanted nine lots for the first trick,
but also because it's the key to deciphering the code.
That's right.
It's baseball.
You initially called Wada-san the wife,
probably because he was the catcher.
In other words, in high school, you were on a baseball team.
If baseball is the key word, then that code can be solved easily.
In high school baseball, the players' numbers are determined by their defensive positions.
If the square thickly outlined in the middle represents the infield,
then you simply read the nine letters in the order of the player numbers.
Based on that, the code we first received reads,
"It's time to play ball."
Yeesh!
The deck collapsed, and all the cars have fallen to the bottom of the ravine.
The code we found next stuck to the chapel door reads,
"One out in the toilet."
The code we found in the rooms we searched reads,
"Two outs in the bath."
The code found next to Kawasaki-san's body reads,
"Three outs in the study."
And the code you just handed Fujide-san signifying a perfect crime reads,
"Perfect game."
By hiding the blank code sheets in Fujide-san's bag, you wanted to make us believe
that after gathering his high school classmates here, killing himself and two others,
and leaving behind an indecipherable code at the crime scenes,
Fujide Raito-san was gloating over committing the perfect crime.
Later, once the police discovered that the victims were on the same baseball team,
this code would be solved eventually.
I don't get it, though.
I understand you inviting Fujide-san so you could frame him,
but why invite Ikue-san?
Was it just to have nine people?
I wanted to show Ikue
that Fujide, the man you dumped your high school boyfriend Nichihara for,
is unbelievably evil.
E-Evil? What are you talking about?
I'm sure you guys have heard
about the nine-error five-inning mercy ruled perfect game.
Yeah, between Nagano Kawanaka Academy
and the high school attached to Shinano University.
Were you guys members of the Kawanaka Academy baseball team that lost that game?
Yeah. I didn't play
because I was injured in the quarterfinal regional preliminary game,
but I could tell from the other side of the TV
that these guys lost that game on purpose!
They threw the game?
Wada, Kawasaki, and Fujide were committing errors like crazy.
Since they got into Shinano University, they must've had a secret agreement.
The Shinano University high school lost in the finals,
but they became famous for their strength in academics and sports after that game.
And at that time, our team's ace was Nichihara Taisei.
Since he was a kid, he pitched crazy fast.
People thought he'd be drafted, but his reputation tanked after that game.
When he wasn't drafted,
he unsuccessfully tried to join non-association
and independent leagues and ended up a free agent,
so he hung himself in this church where we used to play baseball as kids.
All because they threw the game and I wasn't there to stop it!
Is that true?
It's true that we lost on purpose.
But it wasn't to get into college.
We did it for Nicchi.
Huh? What are you talking about?
We won the first game 1-0 in extra innings at the bottom of the 14th.
The second game ended in a tie after 15 innings,
and we barely won the rematch 1-0 in 13 innings.
Because he played 42 innings
and threw roughly 1,000 pitches in such a short amount of time,
Nicchi's shoulder was at its limit.
We didn't intend to lose from the beginning,
but once we started to fall behind, Wada said,
"Let's get the mercy rule invoked for the sake of Nicchi's future."
"He'd insist on pitching until the end otherwise."
But Nicchi's shoulder was already shot.
He's the one who dumped me.
He said he couldn't make me happy with his body the way it was.
No...
It was a coincidence that we got into Shinano University.
We all apologized to him after the game, but because you weren't there...
What...
What have I done?
The murderer didn't speak a word after that, but outside the church,
the blizzard continued to blow,
as though it was sobbing his remorse for him.
Three hours later, the blizzard stopped, and dawn broke.
Nagano police cars arrived in droves.
I can't believe two people were killed.
Sorry about that.
Conan-kun, good to see you again.
So, who are those two guys behind you?
I'm Mori-sensei's number one student Amuro Toru.
And I'm his number two student Wakita Kanenori.
This bum has two students?
Wow, just like Komon-sama.
Komei, let's start inspecting the crime scene.
Oh?
We meet again,
Mori-san.
I haven't seen you since the Kid case.
Who are those two?
They're my students.
Komei, what are you doing chatting over there?
Hurry up.
You're right.
Every moment is precious.
Not a moment should be wasted.
As they say, time is money.
(I'll kill Sasano Prepare yourself)
A death threat?
Yes. That's what I wanted to talk to you about.
Apparently everyone has a grudge against the president.
That guy with the mustache must be the second.
That mustache looks just like the current president's.
This is a murder.
Tachikawa-san, I'm scared.
Damn it.
The next episode of Conan is, "Who Poisoned the Victim!"