Haruyama Junpei (37) Café Manager
The victim is Haruyama Junpei-san, 37 years old,
who operates a café by the train station.
He was killed last night around 9 PM.
We believe he was attacked after closing his shop and heading towards his home past this area.
At any rate, he was stabbed repeatedly.
It's safe to assume the suspect's motive is a grudge.
All right.
Gather information from the locals and—
Uh...
Is something the matter?
Nothing. I just thought he might show up.
In any case, gather information and draw up a list of his acquaintances.
Yes, sir.
A journey of a thousand miles starts with the first step!
Solve 1,000 mysteries and enter a new world!
Curtains rise on a man's quest for revenge.
Follow that suspect! Where is he now?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
"Out For Revenge, Part One!"
It's on the fifth floor of this building.
Inspector!
I knew he'd show up.
Are you here on a case?
You're gathering information for that case that was on the news, right?
Yeah...
One of the victim's friends is inside this building.
I see.
Then allow me to assist you.
Me, too!
You must be Natsukawa Yoji-san, the investment consultant.
Yes, that's me.
What business do the police have with me?
We'd like to ask you a few questions.
Would that be all right?
Come in.
You have guests.
Don't mind them.
Well?
What did you want to ask me?
You've probably already seen it on the news,
but your friend Haruyama Junpei-san was found murdered this morning.
Huh?
Looks like your guests knew Haruyama-san, too.
Excuse me, but who are you two?
We've got nothing to do with this.
I was just thinking about how I'd heard that story on the news.
For reference, could we get your names?
My name is Fuyuki Ryuzaburo.
I make a meager living in finance.
I'm Akiba Miyako.
I work in real estate.
Neither of them are on our list of acquaintances.
Well?
What did you want to ask?
Do you know anyone who may have held a grudge against the late Haruyama-san?
There wasn't anyone like that.
What about you two?
Who knows?
I don't know anyone named Haruyama.
You guys...
Even if I knew Haruyama,
the murder happened last night, right?
If you investigate my whereabouts at that time, you'll find that I have an alibi.
I have nothing to do with the case.
Likewise.
It would be wise to take your investigation elsewhere.
Those three are hiding something.
Most likely.
But why hide what they know?
They're either protecting the culprit
or there's some reason why they can't tell us.
The Next Day
All right.
I'll get the truth out of him for the inspector.
He did throw up a smokescreen yesterday.
This place is both a residence and office, right?
Yeah.
Did he go out this morning?
It's unlocked.
Natsukawa-san!
Natsukawa-san, are you all right?
Damn.
Kid, call the inspector.
Got it!
As we told you earlier, last night,
Natsukawa Yoji-san was murdered as well.
He was killed in the same manner as Haruyama-san.
Fuyuki-san and Akiba-san,
you know why we asked you to come here, don't you?
You're going to tell us everything you've been hiding.
Damn.
It wasn't a groundless fear after all.
If both Haruyama and Natsukawa have been killed, then it must be him.
Him, who?
Komoto.
Komoto Takashi.
Who is this Komoto?
Haruyama, Natsukawa, and the two of us got to know each other as regulars at a bar.
That was ten years ago.
(10 Years Ago)
The four of us had dreams and ambitions, but we lacked the cash.
We told each other that if only we had the capital, we'd manage somehow.
That's when Fuyuki made a suggestion.
"I have a high school classmate named Komoto Takashi."
"He inherited a huge amount of money from his parents."
"Let's swindle him out of his money."
"He's a naïve rich boy. I guarantee it'll work."
We presented him with a bogus investment opportunity
and split the money we swindled.
We even hired a lawyer to cover up our fraud.
He must have lost hope after being betrayed by a former classmate.
He left Japan and moved to South America.
I see.
In other words, the four of you
ganged up on Komoto and preyed upon him.
Th-That was ten years ago.
B-But the other day,
we received a frightened call from Haruyama.
He said Komoto was peering into his shop.
He thought he may have returned to Japan to get revenge.
But the three of us laughed it off,
saying it must've been someone else and that he was imagining it.
But then we saw on the news that Haruyama had been murdered.
We thought it might actually be Komoto.
So the three of you gathered because you were worried.
They must've been right in the middle of that.
That's when we visited Natsukawa with the police.
And now that Natsukawa has been murdered as well...
Komoto's the only guy who resented Haruyama and Natsukawa.
Confirm their story ASAP.
Yes, sir.
We'll be asking you for more details down at the station.
(MPD Beika Police Station)
According to the Immigration Bureau, one week ago, Komoto Takashi returned to Japan.
I knew it.
He's already checked out, but we also found the hotel where he was staying.
We were able to collect Komoto's fingerprints from the belongings he left behind.
And?
They matched the fingerprints collected from the scenes of both Haruyama's and Natsukawa's murders.
So Komoto is the murderer, then.
We also found this.
This is an image of Komoto Takashi captured by the hotel's security cameras.
This is what he looks like now?
His hair is snow white.
Also, Komoto apparently said to an employee
that he has an incurable illness and doesn't have long to live.
I see.
With death approaching,
Komoto returned to Japan and murdered Haruyama and Natsukawa,
the men who betrayed him, one after another.
What's wrong with him?
He must be crazy.
Why get revenge now for something that happened ten years ago?
I was curious about that,
so I asked the local police about it.
Regardless of his motive,
we can't allow him to kill anyone else.
You'll act as their bodyguards and do whatever it takes to find Komoto Takashi.
Yes, sir!
It's a brutal serial murder case,
but there's nothing left for me to do.
Yeah, seems that way.
The Next Day
Shikigawa Valley
(The Uedas)
See? It's a little scary, isn't it?
But the view is incredible.
It certainly is!
I know I shouldn't be out walking around,
but my client wanted to meet outdoors.
It can't be helped.
I need to check out the area beforehand.
I didn't say anything.
Now this is a view.
Akiba-san, I'm going to go check out that noise.
Stay there!
Akiba...
K-Komoto...
It's all...
It's all your guys' fault!
Crap!
Die!
Akiba-san! What happened?
K-Komoto just fell.
What? Komoto fell?
There's no way he survived a fall from that height.
Yeah.
You're saying this is what happened.
You were lured away by a noise in the thicket.
While you were looking elsewhere,
Komoto attacked Akiba-san, and after a struggle, Komoto's foot slipped and he fell.
I'm sorry.
You didn't see the moment Komoto fell?
No.
What? Are you trying to say I pushed him?
No, I didn't say that.
It's true.
She's telling the truth.
That man accidentally fell by himself.
We saw it, too.
Yeah.
See?
That person must've seen it, too.
Huh?
They're not here anymore.
Looks like there's several witnesses.
Yeah. In other words, Komoto Takashi accidentally fell to his death.
Looks that way.
But where is the body?
Is it possible that he survived and fled?
It did take us a while to get down here.
You're saying he disappeared during that time?
It's not impossible.
But a fall from this height?
Detective Takagi, how did Komoto get here?
There's a rental car that Komoto seems to have driven here.
Then if he survived, even if he was injured,
wouldn't he have used that car to flee?
Maybe he was so badly injured that he couldn't drive a car.
What?
In any case, I'll check out the hospitals in the area.
Good idea.
What a waste of time.
There's no way he survived a fall from there.
Anyway, I can go now, right?
That should be fine. Chiba.
Yes, sir.
What?
I don't need a bodyguard anymore, do I?
He's dead now.
It's just to be safe.
He'll escort you home.
Let's go.
Now that the suspect is dead, the case is closed.
It's not what I would've wanted, though.
I know what Takagi said,
but it's hard to believe he survived a fall from up there.
Right.
But why haven't they found a body?
It doesn't look that deep.
It wouldn't be odd if the body got caught on the rocks at the bottom of the cliff.
(Shikigawa General Hospital)
I see.
No injured patients matching that description have arrived.
Thank you.
Are you a police detective?
Yes?
If you're looking for him, then is he the suspect in a case or something?
Yes.
In that case, I hope you find him soon.
It would be terrible if he did anything.
Yes...
Hello, Inspector Megure?
I didn't find anything. Komoto hasn't shown up at the hospital.
Komoto destroyed himself, then.
He fell headfirst and screamed all the way down to hell.
In other words, you and I survived.
We have the devil's luck.
2 Days Later
Stabbed repeatedly with a knife.
Same method.
T.K.?
Komoto Takashi.
Akiba-san was murdered last night around 11 PM.
Komoto Takashi's fingerprints were found on the lighter left next to the body.
So Komoto survived his fall from that cliff.
And he has resumed his revenge murders.
Inspector Megure.
I've learned why Komoto sought revenge now.
When he first moved to South America,
Komoto Takashi sometimes lost consciousness.
It was a psychological condition caused by an extreme distrust of others
and posed no threat to his life.
It must've been caused by the betrayal of those four.
Since it hadn't happened during the past several years,
he believed he had recovered from his condition.
But one month ago,
Komoto was told by his doctor that he didn't have much time left to live,
so he left on a trip with his beloved wife
to make his final days the happiest they could be.
However, his condition caused a tragedy on their journey.
They got into an accident while on their trip.
While Komoto was attempting to call an ambulance for his badly injured wife,
he lost consciousness due to his condition,
and his wife passed away.
He was still suffering the effects of their betrayal ten years later.
And if that took the life of his beloved wife,
I can understand why he sought revenge.
Damn it.
He blamed us for the death of his wife, too?
Save me.
Please!
(Incoming Call From Number-Withheld Public Telephone)
Hello?
It's Komoto.
K-Komoto?
You're the last one left, Fuyuki.
You'll pay for deceiving me ten years ago.
Spare me, Komoto!
I was wrong. I'll return your money.
I'll return ten times what we took, okay?
Money, money, money.
You think you can erase your sins with money.
No wonder you think you can buy your own life with money, too.
You're the same scumbag you ever were.
K-Komoto?
Komoto, hello? Komoto!
Spare me, Komoto!
Find him.
Do whatever it takes to find Komoto.
Yes, sir.
So his revenge wasn't over yet.
Yeah, but why did he bother to call him this time?
Because he's the one he hated the most.
He's the one who suggested they swindle him.
That's true, but...
Something's not right.
There's only one conceivable explanation.
He's got something wrapped around his stomach.
That's Mr. X?
He wouldn't bother retrieving a dead body
or burying one in the mountains unless he was really determined.
Retrieve a dead body?
Wait a minute.
What if he had still been alive then?
That would mean...
The next episode of Conan is "Out For Revenge, Part Two!"