A dine and dash?
A journey of a thousand miles starts with the first step!
Solve 1,000 mysteries and enter a new world!
A dine and dash in Beika City?
A popular idol is behaving mysteriously!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
"The Idol Whose Smile Disappeared!"
Poirot
Detective Agency
Come in.
Excuse me.
Starting today, I transferred from the Haido City police box to the Beika City police box on 4-chome.
My name is Yamasato Futoshi.
Officer Yamasato?
There's a case I'd like you to crack, Detective Mori Kogoro.
Crack a case?
Yes, crack a case.
Our story begins with a single phone call I received
at the Beika City 4-chome police box today.
Hello, this is Beika City 4-chome—
What? A dine and dash at a family restaurant?
I'll be right there!
I headed there immediately, but...
What? The dine and dash has been resolved?
Seconds before I arrived,
the blonde girl who dine and dashed returned with her mother to apologize.
Seconds before, huh?
We passed by each other.
When I arrived at the restaurant, I encountered a sobbing blonde girl and her mother,
who was supporting her, in front of the restaurant.
According to the mother, her daughter forgot her wallet and panicked.
So it's been solved, then.
Why don't we have a drink to celebrate?
No, thank you. I'm currently on duty.
And besides, the case isn't over yet.
The problem is what the waitstaff said.
They claim the girl who dine and dashed
and the girl who came to apologize seemed like completely different people.
The girl who dine and dashed was a blonde wearing sunglasses,
but she seemed like a different person from the girl who just came to apologize with her mother.
What do you mean?
When I brought the chocolate parfait to her table,
I got a glimpse of her face.
The smile she had then looked just like hers.
It's cold!
Her? You mean...
Apparently her smile looked just like that of idol Kakurai Kayoko.
Kakurai Kayoko?
Actually... there was another similar case.
It happened three months ago at the police box in Haido City where I was stationed at the time.
(3 Months Earlier)
Hello, this is Haido City 5-chome.
What? A dine and dash at a ramen restaurant?
Yes. I'll be right there.
I headed there immediately, but...
What? The case has been resolved?
According to the owner, as in today's family restaurant case,
it was a blonde woman in sunglasses who dine and dashed.
As soon as she finished eating her ramen, she suddenly ran off.
The owner immediately called it in,
but after ten minutes, the blonde and a woman claiming to be her older sister showed up.
According to the sister, her younger sister forgot her wallet and panicked.
I see. Those are similar stories.
So, did the owner of the ramen restaurant also say
that the blonde with sunglasses looked like Kakurai Kayoko?
No.
What?
That evening, at the Haido City Hall, there was a DDPP handshake event.
DDPP?
It's the idol group Kakurai Kayoko belongs to.
Kakurai Kayoko is the star of DDPP.
Her smile is remarkably cute.
Her popularity alone has exploded.
At the Haido City handshake event, there was a huge line in front of only Kakurai Kayoko's booth.
But apparently, the other members thought poorly of her.
On one occasion, they became jealous of the amount of gifts she received.
On another occasion,
they all ignored Kakurai Kayoko when she showed up late to a dance lesson.
On yet another occasion, in the powder room...
Due to that string of incidents, the smile finally disappeared from her face.
She was taken away in an ambulance.
That night, the blonde in sunglasses dine and dashed at a ramen restaurant in Haido City.
I didn't get it at the time,
but after what the Beika City family restaurant waitstaff said today...
The smile of the blonde in sunglasses who dine and dashed
looked just like Kakurai Kayoko's.
That's when it clicked.
The blonde in sunglasses who dine and dashed
at a Haido City ramen restaurant three months ago
may have been Kakurai Kayoko as well.
After suffering the jealousy of the other DDPP members, Kakurai Kayoko was distraught.
She awoke in a hospital room and felt hungry.
She looked around the room and saw her bag there.
Inside her bag were the blonde wig and sunglasses she wore onstage.
Disguising herself using those, she left the hospital room
wandered around the city at night,
and eventually dine and dashed at a ramen restaurant.
Currently, Kakurai Kayoko is taking a break from the entertainment industry.
She's recuperating at a hospital in the countryside.
Did the distraught and recuperating Kakurai Kayoko leave the hospital in the countryside,
disguise herself as the blonde in sunglasses,
and dine and dash at a Beika City family restaurant?
Great Detective Mori Kogoro, I'd like to ask you again.
Please crack this case!
Huh? What? Incredible!
He's already asleep and solving—no, masterfully cracking the case while he naps!
What?!
He's just asleep because he drank too many beers.
I'm home!
Dad, listen to this.
Just now, at Beika Park...
Sorry for interrupting.
I'm currently cracking a case.
Cracking a case?
That's right. I'm cracking a case.
I asked for his help.
I'm Yamasato from the Beika City 4-chome police box.
Nice to meet you. I'm Mori's daughter Ran.
What case are you solving?
More importantly, Ran, weren't you about to say something?
Oh, right. I just saw her.
Saw who?
Kakurai Kayoko-chan.
What?!
You saw Kakurai Kayoko?
Where? Where did you see her?
Where? At Beika Park.
Tell me all about it!
On my way home from school just now,
I was walking through Beika Park with my friends.
It looked like there was an on-location shoot for a drama or movie.
We wanted to see who was appearing in it,
so we searched the area.
That's when we found a woman who looked like an attendant
standing in front of a van.
We were certain someone famous was inside.
We snuck behind the van without being seen by her and looked inside.
Start!
No.
No, no.
I think they were filming Kakurai Kayoko-chan's first movie
after returning from her hiatus.
How old was Kakurai Kayoko's female manager?
What?
Around 40?
How old was her female attendant?
The woman's age?
Around 20?
That's about the same age as Kakurai Kayoko.
Um, I've got something to do, so I'm going to go.
It seems the thing I personally feared the most has happened.
The distraught and recuperating Kakurai Kayoko should've retired from the entertainment industry.
But her agency—no,
the entertainment industry is trying to force Kakurai Kayoko
to return when she hasn't recovered yet.
Detective Mori Kogoro.
What I'm about to tell you are my personal thoughts.
It's certainly not any kind of logical deduction.
Please listen.
Kakurai Kayoko came to Beika City in order to film her first movie after her return.
However, her mental health had not yet recovered.
Unable to withstand the pressure,
she disguised herself as the blonde in sunglasses, left the shooting location,
and headed to a family restaurant where she dine and dashed on a chocolate parfait.
Later, in order to hide the truth,
her female manager and attendant disguised themselves
as a mother and daughter and went to pay her bill.
That's just me clumsily thinking aloud.
I'd be delighted if you were able to use it for future reference.
Now then, Detective Mori Kogoro! Crack the case, please!
What do you want me to deduce after that?
Crack the case, please!
Does this guy just want to show off his detective skills to a famous detective?
Yikes.
Crack the case, please!
Okay, okay.
Does this case really need a detective to crack it, anyway?
I shall crack this case.
Thank you—ow, ow.
I hit my head on your shoes. Ouch...
Shoes?
Conan, get in touch with Ran.
Okay.
What was up with that police officer?
What is it, Dad?
Ran, where did Kakurai Kayoko's tears fall when you saw her inside the car
at the filming location in Beika Park?
Where were they falling?
On the red shoes she was wearing.
What kind of shoes was her attendant wearing?
Her attendant's shoes?
They were sneakers.
Officer Yamasato, where did the crying daughter's tears fall
while being held by her mother at the restaurant?
If they fell on sneakers, then the daughter was actually the attendant.
If they fell on red shoes, then it's possible that...
It's possible that...
Red shoes...
What?
Uh, excuse me.
Was it Kakurai Kayoko herself who went to pay the bill?
The truth is stranger than fiction.
It's a bit odd for me to say,
but allow to me admit that even I, the great detective Mori Kogoro,
am a bit surprised by this conclusion.
I can hang up now, right?
The mother and daughter who went to the Beika City restaurant
to apologize were the manager and Kakurai Kayoko herself.
Does that mean Kakurai Kayoko isn't distraught?
Kakurai Kayoko is not distraught.
Three months ago, on the day of the Haido City ramen restaurant incident,
after suffering the jealousy of the other DDPP members
and being taken to the hospital,
as you deduced, Kakurai Kayoko woke up hungry,
took the disguise in her bag and left the hospital room.
Remember what the manager disguised as her mother and older sister said.
My daughter forgot her wallet and panicked.
My sister forgot her wallet and panicked.
That was probably the truth.
If that's true, then...
She really did...
...forget her wallet and panic?
Does that mean Kakurai Kayoko is just an airhead?
It's certainly possible.
Air Head
No...
Kakurai Kayoko...
An airhead?
My Kakurai Kayoko isn't an airhead!
My Kakurai Kayoko isn't an airhead,
my Kakurai Kayoko isn't an airhead,
my Kakurai Kayoko isn't an airhead.
I need a drink, too!
You're on duty, Officer Yamasato!
Officer Yamasato, what's wrong with your Kakurai Kayoko being an airhead?
Officer Yamasato, you underestimate idols.
I've underestimated idols?
Going forward, idols must be strong.
Strong?
Perhaps what Ran saw wasn't her practicing her smile,
but practicing how not to smile.
No. No!
It's possible.
Kakurai Kayoko is trying to become a new person.
A new Kakurai Kayoko...
Your Kakurai Kayoko is strong.
She has the strength to withstand the jealousy of the other DDPP members.
And above all, Kakurai Kayoko has acting skills.
Kakurai Kayoko's acting skills?
Yeah, right. That's not possible.
Kakurai Kayoko has a cute smile.
That's all she has.
She's more than that.
Why did the female manager appear to be her mother at the Beika City family restaurant?
Why did she appear to be her older sister at the Haido City ramen restaurant?
Why?
Remember what the waitstaff said.
The girl who dine and dashed and the girl accompanied
by her mother seemed like two different people.
That was because of Kakurai Kayoko's acting.
She played a daughter at the Beika City family restaurant
and a younger sister at the Haido City ramen restaurant.
What is this if not acting skills?
Kakurai Kayoko... is an actress?
Yes.
Right now, Kakurai Kayoko is attempting to be reborn as a new Kakurai Kayoko.
Great Detective Mori Kogoro,
you've cracked the case marvelously!
You're on soon.
Okay.
Thank you, Great Detective Mori Kogoro.
Well, goodbye.
By the way, Officer Yamasato, shouldn't you get back to your duties at the police box?
Oh, my shift ended a long time ago.
Oh, really?
He finally left.
We're filming.
Now face the sun and shout.
Kayoko
Blood?
What are you doing, Ayumi-chan?
I'm looking for a four-leaf clover.
Impossible.
She covered her eye just now.
Her right eye must be damaged.
The next episode of Conan is "Picking Wild Plants and Clovers, Part One!"