Kudo
A journey of a thousand miles starts with the first step!
Solve 1,000 mysteries and enter a new world!
Sera's hypothesis and fearless smile!
The Akai family closes in on the truth!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
"The Antique Tray Can't Be Hidden, Part One!"
What?
You're going to make a fortune off an antique dish?
Come on.
Have you forgotten your painful experience with the Persian rug?
I know.
That's why I had an appraiser look at it this time.
He called to let me know he has my results, so I'm on my way to get them now.
So, where'd you get the dish?
I've taken you kids before to my uncle Agasa Kurisuke's villa.
Oh, right.
That villa with the hidden star, sun, and moon code.
That's right.
That was before you came here, Ai-kun.
Yes, I heard about it from the children.
It started as a treasure hunt you set up at the villa,
but the code led up into an attic.
They even found a mummified corpse and plates for making counterfeit bills.
In the end, they caught the scoundrel who wanted the plates.
That's right.
I found an old wooden board in the back of a shelf
when I went to hide the toys for the treasure hunt.
Since the handwriting was so nice,
I brought it home and put it on display.
Just the other day,
I realized it wasn't a board, but a flat box with a sliding lid.
I found an antique dish inside.
Huh.
My uncle Kurisuke was a wealthy man.
I thought it might be a rather valuable antique,
so I asked an appraiser I know to appraise it for me.
Are you sure it was okay for you to take the dish?
Uncle Kurisuke passed away 50 years ago.
Aunt Teiko who inherited the villa said I could do whatever I wanted
with the things inside the villa.
She passed away last year anyway, so it's mine now.
So, why'd you call me here?
I'm the one who invited you over.
I'd like you to do something about her.
Her?
That tomboy named Sera Masumi who's watching us from behind the gate as we speak.
That's why you had me come in through the back?
That's right.
If you came in through the front door, she would've come with you.
So, why is she watching this house?
You know, don't you?
Well, it's not the house.
It's probably you.
What?
Why would she be watching me?
Well, a-actually...
What?!
She suspects that I've been turned into a child by that drug, just like you?
How could you expose our secret like that?
Do you want to die?
It's not like that.
Sera's got keen instincts.
Apparently she asked Ran and Sonoko if they knew any mature kids besides me.
They told her you fit that description.
So, do you know any other kinds who are strangely mature for their age?
It's got to be Ai-chan, right?
Yeah, Haibara Ai.
She lives at Professor Agasa's house.
She's more than just mature.
She's got a totally cool personality.
She's probably got a lot of questions for you.
In any case, I don't know what she wants to ask me,
but if your so-called "Black Organization" finds out
that we've been turned into children by APTX 4869,
they'll kill both you and I,
as well as anyone associated with us.
Yeah.
I know that.
D-Did she get impatient and decide to try a direct approach instead?
Hey!
Make her leave!
What?
Hurry!
Jeez.
How am I supposed to make her leave?
Yes?
S-Subaru-san.
I received a bunch of cherries from an acquaintance, so I came to share.
More importantly, did you see anyone at the gate?
Yes, I did.
There was a girl wearing a motorcycle helmet.
Huh?
Conan-kun, what are you doing here?
I came here early this morning because I had something to do.
Oh, really?
In that case—
By the way, Professor,
how did the appraisal of that antique go?
I was just on my way to get the results.
He said he'd show me something interesting he's appraising while I'm there.
Something interesting?
Are you familiar with Chinese black lacquer trays?
They're wooden objects painted with layers of black and red lacquer
until they're completely black with patterns carved into them.
You mean like the tray that appeared on the appraisal TV show the other day?
I think it was worth 100 million yen.
100 million yen?
That's right.
Apparently three people saw that program
and realized they had similar trays at home and asked him to appraise them.
Surprisingly, all three trays have exactly the same crane design on them.
Does that mean of the three trays, two of them are fake?
Exactly. He said the real tray would be worth several tens of millions of yen.
He invited me to come watch him explain the difference
between the real tray and the fakes to the people who hired him.
I see.
In that case, would it be all right if I accompanied you to this appraiser's house?
I'd like to see that black lacquer tray for myself.
S-Sure, that's fine.
What will you do?
I think I'll pass.
I'm not interested in antiques.
What?
So I'll watch the house for you, along with that girl.
You're not interested in old trays either, are you?
So that's her angle.
I'm... I'm going with the professor!
I love old trays!
Then maybe I'll go, too.
After all, it's worth several tens of millions of yen, right?
Suddenly I'm interested.
Then why don't all five of us go?
I-I suppose.
That's that. I look forward to spending time with you, Ai-chan.
Come on, we're both girls. There's no need to be so cold.
Hey, Subaru-san.
Come with me.
Why did you invite Sera?
Sorry, kid.
I couldn't allow her to continue behaving suspiciously at the gate.
Besides...
There's something I've been wanting to ask my sister.
Hey, the character for "Ai" in Haibara Ai means sadness, right?
That's a little unusual, isn't it? Did your parents choose that?
It looks like she's asleep.
Excuse me. Nishitsu-san!
It's Agasa, here for my appointment.
Nishitsu-san!
Maybe his hearing aid is acting up again.
I'll go get him. Wait there.
Understood.
Nishitsu-san.
By hearing aid, did he mean the "Deaf Angel" he made before?
Yes.
The Deaf Angel works fine at first,
but quickly develops issues and it becomes difficult to hear anything.
Like they say, names and natures often agree.
"Names and natures often agree?"
You know some difficult phrases.
Yes, is there a problem?
Now she's fighting back.
High quality lacquer has been applied in layers.
It's truly exquisite.
There are probably people who would pay 80 million—no, 100 million for this.
I asked you to wait in the other room.
What's the matter?
Did you call me?
In that case, I must apologize.
It seems my hearing aid is acting up again.
More importantly, take a look.
Look at its dignified and magnificent appearance.
This is the real black lacquer tray.
Unfortunately, it's not the one you brought.
No...
However...
That's my tray!
Excuse me.
Nishitsu-san.
It's Agasa, here for my appointment.
Where are you, Nishitsu-san?
Nishitsu-san.
Nishitsu-san?
What happened?
Who did this to you?
Th-This... this is the real tray...
The real tray?
Wh-What's this?
A crane design?
Must be the black lacquer tray he mentioned.
In any case, we need to call an ambulance and the police.
Oh, no. My phone is in my car.
Nishitsu-san, wait here. I'll be right back.
What?
He was bleeding from the head and lying on the ground?
The appraiser?
Yeah, with the black lacquer tray right in front of him.
Did you call an ambulance?
The thing is, I left my phone in the car.
Haibara, call an ambulance and the police.
Got it.
Take that turn. It's the second room from the end.
That's the room.
What's this?
It's no use. He's dead.
Hey, Conan-kun.
I don't see a tray anywhere.
What?
What's going on here?
You're making quite a lot of noise.
What's wrong?
Who are you?
You're not scoundrels here to steal my tray, are you?
If you're outsiders, could you please leave?
He lost a lot of blood from his head.
There's also a rather deep stab wound on his back.
According to the coroner,
the cause of death was most likely aortic injury
due to the stab wound in his back inflicted by a pointed bladed object.
Pointed bladed object?
Yes.
The weapon was almost certainly that spear closest to us over there.
The culprit's fingerprints weren't on it,
but there's blood on the tip of the blade.
There are also marks on the metal base that were made when it was used to strike something.
I see.
Judging by the fact that the victim Nishitsu-san was still alive
when Agasa-san first came to this room around 2PM today,
after knocking down the victim with the spear,
the culprit probably hid inside a wardrobe since Agasa-san arrived.
And after Agasa-san left the room to call the police and an ambulance,
using the spear they used to knock him down,
they finished him off by stabbing him in the back.
By the way, Agasa-san, what are you doing here?
I asked Nishitsu-san to appraise an old dish for me.
I came to hear the results.
I brought some friends who happened to be at my house.
If you asked him to appraise something, does that mean...
Yes.
The victim Nishitsu-san was an antique art appraiser.
But why would someone kill an antique art appraiser?
Probably because of the black lacquer tray.
Black lacquer tray?
Yes.
It's a type of Chinese lacquerware.
Apparently he was asked to appraise one worth several tens of millions of yen.
Agasa-san said the tray was in front of the victim
as he was bleeding from his head and barely breathing in this room,
but that tray is no longer there.
Perhaps that means that's what the culprit was after.
Actually, if that black lacquer tray is in that box over there...
This tray here.
Then it hasn't been stolen.
See the two similar boxes next to that one?
Why don't you take a look inside those?
Seriously?
All three contain the same tray.
What's going on here?
He happened to receive three requests to appraise trays
with the same pattern at the same time.
Because a similar black lacquer tray
was appraised at 100 million yen on an appraisal TV show.
100 million yen?
This tray is worth that much?
Apparently the victim said he'd explain the difference between
the real tray and the fakes to us and the three clients who hired him to appraise them.
It's natural to think there's a culprit who killed the appraiser,
and put the real tray in their own box
in order to get their hands on that fortune among you three.
I see.
Then one at a time, why don't you tell us
your name, profession,
and what you were doing where around 2PM when the murder took place?
My name is Tojima Motoyuki.
I'm a salaryman at a securities company.
I realized there was a tray identical to the one seen on the appraisal TV show
in the storage shed I inherited from my father, who passed away last year,
so I hired an appraiser.
I thought it'd be nice if mine were worth that much.
So you wanted to sell your tray for money.
I don't have any money problems.
There's just nothing better than having a nest egg for after retirement.
What were you doing where around 2PM?
Nishitsu-san said his professor friend would be arriving soon,
so he asked the three of us to wait in this reception room.
I went to the bathroom, but got lost since this house is so large.
I wandered around for a while.
While wandering around, I heard them running down the hallway,
so I went to that room.
We're talking about 100 million yen!
I bought that tray 20 years ago for 100 million yen!
Mine's obviously the real one!
C-Could you tell us your name and profession first?
Chono Kinji.
Until ten years ago, I was the president of a real estate company.
Now I'm retired.
What were you doing around 2PM?
I was in this reception room with this woman for a while,
but sitting still isn't for me.
I went to the study and was absorbed in reading about old works of art when, like him,
I heard someone noisily running down the hallway and headed there.
I see.
In any case, mine is the real black lacquer tray.
If that tray is fake,
I'd be too embarrassed to face my family.
I am Sakamaki Suzue. I am the director of the Furuito Art Museum.
I brought the black lacquer tray that has been on display at the museum for many years.
We wanted to make that tray the main attraction
of our reopening after the museum's remodeling.
The museum owner asked me to confirm the piece's value,
so I hired an appraiser.
We're curious to know if it's worth as much as the tray seen on the TV show.
I see.
I never dreamed there would be two other people with similar trays.
You were in this reception room around 2PM?
Yes, alone.
At first, the housekeepers were here with me.
This home has housekeepers?
Come to think of it, I think I met two when I came here before.
This woman sent them shopping after she said she doesn't like sweet things
and asked if they had salty rice crackers.
All I did was ask if they had any.
I didn't demand them.
It didn't sound that way to me.
But...
Those housekeepers just returned.
Apparently they were getting more ingredients for dinner while shopping for rice crackers.
I see.
Is there nobody else in this house?
Normally the son and his wife live here,
but they're currently on vacation.
Huh.
I see.
In other words, excluding the three of us in the entryway,
at the time of the murder, the people in this house were
Tojima Motoyuki-san who got lost on his way back from the bathroom,
Chono Kinji-san who was reading books on antiques in the study,
and Sakamaki Suzue-san who was alone in this reception room.
The three of you could move freely throughout the house.
Any one of you could've stabbed Nishitsu-san to death with a spear.
Since a spear has a long handle,
you wouldn't get much blood on you even if you hit or stabbed someone.
How old are you actually?
You took the same thing Conan-kun, didn't you?
There's blood on this.
What?
I see. So you're the culprit.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
There's blood on the backs of all three trays.
The next episode of Conan is "The Antique Tray Can't Be Hidden, Part Two!"