Sera suspects that Haibara may have been turned into a child
and is trying to get close to her.
In order to dodge her investigation,
we accepted Professor Agasa's invitation to visit an antique appraiser along with Subaru-san.
However...
Nishitsu-san.
Where are you, Nishitsu-san?
Nishitsu-san?
What happened?
Who did this to you?
Th-This... This is the real tray...
Wh-What's this?
A crane design?
Must be the black lacquer tray he mentioned.
In any case, we need to call an ambulance and the police.
Oh, no. My phone is in my car.
Nishitsu-san, wait here. I'll be right back.
That's the room.
What's this?
It's no use. He's dead.
Hey, Conan-kun.
I don't see a tray anywhere.
What?
What's going on here?
You're making quite a lot of noise.
Who are you?
You're not scoundrels here to steal my tray, are you?
If you're outsiders, could you please leave?
Later, the police arrived, and in another room,
they questioned the three people who were inside the house when the murder occurred.
A journey of a thousand miles starts with the first step!
Solve 1,000 mysteries and enter a new world!
Behind the scenes of the case, the Akai family's secrets intertwine!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
"The Antique Tray Can't Be Hidden, Part Two!"
Is there nobody else in this house?
Normally the son and his wife live here,
but they're currently on vacation.
Huh.
I see.
In other words, excluding the three of us in the entryway,
at the time of the murder, the people in this house were
Tojima Motoyuki-san who got lost on his way back from the bathroom,
Chono Kinji-san who was reading books on antiques in the study,
and Sakamaki Suzue-san who was alone in this reception room.
The three of you could move freely throughout the house.
Any one of you could've stabbed Nishitsu-san to death with a spear.
We'll know immediately who the culprit is.
After all, I'm sure they put the real black lacquer tray inside their own box.
You're right.
Once an appraiser examines the trays inside those three boxes,
it'll be clear as day who the culprit is.
You really are grown up, aren't you?
"Clear as day" is an expression used to describe something very easy to see or understand.
It's extremely unusual for a first-year grade school student to use that expression.
How old are you actually?
You took the same thing as Conan-kun, didn't you?
Is it that strange?
What?
In this day and age, even grade school students walk around with smartphones.
They can immediately look up any terms they see or hear on TV or in books.
On top of that, the professor often uses complicated language.
It wouldn't be that odd if his roommate picked up some of his language.
I suppose not.
In that case, get another appraiser to come here.
Yes, sir.
Hey, wait.
Did the culprit really put the real tray inside their own box?
Maybe they simply put it back inside the empty box.
Y-Yes, that's right, in order to make it seem like the culprit was after the black lacquer tray.
Maybe this was the work of some other person who held a grudge against him.
Yeah. For example, maybe the tray they brought received harsh criticism.
In any case, I won't stand for being named the culprit just because the real tray is in my box.
Either way, we can't not call an appraiser.
Getting a noted appraiser to come here would probably take some time.
Hey, Professor.
Didn't you say Nishitsu-san said the tray in front of him was the real tray?
Y-Yeah...
He touched the tray with his bloody...
That's right.
Nishitsu-san's bloody fingerprints are on the back of the real tray.
Really?
Yes, when I found Nishitsu-san and ran to his side...
Who did this to you?
Th-This... This is the real tray...
You should be able to identify the culprit if you turn over those three trays.
In that case, everyone, so nobody tries to make excuses later,
could you all sit behind your own box?
Let's begin by checking the back of the tray inside Tojima-san's box.
Naturally, whoever owns the bloody tray will become our prime suspect.
There's blood on this.
What?
I see. So you're the culprit.
N-No! It wasn't me!
Now, now. Just to be sure, let's look at the other two trays.
Whoa, whoa.
There's blood on the backs of all three trays.
What's going on here?
Well, uh...
The culprit probably noticed the blood on the back of the tray,
and used quick thinking to put the same bloody mark on the other two trays.
So we wouldn't know which one is the real tray.
Which means we'll have to call an appraiser after all.
Agasa-san, is there anything else that would help us identify the real tray?
I'm not so sure.
Come to think of it, when I flipped the bloody tray over sideways,
the crane's beak was right at the same spot as the blood.
If you turn them over sideways, the beak's position will tell us which one is the real tray.
To make things clearer, let's turn the trays so the blood is at the top.
When we turn them over sideways, whichever tray's crane's beak is pointing straight up is...
None of the beaks are pointing straight up.
That's impossible.
Come on.
Didn't you say this would identify the culprit?
This is nonsense.
Identify?
Come to think of it, how did you identify me?
You spoke to me while I was watching the professor's house from behind the gate.
Hey, you.
If you're interested in someone inside, why don't you come with me?
And you answered Conan-kun's question in this way...
More importantly, did you see anyone at the gate?
Yes, I did.
There was a girl wearing a motorcycle helmet.
How did you know I was a girl?
Normally you'd assume someone dressed like this wearing a motorcycle helmet would be a man.
What about me seemed feminine to you?
You don't actually know who I am, do you?
How did you know I was a woman?
It was your bottom.
What?
My b-bot...?
Yes, your uniquely feminine hips make it quite obvious.
I didn't think it was necessary to say out loud.
I see.
My butt, huh?
Isn't Sera your younger sister?
You know everything, don't you?
Then why don't you tell her?
Because I want to keep my sister out of this as much as possible.
Anyway, I can't believe it's been 17 years.
Why?
Why do I have to go to Japan?
I already have so many friends in England!
Shukichi, have you forgotten what Father told us in his message?
We're going to hide the fact that we're English and live in Japan.
But I didn't get to say goodbye to my friends.
Shukichi.
Do you remember Father's friend Haneda-san?
Yeah.
Remember his son Koji?
Oh, yeah. The guy who's good at that shogi game.
Apparently Koji-san died a mysterious death in the United States.
Father traveled there because Haneda-san asked him to uncover the truth.
He discovered a vile organization is involved,
so we're seeking refuge in Japan, just to be safe.
It's all right, though. He's a very strong person.
He'll round up those evil people and return to us right away.
He has two adorable sons waiting for him, and besides,
I'm sure he'll want to meet her, too.
Her, who?
Your younger sister.
Come on, Ai-chan.
What are you talking about?
She's grown so much.
I see. I understand.
Bye.
Well? Were you able to get an appraiser?
Apparently they can't come until tomorrow.
What? You mean every appraiser in Tokyo?
Yes.
All the noted appraisers are either on business trips to other prefectures or overseas,
or else they're not feeling well.
Whoa, whoa. Surely you don't mean...
You don't expect us to stay here until tomorrow, do you?
Uh, well...
Give me a break.
I'm supposed to meet a buyer for this tray tonight.
They're visiting from overseas.
If I miss tonight, I don't know when I'll be able to see them next.
I'm in the same boat.
Tonight is the 40th anniversary party for the real estate company I founded.
How could I attend such a monumental event without this tray?
My speech includes an anecdote about the difficult time I had acquiring this.
And I need to leave in three hours.
I hired a cameraman and studio to shoot photos for the museum's reopening pamphlet.
Naturally, the photos will be of this tray, so I'll be taking mine with me when the time comes.
No, wait.
That tray is evidence in a murder case.
The police will be holding on to it for a while.
And the other trays, too.
You can't be serious. What about tonight's party?
What about my buyer?
Please calm down.
We can't allow a murderer to walk free.
We'd appreciate your cooperation.
Inspector Megure.
What is it?
Forensics found this next to the body.
It seems to be a hearing aid.
A hearing aid?
Ah, that's the "Deaf Angel" I invented.
"Deaf?"
It's a wireless hearing aid the late Nishitsu-san bought from me.
It turns the voices and sounds around you into the gentle whispers of an angel.
Which means it probably fell out of his ear when the culprit struck the victim.
Do you recognize this?
Yes.
I did notice that he had something in his ear.
I didn't realize it was a hearing aid.
He spoke with us just fine.
Of course he did. My inventions work great.
Excuse me, Agasa-san. Could I talk to you?
What is it?
The victim's phone received a message from you about 20 minutes before the murder.
Does that sound familiar?
Yes, I sent him a message telling him we were on our way.
For some reason it looks like that message was never opened.
The phone was set to play notification sounds, though.
I don't know what to tell you.
It was probably already malfunctioning by then.
It's what you'd expect from a "Deaf Angel."
What a fitting name for the device.
I can't hear you.
Fitting?
If you ask me, your behavior is hardly fitting for a child.
Come on, Ai-chan. Tell me about the drug.
You turn back into an adult periodically like Conan-kun, right?
If you've got it, could you share some with me?
That drug that restores the flow of time.
"Restore the flow of time?" What do you mean by that?
What?
"Restore" implies there's something wrong with the current situation.
Or perhaps there's something wrong with someone other than you.
It's none of your business!
No way. He vanished?
Huh?
That was a 50-50.
It's my fault for touching a nerve, but you're also at fault for suddenly kicking me.
Perhaps my advice is unwelcome,
but if you want to be more feminine, perhaps you should behave less violently.
I'll be fine. I don't have to do anything to become more feminine.
My mom's chest used to be huge.
"Used to be?"
Does that mean your mother passed away?
No, it's not like that, but...
But?
Seriously, it's none of your business.
I see. Akai-san wants to confirm his mother's well-being.
Which means that middle-school-aged girl is Sera and Akai-san's mother.
She's that Mary woman I met at the beach a long time ago.
Since Sera keeps asking about the drug, then as I thought,
that must mean she was shrunk after being forced to take APTX 4869, too.
But who is she? Why did she take the drug?
All I know is that she has exceptional deductive skills,
Sleep is a biological function
of the periodically repeated loss of consciousness.
In other words,
The old man's voice...
it's practically impossible for a person to speak while sleeping.
A smartphone behind his neck?
Naturally, sleep talking is an exception.
Where did that come from?
The words I'm speaking now must sound like
nonsensical sleep talking to you.
But since they are the words of the detective who has solved this ridiculous case,
I ask that you listen.
is an excellent martial artist,
What's it doing there?
I should take one of under the balcony, too.
I-Is he dead?
No, they struck his vitals and knocked him unconscious
during the seconds it took for me to run here.
They're as quick as a secret service agent.
It must've been the sister out of territory.
and is English.
After all, you're the apprentice of my country's greatest detective.
Y-Your country?
You're English?
Yeah, although I'm an American now.
England?
No way! Does "sister out of territory" actually mean...?
Hey, you.
Making us stay here won't get you anywhere.
B-But...
I'm leaving.
You can't leave.
Judging by the situation,
it's likely that one of you struck Nishitsu-san the appraiser on the head with a spear,
and used that same spear to stab him in the back and kill him.
We'd like you to stay a little longer.
How much longer?
How are you going to find the culprit when none of the appraisers can make it here?
We're currently reaching out to appraisers from other prefectures.
If you could wait just a little longer...
When you flipped over the tray, what was the orientation of the crane carved onto the front?
We can put our trays back in our boxes and leave now, right?
You can finish questioning us another day.
What if I told you I could tell the real tray apart from the fakes without an appraiser?
I know who had the real tray.
What?
The next episode of Conan is "The Antique Tray Can't Be Hidden, Part Three!"