Ancient Oriental Culture Museum
Entry Fee Weekday Adults 600 yen Children 300 yen Weekend Adults 700 yen Children 350 yen
Tutankhamun.
The Sphinx.
The Rosetta Stone.
And finally...
The Screaming Mummy.
Ancient Egypt sure is mysterious.
But isn't everything on display here a replica?
Why did we bother coming to this museum on the way home from school?
Curious?
We're here...
For these!
These Egyptian god keychains are super popular among our classmates right now.
And you can only buy them here.
That's right.
Super popular, huh?
Finally arriving after swaying back and forth,
draw close to mysteries and begin deducing the truth!
The mystery of the cursed statue returns to life at the museum!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
"The Cursed Museum!"
This one's good, but it's hard to say no to this one.
Oolong Tea
Don't you think this one's cute, too?
I doubt we'll be leaving for a while.
What's this?
A notebook?
Ah, they have guests write reviews and requests in here.
Some of the reviews are quite harsh, but they're quite helpful.
Uh...
Oh, excuse me.
I'm Kowata, the director of the Ancient Oriental Culture Museum.
Nice to meet you.
So it's his taste that's reflected in this place.
We'll be closing soon, but enjoy yourself until then.
Kids are very welcome here.
Closed
Okay, I'm getting this one.
Anubis is mine.
They finally made up their minds.
Excuse me.
Have you made up your minds?
Yes.
We'd like these, please.
Sure thing.
Oh...
Ishikawa-kun, could you handle the register?
Yes, sir.
This way, please.
Okay.
What was that?
What was that sound?
Conan-kun!
Conan-kun, what's wrong?
C-Could it be?
Ran-neechan, call the police.
Got it.
It's the curse.
It's Anubis' curse.
Hey, Detective Takagi.
Was this an accident or a murder?
We don't know yet.
It's the curse.
It's clearly Anubis' curse.
What curse?
Look at the object he's holding in his right hand.
A-A feather?
Is that an ostrich feather?
Indeed it is.
Wh-What's so special about ostrich feathers?
The Book of the Dead.
That's right.
Th-The Book of the Dead?
The Book of the Dead is a guidebook to the afterlife.
It describes how the dead reach the afterlife.
What does that have to do with ostrich feathers?
The dead are judged after their death.
Their own heart is placed on one side of Ra's scales.
An ostrich feather is placed on the other side.
If the deceased's heart is tainted by sin, the scales tip out of balance.
If the deceased is judged innocent, the way to the afterlife opens to them.
However, if they're guilty, the beast Ammit consumes their soul.
And presiding over that judgment is...
God of the Underworld and mummification, Anubis.
I've heard about this.
A bunch of archaeologists died mysterious deaths.
That's the curse of the pharaohs.
Anubis must've judged this person guilty.
Does that mean Anubis is the culprit?
Does that mean the Anubis statue happened to fall as the victim was passing by it?
Don't you think it's odd, though?
There's a wound on the back of his head.
Yes. Forensics said further investigation is required to determine
if he got that when he was struck by the falling statue.
Then what about that broken pedestal?
The broken leg is a different color from the other ones.
You're right.
Was only this leg made using a weaker wood?
Which means after a certain amount of time had passed,
the wood could no longer bear the weight of the statue, causing it to fall.
It's an improvised timer.
In other words, the culprit could've rigged this in order to fabricate an alibi.
Y-You mean...
Yes. It's likely that this wasn't an accident, but a murder.
Director, we'd like to check your security camera footage.
O-Okay.
By the way, how many employees are there aside from yourself?
Just Ishikawa-kun.
Nothing beats low labor costs.
That's him.
We determined from his wallet that the victim was Uchida Hiroaki-san, 47 years old.
He worked in construction.
We've already contacted his wife, and she's on her way here.
Additionally, we believe this woman is his wife Uchida Yuko-san.
She's been coming here a lot recently.
What?
I offered her an annual pass, but she declined my offer.
I-I see.
Keep playing the tape.
Okay.
Stop.
Who is that?
That's Yamada-san, a regular.
He's one of a few guests who have an annual pass.
Keep playing the tape.
Okay.
Nobody came to the museum after this.
In other words, one of them is the culprit.
That's definitely my husband.
How did this happen?
You came to this museum today, didn't you?
Yes.
Did something happen inside the museum?
I don't know.
He suddenly showed up while I was viewing the exhibits inside.
We got into an argument, and I left before him.
I don't know what happened after we parted ways.
Why did you get into an argument?
He was a very controlling person.
He was angry that I came here without his permission.
Does that mean your husband followed you?
He'd make it sound like he caught me cheating,
but as far as I'm concerned, he was acting like a nasty stalker.
Then...
I can't say we were a happy couple.
I was considering divorce.
Are you sure you should be saying that?
You'd figure it out if I lied.
It's better to be honest.
Just to be sure, could we check your phone's history?
I'm sorry. I don't have a cell phone.
What?
That's unusual in this day and age.
That woman is the culprit!
I saw them.
What did you see?
I saw them arguing.
They threatened to kill them.
Who did?
The husband.
They even said, "You'll never get away with it!"
Who did?
That was the husband, too.
It makes no difference who said it.
The culprit is definitely the wife!
You also don't have an alibi.
Fool! Who's got the time to bludgeon a stranger?
I told you, it's Anubis' curse.
We're asking for your alibi for when the incident took place.
What were you doing around 3PM, 30 minutes before the body was discovered?
I was repairing a mirror.
After that, I met up with the director and some guests.
I believe I was preparing to close the museum.
In other words, you were both alone.
Yes.
Ishikawa-san, how long have you been working here?
Who, me? I think it's been about two years.
Huh.
I can't believe he doesn't know the difference
between the pharaohs and Anubis after working here for two years.
Ultimately, nobody had a solid alibi.
Let's look into the backgrounds of the victim and suspects.
We may discover a surprising connection.
You're right.
This Uchida man is unbelievable.
On top of his countless minor offensives, he has a history of cheating, brawling, and debt.
Hello?
Detective, I know who did it.
You do?
Yes. I'm confirming it now, but it must be them.
Who is it?
Well, actually...
What are you—
What's the matter? Sir?
Sir?!
Sonoko, are we really going back there?
I'm Mystery Queen Sonoko.
Of course I'm curious to know how yesterday turned out.
I guess so.
Hey, look.
What are you doing?
D-Don't touch me!
I am Anubis!
I am the god of the Underworld who judges the souls of the dead!
This voice...
Is that the director?
Present your heart to me!
What's going on here?
I received a call from the director this morning.
He said he knew who the culprit was.
What?
But before he could tell me their name, the call ended.
I rushed here and found him like this.
His soul was tainted!
His soul tainted by lies was consumed by Ammit!
Take him to the station.
Yes, sir.
Hey, what are you doing?
How dare you put your hands on a god!
You mustn't touch me!
Inside that cursed notebook is...
No! Let go!
If you look at it, you'll be cursed!
The only thing the cursed can do is pray!
Conan-kun, don't. You'll be cursed.
I'll be fine.
Judging by his behavior, there must be something about the culprit in this notebook.
I see.
So that's how it is.
But Conan-kun, why are we going to Tokyo Station?
This notebook is full of reviews from lots of people, and Uchida Yuko-san's are among them.
What?
She didn't write her name, but the initials are the same, so it must be her.
If you look back through reviews written in the same handwriting,
you'll find that Yuko-san has left 17 reviews.
At first glance, the remarks seem harmless,
but if you read them carefully, you'll notice they have something in common.
What's that?
"It was raining in Shibuya."
"Shinjuku at night reminds me of Cairo at night."
"Flowers were blooming by the river in Meguro."
"The cicadas in Shakujii Park were..."
I know!
She's meeting someone.
There's always the name of a location in each of her comments.
Come to think of it, she said she didn't have a cell phone.
So it's a code.
Also, look at the dates of the comments.
The dates? But all the comments have dates.
The dates and times go back and forth.
I know.
This isn't when she wrote the comment, it's when she's meeting someone.
The last one is 11 o'clock on the ninth.
We only have 20 more minutes!
Let's hurry!
We're here, but where are supposed to look? Tokyo Station is huge.
This certainly is a problem.
I've requested backup, but we need to narrow it down somehow.
Where is she? Where are they meeting?
15 more minutes.
Ten more minutes.
Damn it. Which words indicate where they're meeting?
Today I got to see the Book of the Dead.
The hieroglyphs are arranged in such an orderly manner,
like the bricks in the wall at Tokyo Station.
By the way, the sun rising over the Libyan Desert was magical.
When the deceased watched their hearts
weighed against an ostrich feather on Anubis' scale,
all they could do was pray.
That's why I'll begin by praying, too.
Let me see that.
What's the Libyan Desert?
It's a part of the Sahara Desert in southwestern Egypt.
Huh, I guess Yuko-san's been to Egypt.
H-Hold on.
Huh?
I reviewed some records last night, and she's never been to Egypt.
She doesn't even have a passport.
What?
That's it.
Sonoko-neechan, you said the Libyan Desert is in southwestern Egypt, right?
Y-Yeah.
Then it's impossible for the sun to rise over the Libyan Desert.
Oh, yeah.
Then this is part of the code, too?
See how it says "I'll begin by praying" before that?
Yeah, I see it.
That's where it starts.
Where it starts?
At Tokyo Station, there are facilities for praying here.
The prayer room.
And since the Libyan Desert is in southwestern Egypt,
if you head southwest from the prayer room...
The taxi stand.
What? What is Ishikawa-san doing here?
Ishikawa-san, I knew you would come here.
This case started with the discord between the Uchidas.
After witnessing their argument,
Yuko-san's lover decided to commit a crime in order to protect her.
You're wrong! I'm the one who killed him!
A woman couldn't have committed this crime.
Even if you dropped the feather in the hallway
and attacked him from behind as he picked it up,
it would've been difficult for you to drag the body
or tamper with the two-meter tall Anubis statue's platform,
even though it's a replica, in such a short amount of time.
No! I did it!
No, you had nothing to do with the murder.
How do you know that?
It was written in the notebook.
What? Wh-Where?
It wasn't written explicitly.
What was it, then?
Her final note was written in her usual handwriting.
If she'd been involved in the murder,
it would've affected her handwriting.
You're right.
Come to think of it, Ishikawa-san mixed up Anubis and the pharaohs...
But that was a lie meant to direct suspicion away from himself.
He pretended to be ignorant so we wouldn't suspect him.
Is he responsible for the director's curse, too?
You showed up just before the director
could tell Detective Takagi the culprit's name, didn't you?
When you explained the situation to the director,
he felt sorry for you two and had second thoughts about telling the truth.
So he pretended to be cursed by Anubis to avoid testifying.
I see. Then he wouldn't have to perjure himself.
You're right.
I'm responsible for everything.
I know I've caused trouble for the director.
But Uchida Hiroaki deserved to die!
You're wrong.
What?
Violence, controlling behavior, violations of privacy, and all manner of harassment.
I know Uchida-san was having affairs with multiple women for several years, too.
I was in hell.
Ishikawa-san saved me from that hell.
Yuko-san...
However,
that doesn't make it right to take a person's life.
Hey, apparently a Aztec culture museum is opening on the other side of the station.
Want to check it out sometime?
What?
What about Ancient Oriental culture?
That's old news. Aztec culture is in now.
The Incan Empire, Machu Picchu, Lake Titicaca, Quetzalcoatl.
It's so romantic.
Do you even know what those words mean?
Looks like you need a little educating.
I'll show you what a real story looks like.
Michiko-san, apparently it's possible that you've been poisoned.
What?
I see.
So that's how it is!
The next episode of Conan is "The Whistling Bookstore 3!"