Hello?
Thanks for today. Yeah.
Yeah, that's right. I only went because I was told they were all hot doctors.
But it was like, where are all the hot guys?
What? Oh, sorry.
I can't. I'm busy doing something else tomorrow.
No, it's not like that.
Yeah, something like that.
Yeah. I'll call you later.
Good night.
Man, what was up with today's game?
Seriously. Why'd they get so many hits off during the final inning?
There was that, too, but why'd they have him pinch hit at the very end?
Oh, that?
Hey, there's something lying on the ground.
Hey, miss! If you sleep out here, you'll catch a co—
Sh-She's dead!
Finally arriving after swaying back and forth,
draw close to mysteries and begin deducing the truth!
The witness is a shut-in!
What is the truth they won't reveal? Why can't they leave their home?
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
"The Wordless Witness!"
The murder victim is Shinozaki Himeno-san, 26 years old,
a domestic helper who lived in the area.
According to the friend she was speaking with on the phone before her death,
the victim was coming home late after a mixer.
We believe the weapon was a hard rod-like object,
but we still haven't identified it.
Another random attack?
C-Conan-kun? Mori-san and Ran-san, too?
You already got wind of the case?
They say every detective has his case.
I believe there were two similar incidents in this area last week.
Yes. Young women dressed in flashy clothes are being struck over the head at night
with the same rod-like weapon used in this case.
It's safe to assume the same person is responsible.
Fortunately, in the previous two cases,
the victims were only injured, but this time...
You mean their crimes are escalating?
Yes.
In any case, we need to arrest the culprit as soon as possible.
But this area is totally deserted at night.
There aren't any security cameras nearby.
Just like the previous two times, I doubt we can count on any eyewitness testimony.
We didn't find anything notable among her belongings either.
Did the previous victims say anything about the incidents?
Well, actually...
Perhaps because they were drunk like this victim,
neither of them remembered the incidents.
I see.
Hey!
Kids should stay out of this.
Behave yourself and wait over here.
Anyway, this seems like it'll be a difficult investigation.
Yeah.
Hey, kid.
Do you know those police officers?
What? Uh, yeah. Sort of.
The random attacker left that body behind, didn't they?
Uh, well...
Oh, come on. I can keep a secret.
More importantly, who lives in that house?
That's Komori-san's place.
A mother and her son live there.
Her son Hikaru-kun lives on the second floor.
Apparently Hikaru-kun failed to find a job.
He's been cooped up in there forever.
I believe it's been about three months.
I think they're called idol otakus?
Apparently he was following Okino Yoko around.
That's probably why he failed to find a job.
I'm telling you, kids these days...
Huh?
Where are you going, son?
That brat!
You're looking for Hikaru?
Come in. He's up here.
But I don't think there's any point in asking him questions.
He stayed in his room when the police came here earlier.
You heard her.
But maybe he'll talk to a great detective.
Well, yeah.
This is Hikaru's room.
Whoa!
Wow...
He's been a fan since her Earth Ladies days. Outstanding.
Hikaru.
A detective wants to speak with you about the incident.
I'm the great detective Mori Kogoro.
Hikaru-san, I'd like to ask you some questions.
"I didn't see anything."
"Leave."
This is how he's been recently.
He won't even speak to me.
Hikaru-san.
Hikaru-san, open the door.
This is hopeless.
But why did he say he didn't see anything?
Huh?
What do you mean?
Regardless of whether or not someone is the culprit,
wouldn't their first concern be becoming a suspect?
Generally, yeah.
I'd understand "It wasn't me" or "I don't know anything,"
but the first thing Hikaru-san said was "I didn't see anything."
Maybe Hikaru-san did see something.
In the same way that the crime scene can be seen from that room,
that room is visible from the crime scene.
Even if Hikaru-san didn't see anything, maybe the culprit saw Hikaru-san.
This is taking too long!
Hey, open this door!
Hey, Dad!
That's enough, please.
I just need to talk to him for a little bit.
I'm sorry, but...
Make sure you lock your windows and doors, just in case.
I will.
Are these Hikaru-san's leather shoes?
What? Yes, probably. Why?
They're dirtier than you'd expect for someone looking for a job,
and they have a different feel from the other shoes here.
You're right.
They've been here since last week.
That's when the random attacks started.
What do you mean by that?
What? Nothing.
In that case...
What happened to the shoes that were here?
What? There should be some Okino Yoko sneakers there.
They seemed so important to him.
Where did he put those?
Maybe he gave up on following her so he could focus on finding a job?
I hope you're right.
Come to think of it, we started communicating via text last week.
I see.
Did you figure something out?
No, not at all.
Jeez.
Well, we got nothing out of that.
Do you think Hikaru-san really didn't see anything?
It wouldn't be odd if he witnessed something,
but it doesn't matter if he won't talk to us.
How'd it go?
Is that boy connected to the case somehow after all?
I knew he seemed suspicious.
Huh?
Hey, wait!
Come on, tell me. Here's my address and phone number!
I'd do anything to help!
The series of random attacks have finally resulted in a death.
The police have not yet found any convincing evidence,
and the investigation's progress is expected to be slow.
Random attacks like these are the most challenging cases to solve.
I'm certain Hikaru-san saw something.
The question is why does he so stubbornly refuse to testify?
Here's our next story.
The Okino Yoko-san dome tour that began last week
concluded last night amidst tremendous excitement.
Yoko-tan!
The old man can hardly criticize others.
Wait a minute. Could it be?
Coffee Poirot
The truth is starting to become clear!
I'll be back late. You can microwave your dinner. Mom
Ow...
I'm sorry. Are you all right?
Yeah, sorry.
You're that kid from this afternoon.
What?
Nothing.
You're Hikaru-san, right?
Did you run away from home?
What?
Your suitcase.
Yeah, something like that.
You shouldn't do that. Your mom will be worried.
What?
Come on, let's go home.
Hey, wait.
Seriously?
What is this?
What's going on?
We were too late.
What's going on here?
The random attacker took him away.
The real Hikaru-san.
Ow...
Where am I?
Wh-What are you talking about?
Hikaru is... I'm right here.
If you assume he swapped places with someone, it explains everything.
Why he stopped speaking last week,
why his favorite sneakers vanished around the same time,
why those out-of-place shoes appeared in their place.
And why the bottoms of those shoes were worn down differently from the others.
The real Hikaru-san is a hardcore Okino Yoko chaser.
Naturally, he wanted to go to her dome tour that started last week.
But Hikaru-san was a shut-in. His mother would never allow him to go to a concert.
So Hikaru-san asked you, his friend, for a favor, right?
He asked you to take his place while he was at the concert.
Who are you actually?
I have to get out of here.
He escaped.
I'm Hikaru's friend Kageyama Shinobu.
Everything you said is correct.
I got to eat and live here for free, so it was a great deal for me.
I never thought something like this would happen.
Your identity's been discovered.
There's no reason for you to refuse to testify anymore!
Tell me. What did you see last night?
I'm sorry.
I'm not getting any more deeply involved in trouble!
Are you sure you're okay with that?
Hikaru's life is in danger in your place.
If you make the wrong choice here,
you'll regret it for the rest of your life.
I don't want anyone to go through that.
Who are you?
You're right. I saw the culprit.
But it was dark.
I only caught a glimpse of their face.
The only thing I saw clearly was...
Thanks.
That's plenty.
Let's go. We're going to rescue Hikaru-san!
All right!
Why, you...!
You brat!
It's no use. He's not answering the phone.
Then he's already—
Don't give up!
Please let us make it in time.
Someone—
This is your fault...
for seeing something you shouldn't have.
Something I shouldn't have?
You saw me last night.
Doing what?
You saw me kill that woman from your room.
Last night, from my room?
I've got nothing to do with this anymore.
I see.
He didn't want to get involved in any trouble.
I suppose that's how friends are.
I guess I got what I deserved.
Hikaru!
What are you muttering about?
It's fine. Kill me.
I failed to find a job, and my friend abandoned me.
There's no point in me living anymore.
That's right. Because kids like you keep screwing around,
the world's going to hell!
Listen to me, lady!
He's not the one who saw you last night! It was me!
What?
He didn't see anything!
I'm the one you have to kill!
Kageyama—
What the hell's going on?
Now!
Take this!
Hikaru!
Are you okay?
Kageyama...
I'm so glad you're okay.
Look at this.
Apparently those two are establishing a start-up company together.
They're bound to fail.
You can't know that unless you try.
I'm sure they'll be fine.
By the way, what's he doing?
Apparently he's searching online for a Mori Kogoro double.
While he's working, I can take it easy.
I'll use my double to make money.
Call the police immediately!
Excuse me, I'm with the police.
Could I have a few minutes of your time?
What do the police want with me?
Conan-kun.
So you witnessed the incident through the curtains,
but the police wouldn't take you seriously?
I really did see something!
The next episode of Conan is "Beyond the Curtain!"