Wow!
It looks so good!
Yeah!
Shall we eat?
Thanks for the food!
By the way, why aren't Conan and Haibara here?
Ai-chan has a TV show she wants to watch, and Conan-kun's home alone at the detective agency.
It's too bad they couldn't come with us.
Yeah.
Everyone, look at that.
Huh?
Finally arriving after swaying back and forth,
draw close to mysteries and begin deducing the truth!
A vanishing case witnessed as a silhouette!
Cast a bright light on it and you'll find the culprit!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
"Beyond the Curtain!"
A man and a woman?
You can see their silhouettes so clearly.
They look like shadow puppets.
Do you suppose they're eating?
They're probably throwing a party.
Things seem to be going well between them.
Wait, are they...
C-C-C-Could it be?
K-Kissing?
Like I said, things are going excellently!
H-H-H-Hey! This isn't appropriate for children's eyes!
Huh?
Wh-What's going on?!
Aren't they making up?
They're clearly fighting.
Oh, no!
Call the police immediately!
He's here.
Hurry, officer!
Yes?
Excuse me, I'm with the police.
Could I have a few minutes of your time?
What do the police want with me?
Well, someone reported that they saw a man
attacking a woman inside your home through the curtains.
They saw a man attacking a woman through the curtains?
In that case, I have a large pet dog.
Perhaps that's what Chocolat playing with me looked like through the curtains.
That's not what happened!
That wasn't a dog. It was a man.
What do you think? Could I take a look around inside?
Very well. In that case, officer, would it be all right if you only you came in?
I don't want strangers looking around inside my home.
Understood.
That way! They went that way!
Don't let them escape!
Over there! Hurry!
You're not getting away!
Conan-kun.
Ayumi-chan? What happened, guys?
We'd like to get your advice on a situation.
Advice?
Last night, when we went to a restaurant with Professor Agasa...
Everyone, look at that.
A man and a woman?
You can see their silhouettes so clearly.
They look like shadow puppets.
Do you suppose they're eating?
They're probably throwing a party.
Things seem to be going well between them.
Huh?
W-What's going on?!
So you witnessed the incident through the curtains,
but the police wouldn't take you seriously?
We really did see something!
Then why are the police saying nothing happened?
It's not like we could do anything about it.
The cop said there was only a woman inside.
Are you sure it wasn't just a mistake on your part?
No, it wasn't!
We all saw it!
Okay, I believe you.
But there's too little information.
Anything helps. Tell me everything you remember.
According to the police,
the woman who lives in that apartment is Kokubun Yuko-san, 26 years old.
She works at an event planning company.
This is the photo we found of her on their website, taken when she was hired.
You've done your research, Mitsuhiko.
So, what were the two silhouettes doing?
The man brought dishes and wine to the table.
The woman stayed seated the whole time.
Yeah.
We thought they were enjoying a party together,
and then the man suddenly became violent.
Now that I think about it, maybe that wasn't a party.
It kind of looked like a police officer questioning a suspect.
To me, they looked like a couple just before a proposal.
I think they looked like an old man and woman basking in the sun.
How did you guys all see different things?
We can't help that. That's what it looked like to us.
Silhouettes, huh?
Depending on the perspective and angle,
their size and overall impression can change completely, like shadow puppets.
The police claim only the woman who was allegedly attacked was inside.
That's the exact opposite of what they're claiming.
What's going on here?
Interrogation!
Sunbathing!
How do you sunbathe at night?
What? Uh...
They were having an afternoon nap at night.
They'd been staying up all night from that afternoon.
You two have got everything backwards.
Backwards?
I see. So that's how it is.
Conan-kun, did you figure something out?
Yeah, I did.
If everything you're saying is true, then this is the only possible answer.
Sorry to bother you while you're so busy, Detective Takagi.
It's fine.
Did Kokubun-san really say they have a pet dog?
I've said repeatedly that we don't allow pets here.
Looks like no one's home.
Yeah.
Hey, kids!
She loves sports, huh?
So a woman lives alone here.
Is that blood?
Looks like it.
This blood someone tried to wipe clean, the broken glasses and plates in the trash.
And it doesn't look like she has a pet dog.
Conan-kun.
Look at this.
She must've really hated him.
Conan-kun, what we saw last night...
Yeah, last night you guys watched a crime take place.
But what we saw was...
You had it backwards.
Backwards?
People tend to get stuck on their first impressions.
And it doesn't make sense that the man was delivering dishes
and wine to the table when the woman who lives here was sitting the whole time.
If you swap the genders of the people,
then it also explains why the police officer said there was only a woman inside.
In other words, the person you thought was a man was a short-haired woman,
and the person you thought was a woman was a long-haired man.
What?
Look. This is a recent photo of her.
You're right.
We had no idea.
She only let the police officer inside the apartment
because he'd been told that the victim was a woman.
That did in fact allow her to get away with it.
Though she made it through that visit,
she must sense the investigation turning up the heat on her.
In other words, she's already acted on the next step?
Detective Takagi.
I checked the security cameras.
I saw Kokubun Yuko-san leaving early this morning with a large suitcase.
Head back to the station and report what you saw.
Yes, sir.
I'm going to check the security cameras in the area.
We don't need to help?
Nah, I think it'll be fine.
Are you sure?
Surely not even you can deduce where the culprit went, right?
I don't know about that.
What does that mean?
She probably still believes that as long as the body isn't found,
she can keep evading the police.
Which means she's probably doing what she'd do on any other day.
See?
What is this?
Kokubun Yuko-san's social media profile.
But maybe she buried the body before going to work.
No, she's probably still pretending everything is normal.
Since it seemed like a premeditated crime,
if she's going to bury the body, she'll probably do it after work.
Hey, look. We've arrived.
It's the flower park.
It's so pretty.
Thank you for visiting the park today.
The Haido City Flower Park will be closing soon.
Let's hurry. She'll make her move once work is over.
Kokubun-san? Oh, she already left.
When?
Just now, I think.
The truth is...
What?
We'll split up from here on out. Let's find her.
What should we do once we find her?
Slow her down until the police arrive.
How?
Leave that to me. I've got an idea.
I found her. She's heading towards the exit from the plaza.
All right. Follow the plan, guys.
Got it.
That way! They went that way!
Don't let them escape!
Over there! Hurry!
Where did they go?
Don't worry. They're trapped in here.
It worked.
Professor.
Good work, everyone.
Now let's leave the rest up to Conan-kun.
You're Kokubun Yuko-san, correct?
What?
Uh, yes. That's me.
Who are you?
My name is Mori Kogoro. I'm a detective.
What does a detective want with me?
I'm actually looking for someone.
And you think I can help you?
Of course you can.
Nobody else knows where he is.
Who are you talking about?
Don't play dumb.
I'm talking about the man you had dinner with last night.
I have no idea what you're talking about.
The police investigation is already closing in.
See? They're just over there.
By the way, what's inside that suitcase?
What do you think is in here?
If I'm correct, he should be in there.
You're not very nice, are you?
Most detectives aren't.
It's his fault.
After naming me his guarantor and borrowing a bunch of money,
he bilked his debts and pushed all the responsibility onto me.
Apparently he spent the money on other women.
He destroyed my life, forced his debts onto me, and then tried to dump me.
So I destroyed him!
What do you want me to do to you?
Shall I start by cutting all your fingernails to the quick?
Or perhaps I'll make you swallow a thousand needles.
Or would you prefer to be electrocuted?
You don't like pain? In that case...
How's this?
Apparently if you drink these together, you can end your life pleasantly.
But we can't do that.
You have to experience the worst possible pain and suffering.
Otherwise, I won't be satisfied.
You think I'll let you go?!
I can't believe someone was watching.
Uh, everything's fine.
Ahem.
More importantly, you must've been rather surprised
when the police paid you a visit after the murder.
Excuse me, I'm with the police.
Could I have a few minutes of your time?
What do the police want with me?
Well, someone reported that they saw a man
attacking a woman inside your home through the curtains.
They saw a man attacking a woman through the curtains?
In that case, I have a large pet dog.
Perhaps that's what Chocolat playing with me looked like through the curtains.
What do you think? Could I take a look around inside?
Very well. In that case, officer, would it be all right if you only you came in?
I don't want strangers looking around inside my home.
I thought that was pretty clever of me, but apparently it didn't work.
Crimes are a gamble you have a slim chance of winning.
You shouldn't have done it to begin with.
Mr. Detective.
Yes?
Do you smell something burning?
Huh? What?
Hot, hot!
Are you all right?
Y-Yes, of course. I'm fine, obviously.
Mr. Detective, you're alone, aren't you?
What do you mean by that?
Do you think you'd be willing to let me go?
I can't do that.
I see. That's too bad.
Mr. Detective, you know what that means, don't you?
Mr. Detective, why won't you let me see you?
I'd like to see your face.
I want to see the face of the detective who hunted me down...
Up close!
Why, you...!
Kokubun Yuko, the time is 19:58.
You're under arrest for a weapons violation.
You got here quick, Detective Takagi.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Conan-kun.
Okay, what's this?
A sea urchin!
What are you talking about? It's a crab.
What?
Genta-kun, does that really look like a sea urchin to you?
What? I'm just being honest.
At least they're both sea creatures.
Anyway, I can't believe what we thought was a pleasant date was actually a ghastly affair.
Seriously, and there was only a single curtain between you and it.
As they say, the future lies beyond the veil.
Hey, Conan.
What does that look like to you?
Huh? Isn't that a rabbit?
Right?
What?
It's clearly an eel carrying a leek.
How does this look like an eel to you?!
This is the eel's head, and this is the leek.
It's ducks that carry leeks.
Is that right?
Huh? Isn't this place...
Jeez.
What? The president's been murdered?
He drowned in red bean paste?
A red car, shampoo...
The next episode of Conan is "Ballad of the Woman Who Loved Cake!"