Kasuga Ryuji (30) Artist
Finally arriving after swaying back and forth,
draw close to mysteries and begin deducing the truth!
Facing an artist, Ran smiles!
But her prim pose hints at a case!
Always determining the one truth
with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
his name is Detective Conan!
"Mori Ran, the Model!"
A modeling job, huh?
Conan-kun, you must be bored.
No, this is super interesting.
Professional artists are incredible.
Really? I'm glad to hear that.
Kasuga-sensei and Ran-san, why don't we take a break?
I've made some tea.
Yes, let's.
Thank you.
I should be able to finish today as planned.
It was quite the twist of fate.
I went out to do some shopping that day.
My ideal model happened to show up there.
E-Excuse me.
Yes?
But you didn't know who he was.
I'm sorry that I didn't know at the time that you were a famous artist.
It's fine. It just means I still have a long way to go.
Your works are special, Kasuga-sensei.
What was that?
Hello.
Hey.
Uh...?
This is Conan-kun.
He came to watch since Ran-san's painting will be finished today.
Hello.
Hello. I'm Kasuga-sensei's apprentice Komiyama Yoshio.
Conan-kun, you must like art, too.
Yeah.
I can't tell them I came because I was worried about her.
Well, I'm going to get started on my work.
Really? Why don't you join us?
Thank you, but I'm fine.
Has Komiyama-san been an apprentice for a long time?
What? No.
He's a new artist who just recently became an apprentice.
Huh.
Sir, we should get back to work soon.
Got it. Thank you.
But first, I'm going to check on Komiyama-kun.
Kasuga-sensei really trusts you, Riko-san.
I don't know about that.
For him, keeping track of time is just an assistant's job.
Why?
Kasuga-sensei becomes absorbed in his ideas when they come to mind,
so he often loses his belongings.
That's why he doesn't carry anything with him.
He doesn't even wear a watch.
I see.
Nice colors.
Thank you.
Sir, there's something I've always wanted to ask you.
Why have you been drawing portraits recently?
You're opposed to the idea, too?
Sometimes I feel like drawing whatever I want.
I didn't mean it like that.
I was just wondering why you suddenly switched to drawing portraits—of all female models, no less.
Is there some criteria you use to choose your models?
No. They're all strangers I scout around town.
I guess I follow my intuition.
I see.
Models aren't important to me.
They're simply tools used to evoke an image.
In the end, my art is everything to me.
But it would seem some realities can't be improved upon.
There they are.
Hey, who are you?
Hello. I'm Edogawa Conan.
I'm visiting the studio.
I see.
Nothing's happened to the model this time, right?
What?
The truth is, there are some shady circumstances concerning his models.
Shady circumstances?
Well, he had two previous female models...
Tell me more about that.
Huh? Come to think of it...
Conan-kun said he was going to check out the yard.
I'm sorry. He always runs off before I know it.
The weather's nice today.
I understand the desire to go outside.
Let's hurry up and finish this for his sake, too.
This is the place.
Someone pushed me from behind here.
Is something the matter?
No. How about witnesses?
Did they see anyone suspicious?
No.
Apparently not.
Come to think of it, I saw Kasuga-san on my way here that day.
What?
I saw him from behind, so I'm not 100% sure.
I think he was sitting on the riverbank and looking at the river.
I was scouted to model for him around here, too.
I thought he must come here often and didn't think much of it.
Don't let it bother you.
Huh?
Riko-san isn't too fond of me making these paintings that don't bring in any money.
I-I see.
Riko-san isn't just my assistant.
She's also my manager.
As someone who handles money, I'm sure it's a nuisance.
I understand that, but...
This is the place.
I was waiting for the light to change here when someone pushed me from behind.
You didn't see the culprit?
No. This place is deserted at night.
The police said there weren't any witnesses.
The only clue to the culprit's identity is the sound that I heard.
What sound?
Like a clattering sound.
I felt like I'd heard it before, but I don't know what it was.
I see. Where were you scouted for modeling work?
What? Oh, at a nearby café.
Come to think of it,
I might've seen Kasuga-sensei around here on the day of the incident.
What?
I thought Kasuga-sensei had gone home after he finished working,
but maybe he was on his way to that café.
It seems like he's a regular there.
But that random attack ruined everything.
I'm on my university's track team.
Because of my injury, I'm not sure I'll be able to run like I used to.
My brother's really bitter about it
and says he'll do whatever it takes to catch the culprit.
Your brother?
Komiyama-san?
Oh, uh...
I'm sorry. I'm looking for materials.
What is this room?
It's Kasuga-sensei's late wife's room.
What? Really?
There aren't any materials in here. You should head back.
A-All right.
Our Standard Date Route
Evening at the Riverbank
Our Usual Vienna Coffees at the Café
This is my brother.
So that's how it is.
All right.
Hey, Machiko-san. By any chance...
It's done.
Did the incident occur...
Let's sign this and call it done.
Yes, sir.
...the day your painting was completed?
Thank you for modeling.
That better be true.
It definitely is.
Kasuga-sensei lost his wife six months ago in an accident.
Since they were such lovebirds, he was terribly depressed about it.
He couldn't even enter his studio.
After a while, he suddenly started finding models and painting again.
But both models were attacked by someone on their way home.
I learned that the incidents always occurred on the day their paintings were finished.
And Ran's painting will be finished today.
Damn it. Hurry, kid!
Yeah!
Kasuga Ryuji.
We need to talk.
What's the matter?
You're the one who pushed my sister.
Huh?
My real name is Nogami Yoshio.
I'm the brother of Nogami Machiko, one of your models!
What?
On her way home from this studio,
my sister was attacked by someone and badly injured.
I've been searching for the culprit.
I joined your studio, looking for information.
I've been watching you.
It was shortly after joining your studio
that I learned my sister wasn't the only victim.
Another model suffered an accident, too.
What?
Today, after seeing a room in your studio that I hadn't investigated yet,
I finally learned what your motive is.
The shock of losing your wife drove you crazy!
You're approaching women in locations that were important to you and your wife,
having them model for you, and then hurting them once the painting is complete.
Sir, that can't possibly be—
No, wait!
Kasuga, you're coming with me to see the police.
It's true that in my heart, I was painting my wife.
I thought it might help me get over her.
That much is true.
But attacking models? I have no idea what you're talking about.
You're playing dumb?
Because of you, my sister's dream was shattered.
Hey, what are you doing?
I'm glad you're all right.
Are you Mori Kogoro?
Dad.
You're Ran-san's father?
I see. Mori...
I'm surprised. I didn't know Detective Mori was on the case.
What? Uh, yeah, sure.
But I just...
Just happened to...
Sorry, old man.
That's right.
I looked into the place where my precious daughter was working.
Komiyama-san, you believed the following to be true about the attacks:
Both models were attacked on their way home from the studio in deserted areas.
Therefore, the culprit must've followed the victims since they left the studio.
In other words, you believed the culprit must be someone from the studio.
Yes, that's right. That's why Kasuga is—
As you deduced, the culprit is someone from this studio.
But it's not Kasuga-san.
It's not me. Don't do that. What are you—
Unfortunately, there's proof, Rokui Riko-san.
At first I suspected Kasuga-san as well.
After all, he was spotted near both crime scenes when the attacks took place.
However, I found the testimony of Nogami Machiko-san, the second victim, strange.
She heard a certain sound when she was attacked.
That's right. Kasuga-san doesn't carry anything with him.
If he'd done it, the victim wouldn't have heard anything.
Apparently it was a clattering sound.
I believe it may have been the sound of a sketching pencil.
As an artist's assistant, you carry those around with you all the time.
But that's not enough to—
Of course, that's not all.
I have proof that you're the culprit.
The pole of the steps Ayu-san was pushed down was scratched.
Some paint had come off.
You probably grabbed onto that pole when you tried to push Ayu-san.
Your wristwatch has a metal band,
but one part is shaped differently from the others.
Not only that, but it seems rather new.
Perhaps you damaged it during the attack and had it repaired in a hurry.
This is, uh...
We'll know once we check with the watch repairman.
No way. You're kidding, right?
W-Wait a minute. Why would you attack them?
Because I hated the models.
I was a fan of Kasuga-sensei and asked him to make me his assistant.
Spending time together while he was working made me so happy.
But that was taken from me.
I wondered why I couldn't be his model.
Before I knew it, I was following them.
And then...
How wonderful.
I can't allow someone who doesn't even know who Kasuga-sensei is
to have this painting made of her!
Crap!
Kasuga-sensei told me that I was the last portrait he'd paint.
Once he finished,
he wanted to paint for work with you again
because you supported him.
No...
Kumagaya
Rice crackers!
So this is her new job.
Perfect for me, right?
Yeah. It's important to choose for yourself.
What?
You don't know?
Seriously?
Double H refers to...
Come on, really?
Damn it, Chukichi.
Yumi-tan? As in Taiko Meijin's girlfriend Yumi-san?
We hear about you from the Meijin all the time.
So, what are you guys all doing together?
The next episode of Conan is
"Taiko Meijin's Shogi Board, Opening Move!"