Is that the delivery service?
No, I'm sure it's Mitsuhiko and his friends.
Mitsuhiko?
He's a kid from the neighbourhood.
I promised him that I'd show him my figurines.
Are you saying a bunch of kids are coming here now?
I was the one who invited them.
Mitsuhiko said he likes Yaiba, after all.
The contest deadline is just around the corner!
-I'm sorry. -Don't apologise.
Besides, Shiraishi, you're the reason we're so close to the deadline.
What did you say?
You got cigarette ash on it, so we had to do it all over again.
But you were the one...
Calm down, now.
They're already here, so stop fighting.
The love for deduction and the exhilaration
of unravelling mysteries that comes before sleep!
Students fired up by figurines.
Friendships breaking apart by the fanning of flames.
He sees through the one and only truth.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
His name is Detective Conan!
"Figurine of Revenge"
It's beautiful.
Did everyone make all of these?
Yes, everyone here who's in the circle made them.
-I see. That's amazing! -A... a gun!
What are you doing?
The gun is glowing!
What's going on?
It's just a lighter in the shape of a gun.
A lighter?
Ayumi?
Hey! How long are you going to hold on to him?
Get off her, Conan!
You're all moving around so much and making a lot of noise!
If you're going to be a nuisance, just go home!
Hey! That's not how you should tell them off.
What did you say?
Aoki, how about you show them
the Yaiba figurines you're so proud of?
That's right! It would be great, Aoki.
You're right.
That's awesome!
There are so many Yaibas!
This is a limited edition Yaiba, isn't it?
I'll be back right away,
so you guys can hang out here in the meantime.
Sure!
Why did you have to invite those kids?
I said I'm sorry.
Even if we can't make it in time for the contest,
we could always display it at the university festival.
No way! We have to submit it to the contest
and win no matter what!
I don't mind not winning the contest.
My future is on the line here!
Future? Do you mean your employment?
Hey, Shiraishi, are you hiding something from us?
Shut up! It's none of your business!
Anyway, we have to make it to the deadline, okay?
It's fine.
We only need to send pictures for the first stage of judging,
so we can just upload them to the website by the end of the day.
By the end of the day? But the deadline is tomorrow!
Tomorrow's the anniversary of Yuri's death, so...
I'd like to visit her grave and show her our work.
It was her dream to enter the contest and win it, after all.
Yes. Out of all of us,
Yuri was the one who had the most sense for it.
No matter how talented she was,
it doesn't matter now that she's dead.
Watch your words, Shiraishi.
Is she helping with the filing in the afterlife?
Hey, stop smoking right now.
Shiraishi!
Outstanding Design Award, you say?
-What? -Conan, incoming!
Go!
Come on.
Ouch!
It's you again!
I'm sorry.
Are you okay, Conan?
Yes.
Hey, Genta, what are you going to do if this breaks?
Put it back where it was and don't touch it anymore.
-I know. -Conan? Where are you going?
I'm going to the toilet! The toilet.
It's no good. It's going to leave a stain.
It's all right. Don't mind it.
I'm sorry.
The bottle is all empty now.
What is this?
This can't be.
No.
There's no doubting it.
He's been pushed that far.
But I also understand his feelings.
After all, Yuri ended up like that because...
Yes. I can't allow it, either.
Yes, I can make it in time somehow.
So, things will go as promised, right?
If I win the contest, I'll receive a tentative offer from your company.
Conan, what are you doing over there?
Nothing.
Mr. Mizuhara bought us some ice cream and juice drinks!
Come on!
There are so many of them!
You can choose whichever one you like.
Which one am I going to get?
Where's Shiraishi?
He's probably working on something.
I'll bring these to him.
Shiraishi said he'll eat when he's done with some more work.
I see.
That was delicious!
Genta, you've finished your ice cream?
But I want to eat more!
I'll give you my share, then.
Really?
You can have it.
By the way, do you want to watch some Yaiba DVDs?
Yes, we do.
Just wait for a while.
Which one shall we watch?
Is it a blackout?
No!
But something must have happened in the next room!
It's dangerous in there.
Shiraishi!
Shiraishi, are you okay?
Conan.
There seems to be an explosion.
Gosh, the door is locked!
Shiraishi, unlock the door! Shiraishi!
Mizuhara! Bring the door key here!
Yes.
-You guys hurry on outside -Shiraishi!
and call the fire department!
-Got it! -Hey! Answer us!
-Let's go! -Yes.
-Shiraishi. -Answer us, Shiraishi!
Where were you when the fire occurred?
Yes, sir. We were with the kids in the living room.
We all had ice cream together.
And then, there was a big explosion, and the lights went out.
That's when we heard another explosion.
You heard two explosions.
What did you do after that?
Of course, we wanted to help Shiraishi, so we went to the workroom.
But the door was locked.
Is it usually locked?
No, sir. The kids were visiting today,
so maybe that's why he locked it.
So that he wouldn't be disturbed while working.
I see.
If I had found the key sooner.
So, what was the cause of the fire?
A lighter was found on the floor,
so it's likely the room caught fire
when he tried to light a cigarette or something.
Excuse me.
But there was a different noise before the lights went out.
A different noise?
Excuse me, Inspector.
How is Shiraishi doing?
I'm sorry to say, but he seems to have inhaled a lot of smoke,
so by the time he was brought to the hospital, he was already...
That can't be.
I'm sure one of the sounds was not an explosion.
What could it be?
What are those?
It's a rubber glove and some copper wire.
A rubber glove and some copper wire?
The wall socket is burnt.
So that must have been what made the sound!
The fire seems to have burned the most around the rubbish bins.
What is this?
This must be the lighter.
But if I recall, his lighter...
That's a thinner bottle.
And not only is the bottle open
but there's also a nylon thread tied to it.
Could this be...
Hey, kid!
You shouldn't come in here without permission!
I'm sorry.
It's just that Officer Takagi
told me to ask if there were any lighters other than the one
shaped like a gun.
No, I don't think there were any.
So there weren't any other lighters?
Come on, now! Hurry out.
And one more thing. What is that?
It's probably an exploded plastic bottle.
It changed shape because of the heat, so it's hard to tell.
An exploded plastic bottle?
He must have...
I see.
So that's how it is.
But why would the thinner bottle be there?
It's from Dr. Agasa.
Hello?
Hey, Miss Saki.
Why are the windows in that room boarded up with cardboard?
Mizuhara broke the windowpane yesterday.
We put the cardboard up as a temporary measure.
So I see.
But don't you usually have the window open when you're painting?
We do have it open most of the time.
But we thought we wouldn't be painting much today,
so it would be okay.
Is everyone ready?
We investigated the scene and found it's highly likely
that someone caused the fire on purpose.
First, about the blackout.
The wall socket next to the TV stand is burnt.
A rubber glove and some copper wire were also found on the balcony.
In other words, we found evidence that
someone intentionally caused a blackout
by feeding copper wire into the wall socket,
resulting in a short circuit.
When we heard the first explosion,
someone was next to the TV looking for Yaiba DVDs.
It was Mr. Mizuhara.
What do you have to say, Mizuhara?
I don't know what you are talking about.
But why would Mizuhara do such a thing?
There were two explosions at the time of the incident, right?
I'm sure it was because the different solvents in the room
exploded at different times.
But most of the burning happened near the rubbish bins
and where Shiraishi was lying down.
Other areas weren't as burnt.
It means the solvents didn't explode one after another.
Speaking of which, there was an exploded plastic bottle
that fell to the floor.
This must be it.
It must have been filled with dry ice
and made to explode.
How would it explode?
When you put dry ice in a plastic bottle and close it,
the pressure from the sublimating dry ice
can make the bottle explode.
It's dangerous, so don't try it at home.
Yes.
The sound of the explosion was to signal the timing of the blackout.
And the blackout was the trigger that led to whatever
caused the fire.
This was the item that caused the fire.
This thinner bottle with a nylon thread tied to it
was found in the room.
Mizuhara, when you brought the ice cream to Shiraishi,
you had already put dry ice in a plastic bottle filled with water.
You opened the tied thinner bottle you prepared beforehand
and put it alongside the plastic bottle on a shelf next to the door
before leaving the room.
The other end of the nylon thread was tied to the lock on the door.
After that, the plastic bottle exploded.
The force caused the thinner bottle to fall
and pull the nylon thread so that the door is locked.
And the thinner poured out of the fallen thinner bottle.
If Shiraishi lit his cigarette at that moment,
he would ignite the thinner and cause the explosion.
However, he wouldn't necessarily think to smoke at that time.
That's why you used the sound of the plastic bottle exploding
to cause a blackout and darken the room.
Breaking the glass window
and putting up cardboard as a temporary measure
were probably done for that purpose as well.
Excuse me, officers.
What do you mean by causing a blackout
because he wouldn't necessarily think to smoke at that time?
I don't think he would smoke just because the room got dark.
Wouldn't he turn the lights on again because the room got dark?
But there was a blackout!
You're right.
Put yourselves in Mr. Shiraishi's shoes and think.
What would you do if a plastic bottle exploded and the room got dark?
I'd use a lighter to light up the room.
Mizuhara. To ensure that a fire would occur,
you robbed Shiraishi of his sight
and took his smartphone and lighter out of the room.
Then, he would be forced to use the gun-like lighter
painted with glow-in-the-dark paint next to the door.
Conan found a smartphone and a lighter
in an ice cream box that was in the freezer.
Not only that.
Judging by the severe burning in the rubbish bins,
you must have placed a lot of tissues
doused with flammable fluids in them.
How about that, Mizuhara?
What will you say to it?
I'm sorry!
Before the fire occurred, I spilt a lot of ethanol
and used the tissues to wipe it off!
So that's why...
Saki is not at fault here!
I was the one who told her to do it.
So this is an accident! Please believe us!
The conversation I heard was indeed...
This can't be.
No.
There's no doubting it.
He's been pushed that far.
It was the two of them noticing what Mr. Mizuhara was planning.
Wait.
But I also understand his feelings.
After all, Yuri ended up like that because...
Yes. I can't allow it, either.
Could they... could they be the ones...
Please think of it as a coincidence!
Gosh, so that's how it is!
Dr. Agasa? Where are you now?
As I said, it was only...
That's enough, you two.
It's just as the police said.
So, you are admitting to it.
-Yes. -But why would you do such a thing?
It's for Yuri's sake.
And Yuri is?
She was a member of the circle
who committed suicide last year.
The other day, I showed her parents the designs she made.
And I found that the design we're working on,
which Shiraishi supposedly came up with,
was the same!
When I pressed him about it,
he readily admitted to stealing Yuri's designs
for the designs he had made until now.
Not only that...
She committed suicide just because of some figurines.
What a stupid woman.
Yuri had looked up to Shiraishi,
who regularly participated in design contests,
since her high school days.
She was delighted to have been in the same circle as him.
He used those genuine feelings against her
and betrayed her,
so she despaired and killed herself!
So that's why I...
Spare the details until we're at the police station.
Wait a moment.
Dr. Agasa?
I heard the details from Conan.
Mizuhara was the one who set up and caused the fire, correct?
But the others would have been able to help Shiraishi right away.
After all, Mizuhara's setup had failed to work.
Officer Takagi,
where's the thinner bottle that was used to set up the fire?
It fell in a corner of the room.
That is evidence that the setup did not work as planned.
Pardon?
Think about it carefully.
If the setup had worked,
the thinner bottle would hang from the door,
and the nylon thread would eventually burn up, making the bottle fall.
You would have found the bottle near the door.
Perhaps the force of the exploding plastic bottle was so strong
the thinner bottle with the nylon thread
was blown away by the impact.
I see.
But it is still true that the door was locked.
These two realised what Mizuhara was planning to do
as well as the fact that the plan was highly likely to fail.
So, when the first explosion occurred
and the lights went out,
they stopped Conan, who was on his way to help.
They then waited for the second explosion.
But just as they had feared, the setup didn't work as expected,
and they had to stop Shiraishi, who was trying to escape.
Shiraishi!
Shiraishi, are you okay?
-Aoki, open the door! -Seriously, the door's locked!
Shiraishi, unlock the door! Shiraishi!
Mizuhara! Bring the door key here!
You guys...
We heard that you fought with Shiraishi.
Yes, that's right.
She was the one who came up with this design.
Shiraishi, you...
Besides, Yuri also showed us her design once.
That was when...
Yes, it kind of resembles Shiraishi's design.
You can't do that, Yuri.
You have to bring out more of your own individuality.
That's right. You shouldn't just try to copy what Shiraishi had done.
Even though we didn't know it at that time,
we had hurt Yuri's feelings.
It could be that because of us, Yuri...
"Beika City Figurine Art Contest"
"Outstanding Design Award: Yuri Kurose"
First, we have to find out about the lovers.
Is that so? If that is the case, we'll give our extensive support.
The company I worked at went bankrupt all of a sudden.
My sister was followed by a stalker.
You've had a streak of terrible luck.
If that is the case...
Next Conan,
"The Pork Soup Is A Signal To Risk One's Life"