That's amazing!
It flew up in the blink of an eye!
It went really high up too!
Let me see!
Me too!
Hold on!
It can ascend up to 10 thousand metres...
...in 30 minutes!
That would have made it into the
world's record for drones.
Anyway, how do you even control it
at that height?
By using satellite signals.
That way, it can be controlled
no matter how far away.
The video and coordinates data sent back
from the drone...
...are the actual data received
from the drone itself.
It's not easy to control the direction,
speed and camera all at the same time.
But why did you make a drone like that?
Why, you ask?
It's every man's dream!
With this, I can climb Mt. Everest...
...without physically having to be there!
What a creepy laugh.
I foresee this new device giving rise to
multiple legal issues.
We will bring you the latest news
of the upcoming Summit Meeting in Tokyo...
...right after the commercial.
Next week, the summit will be held
at the international conference hall
located in Edge of Ocean,
the integrated resort
built on reclaimed land.
Scheduled to open to public from next month,
the Edge of Ocean has various facilities...
...incorporating water in its design,
befitting of a coastal city.
The Casino Tower's design,
inspired by seashells,
will also serve its purpose as a beacon
to safeguard the ocean itself.
From this tower, one can have a
bird's eye view of the Edge of Ocean.
Located right beside the Casino Tower,
this shopping mall has...
...a huge waterfall,
and a sky garden,
for visitors to feel at ease.
And there's one more concept.
The interior of the
conference hall was inspired by...
...the breathtaking beauty
of Japanese gardens.
On the first floor, is a posh restaurant.
Have a look over here!
The double-deck monorail
that circles the perimeter!
This smart city has an artistic blend
of traditional and futuristic.
As you can see,
Edge of Ocean is connected by two bridges.
On 1st of May, the day of the summit,
the Metropolitan Police Department,
who are in-charge of security,
will have up to 22,000 police officers
in the city.
Next up, the latest news
on the unmanned probe, "Swan"!
I am high school student detective,
Kudo Shinichi.
One day, at an amusement park
with my childhood friend
and classmate Mori Ran,
I witnessed a suspicious transaction
between some men in black.
Too engrossed in watching,
I failed to notice another of his accomplices
approach me from behind.
I was drugged and when I woke up...
My body had shrunk!
If those men knew that
Kudo Shinichi was still alive,
they would target my life again
and also endanger those around me.
Taking Professor Agasa's advice,
I hid my identity.
But when Ran asked for my name,
I spontaneously told her
it was "Edogawa Conan".
Because Ran's father is a detective,
I moved in with her family
to gather information on those men.
These kids are Genta, Mitsuhiko and Ayumi;
classmates of my shrunken form.
And this is Haibara Ai,
whose real name is Miyano Shiho.
She was a former member
of the Black Organisation.
When she drank the same drug
in an attempt to kill herself,
her body shrunk too.
And a member of this mysterious organisation,
code-named "Bourbon", is Amuro Tooru
whose real identity is an agent of
the secret department nicknamed "Zero",
a department that commands the
National Police Agency Security Bureau.
To keep things under wraps,
he works part-time in Café Poirot
while being Mouri Kogoro's apprentice.
Even though my body has shrunk,
my intelligence remains.
There is always only one truth!
The unmanned probe, Swan,
has completed its survey of Mars...
...and will finally return to Earth
on 1st of May.
During its return trip,
the probe's main body...
...will combust in the atmosphere,
and a returning capsule of
approximately four metres in diameter...
...will re-enter the atmosphere.
Upon which, it will descend via parachute...
...into the Pacific Ocean west of Japan.
I see.
Within the capsule itself is a GPS
with a precise navigation system.
This makes it possible to keep it
within a 200-metre diameter
of the landing point!
Hold on, Genta!
Let me try too!
I want to try too!
Perhaps I ought to split the controller
into three parts
for direction, speed and camera?
We have a news flash.
There has been a huge explosion
at the international conference hall...
...scheduled to host the Tokyo Summit
next week.
Here is footage from the surveillance camera.
This is...
Because the intergrated resort,
Edge of Ocean...
...has yet to be open to the public,
- Professor!
- there were no visitors.
Multiple casualties were suffered
by the police
in charge of the area's security.
According to the police's statement,
- That could be a terrorist attack.
- there was a huge explosion
- But isn't the summit next week?
- at the integrated resort, Edge of Ocean.
- Maybe it was an accident.
- The number of casualties
and cause of the incident...
...are still unclear
and currently under investigation.
The casualties were police officers?
How worrying.
Professor! The video is gone!
Right, I'm coming over!
Come to think of it,
if a terrorist incident took place
right before the summit,
won't security during the actual event
be tightened even more?
What's wrong?
The footage right after the explosion...
What was on it?
It was just for a moment,
and I could be mistaken...
But that person...
...works at Café Poirot.
I remember his name,
as Amuro Tooru.
Amuro?!
(Police station)
From the forensics,
no explosives could be found at the scene.
The conference hall has a
Japanese restaurant on the first floor,
and the explosion took place in the basement,
where the kitchen is.
From there,
a huge amount of gas was detected.
I think it's safe to conclude that
the explosion was due to accumulated gas.
- Gas, huh?
- So it was an accident.
Wait. This building was constructed
only recently.
A gas leak is unlikely.
Yes, this gas pipe is the latest model,
and can be controlled remotely.
If so, why was there a gas leak?
Could the system be faulty from the start?
Weren't inspections carried out?
Inspections were scheduled for today.
What's going on?
The network connections in Edge of Ocean...
...were set up today.
And this morning,
inspections were scheduled to be done...
...right after security checks
by the Public Security Bureau
had been performed.
If that's the case,
then it's likely to be an accident.
Yes, if it's a terrorist attack
targeting the summit,
it's pointless
if not carried out with all the...
...important figures
from various countries gathered in the hall.
Regarding the summit,
due to this incident,
there will likely be a change in location.
It's likely to be an accident.
Reporting in!
State your name and jurisdiction.
Public Security Bureau, Kazami Yuuya.
About the ignition for the gas explosion...
We don't know yet.
We are still inspecting the electric works.
That ignition itself...
...could have been a high-voltage cable.
Did you find any construction fault?
No. However,
the casing for the high voltage cable...
...had a burnt fingerprint on it.
So, the fingerprint was from
before the explosion?
Yes, the only ones
who were on-site this morning,
were the construction workers
and Public Security Bureau personnel.
Therefore, we tried finding a match
for the fingerprint...
...from the workers'
and police officers' database...
...and found one,
from someone formerly
from the Criminal Investigation
1st Department:
Mouri Kogoro.
What?
How can that be?!
This can't be.
It's impossible...
(Detective Mouri Office)
The conference hall on reclaimed land?!
I've never even been there!
But we found your fingerprint at the scene.
That's nonsense!
Dad, could you have entered
while you were drunk?
Like I said, I've never been there!
It must be a misunderstanding!
Search all you want, you won't find a thing!
Excuse me.
Ah, yes.
Conan.
What's going on?
That police officer...
...has an injury on his face; is he alright?
Oh, you mean Kazami?
He was there when the explosion took place.
Oh! I need to use the toilet!
Right, what's up?
Your father is being suspected of a crime?
Yes. Well,
I believe it's a misunderstanding but...
Roger that, I'll investigate too.
Having a spare phone can be tough.
Huh? Where's my smartphone?
Professor?
Oh, Shinichi? What's going on?
I have a favour to ask.
How much longer will you take?!
Oh, sorry about it, but...
My smartphone...
Oh! This is fun!
Genta!
Slow it down, please!
I'm doing a recording!
Sorry!
But this is amazing!
It can fly so far!
And it can be controlled
even at a 30-kilometre distance!
We made it fly 20 kilometres!
We even delivered something
to my grandmother in Saitama!
She was simply delighted!
Since when did you...
But isn't this monitor a little too small
to see clearly?
It wasn't designed for three-way usage.
Professor!
Add a monitor to my controller too.
Mine too!
Is that right...
Alright! Then let's have a quiz!
Okay? If you answer correctly,
I'll attach a monitor for everyone!
Here's the quiz!
(Professor Agasa Quiz)
Among the rows of hiragana characters,
which of these are of the largest scale?
1) Row "A".
2) Row "Ka".
3) Row "Sa".
4) Row "Ta".
What does "largest scale" means?
In other words,
which of these are the largest in size!
A large scale hiragana?
In row "A", there's a, i, u, e, and o.
Row "Ka" is ka, ki, ku, ke, and ko.
Think about what's in each row.
Sa, shi, su, se, so...
Ta, chi, tsu, te, to...
I have no idea!
Hey, Ayumi! Don't move the camera!
Oh, sorry.
1st hint: Swan.
Swan?
Hey, Ai!
If you think about a swan...
Swan Lake...
A big lake would be,
the "Mi" row!
Hmm? Not this row.
2nd hint: the swan will return.
The swan will return home?
Then it must be the lake!
Home... home...
I got it!
The unmanned probe, Swan,
will return from space!
So the answer is?
Number 1! The "A" row!
Within a, i, u, e and o,
"u" is the center (reads chuu),
and that forms "uchuu" (universe)!
The universe is larger in size
than anything else!
Indeed, that's perfect!
Hurray!
Aww, Ai! You always give them too many hints!
Hey Professor,
isn't it dangerous to have a quiz
while operating the drone?
And the recording they are doing right now
is not a game like your quiz!
I apologise.
Our detective department,
the Public Security Bureau
and the security department...
...were inspecting the location
before the summit,
and during the explosion,
the Public Security Bureau were in-charge.
That's why Officer Kazami was injured.
He was stationed outside the building
so his injuries are minor,
but those in the building...
It was mentioned on the news that
there were fatalities.
I shouldn't say something like this,
but I'm glad that...
...no civilians were harmed,
and the casualties
were police officers alone.
If the explosion happened during the summit,
it would cause a world-wide panic.
No, the Metropolitan Police Department...
...and the Public Security Bureau
in particular have been hit rather hard.
Then again, it can't be helped that
an explosion happened before the summit.
An accident?
Based on the primary evidence at the scene,
it appears to be an accident. But...
Uncle Kogoro's fingerprint was found
at the scene?
Yes. And because of that,
Kazami treats it like criminal case.
Officer Kazami...
Thank you, Officer Takagi.
Goodbye!
Get home safe!
Ran, what's wrong?
Shinichi! Help me!
They are going to arrest my dad!
Darn it!
I have no idea!
From your laptop in the drawer,
we found the schedule of the conference.
Also, the floorplan
of the exploded conference hall.
That's impossible!
My father can't possibly have such data
in his laptop!
That's right!
He's laptop illiterate!
That's right! I can't do that!
Anyway, we will discuss the details
at the station.
Don't mess around with me!
I won't go with you Public Security Officers
for interrogation!
Then we will arrest you on the spot
for obstruction of justice.
All I did was brush your hand away!
Hey!
No way!
This is impossible!
28th April, 4.56pm.
Hey! Let go of me!
If you struggle, you will only
increase suspicion against you.
- Let me go!
- Wait!
If the culprit was Uncle Kogoro,
then what was his motive
for causing the explosion?
That's right! What am I after?!
We will go into that
during the interrogation.
Hey, hold on!
Dad!
Calm down, Ran!
Contact Shinichi now!
I've already done that!
I called him, but...
Why, at such a crucial time...
Why isn't he here?!
This is a Public Security Bureau officer,
right?
Well, how should I know?
Wasn't Officer Kazami also injured?
And so are you.
So that means you were also
at the scene of the explosion?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
You were there for the inspection,
weren't you?
You found out there was potential
for a terrorist attack,
but at this rate,
they would just write it off as an accident.
And that's why you created a suspect!
Aren't I right?
It's highly likely
for officers like yourself...
...to work on your laptops at the scene,
and leave behind fingerprints in the process.
You know,
the police won't entertain anything
without evidence.
Why did you do such a thing?!
I have something I must protect
even at the expense of my life.
This time, Amuro might be an enemy.
Why?
Why won't you defend Dad?!
Do you really think he'd have done that?
He's not capable of such a thing.
So... why?!
Like you know, us lawyers...
...can't defend our own blood relatives.
It's very likely that the judge...
...may rule a lack of impartiality.
So, if I defend him,
we would only be at a disadvantage.
No way.
Don't worry,
I will find a good lawyer in no time.
(Contact an attorney for Dongdu University alumni)
(Beika Lawyers Association Directory)
What a shame.
It really turned out just as Furuya said.
But if we'd only found out earlier,
our colleagues wouldn't have had to die.
Who would expect an explosion
before the summit?
Right now,
we are investigating the list of...
...local extremist group
and international terrorists.
What about your side?
I'm looking into the connections made
with the gas line.
It seems to be using a rather unusual system.
What is it?
In due course of the investigation,
I'll convey that to the security department.
Roger that.
What about the thing I told you?
Yes. I've made preparations for "2291".
Furuya?
I got it.
That's...
As expected.
But...
In other words,
from within Mouri Kogoro's laptop,
was a record of connections made
to the gas line's switch.
Yes, that was reported
by the Cyber Crime Department.
It's confirmed now.
Mouri Kogoro sneaked in here, opened this,
and meddled with these high-voltage cables.
Hold on!
If so, the surveillance camera would
have caught him on its footage!
No, the internet connection was
only available from yesterday.
No way!
How's the interrogation?
He continues to deny everything,
but we can still press charges this way.
Do you intend to press charges
without finding a motive?!
If we get any evidence,
we will press charges.
Where the police is concerned,
it's a no-brainer, right?
Wait! Something is off!
Something is definitely strange!
What's off? And what's strange?
Do you think
we will deploy more investigators
just because of your opinion?
Is that so?
Yes.
No way!
Why wouldn't anyone defend Dad?!
Because it's a huge case?
That's right, and also...
The accused happens to be the
infamous "Sleeping Kogoro".
Any lawyer would hesitate to defend him.
Come in.
Excuse me.
Officer Hatori.
I think I need to let you know
before the news gets released.
What is it?
They... are going to
press charges against Mouri Kogoro.
There's enough evidence to
press charges against him?
The fingerprints found at the scene,
the floorplan and conference schedule
found in his laptop,
and the access log of the gas line.
Indeed, that's sufficient to prosecute.
Why? Dad...
Mum...
Wait for me, Ran.
I'll definitely save your dad!
Professor! Have you found something?
Oh, you're here.
Look at this.
Indeed.
That looks like explosives.
You asked me to do a video recording...
...of all the debris, right?
I've stitched up the video...
...like a puzzle and restored it.
In order to find out what kind of bomb it is,
Ai is on the internet as we speak,
trying to find a matching image.
Alright, I found it.
The explosives.
What is it?
I'll pull out the details.
An IoT pressure kettle?
It's like a pressure cooker
but in the form of a kettle.
Using a smartphone, one can adjust its...
...pressure, temperature and timer,
and easily whip up dishes like soups.
Cooking?
Other than the pressure kettle,
there were other things like frying pans,
pots and utensils everywhere.
The explosion occurred inside the facility,
inside the kitchen of the restaurant.
What?
So it wasn't an explosive?!
Hey!
You asked me to search for the explosive,
and Ai worked hard for this too!
What's going on? This is unlike you.
I'm sorry.
What's the matter? What happened?
Uncle Kogoro...
...is going to be prosecuted!
Who's there?
What?
What did you say?
(Tachibana Kyoko, 29, lawyer)
So, please allow me, Tachibana Kyoko,
to defend "The Sleeping Kogoro"!
These are all the cases
I have handled before.
The Extremist Case of Nijoin University,
and the Spy Case of the Ministry of Economy,
Trade and Industry...
You have done several cases
related to public security.
Then this current case
would be perfect for you.
And what were the outcomes of those cases?
What?
Little boy, you sound so grown up
for your age.
I lost them all.
Oh,
but these public security cases are tough.
Indeed. As you are aware,
the rates for prosecutors winning the case
is above 90%.
And that's even higher
for public security cases such as these.
That means there's no way to win,
but I'm a "keiben", so...
Keiben?
In other words,
a freelance lawyer with no attachment
to law firms.
So I am obliged to take on cases
even if they are disadvantageous.
So that's why you'll defend my dad?
You need a lawyer, don't you?
I heard about it
from the lawyer's association,
so please let me do it!
That's right.
Please wait!
No, we can't accept this, Mum.
That lawyer has no intention
of winning the case at all!
Indeed.
But looking at it differently,
because she's hopeless as a lawyer,
the prosecution may underestimate her.
But that's no winning strategy!
It's probably better
to get a court-appointed lawyer.
Then I won't be able to interfere.
But if she's involved,
I can give my two cents.
Even so...
- I feel really uneasy.
- What is the cat's name?
It's Goro!
It looks like you'll be denying...
(Makoto Kusakabe, 40, Attorney)
...everything to the police.
That goes without saying.
I didn't do anything.
But there is so much evidence
pointing to you as the culprit.
It beats me too!
I can only imagine,
that someone is trying to set me up!
This explosion case will be handled...
...by Prosecutor Kusakabe.
That sounds like bad news.
I've heard of him,
in spite of the little experience
I have with public security cases.
Is he that good a prosecutor?
He's as good as Attorney Kisaki.
And unlike me, he has never lost before.
I'm familiar with this case.
Unauthorised access into NAZU's system.
You mean that well-known,
American space research centre?
Yes. Last year, some game company's staff
decided to access their system for fun.
The prosecutor for that case
was also Kusakabe.
And, the outcome was...
Of course, he won that too.
"Of course", huh?
Good grief.
As a result of today's investigation...
It bothers me that Mouri Kogoro has no motive
to carry out this terror attack.
(Iwai Sayoko, 40)
Motive, you say.
But with already this much evidence,
can't we just press charges tomorrow?
Well...
For example, if the gas line from the scene
was accessed and recorded in this log,
using the suspect's laptop
as an access point,
then it would make logical sense.
On top of that, by leaving the floorplan
and schedule in the laptop as evidence,
- Mouri Kogoro could be a scapegoat.
- Chief Kusakabe...
That is...
...mere presumption on your part,
disregarding all the evidence too.
Iwai, I made the police
carry out extra investigations,
Prosecute Mouri Kogoro.
That's the public security department's
decision.
Understood?
Does that public security department...
...belong to the prosecutor's office,
or to the police?
That will be all.
Please leave.
You were asked
to carry out extra investigations?
Yes, by Prosecutor Kusakabe.
So, based on the result of
this investigation,
they may not press charges against my dad?
No.
Although Kusakabe requested
for extra investigations,
the Public Security Bureau has
already decided to press charges.
Hold on!
Why would the decision to press charges
come from the police?
The police themselves...
...are in no position to interfere
with the prosecution!
No matter what,
that right alone is exclusive...
...to the prosecution!
Yes, it is as you said.
However, it applies for
prosecuting civil and criminal cases,
as well as special investigations cases.
But when it comes to
the public security department,
you should know
it would be a little different.
Yes.
Even if we call it
the public security department,
there is one of each in the
Tokyo Metropolitan Police Department,
the National Police Agency
and the Public Prosecutors' Office.
Although the police hands all investigation
outcome to the prosecutors,
the prosecutors may also investigate it.
The prosecutor's decision to...
press charges against the suspect or not,
would normally be based on
this investigation.
However, the public security department of
the prosecutors' office is different.
To put it simply,
one can't fight against the
police's public security department...
...due to the disparity
in the number of members
as well as their skills.
Therefore, there are times
where the "concern of public security"
can come into place.
Concern of public security?
For an explosion to take place
at the summit's location,
is a great humiliation
to the Public Security Bureau.
I can imagine their pressure
to press charges.
Then dad would be...
Yes, they will definitely press charges.
No...
This lawyer...
It's as if she's on the prosecution's side!
Kogoro's laptop...
Did you check the possibility of it
being manipulated by someone else?
Well, Kusakabe did request
for additional investigations.
Please tell me all you can!
I really want to help Uncle Kogoro!
Any sort of information will do!
Mr. Mouri...
What happened to him?
Amuro...
You overheard us?
What is it?
I was worried about Mr. Mouri,
so I brought some snacks from Café Poirot.
Mouri is no longer here.
He is now awaiting prosecution...
...under police custody.
There's no way you wouldn't know, right?
I see. You are still as sharp as ever.
Hey, you're not allowed to bring him...
...such items while he's being detained.
Understood!
What is he after?!
2991, submission complete.
What? What did he say to Amuro?
Darn!
Hey! Officer!
Return the laptop
you took from Uncle's house!
It has my favourite game in it!
Like I said before!
It's part of the evidence
so we can't return it yet.
Hey, Conan! Stop this!
Professor made that game for me!
Conan, I called you a few times.
What?
My battery is flat.
Can you charge it with that?
Yes. Thank you!
Normally, it would have lasted longer.
Why did you call?
They will be bringing information
of the case soon.
Ran said she wanted to show you too.
Because Conan always finds
interesting angles.
And you might be able to tell Shinichi
about it too.
Yes! I will let him know for sure!
Thank you, Conan.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
These are the evidence
the prosecutors submitted.
So, that means...
...they have decided to press charges?
The prosecutor's side has decided...
...to press charges as soon as possible.
Dad...
Don't worry, we'll definitely save him.
Let's go over there.
Yes.
Record of statement,
the crime scene appraisal,
and crime scene photographs.
That's a lot.
I've got to find something.
Darn it, there's nothing?!
What's wrong?
No...
It feels like I've seen this somewhere.
Looking at these,
it clearly shows
the method for the explosion.
The police investigation reports,
are like a written manual of the crime.
Manual...
Yes, this is Tachibana.
The court?
Yes.
Pre-trial arrangement procedure...
Iwai!
Why did you tell the defence...
...about the prosecution,
without even telling me?!
Stop making me repeat myself.
That's the public security police's decision.
So they decided on the prosecution,
and now the timing?
On top of that,
the court has already
contacted the prosecuting side,
as well as the defence, to complete the...
...pre-trial arrangement procedure tomorrow.
So why was this information conveyed to you?!
I'm the prosecutor in-charge!
You will be notified
once the formalities are done.
It's not here, that huge tub of ice cream...
Indeed.
I'll go ask the staff,
and you get the flour and eggs!
You'd make a great wife, Azusa.
Please be mindful of your behaviour!
You're so popular
with the regular high school girls.
Our last conversation went viral
on the internet!
In this day and age,
one never knows
when someone else might be listening!
Indeed.
Furuya.
Why are you bent on trying to make it a case?
If it's treated as an accident,
we will lose one warrant.
But as public security officers,
we can conduct investigations
without warrant.
All the more we have to do it legally.
We will be suffocating ourselves.
We are obligated to take care of...
...any illegal activities on our parts.
That's public security.
But the decision
to announce a case legally...
...or to conceal it legally,
that's also on us.
Of course.
It is based on whichever decision...
...can protect Japan the most.
Hey, Amuro!
(Tokyo District Court)
So, first of all...
From the prosecution's side,
please clear the facts to be proven,
and provide the evidence.
Yes.
We will submit a list of evidence.
Ran.
Calm down.
But...
The trial is not today, is it?
That's right.
This is the pre-trial procedure.
Its purpose is to arrange all the points
of debate and evidence,
and also to decide on a trial date.
Didn't I mention that?
I know, but...
Ms. Kyoko!
Iwai, this is Kusakabe.
Right now,
we have completed the
pre-trial arrangement procedure.
The evidence that Kusakabe submitted...
It was the same as what was submitted before.
This is the list.
The trial date?
It's decided.
Just as planned before.
Sorry, please read through it.
I need to use the washroom.
Oh, Ms. Kyoko!
It's the other way!
Ms. Kyoko!
- This is...
- How's the situation?
The bug I placed on Kazami yesterday...
Is he nearby?
I see, please carry on.
He's nearby!
Could he be...
...in this court?!
Where?!
Isn't this Kyoko's ringtone?!
Hello, Kyoko?
I have something to confirm with you.
I'll be right back!
Why would I be hearing Kyoko's voice...
...through the bug on Kazami?!
Could she just happen to be near Kazami?
No. If I could hear her voice,
they should be rather close.
It can't be a coincidence.
According to our investigation in PSB,
the unauthorised access to the crime scene...
...was carried out using "NOR".
NOR?
It is a browser software...
...encrypting an IP address,
that bypasses a few computers,
thus making it untraceable.
Can you crack the anonymity of NOR?
Technically, I can't.
But if there are any flaws or bugs...
...in the NOR software,
it will be possible...
...to pinpoint its user.
So that means,
if we can weaken the culprit's NOR software,
we can possibly trace its user.
Right now, we are trying to trace the server,
while searching for the possibility...
...of tracking down the user.
My apologies.
I've been summoned.
I'll excuse myself.
Okay.
Are you trying to eavesdrop on the meeting?
Why are you here?
As long as it's related to Mouri Kogoro,
you'll give it all you've got.
Or, is it...
...for Ran's sake?
It's fine. Come on out.
Why did you call me out?
Furuya?
I would have expected more
of a Public Security Officer.
I-I'm sorry.
Who did this?
Wait!
This bug...
Was it set by you?
No way.
He's only a child...
The organisation that Amuro is from,
which can control the entire nation's
public security officers...
...is nicknamed "Zero".
Only a handful of public security officers...
...are able to receive his direct orders.
And one of them is you, Officer Kazami.
Who exactly are you?
Edogawa Conan,
a detective.
The man you address as Amuro,
is a murderer.
Last year,
the suspect we brought in for interrogation
was driven to commit suicide.
Suicide?
Sorry, I shouldn't have said that to a child.
Why did I say those things
to a child like you?
It's not your problem.
So, before the PSB...
...can pinpoint the accessing address,
they got Mouri Kogoro.
Excuse me!
Right now...
The city is in trouble!
W-What's this?!
Mum! Something's wrong!
No way!
What?!
- Is something wrong?!
- Hurry up!
- Whoa, this is bad indeed.
- Whoa! Amazing, what is this?!
It's always the same thing.
For today's summit, tight security
has been stationed all across Tokyo.
Currently, the police have yet
to release a statement...
...regarding the numerous strange occurences
in the city.
Not only in Japan, members of the summit...
...are voicing their complaints
to the Japanese government.
Personal computers and electric kettles
have been reported to have exploded.
And panic continues to spread.
What exactly is this?!
I repeat.
Currently, the police have yet to release...
- What is the culprit trying to do?
- a statement regarding the numerous strange occurences.
of electrical appliances exploding.
- Strange occurence of exploding...
- Electrical appliances?
Using a smartphone, one can adjust its...
..pressure, temperature and timer,
and easily whip up dishes like soups.
That's it!
This terrorist attack,
started with the explosion
at the conference hall!
Situation report!
The communications headquarters
is also in a state of panic!
Over 100 locations have reported in!
The headquarters should be
in the police department!
What's going on?!
Is this a terrorist attack?
Where are the official statements?!
Conan, sorry I haven't time
to speak with you now.
Inspector Megure!
All this must be an "IoT terrorist attack"!
IoT terrorist attack?
What the culprit is trying to do,
is make random IoT appliances...
...go berserk via the internet!
So if you cut off the internet connection,
the chaos would stop!
An IoT terrorist attack huh?
What a child.
So that pressure kettle...
...from the crime scene,
should also be an IoT appliance!
So, using the internet,
the culprit manipulated the IoT gas line...
...to fill the place with gas,
then turned the IoT kettle
into an ignition source,
and caused the explosion
in the conference hall!
S-So that means...
Yes!
It wasn't Uncle Kogoro!
Is that true?
That's what big brother Shinichi told me,
so I'll leave it to you!
Conan.
So Shinichi really worked hard...
...for my dad's sake.
Silly.
It wasn't...
...just for your dad.
I see.
If all that is true,
then we can probably win the case.
Yes, because Uncle Kogoro
is now under police custody,
and can't access the internet!
No.
If he set the timer beforehand,
he could still carry out the IoT attacks...
...even after being arrested.
If they trace the server...
...and pinpoint the access point,
Mouri would definitely be charged.
No way!
But isn't the server investigation difficult?
Would it be done in time for the trial?
If the PSB are on it,
it shouldn't be that tough.
Wait.
Why are you so familiar with the process?
Oh, I'm so sorry!
Well, little boy...
They often perform such an investigation.
The PSB has many "cooperators", after all.
Do you mean civilians
who help with their investigation?
That's right.
In particular, investigations involving...
...server related issues...
...under the wiretapping law.
The PSB has many cooperators.
With such a cooperator,
they can soon find evidence...
...of Mouri Kogoro's unauthorised access.
Well, provided such evidence exists,
of course.
Right, this will do.
Do you think so?
Yes. Let us ask the companies directly.
I knew it, something felt strange.
She is hiding something.
Regarding the numerous strange occurences
in the city,
the MPD just released a statement...
...that it could likely be
an IoT terrorist attack.
Who would have expected
an IoT terrorist attack?
All the same, you even managed
to pinpoint the method used.
I wasn't the one who found it out,
but thanks to that, I could make it a case.
And so, I would like to settle...
the illegal deeds I had performed.
Release the cooperator.
Before that, please tell me...
...what information Zero has at this point.
NAZU?
Release this information...
...to the anti-cybercrime department,
and let the investigation team report this
in their meetings.
You want the investigation team
to take credit for this?
It should be reported by us, the PSB.
It's a reward.
It is to their credit, that...
...we were able to turn
the explosion into a criminal case.
Also,
the higher ups are aware that...
...this information came from Zero.
You're scary.
Kazami. Above me, are two people...
...way scarier than I am.
And one of them,
is still a child.
I just thought of the same kid as you.
We have found...
...traces of unauthorised access
from Mouri's laptop.
As speculated,
it was used as an access point.
And the trace itself?
From a public wifi,
using an untraceable smartphone.
So we couldn't pinpoint it.
But at that point of time,
(Tokyo Detention Center)
Mouri was detained under police custody,
so it was impossible for him
to be an access point.
And like before, the current IoT attacks...
...were also accessed via the NOR software.
So it's the same culprit.
How is the investigation
in locating the server?
According to the report
from the anti-cybercrime department,
the system was found in NAZU.
Hello! Sorry I'm late!
Kuriyama,
I'm sorry about this.
You rarely have a vacation, and yet...
No, it's fine!
You have an important matter at hand
and as your staff,
how could I be out gallivanting?
Thanks for your help.
So...
Here's the investigation on Tachibana Kyoko.
Hmm? Kudo Shinichi asked me to do it.
Shinichi did?
Huh? Big brother Shinichi ordered that?
Why would he want to investigate Tachibana?
If big brother Shinichi wanted it,
he definitely has a good reason.
Shall we look at the report?
We found out that Tachibana's staff...
...broke the law last year.
Isn't Tachibana a freelance lawyer?
She shut down her firm last year.
At that time, her staff, Haba Fumikazu...
...illegally accessed and stole...
...from a game company.
But after Haba was arrested
for investigation,
he commited suicide
while under police custody.
What? Suicide?
Suicide...
(Investigation Report)
What's going on?
A third party...
...was manipulating Mouri Kogoro's laptop,
therefore it's unlikely that
he's the culprit.
Yes!
And that's it.
So what about the fingerprint?
That burnt fingerprint, you mean?
It's really easy
to transplant something like that.
Is that the PSB's conclusion?
They will not prosecute Mouri Kogoro.
So the decision not to prosecute...
...will be based on the PSB's words?!
You're so stubborn.
What? Iwai?
Yes.
She suffered minor burns,
but went to the hospital just in case.
Could that
have been an IoT terror attack too?
We checked the smartphone,
and it's the same as before:
an access from the NOR software.
Excuse me.
Yes, this is Shiratori.
What? Hold on!
They are not going to prosecute Mouri!
Mum!
That's great, Ran.
Yes, thank you.
I need to tell Shinichi,
and Sonoko too!
Anyway, what should we do?
This is from the investigator...
...in charge of Haba Fumikazu's case.
Isn't this person the victim...
...from the smartphone that got set ablaze?
She was the prosecutor in-charge.
But right now, she's Kusakabe's superior,
who was from the same year as her.
That's right.
Iwai was promoted...
...thanks to Haba Fumikazu's case.
By the way, what is this?
Why are you investigating...
...me and my former staff?
Well...
I'm sorry, we wanted to know...
...more about you,
so I asked Kuriyama to do it.
You did a good job investigating.
You'd make a great employee too.
"You... too?"
You speak as though...
...Haba Fumikazu was also a great employee.
Wasn't he a bad employee who stole,
and caused your firm to shut down?
A bad employee?
That wasn't Fumikazu's fault!
It was my fault for being so helpless...
He was a mere employee,
but you addressed him by his first name.
What about his suicide
in the detention centre?
He commited suicide,
soon after facing interrogation
by the public security officer...
...at the detention centre.
Last year, he drove a suspect...
...to commit suicide at the detention centre.
Why would a public security officer....
I've never heard of that.
When Fumikazu commited suicide,
something strange happened.
This Haba Fumikazu was dismissed
as a legal apprentice, right?
So his ambition was to be a judge?
Yes, but...
During the judicial ceremony,
he...
(4 years ago, Law Training Institute)
To those who would from this day,
become a judge or a lawyer...
- Your connections made here...
- Director!
Director!
About...
About my rejection,
I would like an explanation!
What is the meaning of this?
The reason behind my rejection...
The reason!
How could you, with no reason...
You took away my mission...
...to be a judge!
I won't forgive this!
That action...
...was deemed as self-fulfilling,
self-righteous behaviour and as a result...
His path as a lawyer was destroyed,
and so was his future in the legal world.
Why did you take Haba as your staff?
You see, people have two sides to them.
What people could see,
was only one side of him.
I heard from your daughter outside,
that if they are not prosecuting
Mouri Kogoro,
then my business here is finished.
What? Ah, yes.
Then, please excuse me too.
There are still investigations pending.
You have to investigate the culprit's NOR,
right?
Yes, we have requested help from NAZU.
NAZU? The American organisation?
Yes. Last year,
they had an unauthorised access...
...made via NOR.
Ah, the case Ms. Kyoko worked on.
Because of that, NAZU completed a system...
...capable of tracing NOR users,
and they will help us trace it from tomorrow.
They are tied up with the task...
...on Swan's landing mission, after all.
You mean, the unmanned probe?
Yes, it happens on the same day
as the summit,
so the police are all frantic.
I see, so the summit is today as well.
At the time of the explosion,
the Public Security Bureau were in charge.
The prosecutor's public security department
doesn't stand a chance against
the police's public security department.
Therefore, there are times
where the "concern of public security"
can come into place.
The PSB has many cooperators.
Isn't this Kyoko's ringtone?
Why am I hearing it through the bug
on Kazami?
The man you call Amuro,
is a murderer.
He commited suicide
while under police custody.
I know about this case.
Unauthorised access into NAZU's system.
An IoT terrorist attack?
Making IoT appliances
go berserk via the internet!
The police investigation reports,
are like a written manual of the crime.
I found a matching image!
It feels as if I've seen this somewhere.
No way. It can't be...
Midori!
Send me the details...
...on the unauthorised access
into NAZU's system!
That's what Shinichi said to tell you!
Conan!
We're going to pick my dad up...
...from the police department!
Darn it, why won't Shinichi answer his phone?
It looks like you expected me to come here.
The first time I felt something was off,
was back then.
Excuse me.
Ah, yes.
I got Professor to help me investigate...
...and there was a tracing app in it,
the sort that doesn't leave any icon.
What about the evidence left by the PSB?
None, as expected of the PSB.
Since you already knew that,
why didn't you remove the app?
Because I'm going to meet the culprit now.
You know the culprit
behind the terror attacks?!
Yes, and their target too.
The target, is you and your team, Amuro.
The root was the unauthorised access
into NAZU.
That was last year's...
Haba Fumikazu?!
Yes.
Last year, Haba commited suicide
in the detention centre, didn't he?
Yes. It was on this same day last year.
This very day... last year?!
I see. How awful.
The culprit has yet to
finish getting revenge!
IoT terrorist attack?!
Amuro!
Go!
At last, the unmanned probe, Swan,
has returned to Earth from Mars.
Good evening, everyone.
This is the Nagano Astrology Channel.
Right now,
we have observed the Swan's location...
It's already so late, time to go home.
But the Swan will return soon!
Let us watch the live broadcast!
No, watch it at home.
No way! Haibara...
Yes. What's up?
The children want to
watch the live broadcast.
Time left until it enters the atmosphere?
I think it's...
Kudo?
Another hour or less?
We have no time!
Conan, so the culprit...
Yes. The culprit is attempting to...
...hack into NAZU and make it crash!
But, where....?
Darn it, could it be...
From space?!
He's here!
Uncle!
Dad!
Welcome back!
Sorry to make you worry, Ran.
I'm so relieved...
Sorry to have caused you trouble, Eri.
What are you talking about?
I'm so glad!
Sonoko, thank you!
Right! I should send this emotional scene...
...to that mystery-solving geek!
Wait, Sonoko!
This should be able to reach him!
Say cheese!
What?
What's going on?
Someone bring a spare light over!
Inspector!
The reserve generator appears to
be destroyed!
What?!
What's going on here?!
A report from NAZU!
There's been an unauthorised access...
...into the unmanned probe!
What?!
At this rate,
the capsule won't be able to eject...
...from the probe's main body!
The main body of Swan,
will be burnt off in the atmosphere...
but its landing spot is unpredictable,
(NAZU Control Center)
and NAZU is now in a state of panic!
Here's the latest estimation data!
East longtitude 139°45′8″405.
Based on their estimation, it's...
It's here.
No way...
Conan!
As expected, the culprit's target is...
The Tokyo Metropolitan Police Department!
The capsule will land
in the Tokyo Metropolitan Police Department?!
What's going on?!
If it's a capsule larger
than four metres in diameter,
the damage will be unthinkable!
Prepare a huge transport vehicle right now!
Evacuate everyone
within a one-kilometre radius
of the Tokyo Metropolitan Police Department!
Yes, Sir!
Let's go!
Where's the evacuation map?!
There's no time!
Dad...
Don't worry, I'm here.
Eri, you too.
Do not leave my side!
Yes...
Good job.
The capsule that ejects
from the Swan's main body,
is crashing down like a meteorite!
In other words,
before it enters the atmosphere,
we only have a small time frame
to control its path!
Within a one-kilometre radius of
(Head of Department of Environmental Conservation)
the Tokyo Metropolitan Police Department,
the total number to be evacuated
from parks, hotels and offices,
(Cabinet, Settlement Room)
is over 150,000!
We have prepared an evacuation ground...
(Head of the Traffic Department)
...away from the one-kilometre radius
and cleared the roads for these people.
(Department of Defense official)
Prime Minister! We've just received...
...a report from NAZU
that they can't rewrite the data!
What?
The signal sent from the ground stations
to the probe...
is specially encrypted.
But if those codes don't match,
then they can't rewrite the probe's data!
In other words,
the culprit changed the code?!
Yes, at the time when he hacked into NAZU...
...and changed the probe's path!
We need to find out what the code is!
I would like you to be a cooperator.
Get a hold of this professor who
creates all these amazing inventions.
What are you trying to do?
Bring a dead person back to life!
It's just like him,
to think of such a strategy.
It would be great
if we could extract the code
using this method.
I have successfully quickened the process!
Professor, the footage is too unstable.
This isn't going to work.
This is the first time I flew this at night!
I want to fly a drone at night too!
It's not fair for Professor to play alone!
All of you...
They didn't show the Swan on TV!
Okay, so who wants to give me a hand?
Professor's control is too unstable.
Hurray!
I'm so excited!
How mean...
Leave it to these children,
and let us proceed with the preparations.
We are the...
Drone...
Flying team!
Go!
Starting from now,
approximately 30,000 people will be evacuated
to the reclaimed land on Tokyo Bay,
the Edge of Ocean.
Where was it again?
I have no idea!
Isn't that where they planned
to have the summit?
Indeed, we will evacuate to the Casino Tower.
Casino Tower?
There it is!
Right. I have to contact Shinichi!
NAZU continues to send the code,
but they still can't access the probe.
Darn it!
We have got to find out the code,
as fast as possible!
Are you looking at data
from NAZU's ground station?
Culprit behind the terrorist attacks?
I didn't expect it to be you,
Prosecutor Kusakabe.
What's going on? Both of you?
I should have known it earlier,
when I saw the list of
evidence you submitted.
Only the culprit himself could have known
that piece of glass,
as a part of the real ignition.
And you submitted that as evidence,
when the ignition was still...
...assumed to be the high-voltage cable!
Nice timing.
These are the trial documents from...
...last year's case of illegal access
in NAZU's system.
The one you were in-charge of.
I see.
The modus operandi of that case,
lies in making use of NOR
for unauthorised access.
You employed the same method from the case...
...you were in-charge of,
to carry out cyber-terror attacks.
But you made a mistake with that.
NAZU already completed a system,
that could trace NOR users.
Knowing that, you used a bugged NOR system...
...to fake an IoT terror attack
on your own superior.
In order to make the police
go after that decoy,
you picked the opportune moment
to carry out the attack.
Don't touch my stuff!
Stop!
There are traces of NOR usage
in that smartphone!
You've got to be kidding me!
I won't let you get away!
Darn it, that didn't work?!
No problem!
Darn!
Prosecutor Kusakabe,
are the public security police...
...the reason behind your terrorist attacks?!
If there's an explosion in the summit's hall,
and an American probe falls into Tokyo,
the Public Security Bureau
will have no credibility left!
Why do you hate the PSB so much?
With all the authority you PSBs have,
public prosecutors like ourselves...
...can't fight for justice fairly!
Is it okay to sacrifice lives...
...in the name of justice?!
It was never my intention
to kill any civilians!
That is why the explosion occured
when there were
only Public Security officers!
I chose an IoT attack
that wouldn't kill anyone!
That's why I chose that crashing point
for the capsule!
You caused the blackout
at the police department
so that the civilians could evacuate?
Yes.
I see.
That's why you created
all those IoT attacks along the way,
to prevent people from entering.
Even so, there is bound to be casualties!
For the sake of justice,
some sacrifices are definitely necessary.
That's not what justice is about!
My...
My cooperator,
was also sacrificed!
Was it Haba?
I knew it. Haba was your cooperator?
How did you...
It was your passcode.
You seemed conscious of it,
but didn't mute the sound...
...so that you wouldn't forget him?
Haba Fumikazu.
No.
It was so I would never forget to
get revenge on those scumbags!
Every cooperator of the PSB...
...reports to Zero and is managed
by their code number.
But fellow officers wouldn't know
about each other's cooperators.
Until last year, we had no idea
about public security prosecutors...
...having cooperators.
So that's why you could dispose
of my cooperator so easily?!
I see. There's a hidden reason,
behind the case Haba created.
I was the one...
...who asked Haba to do that.
It was in order to research on...
...the unauthorised access into NAZU.
That access data,
was in the game company
that the suspect made use of,
and Haba wanted to steal that.
(Tokyo Detention Center)
PSB's cooperators are tasked with...
...illegal and risky activities
for investigation purposes,
and that is why the relationship
between the officer
and cooperator is said to be stronger than
that of blood relatives.
It's not merely business.
Connected by our sense of mission,
it's as if we are of one heart and mind.
When they interrogated you,
why didn't you tell them
you were my cooperator?!
I couldn't let my mistake cost you your job,
as a public security prosecutor.
Rather than for me, think of yourself too!
I understand the pain more than anyone else.
When I was stripped of my mission for justice
Please! Think of your own life too!
The lives of many Japanese
are way more important...
...than my life alone.
Like I always said,
I share your resolution.
(Prosecutor's Office)
I revealed everything to the prosecutor...
...handling his case.
Haba was working for me.
I instructed him to carry out the crime.
Even so, I will still press charges.
What?!
Truly, I didn't expect the PSB to...
Don't worry.
I'll make sure your name is not revealed,
and that the trial ends smoothly.
That's not what I came here to say!
After everything,
I wanted to speak directly with the PSB,
and when I was heading
to the detention centre,
Yes?
Haba committed suicide.
I don't know why, but...
after the PSB officers conducted
an irregular interrogation on him,
he ended his life.
The ones who drove Haba to commit suicide...
No, the PSB killed Haba!
That is why you planned to crash the probe...
...into the Metropolitan Police Department.
Yes, when I knew that
the day Swan would return...
...is the same day Haba died...
What about the IoT terror attacks?
They were not a part of my plan,
but I couldn't let an innocent man
get prosecuted.
You carried out the IoT terror attacks
in order to prove Mouri Kogoro's innocence?
But unfortunately, the damage done...
...was more widespread than I expected.
You cannot bear the burden of
so much wrongdoing.
Tell us the code to the probe!
Public prosecutors
are the protectors of justice!
I can't let them get away
with what they did to Haba!
Tell us the code!
You might as well just arrest me!
I will remain silent.
Prosecutor Kusakabe!
Kusakabe...
It can't be!
Why is Haba...?!
This is live from the MPD.
What's going on?
The PSB officer who interrogated him...
...faked his suicide,
and made him start his life anew.
In order to hide the fact...
...that PSB officers employed cooperators
to assist in investigations...
...and to prevent prosecutors
from having any other cooperators,
even you were kept in the dark.
We have the means to settle...
...our own illegal activities.
But you have no such ability!
That was the PSB's decision.
Just like how Haba was obsessed
with becoming a judge,
you too, possess a strong sense of justice.
And that was why...
...you made Haba your cooperator,
because he had nowhere to
go after being dismissed.
That's right.
Kusakabe saved my life
from hitting rock bottom.
Although it was a mere two years,
Kusakabe's words to me were "Thanks to you,
I could fight on as a prosecutor!"
And that is why I continue to fight on.
Kusakabe, tell them the code you changed!
If it crashes into that place,
Haba will not emerge unharmed!
How deceitful.
That is how the PSB works!
The Swan will soon enter the atmosphere!
Still no idea on the code?!
At this rate,
they won't be able to
access the probe at all!
Furuya, there's no time!
Quick! Spill it!
Prosecutor Kusakabe! Hurry!
But...
Kusakabe...
Is this the sense of justice
I believed you possessed?
The code that I changed,
through illegally accessing NAZU's system,
is...
What? A blackout?!
Yes! In just five minutes
after it enters the atmosphere!
Within that time frame, there will be plasma.
So we can't be sure
if the path could be altered.
And there could be a chance that
the parachute won't deploy.
No way!
Let Haba...
Let Haba be evacuated from there!
Prosecutor Kusakabe!
Any word from Shinichi?
No, not yet.
I got to his voicemail.
What is that guy doing?
Conan's phone seems to be out of battery.
If it's that guy, he'll be just fine.
This is really high up.
Hurry, over here!
Haba! Where are you?!
What's going on?!
He's not here.
B-But from the phone screen,
he was definitely...
What you saw was a composite video.
What?!
Using a footage filmed with a drone,
combined to look as if
he was on the MPD's helipad.
He's in a safe place right now.
I see.
Amuro, if we can't alter the crashing path,
the landing point would be...
Yes. A four-metre wide capsule
will crash land here,
with a speed of over 10km/s.
Are you able to get explosives right now?
Do you intend to destroy
a heat-resistant capsule?
No.
We need just enough explosives to
change its course to the Pacific Ocean.
Unbelievable...
Have you any other ideas?
Kazami, do it right now.
Yes, illegal activities like this are
second nature to Public Security Officers.
This is one of the strongest explosives
we have confiscated.
Is it traceable?
It's close to the deadline to be discarded,
so all we have to do is rewrite the records
and it will be fine.
Alright.
Please proceed.
Not a problem.
We'll send the capsule's projected course
to your address.
Alright everyone, let's go!
Alright!
Got it!
Fancy asking me to calculate
an ideal place for activating the explosion
Darn it, what a slave driver!
Mitsuhiko, Ayumi,
Genta.
And Ai...
You will protect this country!
It's shaking a lot!
The Professor's things are too heavy!
Let's just get rid of it!
No way!
Those items are very precious!
Error margin is within a 10-metre radius.
I'll send you the footage from the drone,
so you take care of the timing.
Yeah, I'll leave it to you.
But is it really okay?
For us to film the Swan
at such close distance?
No problem,
we have permission from the police.
Or rather, from the public security bureau.
What?
(Cabinet Secretary)
The parachute didn't deploy?!
It appears to be locked onto the heat shield!
Prime Minister,
please give your permission to destroy it!
Hold on!
But...
If we try to destroy it at such a height,
there will be more casualties.
It has passed 30,000 metres in altitude.
I got it.
Don't make any mistake.
Understood!
Amuro!
Can we get the timing right this way?
Yes.
Approaching the capsule!
I'm depending on you guys.
At this rate, there will be a collision!
Don't worry!
That drone has a system
that senses nearby objects,
and dodges automatically!
Everyone. Unless you fly it closer,
we can't see the capsule flying in!
I want to see it!
Go, Mitsuhiko!
I got it!
Kudo, don't do anything reckless.
It's coming!
Go!
The parachute deployed!
- What?
- We can't see anything?
Did it crash?!
Doesn't it have an automatic dodge system?!
Ah, perhaps...
...the battery went flat.
There never was such a system.
I guess it all went well?
I'm amazed.
Who are you guys?
I guess you could call us...
...the small detective's cooperators.
Got it.
It was a success.
That's great!
Furuya,
I'll bring the suspect back.
Okay.
Hold on.
Kusakabe,
even now, we are still of one heart and mind.
Yeah.
Let's go.
Fumikazu!
Kyoko!
Fumikazu...
You're still alive.
He's really...
...one scary person.
So you were a cooperator too...
And moreover, for a prosecutor!
Ms. Kyoko.
You were a cooperator too, weren't you?
For Officer Kazami.
Boy, did you hear about it?
The reason I employed Haba.
As a dismissed employee,
the PSB had their eyes on him.
(4 years ago, Tachibana Law Firm)
So I employed him,
and made him report his actions.
But in the process...
...of working with him,
I was somehow attracted to him.
The feeling was mutual.
That's why I'm really sorry that
things turned out this way.
So you were a cooperator, just like me.
Everything started with the...
...illegal access into NAZU's system,
didn't it?
Yes.
The PSB had instructed me to investigate,
while assuming the suspect to be guilty.
At that time,
he was arrested at the game company...
...frequented by the suspect.
I didn't know why he did that.
I begged the PSB to help him.
But he commited suicide,
and I hated the PSB as a result.
I closed down my firm,
and searched for an opportunity
to get revenge.
And that was when,
you were instructed to defend Uncle Kogoro...
...and prove his innocence?
Yes. I didn't understand why the PSB...
...wanted to make him innocent,
so I thought I should do the opposite.
And implicate an innocent person?!
I had no choice!
I had no idea...
...he was still alive
and under the protection of the PSB!
If I had known, I wouldn't have...
Fumikazu is now...
...your cooperator, right?
What is his number?
Number?
Internally,
the PSB knows us by number, right?
I'm 2291, aren't I?!
So, what is his number?!
Tachibana Kyoko.
You are released from your position
as the PSB's cooperator.
Is it alright? Kazami.
We have to settle any illegal activities
on our parts.
That's Public Security, isn't it?
This is Haba's location.
You are free now.
If you want to meet him, we won't stop you.
Don't be so presumptuous!
To be your cooperator was my decision!
To betray you was also my decision!
And to love him, was my own decision too!
Do not for one moment,
think that you can control my entire life!
Goodbye.
Kyoko...
No matter how much we are hated,
we have to protect her, and that's...
- What's that?
- Public security.
Thanks to you,
we were able to arrest the terrorist...
...who underestimated Japan.
At which point did you know
it was a terrorist attack?
It's as you inferred.
That day,
while inspecting the conference hall,
I realised that the gas line could be
controlled remotely via the internet.
I figured it could be used
for a terrorist attack,
and ordered a security inspection.
But based on the situation at the scene,
it could be ruled as an accident.
So you had to create a suspect.
And we had to have that suspect...
...handed over to us as soon as possible.
That's why you arranged for Kyoko...
...to defend Uncle Kogoro,
and to have him released
while preventing the ruling of an accident.
You're amazing,
you solved the entire mystery.
No, I have one mystery unsolved.
And that's...
Phone.
Your phone has been glowing since just now.
(Mouri Ran)
Shinichi?
I have been evacuated to the Casino Tower
in Edge of Ocean.
Call me when you get this message.
What?
The capsule?!
An unknown explosion...
...has caused the capsule to crash enroute
to Tokyo Bay's reclaimed land area!
One of the reclaimed land areas,
is the Edge of Ocean
with 30,000 people in it!
There's nothing we can do!
- Take it slowly.
- We still have time.
Everyone, please calm down!
Just like how we came here,
everyone can get onboard!
Inspector...
There's been an error in the report,
and civilian vehicles are evacuating here!
What?!
There's a huge traffic jam
on the two bridges here!
This is a problem.
Everyone is panicking.
Shinichi...
Darn it, I can't reach Ran!
What should we do? There's no time!
Amuro, this time,
I'll need you as my cooperator.
There's a traffic jam ahead!
The evacuation instruction
wasn't carried out properly?!
Is that the Casino Tower?
Furuya!
The capsule's parachute has fallen off
and it's now accelerating!
What?!
The estimated point of crash
from NAZU is out!
In five minutes,
it will crash into Casino Tower!
- I'll send over the data!
- Ran...
Darn it, what should I do?!
What should we do?!
Amuro!
Hold on tight!
What do you have in mind?!
Here!
I thought I was going to die...
That was amazing though.
So, what should I do?
Hold on!
Head for that building under construction!
Alright!
Don't leave my side.
Okay.
It looks like the situation got worse.
Can we make it?
Considering the height of this building,
and the distance to Casino Tower...
If you accelerate from here after 1 minute...
It's do-or-die.
Please make it in time!
Ran!
What?
The power of love is great.
I've been wanting to ask you this.
Do you have a girlfriend, Amuro?
My...
lover, is...
...this country.
Let's go!
Can I miss by a millimetre?
That's part of the plan.
It's no use, it's not high enough!
Bring it on!
Go!
Dad!
Ran!
We'll take care of the rest from here.
You should get going.
There's still a mystery unsolved.
Why did you choose to involve Uncle Kogoro?
Because of my position,
I can't openly participate in investigations.
So if I involved him in the case,
you'd definitely become my cooperator.
Wasn't that the only way
I could make use of your true ability?
You give me too much credit.
(Agasa)
Inspired by investigation reports...
...that are akin to a "manual for crime",
the former prosecutor began a chain of
terrorist attacks...
...based on this strange motive.
It looks like the PSB was changed.
That must have been the PSB's doing as well.
It has been safely retrieved
from its landing spot in Tokyo Bay.
The capsule of the unmanned probe, Swan,
contains material from Mars.
We can look forward to solving...
...more mysteries of the universe.
- The unmanned probe, Swan,
- Amazing!
But I wanted to see it from the drone...
We should have thrown out Professor's stuff.
These children have no idea
how much they contributed to the retrieval.
Yes, but we saved Japan from a huge crisis.
They really are an amazing bunch of people.
Alright!
Let's explore Mars with Professor's drone!
That's a good idea!
Let's do it!
Professor! Please make a new drone!
Make a bigger one!
Maybe I can try...
Hurray!
I'm excited for Mars!
No, that's not possible.