(Yasuko Kawabe)
Yasuko Kawabe...
if you're going to hate anybody
hate that talent of yours...
All is for the sake of a quiet night...
(Full Score of Fear)
I'm Shinichi Kudos a high school detective.
I went to have fun
at an amusement park with Ran,
who is a childhood friend
as well as my classmate.
I happened to witness
the suspicious transaction site
of men in black.
Since I was absorbed
in watching the transaction
I didn't notice the other guy,
one of the members coming at me from behind.
I was forced to drink a drug by that man
and when I woke up...
I found that my body had shrunk!
If they find out that Shinichi Kudos is alive
they'll come after me again
and I would be endangering
the lives of those around me.
Therefore, taking Dr. Agasa's advice,
I decided to hide my true identity.
When Ran asked me for my name,
I told her that it was Conan Edogawa
on the spur of the moment.
In order to get information on those guys
I decided to free-load at Ran's house
being that her father is a detective...
Here goes Mitsuhiko!
Leave it to me!
Okay... There!
Mitsuhiko!
Conan!
There it goes, Ayumi!
M,me?!
Leave it to me, Ayumi!
All right!
They're my present classmates Genta,
Ayumi and Mitsuhiko...
They organize a thing
called the Youth Detective Squad
and make me a member without
even asking me if I want to join them...
There's another member with us...
Her name is Ai Haibara...
Her real name is Shiho Miyano...
Since her parents were scientists working
for the Black Organization she was young,
she used to work for them
under the code name Sherry
and discovered the drug Apotoxin 4869...
But, her one and only older sister
was killed by those guys
and so she resisted them.
She decides to take her own life
and drinks the drug.
But only her body shrinks...
This is how we met each other
and end up living our lives as 1st graders
at an elementary school,
while pursuing the identity
of the men in black...
But, this little detective here
just can't help forgetting
his present situation
and makes brilliant deductions
using Dr. Agasa's inventions
To solve one difficult case
after the other...
Thanks to him, I'm always cold sweating...
Well, in music class
I'm cold sweating for different reasons
when it comes to him though...
You know, the usual...
A child with the I.Q. of an adult,
no case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan!
He sees through the one and only truth!
Kazuki Domoto?
You know him, don't you, Shinichi?
Yeah. He's the founder of the Music Academy
that was bombed last week, right?
I mean... I'm here at right now...
Although Mr. Domoto was a famous pianist,
he suddenly switched to playing the organ.
You see... And in order to make his new hall
he brought a pipe organ that he found
at an old church in Germany over here...
Yeah, one that Bach was said
to have actually played.
That's the one, isn't it...
We get to go to
the opening of the new Domoto Hall, you see!
On top of that, thanks to Sonoko
we get to go see the rehearsal too.
Come to think of it,
Suzuki Construction Company built that hall,
didn't they?
They key of the piano...
It flew all the way here...
Let's go, Shinichi!
You get to hear that
Stradivarius live you know!
You were saying that
since you play the violin too,
you wanted to hear the real thing once,
didn't you?
What's he doing...
Hey! Are you listening or what?!
Sorry, sorry,
I happen to be busy investigating a case
right now you see...
Can't you even take a little time off?
The rehearsal's the day after tomorrow...
Too bad,
I guess I'll have to pass it up this time...
The concert's next week Tuesday...
Can't do...
I'm in the middle of an investigation...
But, maybe you'll finished by then.
I'll have Sonoko hold a seat for you too,
just in case...
I'm telling you that there's no need to...
Keep out of my business...
Keep out of your business?
Oh, well...
Oh yes! I guess so!
I'm just a busy body whose
only talent is doing Karate!
I didn't say that...
All's well. You could never be Holmes,
Shinichi,
not even if you listened to Stardivari.
What?!
I mean... you're tone deaf too.
Ran, how dare you...
Well, keep up your good work, then!
Mr. tone-deaf detective!
Heck! I'm never going to invite
that deduction freak ever again!
Shoots...
Hello...
Oh, Conan?
What would you like for dinner tonight?
Oh, uh...
Would curry be all right?
Or would you rather have...
Oh, yep, curry's fine...
Great... You're really so easy
to get along with, Conan.
Okay, then be careful and come home
before it gets dark.
Okay.
Bye Bye.
I can be pretty easy
to get along as Conan and yet...
(Kazuki Domoto, Pipe Organist and Composer)
Splendid! Excellent, Mr. Domoto?!
Mr. Domoto, you were really fantastic.
It's got an attractive touch
that's different from that of the piano...
Just as would be expected of Kazuki Domoto.
It sure was a fantastic performance...
I've seen him on TV...
See, that person with the glasses...
Oh, Mr. Takumi Fuwa...
He's been Mr. Domoto's exclusive piano tuner
for 35 years and...
has become the building head
of the Domoto Hall this time.
He...
The German man who
just turned to look is Mr. Hans Muller...
A pipe organ tuner...
Although he looks cheerful. like that now,
it seems that he really had it out
with Mr. Domoto before...
The one who's interpreting on the side,
is Mr. Domoto's son Genya a pianist.
He's the one in charge of this performance...
And see, those two women over there...
They're Mr. Domoto's disciples...
The one on the right is,
soprano singer Ms. Lala Chigusa
of Mr. Domoto's Academy's 9th class...
The nervous looking one beside her
is a student of the 8th class
of the same academy,
violinist Ms. Shion Yamane...
Oh, the substitute for Ms. Yasuko Kawabe
who got hurt in that explosion accident...
Yes, right.
It just so happened that during the accident,
Ms. Kawabe's Stradivarius was out for tuning
and safe,
so it turned out that Shion would borrow it
and do the performance...
And, the one sitting in the front most row
of the audience is...
Ms. Reiko Akiba, right? A soprano singer...
So you know her after all...
After all, she's famous...
(Reiko Akiba, soprano singer)
Shion, get ready!
Oh, yes sir?!
From the first piece, Ave Maria.
Yes sir...
I see she's still not ready
to practice with me yet...
Yeah, I'm sorry, but will you wait a while.
I, I'm sorry...
We finally get to listen to
Stradivarius live, don't we?
Ms. Sato!
As for me, I prefer Amati...
Please be quiet!
No, no, no!
Not good at all!
What have you been doing this past week!
I'm sorry...
Huh? Was anything wrong?
No... it sounded perfect...
No...
A Stradivarius sounds louder...
Once more, from the top!
Yes, sir!
What is it? What's up?!
It looks like the string
of the violin snapped...
I'm sorry, I'll change the string right away!
How's the balance of the sound?
Hmm, no problem I guess...
Oh boy...
I wonder if I'll even get to sing today...
Ms. Soma, may I have a moment with you...
Would you at least let me go to the restroom?
Mr. Mouri...
Do you have any clue as to who the bomber is?
No, not yet.
Was a plastic bomb used after all...?
Yeah... The timer was found too.
It seems to have been set to go off
at the time the two were going to perform...
Which means that this is...
I'm sorry, Mr. Mouri,
I can't tell you the details
of the incident just yet...
Especially not in front of a child...
A child...?
You go play over
where the other children are!
Alright.
Wow! It's huge!
It's not only big, it's beautiful!
Fantastic, isn't it?
Um, how does sound come out of a pipe organ?
In principle,
it works in the same way as
when you play the recorder in school.
See all the pipes that are line in rows?
Air is blown in to each of the pipes
like you would when playing the recorder
and sound is produced.
Air?
But the pipes don't have holes
like those on a recorder...
Right, on a recorder you press on the hole
to produce different sounds,
but in a pipe organ...
when you push the key,
the pipe that corresponds with
that key produces sound...
Each pipe can only produce one sound.
What's that thing that looks like a switch?
This? This is called a stop knob,
and when you pull this out,
they each produce a different tone...
For example... if you pull this...
It's a trumpet!
It's a flute!
... Organ performers combine these sounds
and produce sound variations
in their performance.
I see, I really learned a lot!
And, now, for the quiz that
you've all been waiting for.
We haven't been waiting for it...
A certain opera singer hurt his throat
and was waiting to get operated on,
he decided not to have surgery
and recovered with the pill
that his grandfather had...
Now, who was this opera singer?
1. Soprano...
2. Alto...
3. Tenor...
4. Bass...
This is a tough one...
A hint, Doc?
What's another way of saying surgery?
Operation...
or "Ope" in short...
And... It was his grandfather's pill, right?
Conan, do you know the answer?
Yeah... easy...
-First...
-Number 1...
The answer is soprano singer number 1...
Since the opera singer
didn't have the operation,
you subtract "op" from "opera".
A pill is a little round pellet...
A pill from grandfather means you add a
circle to the word "grandfather"
Combine everything...
Ra...
Sopra...
no...
Soprano!
Silly...
Correct...
But, how rude to call it silly...
Excuse me, Ms. Akiba...
Will you spare me some time...
Really...
I hope it's not going to take long...
I would like you to tell me once more
about the e-mail
that Ms. Yasuko Kawabe sent you
just before the bombing...
I can't perform with amateurs
that can't tell the difference in sound.
Please explain what this e-mail means...
What meaning?
It's just what it says, isn't it?
Like I told you before, Ms. Kawabe and I...
Met for the first time
at the press conference
of this performance, was it?
Yes, and at that time
she said that she was going to listen to
the performance of
the two people that passed away,
so that she would mail me
what she thought of them later...
In other words, the sound of the two
and the sound that Ms. Kawabe creates is...
Did she mean that
she didn't want to perform with them,
because they couldn't tell what kind of sound
she wanted to express as a musician?
I guess so...
Why don't you go ask her in person?
I heard she already regained consciousness...
She did regain consciousness,
but maybe because of shock
from the explosion,
she seems to have amnesia of
before and after the incident.
Oh?
Another thing...
This was found at the scene of the crime...
The body of a flute...
Yes,
the flute can be divided into the head,
body and leg part.
And, the body part was found.
It could be that a student forgot it
or something but...
Only the body part being found bothers me...
Is there anything you can remember about it?
Ms. Akiba?
No, I don't!
Okay, I guess that's all!
Hey, Ms. Akiba?!
What's that?
What're you drinking?
Tea...
Will you give me some too?
No!
Stingy!
Is there something good in it
for your throat or something_
It's none of your business, is it?
If it's really so,
maybe we'll get first place
at the singing contest!
Singing contest?
Yes... We're going to have
a singing contest against other classes...
That's right!
Will you please be our singing instructor?
We're scheduled to start singing practice
from 2:00 tomorrow!
Ran's going to play the piano for us.
But, the problem is the one who's
going to be teaching us how to sing...
Hey, brats!
Just who are you referring to as a problem?
-Just what problem do you think I have?
-I'm sorry, please don't let them bother you.
Don't tell me that you're referring
to the 9th Symphony.
I hate it...
I don't know about the symphony part,
but it's Teitan Elementary's school song!
Huh? She's talking about
Beethoven's 9th Symphony.
Oh? Is that right...
Okay. I'll be your singing instructor.
After all I used to go
to Teitan Elementary myself too...
Oh, is that right?
So, just go on home for now, will you.
You're interrupting me!
Yes, ma'am...
I'm happy that she agreed
to be our singing instructor, but...
She sure is a snob, that lady...
Yes, a little, I guess...
A typical "Queen" type person, I guess...
Yeah, she kind of resembles you...
Oh, no, well, she's beautiful, you see...
It's hard to tell
whether Ms. Soma's nice or mean...
Yeah, but maybe she...
was only asking us to leave
because she was concerned
about Shion who was nervous.
Huh? I think you're thinking too hard.
I wonder...
Love13
Oh come on! Don't get all that serious.
I'm just an amateur, you know...
Lions run at top speed
even when going after rabbits, you know...
Yes, yes,
I'm no more than a rabbit to you after all...
That's right!
Let's play mixed doubles next time.
And, invite Makoto and Shinichi
to play with us.
Shinichi?...
That deduction freak...
No...
Oh, so you had it out with Shinichi...
I guess it's best not to get involved
in a married couple's quarrel...
It's nothing like that!
I mean, you guys are amazing...
You're always fighting and making up...
Oh... but, it sure was long back then
I think you didn't talk to him
for a week or so?
When was that?
Remember? When we just became 8th grade...
Oh, I remember!
Back then...
Huh? I wonder
what we were fighting over then...
Then, how'd you make up?
You don't remember
why you fought or how you made up?!
But, let's see...
Stop! Stop! Hold it!
I mean, you're fighting and
you're going home together side by side?
But we live in the same direction.
Never mind... Go on...
Then... I heard a song...
Back then, I heard a song
from the direction of the river.
And while listening to the song
I just sort of mellowed out...
You made up...
And, what was the song?
I wonder what it was... that song?
I think it was a famous song though...
But...
It sure was a song that came sinking
deep into my heart.
"From green and prosperous hills"
"A distant echo sounded"
"Singing with a smile"
"Engrave the scorching sunshine"
"in our hearts"
"Tightly grasp the future"
"Teitan, Teitan, Teitan elementary"
How did the children do?
Well...
First of all, You!
Your voice is too loud.
Match your volume to everyone else!
And, Mr. Freckles that's next to him!
You're right on key
but your heart drifts away at times.
Are you dazzled by the profile of the girl
that's standing diagonally in front of you?
Diagonally in front...
It's Ai.
And, you, young lady
Is good at singing but...
sing more like a child, will you.
I'm not a child.
Hey, hey.
You're right on key and energetic too.
Very good
Don't be distracted by the voices
around you.
-You should be more confident.
-She really is something though.
Although she doesn't look like
she's listening at all,
she's listening to each and everyone's voice.
Yeah, she's got the ear of a musician.
The problem is...
You!
Huh? Oh... yes!
You're off key from beginning to end!
I hope you're not doing it on purpose?
Oh... N... no...
He's not doing it on purpose!
Conan is just tone-deaf!
I thought you were standing up for me
What a bummer. The piano's not right either.
The sound is all low in general...
I don't think the piano's been
tuned as it should be.
Really?
I didn't notice.
I thought so too...
She's...
Ms. Akiba, do you have perfect pitch?
Yes, I do.
What... does perfect pitch mean?
It's an ability in which,
the instant you hear a sound,
you know what note it is and
how it sounds
For example...
E5. Mi.
B3 and F5. Ti and Fa!
She's right.
Wow.
That's why she's such a good singer.
I wonder about that.
I can't really say that
perfect pitch is something
that is absolutely necessary for a musician.
I was this way to begin with,
but I've heard that
you can do the same with practice.
If I remember correctly,
I think that piano tuner Mr. Fuwa
practiced his way to where he is now?
Well, this is as far as I can teach you.
It's up to you to practice and complete
what you have to do from here.
I'll come listen to you again
when you get to be much better than now.
What?!
Are you leaving?
I wish you'd show us an example of
how to sing before you go
I agree!
How much will you pay me?
Professionals don't sing unless you pay them.
Bye.
This is the one.
Hey, that's my tea!
Thank you!
What's the matter, Genta!
My throat... My throat
Genta! Genta!
Are you all right, Genta
Somebody... put
something in there,
isn't that right...?
R... Ridiculous,
it couldn't be...
Let's take him to the
hospital right away!
I wonder if Genta's
going to be okay...
He did look like he
was really suffering.
His eyes were all red.
When did you
last drink that tea?
Huh... I think it was before noon.
Where?
At the Domoto Academy...
I rented a lesson room and
... practiced singing...
I went to the restroom before leaving...
During that time,
I left this bottle in the lesson room
with all my other things...
If someone put something inside,
it had to be at that time, then.
But, who?
Thank you very much.
Genta!
Are you all right?
I... I'm not okay...
What did the doctor say?
Yeah, he said that although Genta's throat
is pretty swollen,
he thinks that he'll recover in 4 to 5 days.
So , he's going to get better.
I'm glad
But,
it means that he won't be able to
use his voice for 4 days.
Yeah... It's only 3 days more
to the performance at Domoto Hall.
If Reiko had drunk it,
she may have not been able to perform.
Let's tell Inspector Megure about it,
and have him check
the contents of the bottle.
Okay, I'll take it to him.
Oh, but before that.
We'll take Genta home!
Me too.
I'll go too!
I've got to go see his parents
and tell them that he drank
somebody else's thing without permission
and would like to give them
a piece of my mind
as to the way they brought him up!
Sorry.
Genta...
Cheer up, Genta.
Four days will go by in a jiffy.
I want grandpa's pill... too...?
Really...
it's turning out to be like Doc's quiz.
Everybody, move to the side!
No!
Run for it!
Hurry!
Darn... I can't see the driver's face!
Right! Turn right!
What the...!
Are you all right!
Darn...
-Are you all right?
-Yes.
What's with that truck,
going the wrong way on a one-way street.
Reiko...
Oh, your leg is bleeding.
Phooey, this is nothing.
Did it decide not to attack
because the cab came along?
Or.
Okay, then sorry,
but I'll leave the children to you.
I'm going home with this cab,
so will you please
tell the police what happened?
I mean... are you leaving?
Nothing good has happened so far staying
with you people.
Is that so...
That's not nice...
Inspector!
What was the cause of the explosion?
Yes.
It seems that the propane gas
inside the room was leaking
and a lighted match ignited it.
Only there are traces of the gas detector
having been destroyed beforehand.
Then, it wasn't an accident,
but rather, homicide...
The victim was the owner of this shop,
Mr. Osamu Shida, age 36.
Mr. Shida is a violinist
and belonged to the first class
at the Domoto Academy.
He was a student of the first class?
The same as
the two previous explosion victims.
It sure doesn't seem to be a coincidence...
No, it's no coincidence!
Officer Sato...
I found this in the store...
What's this?
The leg part of a flute...
No doubt about it,
it's a serial killing committed
by the same person.
Moreover, the killer left a message behind...
The body part and the leg part...
The head part is still not found.
The culprit is going to commit
another murder...
About Mr. Hisao Sone who drowned to death ...
after crashing while he was flying
the para-glider yesterday...
Oh... I heard that he was a viola player...
The fact was, it turned out
he was a student
in the first class at Domoto Academy...
Then, don't tell me that.
Yes...
Mr. Mizuguchi and Mr. Renjo
who died the day before yesterday,
as well as Mr. Shida and his classmate who
died of the explosion...
They were all members of
a piano quartet until 2 years ago.
So. it's a serial murder case committed
by the same person after all...
Most probably...
According to the prefectural police,
traces tiny slashes made with a knife
were found on the cloth wings... and canopy.
And above all,
from under the seat of Mr. Sone's car...
The remaining part of the flute...
the head part was found, right?
But, now that the parts
of the flutes were all found,
I reckon it means that
the serial killings have ended.
I sure hope so...
And. Ran...
Yes, sir...
About the contents of the thermos
that you wanted me to check on...
The result of forensic investigation,
a very strong drug was found mixed
into the drink...
It's obviously too serious a crime
to be taken as just a prank...
What about the truck that attacked us?
It was a truck that
was stolen near the scene of the crime...
In other words,
the culprit tried to hurt Ms. Akiba
and drugged her drink, but failed,
So next,
tried attacking her with a stolen truck,
to carry out the original purpose.
The purpose of
keeping Mr. Aikba from performing
at the opening of the Domoto Hall...
Uh, if Reiko can't perform,
who's going to be her substitute?
Most probably Lala Chigusa...
The number one candidate to sing
the soprano part for the event was she,
who belonged to
the 9th class of the Domoto Academy,
as well as being his student.
But Ms. Yasuko Kawabe,
who was already chosen to perform,
recommended Ms. Akiba that
she had always wanted to sing with,
despite never having seen her
in person before.
That's seems to be
how Ms. Akiba ended up being here...
The next problem is the connection
of the foursome with the case.
For now, no connection between Ms. Akiba
and the foursome has been found...
The only thing we've found so far is
the connection between the first two people
who died of the explosion and Ms. Kawabe.
I guess it's about them being scheduled
to perform together, eh...
The bomb was set under the floor
where the two that
died of the explosion were.
Which means
that Ms. Kawabe unfortunately got involved...
We can't be all too sure.
So long as there is someone whose motive
is to hurt Ms. Kawabe is around...
Are you referring to the candidate,
Ms. Lala Chigusa who was chosen
before Ms. Akiba?
And one more person,
Ms. Shion Yamane who
is going to substitute for Ms. Kawabe too...
Huh? Her too...
Yes... If after borrowing the Stradivarius
from Ms. Kawabe,
Ms. Yamane gives a great performance
at the concert
where a lot of internationally
famous musicians are present...
her name will instantly
become well-known worldwide.
By the way,
there's still one more thing though.
She is Mr.Domoto's favorite...
And he chose Ms. Kawabe to perform with him
Because he had his eyes not on her,
but on the Stradivarius that she owned...
He actually wanted to choose Shion...
So in order to choose Shion
and to make her play the Stradivarius,
he rigged it so that Ms. Kawabe
would be seriously injured.
This is also a possibility.
The relationship
between people is so complicated
that it's sort of difficult to understand...
In other words,
the one who has a motive against Ms. Kawabe
and Reiko is Ms. Lala Chgusa.
The one with a motive
only against Ms. Kawabe
is Mr. Domoto and Shion.
The only thing is,
all three of them seem to have no motive
against the foursome that have been killed...
Right.
Yeah, that's right...
Oh, was the piano in the practice room
that blew up a special kind of piano?
No, not that I know of...
Why do you think so?
When I went there some time ago,
I saw the man called Mr. Fuwa
carry a piece of debris of the piano
with great care and take it home...
So, I thought that
maybe it was something special...
Hey, don't go skittering here
and there on your own!
I'm sorry...
The piano was one that
Mr. Domoto continued to play
at his residence for more than 30 years.
When Mr. Domoto, retired as a pianist,
is seems to have been moved to the academy
to be used by the young students
for practice.
Of course when it was
at Mr. Domoto's residence,
and even after it was moved to the academy,
the piano seemed to be tuned by Mr. Fuwa...
Well,
I guess the piano was like a son to him.
Now do you get it, brat!
Come to think of it,
it seems that Mr. Fuwa
was didn't care much for them...
He seems to have thought that
they were not living their lives decently...
But, it's hard to think that
he would kill the foursome
just because of something like that,
isn't it?
Right...
Even if we were to assume
that he didn't like
how they lived their lives,
It would then leave Ms. Akiba
out of the picture...
Inspector, maybe Ms. Akiba's case
and the foursome should be
thought of separately...?
But, with all this happening
around Mr. Domoto,
don't you think that too many things
are coincidentally falling into place?
I guess so...
Well, at any rate,
I asked Takagi to keep guard over Ms. Akiba
at least until the concert
the day after tomorrow is finished,
because I felt there was a need to.
Uh,
but... she told me to stay away from her
because my being there was bugging her...
Darn...
Just what do you think you're doing,
Takagi...
If Reiko is attacked again,
a letter of apology
is not going to settle things, you know
But, she did say that she would stay
at home today and tomorrow.
You idiot!
How can you come back here just like that!
I ,I'm sorry...
(Mouri detective agency)
Bye!
Conan!
Good morning, Conan!
Good morning!
What's up, you guys,
from so early in the morning.
We're going to see Kamen Yaiba.
Kamen Yaiba?
We got a hold of
highly confidential information
that they would be shooting
an early morning location today
at Ryokuchi Park by Teimusu River.
We thought that seeing it,
would cheer Genta up a bit...
He doesn't look to be
in bad shape either way, though...
That's why we came to get you too, Conan...
Were you on your way somewhere?
Yeah... I was...
Where to...?
Does it matter where...?
Is it more important than your bond
of friendship with Genta!
... Oh boy
I'm going over to Reiko's place.
Reiko?
I don't think you should.
I think you'll be scolded again...
Yeah... maybe,
but I've got to protect her from the bad guy.
Bad guy... You mean,
the one who attacked the other day...
You're going to protect her, Conan?
Oh, yeah, I wonder why...?
I don't really know why myself either...
But, I can't help myself
from wanting to do so.
It's just this feeling I have.
You're probably in love.
You do like older people, so...
Oh come on, no way...
At any rate, take care of Genta, okay.
I'm counting on both of you.
I'll leave it to you!
Conan...
Does this mean that
he has a lot of trust in us...
I guess so...
Yes.
Good morning, Reiko.
I'm sorry to be intruding on you.
Oh, hey, you?!
It's a nice condo...
It seems to be very quiet around here too...
Hey, you!
What's with you,
stomping into somebody's room like that?!
Just what do you want?
Singing lessons...
I want you to give me special training.
Oh, come to think of it,
you're that tone-deaf boy...
But, not today, no.
You're going out, right?
I heard that you always go forest bathing
before an important concert or recording
to refresh yourself.
Why'd you come if you knew about it?
So that I could keep you company.
Goodness... didn't I tell you last time?
That I don't want to stay around you people
because nothing good
seems to happen when I do...
You try to stay away from us by saying so
to keep us out of danger...
Because you're sure
that the culprit is after you...
You went to Genta's house with him,
not to complain to his parents,
but to see with your own eyes
that he got home safely, right?
Just what are you talking about.
Oh, before leaving, could I have some juice?
I'm thirsty .
Oh, boy...
All I've got is pure 100% orange juice,
but don't be spoiled, okay.
Okay, that's fine...
The flute...
Besides, that man...
Hey!
You're 10 years too young to be interested
in the bedroom of women!
Uh, do you also play the flute, Reiko?
It's none of your business!
After you drink it, hurry on home!
I'm not giving you singing lesson,
nor are you coming with me to the forest.
Okay...
I'll follow you on my own, so don't mind me.
Oh, boy... Don't blame me if you get lost.
I'll be fine, just fine.
Inspector Megure!
A connection's been found
between the foursome and Ms. Akiba!
What?!
In January 3 years ago,
at the lodging of Domoto Academy in Izu,
a flute player who was staying
with them at the lodge
got drunk and fell to his death from a cliff.
He was Mr. Hikaru Soma age 28.
He was in the 6th class of Domoto Academy.
Don't tell me that they?
No, although they were the ones that
forced Mr. Soma
who couldn't drink to drink...
it was concluded that they had nothing to do
with the victim falling off the cliff,
and the case was closed
as an unfortunate accident.
I see...
And, what's the connection with Ms. Akiba?
The thing is, this Mr. Soma happened
to be Ms. Akiba's fianc.
What?!
Inspector...
It is very likely that she still
harbors hate towards the foursome...
But if so, why was she attacked...
Kamen Yaiba, Yaiba... Let's all call him...
Kamen Yaiba,
Yaiba... He'll come running anytime...
Hello!
Hello...
I wonder if those two are mother and child...
They don't look alike at all.
I wonder why they're walking so much
apart from each other?
Maybe his mother scolded him.
Oh boy...
Hey... Do you know why
I take a walk through the forest
the day before my concert?
I want to bring nature into my body...
Because the music of Europe
was born surrounded by great nature...
Do you understand?
I think I do...
Are you all right, Reiko?!
Yes...
Run!
Go ahead!
So, the culprit's struck again, after all.
This is bad!
She's going to be shot.
Reiko! This way!
Why... Why didn't the culprit shoot...
What the hell is the culprit after...?
Uh, shouldn't report this
to the police after all?
No, because like a just told you
a while ago,
f I report this to the police...
It's going to take up your time
and may get in the way of
your concert tomorrow, right?
I understand that too, but...
If you understand,
don't say a thing about it.
I'll go tell them about it,
once the concert is over.
Understand!
Okay...
Oh, Officer Takagi...
Oh, Ms. Akiba! Conan, you too...
Ms. Akiba, I've been looking for you.
You told me that
you weren't going anywhere today...
I was on a date with him.
A, A date...
Ms. Akiba, there's something
I'd like to speak to you about.
Later, okay...
It's about Mr. Hikaru Soma...
Mr. Hikaru Soma was your fianc, wasn't he?
Inspector.
I will tell you everything I know.
But, please let me do
so after the concert tomorrow.
Uh, Inspector...
Does Mr. Soma have a mole over here?
Yeah, he does. But, why do you know...
Because I saw a picture of him
in Reiko's room...
Huh? Did you go inside Ms. Akiba's room?
Yep...
Right, will you please take me home!
I'll tell you everything I know.
So, we brought him here...
But, all he told us was
that he saw a picture of Mr. Soma
as well as a flute in her room.
My God...
But, Inspector.
Even if she did have a motive
to kill the foursome,
that doesn't conclude
that she's the culprit, does it?
She was in fact,
attacked by a truck after all...
Uh, didn't Mr. Soma have anyone else
in his family
that would've wanted to avenge his death?
No, not at all...
Uh, please have some tea.
Oh, thank you...
Thank you, Ran.
Here you go...
Uh, his mother was an unwedded mother,
and she passed away 5 years ago.
He has no brothers or sisters.
Father?
No, we don't have any information on him.
We don't even know if he's alive or not.
That's...
(Hikaru Soma, deceased at 28,
Mother, deceased, Father unknown)
The foursome who were killed
have also caused other problems...
At times,
they would perform drunk at concerts,
And get bawled out by Mr. Domoto later.
What? When did this happen?!
Oh, yes, sir...
Here it is...
It was when they were performing
Beethoven's piano quartet
at a concert a year ago.
I got it, Inspector...
I know who killed the foursome,
seriously hurt Ms. Kawabe,
and attacked Ms Akiba,
as well as the culprit's motive for doing so.
Really, Mr. Mouri?!
Yes! The culprit is...
You! Mr. Genya Domoto!
Why, because you're a fan of Beethoven...
To...
the point of being a freak, a maniac!
Hey, just what do you think
you're saying out of the blue?!
You killed the foursome
because they performed Beethoven's piece
drunk on stage!
There couldn't be nothing more desecrating
to a great composer than this.
You seriously hurt Ms. Kawabe
because when you performed with her
in the past,
you got into a heated argument with her
about the interpretation of the piece...
This was written in detail
in Ms. Kawabe's essay...
You attacked Ms. Akiba
because during rehearsal...
Phooey, I hope you're not talking about
the 9th Symphony of Beethoven.
I hate it!
She bad-mouthed
the 9th Symphony of Beethoven!
Wait a minute!
It's true that I like Beethoven,
and I also respect him.
But, I'm not all that maniac over him.
No, there's no doubt about it.
The proof is that your hairstyle
is just like that of Beethoven!
M, Mr. Mouri?
You've gotta be kidding!
I've had this hairstyle since birth!
I took after my late mother!
If you insist that I'm lying
take a look!
T, True...
They look exactly alike...
Well?! When it comes to the foursome
and Ms. Akiba,
the story doesn't stand
unless I'm a Beethoven freak,
and when it comes to Ms. Kawabe,
we're both musicians.
There are times when we get into
heated disagreement regarding
interpretation of a piece.
But, that has to do
with the music we're playing
and it's no reason for hating each other...
It's so ridiculous,
it's not worth talking about!
Oh, but, you see...
Inspector!
Did you all come here at this time of night
to tell us your silly deduction?!
Moreover, we've got an important concert
coming up tomorrow!
Yes, we are fully aware of that...
Will you all please leave for tonight?
You can interrogate us
or do whatever you need to
after the concert is over!
I was pretty sure but...
Where does he get his confidence from anyway?
Uh, Officer Takagi.
Hasn't Ms. Kawabe gotten her memory back yet?
No, although she's recovered to the point
where she can chit-chat for a while.
She says incomprehensible things like,
the air conditioner has a pitch,
so it bothers her and she can't sleep.
The air conditioner has a pitch? Maybe...
We don't have to take it out right
now , do we?
Sorry,
please use this.
Thank you.
The contents of the program is the same
as the real performance
and we get to sit wherever we want to
in the empty audience so "Generalprobe"
is really worth seeing.
During the actual performance
we'll be sitting above.
I begged daddy to get the seats for us.
Wow! they're balcony seats!
There are 10 seats,
so we get to take up the whole space.
10 people...?
I invited Doc and the children too.
And one seat for Shinichi too.
Tell him about it.
And, also that he can get his ticket
at the reception desk.
Never mind a guy like him...
Never mind, just hurry and tell him.
We don't want to waste a seat, do we?!
Oh, okay...
I don't think he'll come, though...
Sorry, Ran...
I guess you didn't tell the police
about yesterday.
Thank you for now.
No problem...
But, is your leg okay?
Yes.
It won't interfere with my singing at all.
Uh, Ms. Kawabe has perfect pitch too,
doesn't she?
Right.
I found out when I saw her during practice
and that's another reason we hit it off well.
What about it?
No, it's nothing.
Oh... I'll be going then.
Okay, give it your best shot.
Reiko and Ms. Kawabe
both have perfect pitch...
This means...
I didn't want to talk to him on the phone
so I send him mail.
Oh... I hope Shinichi can make it.
I couldn't care less either way...
But, I wouldn't want the seat to go to waste.
That's what I just said a while ago.
Huh? Oh, you did...?
We have no choice. Let's start without him.
Is anything the matter?
Oh, Mr. Mouri, Mr. Muller isn't here.
Huh? You mean the organ tuner?
He promised to tune the organ
during Generalprobe...
Oh my God.
He won't answer his cell phone
and the hotel tells me he hasn't been back
from last night...
From last night...
Well, all that's left
is the final touches in tuning,
so even if he doesn't show up,
it won't be all that much of a big deal...
But, doesn't that mean that
his whereabouts is unknown?
Did you notify the police?
No... because it would be
too time-consuming and troublesome
with all the questioning for now.
I want everyone to concentrate
on the concert just yet.
Shion looks like
a totally different person.
"Ave Maria"
"Full of grace"
- "God be with you"
- This voice...
""Praise be to You among women..."
Shion's violin was really fantastic,
wasn't it?!
Really! It was completely different
from the way she played during rehearsal.
It was as if the Stradivarius was her own.
What the...
And, Reiko's singing was superb too!
Conan!
You guys... are here so early.
We won't let you in even
if you're a minute late.
We asked Dr. Agasa to bring us here early.
What're you holding?
I think it's a recorder.
You idiot!
Why would you bring something
like that to a concert
that's going to be playing classical music!
Don't get angry at him.
Genta says that since he has no voice,
he wants to at least sound the recorder...
But a recorder...
Of course he won't sound it
during the performance,
right Genta?
He just answered yes.
Keep it hidden when in the hall.
No cell phones here either.
I know. I even made them leave
their detective badges behind.
Uh, I'm hungry.
Okay,
shall we have something light to eat then?
I guess so. The performance starts at 5:00,
and we don't want to get hungry
in the middle of the performance.
He's saying,
"eels over rice, eels over rice."
It'd be nice if he could have
conversation using the recorder.
Oh, there's no reason why you can't.
Just switch the notes for letters.
Notes...
To letters... did you say?
But, since they're alphabets,
I guess it's not possible
for Genta to handle.
That sound bothers me after all.
Ran,
I just remembered I have something to do.
I promise I'll be back in time
for the performance.
Hey, Conan!
I tell you, that selfish brat.
That sound!
Doesn't that note sound a little strange?
Yes, I agree.
I noticed while I was singing...
I've figured out which key it was,
but I can't tell
which stopper the tone belongs to,
Because so many were being sounded
at the same time.
It's slightly low after all,
no doubt about it.
It came from around there.
I think it's the short pipe way inside.
Just one of the keys are not tuned right.
I'll have to have it fixed
before the actual performance.
But, Mr. Muller's whereabouts is unknown,
right?
Right.
I'll go tell Mr. Domoto about this...
He doesn't seem to be here...
I guess not...
I wonder if he went on a tea break
or something...
Or, he may be over there...
It's amazing you noticed that sound.
I've got pretty good ears.
It's way more than good.
Maybe you've got perfect pitch too?
I sure wish I did...
Mr. Domoto's not around...
Do you know of any other place he may be?
Well...
Maybe just like you said,
he may be having tea or something?
Honoured guests,
smoking is prohibited in all areas
of the building
Ms. Akiba's still not here?!
No, she's not answering her
cell phone either.
I'm having the staff look for her too, but...
Don't tell me that her whereabouts
is unknown too?!
I don't know.
First, it's Mr. Muller, and now her...
What on earth is going on?!
We've only got 15 minutes to go
before start time.
If she doesn't come around till then...
Please let me do it!
After what happened to Ms. Kawabe,
I continued practicing up to now
just in case.
But...
Please!
I promise I'll sing better than Ms. Akiba...
No need to try singing better than her!
Music is humans seeking answers from God...
Sing as if praying...
Shinichi didn't come after all.
I wonder what's up with Conan,
when the performance
is almost ready to begin.
Really, I wonder where Conan went...
Yep... but I'm sure Conan's okay!
I believe him!
I guess so!
We should believe him
like he believed in us!
He'll be fine.
I just know Conan will be okay...
Ladies and Gentlemen,
we have an announcement to make.
Ms. Reiko Akiba who
was scheduled to sing today
is suddenly unable to make it
for the performance.
Singing in her place
is Ms. Lala Chigusa of
the 9th class of Domoto Academy.
We apologize for this sudden change
in performance
and your understanding
is greatly appreciated.
Why?!
She was singing so beautifully
during Generalprobe and yet...
I wonder if something happened to her
along with Shinichi.
A vinyl sheet?!
What is it?!
Reiko! Reiko!
What the?!
Where is this?
This is the downstream of
the canal.
It's most likely that
the culprit who attacked us
sailed us off into the canal
from the lake at Domoto Academy...
But, who on earth would...
I have no idea.
Besides,
why did the culprit knock us out first
and out us on the boat?...
I've got to get back quickly...
or the concert will start...
But... Even if we were to swim back,
that wall is too high to climb...
It seems like no one is here...
I guess not... But, look.
There's a telephone on that wall over there.
If only we could reach it,
we can call for help...
Wait here...
Even if we can't reach the phone,
maybe we can call for help
if we can unhook the receiver...
How do we do something like that...
When you make a call
with a push button phone,
the buttons make a sound don't they?
That's called a DTMF signal.
It sends a combination of
two signal tones of high and low
in order to dial the number
that needs to be reached.
So, if you can mimic the exact sound...
We can make the call...
I think it was, for the number
1 in 110 was 697 Hz and 1209 Hz.
The number 0 is a combination of
941 Hz. and 1336 Hz...
It's okay.
I remember the sound of the buttons
of the phone by ear...
But, first we have to unhook the receiver...
Leave that to me!
The problem is a few minutes
after the receiver his unhooked,
we won't be able to another phone call
at all...
In other words, we have only one chance...
If we fail, we've got no choice
but to wait for someone to find us...
We don't have time to wait...
We have no other choice
but to give it a try...
Okay, we've got to rehearse ASAP...
What was that sound just now?...
An explosion... Something exploded...
It's in the direction of Domoto Hall!
Don't tell me that...
This is the West Tama City Forest of Music!
A little while before,
there were two explosions at Domoto Hall.
The explosion seems to have occurred
on the innermost part
on the left hand side of the hall
and the doorway to backstage
in the center left!
The concert has begun 5 minutes ago!
We still have no information
on how things are inside!
Again...!
Quick! The next number zero!
I guess we'll make it.
Let's pull the boat closer.
Over here is fine! Stop the boat!
And,
how are you going to unhook the receiver?
Watch.
Wow!
Here goes!
Yes, this is
the police department communications room.
What?! Ms. Akiba and Conan?!
Yeah... They were hit by someone,
put on a boat and made to sail
to where the canal is.
The location
is West Tama City West Tama reservoir...
There they are!
There they are! Over there!
So, it's the Domoto Hall after all?
Yes, there have already been a total of
more than 10 explosions already.
All of them
were the pillars outside the building,
but we haven't found
what's causing the explosions yet...
Somebody set the bombs up.
I don't know if they're time bombs
or set off by remote control,
but it's most probably the being done
by the same person
who killed the foursome...
I guess so, because the first case
also involved an explosion...
I wonder why the culprit
didn't kill us but rather,
pulled us far away from Domoto Hall...?
Don't tell me that...
Not again...
Um! Can't you call inside?!
Ran and Pops are inside...
Well, we can't get through by phone.
Maybe the culprit cut the lines...
What about the cell phones...
No way.
It's manners to switch the phones off
during the performance
and except for a certain area,
the inside of the hall
is out of service range...
Besides, I think that all is fine inside...
The entire inside of the hall
is completely sound and water proof...
Maybe they haven't even noticed
that it's exploding outside...
Which means that
the concert is still proceeding?
Yes, I'm sure.
But, we can't be sure that the explosions
are going to be
limited to outside the hall...
I'm sure that the explosions
will start occurring inside eventually...
if not already...
Ran...
"And gave himself to me"
"Therefore I will not leave Jesus"
"Even if I feel my heart is hurting"
Good evening, Ladies and Gentlemen.
Thank you so very much for coming tonight,
I am Kazuki Domoto.
As you all already know,
tonight we finally get to present
to you this pipe organ performance.
Hurry, this way! Over this way, this way!
Just what's taking you so long!
Hurry up and bring the hose!
My God...
But the hall
in the middle hasn't been bombed...
I'm sure the people inside are safe!
Too soon to get optimistic!
All the places making entry
from outside possible are closed off...
It's impossible to rescue
those inside in this situation.
Oh no...
Besides, we don't know which pillar
is going to explode next either...
There is a total of 23 pillars
on the outside...
I wonder if the culprit is planning
to blow all of them up...
Darn... what can we do...?
We've got no choice but to go
in from the ceiling...
Do you think you can?
If we do it now, we may be able to
manage getting in that way...
However,
this is not a heliport to begins with so,
I'm not sure if the roof can endure
the weight of the chopper...
Okay.
Please fly as low as you possibly can.
We'll jump from there!
Let me show you the way!
The corridor going from the roof
to the 4th floor is complicated.
That's why...
No, but that would be too dangerous...
We don't have time to be arguing, do we?
Let's hurry
while the explosions are stopped!
Lower!
More!...
A little more!
A little bit more!...
I can't take it any lower!
The air current is worse than I thought,
so the chopper can't maintain stability...
Jump our while you can!
Let's go, Ms. Akiba...
Conan, you stay here in the chopper, okay...
What the... Conan?!
I'm going to stay back here too!
Until Ran and all the others are rescued!
Conan!
Besides, I've seen the culprit!
What?! I don't know if it's the same person
who's causing the explosions,
but I saw the face of the one who hit us!
The person may be inside this hall, right?
So...
Hey, hurry up!
I can't hold this thing any longer!
Okay, I guess I'll have to take you along...
Hurry, Takagi!
Okay!
This is the inner corridor of the 4th floor.
I mean, which just came straight down!
You wouldn't have let me down
if I didn't say what I did, right?
I just did what he did.
I wonder
if he really saw the face of the culprit?
What a surprise...
I didn't think it possible,
but they really don't seem to
have noticed the explosions...
Let's search for the bomb...
because it's impossible
to evacuate this many people at once...
If the purpose of the culprit is
to bomb this hall,
I'm sure that a bomb
is also set inside this hall too.
Okay!
Conan, you and Ms. Akiba stay right here,
okay?
Okay!
Let's go!
Ran...
Hold on...
Inside! How're things inside?!
"Come to Him all who are weary"
"Come to Him all who are burdened"
"And he will give you relief"
The culprit is someone who knows
this hall inside out,
as well as set a bomb up...
I'm sure the culprit
is among the members of the staff...
Something's wrong with this sound
after all...
If it were the piano,
I know Mr. Domoto
would be able to tell right away,
but since it's only been two years
since he started playing the pipe organ,
I guess it's tough to notice
the difference in sound...
Difference in sound?
Amateurs who cannot tell
the difference of sound apart...
So, that's the story...
Ms. Kawabe noticed the difference in sound...
because she has perfect pitch...
But wait a sec...
Then, why did that person...
Don't tell me that... that person...
If so, why her...
His mother was an unwedded mother...
I see... So, that's it...
But... what does the difference
in sound have to do with the explosions...
I just realized now but,
the time when the explosions stopped
for a while
coincides with the time that
Mr. Domoto was making his opening speech,
right?
Maybe the culprit
didn't want anyone to notice
the sound of the explosions after all...?
No, that's not it!
The explosions are set off only
when he plays the instrument!
I see. That's why the sound's not right...
It's that sound again...
Uh,
how many times was that sound heard?
Do you know how many times
that off tune sound was heard
since the concert started till now?
Uh... I'm sure it was...
Twice during the first Ave Maria...
10 times...
in Cantata that was played next...
And, the one being played now,
makes it 8 times...
So, it sounded a total of 20 times.
So, there'll most likely
be four more explosions!
That particular sound
and the explosions are working together!
That's why there was no explosion
while Mr. Domoto
was delivering his greetings.
There are 23 pillars outside the hall.
In other words,
to explode all the pillars
and inside the hall as well
24 explosions need to take place...
Which means...
Right...
He's got to stop playing before the sound
is heard 4 times from now,
or the bomb within this hall
will explode...
It's that sound again.
Darn, it's connected to that sound
after all... I'm pretty sure the culprit
is watching from somewhere...
Again!
I've found him!
It's him after all...
Okay!
I'll go up on stage
and stop the performance!
Wait!
If you stop the performance,
the culprit will use the remote controller!
I've found the culprit
holding the remote controller!
But...
Darn, what can we do...
Isn't there a way in which
we can stop the performance
without being noticed...
Isn't there a way to make the culprit
have second thoughts
about making the bomb go off...
3 minutes...
Is 3 minutes enough?
Yes... but...
I'm counting on you, Mr. Detective...
"As long as you're here"
"I believe in our love"
"How beautiful"
"How beautiful that voice"
"Who saved a wretch like me"
It's Reiko!
This song...!
It's Amazing Grace...
"...was lost, but now I'm found"
"was blind but now I see"
What's she going to do at this point...
"Was Grace..."
"Amazing Grace,
"how sweet the sound"
"That saved a wretch like me"
"I once was lost, but now am found"
"Was blind but now I see"
"Was Grace that taught..."
The person back then...
was Reiko after all...
"And Grace, my fears relieved"
It should've been erased after all...
You can't erase it...
You can't do anything about the voice
that touches the hearts of others...
That's why you were hesitant too, right?
Besides,
this song is your son,
Mr. Soma's... favorite song...
And, the one singing it,
is the woman your son loved...
The key to the deduction
was the difference in sound...
At first I thought
that the difference in sound
was because of the tuning...
But, no...
I found that a small sensor
that detects air flow
was set up inside
one of the pipes of the organ,
and only the sound
that came out from there was slightly off...
When the sensor inside the pipe detects
the flow of air
A signal is sent to the bombs
that are set up in order,
and they explode.
When the last bomb explodes,
this entire hall collapses...
There was no explosion during Generalprobe
because the blasting machine
was switched off,
isn't that right...?
Former building head of Domoto Hall
as well as piano tuner, Mr. Takumi Fuwa...
It's not here either...
Bad...
The bomb may go off before we find it...
Quiet!...
What is this sound?
Don't move!
Police!
Mr. Muller...?
"How sweet the sound"
How did you figure out it was me?...
Perfect pitch...
Mr. Fuwa, you have perfect pitch
and yet you didn't point
anything out regarding
the difference in sound
during Generalprobe, did you?... .
That's when I thought something was fishy...
I see...
and how did you figure out
I was Hikaru's father?...
Your car's license plate number,
52-83...
That's your son's birthday, isn't it?
You used it as a proof of bond
between you and your son
that you couldn't expose to the public...
And the picture of you in your younger days
that I saw at Mr. Domoto's house...
You looked so much like your son...
You killed the four musicians
as to avenge the death of your son
who died of an accident...
You left the parts of
the flute back at the scene
to deceive the police into thinking
that the three cases
completed the serial killings...
You hurt Ms. Yasuko Kawabe
and got her messed up in this case,
she has perfect pitch and would've noticed
the difference in sound...
People who are afraid of people
with perfect pitch
are only those who themselves,
have perfect pitch...
From this standpoint, you're the only one
who could've done all this...
And one other person...
Ms. Reiko Akiba also has perfect pitch.
But, being that
she was your late son's fianc,
you couldn't make yourself use a bomb
on her that may take her life,
as you did with Yasuko...
That's why you drugged her drink,
and attacked her using the dump truck
and the air rifle.
In order to make her stay off the stage,
all you had to do
was make her lose her voice
and break her leg...
"Was blind but now I see"
He played it!
Why... Why...
It won't explode...
We removed the sensor
that was set up inside the pipe
before coming here...
3 minutes...
No, 2 minutes was enough to do it...
You're really something, sonny...
What was your name again?
Conan Edogawa
A detective...
Bravo!
Bravo! Bravo!
There he is...
He's holding a remote controller...
Then, he's the one after all...
What shall we do?...
Shall we break in before it explodes...
No!
The minute we break in,
he'll blow the place up
with the remote controller!
Then, what on earth do we do...
That room...
If from that room,
I may be able to do something about it...
Do what...
I'm going to fire at him...
before he pushes the switch
of the remote controller...
Too bad Mr. Detective...
I can bomb this place
using this remote controller...
You lose.
I wonder about that...
You can't really tell yet...
What can't I tell...
I don't know how you guys made it
into this hall but,
the fact that they're not breaking in
must mean that just a planned,
the hall is enveloped in flames
and they can't come in.
I didn't count
on the sensor being removed but...
all is well...
because now I get to bomb
the place whenever I wish to...
I'll send everyone off to the world beyond
while the performance is still in session
as my farewell gift...
Darn! Back then...
I'll blow you up
while you're playing your favorite organ...
Kazuki Domoto...
Conan...
No good... I can't shoot...
All right. Hurry up and start playing again,
Domoto...
What shall I do...
I can't use the tranquilizer gun.
Which means...
What other way could there be...
Move out of the way, Conan...
Please!
Lend it to me!
M, My recorder...
I got my voice back!
Okay, go on...
Darn!
This is goodbye, Mr. Detective...
No way!
mi-la-la-la-fa
Shoot!
Shoot?
What was that sound, just now?
The whistle signaling the end of the game!
What?!
Police! Freeze!
I lose...
Mr. Fuwa,
where is the remaining bomb?
In the attic right above the stage...
Officer Takagi, contact the Inspector.
Yes, ma'am!
I know I have no right to but...
Would you let me listen to
the performance till the end?
I will tell you everything after that...
Okay.
The fire's almost extinguished here too,
-so we'll all be there on the double...
-Inspector!
There's an opening
in one part on the east side!
Okay, let's go!
I'll call you again!
Uh... why did you set bombs to this hall?
I've been serving as...
Kazuki Domoto's exclusive piano tuner
for the past 35 years.
We walked along life together...
However, two years ago,
he suddenly retired his position
as a pianist...
Then, he tells me
that he wants me to be head of the building
the will be completed in two years...
Of course, I couldn't refuse...
He said I'd be free
to continue tuning pianos...
But,
being that I was,
the internationally famous pianist,
Kazuki Domoto's exclusive piano tuner
for the past 35 years,
I just couldn't make myself
become a tuner for anybody else...
My pride wouldn't allow me to do so...
But then again, I'm just a mere craftsman...
I couldn't see myself being able to
handle the work of building head...
I was overwhelmed with grief...
Just two years ago,
I lost my wife, and a year after
that my son dies of an accident...
And, I end up losing the only thing left
for me to live for,
my job as a piano tuner.
I have nothing to live for anymore...
The music that I loved so much
has changed into discord unpleasant
to my ears...
Right... I hear sounds my dreams.
I jumped out of bed that night
after having a nightmare...
and decided... that I would erase everything,
in order to get back quiet nights...
I wanted to erase everything,
of course the foursome
who took my son's life,
selfish Domoto,
the pipe organ that took his interest
away from the piano,
and Domoto Hall...
I also want to get rid of the lives
of all the musicians the world over,
and audience who come to
listen to the organ performance!
I agreed to be appointed
the head of Domoto Hall...
I thought it was the best position to be in
if I wanted to rig the organ
and set up the bomb in the hall...
On the other hand,
I couldn't help feeling sorry
for the piano that was disposed
of by Domoto, just like me...
So...
You mean you bombed the practice room
along with the piano
out of love for the piano...?
This is my entire story...
Okay, then...
Will you please tell Domoto to come here.
Mr. Fuwa, please calm down!
Don't worry...
This is so I can commit suicide...
I have no intention of hurting any of you...
Conan, please leave the room.
No way! How dare you kill yourself
without first making amends.
I won't let you do something unfair
like that!
Conan!
Mr. Fuwa! Don't do anything stupid!
Shut up! Hurry up and call Domoto!
Mr. Fuwa!
I'm over here.
Mr. Domoto!
Mr. Fuwa, I'm sorry...
I had no idea that you were cornered
to such a point...
So, you finally understand
what I had to go through
thanks to your selfishness...
That's not it, Mr. Fuwa...
I retired from being a pianist
because I noticed that your tuning
was becoming slightly off tune...
I couldn't bring myself to tell you thinking
that I might hurt your pride...
Yet, I didn't feel like forming a team
with a new tuner either at this point...
that's why I retired
from playing the piano...
It can't be! I have perfect pitch...
It's true that you have perfect pitch...
But, I think that your auditory senses
have gone downhill because of age...
I experienced the same thing
of not being able
to tell whether the notes
were slightly off key...
That's a lie... a lie...
It's a lie... a lie...
If I knew
it was going to turn out like this,
I should've told you the truth
to begin with...
I'm really sorry...
Too late apologizing now!
It's all your fault!
Wrong!
If my best friend did the same thing to me,
I would think that she must've had some damn
good reason to have done so...
and that,
it could be something that she had done,
not for herself,
but rather, out of consideration for me...
I think that's
what would first come to mind...
Why,
because I believe my best friend...
... I would feel the same too!
Too think that there
was an explosion like this outside...
We didn't notice anything at all...
Conan seems to have helped out a lot too.
Just like I thought.
It was just as I said, wasn't it.
It's amazing that Shinichi understood
the message you sent on the recorder.
Changing the name of notes into alphabets
come out in detective novels too.
In German the B note is referred to as H.
But,
since he knows that my mother is English,
I think he deduced on the spot
that I was playing the B note.
This depended on his quick
deduction skills.
Then, I counted on his perfect pitch.
I see...
Besides, I believe him too...
As a partner...
I was pretty sure that
the Beethoven guy was the one, though...
Dad, are you still at it?
But, that deduction freak
didn't come after all,
did he.
Oh, Shinichi?
Never mind that guy already...
Come on, let's go, Conan...
He was here till just a while ago, but...
Uh... this sound...
Oh, the violin...
It's Amazing Grace.
I mean, the way the violin is being played...
The way the violin is played?
Shinichi.
Hey, Ran?!
Shinichi! Shinichi!
Shinichi, left!
Conan!
He says he has to work on a case...
So, it was Shinichi, after all!
He said that after hearing Reiko sing,
he recalled what happened 3 years ago,
so he took the violin that was backstage
and played the song you
just heard a while ago.
He said that he was playing
for you and himself!
Shinichi was saying he felt bad
for what he did to you...
Did you have a fight or something?
Oh, nope... It's nothing...
I wouldn't forgive you
if you came along now, anyway...
Idiot...
I... came here a lot with him...
It was our dating course...
Oh! is that so...
The spring that he passed away
because of the accident,
I sang the song that he liked here
where we used to date...
And that song was Amazing Grace.
Right!
I... used to hate those four
at the beginning...
To the point where I really wanted
to kill them myself...
But, I've decided to forgive them...
Because Amazing Grace
is a song of forgiveness...
I'll be on my way, then...
Conan,
let's harmonize together again someday.
See you...
Bye.
Bye-bye.
By the way, Ran,
how did you know
that Shinichi was playing back then?
Oh... because he
has a strange habit when playing,
that you can tell right away.
I see...
What did she mean
when she said strange habit when playing?
I won't just let him get away.
This is the best time
to send him out into the wild.