What have I done to deserve this?
Damn it!
WSG Boston is going to start soon,
but the stadium is yet to be completed.
Wonder if it is going to be
finished by the opening day?
If it remains unfinished,
the whole nation is gonna be furious.
You said it!
Get out of the way! Get out of the way!
This Hyper Linear Liner has
a maximum speed of an amazing
1,000 kilometers per hour!
HYPER LINEAR LINER
Amazing! Like a flash!
Amazing!
I can't wait to ride it!
Everyone, thank you
for your generous applause!
This newly created Hyper Linear Liner
can reach Shibahama Station in Tokyo
from Shin-Nagoya Station
in an astounding 25 minutes!
Amazing!
But where is this Shibahama Station?
What, you don't know, Genta-kun?
Nope.
The lady said she's going to
explain right now.
Oh, that's perfect.
Now, then, Shibahama Station lies between
Kawashina and Okamatsucho stations,
and was built to accommodate
the Hyper Linear Liner's arrivals and departures.
And an underground passageway
connects the station to this venue,
the Shibahama View Hotel.
Shibahama Stadium,
where the WSG Tokyo Opening Ceremonies
will be held next month,
will also have
a direct connection as well.
Even after WSG Tokyo opens,
the area around Shibahama Station,
as the Hyper Linear's terminal station,
is expected to be a place
where people come together.
What does "WSG" mean?
I don't know.
Um, I believe it's...
What's bugging you guys?
Oh, Conan-kun and Ai-chan.
That was a long trip to the bathroom.
It took a while to find it, that's all.
Sorry to make you all wait!
Hey, Conan.
Do you know what "WSG" is?
Yeah, of course.
"World Sports Games" or WSG for short.
It's a sporting event that's held
once every four years!
Athletes from all over the world will
compete for the honor of their country!
...the Hyper Linear train will finally
be unveiled to the public!
Among those who will be on board that day
are the WSG Tokyo sponsors here today,
and members of the WSG Association
from each nation.
And today, representing
all of those nations, we have a comment
from the International WSG Association,
president Alan MacKenzie-san.
The Director of the FBI?
Hello, everyone in Japan.
I look forward to attending
the opening ceremony
of WSG Tokyo with all of you,
and getting on the world's first
Hyper Linear with everyone.
Thank you very much, Alan-san!
We also have another
announcement for you all.
Lucky them! I wish I could ride it, too!
-Us commoners don't stand a chance.
-Members of the general public will be
chosen through a random drawing
to ride the Hyper Linear, as well!
All right!
-Oh, brother...
-Wow, so much hype!
You'd think they'd already
won the tickets.
But isn't it a bit too early to celebrate?
Huh? Why?
She said it was a random
drawing, remember?
What do you think
the odds of winning actually are?
Man, they're such cheap dark overlords.
No, we still have a way!
I believe that several companies
in the Suzuki Conglomerate
are WSG Tokyo sponsors.
I see! We just have to go ask
Sonoko-oneesan!
"We just have to ask"? No way.
Those Platinum Tickets
aren't easy to snag!
Life just isn't that easy!
Now, now, Sonoko, shouldn't I
at least try to ask?
Right. Maybe just enough for the children...
Jeez, aren't you being
way too soft on these brats?
Please stay out of this!
We were this close!
Don't ruin it for us!
Look here.
Be grateful you could even come here!
(WSG TOKYO SPONSOR COMPANY SEND-OFF PARTY)
Okay.
I'm terribly sorry to bother you,
but can we start setting up
the food wagons here?
Oh, sure.
We'll get out of the way.
-Looks delicious!
Everyone, meet up in front of the door
after you finish grabbing your food!
-Okay!
All right, let's go!
Yeah!
Let's eat a ton and get our money's worth!
Genta-kun, only the person
who paid gets to say that.
They sure switch gears real quick.
Well, sure.
They are younger than us, after all.
"Younger"? You and I are still in our teens.
All right then, let's be flexible.
Here's to the innocent little kids.
Cheers.
A blackout?
What the?
What just happened?
What was that light?
Sorry, Haibara. Can you hold my glass for me?
Huh? Hey, Edogawa-kun!
Oh, come on!
I'm sure I saw a light around here.
Conan, are you all right?
Ran... neechan.
Y-Yeah.
Hey, they're back on.
Now I've got to look for the kids.
Dad?
If you're here, answer me!
Sonoko, what's wrong?
Oh, Ran!
Actually, I can't find my dad anywhere.
Calls aren't going through either!
But you were with him just now.
Right, but when the emergency lights
came on, he was gone...
Really, where did he go?
Oh, it's John-san.
John-san!
I'm sorry to interrupt your conversation.
JOHN VOIT (51) JAPAN CODE CEO
May I have a minute of your time?
Oh, Sonoko-san! What can I do for you?
Um, it's about my father
who was just with us a few minutes ago.
Do you happen to know where he is now?
U-Um, John-san?
-I know nothing!
-Ah! John-san!
Sir, please don't run!
Hey, that's dangerous.
-Ran, did I say anything weird?
-Edogawa-kun.
The blackout lasted
about 30 seconds, right?
Yeah, not much of a window to just
vanish from a huge place like this.
That means it's time for us!
It's been a while.
Right!
We...
We are...
-We are the Detective Boys, after all!
DETECTIVE BOYS
Sonoko-neechan, why don't we
have the hotel clerks look for him?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
-Inspector Megure!
What's the situation?
Chairman Suzuki still hasn't been found.
I see...
He still hasn't responded to
the calls from the building PA, either.
This may be a kidnapping for ransom.
Also, Conan-kun and the others
were also attending the party.
We have a testimony that a light
similar to a whitish blue spark
was seen right after
the power outage happened.
Let's hear what they have to say.
I think it was that thing...
You know, the one
that villains in TV dramas use
to shock people and make them pass out.
-A stun gun!?
-Don't tell me...!
Someone stunned
and abducted the Chairman too?
Chairman Suzuki "too"?
But it's impossible to drag
an unconscious person
out of here in 30 seconds.
You've checked
the security cameras, right?
Yes. After the emergency lights came on,
there was no sign
of any suspicious-looking activity.
So how did they spirit away an
unconscious person with everyone watching?
And what was their purpose?
Just as I thought!
-What's the matter?
-Did you find something?
I smell eel from somewhere around here!
So those kids followed us here
from the room?
-What? I don't smell it at all.
-Let's send them back right away.
I can still smell eel here,
so where the heck are they?
So that's it!
Hey, this spot... There's exactly
one wagon's width open here.
Maybe there was some food here as well?
Let's see...
That's where the broiled eel and rice
steamed with eel sauce should be.
What's that? Sounds super tasty!
But that's strange.
Since we'd only just served
all the rice dishes,
how could it be gone already?
Perhaps it was too delicious
and popular, so it ran out already?
No, look here.
A person would fit down here.
You don't think they used that
to transport Chairman Suzuki?
True, they could have carried him out
this way without attracting attention.
But in that case,
wouldn't the most likely suspect
be either a hotel worker,
or someone dressed up like one?
Find any witnesses who saw a hotel worker
pushing a wagon out of here!
Go back and check
the hotel security cameras again, too!
-Yes, sir!
And you kids need to go back
to the room immediately!
-Okay!
This way.
The smell of eels is heading this way!
Genta-kun, you're amazing! Like a police dog!
I didn't know you had such a talent!
What, you telling me you guys didn't know?
I have a feeling we did.
It's getting really close! The smell is
getting stronger and stronger!
The place is empty, huh?
They're interrogating
the employees right now.
How's it looking, Genta-kun?
I'm sure it's somewhere inside this room.
I found it.
For real, Haibara-san?
That wagon in the back.
It's the same as the ones
back at the party venue, isn't it?
Found him!
What's a male worker's uniform doing here?
Edogawa-kun!
Chairman Suzuki isn't inside the wagon!
Got it!
That looks so tasty!
You mustn't eat any. It's evidence.
-What?! I can't?
-Broiling sauce?
That's right!
Found him.
MEDICAL OFFICE
So the perp's face?
I didn't see them.
There was the blackout,
and the next thing I knew, these kids—
It's all thanks to us,
the Detective Boys! Right?
-Right!
-Yup, yup!
Inspector, his testimony is
the same as President Mitsuzuka's.
So the same thing happened to
this "President Mitsuzuka," huh?
So that really was a criminal incident after all?
Hey, Dad, what are you talking about?
Remember me telling you about that friend
I met last week who suddenly disappeared?
You mean that female CEO that
you've been golfing a lot with lately.
Is that so, honey?
EIKO MITSUZUKA (48)
MISTUZUKA CONFECTIONERIES COMPANY PRESIDENT
Oh, no, we don't go alone.
But right after the police came,
they found her
in the golf course bathroom, right?
Yes, but she never told us anything
about what happened that day.
And she didn't come
to the party today, either.
Wait, so is this lady CEO named
Mitsuzuka also a WSG Tokyo sponsor?
Yeah, that's right.
Eiko Mitsuzuka. She's the president
of Mitsuzuka Confectioneries.
Hey, I've seen this logo before!
Cause it's the same logo
on Masked Yaiber candy bars!
You're right.
What I'm more worried about—
Hey, look! It says "Masked Yaiber Show!"
It looks like there's one at Shibahama Station
the day of the Linear's first run!
MASKED YAIBER SHOW
JULY 24, SHIBAHAMA STATION SQUARE
-Are you kidding me? I so wanna go!
-Indeed!
Sorry, but...
It looks like they've long since
closed down applications for tickets.
What?
-What the...
-What a bummer!
Anyway, what's bothering you is...
-...this, right?
-Yeah.
Both this company and Chairman Suzuki's
company are sponsors for WSG Tokyo.
And the leaders of both companies were
just abducted, one after the other.
Could it be a coincidence?
Yes?
It's me.
I know this is sudden, but you know
about the WSG Serial Kidnappings
from 15 years ago, right?
Of course.
That abominable incident may be
happening again... This time in Tokyo.
Yes, it seems that way.
DETECTIVE CONAN: THE SCARLET BULLET
I'm Shinichi Kudo,
a high school student detective.
I went to an amusement park with my
childhood friend and classmate Ran Mori.
There, I witnessed a man in black
making a suspicious deal.
I was so caught up in watching the deal
that I didn't notice his accomplice
approaching me from behind.
That man force-fed me poison,
and when I woke up...
My body had shrunk!
If they were to find out
that Shinichi Kudo is still alive,
my life, and the lives of those
around me, would be in danger.
On Professor Agasa's advice,
I decided to conceal my identity.
And when Ran asked me what my name was,
I blurted out "Conan Edogawa" in a panic.
And then, to gather information on them,
I ended up crashing at Ran's house,
since her dad's a detective.
I'm not the only one
after the syndicate of men in black.
The Federal Bureau of Investigation,
the FBI's James Black, Andre Camel,
Jodie Starling. And Shuichi Akai.
He's the top sniper in the FBI.
Right now, he's disguised as
a grad school student named Subaru Okiya,
and is hiding out in the Kudo residence...
in other words, my house.
His younger sister, Masumi Sera.
She's a female high school
student detective
who transferred into Ran's class.
She's living in a hotel
with a mysterious girl,
but that girl is most likely
Akai-san's mother, Mary.
If she'd been administered
the same drug as I was,
and her body had shrunken...
This guy that calls her "Mother Mary" is
Sera's other older brother,
Shukichi Haneda.
Currently, he's the holder
of six championship titles in shogi.
In other words, these four are
all members of one family.
And this family is about to become
deeply involved in this case...
Although I've become smaller,
my intelligence is the same!
A great detective who leaves no case unsolved!
There is always only one truth!
Sonoko-oneesan!
Can we really take
all these Yaiber goods home?
There's even a Yaiber scarf!
And action figures!
They're all presents for you guys!
It's my thanks for finding Dad for me!
-Hurray!
-Good for you, guys!
-I think I'll pass...
-Me, too.
Actually, there is one more thing.
Ta-da-da-dah!
What do you think these are?
-What are those?
-Letters from somebody?
Nope!
What? Tell us the answer!
These are the Platinum Tickets
that are being raffled off nationwide,
which will get you on board
the Hyper Linear train!
Amazing!
Way to go, Sonoko-sama!
Thank you very much!
It's still too soon to be rejoicing!
Even I could only manage to
get my hands on six of these tickets.
-Just six.
Which means...
One.
Two.
Three.
Four, five, six, seven.
Seven of us—
No, no, counting me, that makes eight!
Professor, you're an adult,
so it's a given that you'll decline.
What? No way!
So that's one more who can't go!
And we're going to decide who that is now!
What!?
How are you going to pick?
Naturally, by one of the professor's
specialties, a quiz!
Why's that?
Because that would be the most fair!
You kids better not think
that you can get everything for free!
Cheapskate!
Well, I did want to go, too,
but there's no way around it.
So, for the rest of you...
All right, I've got a quiz!
The "Hyper Linear" that you guys
will be the first to board in the world...
Actually, someone's already
been on it before you.
Now, of the next three people, who is it?
One, Lawyer.
Two, Doctor.
Three, Missionary.
-The question is all too easy.
-You said it.
What? That was quick.
Well, I do want to ride the Linear.
-Sonoko, did you figure it out?
-Not a clue!
Correct!
This question is hard!
Hey, give us a hint!
I don't get it at all!
Fine... A hint.
The Hyper Linear, in order to
lift itself up from the track,
uses a really strong magnet called
a "superconductive magnet (chou-dendou)."
And when you think of other ways to say
"lawyer," "doctor," and "missionary",
you get "legal expert (houritsuka),"
"physician(isha),"
and "preacher(dendoushi)," right?
Oh, I get it, Professor!
-All right.
-Is the answer...
-Correct!
-All right!
Ran?
Oh, sorry, Sonoko.
Now, there are only three tickets left!
I'm not losing to you brats!
Sonoko-sama here will be the one
boarding the Hyper Linear!
But this is hard.
A missionary is a preacher (dendoushi).
A missionary is...
...a preacher (dendoushi).
Superconductive (Chou-dendou)...
-Oh, I get it!
The answer is the preacher,
in other words...
Number 3, the missionary!
Correct!
Hurray!
We really are so lucky!
Right. Getting to ride the Hyper Linear,
that's so amazing!
And we got tons of
these Yaiber goods, too!
Man, I wanna hurry home
and brag to Dad and Mom.
Oh, sorry... I forgot my smartphone
at the Professor's house.
It might take a while if I have to
look for it, so go on ahead without me!
Well then, see you later!
-See you later!
-Yeah!
We also have to go meet up
with Sera-chan now, so...
-Okay!
-Later!
-Want to go for tapioca again today?
-Sounds good!
You need something?
I wanted to go on
a drive with you.
Would you mind coming
with me, little boy?
-Heading out.
-Please do.
WSG TOKYO SPORTS-WATCH GUIDE
Sponsors for WSG Tokyo...
that's what they have in common, right?
President Mitsuzuka
who disappeared during a round of golf,
and Chairman Suzuki
who was abducted during a party.
And there was a similar case
in the United States, 15 years ago.
Just as I thought!
I see that the FBI is
on the move, after all.
I wouldn't expect any less.
I looked it up on the internet.
So 15 years ago in the US,
right before WSG Boston,
there was a series of kidnappings,
all targeting the heads
of corporate sponsors, right?
The first one was the head of a
Japanese confectionery maker in Atlanta.
The second was the head of
a financial group in Chicago.
The third was the head of
a car manufacturer in Detroit.
Because the cases occurred
in multiple states,
the FBI took charge of the investigation.
But the third victim, who managed to
escape his captors on his own,
was shot to death in a station.
After that, the first and second victims
were safely released.
But for some reason, they clammed up
concerning the perpetrators,
and refused to cooperate
with the investigation.
I'm told the perp was Japanese?
A man named Makoto Ishihara,
who was a sushi chef in Boston.
He was at the WSG Boston party
attended by all the victims.
Furthermore, he was also nearby
when the third victim was shot.
And his fingerprints were found
on the murder weapon...
A gun that was found at a later time.
However, once the FBI arrested him,
Ishihara denied any wrongdoing.
What? I heard that his motive was to
protest the commercialization
of the WSG via a terrorist attack.
Because the companies
whose leaders were abducted
all dropped their WSG sponsorship
soon afterwards,
that's what people were led to believe.
The companies that dropped
their sponsorships
were censured all over the United States.
Well, they are unforgiving
towards people who cave in to terrorists.
Also, when I looked up who was the head
of the FBI back then, it was this guy.
You know who this is, right Subaru-san?
Alan MacKenzie.
A man people say will be
the next president.
Right. He's now the chairman
of the WSG Association,
and will arrive in Japan shortly.
That bother you?
I mean, there was a similar case
in the States 11 years ago, right?
Yeah, a copycat of the crime
from 15 years ago.
When I looked that one up, it was also during
Alan-san's time as FBI director.
But the FBI arrested the perpetrator for
that one before there were any deaths.
The perp admitted that he'd mimicked
the crime from four years before,
and also gave up his accomplices.
The FBI believes that
that copycat criminal
has reappeared in Tokyo now.
True, once again, the first victim was
the head of a confectionery maker.
The second was also
the head of a financial group.
It's exactly the same as 15 years ago.
Meaning the third target will be
the head of a car manufacturer, huh?
Thank you, little boy.
MORI DETECTIVE AGENCY
A client for Dad?
Huh? I've seen that guy somewhere...
JOHN VOIT, CODE JAPAN
PRESIDENT AND CEO
Mr. John Voit is the president and CEO
of Code Japan.
He's a famous man
who's been all over the news lately.
Oh, so Dad was meeting someone important!
-But what does he want from...
-Code Japan, huh.
Back when Takara Motors was
going bankrupt, they decided to become
a subsidiary of
the British car maker Code...
Is he the one they'll be going after next?
I'm home!
-Masumi, it came.
-What did?
The Linear that the target will be
boarding.
That's my mom!
Actually, I just heard this from Ran-kun,
but it seems like Conan-kun
will be on this train as well.
That little boy?
Oh, it's Kichi-nii.
Hey Kichi-nii, what's up?
I'll be heading over to Nagoya for work
on July 24th.
So I was wondering
what you wanted as a souvenir!
What? Kichi-nii, you're gonna be
in Nagoya that day, too?
You too, Masumi?
Then, since we'll both be there,
let's meet up in Nagoya!
Oh, uh, I'll give you a call
when I get to Nagoya, okay?
-I'm hanging up now!
-I have no time to see you in Nagoya!
Jeez... Kichi-nii!
You can't park here.
I'm sorr— Oh! Yumi—
Just as you'd expect
from the Taiko Meijin,
there you are like the real Hideyoshi,
cheating on me over the phone
with your new woman, you bald rat!
I-I wasn't!
Then who were you calling that you had to
hang up the second you saw me?
Fine.
I'll introduce them to you properly, Yumi-tan.
Dinner's ready!
-Okay!
-Yeah!
Time to eat!
These pork cutlets are tasty!
Ran-neechan, can I turn on the TV?
-Sure.
-Yay!
All eyes on the next story, everyone!
It's about the Hyper Linear!
It's finally been completed.
Conan-kun, don't just watch TV.
Eat your dinner, okay?
Not only that, but it can reach a top
speed of up to 1,000 km/hour!
It's really in another dimension speed-wise!
(1 MONTH UNTIL LINEAR OPENS PUBLIC TEST RUN)
And because the speed is comparable to
a bullet being fired from a gun,
NIPPON-NO-DANGAN
the world has dubbed it the
"Japanese Bullet".
So amazing. We're gonna be riding on that.
Dad, are you all right?
Ran, you stay seated!
Hey, kid, turn off the TV!
Oh, okay.
Are you guys riding the Hyper Linear?
What if we are?
Never mind that! Take off your shirt!
When are you riding it?
Oh, come on now!
The day of the inaugural run.
The opening day of WSG Tokyo.
What?
Raise your arms, Dad!
It was actually hot, wasn't it?
There's no need for you to act tough
and pretend like it wasn't, okay?
I'm sorry I made a mess.
-Hey, Pops.
-What?
Is that the same Hyper Linear that
John-san will be boarding, by any chance?
Among those who will be on board that day
are the WSG Tokyo sponsors here today,
That's why John-san came here
to ask for your help. Am I right?
Hey, what's going on?
Pops, my friends are going on
the Hyper Linear, too.
If something dangerous is about to happen...
No, it shouldn't end up turning into
that dangerous an incident!
At least, I don't think so.
Well, the two that were kidnapped
came back safely, I hear...
So this time around, they might try to
abduct John-san aboard the Hyper Linear?
What?
That's a big deal!
We have to tell the police!
Hold up! That was who I promised
my client I wouldn't tell!
We can't afford not to!
Those two may have been kidnapped
because of President John!
That's...
He said so himself.
He got drunk at a bar, and might have
let slip to the male patron next to him...
that he was playing golf
with President Mitsuzuka,
and that Chairman Suzuki was
attending that party the other day.
If something like that ever got out,
he couldn't avoid
sullying his company's image.
Sullying its image?
Nowadays, complete strangers
can band together and drive others
to desperation with no vested stakes.
So that's why he requested your assistance?
Yeah, to investigate whether
it's really his fault.
And to keep quiet about it
to the police until it was all clear.
I'm gonna go wash up.
Sorry about the miso soup.
I'll make some more!
Conan-kun, we have to stop the kids
from getting on the Linear!
Yeah.
But they were so happy about it.
Could there be any other way?
Masked Yaiber!
WSG ASSOCIATION BUILDING
Thank you for coming today.
We will now start the briefing
for the Hyper Linear Trial Ride,
-and the WSG Tokyo Opening Ceremonies.
-Look at this crowd!
Because people applied from all over
Japan to be here!
We're so lucky!
HYPER LINEAR LINER TEST RIDE AND
WSG TOKYO OPENING CEREMONIES SCHEDULE AND PRESENTATION
Allow us to introduce ourselves!
I am Maiko Shirahato, the publicity
director for WSG Association Japan.
PUBLICITY DIRECTOR, WSG ASSOCIATION JAPAN
MAIKO SHIRAHATO
I will be your guide for the opening
ceremonies.
What?
Isn't Shirahato that pharmaceutical company
where your father worked, Haibara-san?
That was Shirohato Pharmaceuticals.
Not Shirahato.
So I don't think
they're related in any way.
I-I am the chief development engineer
for the Hyper Linear, Osamu Inoue.
Um, how can I make it easy for you
to remember my name?
CHIEF DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER, HYPER LINEAR LINER
OSAMU INOUE
Since I'm Osamu Inoue...
Inoue-san, please move on!
Oh, okay...
I'm the one who programs the train
to run safely, and during the trial ride,
I'll be explaining the technical
aspects of the Hyper Linear to you.
-Also—
-Okay! That's it!
And finally, you have me!
Cabin attendant for the Hyper Linear,
the idol of the Hyper Linear staff!
I'm Ellie Ishioka!
ELLIE ISHIOKA
CHIEF CABIN ATTENDANT, HYPER LINEAR LINER
You can remember "Ellie Ishioka" with
a simple "welcome back", oka-eri!
But what about
the "ishi" part of her name?
Leave it to Ellie-san.
She knows how to sell herself.
Yes.
Next, I will explain the schedule
for the actual day.
At 10 a.m. on July 24, you will all gather
at the Nagoya International Airport!
Our destination will be Shibahama Stadium,
where WSG Tokyo's opening ceremonies
will be held.
SHIBAHAMA STADIUM
Since it's a trial ride from
Shin-Nagoya Station to Shibahama Station
in Tokyo, we'll be departing from Nagoya.
And at Nagoya International Airport,
we will meet up with the WSG committee
members and sponsors.
When all Hyper Linear passengers
have gathered,
we will start with a health
check at the airport hospital!
As you will be the first people
in the world to...
Hey, Conan-kun, this means that
the sponsors will also be checked
for their health, right?
I think so.
After that, it looks like
we'll be together
all the way from the airport
to Shibahama Stadium.
That means the Linear may not be the only
place where they'll go after John-san.
Yeah.
We'll have to be on our toes
at the airport and in the stadium, too.
Wait, Conan-kun, don't tell me
you're coming along?
-Of course I'm going.
-You absolutely can't!
I asked Sonoko to get
five of those tickets!
But I want to go on the Hyper Linear.
Back when he was a student,
ALAN MACKENZIE
WSG TORONTO PARTICIPATION PHOTO
he participated in WSG Toronto
as an athlete in shooting!
Shooting?
He was also the former director
of the FBI, right?
Alan-san became president
of the International WSG Association
seven years ago.
Seven years ago... Wasn't that the year
that Tokyo was named WSG host city?
That's correct!
Doesn't this link between President Alan
and WSG Tokyo feel like destiny?
There's one more thing!
Everyone, please take a look at
this model of the Hyper Linear!
Just before the Linear arrives
at Shibahama Station,
it will eject a surprise effect where
flags of all nations fly out like this!
That's another idea of President Alan's!
Hold it, Ellie-san!
You weren't supposed to mention that!
It's no longer a surprise now!
And, well...
So please pretend
you didn't hear any of that!
P-Please don't tweet about it
or anything, okay?
Now, please take a look at the pamphlet
we handed out at the entrance.
We'll go over the rest of the schedule
for the actual day, as well as
THE STORY BEGINS,
HYPER LINEAR LINER
seat assignments aboard the Hyper Linear.
I see.
It looks pretty tough
for us to infiltrate.
You guys are pretty enthusiastic
for a case happening in Japan.
If there's a copycat of a case
that the FBI solved,
we need to be the ones to capture them.
We have authorization
from FBI headquarters,
for the sniper bullet
requested by Akai-san.
Sniper... Don't tell me you guys are
planning on killing the perp?
Conan-kun.
The FBI has its own ways
of dealing with things.
-All right!
-Yaiber Show!
-Let us go to the Yaiber Show!
-Good thing they jumped ship so easily
-from the Hyper Linear to Yaiber.
-Yeah.
But she's still headed to Nagoya.
"She"?
Ran-neechan from the detective agency.
Y-Yeah...
Wait, Shinichi,
how did you know about that?
Oh, you heard from Conan-kun again,
didn't you?
In any case, you shouldn't go.
I'll protect your dad for you.
Protect?
So Shinichi, you're set on
going to Nagoya.
In that case, I'm going, too!
Hey, Ran!
It'll be all right.
You'll just be
one more person for me to protect.
You've got it wrong!
Protecting you is my—
Your what?
I-In any case, you shouldn't be going!
Hey, wait. Shinichi?
Idiot.
Don't make me say it.
NAGOYA INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT
Everyone boarding the Hyper Linear,
thank you for allowing us to
take attendance.
And we've been informed that
the sponsors have just arrived.
That back...
It's Ran, isn't it?
Hey, Ran! I told you not to come!
I mean, there's no way you can protect
John-san by yourself, Dad.
I don't need your help!
President John has hired
his own SPs as well!
And you even brought the kids with you!
Conan-kun and Ai-chan!
So you're here, too?
Well, Haibara insisted on coming.
I have no interest in Masked Yaiber.
I hear a faint voice calling for me!
Everyone, let's say it
all together this time.
Here goes!
-Help us, Masked Yaiber!
I have accepted all of your feelings!
Masked Yaiber is here!
He's so awesome!
And look at me, chaperoning the kids...
Conan-kun?!
Look out!
He's just a child. Nothing to worry about.
Are you all right, boy?
Y-Yeah...
I saw a slope, and I couldn't stop
myself from running down it!
-You didn't hurt yourself, did you?
-Nope!
Mister, your Japanese is really good!
Yes. I've been here in Japan
for a long time, you see.
-Oh, I see!
-Hey, kid!
Didn't they teach you at school
not to run down the hallway?
I'm so sorry, he's an acquaintance's kid...
Ran, make sure you keep an eye on him!
-Hey!
-Now, let's get going!
Hey, Conan-kun... You're big enough to
make it home with Ai-chan now, aren't you?
Huh? That's impossible. I'm just a kid.
But... Ai-chan, you're big enough
to head home, right?
I can't make it home. I'm just a kid.
Let's hurry on in.
We're the very last ones now.
R-Right.
INCOMING CALL
SUBARU OKIYA
I just landed at
Nagoya International Airport.
And I have
a certain request for you, my boy.
Got it.
If worse comes to worst,
I'll give it a shot.
Who are you talking to?
Haibara.
It's Genta! He's saying
the Yaiber show is really fun!
I see.
Everyone else is waiting for you.
I'll be right over, so go on ahead.
You'll get lost, so hurry over.
Yeah!
Hello?
-Everything okay?
-Yeah.
Anyway, did you look into my request?
Of course.
According to FBI records,
Ishihara was incarcerated
and then passed away.
Huh? Ishihara had been
denying the charges, right?
According to the memoirs
of the FBI director at the time,
he'd been proclaiming
his innocence the whole time.
The FBI director back then was...
-President Alan.
What are the chances
that Ishihara was falsely accused?
None... or so I'd like to believe.
Also, Ishihara had a wife and a daughter.
He had a family!?
After he died in prison,
his wife and daughter returned to Japan.
Their names are...
Got it. I'll check the guest roster.
I'm sure Pops has one.
President Alan has arrived!
ALAN MACKENZIE (64)
INTERNATIONAL WSG ASSOCIATION PRESIDENT
Everyone, please greet him with
a large round of applause!
That was quick.
So, how was it?
They weren't on the roster.
I see.
Well, there is the possibility
that they changed their names
under the witness protection program.
Ishihara was the perp, right?
Would his family be candidates
for the witness protection program?
Anyone can enter it
if there's the possibility
that the perp's accomplices
could assault them.
After all, it's a plea bargain
to force them
to assist with the investigation
by assuring their safety.
Can you check if Ishihara or his daughter
were in the program or not?
If the FBI was responsible for
the witness protection,
we'd see it right away,
but if the USMS handled it,
it will take a little time.
Huh? Why?
The FBI and the USMS
aren't exactly friends.
I-I see...
By the way, when you're changing names
under witness protection,
can you change it to whatever you want?
That would be difficult.
-Are you absolutely sure?
-Conan-kun?
You might be able to if there was little risk
of your previous name being identified.
-Where did he go?
-I see...
Ise will hold Tsu.
Tsu will hold Ise.
Owari-Nagoya will be held by the fort...
Nothing less from one of the three
famous castles of Japan.
Stop mouthing off
with that smug look on your face!
Yumi-tan!
I was going to go pick you up
once you arrived at Nagoya station.
I'm surprised that you figured out
I was here.
Of course I'd know.
You're a celebrity!
(Taiko Meijin spotted!)
Hey, that's me!
More like, what do you mean that
we're meeting up for a date in Nagoya!?
I had work over here today.
Jeez, you should've told me
you'd be wearing a kimono!
I would have coordinated
my clothes accordingly.
I-I'm sorry.
Anyway, are you done with work?
Yeah. Today I'm just scouting.
Now, look here.
Isn't it amazing that we'll be playing
in a place like this,
overlooking Nagoya Castle?
-Playing?
-I didn't tell you?
PLANNED CONSTRUCTION SITE
FOR NAGOYA SHOGI HALL
This is where they're building the
Nagoya Shogi Hall.
Oh yeah, you said you were on the
executive committee for its construction.
Yeah. I volunteered myself.
You really are a fanboy!
I couldn't let any other
shogi players do it.
What?
If you get dragged about everywhere
to secure funding,
there'll be no time left to play shogi.
I'm the only one
that needs to feel that pain.
Chukichi...
NAGOYA INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT HOSPITAL
The simple checkups we will be doing
now will be held in a coed room.
We will now show you to the exam room
on the second floor, so please follow us.
-What's wrong?
-It feels like we're being watched.
I'm working today, so I have to make sure
my cover's not blown.
Okay, your blood pressure is normal.
-Next. Mr. MacKenzie!
-Yes.
Oops.
That's an energy drink, right?
Looks like it.
Here you go, Alan-san.
Oh, thank you.
I just bought it at the airport.
I haven't slept for a day.
If I fell asleep during the ceremony,
it'd be a mess.
Both of you understand English?!
Just a little, because there are
classes at school.
Same here.
What the?
Everyone, please calm down!
Please don't panic!
Please evacuate outside without running!
Someone help us!
Darn it, this door won't budge!
Is this a plot to take my life?
Don't worry! We will protect you!
-Dad! I'll go look for a way out!
-Hey, Ran!
Ran-neechan! Answer me!
-Ran-ne—
-Edogawa-kun!
This is no explosion!
-It's a quench!
-Quench?
Edogawa-kun, hurry up and escape...
Hey! Haibara!
Hurry and escape...
At this rate, everyone is sure to die.
Haibara? Hey, Haibara!
Stay with me, Haibara!
Haibara!
Sh-Shinichi?
Ran!? Are you okay?
Hey!
M-My body won't move...
Wh-What in the world is going on...
Hello? What's wrong, little boy?
Who is it!?
What happened here?!
What a mess we're in! How shameful!
I couldn't help it.
I was about to collide with a car
that came out of nowhere!
But we're fine.
This is the only road from the airport
leading to the urban district.
INCOMING CALL
KICHI-NII
She hung up on me. Why?
There you are, Chukichi!
Who have you been calling
for the past few minutes?
My family.
I wanted to introduce you
as the woman I have been dating.
But maybe they still aren't
ready to accept you yet.
I told my mother that there was someone
I wanted to propose to
once I won every shogi title out there.
One or two titles shouldn't matter.
You have the best title out there, anyway.
This one, named Yumi Miyamoto-sama!
Yumi-san...
Wait, Yumi-tan, are you drunk?
Not at all!
-Come on, back to the store!
-Look out, Yumi-tan!
Are you in pain anywhere?
-No, I'm fine.
-Where are you, Ran!
Ran!
Shinichi?
I'm not Shinichi! It's me!
Dad...
Where are Conan-kun and Ai-chan?
They're still passed out.
I'm going to check on President John's
condition now, so wake them up for me.
Conan-kun!
Ran!
Neechan... Are you okay?
Yeah, looks like I'm perfectly fine.
What about you, Conan-kun?
He's not here! President John is gone!
It's not like he woke up before us
and he's already being examined?
-I don't know!
-All right!
The transmitter I put on John-san
still works!
Ran-neechan, take care of Haibara!
-Where are you going?
-Bathroom!
NAGOYA
Little boy, what happened?
I got roped into trouble at the hospital...
(CONAN EDOGAWA)
It's fine as long as you're okay.
But John-san has been kidnapped.
What?
Following the transmitter's signals,
John-san has gone through the only path
out of the airport,
and is likely heading east
on Triton Bridge...
-Can you pursue him?
-Yeah...
Static?
Which way did it head from here?
Follow that red car!
-Why?
-Just hurry up and do it!
That motorcycle and helmet... It can't be...
Who is that exactly?
It doesn't matter. Don't let him get away!
Got it!
Don't tell me it's busted now?
Look out!
Darn it!
That was close!
Haibara! Are you awake, Haibara?!
Ran-neechan woke me up.
I'm glad you're okay! Actually—
Hold on, let me move over a bit.
No good! John-san's cellphone
has been powered down.
Where are you?
My glasses broke!
Maybe it broke when you collapsed
because of the quench earlier?
I need you to confirm John-san
location right away.
Location, you say...
How did you know that I brought
a spare pair of glasses with me?
I mean, you're always prepared and stuff.
Hold on just a second.
I'm counting on you, Haibara!
What was that explosion earlier?
(NURSE STATION)
-Please calm down!
-Excuse me!
There's a possibility that a
quench has occurred!
Please call an MRI technician right away!
O-Okay!
MRI Technician, Takahashi-san...
John-san has entered the main island,
and is heading south
from around the Tokai Interchange!
At this speed, it must be
either a car or a motorcycle.
MRI room, stat!
Subaru-san, John-san is currently—
I heard it. The Tokai Industrial Complex!
Found it!
Haibara! Where is John-san?
Right now, he's stopped near
the Tokai Industrial Complex.
I'm going to enter the MRI room now.
The magnetism inside
may cause abnormalities
in electronics like these glasses.
Well, if it was a quench,
I think I'll be okay.
So what is this "quench" thing, anyway!?
Oh, even our great detective doesn't
know what a quench is?
Well, excuse me!
Then, let me tell you.
MRI uses superconductive magnets.
(SUPERCONDUCTIVE MAGNET)
They use liquid helium to keep its
temperature low.
LIQUID HELIUM
But if that temperature goes up
for one reason or another,
it explosively evaporates.
So that's what a quench is!
Right.
If a quench happens, the helium gas
quickly lowers the oxygen concentration,
so it can be life-threatening
in a matter of minutes.
But there are safety measures to prevent
something like that from happening...
So why?
It's an IV stand that isn't suitable
for use near an MRI.
The emergency shut-off button
has been pressed, too!
What does that mean?
I believe something like this got stuck
to the MRI's superconductive magnet,
and someone panic-pressed
the emergency shut-off button,
causing the quench to happen.
But normally all piping in the hospital
is supposed to close
when the emergency shut-off button
is pressed, right?
What? That's right.
When it detects smoke,
the internal piping closes,
and only the pipes leading outside
should be open.
But then, why did it?
Where to?
Please come to the control room!
The pipes leading to the second floor
have been set to stay open,
and the ventilation has been
set to work at full throttle!
Did you hear that?
That's why the smoke
that filled the second floor
was ventilated out immediately,
and we were spared from
oxygen deprivation.
-So the perp did that on purpose?
-Probably.
If so, this perp has no intention
of killing anyone.
I see!
So that's why they left their abduction
targets where they could be found easily.
I've arrived at Tokai Industrial Complex.
Where is the target?
He should be close by.
John-san isn't moving right now.
That motorcycle again!
This feels like...
Jeet Kune Do!
Who in the world are you?
H-He's strong!
At this rate, I'm going to be taken out!
This kid...! It can't be!
So it is you, Masumi!
Where are you, Subaru-san?
That's a disguise, isn't it?
Who in the world are you?
Sera-no-neechan!
Conan-kun!
What are you doing here?
Huh? Oh... There's someone I'm looking for.
All the way out here
in a factory like this?
I have my reasons.
SENDER: M
SUBJECT: GO AHEAD.
It won't do for me
to see that child right now.
Got it, Mom.
Sera-no-neechan!
That person you're looking for...
Would it be John-san?
You really are sharp.
That's right.
I know where John-san is right now.
-What?
-Follow me!
Hey, wait!
So what brought you here?
I saw it in the hospital lobby.
What just happened?
That cart was calmly moving along
while everything around it was in a panic
from the explosion.
Did you see the driver's face?
It was very brief,
so I didn't get a good look,
but from the physique, it was a man.
The perp is male...
Right there!
John-san's transmitter is
right around there!
John Voit is somewhere around here!?
The perp left the targets
where they'd be easily found.
It's likely the same story
this time around, too.
I'm going to try calling
John-san's cellphone.
You know his number?
Well, yeah.
By the way, I heard that John-san's
phone's turned off right now.
No, if the perp is the kind of guy
I think he is...
I hear it... Where is it?
I know.
He's above us!
Okay!
Found him!
Why would they leave him
in such a conspicuous place?
Because the perp had
no intention of killing John-san.
Time to eat!
So tasty!
After all, if you're in Nagoya,
you really gotta eat some hitsumabushi!
Dad!
Shinichi just called and said
they found John-san!
Why is that detective boy calling
about something like that?
I don't care!
Just tell the people in charge!
You keep an eye on that hitsumabushi!
It's mine!
Yeah, yeah...
Thanks, Shinichi.
Yeah, we're fine over here.
Sheesh, you really should contact me, too.
John-san, do you remember anything
about when you were abducted?
When it happened...
I was suddenly engulfed in white smoke,
and I couldn't breathe, but...
When I came to briefly,
I was inside a car...
It felt like there was someone next to me...
Was that the perp?
I don't know...
Was it a man or a woman?
I don't know.
So we can't board the Linear?
Why?
But our test results showed nothing wrong!
I know, but we can't have
another incident like before,
-Man, that was tasty.
-Yeah, it was delicious.
So they decided that it would be better
to return to Tokyo using the bullet trains.
-What?
-Ellie-san is in trouble!
-I should take a firm stand and—
-Ellie-san! Inoue-san!
Is President Alan here, by any chance?
I haven't seen him.
Nor I.
I searched the hospital
and the conference room too...
President Alan is nowhere to be found!
AICHI
You're the one that called 110?
I am, but you're so late!
I'm sorry.
There was an explosion at the airport, so
most of the Nagoya police are out there,
leaving us short-handed.
In any case, just get him to a hospital!
I'm really glad you guys helped me out.
Thank you.
-No problem!
-Take care of yourself, John-san!
Mission accomplished!
We were able to protect
the VIP from England...
Good job, Masumi.
They've decided to send us home
on the Shinkansen Bullet Train.
Huh? The Linear isn't running after all?
It looks like it's going to
depart from the station
in time for the opening ceremonies
without anyone on board.
Without anyone on board?
Because the Linear runs autonomously.
But enough about that.
President Alan is missing.
That "someone else in the car"
that John-san mentioned just now...
It might have been President Alan.
Hold on a sec!
I'm gonna make a phone call!
Oh, sure.
I found the perp's car, little boy.
It's in the airport parking lot.
The only thing we were able to find out
was that the driver is likely to be male.
The perp is a male, after all?
The FBI director back then was...
Hello, everyone in Japan.
What are the chances
that Ishihara was falsely accused?
Akai-san, it looks like worse...
has come to worst.
Head over to Shin-Nagoya Station
right away!
Yeah...
Roger that.
Sera-no-neechan! To Shin-Nagoya station!
-What?
-Hurry!
What's wrong?
You know how he said that most cops
in this jurisdiction are concentrated
at the airport because the perp
caused that quench?
I get it!
The security at the station is
stretched a bit thin!
Right!
Fifteen years ago...
WSG CONSECUTIVE KINDNAPPING CASES
T.M. COMPANY PRESIDENT SHOT DEAD
The third victim was shot dead
inside a station.
So they're going to use a gun to kill
again at Shin-Nagoya Station this time?
No, I'm sure they'll be using
the "Japanese Bullet"!
In other words, the final showdown
will be on the Linear.
Right. Akai-kun is headed to
Shin-Nagoya station as we speak.
-We should hurry over as well.
-Got it!
Yumi-tan, you're drinking too much.
You have to hold back a bit more,
or I can't introduce you to my family...
What does your family have to do with it?
We're gonna get married, anyway!
So tasty!
You mean you're going to
accept my proposal?
Of course!
Yumi-tan!
I'll make you happy, I promise!
Shall we return to Tokyo, too?
Please follow me!
I wanted to go on the Linear...
What a shame.
Is something the matter?
I can't find a child that was with me...
Ran!
Have they found President Alan?
Probably not yet.
But they're going to
run the Linear as planned,
and also go through
with the opening ceremonies.
SENDER: EDOGAWA
SUBJECT: SORRY, HAIBARA
That's the WSG Association's decision.
I doubt it will be overturned.
How was President John doing?
It seems he's doing all right.
Shouldn't you be there with him?
I told you, President John has his SPs.
My job is to investigate the case.
Let's go!
Hold on! Conan-kun hasn't come back yet!
What about his phone?
I've been calling and calling,
but I can't seem to get through.
If you're wondering about Edogawa-kun,
he said that he'd be heading home
with someone he knows.
CONGRATULATIONS!
There have been slight changes
to the original plan,
and no passengers will board
the world's first Hyper Linear.
Even so, look how many people
have gathered to get
a look at the Hyper Linear!
Now, it's finally time!
-Ten, nine, eight, seven, six...
-Now, it's not just train fans,
-five, four, three, two...
-but all of Japan, no...
People all over the world have been
eagerly awaiting this historic moment!
One!
The Hyper Linear has just been
set in motion, right on schedule!
What?
THE SPEEDS OF THE LINEAR ARE PRESENT IN THE COLORS
Let's learn the mechanics
behind the Hyper Linear!
THERE ARE 7 COLORS EVERYONE SHOULD REMEMBER WELL!
The linear starts out
by running on its wheels.
Then, when the Linear accelerates over
150 km/h, the magnets and the suction
from the coils will lift the train
above the tracks.
After that, the Linear will enter
the "vacuum tunnel."
Inside it, air resistance
has been reduced,
so the train will
accelerate to 1,000 km/h.
Speed can be controlled
from within the train,
and when it emerges from the tunnel
and decelerates to 300 km/h,
the "air brake" will take effect.
Furthermore,
when it decelerates to 150 km/h,
the wheels stored within
the chassis will emerge.
If there's no driver on the Linear,
who's controlling it?
Well, that's—
A very good question.
Actually, within the Hyper Linear,
there is a room designated as
the manual operation room.
However, this operation room is
only for test runs,
so they are not normally used.
Instead, the control room located
between Shin-Nagoya and
Shibahama stations controls the Linear!
Now, let's take a look inside the train
as it's racing along.
-What?
-We can see inside the Linear?
Hurray!
Unfortunately, there are no passengers
aboard today so there isn't anyone—
Conan-kun?
Sera-chan!?
If President Alan isn't on board,
being scolded won't be
the end of it for us.
Hey, do you smell something?
This is President Alan's!
Huh? Is that so?
Hey, that perp you saw at the airport...
How many suitcases
did he have on the cart?
Two.
Both suitcases were identical.
Two identical suitcases...
If I remember correctly, the suitcase
John-san was placed in...
was the type with a zipper!
Conan-kun, what are you doing?
This tangy scent... Can it be?
Spotted them!
The energy drink-smeared wheel prints
of a suitcase!
The vitamin B2 in energy drinks is
fluorescent.
It lights up under black light.
But anyway, that's
a really useful wristwatch
if it's got a black light on it as well...
It's a detective tool from
a reliable professor, after all.
Those kids must miss me so much,
they're spreading rumors about me!
I got caught up in the repairs
so I'm running quite late now...
I hope they're enjoying
the Masked Yaiber show.
Weak. You're too weak, Yaiber!
We will take the children now!
S-Stop it, Jocker!
-Hey, isn't Yaiber in trouble?
-There are way too many enemies!
Okay, now!
-Yaiber! Do your best!
Ugh, when is professor coming...
That's enough, you phantoms!
-Whose voice is that?
-Where are you?
Hey, look at the sky!
Then, the two that are
currently aboard the Linear...
Sorry, he's with me.
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
Well, um...
Please stop the train at some station
along the way and drag him out!
I'll go pick him up!
Well, um...
We were supposed to
have a trial ride today,
so it's been programmed not to
stop at any stations along the route.
But you can operate it
from the control room, right?
If we do that, it will also cancel
the flying of the national flags
from the Linear
during the opening ceremonies.
That was President Alan's idea, right?
Right, it was.
Would it be okay to cancel it because of
what's going on aboard the Linear?
But we should contact
the control room regardless.
I'll go handle that.
Conan-kun, Sera-chan...
Hello? Can you wait for just a bit longer?
No...
We've reached the time limit.
Got it.
Go!
We have to hurry and find President Alan.
Conan-kun, that sound just now was
a gunshot, right?
A bolt-action rifle, no less.
Just what have you been up to
all this time, and with whom?
It's fine.
The guy on the other end is on our side.
Do as you like from here, little boy.
Hold on.
There's one more thing I need you to do.
All right.
Give me the numbers
of all the participants.
What are you doing?! Jeez!
Okay!
What do you think you're doing?
I'm borrowing this.
Hold on, Ai-chan! What's wrong?
Jeez, you sure work people hard.
-The trail ends here.
-You're right.
-I'm opening the door.
-Okay.
Could he actually be inside!?
Hold on a second!
Are you all right?
So he's conscious, after all.
Where am I?
Inside the Linear.
How were you able to find me?
Thanks to the drink you dripped.
I'd expect nothing less
of a former FBI director.
It's President Alan!
-What the?
-Mori-san!
What in the world is going on?
Do you know something about this?
Everyone, listen up!
President Alan was kidnapped along with
John-san during that quench!
Say what?
And they were both
put inside the perp's car.
Then did Alan-san see the face of the perp?
Unfortunately not.
But...
We already know who the perpetrator is.
By "we" you're talking about Conan-kun, too?
Oh, no!
The one who knows is Shinichi-niichan!
So, who is the perp!?
Before that, Conan-kun wants to
make one last confirmation.
You mean Shinichi-niichan...
Okay, please do it.
Okay!
INCOMING CALL
UNKNOWN CALLER
Unknown caller?
I got a call, too.
Hello?
Who is it?
-Hello?
-From who?
Could it be that...
everyone's cell phone is ringing?
Mine and Conan-kun's are ringing, too.
President Alan's, too.
But there's one person
whose phone isn't ringing, right?
Yup.
Isn't that right?
Maiko Shirahato-san.
-Shirahato-san?!
Looks like your phone isn't ringing.
Oh, the battery's dead, see.
No, you haven't run out of juice,
have you?
I'm sure the electronics are acting weird
because you started up the MRI.
In other words...
The person who triggered the quench
was you, Shirahato-san.
My cellphone was broken...
You're going to treat me as the
perpetrator because of a coincidence?
Then, are you telling us that the fact
that you're on the Hyper Linear
is also a coincidence?
More than anything, Maiko Shirahato...
It's not a coincidence that your name
is an anagram of "Makoto Ishihara,"
the perpetrator of the shooting incident
from 15 years ago?
You couldn't give up
the name of your father,
who died maintaining his innocence,
could you?
Alan!
That gun!
Oh, what bliss! So you remember!
That's right.
It is the same model
as that case 15 years ago.
That perpetrator,
by that I mean your father,
insisted he was innocent 15 years ago.
And yet, the FBI still arrested my father!
Do you remember the first victim
of that case 15 years ago?
The head of a Japanese
confectionery maker, was it?
When the head of that Japanese company
was abducted, my father was with me!
So you're saying he had an alibi...
Back then, that's exactly
what I testified to the FBI!
And yet, my father was arrested...
And all the while proclaiming
his innocence, while incarcerated...
And my mother, right after
moving back to Japan...
All that anxiety must have gotten to her.
Her death was all too quick.
So that's why you've been harboring
a grudge against the FBI all this time.
That's why I changed my name
as I was told to by the USMS.
You mean that witness protection program
that comes with a plea bargain.
You're pretty well-versed for a child.
Right.
The USMS had no clue
about Japanese kana letters.
That's why they didn't notice that
I used the same letters
as my father's name.
And then, 7 years ago, I found
the gods of fortune on my side!
Seven years ago...
That was the year that Tokyo was
named WSG host city.
Right. And...
it was the year this man
became the president of WSG!
It felt like destiny to me!
And that's why you decided to
infiltrate WSG Association Japan.
Right.
That's how I found out that this man
would be aboard the Linear...
Aboard the "Nippon-no-Dangan"...
the Japanese Bullet!
And that's why you recreated the case
from 15 years ago?
Just so I could remind this man
of his own crimes.
But you didn't kill any other people.
That's right.
The only man I need to kill is this one.
You two get out of the way.
Right when this "Japanese Bullet" arrives
at the terminal station...
That's what I'd planned at first... But
thanks to you two, I'm changing my plan.
I'm going to have him die right now!
So the gods really are on my side.
Stop it!
You told me that only I need to die?
Yes, I only need to kill you!
Okay, then shoot here!
Mr. MacKenzie!
Here!
Shoot here from a higher position!
Then, even if the bullet goes through me,
it will only hit the floor.
"Shoot here from a higher position,
aiming for my chest."
"Then, even if the bullet goes through me,
it will only hit the floor."
The Linear uses
super-lightweight materials
in order to attain higher speeds, right?
Oh, that's right.
If the bullet goes through
the wall or the ceiling,
it will affect the Linear's course.
And that would endanger everyone here.
Same with the floor, sturdy as it may be.
If you shoot from point-blank range,
you can still pierce it.
That's why Alan-san is telling you to
move away enough
to barely hit his left chest, and to aim
from as high a position as possible.
You need to shut up!
Shirahato-san...
I'm sure you know, but
Alan-san is a professional shooter,
who once competed in the WSG
as a shooting athlete.
Conan-kun! Dad!
Here! Aim here!
Higher!
Go back!
More!
Lift your arms!
One more step!
Now!
Conan-kun!
What? What just happened?
Who was it? Who shot her!?
I'm sure the shooter was... Akai-san.
But Shu is still in Nagoya, isn't he?
The Linear is approaching Yamanashi now.
It's impossible to snipe her
from that distance.
NAGOYA/YAMANASHI/TOKYO
That's why Akai-san had
a special bullet made.
A bullet not made of steel, but of silver!
A silver bullet that won't stick to
the electromagnets embedded
in the walls of the Linear's tracks.
If the Linear's lift magnets generate
electromagnetic induction voltage,
when the silver bullet, traveling
at 1,000 km/h, enters the tunnel,
the bullet would remain unaffected
by gravity or air resistance,
and thus able to pursue
the Linear at the same speed.
And then,
if the Linear were to decelerate,
and that deceleration time
lasted long enough...
the silver bullet could use that time
to pierce through the Linear's
super-lightweight material.
And in that instant,
if the perp's vital spot is
at a pre-calculated location
within the cabin,
that would make sniping possible.
And to do that, he would need
an accomplice within the cabin.
-You're not saying that's—
-Yes, that boy, Conan Edogawa-kun.
Shirahato-san!
Conan-kun, Sera-chan, are you all right?
Everyone is fine.
-Why was the perp shot?
-Was it accidental fire?
That doesn't matter.
Stop this Linear at the nearest station
and call an ambulance!
Considering the Linear's current location,
the closest station would be
the terminal station.
In other words, Shibahama Station...
We'll have the police and an ambulance
standing by at Shibahama Station.
Whew, and that's another case closed.
Nope, not yet.
That's right.
Her accomplice is still on the loose.
What? An accomplice?
Yumi, are you okay?
Ima'okeeey...
I won't puke...
Until I see your family.
Let's go back to Tokyo for today.
Let's just take a taxi to the station...
That car is definitely
breaking the speed limit!
Hey, you! Stop!
Y-Yumi-tan!
Yumi-tan! Are you okay?
Hey, Yumi-tan! Yumi-tan! Yumi-tan!
There's an accomplice? What do you mean?
Isn't that right, Conan-kun?
Looks like Sera-no-neechan noticed too,
Shinichi-niichan.
Of course I would notice,
after seeing something like that.
Clearly, someone was
operating it remotely.
Right when the perp had
her back to the wall, too.
In other words,
the accomplice helped her out.
The perp had a huge suitcase
with President Alan in it,
and came on board.
Even with fewer cops
around Shin-Nagoya Station
thanks to the quench incident
at the airport,
normally, it would still be a tough task.
In other words, the accomplice is
involved with the Linear, and is male.
Isn't that right, Inoue-san?
Coming up with a method
like the quench and pulling it off...
Who but the engineer of the Linear?
Come to think of it,
both the Linear and MRIs
use superconductive magnets.
Were you able to make a device like that
because you were in charge of programming?
The only one who can remotely
achieve sudden deceleration like that,
is the engineer who can see inside
the Hyper Linear Liner in real-time!
Darn it!
-You're not getting away!
-Found it.
The software linked to the system
for the Hyper Linear's control room!
G-Give that back!
Why did you do such a thing?
There were only two Japanese people
involved in the case from 15 years ago.
The culprit, Makoto Ishihara,
and the first target,
the confectionery maker head.
That was my dad.
What!?
After pulling out of the WSG sponsorship,
my father got blasted by
everyone in America.
Ultimately, he was fired from his position
as head of the company!
My family lost everything thanks to
that incident 15 years ago!
But the FBI pinned it all on the wrong
perpetrator and closed the case.
The wrong perpetrator?
Four years later...
That copycat was captured.
I knew that guy's face!
One of the perps that abducted my father
15 years ago, that face!
The FBI buried my testimony!
Just so they could cover up the fact
that they locked up an innocent man!
Is that your grudge against the FBI?
The censure my father was getting
from everyone in America was intense.
We couldn't possibly stay in
the United States because of it.
So that's why you came to Japan?
And then, back here in Japan...
As I did research on the case
from 15 years ago on the net,
I found a woman
who harbored the same grudge.
Maiko Shirahato, your accomplice?
Yeah, that's right!
Outta the way!
Hold up, darn you!
Dad!
Haibara, what's going on? What's wrong?
Are you all right? Answer me! Haibara?
Haibara?
Haibara?!
The perp escaped. Shin-Minatohama Station.
Darn it!
Hello, Sensei? Where are you?
Yes, I get it. I need to head over to
Shin-Minatohama station, then.
Camel!
On it!
Since I last saw her,
it's like she's become
a completely different person.
Come to think of it, I once asked you
to be her bodyguard, didn't I?
There was.
CONAN EDOGAWA
What's up, little boy?
He's huge, but he runs fast!
He even had a getaway car ready, too!
Soon, the world's first Hyper Linear
will arrive at Shibahama Station.
MASKED YAIBER
Come on, let's go home.
Huh? No way!
The Linear is finally going to come by.
Let's head over to the platform to see it.
What should we do, Professor?
We have no choice...
I think it's impossible
to chase after them now.
Darn it...
Ran! Contact Inspector Megure!
Yup. After this,
can you go help Sensei out?
On the other end of that call,
there are two people
that you call "our allies."
Huh? What are you talking about?
One is the person you call "Sensei."
The other uses a rifle
and is most likely FBI.
It is now 10 minutes before arrival in
Shibahama Station.
We will now begin deceleration.
It's ringing.
Shinichi! Where are you right now?
Dad contacted me and said
he lost sight of the perpetrator
at the Kouhoku Interchange
in Shin-Minatohama...
Shinichi?
You had... two smartphones.
Yup, that's right.
Hello, Sensei?
The current location of the perp is...
Near the Kouhoku Interchange?
If they headed to the Kouhoku
Interchange from Shin-Minatohama,
perhaps they are
heading to Tokyo via Daisan Keihin?
Or, they're making it look that way,
and are headed to the coast
on the southbound lanes.
For what purpose?
I think it's better not to overly
complicate your thoughts.
For instance, beyond Kouhoku Interchange,
an industrial
road stretches east and west.
If you head west on that, you arrive at
Kamoike Bridge over the Tsurumi River.
And right around now, you should be
able to see the Linear from the bridge.
Don't tell me—
You mean the perp is
going after the Linear!?
Most likely.
-Jodie!
-Got it, Shu!
-Camel!
-On it!
-Hurry to the Kamoike Bridge!
-Roger that!
Conan-kun, can you show me
both of your smartphones?
I want to know who my allies are.
Or is there a reason why
you can't show them to me, maybe?
This will end it all.
What was that sound?
It can't be... We're accelerating?
I thought they decelerated because
we're almost at Shibahama station.
No way...
Are they still trying to kill Alan-san?
By using this "Japanese Bullet"!
Found it.
That black German car.
Looks like that's the one.
-Be careful.
-Okay!
What is that car, an unmarked cop?
Following it!
At this speed, the wheels won't
extend from the Linear!
It's going to collide into the station!
Can't you do anything about this?
You're asking me?
The Hyper Linear has a manual
operation room, doesn't it?
Contact the control room and
get some instructions from them!
Those two might be able to do something.
Oh no, amateur children
wouldn't be able to operate—
Hurry up and just do it!
No good. The brakes aren't working!
Darn it!
Haibara, we can't decelerate even if
we follow the control room's directions!
-Why no speed change?
-The cause is unknown!
The control room is saying
they can't operate it either!
Why not?
Some unknown program is
running on its own,
and they can't seem to stop it!
Meaning another system that the perp
programmed beforehand?
If it keeps going like this,
what will happen?
We stopped all electrical currents
on the tracks,
so there will be no force
to keep the Hyper Linear afloat.
It will gradually slow down,
and in the end...
make a belly landing.
A belly landing!
It'll be all right.
As long as the train's superconductive
magnets are working, they won't derail.
Even if it slows down, it will make the
belly landing while maintaining balance.
Who in the world are you?
Just a grade school student
who's crazy about science.
What's that!?
Camel, you have the skills
to pull this off, right?
Yes. It's just that
I'm not familiar with this area.
Don't worry, I'll do the navi—
No, we'll take care of that.
You've memorized all the maps
of that area. Right?
Yeah. I see a path to victory.
First, divide the offensive
into two fronts.
Jodie, Camel, you two need to split up.
Akai-kun... We've split up.
What do we do next, Shu?
-One will maintain the status quo.
-Camel, keep on its tail.
The other will standby in the location
I'm about to name.
What? Standby?
An unorthodox form of a shogi puzzle.
With this tactic,
it's five moves to checkmate.
You're late! Let's go after the perp!
Actually, we have intel that the Hyper
Linear is running out of control.
In five minutes, it will crash into
Shibahama Station!
What did you say!?
Everyone, please stay calm as you proceed!
Everyone, are you with me?
-We're fine, Professor!
-We can't get a look at the Hyper Linear?
What in the world has happened?
-What?
-An earthquake?
The tremors are so violent,
I can't stay on my feet!
The door...
-Why are they losing balance like that?
-Yes, I understand.
When I asked the control room,
they said that there's liquid helium
leaking from the Hyper Linear!
No way! A quench?
I'm not getting any response anymore!
Edogawa-kun! The superconductive magnet on
the Hyper Linear has quenched!
I see, so that explosive sound earlier...
At this rate, they're going to derail...
What can we do?
Oh, look there!
That looks dangerous!
Conan-kun...
Ran!
Ran?
Edogawa-kun, that room you were just in,
that was the sub-control room.
You might be able to
get the brakes to work
from the main operation room
in the front car!
-Got it. Thank you!
-Hurry!
First move. The offensive heads to
Yanishi Station near Hachiouji Highway.
Camel, head to Yanishi station.
What? If I do that, I'll distance myself
from the perp's car!
-Just do it. Yanishi Station.
-Okay!
So that guy wasn't
chasing after me or anything?
Second move.
The defensive continues down
Highway 109 towards Umenoki.
It's up ahead!
That's it, huh?
What should I do? At this rate...
INCOMING CALL
SONOKO
Sonoko?
Ran!? Shibahama Station is in an uproar
over the runaway Hyper Linear!
They've canceled
the WSG Opening Ceremony, too,
and there's an evacuation advisory
in effect!
No way...
You're on the Shinkansen now,
so you're okay, right?
I'm okay, but there's something else—
I called Ai-chan but couldn't get through,
so we've been worried!
Ai-chan is with me, but Con—
Oh! Haibara's right there?
Then tell her, please tell her!
It was unbelievable! A new Yaiber...
...came down from the sky in a parachute!
It was awesome!
P-Parachute...
-A parachute!
No good. The brakes over here
seem to be broken as well.
Looks like we're done for.
Wait, Conan-kun, what are you doing?
I was just wondering what this was.
Edogawa-kun, can you hear me?
He's here!
Darn it!
What is that car?
I'll pursue him right away!
Third move.
The offensive will head to Loop Highway 2.
Loop Highway 2, Camel.
B-But I finally caught up to
the perp again!
-Camel!
-H-Heading over.
I've completely lost sight
of the perp's car.
No, he's right here.
Got that, Conan-kun!?
Even if you can't operate the brakes,
there's a better chance
that everything else will work!
Yeah, got it.
When you're done setting up,
hit the blue button!
Yeah, thank you!
Well now, I guess we'll head to
the rear operation seat just like Ran-kun
and company have suggested.
-I'll stay here.
-What?
It's better to split up, just in case.
If you hear my voice from there,
think of it as the sign to go ahead!
Roger that!
Huh!? How!?
How is this happening!?
Fourth move. The defensive will
change lanes and head to a side street.
You bastard!
No good! I can't follow him. I've failed!
You haven't. Fifth move.
The offensive at Shin-Minatohama Bridge...
Checkmate!
Jodie!
He really showed up...
Freeze!
Who the hell is that!?
It should only be a little further
to the very front...
All right, once I've tied this end,
my work here will be done!
Now, all I have to do is to wait for
Conan-kun's signal.
I'm here...
Now, Sera!
That's a huge parachute!
Go!
Conan-kun!
Darn it! No way am I gonna die here!
No way...
The monitor is back online!
Out of my way!
Not there...
Sorry, do you mind?
Conan-kun!
Sera-chan!
Both of you, please answer me!
Edogawa-kun!
H-Haibara...
Ran-neechan...
Don't worry... We're all okay!
For the perpetrator to come right to us...
What kind of magic did you use, Shu?
It wasn't magic. It was shogi.
Shogi?
Yeah.
On my side is the best brain in Japan...
No, in the whole world.
FBI!
I want to see both hands behind your head!
On the ground, face down!
FBI, you say?
FBI...
The same FBI that buried my testimony!?
Fifteen years ago,
I'm positive that I witnessed it.
But you guys took Ishihara...
Makoto Ishihara was a mistaken
perpetrator that you guys cooked up!
The perp from 15 years ago was
Makoto Ishihara.
-Don't lie to me!
-It's not a lie!
The copycat perp we arrested four years
later admitted as much!
That copycat was the man you witnessed.
And that man was Makoto Ishihara's
accomplice in the case 15 years ago.
Lies!
Then when you arrested him 11 years ago,
why didn't you ever name him
as one of the perps
from the case 15 years ago?
Because of the plea bargain.
He gave up the name of his accomplice
for his past crimes
in exchange for immunity.
That man was granted immunity from
prosecution in the case 15 years ago.
That's why we never named him.
Maiko Shirahato's father, Makoto Ishihara,
was an accomplice of the perp
who kidnapped your father.
So you aligned yourself
with such a person,
and became a criminal
seeking needless revenge.
That's not true! It's all because of
your selfish plea bargains!
Selfish plea bargains?
That's right!
The filthy tactics
you guys are so good at!
Because of that, I—
How do you think you and your family
were able to escape
the censure of the entire United States?
How do you think you were able to pull off
this foolish charade of a revenge tragedy?
What are you saying?
It was all because you changed your name
under the witness protection program.
Am I right?
That's also one of
the "filthy plea bargains" you speak of.
-And the perp?
-Over here.
Let's leave the rest
to the Japanese police.
Conan-kun! Sera-kun!
Both of you! How badly are you injured?
I only have minor scratches!
Same here!
I'm glad you're safe and sound.
Who is that?
That's the perp, Maiko Shirahato.
I'll hand her off to you.
I see, so she survived.
I have to hand it to you, Shu.
That was a difficult snipe
using the Linear's tracks...
And you avoided her vital organs
so precisely.
No one but you could have—
No, it wasn't me...
It was all thanks to that little boy.
Right when everyone's cellphones rang?
Yeah. That was when
I sent a text to Alan-san.
"If worse comes to worst, I want to
position the perp's shoulder
at that spot, so please help me out."
Higher! Go back! More!
So that's why...
Not killing even the most
dangerous of criminals.
That seems to be that little boy's policy.
Not how we at the FBI operate.
Man, that was my favorite jacket, too.
Oh, well.
Let's go back.
Sure!
Yeah.
I'll leave it parked there,
so come and get it.
Roger that.
And...
There are two passengers aboard.
So please get them home
as courteously as you can.
My bad, Camel.
Hey, FBI kid.
I don't know who the hell you are,
but because of you,
a VIP of my country nearly came to harm.
Luckily, this time around
nothing serious happened,
so I'll let you off the hook.
But know that there will be no next time.
"Kid," huh?
What?!
You don't remember?
Even after that promise we made?
Well... I was drunk, so I remember nothing...
I-Impossible...
I do remember that I puked inside
someone's car, though...
What is this smell?
Hey, you guys!
I hear you're up next!
-Right!
DETECTIVE CONAN
COMING GW 2022