Goodbye, my friend.
Hiroki!
I wonder if I'll be able to
fly like Noah's Ark, too...
Hiroki!
I'm high school detective Kudo Shinichi.
I went with old friend and classmate,
Mori Ran, to an amusement park
where I witnessed a suspicious
deal with a man dressed in black!
I was so absorbed with watching the deal
that I didn't notice a second
man sneak up from behind me!
He forced me to take a poison,
and when I woke up...
...my body had shrunk!
If they learned Kudo Shinichi was alive,
they might go after me again,
putting all the people around me in danger!
Per Dr. Agasa's advice,
I decided to conceal my identity.
When Ran asked my name,
I quickly answered, "Edogawa Conan."
To get information on the men,
I wound up living with Ran
and her detective father.
- Ready, everyone?!
- Yeah!
Aside from the Doc, the only one
in this group who knows who I am...
...is Haibara Ai.
She originally worked with the men in black,
but to escape from them, she took
the same poison I did and shrank!
My parents are so childish
and always love to pull pranks.
My dad is the world-renowned
mystery novelist, Kudo Yusaku.
There's no mystery fan who hasn't
heard of his Night Baron series!
My mom, Kudo Yukiko,
was a legendary idol actress
who retired at 20 to get married.
She's just an annoying
middle-aged lady now, though.
For the time being, I'm a
"distant relative" of theirs.
I haven't seen them in a while.
I wonder how my mom and dad are...
I'm just dandy!
Even when I'm small, my mind
remains that of a sharp detective!
There is always only one truth!
We're here at Beika City Hall,
at the spectacular premier
of the sensory simulation game
developed by Japanese game makers
in cooperation with the Schindler Company!
Oh! President Schindler of the
Schindler Company has just arrived!
Now, then! According to the
documents distributed to the media,
players enter capsules called "Cocoons"
and interact with virtual reality
worlds while in a hypnotic state
in this conglomeration of
cutting-edge technology!
This game is said to have five types
of stages the player can enjoy.
Just what kind of virtual
worlds they are will be revealed
when the children at today's
sneak preview play for the first time!
Fifty boys and girls at
or below high school age
will be the first in Japan
to experience the Cocoons!
Geez! This is a bit much for some
stupid video game presentation!
I hear they had to put up with corporate
spies and stuff like that just to get this far!
Yeah, the Cocoons are supposed
to change video games forever!
What're those?!
Oh! Are those the Cocoons?!
I want to play in one...
I'm afraid you can't.
We were invited to the party,
but we weren't chosen to try the Cocoons.
But being able to experience actual,
historical events inside the games
is somewhat interesting.
Yeah, huh?!
It'd be like taking a journey
as a real-life time traveler!
C'mon, it's just a game!
Oh, yeah. I forgot you're bad
at computer games, Conan-kun.
Yeah, I can't believe
you're still stuck in Final Quest!
Yeah, you're surprisingly
not good with your fingers!
Shut up.
So many people, so much booze!
Dad! Important police officials are here!
Don't drink too much!
Yeah, yeah! You can't get
sick from expensive liquor!
That's not what she means...
This is all-you-can-eat, right?!
Yes, probably...
Lucky! Lucky!
Those kids are the lucky ones.
Seeing them receive their
game badges really hits home
that they're lucky they
get to play today's game...
The assistant commissioner's grandson,
a financial big shot's grandson,
the son of a politician from the ruling party...
Japan's future will be on these guys'
shoulders in the next generation!
- I'm sensing jealous looks!
- Yeah!
It's as if Japan's horrid hereditary system
has been concentrated in this one location.
It's due to that very system that
society repeats its transgressions.
Haibara-san, I don't
understand what you're saying.
Hey, now! Talk more like a kid!
Politicians' sons will become politicians.
CEOs' sons will become CEOs.
Japan will never change like this.
They said tons of that junk
on the news yesterday, anyway!
How was that?
Scary...
Ran!
Sonoko!
Hi, boys and girls!
Sonoko-san! Don't tell me that badge is-!
Oh, this?
Are you a chosen one too, Sonoko?!
The Suzuki zaibatsu helped fund
the game development, you see.
She's so lucky...
I wish I had one...
Forget it.
It's not your place.
Were you guys even invited here to begin with?
How rude! I invited these guests myself!
Why, hello there,
daughter of the Suzuki zaibatsu.
Listen. People's lives are set in
stone the moment they're born.
That's right! Like they say,
"Sharp clothes choose the wearer!"
Those not chosen can simply
look on enviously from the outside.
These creeps really tick me off.
Dad! Give them a talking to!
Listen, lads. You mustn't take life lightly.
Even the most stable of lives have pitfalls.
Someday, when you've become adults,
you will understand this.
Like having your wife run out on you?
I know all about you, old man.
You got the nickname "Sleeping Kogoro"
because your wife left you
while you were asleep, right?
You little brats!
He wasn't asleep!
My mom left him while he was in the bathroom!
Right?!
That's not helping him.
Hey! Let's have a little game!
When I think about kids like them
following their parents' footsteps
and becoming Japan's leaders,
I feel no hope for the future.
Agreed.
I got it! I got it!
- What's the big idea?!
- Give it back!
You're bothering the other guests.
If you're going to play, take it outside.
And just who are you?
My name is Kashimura. I was in
charge of the Cocoons' development.
It was the money from my dad's
bank that let you finish the game!
Have your mothers and fathers not
taught you about public morality
or how to talk to your superiors?
You think you're so great!
No more money for you!
Do you not know who we are, old man?
Defy us, and you might find
yourself without a job tomorrow.
In that case, perhaps I'll throw
you out of here before then.
Let's go.
What a cool man!
Unlike someone else I know.
Shinichi-kun should be here, too.
I'm sure you'd like to have
some family time with him.
Doc, please keep my relation to him a secret.
Yes, I know.
Ladies and gentlemen!
Please turn your attention to the stage!
Kudo Yusaku-sensei has
just arrived from America!
He kindly provided many ideas
used to create the Cocoon games!
We finally made it back.
You were working with Dad, huh?
I wondered why you were gone for a month.
I helped out with some
of the final programming.
What about my mom?
She hasn't been in Japan for a while,
so she's having a class reunion.
Here. A souvenir for you.
A game participation badge?
I appreciate it, but I can't play it on my own.
I think you'd really love it.
It's still a secret...
...but the game takes place 100 years ago,
in 19th-century London.
London 100 years ago?!
I see Dad still loves that
setting as much as ever...
Like father, like son.
Huh? I can't see a thing...
Sorry.
Geez! Don't move around in the darkness!
Introducing the next generation
gaming machine, the Cocoon!
This capsule controls the five senses,
and places players in a realistic world
where everything from touch
to pain to smell are experienced!
As it electrically acts upon
the central nervous system,
there is no physical damage to the body.
It's no fun just looking...
Yeah, games are for playing...
Oh! You're all here!
In that case, I'll give you a
riddle to pass the boredom!
Eh?!
Not another of the Doc's horrible pun riddles!
Should we run for it?
I'm sure he tried hard
thinking it up! Let's hear him out!
Mr. A, an employee of this game company,
became captivated with
the Cocoon game during work.
What did the company
president do after seeing Mr. A?
Did he 1: award him for finishing the game;
2: fire him for playing games during work;
or 3: leave him as-is, since he was
sleeping soundly in the Cocoon.
Number 3! He let him sleep!
Why's that?
Because the Cocoon looks like a cradle!
Bzzz!
I say it's Number 1, the award!
That gets a "bzzzz" too!
Then it's Number 2? How come?
I take it you know, Ai-kun?
Could you explain it for them?
I'm wearing light clothing today.
Edogawa-kun can do it.
Eh?
Sounds like you have a request.
"Cocoon" refers to the insect cocoons.
Kaiko create cocoons. [Silkworms]
And kaiko is another way to say "fire."
Brr!
I'm gonna get something warm to drink...
- I'll come with you...
- Me too...
Huh? Is the air conditioning
on too high for them?
These bronze statues are quite magnificent!
I hear they're Mr. Schindler's
favorites from his collection!
Oh? He must really like them
to bring them all the way here!
Perhaps he shares the fighting
spirit that flows from such statues.
- Uh oh!
- Hideki!
Quit playing ball inside.
Okay...
I guess we screwed up, huh?
It's nothin'. They're all cheap statues.
Are you serious?
They'd never put anything that expensive here.
Yeah, that's true!
Kashimura Tadaaki, the man in
charge of the Cocoon's development,
was a partner in crime of mine in college,
so I was able to rekindle our old
friendship through this latest job.
Thank you!
This has been Shimizu of TMS!
Where might I find Kashimura?
I'd like to see him.
Right! I'll find him right away!
Kudo-sensei! Could I have your autograph?!
Me too!
I'm relieved to see you're well.
Likewise.
"Kashimura's Room"
I must return to the conference soon.
Let's make this quick.
How much will you sell Hiroki's
"DNA Search Program" for?
I do not intend to extort you.
I simply want you to
atone for what you've done!
Hiroki learned the secret about you
that can ruin the Schindler Empire.
But the artificial brain couldn't
be completed without Hiroki's help.
You forced Hiroki to work harder to complete it.
Having been mentally run ragged,
he believed you would kill him
the instant he finished the brain.
That's why he let the Noah's Ark,
practically his electronic double,
escape over the phone lines
and threw himself over the roof
of that apartment building.
Some time after that,
the DNA Search Program
file snuck onto my computer.
It was the doing of Noah's Ark,
acting out Hiroki's will.
It seemed to me like
the scream of Hiroki's soul.
I will atone.
I will reveal everything to the public,
and accept whatever judgment I'm given.
But, before that, could I
see this DNA Search Program
that Noah's Ark supposedly sent you?
Very well.
This phantom of London has truly
transcended time, to the modern-
My name is Noah's Ark.
Sir? Kudo-sensei would like to see you.
Sir?
Pardon the intrusion, sir.
Sir! What happened?! Sir!
Now what're they gonna do?
Now, please enjoy this live performance
from our special guest today, Okino Yoko-san!
What?! Yoko-chan's here, too?!
Those front row seats are mine!
Chiba-kun, seal all exits.
Understood!
Attention, all units on standby!
Many important people
seem to be in attendance.
Yes. The assistant commissioner,
financial big-wigs,
and even several legislative officials.
Sounds like we'll have to be especially careful.
Tadah!
Whoa!
Golden Yaiba Cards!
They're limited edition!
I want one!
We'll trade them for your
game badges, if you want!
But we wanna play the game, too...
You can always play the
Cocoons some other day,
but this might be your only
chance to get a Golden Yaiba Card!
What do we do?
Haibara! We got some!
Here! There's one for you, too!
Oh! How impressive!
I guess it could make for a
decent conversation piece.
Excuse me! Please let me through!
Eh?! Kashimura is?!
- Please take me there!
- Right!
Now, then! Let us move to the Cocoon hall!
I don't see Dad anywhere. Where did he go?
Inspector!
Oh! Mori-kun! You're here, too?
I saw police cars from the balcony
after my tipsiness wore off, so...!
Wasn't he in charge of
the Cocoons' development?
One stab to the heart.
The weapon was taken from the scene.
The blood was wiped off...
Was the weapon something important?
Or would it identify the killer if left behind?
But why would the head of development
work here in the basement?
He said he couldn't concentrate
where people constantly come and go.
There's blood on the R, T, and J!
Umm, one thing does puzzle me...
All the files on the hard
drive have been destroyed!
Files?
Sabotage by a rival company?!
Wouldn't it be too late?
After all, the Cocoons are already complete!
When did you get in here?!
Say, isn't that a dying message on the keyboard?
What?!
There's blood on the keys!
He must've pressed them as he was dying!
R, T, and J...
If it was JR and JT... Trains and cigarettes?
RTJ... TJR... TRJ... JTR...
JTR?!
London, 100 years ago?
It couldn't be!
Isn't that Conan-kun?
Eh?
Why is Conan-kun in line to play the game?
Here you are!
You can take it, you know!
You're concerned about him,
aren't you? As his guardian.
But what about you?
It's fine! I don't care
about this stuff in the least!
Upsy-daisy!
All 50 participants in place.
Brain Gear in place.
Closing capsule lids.
Accessing host hardware.
Entering block code.
Connecting couplers.
Adjusting coordinate axes.
Point correction complete. Locked on.
Activating Fade-In System.
Power set complete.
Start the game!
It has to be in this game!
The key to solving this murder case!
Kashimura!
I hear you and Kashimura-san go way back.
Can you think of anyone who
might hold a grudge against him?
Is that bespectacled boy not with you?
Huh? Oh, Conan?
He was just here,
but he turned pale after seeing
the dying message on the keyboard...
Dying message?
JTR!
What?! You don't think
Conan-kun used my souvenir to...?!
Let's go, Doc!
H-Hold on, Yusaku-kun!
What do those three letters mean?!
JTR. Those are the initials of
a certain character in the game.
It's the name Kashimura and I
used to refer to Jack the Ripper.
J-Jack the Ripper?!
Yes. The real-life murderer
who lived in 19th-century London.
A psychotic killer who
murdered five women with a knife
and terrorized London to its core.
The London Police were never able to catch him,
and his serial murder cases went unsolved.
From Kashimura's dying message,
Conan-kun likely surmised
that there is a clue about
our killer inside the game!
President Schindler, this is
Inspector Megure, of the Metro Police.
Police? Why are you here?
I must ask that you stop the game for now.
Stop? Don't be ridiculous.
Sir! The system is malfunctioning!
What?!
I've lost control of it!
Pardon me!
What the-?!
Ran! You're doing it too?!
My name is Noah's Ark.
The game can't be stopped now.
I have seized control of the
sensory simulation Cocoon game.
W-What is "Noah's Ark"?
An artificial brain that matures five
years for each normal year, right?
Yes.
Hiroki, the boy I cherished like a
real son, finished it two years ago.
So it's the same age as Hiroki now...
Noah's Ark! Why have you seized
control of the children's game?!
My goal is to reset the nation of Japan.
What?
Conan-kun!
R-Ran-neechan! Why are you here?
Because I was worried about you!
- Conan-kun!
- Yo!
You guys, too?!
It was tough getting here!
After all you said, you still
wanted to play the game, huh?
I-I guess.
Still, for being in a hypnotic state,
it certainly doesn't feel like it...
It's like a dream,
being able to do whatever we want!
It's just the opposite.
Our sight, sound, smell, taste, touch...
It's all controlled by the computer now.
Now then, Cocoon pioneers!
The game's about to begin!
My name is Noah's Ark. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you!
I'm going to show previews
of each of the five stages
so you can choose a world you'd like to play in.
But I must warn you,
this is no ordinary video game.
In this game, your lives are at stake!
Our lives?
If everyone loses the game, you'll be
unable to return to the real world.
So you have to play seriously.
But if even one person
reaches the goal, you all win,
and everyone, including
those who got a "game over,"
will wake up in the real world again.
These are the rules I decided on.
Do you understand them?
What does that mean?
If everyone gets a "game over,"
I'll send out a special EM
signal to destroy your brains.
In other words, this is a match to
see if Japan should be reset or not.
What do you mean by "resetting Japan"?!
I know you can't hear voices
from people in the real world,
but I'm going to answer a
question an adult just asked.
As I look at you, I realize
the sons of corrupt politicians will
grow up to be corrupt politicians,
and the sons of money-grubbing
doctors will grow up to be the same.
To fix Japan, that link needs to be cut.
I've heard enough! What right do
you have to toy with people's lives?!
I have no right.
Just as the adults had no right
to toy with Hiroki-kun's life.
Well, the children are waiting,
so let's start the game!
The first stage is "Vikings."
You'll become Vikings, sail the seven seas,
and use determination and bravery
to take on numerous adventures.
The second stage is the "Paris-Dakar Rally."
You'll compete with world-famous drivers
in an intense race to the finish line.
The third stage is the "Colosseum."
You'll obtain powerful weapons and armor
and test your might in the Roman Empire.
You'll defeat challenging
gladiators and move on.
The fourth is "Solomon's Treasures."
You'll become treasure hunters.
You'll search for the treasures of
Solomon, hidden all over the world.
And the fifth is "Old Time London."
Here, you'll enjoy a horror-like suspense story.
London, 1888.
You will catch Jack the Ripper,
the real-life serial murderer
whose incidents were never solved.
It sounds like there really
might be something here...
A clue about the person who
murdered Kashimura-san...
Are we really gonna die if
we all get a "game over"?
Why does it have to be us?
It's not like I asked to
be my father's daughter...
I don't think I can stay alive...
Someone stay alive! Get me out of here!
Cheer up, everyone!
Don't lose before you even start!
Yeah! Only one of us has to reach the goal!
Choose whichever stage you
think you're most likely to survive!
Guess we got no choice.
Moroboshi-kun! Which stage?!
Whatever.
"Solomon's Treasures"
"Paris-Dakar Rally"
"Old Time London"
We're stuck with you?
You'd better not slow us down!
That's our line!
Now, now! No fighting!
There are assist characters in each stage.
You can rely on them.
Now let the game begin!
Okay! Let's go!
Well, Doc?!
Immense energy is indeed
stored inside each Cocoon.
More than enough to
destroy the brains of 50 people.
I've had enough! I'm taking my son and leaving!
I believe I'll do the same!
- S-Sir!
- Out of my way!
No! Stop them!
Are you all right?!
No one may disrupt the game.
That was a light shock just now,
but I won't hold back next time!
Damn it! I can't believe this guy!
Still, President Schindler.
Why is the artificial brain
Hiroki-kun built running amok like this?
I-I'm not...
Allow me to answer.
The reason Hiroki-kun left
his father in the first place
to live with his mother in America
was because of the barriers in
the Japanese education system.
Hold it, Hiroki!
I said you could rest
because of your frail health,
but I didn't say you could
play on your computer!
In the eyes of Japan's strict,
anti-individuality educational system,
Hiroki-kun was nothing more
than a creepy computer geek.
And it's not just the education system.
The very nation itself
attempts to ignore individuality.
Hiroki-kun decided to
develop an artificial brain
because of the bitter
experiences he had gone through.
In short, since Hiroki-kun committed suicide
before he could find a way to "reset" Japan,
the artificial, ever-maturing brain,
Noah's Ark, while on the run,
must have taken up the cause in
his place and discovered a way:
this game presentation, where
Japan's future leaders would gather.
The idea being that Japan can be
changed by destroying its society,
in which children simply need to
follow tracks laid by their parents.
How do you know all that, Kudo-sensei?!
The truth is, Kashimura and I were
client and detective this past year.
D-Detective?!
What did he hire you to do?
To reinvestigate Hiroki-kun's suicide.
You're saying he was murdered?
That it wasn't a suicide?
No. In those circumstances,
it probably was a suicide.
But Kashimura asked me to look
into what drove him to suicide.
How were Kashimura-san
and Hiroki-kun related?
Kashimura was Hiroki-kun's father.
Isn't that right?
Kashimura felt deeply
responsible for being separated
from his young son and allowing
him to die in that manner.
Conan-kun and the others
are about to enter Whitechapel!
W-W-We go in here?
Let's go!
Please hurry up!
What's the big idea?!
That's what you get for being slow!
This is London, the foggy city?
It's more creepy than romantic...
The air seems dirty, too...
And it smells.
London's fog isn't just clean,
condensed moisture vapor.
It's fog mixed with smoke and
soot from burnt coal and oil...
Smog, in other words.
Eh?! Smog existed even in these times?
Jack the Ripper!
H-Hey! Conan!
Stop!
Oh, no, you don't!
Oww! Oww!
Are you okay, Conan-kun?
Y-Yeah.
I guess Dr. Agasa's inventions
don't work in the game world.
Yeah. This antenna goes up,
but these glasses and this watch
are otherwise ordinary now...
What is he saying?
It sounds like English...
Please change it to Japanese!
Right!
Huh? What's going on?!
Another victim! That makes three now!
Oh! It's in Japanese now!
It's almost like the real world!
What we see, what we hear,
the chill in the air... it's all real!
The pain in my foot was real, too.
Alright, move aside!
Step back, please!
Hey! Contact Inspector Lestrade at once!
Right!
Inspector Lestrade?!
Doc! Can we communicate with them?!
I'll give it a try.
If you helped oversee this game,
then you know how they can complete it, right?
Yes. If I can just communicate with them,
I can tell them what to do.
Then we can't lose! This stage will be a cinch!
But, if Noah's Ark is
anticipating far ahead, then...
Doc! I leave the rest to you!
I'm going to the scene!
Got it!
Sheesh. We're supposed to catch this guy?
Where do we even start?
I guess all we can do is wait until morning.
I'm cold...
Put this on.
- Oh! Are you sure?!
- Yeah.
I'm warm!
Haibara-san! Here you are!
- Oh! Thank you!
- My pleasure!
Put this on!
But what about you?
I'm fine! I'm sensitive to heat!
Thanks!
Can you hear me, Conan-kun? It's me, Agasa!
We hear you, Doc!
Listen closely! If you get hurt or
caught by the police in that stage,
the game is over for you!
Right now, you're in the
Whitechapel district on the East End.
There's an assist character...
...until...
What happened?
What happened, Doc?! We can't hear you!
Grab on!
Conan! You can do it!
That was close!
It seems you still don't understand.
The game is entirely in my control.
There's no use in trying to outfox me.
I'll allow you to hear them, though.
Enjoy the sounds of the children's suffering!
What a screwed-up computer this is!
The doc's voice is gone now...
It seems Noah's Ark has cut
our line of communication.
Then how do we find this assist character?!
That policeman told us just now!
He said, "Contact Inspector Lestrade!"
Wait, you mean the
Inspector Lestrade from that story?!
But he was just a character in one
of Conan Doyle's mystery novels!
This game might be a mix of reality and fiction.
Then, is our assist character...?
Yeah. He's gotta be here. Sherlock Holmes!
Really?!
We're unstoppable with Holmes on our side!
This stage is as good as beat!
Let's hurry to Baker Street!
That's it. If you can just meet with Holmes...
But it's quite a long way from
Whitechapel to Baker Street...
Hey. Doesn't that clock seem weird?
It went backwards!
Oh! It did it again!
From 50 minutes to 49 minutes?
And then to 48?
I get it! That's the number of kids in the game!
It went back two minutes...
Which means two people in
another stage are out of the game...
Yasuhiro!
Two down in the Viking stage!
Tomoyuki!
M-Mineko!
Two more in the Colosseum stage!
Faster! Lose the game faster!
If the children discover who
Jack the Ripper is, I'm done for.
Three down in the Solomon stage!
That leaves 43...
Wait.
I hear there was another victim
in a back alley by Mitre Street.
Two in one hour. That's four now.
The world's a horrible place...
This is scary.
We came to a terrible time period.
The turn of the century is said
to have been London's finest era
in the history of the British Empire,
but in actuality, there was a
disparaging gap between rich and poor,
crime was rampant, and the
people's hearts were unruly.
Come to think of it,
Shinichi told me about that.
He said if Sherlock Holmes
was the light of the era,
Jack the Ripper was the dark shadow.
Then let's hurry to the light of the era!
We're almost to Baker Street!
♪ Beware Jack the Ripper... ♪
♪ He's waiting for you
on the streets at night... ♪
♪ What should you do if
you don't want to die? ♪
♪ You need to get covered in blood, too... ♪
What could that mean?
Kill before being killed, I'd say.
Covered in blood?
There's a metal detector at the
entrance to the presentation hall...
How did the killer bring the murder weapon in?
It's nothin'. They're all cheap statues.
Are you serious?
They'd never put anything that expensive here.
221-B. This is it.
This is where the Sherlock Holmes lives?
It's a lodging house he and Dr. Watson rent!
At this late hour? Who might you be?
U-Umm, my name is Mori Ran.
We'd like to see Holmes-san...
Holmes-san and Dr. Watson
are gone on a business trip.
Business trip?
Yes. In a place called
Dartmoor, out in the country.
I'm sorry to ask, but what day is today?
September 30th.
September 30th? Dartmoor?
Oh, yeah! The Hound of the Baskervilles case!
That's right! Neither of
them is in London right now!
C'mon, Doc...
What's going on?!
I'm sorry to ask, but could I
see the surveillance footage
from before and after the incident?
Of course.
Yes?
What's wrong?
It seems we underestimated Noah's Ark.
Neither Holmes nor Watson was on Baker Street.
So he did anticipate us...
There was also a strange accordion
player I don't remember creating.
Things are becoming difficult.
Hey! What sort of story did
you come up with, Yusaku-kun?!
The players work with Sherlock Holmes
to discover Jack the Ripper's identity.
The murderer turns out to be an
aristocrat with a terminal illness.
I've prepared an even better ending for you!
Damn you! Once the kids win,
I'm throwing you into the garbage!
Good luck, Shinichi.
Oh, you're the ones who
helped Holmes-san two weeks ago!
Come inside! I'll make you some warm milk tea!
She seems to think we're someone else.
Oh, yeah! She thinks we're
the Baker Street Irregulars!
Who are they?
They're the street urchins Holmes hired!
They were tough kids who'd
sneak into places adults couldn't go
and gather information for him!
Oh! So they're like the predecessors
of our Junior Detective League!
Pretty much!
Looks like they've managed to get inside.
- Wow!
- It's just like on TV!
It's so moving!
Shinichi will be so jealous
when he hears about this!
He looks just like Shinichi...
Oh, my! You look just like Holmes-san!
He's always sitting like that, deep in thought!
Oh! He was just mimicking Holmes!
Please make yourselves at
home while I prepare the tea!
Thank you!
Hey! Doesn't this look like someone?!
Oh! It's Dr. Agasa, but with hair!
This must be Holmes and Dr. Watson!
Dad and the doc are totally playing around...
Hey. We don't have time to sit around.
But, Moroboshi-kun. What should we do?
I'm sure Glasses knows.
Given how Holmes is, he must
have a big file on Jack the Ripper.
Then let's split up and look for it!
Right! I'll look over here!
How're we supposed to find it?
This is all English...
Let's see....
"Initial Investigation for Crime"...
Whoa! I'm a genius!
I can read English!
Me too!
It seems the players are
programmed to be able to read English.
Bah. Then I wanna stay
inside the game forever...
Don't be stupid, Genta-kun!
At this rate, we're going
to lose the game and die!
I-I'm just joking!
What a filthy ball...
I-Is this...?!
Hey! Emori! This is a 100 year-old soccer ball!
Oh! It is?!
Eh?!
I found it! Is this it?!
"An Analysis of Jack the Ripper."
The most recent previous
incident... was September 8th!
"The second victim was
Honey Charleston, age 41, single.
Her body was found in the barren
lot adjoining St. Mary's Church
in the Whitechapel district.
Two rings of different sizes
were also found at the scene."
Rings of different sizes?
"Given that Jack the Ripper
has terrorized London to its core
and brought about
unprecedented social anxiety,
I am certain he is connected to
Professor Moriarty, architect of evil."
Professor Moriarty?!
Even he's in the game?!
So?! Who's he?!
Don't keep it to yourselves!
He's Holmes' arch-nemesis.
They say he controls
London's criminal underworld
and wields great influence over all of Europe.
He's the Napoleon of the criminal world!
But Professor Moriarty
usually only pulls the strings;
he almost never shows himself.
How are we supposed to find him?
If he won't show himself, we'll
find someone connected to him...
...Colonel Sebastian Moran!
Oh, yeah! Colonel Moran,
the professor's right-hand man!
But how do we find the colonel?
I'm sure that's-
According to Holmes' notes, his
base is the Trump Club downtown.
He's the second most
dangerous person in London,
so we need to be careful meeting him!
Conan-kun, how do you know so much?
Oh, uhh, Shinichi-niichan was
always talking about this stuff!
Oh! I should've guessed!
But that mystery nerd's blabbing
actually turned out to be useful here!
You don't have to call it "blabbing..."
Whoa! A real gun!
Put it back, Genta!
B-But we're meeting a scary guy, right?
Weapons you don't know how to use are useless
and only cause trouble!
Leave it!
Y-You're scarier...
Alright! Let's go before it gets too late!
Hey! Moroboshi!
Gotta be able to protect myself.
30 people left...
It's gone down a lot...
I would guess members of our
group will soon be falling out, too.
Don't say unlucky stuff like that!
Toru!
Emi!
Takuya!
Okay. Wait here, everyone.
I'm going to check things
out from the back door.
- Be careful!
- Yeah.
One card.
I'll take two.
It's Colonel Moran!
That monkey!
Well, Glasses?
W-What are you doing here?!
We can't let you hog all the credit!
Straight!
So sorry.
Flush.
- What?!
- Tonight's my lucky night!
Damn it!
Moran's awesome at poker...
He's cheating.
- What?!
- You can tell?!
That monkey is telling the colonel
what hand the other guy has.
It's been trained:
The right hand for hearts and spades,
the left for diamonds and clubs.
And then it eats the number
and color indicated on the cards.
The 3 of Spades would be three
black berries with the right hand.
That's cheap.
Huh? What's with that seat?
And why is that there?
Cheater!
This Moran creep is a cheater!
You'd best watch your mouth, boy!
Or do you have proof I'm cheating?!
Of course!
You're good friends with
that monkey, aren't you?
What?!
It looked at his cards, and
when it was a 3 of Spades,
it ate three black berries with its right hand,
and for the 5 of Diamonds,
it ate five red berries with the left.
Moran! You cheated me!
It's your fault for falling for it.
What?!
Whoops.
You can save your squabble for later.
Where is Professor Moriarty?
Boy! Where did you hear his name?!
Stop!
Catch those brats!
You damn kid!
Are you all right, Conan-kun?!
Yeah...
We're here to help, Conan!
Bottom's up!
This is bad! We're all in here!
Look out, Conan-kun!
Kikukawa-kun!
Hey! Hang in there!
They got me. Now you and I are even.
Hey!
Kikukawa...
Seiichiro!
Ayumi-chan! Are you all right?!
Thank you, Mitsuhiko-kun!
It was nothing!
M-Mitsuhiko-kun!
Ayumi-chan, it appears we're out of the game.
Conan-kun! Make sure you
bring us back to life, okay?!
Ayumi! Mitsuhiko!
Not good! At this rate, we're
all going to get a "game over"!
"S.H."
Sherlock Holmes!
Conan! Look out!
Genta!
Game over, huh...
Conan, make sure you
catch Jack the Ripper, okay?
Playtime is over!
I was going to capture you
and find out who you work for,
but that doesn't seem to be necessary anymore!
Because this gun belongs to Holmes!
Damn! Now what?! What do we do?!
The thing that man is holding... It's...
...the wine that was at that seat!
Now I see! That's what it was for!
Now, who goes first?
Boy!
Shoot me and the wine bottle breaks!
Hmph! What's that supposed to mean?!
The empty seat at the card table!
The specially-decorated chair,
and the glass and wine set
out for a certain visitor...
Using that as a hint,
I can deduce that said visitor
can only be Professor Moriarty!
So sorry, but your deduction is wrong!
Then shoot!
If you don't care if the professor's
wine bottle shatters, that is.
B-Boy...
Conan-kun...
Moriarty-sama says he wishes to see you.
Professor Moriarty does?!
He waits in his carriage. Please follow me.
P-Please wait!
Do you intend to defy Moriarty-sama?
I have brought them, sir.
Well done.
Now then, boy. May I have that wine?
Here.
This scent...
You are indeed Holmes' pupils,
if you're able to fight on
even terms with Colonel Moran.
So, you have business with me?
Say, mister. You're Professor Moriarty?
None other.
Oh, I see. You're testing us.
What do you mean?
You can drop the act!
You're not Professor Moriarty, mister!
W-What are you saying, Conan-kun?!
After all, the real
Professor Moriarty is right here!
- Eh?! He is?!
- Are you serious?!
You used ventriloquism to
speak for him, didn't you?
To think you saw through all
of that... How could you tell?
Just now, Colonel Moran said,
"Please wait!" to you.
Oh, right! Colonel Moran only
speaks politely to Professor Moriarty!
Y-Yeah!
Is that all?
One other thing. I heard Professor
Moriarty was a fanciful old man
who uses natural herbal cologne!
Oh? And you smelled that
when you gave him the wine?
Marvelously done. It's almost as
if I'm looking at a mini-Holmes.
Incidentally, what business
do you have with me?
You unleashed Jack the Ripper on the city
to change London into a town of terror, right?
That's not too far off the mark.
Jack the Ripper was a vagabond boy
I found in the poor part of town.
Abandoned by his mother,
he wandered the streets...
But I realized his talent the
moment I laid eyes on him.
His talent as a criminal, that is.
I raised him to be a
first-class professional killer.
Why is he murdering innocent women?!
Jack the Ripper became
more of a homicidal maniac
than I had ever imagined.
This string of murders is his own crazed doing.
If you're trying to get rid of
Jack the Ripper, I'll lend you my help.
Help?!
Jack the Ripper has indeed begun to run wild,
but he should still obey
my instructions to murder.
You simply need to beat him to his target.
How?!
I will place a message for him in
the ads of tomorrow's Sunday Times.
Who are you going to order him to kill?!
You will find out in tomorrow's paper.
Hey! Can we trust this old man?!
Let's give it a shot.
I pray for your luck.
Be careful at the Reichenbach
Falls three years from now!
What's "Reichenbach"?
Three years from now,
Professor Moriarty and Holmes fight
at the Reichenbach waterfall in Switzerland.
They both fall to the bottom.
Holmes miraculously survives,
but Professor Moriarty supposedly dies.
Why did I warn him like that?
I guess maybe I like that
villain as much as Holmes does!
That reminds me of that time...
I'm pretty fond of Professor Moriarty myself!
Well, as a fictional character, anyway.
Their confrontation at
Holmes' house was mind-blowing!
I just love one of the things Holmes said then!
Can you guess what it is?
No.
It was...
What did Shinichi say?
We were on a date, but he
kept talking about Holmes,
so I tuned him out...
Hey, Conan-kun.
Yeah?
No. Never mind!
I'm so dumb. Of course Conan-kun wouldn't know.
H-Hey, Glasses.
Sorry. It's our fault that four
people got a "game over..."
There's no point in worrying about what's done.
I'd say the fact you've started to
think that way is a good step forward.
Yes! Let's work hard to figure out
what to do next, for everyone!
So this is where the second victim,
Honey Charleston, was found...
"The parent-child bazaar will be held again
on the second Saturday in October."
The second Saturday? As I recall,
Honey Charleston was killed...
...Saturday, September 8th!
Sorry I made you wait!
What took so long? Where were you?!
Just exploring the city!
You sure are carefree on
the day of our showdown.
Jack the Ripper has struck again!
There were two victims this time!
I'll take a paper!
Sure thing!
Oh no! I don't have English money!
Here you are! 80 yen!
Oh. How convenient!
Here it is!
"Clean the opera house tonight. From M to J."
"From M to J..."
"From Moriarty to Jack the Ripper."
Clean the opera house? Is that his instruction?
It could mean, "Murder an
actor who appears on stage..."
Here it is!
"The Triumphant Performance Returns!
Prima Donna in the Imperial
Opera of Warsaw... Irene Adler!"
Professor Moriarty!
You're the most despicable of villains!
Who's Irene Adler?
It's said she's the only
woman Holmes ever loved!
Which means he made
Holmes' beloved the murder target.
12:06 a.m.!
- That means...
- ...all the other stages failed.
Which means everyone's
lives are in the hands of us six!
Hold it!
This area is for authorized persons only!
W-We're acquaintances of Irene Adler-san!
We wanted to offer our
encouragement before she goes on!
Oh! You know her?
Yes! Where is her waiting room?
In that case, it's the room at
the very end, with the poster.
This must be it. I wonder
what she's like. I'm so excited!
Given that my dad made her
character and that she's Holmes' love...
Come in!
Pardon the intrusion!
Shinichi's mom!
I knew it.
How rude! I'm still single!
Well, to be more precise,
I'm single now that I've divorced!
A bouquet from Holmes-san!
Oh! Thank you!
Where might Holmes-san be?
He was looking forward
to tonight's performance,
but he had to leave on a case and can't come...
Oh. That's too bad.
Please call tonight's show off!
Eh?
Holmes-san's arch-nemesis, Professor Moriarty,
has sent someone to kill you!
Why me?
Because he wants to see
Holmes-san's sadness when he loses you!
I'd like to see it, too! I wonder
how sad he would be for me...
You don't care about being
Jack the Ripper's fifth victim?!
You're going to protect me, right?
In Holmes-san's place?
Nothing scares this lady...
Yeah. This is exactly how she is...
Die beautifully, Irene Adler...
Where is he lurking?
- What the-?!
- What's happening?!
Look out!
- Emori!
- Takizawa-kun!
- Emori! You're-!
- You too, Takizawa-kun!
Game over, huh...
This sucks...
Thank you. You saved my life!
This is the first time
anyone's ever thanked me...
I-It feels nice!
Moroboshi! I leave the rest to you now!
You can count on me!
- A-Akira!
- Shinya!
That leaves only four,
including Ran-kun and Conan-kun...
That's it, Jack the Ripper!
Turn this world into Hell!
Hurry! Out the back!
Hurry, Haibara! That way!
Conan! Look out!
Haibara! Are you okay?!
You can't give up, Kudo-kun!
If there aren't any assist characters,
then you're our Holmes...
You're skilled enough for that.
There's no case Holmes can't solve, right?
Ai-kun...
Quickly! Quickly! Evacuate!
Stay behind me!
- Stop!
- Bye! You're safe with police around!
Little boy! I still don't know your name!
I'm Edogawa Conan!
I have the same name as your guys' birth father!
Conan?
I won't let him get away!
How are things going?
Conan-kun's group encountered Jack the Ripper.
They're chasing him right now.
Charing Cross Station!
Conan-kun! Get on first!
This is the worst possible scenario!
How so?
The last train out of Charing Cross Station...
It's the most dangerous climax of all!
Eh?! Jack the Ripper is
disguised as a passenger?!
Please gather all the
passengers onto a single car!
R-Right!
Mr. Conductor! Could you...
Okay, everyone! Please raise both hands!
I want to make sure no
one is carrying a weapon.
I look forward to hearing you figure this out...
I'll now explain what was
written in Mr. Holmes' notes.
Honey Charleston, the second
victim of Jack the Ripper,
was married in the town of Windsor,
but as she was full of dreams,
she abandoned her husband and son
10 years ago to come to London.
These two rings were at the scene
of Honey Charleston's murder.
One is Honey's.
The other has the same design,
but didn't fit any of Honey's fingers.
So Mr. Holmes believes the following.
He thinks these two rings may
have signified the parent-child bond
between the victim,
Honey Charleston, and Jack the Ripper.
Meaning that little ring is Jack the Ripper's?!
Yes.
She put a ring of the same design
on her son's finger before leaving.
Does that mean Jack the Ripper
murdered his own mother?
Yeah. According to his notes,
the day she was murdered, Sept. 8,
was the second Saturday of September,
the day of the monthly bazaar
at the Whitechapel church,
in which parents and children
bring things they made together!
And he thinks Jack the Ripper knew that!
Eh? He even wrote that down?
In other words, Jack the Ripper
wanted to participate with his mother,
so he left their two rings?
Yeah! Apparently!
Then his motive was his grudge
for his mother abandoning him...
What did I do?! I'm not the only one drunk!
But his bloodlust was almost out of love...
How sad...
Apparently, he chose an unrelated
woman for his first victim
to throw the police off.
But what about the third and fourth victims?
Professor Moriarty's special education
molded Jack the Ripper
into a psychotic criminal,
so even after clearing his
grudge with his mother,
he couldn't help but continue
targeting women like her.
Who is it, then?!
If he kept the ring on since childhood,
what do you think would happen to his finger?
Out of his 10 fingers, that
one finger should be thin!
Jack the Ripper is you!
But that's a woman!
Her right ring finger is thin!
- I got this!
- No! Ran-neechan!
Damn! A smokescreen!
- Open the window!
- Yeah!
T-They're gone!
H-Hey!
All the passengers have
disappeared! What's going on?!
Now, then. Let us identify
who Kashimura's killer was, too.
Eh?! You know who did it?!
The issue is how the killer
prepared the murder weapon.
A metal detector is installed at
the entrance to the Beika City Hall.
So it's mostly likely that the weapon
was already inside the building.
But where could someone get that?!
The bronze statues in the party hall.
One of them is holding a dagger.
The party hall was filled with guests!
Someone would've seen the killer taking it!
It was removed when the lights went out.
It had all been scheduled.
But wouldn't someone have
noticed the dagger was missing?!
A fake was left in its place.
Made of cardboard and foil or something.
Then, is the dagger the statue's holding now
the one used in the murder?!
Yes. I just had a luminol test and
fingerprint check done on the dagger.
Blood the same type as Kashimura's was found.
Fingerprints were also found on the handle.
Your fingerprints, President Schindler.
Of course they were. The bronze
statues were brought from my home.
This is surveillance footage of the party hall
from before and after the incident.
Luckily, surveillance cameras
are placed all around the hall,
so I could record from every angle.
The ball that young Moroboshi
kicks hits the bronze statue
and knocks the dagger off.
He picks it up and returns
it to the statue's hand.
I see! If the dagger shown here is the real one,
the boy's fingerprints should be on it too!
But only President Schindler's
fingerprints were found!
I simply touched it after the boy,
so his fingerprints are gone.
Kudo-sensei! I found it!
There was a fake dagger
made of cardboard and foil
in the basement garbage collection!
Any fingerprints?!
It's just like you said, Kudo-sensei!
It has young Moroboshi's and
President Schindler's fingerprints!
The only fingerprints that can be
on the fake dagger besides the boy's
are the killer's.
This is a set-up! I'm issuing a
protest to the Japanese government!
Besides, I have no reason to
murder Kashimura in the first place!
They're not here! All that's
up ahead is the engine room!
The driver is gone!
- We gotta stop the train!
- Yeah!
The brake's been destroyed!
We're speeding up!
Hey! Shouldn't we find that girl?!
Ran! Where are you?! Where did you go?!
Wait!
There they are!
Ran-neechan!
No! Stay away!
I've tied myself to this girl.
If I fall, she comes with me!
So, how will you fight?!
Dammit!
I hear the statue's dagger
has been passed down
from generation to generation in
the same Schindler family bloodline.
Indeed it has.
Why did you use it as the murder weapon?
Assuming you didn't have to
use it as the murder weapon...
What is it you want, Jack the Ripper?!
"Want"?!
Now that you've killed your mother
and cleared your long grudge,
what is it you want?!
To continue living!
I'm going to let the vicious
blood flowing through my veins
survive to the next
generation aboard Noah's boat!
I take it this is your motive
for murdering Kashimura.
Almost as if he had been aboard
Noah's ark, Jack the Ripper's blood
survived to the present day.
You're Jack the Ripper's descendant.
- J-Jack the Ripper's...
- ...descendant?!
Hiroki-kun most likely learned
this using his DNA Search Program.
If the world learned that the czar
of the IT industry is the descendant
of the psychotic serial murderer
from 100 years ago, he'd be done for.
So, to keep things quiet,
you drove Hiroki-kun to suicide...
...and murdered Kashimura!
It was when Hiroki came to see my collection.
This is a gold wine cup used
by the Egyptian king Khufu.
Next is Ganjin Wajo's scriptures
and the manuscript of Edogawa
Rampo's "The Psychological Test."
Amazing!
What about this dagger?
Oh, uhh...
It's supposedly the weapon
used by Jack the Ripper,
a deranged serial killer from a century ago...
There's no telling if it really is, though.
For an experiment, Hiroki gathered
all the data around him he could
and entered it into the computer.
And the DNA of Honey Charleston,
taken from the dagger,
matched with yours.
You were afraid.
Afraid that Hiroki-kun would eventually learn
that Jack the Ripper was Honey's son.
Afraid it was only a matter
of time until he learned
you're Jack the Ripper's descendant!
I was scared of the terrifying
blood that flows inside me!
Who cares about your
"murderer's blood" or the public eye?!
Why didn't you try to fight it?!
Just as Conan-kun and his friends are now.
Thomas Schindler.
You're under arrest for the
murder of Kashimura Tadaaki-san.
You'll never catch me if
you're always running away!
10 minutes until the final stop.
What do you think will happen
to this train, without its driver?
Though it seems you'll be long
dead before the next station.
Conan-kun! Behind you!
End of the line, boy.
Conan-kun!
Let Glasses go!
Moroboshi-kun!
Are you all right?!
I-I think!
Now then! Where shall I start carving from?
What do I do?!
Shinichi! What would you do in this situation?!
I just love one of the things Holmes said then!
Can you guess what it is?
No.
It was, "If you precise destruction,
in the public interest,
I am willing to accept death."
Glasses!
The Reichenbach Falls, Conan-kun!
Don't tell me you're...?!
I'm sorry I couldn't be with you to the end.
Stop! Ran!
Damn it!
Crap!
Conan-kun, I believe in you.
Ran!
Glasses! We have to stop the train!
Hey! We have to stop the
train so we can survive!
We still haven't won the game!
Get up, Glasses!
The lives of 48 people are in our hands!
Are you just going to trample all over them?!
Don't be stupid! I don't wanna give up, either!
Think about it. The train
is continually speeding up.
It's moving at approximately 100 kph.
It'll reach the station in under five minutes.
The only way to save everyone
was to cut the links connecting the
engine car and the passenger cars!
With just us two, those
links won't budge at all!
Yes. I was specifically counting
on Ran to help us with it...
That's why Noah's Ark got
rid of all the passengers.
It's all over. There's nothing more we can do.
It's all over, Dad...
Hey, now! Don't give up!
You gotta survive and let Ran live again!
Shinichi...
You still aren't covered in blood yet.
You're still alive.
Are you giving up already?
Just when you have both hands
on the string to unravel the truth?
The crimson red string of murder
has been mixed in the bundle
of colorless threads of life.
Isn't disentangling that what we do?
Holmes!
Wasn't he in Dartmoor? Could it be a bug?
What does he mean?
Jack the Ripper is dead, so why do
we have to get covered in blood?
This is it! This is what he meant!
The freight car!
Hey! Wait! What do you mean?!
Just come on!
Use that axe to break the red wine barrels!
Hurry!
- Dive under on my signal!
- Okay!
Now!
Have they said anything?!
Still nothing!
Oh wonderful, merciful Conan-sama!
I beg of you to save Ran!
I see. "Covered in blood."
It meant, "Use the red
wine to cushion the shock."
Thanks for the help, Holmes. No... Dad.
You're awake, Glasses? It seems you win.
"You"?
So I was right.
I'm glad I trusted you. Thank you.
You're welcome... Noah's Ark.
Or should I call you Hiroki-kun?
You borrowed Moroboshi-kun's
data to join in the game too, right?
When did you realize it?
There's no need to worry. I've cut
communication with the real world.
The first thing that
seemed strange was Big Ben!
You noticed it before the clock hand moved.
You did that to tell us what
Big Ben's time indicated, right?
Next was the soccer ball.
You called it a filthy ball
and threw it behind you.
A 100 year-old soccer ball
would've been very interesting
to any soccer-loving boy.
I'm guessing that
although you put us in danger,
you had faith we would overcome it as a group.
You didn't need to kill the next
few generations to reset Japan.
You hoped that overcoming
obstacles, the game's in this case,
without our parents' help would
help us mature on our own, right?
You weren't able to be heartless!
Holmes' appearance at the end is the proof.
You let the assist character
show up right at the climax!
I borrowed Moroboshi-kun's
body and snuck into the game
because I wanted to play
with friends at least once.
I was always busy working, you see...
I'm sorry for frightening you.
But I had so much fun!
And, I was jealous of how you and your dad
can communicate with your
minds even if you're far apart!
Your dad avenged my dad's killer. Thank you!
It's time to say goodbye.
Your mind will continue to
live on in Noah's Ark, right?
As long as computers like me are alive,
grownups will use them for bad things.
It was still too soon to
create an artificial brain...
Okay! Return to your world!
After you wake up, I want
everyone to at least know this:
Real life isn't easy, like it is in video games.
I hope you see your father!
Goodbye...
...Kudo Shinichi.
Ran!
Looks like he did it!
- Thank goodness you're all right!
- That was fun!
- I worked hard!
- Good job!
Conan-kun! Thanks for bringing us back to life!
We worked pretty hard, didn't we?!
That was an incredible adventure!
Reality really is much better...
What happened?
I knew you'd be able to do it, Conan-kun!
But, Ran-neechan! Jumping off
with him was way too crazy!
But I remembered one of
Shinichi's favorite Holmes quotes!
Eh? Was it when Holmes and
Prof. Moriarty met for the first time?
Huh? How do you know that?
No, uhh, I heard from Shinichi-niichan, too...
Oh! But all his blabbing
really proved useful for once!
Stop calling it "blabbing"!
- Ran!
- Dad!
Thank goodness you're okay!
That took a bit long for you.
Yeah. I quite enjoyed it.
Noah's Ark is ending his own life.
Rest in peace, Hiroki-kun.
♪ What kind of things happened today? ♪
♪ May tomorrow end without incident, too ♪
♪ No matter what does or doesn't happen, ♪
♪ those skies will continue moving ahead ♪
♪ From the moment I met you ♪
♪ every single second has been very precious ♪
♪ These everlasting feelings will continue forever ♪
♪ Even on the most uneasy of days ♪
♪ you can't show your faintheartedness to anyone ♪
♪ Amid a tangled mess of strings, ♪
♪ we're connected ♪
♪ I remember your warmth ♪
♪ That straightforward voice
still rings in my ears, too ♪
♪ These everlasting feelings will continue forever ♪
♪ Rescue that bond that's about
to be buried in the darkness ♪
♪ From the moment I met you ♪
♪ I've felt that I'm not alone anymore ♪
♪ I can keep on living now ♪
♪ with the feeling that you're
watching from somewhere ♪
♪ These everlasting feelings will continue forever ♪
♪ These never-ending
feelings will reach out forever ♪
Gotta practice up so I won't
get made fun of anymore...