Emergency, emergency,
Superintendent 503 to MPD
Superintendent 503, over.
Have currently located a suspicious car
that looks to be that of
the armed robber on the run,
going from Sotobori Avenue to Miyuki Avenue!
MPD, roger!
Would like report on
license plate number of suspicious car
as well as description of suspects
and clothing, over.
Superintendent 503, roger.
The car is a black van,
Shinjuku 500
Sa-3255.
The description of the suspects are...
Lupin and Fujiko.
Please do not joke around,
Superintendent 503, over.
I'm not joking...
Superintendent 503 to MPD.
Lupin has taken a left
on Chuo Ave. from Miyuki Ave.
Superintendent 503, please cut it out, over.
I'm telling you, I'm not joking!
H, Hey, Officer Sato,
drive more carefully, will you...
Don't you have to contact headquarters?
Oh, yes ma'am!
503 to MPD.
The suspect has made a right turn
on Harumi Ave...
I can't forgive them for using Lupin's mask
to carry out a robbery!!
Welcome, good evening...
It'll be 1,237 yen.
Car up ahead! Pull over!!
I wonder if it's a crime...
Awesome...
Car up ahead, pull over!!
I repeat!
You can't get away!
Pull over to the shoulder of the road!!
How dare they!
An eye for an eye... A tooth for a tooth!
O, Officer Sato?!
They're going to get away...
Hang on tight!
Huh?
Officer Sato, w, what do you plan to...
You'll bite your tongue if you keep talking!
O, Officer Sato?
Quiet!!
H, Hey, Officer Sato?
Officer Takagi! Contact headquarters.
Yes, ma'am!
I tell you, really...
Officer Sato!
Back-up squads and the ambulance
will be here immediately!
They asked for it.
That's what he gets
for using the mask of my first love.
Huh?
Y, Your first love?
Please go check on Fujiko.
Yes, ma'am.
Get a hold of yourself!
The ambulance will be here any minute!
Officer Sato...
It seems that Fujiko is just passed out
and not hurt that badly.
Right...
But, why did you commit a robbery
wearing such a mask like Lupin's?
K... Koumi... Island...
Koumi Island?
Oh... so you wanted money
to go play on that island...
N... No...
No, he says...
What is there on that island?
Jo... Jolly...
Jolly Roger...
Jolly Roger？
Have you heard of it?
No...
（Koumi Island）
Hurry, hurry, mommy!!
Let's go!
Wait for me!
Um, how do you use this?
I'll show you.
Teacher! What kind of fish are there here?
May I have your name
you made reservations under...?
Kogoro Mouri, a detective...
two adults, two students
and five children...
One moment please...
There's a weekly puzzle
on Nichiuri Newspaper,
the really difficult one...
If there are no winners,
the prize money accumulates
and it finally reached 300,00 yen!!
And, just who do you think
won that 300,000 yen?
I, I don't know...
Oh, don't tell me that you...
Right...!!
I mean I'm a detective after all,
so I can solve puzzles hands down...
Well, I'm the one who solved it, though...
With 300,000 yen,
we can relax in Paris... right?
The city of Paris is just the place for me...
But, I thought about it,
thinking whether it's okay for me alone
to enjoy myself.
I thought that I may as well
share the enjoyment with all of them...
That's what I thought... Kind, aren't I?
W, Well...
And, what's our room number?
I'm sorry,
but it seems
we don't have reservations for you...
No kidding?
Hey, hey.
H, Hey, hold it!
I made reservations for sure!!
But your name
is not listed on the reservation list...
You mean we have to sleep outside...?
This island is a subtropical island
so I'm sure there are poison insects too...
We shouldn't have come...
Well, I guess something can be worked out,
because this is not a foreign country
where we don't
understand the language or anything...
You're so adult, Ai...
Well, it's for sure she's not childish...
Since the front desk said
they'd call the tourist bureau
there should be nothing to worry about...
I'm sorry.
But the person on the phone definitely said,
I've taken your reservation!
I understand sir, but...
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
Mr. Kogoro Mouri?
The detective...
I'm sorry,
I'm Iwanaga from the tourist section.
(Iwagana supervisor of tourism)
You see, since this month,
the number of tourists
have increased suddenly,
that all the hotels are full
and everyone here is jumping for joy.
However, I've somehow
found a lodge for all of you.
I mean, after all,
you're the famous Detective Kogoro Mouri...
Please come along with me...
I'll show you the way...
Strange...
What did he do?
Who are they?
Treasure hunters, maybe?
Treasure hunters?
Do they pull out hair?
Tweezers Hunters, right?
No, Genta.
They are people who go around the world
to look for treasure.
How did you figure out
that they're treasure hunters...?
Yeah... take a good look at them...
Those people were all sun tanned but,
other than wrist up and neck up,
they weren't all that tanned were they?
That's proof that
they're always wearing wet suits...
Besides, the color of their hair
was also washed out by seawater...
But,
they could also just be plain divers...
That's true too, but...
with a poster like that around
It's hard not to think so, right?
Koumi Island
Underground palace
Ancient treasures hidden underneath
-Treasure!
Yeah...
I'm sure they have their hopes high...
about treasure that is
lying asleep in the sea...
（Detective Conan Jolly
Roger in the Deep Azure）
I'm a high school detective
called Shinichi Kudo...
Huh? I don't look
like I'm in high school?
She is Ran Mouri,
my childhood friend
and classmate...
When I was dating Ran
at an amusement park,
I happened to witness an evil deal that
some suspicious men in black were making.
I was so absorbed in watching
the deal that I wasn't aware of
the footsteps of another member
that was approaching from behind me.
That man made me drink a drug,
and when I got up...
My body was shrunk!!
If they find out that
Shinichi Kudo is alive,
they would come
after my life again,
and would put the
people in danger too.
Thanks to Dr. Agasa's advice,
I decided to hide
my true identity,
and when Ran asked
me for my name,
I answered,
Conan Edogawa.
In order to get
information on them,
I decided to free-load
at Ran's house
being that her father was
running a detective agency...
This man here is Ran's father,
Detective Kogoro Mouri.
He is the so-called
"Sleeping Kogoro.
The reason is...
this...
She is Sonoko Suzuki...
She is Ran's classmate
and a carefree girl that doesn't seem
to be a least bit of a rich little lady
that she actually is.
This man here is Dr. Agasa.
He makes unique devices
for me one after the other
for I who have shrunk.
She is Ai Haibara...
Her real name is Shiho Miyano...
She was originally a
member of the men in black.
When she fled from
the organization,
She drank the same drug
that I was forced to drink
and her body shrunk.
I still can't make out the
identity of the men in black, but,
I'll settle things out with them
in the name of being
a famed detective!!
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult.
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan!!
There is only one
and only truth!!
I wonder why
treasure hunters are here...?
Oh, treasure was found
about two weeks ago.
Huh? Treasure was found?
You mean the silver
dish that was found
in the underground
palace was genuine?
It seems to have been so...
An underwater palace...
See, there's a little
uninhabited island there, right?
That's Yorioya Island.
About 200 meters east of
it at the bottom of the sea
is a building that is
made of gigantic rocks...
About 10 years ago, the
talk of an ancient ruins
being sunk near Koumi Island began.
A lot of scientists came to check on it
but whether it is man-made
（Underwater Palace）
or whether it is a work of nature
is not known yet.
Yorioya Island seems to have been
further out above the ocean
but seems to have sunk due to
the earthquake that occurred 300 years ago,
and ended up shaped like it is now...
Sunk because of an earthquake?
Was there a landslide or something?
Yeah, it seems that the area has
what is called a methane hydrate layer,
and due to the shock of the earthquake
it broke apart all together
causing a landslide.
This seems to be the view
held by most people.
Hey, Conan...
What's that thing
metan handmade all about...?
Methane hydrate...
In a low temperature
high pressure environment,
a water molecule takes in the methane
and creates a cage structure.
It is also known as "Burning ice."
Burning ice... ？
Cage structure... ？
Sounds Greek to me...
to put it simple, it's like this.
You've made a castle using
playing cards before, haven't you?
In other words, you make a castle
with water molecules
and then put methane
in each of the rooms of the castle.
So, when the temperature rises
or the pressure goes down
it becomes unstable,
is squashed and marsh gas is emitted.
I see!
That's why if an island were on it,
it would lose support
and a landslide occurs!
Well, a very simplified explanation
would be so.
I saw it on TV some time ago!!
Oh... is that so...
Nuts...
Excuse me Mr. Mima,
I'm Iwanaga from the tourist bureau.
Mr. Mima, are you in?
Mr. Mima... Hey...
This place is really different
from the hotel we just left a while ago...
Yes...
I'm sorry, he doesn't seem to be in...
I did phone him though...
Cut out the noise!
Oh, Mr. Mima,
(Mr. Mima owner of Koumi hotel)
here're Mr. Mouri and his group
that I phoned you about a while ago.
It'll be 5,000 yen
for one night with two meals...
If you don't like it you can go on elsewhere.
H, Hey, M, Mr. Mima?!
What an inhospitable guy.
I'm sorry. He's a good person,
but a bit eccentric...
Uh... who will be participating
in the treasure hunt game?
We will...!!
Same here!
And you ladies are going diving, right?
Yes.
If you're going right away,
I'll take you there by car.
Will you please.
What will you two do?
The treasure hunt game
is pretty interesting, you know.
I'll just take it easy,
so don't worry about me.
Mr. Mouri,
will you join the treasure hunt...?
No...
Please tell me where I can go
to drink some local liquor
at a pub owned by a beautiful lady.
Ran Mouri and Sonoko Suzuki...
You want to rent the full set, right?
-Yes!
Kimiko!
Yes.
(Yamaguchi Kimiko)
Are these wet suits okay?
I think you'll both fit into a medium.
Yes.
Just fine.
I'm glad...
since we don't have
too many wet suits available...
Don't worry about it.
Nice wet suits.
You think so?
Sorry to bother you...
Hey, wait you guys,
clean up before you leave!!
We'll come again...
They're treasure hunters, right?
Are they diving with us?
No,
all we did was rent them the air compressor.
People like them have increased lately
that we're finding it tough to handle too.
Oh, because the silver dish was found...
On top of that,
the story that Anne who escaped from prison
hid the treasure on this island
is going around too.
Who's Anne?
This...
270 years ago, in the Edo period
between the years of 1716 to 1735,
there is a story that an underwater palace
emerged above water.
This story is based on the fact
that a sword called the Cutlass
and a pistol
were found in the underwater castle.
From the initials
carved in the Cutlass and pistol,
it is thought that the weapons were owned by,
two women pirates who existed around 1730,
called Anne Bonny and Mary Read...
They were on board a pirate ship
lead by Captain Jack Rackam.
Huh? Women pirates?
Yes!
Anne Bonny and Mary Read...
They were crews on board
a pirate ship lead by Captain Jack Rackam.
I hear that when they were
attacked by the English troops,
despite the other male crew
hiding in the hold,
the two women fought gallantly
with their back against each other...
Oh... with their backs against each other...
Yes, they would leave
the enemies behind them
to be taken care of by their partner
and concentrate only on the enemies
who are in front of them.
It's a feat that cannot be carried out
unless you trust each other.
Ran...
I, I have my mind set that you're
the only one I can trust my back to...
S, Sonoko...
So I'd like to say.
But, I know for you, it's Shinichi, right?
I'd never!
Really?
Really!
Anne who escaped
from a prison in the Bahamas,
moved her stronghold to the Pacific,
and while pirating,
waited for Mary to break out of prison,
it is said that the treasure
that the two robbed
are hidden on Koumi Island here.
So, let's all look for the treasure
hid by Anne and Mary!!
I wonder if these are genuine...?
Beats me...
If they're for real, it'll make the news.
I'll bet this is just something
that was made up to advertise this island.
That'll also make the news...
Either way, they'll make the news.
Sorry, sorry.
I'm sorry
to have kept you waiting for so long...
Hey, hey...
Here you go, this is the treasure hunt map...
You start from here,
and find the 5 points that are hidden
on this map, and get it stamped each time.
Then, you solve the mystery.
The first point is there!
Stamp the empty space
on the bottom of the map,
and from the treasure chest next to it
take out the hint card for the next point.
It's a kid's game...
Oh come on, don't say that.
They're all out to get, you know...
10 and 12...
Is this the key that indicates
the whereabouts of the treasure...?
The next point is,
"The sun may set, but a pirate still shines."
What does that mean?
Give it your best shot.
If you figure out where the treasure is
you'll get a special gift!
Is, Is the special gift something to eat?
You'll see when you find the treasure.
Okay, let's go for it!!
We don't know if it's something to eat yet,
you know...
Uh, sir...
Huh, what is it?
Did you think up all these codes?
Well.
sort of...
there are rental bicycles
at the government building next door
so ride them.
It's too tough
searching for the treasure on foot.
Okay!
You're all for it, aren't you, Shinichi...
Okay! All done!
Okay then... Do as Kimiko tells you to
and enjoy safe diving...
Be careful especially of
the South side of the castle.
There are sharp crevices there...
Please don't scare us.
You'll be just fine,
because I'm going to be with you.
That's right.
-We're counting on you.
You're back early,
what's up?
Sharks!
Since the hint said sunset
we came to the west most cape of the island
but... where in the world
is the treasure chest...?
I see! I get it!!
The hint was "the sun may set but,
pirates still shine", right?!
That is none other than...
the surface of the sea!
I see...!
So?
You mean the stamp is on the sea?
Oh, well...
of course not,
Uh, look at that...
I wonder what it is...
Maybe a fish...?
Isn't it an eel?
They wouldn't be in a place like this...
I see...
Hey, Conan...
What do you see?
Did you figure something out?
Do you know why the fish are gathered?
Why...
Were they playing together...?
Maybe they were hungry and eating together?
Right...
And what is it they're eating?
Plankton... maybe?
Right...
Wow...
Whoppers...
What's supposed to be here...?
Watch...
Wow...!
Sea fireflies!
I see!
The sun may set but the pirate still shines
means this, right?
There it is!
"A thin pirate laughs" it says.
Y, You laugh even if you're thin, right?
What's the matter, Ai?
A blood smeared person wearing a wet suit
was carried away just now.
What?!
I don't know if it was Ran or not but...
Oh, Conan?
Conan and I are going to be gone for a while
but continue the treasure hunt, okay?
Ai left too...
Don't worry,
you still got me, right?
Let's find the treasure without them!
Yeah... I guess so...
R, Ran...
Conan...
Ai too...
A, Are you all right?
Yes, we are...
(Mr. Uehira Koumi island policeman)
How is he, Mr. Uehira?
Oh, Kimi-chan.
Were you with him too, Kimi-chan?
No, I was nearby diving with them...
But, it sure surprised me
to see a shark attack a man...
Moreover,
there were three people all together
but only one man was attacked...
Just what do you mean by that?!
Nothing really...
Oh boy... what a bummer...
There hasn't been troubles
with sharks for years and yet...
This is the first time I've seen sharks
in that area to begin with...
Is anything the matter?
It's what Kimiko just said.
Three were diving
yet only one of them
was attacked, bothers me...
Just a coincidence, maybe?
If those guys were professionals,
they should know how to get rid of sharks,
shouldn't they?
Anything?
A vinyl bag...
Fish blood...?
That seems to have been the reason...
Yeah...
The blood of fish was poured into
a thin vinyl bag and sealed slightly.
Then the bag
was inserted between the jacket...
Water pressure increases 1 atmosphere
at a time, every 10 meters...
There is already 1 atmosphere above water so,
diving 10 meters makes it 2 atmospheres...
and 30 meters makes it 4 atmospheres...
If pushed with that much water pressure...
a vinyl bag like this
would open very easily...
Sharks can hear sound from
more than several kilometers away,
and has a sharp sense of smell
that can make out the smell of blood
that is diluted 1 million times...
Homicide...
Yeah...
although it's still attempted homicide.
Hey, glasses kid!!
What are you two whispering about...?
We've got a case, Pops.
What...?!
What didn't you report it?
To me... The great Detective Kogoro Mouri...
Oh...
What a huge mouth...
But, if he was bitten by a shark
isn't this an accident...
rather than a case?
What do you mean by, "Agh"...
What's this!
H, How is he, Doctor?
I've done all I could...
but he was bleeding so badly...
I'm sorry.
Damn!!
Oh my God!! To think that a person's died!!
No, this is not an accident.
Y, You're the famed Detective...
Kogoro Mouri.
Dad...
Mr. Mouri...
Hey, just what do you mean
by it's not an accident!
Someone lured the sharks to you
and made them attack you...
By using fish blood
poured into this vinyl bag
that was hidden in this BC jacket.
By the way,
I hear that you are treasure hunters...
There seems to be a lot behind this case...
Uh, Ran.
Where are the BC jackets usually placed?
Well...
you can't take it back
to the hotel room so...
I guess, they would have the diving shop
keep it for them around here?
So that they can have air put into air tanks
while they're at ti...
(The storage room)
If anything was done to the BC jacket,
it must've been done here...
If it were to be taken
and worked on it would be too risky.
Shinichi,
could I speak with you for a minute...?
What's up, Ai?
Take a look at this.
Since this is the place that seawater
is washed off from the equipment all the time
it seems to be muddy all the time...
Sorry, but will you take a picture
of this place with this,
because I have to go
check on something else...
Oh,
since when did I become your assistant...?
No, you're not my assistant...
but rather, my partner.
Smooth talker...
Okay then, I'm counting on you.
Yes, sir...
Uh, excuse me.
Huh? What is it...?
Is anyone at this shop at night?
Oh, are playing detective or something?
My house is behind here
and Kimiko's apartment is near the harbor
so there's nobody here at night.
Oh...
Besides, there are no thieves on this island,
so we usually don't even lock the shop...
Oh, Kimiko, you closed the shop last night,
didn't you?
Huh? Yes... but why?
Because this little detective
is giving me the third degree...
I see,
you're checking to see of anyone
rigged that BC jacket, right?
I'm the one who closed the shop last night,
as well as opened it this morning but,
I never lock the shop,
so anyone could've snuck in a rigged it.
How was it?
Did you come up with some clue?
No...
Nothing yet...
I hope you find something...
What's up?
What do you mean, what's up?
Just what do you think you're doing, Conan?!
If you don't come,
we can't find the pirate's treasure!
It's about time
you guys solve things on your own!
We can't do this on our own.
Where are you now?
We're heading for the suspended bridge!
Suspended bridge?
It's on the treasure hunt map.
On the treasure hunt map...
Oh I see it.
Hurry up and come then!
Yes, sir.
Hopeless...
Hey, Ai, are you coming?
I pass.
Ha, ha, ha, just as I thought...
Hey, he, what's this.
(Passage prohibited)
There's no road...
Darn it...
Huh?
Are you alone?
Yep. I think that everyone's on
the suspension bridge above.
I want to go there,
but the road is closed...
Oh I'm so sorry...
There was a landslide because of the
earthquake last week and the road closed up.
If you move a little more on ahead
there's a road where you can take a left,
so go there will you?
Okay. Thank you, Mr. Iwanaga.
Be careful. see you.
I will, bye.
Let's forget it. I can't figure it out.
We'll be fine if Conan comes.
We'll manage without Conan.
Let's figure this out on our own.
Huh?
There's a sign
on the other side of the suspended bridge.
Huh?
I wonder what it says...?
Let's go see!
Okay!
I'm starving!
H, Hey, wait for me.
Wait!
Don't move!
W, Why not...
T, This...
(People over 40 kilograms
keep off the bridge)
What is it...
Genta, how much do you weigh?
T, Thirty nine kilos...
No.
I gained a bit and became 45 kilos!
No good.
This bridge
will fall if a person
more than 40 kilos goes across it.
N, No joke!!
Oh... I see!
"A thin pirate laughs."
This probably means to go across the bridge?
Right!
If a thin pirate laughs,
a fat one cries!
H, Help me... Mom!
I found it!
I wonder what it means,"Pirates don't cry."
It's already 4:00,
so I guess we'll continue tomorrow.
Yep... but how should we go back...
True...
With Genta squatting over there,
if we both go back there,
the bridge will go down for sure...
Hey, what're you guys doing?!
Conan!... We found it!
Wow, you guys are pretty good.
The next hint is, "Pirates don't cry."
But if someone more than 40 kilos
gets on the bridge...
it'll probably fall...
Was... it written that way?
Oh no, it said
people over 40 kilos should not cross...
I see,
that's why, "A thin pirate laughs"...
Then it's okay, come on and cross the bridge.
That sign's just a hint.
People who are under 40 kilos
include only women and children.
A code that only they can solve,
could never exist!
Hello there,
Inspector! Hello. But, I don't think
you needed to come all this way, Inspector...
Something was
bothering me a bit so...
In, Inspector!
Thank you for
coming out all this way!
Okay, I'd like you
to start questioning.
R, Roger!!
You're treating us as
if we were suspects...
(Izuyama Taro)
Aren't we more like victims?
If you're victims, why don't
you speak honestly like victims?
Do both of you,
remember seeing these two?
Beats me, I've
never seen them...
These two robbed a supermarket
in Shimbashi last night
and took off with the cash...
They said that you told them to do so...
They said it was for them
to become members of your group...
(Matsumoto Mitsushi)
Beats me...
They're probably lying to get away...
Why you!!
You got proof? Evidence?!
All you've got are their testimonies, right?!
Cool it, okay...
Let's cool head everyone...
Here, have a cold drink.
So... if you have nothing more to say,
I'd like to go back to my room
and get to bed...
So, you really have no idea
who is after you two, do you...
Mr. Matsumoto...?
No, not at all.
See you...
Uh... excuse me...
Will you please give me a match?
I forgot my lighter...
Here...
Thanks...
Thank you very much.
What a waste of time!
Uh... is it okay for me to start drinking,
Inspector...
I'm thirsty...
Go ahead... They don't seem to be involved...
I thought that we would at least
come up with their fingerprints but...
Yes... but even if
we did get their fingerprints,
it would take time for results
to be reached on this island,
whether the forensic officers
were to come here
or be it we send it to them..
Hmm...
By the way, Officer Takagi,
did you smoke cigarettes?
Cough, cough, I, I'm sorry... Cough.
Do you happen to have instant glue? Cough...
I hate to do this when we're eating but,
Dr. Agasa's pun quiz.
Right.
Hey, hey...
Finally...
I thought it was just about time.
In the fish kingdom next to the ruins
at the bottom of the sea,
the evil doings of
the previous king were exposed
and a sea bream became the next king...
Now, who was the previous king?
1. A squid,
2. An octopus,
3. A crab?
Well...?
Hmm...
I got it...
Number 3, the crab...!
Why?
He cut off the head of the one
he didn't like with his pinchers!
Oooh... that's terrible!
Hey, hey.
It's a bit cruel, isn't it...?
I'm sorry...
I think it's an octopus.
Oh, and why is that?
The octopus king tried to take the treasure
of the kingdom all for himself.
Please imagine the looks of an octopus.
You mean monks with shaved heads
always make loads of profit, right?
Exactly.
don't think so.
Then, I think it's number 1, a squid!!
Why...?
Leave it to me!
This time I know it's right.
The King... Oc-to(ok)pus(purse)...
and the squid
squealed,
squealed?
so the previous king was the squid...!
T, That's correct...
I wonder if you can call it a pun...
-Oh... Conan!
This is what you really call
squealing...
It sure is a nice moon...
Yeah...
No offense, but why did you decide
to run an inn, Mr. Mima?
Well, since I live alone,
I could somehow make ends meet
on fishing alone but...
I was asked to do so by the tourist bureau.
It seems that want to increase tourists...
I see...
We could be getting in the way your lives...
This is way better
than the life of a treasure hunter...
Talking of treasure hunter,
does the treasure really exist?
Phooey...
Hyenas don't gather where there's no prey...
Though it may not be the prey
that they're after...
I don't understand it...
Pirates don't cry.
Please think a lot harder, Genta.
Hey, kid.
Is "Pirates don't cry" a hint?
Yes, that's right...
I understand, "Pirates cry"...
"Pirates cry"...?
That could be a hint...
Do you want me to take you there now?
Huh? Are you going out from now?
It's already dark outside,
so I think you should wait till tomorrow...
You can never tell
how the weather's going to be tomorrow...
Are you saying it's going to be bad?
When the south wind blows strongly,
we don't go out fishing...
because the sea will be stormy...
Wisdom that comes from experience!
Then, why don't we all go.
It's good to take a walk after dinner...
Aye...
And, what do you propose to do,
Officer Takagi?
This is uh... called the method,
and the vapor of cyanoacrylate,
which is the substance of this instant glue,
reacts to the fluid that is secreted.
In this way fingerprints can be taken...
All we need to do is now
is wait for some time
until the fingerprints emerge.
Oh...
Since when did you learn
something like that?
Well,
I saw it on a movie I saw some time ago,
and confirmed with Officer Tome
if it could really be done.
Well, I sure hope it works out
as well as it did in the movie...
Is the answer for the hint
pirates don't cry over here?
I don't know about the answer...
But, this is the place
that cries.
Cries... Is it this wind?
It sounds like it's crying.
Oh, yeah really.
We heard it all the way here too, though...
Oh... Of course I know...
The sand here sure has
a large composition of quartz...
The size of the grains is also very small...
I see.
H, Hey, Conan?
Did you figure something out?
Listen carefully.
Wow...
It's crying sand!
I see! That's why, it's "pirates cry"!
The rest is up to you to solve!
I know!
Let's see, it was "Pirates don't cry".
That's it!
Look! It doesn't cry on this side!
That side is where the pirates don't cry.
Just as expected...
Next, it's "The soul of pirates
ascend to the heavens"...
Hmm... I still don't get it...
That tourist bureau section
sure can think things up...
The tourist bureau section chief,
Mr. Iwanaga...
He said that he thought up these codes
by himself, didn't he?
Oh...
Isn't that his job, though?
Doesn't anything ever move you?
Is anything the matter?
What's the matter, Conan?
This is getting to be very interesting!
Conan?
I'm sorry,
but I've got to stop over some place,
so go on home ahead of me, okay!
H, Hey, Conan!
There he goes again...
He really can't work in a group, can he...
Conan...
There...
All we need to do now is get this data
and e-mail it over.
Then, we can get the results right away.
You did it, Officer Takagi!
It's nothing... Ha, ha, ha...
If you want to transfer
to the forensic department,
let me know.
If it's okay with you,
I'll write the letter of recommendation.
N, No... Ha, ha, ha...
Get that over to headquarters ASAP.
Yes, sir!
What're you doing?!
Oh...
I was taking a walk and got lost...
Which way... is Koumi Villa?
That way...
Thank you... Goodnight...
How about it, Officer Takagi,
any word from headquarters...?
Nothing yet.
I see...
What's up?
It, It's the alarm of the tourist bureau...
Which means that something happened
at that tourist bureau?
No, it malfunctions frequently so...
Let's go there anyway, just in case.
Where is it?
It, It's next to the village office...
Please lend me your car!
O, Okay...
I think you'll get word from headquarters
so keep on the look out for it!
Y, Yes, sir...
I tell you,
what's with the chain of cases recently...
Wha! It, It's come...
Uh...
T, This is...
Hurry, get in!
I asked if there were...
any shops run by a beautiful owner...
a pretty hostess...
Ugh... Uuugh...
I'm not even allowed to drink in quiet...
That's why I don't like tourist sites...
I'm going to really get pissed, you know...
cut out the noise!
What's going on?
Hey, hold it!!
Just what do you think you're doing?!
Tourist bureau chief, is this the place
run by a beautiful owner
or what...!!
Who cares,
she's beautiful
if you look at her in the dark...
Take responsibility, will you...!
I'm busy...!
Why...
The exhibition room of the tourist bureau
was broken into...
What?!
Broken into?
Move it!!
Hey, wait?!
Get on, quick!
If you don't get on quickly,
I'm leaving you here!
W, Wait.
Hang on tight! I'm going to rev this thing!!
Hey, wait... Pay your bill...!!
Hey, mister...
What's up?
Oh, Officer, he drank
and ran off without paying the bill.
Arrest him, will you!
Give me a break... another incident...
The exhibition case
was cracked open with a bar...
How daring...
Oh, how about it, Officer Sato...
Yes, just like Conan said, they've been shot.
There are bloodstains left...
I see...
Do you think you can save the site?
That seems quite difficult...
I guess so...
Okay, then come over here
after taking pictures of the site then.
Yes, sir.
The Cutlass and pistol are...
Are they worth any value?
They are treasures that were
taken out of the undersea castle...
Anne Bonny's Cutlass
and Mary Read's pistol...
Now that I'm here,
you've got nothing to worry about.
Mr. Mouri... your face is red...
Oh... well... well...
Since everyone is here...
Kogoro Mouri, you're under arrest!!
Charges are bicycle theft
and drunk driving!
Whaaaat...!!
Hey, hey...
Is, Is that true?!
Yes, sir.
He didn't pay for his drinks at the pub
and moreover, fled on Mr. Iwanaga's bicycle
after stealing it,
the owner of the pub said...
I didn't steal it and flee!!
I had the tourist bureau chief
ride in back of me and brought him here!
Right? Isn't it?
Y, Yes...
Oh, right, Inspector.
The result for matching
of the fingerprints arrived.
O, Oh, really?!
Koji Matsumoto,
is charged for stealing artworks
and excavated goods
from the ruins and museums... the world over,
as well as for murder...
He sure is one hell of a guy, isn't he...?
So, those guys were on
the international wanted list...
Darn, so they are after the treasure
of Anne and Mary after all...?
What do you mean by they're after?
Aren't the pistol and the Cutlass
the only things that were stolen?
Oh, well,
Anne Bonny and Mary Read
were women pirates...
But there is a legend that says that
the two women pirates
who were active some 300 years ago
hid some treasures here on Koumi Island...
You mean the treasures of these people
are really here?
Yes. The Cutlass and pistol that were here
is proof that other treasures exist.
Uh,
Pops didn't you go to a pub
owned by a beautiful woman?
She wasn't any beauty,
just a plain old lady.
Just as I thought...
This smell is...?
Pops, you got something on you...
What's this...
I see...
How do you get off this island?
There's only one regular boat
that leaves in the afternoon,
so the only way out of here
are fishing boats.
Okay, please let word out
to be careful not to get boats stolen.
Y, Yes sir!!
Hey, what about these handcuffs!!
Hey...!!
Uh, Inspector Megure?
Come to think of it, that man called
Matsumoto was giving Ms. Mabuchi,
the owner of the diving shop
money or something.
What?!
Inspector Megure! I just got back.
Good work.
I'm sorry I have to tell you this right now
when you just got back,
but it seems that Matsumoto got in touch
with the owner of the dive shop.
Both of you, head for the dive shop...
We'll go to the hotel Matsumoto's staying at!
-Yes, sir!
In, Inspector... The handcuffs...!
How about it? The weather...
The wind...
The sun is out so I'm sure it'll be fine.
Let's try enlarging it...
The tread pattern is totally different...
It's not this bicycle after all...
Conan.
Oh, Yes?
Conan, it's meal time...!
I'll be right over!
What's the matter?
It's like a GPS...
A GPS?
Why would it be set up on a bicycle?
What the hell is Conan doing anyway!
He'll be here any minute now,
so let's wait just a little more
-See, there he is...
-Sorry to keep you waiting...
You're late, Conan!
I'm starved!
Sorry, sorry...
Huh? Where's Pops?
Well, he said that he had to attend
an investigation conference
and went to the government office.
Now, since everyone is here...
Dig in!!
Let's eat!
I never thought that this would be next!
Yummy!
Give me more!
Uh... when you went to the suspended bridge,
didn't you see Mr. Iwanaga?
Mr. Iwanaga...
Oh, the chief of the tourist bureau...
Yeah...
Nope, we didn't... did we?
No...
We found that place on our own!
I see...
Do you all have enough to eat?!
Yes, we're just fine, thank you.
By the way,
are you planning to dive today too?
No,
I'm too scared
after what happened yesterday...
But, we may not have time tomorrow
so we're thinking of
riding on a boat or something.
I'd advise you not to go out
to see from afternoon...
I'm sure the sea's going to be stormy...
Oh, is that so, after all.
Then, we'd better hurry
and look for the treasure too...
Right,
because we just have one more thing to solve.
Let's give it our best shot, Conan.
Oh...
I... have to stop by some place...
so you guys go on ahead on the hunt.
Then let's just leave the you know who that
just can't seem to work in a group behind,
find the treasure ourselves,
and split it among ourselves!
I agree...!!
It's not on any of the bicycles, after all...
Chief! It's the newest report
on low atmospheric pressure!
What a bummer... A typhoon's on its way...
Please contact the fishing association
and the hotels.
Yes, sir.
What a bummer...
Matsumoto and Izuyama
are not back at the hotel.
There are no traces
that they left the island either,
so they're probably in hiding somewhere...
We know that
at least one of them has been shot,
so he may need to be treated for his wound.
I've checked with the clinic,
but they haven't gone there.
About Mabuchi, owner of the dive shop,
it seems that what Conan witnessed
last night
was the man asking her to get a boat
for the two men to flee from the island.
I'd just like to inform you,
that I don't have the slightest idea where
Matsumoto and his friend are hiding.
Running a dive shop
doesn't bring in that much cash...
That's why I agreed to get ready
what Matsumoto asked for.
I guess I drew an unlucky lottery ticket...
I see...
This cartridge that Officer Takagi retrieved
is something quite old,
so I'm sure it's something
that has been stored away for a long time...
Hmm, as for the rifle,
we're having the Ryoyu Hunting Association
check on it.
Come in...
Excuse me,
I just got a call from
the Ryoyu Hunting Association
saying that the rifle of a member
called Mr. Mineo is missing...
I see.
And, who is this Mr. Mineo?
Yes, he's an old man who lives alone,
and relies on his niece
Chika Mabuchi,
who runs a dive shop for a living.
Please go and listen to what
Mr. Mineo has to say right away.
And please ask Ms. Mabuchi
to come to the station voluntarily...
Yes, sir!!
Please get back the Cutlass and pistol
that were stolen!
Please!
We'll do our best!
I wonder why they went in to steal it now
knowing that we're all here, though...
Yes...
Only Officer Uehira alone
is normally on this island...
so it would've been easier for them
to get off the island too...
They were probably afraid of
taking their time
for fear of their identities being disclosed.
Is any more back up coming from Tokyo?
It seems that
they can't dispatch any choppers or boats
because of the low atmospheric pressure.
We'll have to handle this on our own...
We've got to find Matsumoto and his friend,
and track down the one
who're after their lives...
I found it...
I found it!!
All right...!
The last one was simple, wasn't it?
Yep! "The souls of pirates
ascend to the heavens"
so there's no other place but the lookout!
The stamped letters are the hints.
Go on and find our treasure for us!
The owner's gone
to check the ocean out right now,
so wait a while please.
-Okay...
Thank you for waiting...
I'm sorry...
It's not possible to go out to sea after all.
The waves are too high.
Bummers...
It can't be helped.
Let's go to a quiet place on the beach
and spend time there then.
Good morning, Officer Uehira.
Oh, good morning.
What's with that solemn look...
Is something wrong?
Chinatsu,
would you come with me for a minute?
Inspector Megure
says he want to talk to you...
Excuse me, mister...
Huh? What is it?
I wonder why those hunters
stole the Cutlass and pistol
from the tourist bureau?
If they're treasure hunters
aren't they supposed to be
looking for treasure?
Or did they steal those things
because they're necessary
to find the treasure?
That's why I think they're already
headed for the place where the treasure is.
Would you by chance know where it is, sir?
Why are you asking me?
Didn't you used to be...
a treasure hunter too, sir?
Even if I used to be
a treasure hunter in the past,
that doesn't mean that I'd know
where the treasure is, would it?
You mentioned yesterday that...
Talking of treasure hunters,
does the treasure really exist?
Phooey... Hyenas don't gather
where there's no prey...
Though it may not be the prey
that they're after...
"It may not be the prey
that they're after... "
means that you know what is hidden, right?
Come...
I wonder why the numbers
are divided into red and blue...
Scissors.
Oh, okay.
There are two problems here...
The reason why the numbers
are divided into blue and red,
and the meaning of the numbers themselves.
Maybe the numbers are
street addresses of places on this island.
I see!
Let's go ask go ask the man!
Sir...!
I wonder what Inspector Megure wants to talk
to Ms. Mabuchi about...?
Maybe about the case...
I'm sure it's some kind of mistake.
Go ahead and get in.
-Okay...
Will you load this on together too...
Hey, mister...?!
You stay in the car.
You don't want your friend to get hurt,
do you?
Sir, did you used to
be a treasure hunter before?
Yeah... when I was young...
I came to this island to look
for the treasure hidden by Anne and Mary...
and ended up living here...
I fell in love with
a island lady and married her,
and became a fisherman...
This dates back 300 years.
That's the story...
This is the map
that everything is based on...
The chief of the tourist bureau,
Iwanaga made it
based on an old map just like this one...
It's a code that no one has ever solved yet.
It was thought up 300 years ago...
by Anne Bonmny...
Yeah...
T, Then, don't tell me that ...
if we solve this, we can get hold of
the real treasure...?
Exactly...
If this was made 300 years ago,
it's not a place or a street address.
The most popular way of thinking
would be that they stand for alphabets...
Uh... if so, "5" would be...
"5" would be ... A, B, C, D, E,
-an "E"!!
-Right...
"7" is G
"12" is...
ABCDEFGHIJK,
L...? M...?
The 12th alphabet is "L"!
L.
This makes all of it, right?
The red alphabets have been place on top
and the blue alphabets
have been placed below...
The only thing left now is combination...
Maybe it's a name...?
Maybe the red alphabets make the last name
and the blue the first name...?
I think that's a pretty good guess.
I wonder if it's a name
that has to do with pirates?
Yeah, most likely.
Look, look, if you place it like this,
it looks like a name.
Jolly... is it?
Jolly...
Run for it both of you!!
Don't move!!
Ran...
Phooey! You seem to be able
to use karate a bit,
but you'd better stay still
or your friend's life is in danger...
Our boat...
Why is it in a place like this...
I asked your owner for it.
I paid her for it.
N... No...
This is as far as you come...
There aren't enough air tanks.
Kimiko!!
Don't move!!
Y, You, stay still...
Get on the boat, quick!
Hmm... this kind of stuff's
not my cup of tea...
Then, how about this?
How do you read it...?
Uh... "Gro", I think?
Jolly Gro?
No...
Roger!
Jolly Roger...
Jolly Roger?
Who's that?
A famous pirate or something?
Directly translated,
it would mean "Pleasant Roger."
Jolly Roger
is something that the seamen
around the 1700's hated to see...
It is said that the name comes from
Jolly Rouge, which means red flag
or Old Roger which means devil...
A flag?
A devil?
Yeah...
Jolly Roger
is the pirate flag, that's drawn there...
Wow, Conan.
You solved it.
Yep. What's this?
300 years ago
a seaman who was on board a Spanish ship
passed this island and drew this...
After that, this island sunk into the sea...
It is said that it was due to a thing
called Methane whatevers gas...
Yorioya Island was previously much larger
and protruding out of the sea,
but sank into the sea during an earthquake
that occurred 300 years ago,
and became the shape it is now...
Yorioya Island...
The treasure is on this island?
Yeah, most likely...
But, sure there's still more, though...
There should be a hint
that specifies the location even more...
What's up, Conan?
Did you find something?
The Jolly Roger that
is drawn on the old map,
The skeleton's teeth...
Don't they look like some kind of letter?
True...
it looks like alphabet...
The top teeth look like D.O.S...
and the bottom teeth D.I.O.S.A.S...
Just what does it mean?
Dos Diosas...
(Dos Diosas = two Goddesses)
It means two Goddesses in Spanish.
Wow...!
Just as expected of you, Ai!
That's as far as we go...
We'll have to go to the island
to find out what's left.
But weren't the hunters
searching inside the sea?
Which means the treasure
is hidden in the sea?
No, if so,
there should be a hint
that indicates under the sea...
Besides, the god of the sea is Poseidon,
a male god.
Those guys were probably
looking for another entrance.
The entrance of the two goddesses collapsed
because of the earthquake last week,
and it's become impossible
for adults to go through...
They found the entrance...
That's what despite knowing
that the police were here,
they risked the danger
of robbing the Cutlass and the pistol...
The woman from the dive shop?!
What happened?!
W... Where's Mr. Mouri...
He's not here...
He should be at the government office.
Ran and Sonoko were kidnapped.
On a b,boat...
Who?! Who kidnapped them?!
M... Matsumoto... the treasure hunter.
They're headed for Yorioya Island.
You guys, go to the government office
right away and inform Pops of this!
Okay!
Be careful.
Yeah...
Mr. Mima.
Would get the boat out?
I want you to take me to Yorioya Island...
What?
It's not for the treasure.
I want to go rescue Ran and Sonoko...
Shinichi?!
Conan...
I hear that Ran and Sonoko were kidnapped?
Yeah...
Even if I stop you,
you have your mind set on
going to rescue them, don't you...?
Hold on a sec...
There's something I'd like to give you.
I'll go on ahead and get the boat ready...
Okay...
Take this with you.
It's a compact air tank...
Pull over here.
If you hold it in your mouth
you can breathe air for 10 minutes...
It's too bad that I only have two,
so these should be used
only as a last resort.
Thanks, Doc...
Both of use one tank together!
Now that we're all the way here,
you don't need us anymore do you?
We still have work we need you to do for us.
Hurry up and get ready!
Don't... tell me that...
Sonoko!!
It's show time, young lady.
Just what do you want us to do?!
Your turn's going to be a while later...
What...
Ran and Sonoko were kidnapped by Matsumoto?!
And, where'd they go?!
Where else, but to the island!!
Yorioya Island!!
They found out where the treasure is,
so they went to get it!
Get a boat out for us immediately!!
We've got to go rescue the girls!!
O, Okay!!
I wonder why they took hostages?!
They'd only get in the way
of the treasure hunt!
Those guys want to use the hostages!
Use the hostages?!
Those guys were shot yesterday and hurt!
The place they're planning to dive today
is the place where the sharks
attacked yesterday.
You mean they're going to be used as bait...
Most likely.
Over there!!
Just as I thought...
Now, what? There isn't much time left.
Please take me to Yorioya Island!
What?
I'm sure I can make it through the entrance
of the goddess,don't you think so too?
There's not much air left...
Well, well...
It's amazing
that you made it through alive...
Bring the torch that's over there
and come over here.
You don't know the road, do you?
You're going to die a miserable death
just standing there like that anyway...
Stop dilly-dallying and walk!
Hey, stop pushing me!
Where is this...
We've come up ahead here a lot of times...
Today, we're here
to get hold of the treasure
(from off) of Anne Bonny and Mary Read.
You guys stay still over here for a while...
If you climb a little ways up there,
you'll find a small shrine,
and behind the two goddess statues
you'll find the entrance!
I got it!!
30 minutes is the limit.
Otherwise,
we won't be able to make it back!!
Okay, thank you!
I'll rescue Ran and Sonoko for sure
and bring them back...!!
Anne Bonny and Mary Read...
Strange...
It looks like a place
where even adults can pass through.
The road is blocked because of a landslide
caused by the earthquake last week.
I see...
the hole widened up again
due to the earthquake...
D, Don't tell me that they...
No, I don't think they'd bring the girls
all the way here,
and do a thing like that.
But...
Matsumoto and his friend were shot
last night and are hurt...
If they dive
the sharks will smell blood
and gather around them.
So, what?!
I think they're going to use Ran and Sonoko
as decoy or something like that...
Wait, Mr. Mouri!
Just what are you going to do?!
Let me go!!
I can't just do nothing for Ran and Sonoko!!
Don't Mr. Mouri, it's impossible
because the weather is going to get worse!
Never mind, just let go of me...!!
Excuse me.
Ugh?!
What now?
We've no choice but to go back...
although it's very regrettable.
Go inside already... It's dangerous outside.
But, Conan, Ran and Sonoko...
are in greater danger...
Yes...
True...
The water's receding...
It must be low tide...
Don't tell me we're headed for that hole...?
Exactly...
That hole is the secret path
to the treasure...
Okay, bring that air tank and follow me.
The pirate story was true...
I guess so...
Put the air tanks down and go on ahead!
B, But...
Shut up and go!
Yikes!!
Bones! Bones! Bones...
Whew... I guess it's okay this time.
Gas...
Gas?
Depending on the wind, there are times
when gas is accumulated in this room.
That's why
you made us walk in front of you...
What do you think we brought you along for?
Whew... Hurry up and walk!!
What?
This!
I found it...
Phooey... what an idiot.
He loses his life
because he tries to open the door
by inserting something like this.
This should do it...
You, go on and open it!!
Me?!
I'll do it.
Ran!!
Shoots, no good after all...
Why don't you guys just give up already!
I see, so that's what it is.
Did you figure it out?
Anne and Mary seems to have fought
with their backs against each other's...
In other words...
This is what it means.
We did it... did it boss...
Hey, lend me the light.
Wow...
The treasure... Where's the treasure...?
Ha, ha... hold your horses, ha, ha, ha.
Ran... what now?
We could make a run for it now,
but we'd half to float up the sea,
which is going through a storm
without an air tank.
True...
We've no choice
but to wait here for help to come...
So... I guess so...
Wind...
It's connected...
Darn! It's not here!!
There's no treasure anywhere!
No treasure, not even one measly coin!!
I don't know who it is,
but the one that came here before us
took every last penny out of here!
Hey, what's this about?
I came all the way here
because you said
there'd be a mountain of treasure!!
Shut up! Zip your mouth!!
We've got no choice...
Let's get out of here fast.
After getting rid of the load
we don't need anymore.
Sorry...
this is your fate, girls...
D, Don't move!!
Ran, I'm leaving behind me to you, Ran.
Okay, got you.
Why you!
Darn, this chick is strong!!
Fuh... You can say that again...
But, no matter how strong
she can't... beat this...
Hah!!
This is our last resort...
Both of you, get down!!
Are you okay,
Ran? Sonoko?
Good work, young boy!
It's amazing you made it here.
It's connected to Yorioya Island.
The story about the pirate's treasure
was true after all.
Nope... there seems to have been no treasure,
the men were saying...
They were making a fuss saying that the ones
who cane here before them stole it all.
Oh...
So, that's the story! Too bad!
I think you can come out now.
You were following me from behind
all the way here, right?!
Inspector!! Isn't the boat leaving already?
The wind has subsided too...
Mr. Mouri...
According to the forecast,
there'll be strong wind and rain
until early tomorrow morning,
B, But take a look.
The weather's really getting nicer.
Please calm down, Mr. Mouri.
How the hell do you expect me
to stay calm at a time like this?!
Ran's been kidnapped you know!!
But the only one
who went to rescue her is the glasses kid...
And, all the adults here are just
sitting here sucking our fingers waiting...
Mr. Mouri...
I understand how you feel,
but if the boats can't sail,
there's nothing more that we can do...
As soon as the wind subsides,
we promise we'll go save the girls...
Please endure for now!
Darn!!
Come on out.
You followed me in secret all the way here,
didn't you?
Mr. Iwanaga?
Not really in secret. It sounds bad...
I came here wanting to save the two
who were kidnapped...
Why did you bring a rifle with you?
Well, they were on the
internationally wanted list, weren't they?
Isn't that rifle the one
that was stolen from Mr. Mineo?
Huh? N, No...
Didn't you bring the rifle along
to make sure
they wouldn't take the treasure from you?
T, The treasure has nothing to do with it...
Mr. Iwanaga...
You said that you thought out the code
that was on the treasure hunt map
that you handed out to us, right...
Y, Yeah...
But, I saw the same number codes
at Mr. Mima's house...
On the treasure hunt map
that is said to have been left behind
by Anne Bonny...
300 year ago...
Which means, you must've looked at that map,
Mr. Iwanaga, right?
In other words, you tried to make the people
who came to visit this island,
solve the code
that you yourself couldn't solve.
Come to think of it,
he was also urging dad
to participate in the game too...
I see, the rate of a famed detective
solving the problem
is much higher than that of the children.
Besides,
in order to keep track of the people
who participated in the treasure hunt,
you set a GPS on the bicycles
that were rented out, right?
I, I did that to keep
the participants from danger...
When the numbers on the treasure hunt map
are switched to alphabets,
it reads Jolly Roger...
in other words, the pirate flag...
Yorioya Island was shaped
like that of a skull in the past,
that's why Anne Bonny
left that hint behind...
I think that even the name Yorioya
is variant pronunciation of Jolly Roger...
I think that you went as far as to
solve the puzzle till here, Mr. Iwanaga but,
Jolly Roger had another meaning...
What?!
On the real map the pirate flag was drawn,
right?
And the 2nd hint was hidden
in the teeth of the skull...
It was, Dos Diosas,
the two goddesses...
C, Conan?
Right, you saw them
when you followed me here, didn't you?
The little shrine of the two goddesses...
That was the sign to the entrance...
I, I see...
I wonder why
I overlooked something like that...
Darn... I was mistaken to begin with...
The one who rigged the BC jacket,
and the sniper
who shot the two treasure hunters
was you, wasn't it, Mr. Iwanaga?
The tracks of the wheels of
your mountain bike were found
behind Grotto as well as the place
where the cartridges
of the rifle were found...
Ha, ha... They sure are bloopers that
even a grade school child could point out.
It's not a grade school child
that did this...
It's Pops, Kogoro Mouri.
I'm just telling what he told me.
Pops was saying
that he smelled gunpowder,
from your body, Mr. Iwanaga.
He said that since it was an old rifle,
when you fired it, a lot of burnt remains
must've scattered all over the place.
Oh...
Just as I thought...
Ha, ha... Just as expected of
the famed detective Kogoro Mouri...
E, Earthquake?
It stopped...
This is bad... we'd better get out of here.
Yes... we've got to take them along too...
Yep! Mr. Iwanaga, help us!
O, Okay...
Shoots!!
O, Oh no, the entrance...
It's gas!!
To the boat!
Quick!!
Darn! At this rate...
Conan... what now?
Let's put those people in the cabin
and just in case
make them inhale air from the air tank,
so that they don't breathe in the gas...
And, use this for Sonoko and yourself...
Huh? What's this?
Air tanks that Doc made for me.
What about you, Conan?
I've got mine too, so don't worry.
Oh...
Darn, what now...
The gas'll get to me soon...
Gas? ...
This gas is probably Methane gas,
so it's probably
concentrated near the ceiling...
If I use that gas...
Something... Isn't there something?
I found it!!
Ran, Sonoko!
Do you hear me?
The fact that sea water is flowing in
means that the rocks are not that thick.
So, if you let the gas explode
and broke the ceiling,
we can all float up together
with this ship...
D, Don't tell me you're thinking of
making it out of here on this ship?!
Is it going to work?
I don't know...
But, if things go as they are,
we'll all fall victim to the gas
or wait around until we drown...
If we don't have a chance anyway,
we may as well...
I think it's worth trying...
Yep... So, what do we do, Conan?
I'm going to kick up the debris
of that chain right now
and strike the rock of the ceiling.
If it works out, it should spark fire
and case the gas to explode,
so Ran and Sonoko, go inside the cabin
and breathe using the air tank.
I think that when the explosion occurs
the air in the area
will decrease drastically.
What about you, Conan?
I'll be fine!
As soon as I kick up the chain
I'll dive into the cabin right away,
so don't worry!
Okay...
Inspector...
Hmm... Get the boat ready!
We're heading to the rescue!!
Yes, sir!!
All ready, Conan!
Alright!
O... Oh, no!
Conan...
Conan, get a hold of yourself...
Ran...
Hurry! Hurry!
Can't you go any faster...
P... Pirate ship...
Ran!
Are you all right...!!
I'm fine...!
Saved...
Whaaa...
Run for it, everybody!!
Look out!!
Jump into the sea...
Sonoko!!
Hurry.
And... did you find the treasure?
No.
The only thing we found
was a beat up pirate ship.
I think that was the treasure.
Because I think the map
that Anne Bonny left behind
was not really a treasure map
but a message for Mary
that she left back in prison...
A message?
I'm here!
I'll be waiting here for you forever...
Shinichi...
Like so!
Sonoko...
-You precocious brat!!
-Ouch!!
No, she may be right...
That ship is probably a ship
that Anne had built,
so that when Mary escaped from prison,
and came back,
they could once again go out
and cross the 7 seas.
But, Mary fell ill while in prison
and died...
Anne herself died.
while waiting for Mary...
And that ship that was left behind
waited at the coffin-like cave
at the bottom of the sea
for the day that it would once again
be able to set off into the vast sea.
300 years later today,
the ship goes out on its
first and last journey
delivering you all to the surface.
And, as if going after its two masters...
disappears from sight...
I spoke of something that
isn't quite like me to say...
Please forget about it...
Phooey, well since 300 years
have already gone by,
who knows what the real truth is...
Well, it's sure no mistake
that Anne was waiting for Mary,
Pops...
As proof of that,
under the skull of Jolly Roger,
a picture is drawn of...
Anne and Mary's pistol and Cutlass...
Ran...
Uh...
how did you know back then that
I didn't have an air tank?
Because you looked so much like Shinichi...
I think it was when we were in 8th grade...
It suddenly started to rain really hard
on my way home from school...
Oh, bummers...
Here, use this...
You gotta rush home, right?
Oh, yes, thank you...
What about you, Shinichi?
Don't be silly, I'm a detective you know.
I deduced that
something like this could happen
and brought another one with me.
Wow,
thanks... I have promised to see mother so...
I'll borrow this then.
I'll give it back to you tomorrow!
Okay...!
But, he didn't have
any extra umbrella with him...
He got home soaking wet
and caught a clod...
Right... you looked just like him back then,
that's why.
You look so much like
that super idiot deduction freak
when he grins and bears something!
So sorry...
I'm an idiot...