Ayumi-chan, it's past your
bedtime. Go take your bath.
Just a little more! It's just getting good!
You have swim practice tomorrow, don't you?
Okay...
Who are you? Mr. Dracula?
No.
Just a simple wizard resting his
tired wings after flying for so long...
...Miss.
There he is! That's him!
Don't let him escape!
Catch the Kaito Kid!
See you, Miss.
Eh? You saw the Kaito Kid?!
Are you serious, Ayumi?!
Yeah! He was so cool!
He really is the modern-day Arsene Lupin!
So, what is the modern-day
Holmes going to do?
Don't be stupid! I'm gonna
catch him someday, obviously!
I'm high school detective Kudo Shinichi.
I went with old friend and classmate,
Mori Ran, to an amusement park
where I witnessed a suspicious
deal with a man dressed in black!
I was so absorbed with watching the deal
that I didn't notice a second man
sneak up from behind me!
He forced me to take a poison,
and when I woke up...
...my body had shrunk!
If they learned Kudo Shinichi was alive,
they might go after me again,
putting all the people around me in danger!
Per Dr. Agasa's advice,
I decided to conceal my identity.
When Ran asked my name,
I quickly answered, "Edogawa Conan."
To get information on the men,
I wound up living with Ran
and her detective father.
I'm the great detective, Mori Kogoro...
He's known as "Sleeping Kogoro."
This is because...
...I put him to sleep
with my stun-gun wristwatch
and use my voice-changing bowtie
to solve cases with his voice!
These two gadgets are Dr. Agasa's inventions!
Despite how it seems, he's a real genius,
and he's always making
me new, unique gadgets,
such as a Turbo-Engine
Skateboard, Tracking Glasses,
and Power-Assisted Kick Shoes!
In particular, he upgraded the skateboard
so it can run for 30 minutes at
night if it's charged during the day!
But there are two others besides
the doc who know my true identity.
Hattori Heiji, high school
detective from the west,
and Haibara Ai, a transfer student.
She originally worked with the men
in black, but to escape from them,
she took the same poison I did and shrank!
While following their organization,
I stand up to difficult cases
that happen one after the other!
And now... a new rival has appeared!
I find the ray of light in the
darkness of confusion and suspicion!
Even when I'm small, my mind
remains that of a sharp detective!
There is always only one truth!
Kaito #1412, AKA "Kaito Kid,"
has struck 134 times thus far!
15 of those have been overseas,
in 12 different countries,
including America, France, and Germany!
152 jewels have been stolen in all!
Total loss of 38,725,000,000 yen!
The truth is, a new warning letter
arrived from the Kaito Kid yesterday.
"When time moves from the twilight
of Leo to the daybreak of Virgo.
When a clock with no second
hand inscribes the 12th letter,
at a tall building shining in the heavens
I shall appear and take the Memories Egg.
From the Last Wizard
of the Century, Kaito Kid."
Kaito Kid?!
The "Memories Egg" in the letter
refers to an Imperial Easter Egg,
a treasure of the Romanov
Dynasty, found last month
in the Suzuki Zaibatsu's storehouse.
The Imperial Easter Eggs are
eggs made by the jeweler Fabergˇ,
as Easter presents for the
Russian empress, from the emperor.
Fifty were made between 1885 and 1916.
Therefore, this
newly-discovered egg is the 51st.
The Suzuki Zaibatsu will be putting
the 51st egg on display August 23,
at the new Suzuki Modern Art
Gallery in the Osaka Castle Park.
Now, as for the coded
message... Nakamori-kun.
Yes, sir.
First, "...Moves from the twilight
of Leo to the daybreak of Virgo."
This refers to the evening of
August 22, the last day of Leo,
and the dawn of August 23,
the first day of Virgo,
and indicates the date of the crime.
Next is, "When a clock with no second
hand inscribes the 12th letter."
It's believed this indicates
the time of the crime,
but it has yet to be deciphered!
Lastly is, "A tall building
shining in the heavens."
This is a castle tower!
It indicates the Kaito Kid
will appear at Osaka Castle!
In short, this letter says,
"Between the evening of August
22 and the dawn of August 23,
I will appear at the tower of Osaka Castle
and steal the Imperial Easter Egg!"
We will be investigating in
collaboration with the Osaka police.
In addition, Mr. Suzuki has
personally asked for the help
of the private detective, Mr. Mori Kogoro!
H-Hi!
Our objective here is to
keep the egg safe at all costs!
Even if it means letting him get
away, we must keep the egg safe!
Don't give me that wimpiness!
The egg comes second! Got it, men?!
For our pride and dignity,
we police must throw that snobby
sneak-thief into a freezing jail cell!
I think I just accepted one hell of a job...
Ran! Over here!
Sonoko!
Oh! A limousine, huh?!
That's the Suzuki Zaibatsu for ya!
Today is a special day, after all!
Special?
I gotta be posh if I'm meeting
my beloved Kaito Kid-sama today!
You're so silly, Sonoko!
"Beloved Kid-sama"?
Oh, right! Our driver is
Nishino-san, Daddy's secretary.
Nice to meet you!
He's traveled all over the world,
so he speaks English,
French, and German fluently!
Wow! That's amazing!
It's not fair, Doc!
Conan went to Osaka all by himself!
I wanted to see the Kid again...
Running off all by himself is his specialty!
Now, now. Don't be like that.
Here, have some watermelon
and cool your anger.
Alright!
- Thank you for the food!
- Hold it!
You can eat after you've solved my riddle.
You can't be serious, Doc!
Don't be silly.
You're children. I can't give you
the impression it's easy to get things.
Here goes!
"I [washi] have many grandkids
[ooku no mago]. How old am I?"
Whoa! You have grandkids, Doc?!
It's just a riddle!
I guess it's no use without Conan-kun here...
What happens to this watermelon, then?
Zero.
You're still an egg.
"Washi" can also mean "eagle."
"Ooku no mago" can be
changed to "tamago." [egg]
And you're zero years old if you're in an egg.
Absolutely correct! Well done, Ai-kun!
I knew you could solve it!
- Haibara-san is...
- ...amazing...
Haibara's part of our Junior
Detective League, right?
Which means...
Thanks for the food!
Now let's see how you handle
that other egg, Kudo-kun.
They're really being cautious...
I doubt even an ant could
crawl though unnoticed...
But of course! We are dealing
with Kaito Kid-sama here! He's...
...an elusive, ever-changing, gentleman thief.
He easily breaks through tough
security and safes with his magic,
plus he can completely alter his
face, voice, and personality as well.
One thing's for sure: that's one
heck of an enemy you've made...
...Kudo.
Hattori!
Him again?!
Sheesh! Why do you always
call Conan-kun "Kudo"?!
My bad! It's just that his eyes
remind me of Kudo's, you see.
So I always call him that, on accident.
You're so dumb!
You kept saying all morning that
Kudo's coming, Kudo's coming.
I think you should probably see a doctor.
Hey, is he Hattori Heiji-kun,
the high school detective of the west?
He's a real stud!
Don't even try! He and
Kazuha-chan grew up together!
They're bickering like that now,
but they're really close!
Yeah, I can tell.
They're just like you and Shinichi.
If only I had a boy I grew up with, too...
Why, hello there, Mori-san!
Thank you for coming all this way!
No, it's my pleasure.
Thanks for coming, Ran-san and Conan-kun!
Say, Sonoko. Who might these two be?
Hattori Heiji-kun and
Toyama Kazuha-san, Daddy.
Heiji-kun is known as the
"high school detective of the west."
He's famous in the Kansai area!
That's quite something! I'm depending on you!
Yeah! You can count on me, old man!
Hey, you! Don't call the chairman
of the Suzuki Zaibatsu "old man"!
Now, now, Mori-san.
Anyway, let me introduce you.
This is Sergei Ovchinnikov-san,
1st Secretary of the Russian Embassy.
Nice to meet you.
Next to him is the fine art
dealer, Inui Shouichi-san,
who is already asking to purchase it.
She's Hoshi Seiran-san,
a researcher of the Romanov Dynasty.
Ni hao.
And this is Sagawa Ryu-san,
the freelance cameraman and writer
I've hired to film and document the egg.
Hiya!
But... purchase? For what sort of price?
800 million.
E-Eight hundred million?!
I can pay more, if you'll let me have it.
Chairman! The Imperial Easter Eggs
originally belonged to Russia!
Don't sell yours to this sleazy broker!
Please donate it to one of Russia's museums!
Who're you calling sleazy?!
Great! That's it!
Filming you people might be more
fun than filming the egg itself!
You're acting like you don't care,
but if you're a Romanov researcher,
shouldn't you desperately
want the egg for yourself, too?
Yes... But I can't
compete with 800 million...
Yeah, huh? 200 million is
the most I could scrounge up.
Hey, now. The Kid's not the only
one after the egg! They all are...
In any case, we can save discussion
about the egg for a later day.
Understood.
Very well. I suppose I'll leave for today.
Chairman! I've brought the egg!
Oh, thank you. Put it on
the table, if you would.
Yes, sir!
Come, everyone.
Wow! He's going to show us the egg!
It's nothing that fancy on the outside.
In fact, I unknowingly played
with it as a toy when I was little!
A toy?
So this is an Imperial Easter Egg?
Nishino-kun, could you
get us some cold drinks?
Yes, sir.
I dunno, it's less exciting than I expected.
Yeah. It's like an ostrich egg.
It opens up, right?
That's right! I'm impressed you knew!
Inside is a solid gold model
of Emperor Nicholai's family.
That's really somethin'!
This egg does something interesting, too.
Whoa! This thing's cool!
In Fabergˇ's old notes was the
design for the inside of this egg.
This is what proved it was a legitimate egg.
Is "Memories Egg" the English
translation of its Russian name?
Yes, that's right.
In Russian, it's
"vospominaniya," or "memories."
Say. How is flipping through a book a memory?
You idiot! The emperor reading
a book to his kids is the memory!
Are those jewels shining
underneath the egg's lid?
No, it's only glass.
Eh?
Even though it's a present
from the emperor to the empress?
Doesn't that seem strange?
Apparently, Russia was in financial
trouble when the 51st was made.
No, the Kid's letter is what seems strange.
"A tall building shining in the heavens."
Why would Osaka Castle shine?
You dummy. The retired
emperor who built Osaka Castle
built it as the foundation
for all of Osaka's development!
So it's like the light of Osaka!
Exactly!
The Kid will appear in Osaka
Castle's tower! No doubt about it!
But...
"When a clock with no second
hand inscribes the 12th letter."
We just can't figure out what that means.
Could it be the 12th letter
in the Japanese alphabet?
The 12th letter?
"Shi"? Could it mean 4 o'clock, then?!
No, that's too simple
for one of the Kid's codes.
I've figured it out, Superintendent.
It's not the Japanese alphabet,
but the English alphabet!
The English alphabet?!
The 12th letter in the English
alphabet is L! In other words...
...3 o'clock?!
Impressive, great detective! Well done!
That's gotta be it! 3:00 a.m. is before sunrise
and matches perfectly with "dawn of Virgo"!
Just you wait, Kaito Kid!
We'll get you this time, for sure!
I got "great luck"!
Let me see!
"Waiting: You will reunite
with the person you love."
Could that mean Shinichi-kun?!
- Eh?
- Oh! Good for you!
Introduce him to me sometime!
He's right here.
Now, then! The question is how
we pass the time until 3:00 a.m.
For now, I guess we should eat...
Kazuha, show those two around, will ya?
What about you?
I'm gonna show this runt around the place.
How come? Come on, let's go together!
This is just how men are sometimes.
Right, C-C-Conan-kun?
Yeah!
You're gonna fix that soon, I hope?!
Oh? What's with the attitude?
I can tell 'em the truth, if you want.
P-Please assist me!
Yeah, that's more like it!
Can't forget to smile when
asking people for something!
You jerk...
It's strange seeing those two get along...
Oh, who cares! We can have a girls' day out!
Let's find some hot Osaka men
and have them pay for our meals!
In that case, let's check out Pick-Up Bridge!
You're thinkin' about that
12th letter thing, aren't ya?
Yeah. I know what "L" is in
the Russian alphabet, but...
The Russian alphabet?
The Russian "L" is the English "K."
Hmm, clock hands can't make a "K" shape...
Plus, the "Last Wizard of the Century"
at the end of the letter bugs me.
He's such a snob.
He's never called himself that before.
Plus, the Kid's only ever gone
after jewels. So why the egg now?
Check!
Anyways, what fortune did you get earlier?
I haven't looked at that stupid thing yet.
Why not? It's gonna tell you how
your duel with the Kid goes, right?
Ugh...
Oh? "Some luck," huh?
That's a pretty vague fortune.
There's no telling if you'll win
or lose your duel with the Kid now.
"The one you wait for will come"?
"Travel: Your secret will
come to light. Avoid traveling."
Hey, now!
Don't tell me that means...
Yeah, right.
The fortunes here are right a lot.
What?! No way!
Yes way!
A traditional Japanese restaurant?
Yes. We now know the Kid will
appear at 3:00 tomorrow morning,
so what do you say until then?
Sounds great to me!
Chairman! It's time.
Oh, yes! I appreciate your help!
Oh? Are you moving it to the exhibition room?
- The fake will go there.
- Fake?
All previous times, we naively left
the Kid's prey where he indicated
in his warning letters,
and he swiped it anyway.
This time, we're making it so he
doesn't know where the real one is.
Good thinking! So, where will it be?
I'm afraid I can't tell you!
Only my two men and I know!
Of course...
...I've already made sure
they're not the Kid in disguise!
What are you...
There's a chance that you're the Kid, too!
In that case, I better
make sure you're not the Kid!
My name is Kosaka Natsumi.
This is my butler, Sawabe.
I'd very much like to meet the chairman
in regards to the Imperial
Easter Egg in this pamphlet.
I'm sorry. The chairman is out at the moment.
I can speak with you, if you'd like.
The egg in this photo is different
from the picture my great-grandfather left!
Oh! That's neat! If 3:00 a.m. is
an "L," right now's a Japanese "he"!
"He"?!
It's 7:13 right now.
At 7:20 will be a perfect "he"!
The 12th Japanese letter in that
twilight and dawn line is a "he"!
Hattori! The Kid didn't mean
3:00 a.m.! He meant 7:20 p.m.!
Say what?! Hey! Where are you going, Kudo?!
Osaka Castle! You guard the egg!
Rain? The weather forecast
said it'd be clear...
Wait, Kudo!
The "tall building" isn't the castle tower!
It's the Tsutenkaku Tower!
The Tsutenkaku?!
A weather forecast shines
at the top of the Tsutenkaku!
What?!
Ladies and gentlemen!
Okay! Let the show begin!
W-What the...
Oh, fireworks!
Truly a summer tradition!
They're so pretty!
Even Osaka's fireworks are flashy!
That's strange. Today's not a fireworks day.
Inspector! Fireworks are being
launched over by Osaka Castle!
An incredible amount, too!
Calm down! That's not the Kid.
We still have over 7 hours
until the time he specified.
I doubt he'll ever suspect
that the egg is being hidden
in a warehouse-like place such as this!
Hattori! Which way is the Tsutenkaku?!
That way!
There aren't any fireworks over there...
The fireworks at Osaka Castle are
to take all eyes off the Tsutenkaku!
But why?! Why would he be at the Tsutenkaku?
Damn! We can't make it
to the Tsutenkaku in time!
Wait for the Kid here!
Nishino-san! Where's the egg right now?!
Inspector Nakamori apparently
took it to a different location.
W-What?!
Next up is...
A blackout?!
What's going on?! What is this?!
Something's not right about this!
Oh! A drink in the moonlight!
This is even more elegant!
Stay calm! Switch to the private
generator at once! Quickly!
Yes, sir!
I know what he's after!
H-Hey!
The Hoenzaka Mikado Hospital.
The Dojima Century Hotel.
The Tenman Emergency Medical Center.
The Chanel Ten Hotel.
The Naniwa TMS Hospital.
The Kansai World Hotel.
Bingo.
- Move! How'm I supposed to turn right?!
- Through-traffic gets the right-of-way!
He found out the real egg had
been moved to another location!
So he blacked out the whole town
to make them switch to a generator
so he could locate them!
It'd be the only place besides
hotels and hospitals with lights on!
The Kid! Dammit!
Crap! A dead-end!
Hop on, Kudo!
I get it!
The Tsutenkaku'd be the perfect
place to see where lights come on!
Which means he anticipated all
this when he wrote his letter!
And, to keep the hiding
place less conspicuous...
...security would be light!
He's gonna get it if we don't hurry!
Hattori!
- You stay here!
- What?! Hey! Kudo!
Kid!
Damn!
Crap!
Hurry, Kudo!
Hang gliders fly best with light headwinds!
Meaning he's flying upwind, huh?!
He's starting to lower his altitude!
Osaka Bay is up ahead!
The Kid's definitely gonna land!
Hattori! You okay?!
W-What're you doin'?! Get going!
Let 'im get away and I'll kick your ass!
Hattori...
A-Are you alright?!
- Call the police and an ambulance!
- Y-Yeah...
Just hold on, Hattori!
What was that?
This injury...
The egg's alright!
That's the Kid's monocle!
Did he get shot and fall into the ocean?!
In which case, who was that man just now?
That night, despite their
exhaustive search efforts,
the police couldn't tell
if the Kid survived or not.
The next day, to ascertain
if the egg was undamaged,
its display was canceled,
and it was to be taken back to Tokyo
aboard a Suzuki family ship.
My great-grandfather's name was Kiichi.
He worked as a craftsman
at Fabergˇ's workshop.
He married a Russian woman there,
and the year after the revolution,
they returned to Japan,
where my great-grandmother had a baby girl.
But my great-grandmother died
shortly after, and 9 years later,
my great-grandfather also
passed away, at the young age of 45.
And this baby would be...
My grandmother.
My grandfather and my parents
died in an accident when I was five,
so I was raised by my grandmother.
She passed away this past month.
I was working as a pastry chef in Paris,
but I returned here to tend
to her personal belongings,
when I found this old drawing
I think my great-grandfather did.
The middle is torn out, but...
"Memories..."
Indeed, it is the Memories Egg.
But this one has jewels on it.
Maybe it had jewels originally,
but they got taken at some point?
Say. Could there have
been two eggs, actually?
Eh?
I mean, look. The contours are
too different to be only one egg.
It was actually a bigger piece
of paper with two drawn on it,
but a huge part in the middle is missing now.
I see!
But why is it "Memories"?
There's a mirror here...
Oops! It came out!
What are you doing?!
There was a mirror in it, but it came out...
What?!
Conan-kun!
No, it's okay! That mirror's
made to come out easily!
I guess it was added afterwards or something.
Huh? There's an image of something!
Could this be...
Nishino-san! Turn off the lights!
Eh? O-Okay.
Hey, you! What do you think you're...
H-How is there a picture?
- It's a "Magic Mirror."
- Magic Mirror?
I've heard of those!
They're from Japan and China,
where people worshipped mirrors!
Yes. They're specially-crafted mirrors.
They say covert Christians in
Japan secretly prayed to crosses
that they projected onto walls using them.
Sawabe-san, is this castle...
Yes. Without question,
it is the Yokosuka Castle.
Eh? Yokosuka Castle? The one
often used for commercials and such?
Yes. My great-grandfather
was the one who built it.
My grandmother looked after it all this time.
So that was a Kosaka family castle!
Natsumi-san, could your
great-grandfather have made the two eggs?
After the Russian Revolution,
your great-grandfather and his wife
returned to Japan with the two eggs he made.
He likely sold many of the
jewels on this second egg,
built a castle in Yokosuka,
and hid the egg somewhere inside it.
And then he left a message saying
that he hid it inside the castle
in a Magic Mirror in another egg.
Actually, I also found this
old key with the drawing.
Could it mean something, too?
There's no question that that key
is for the second egg's hiding spot!
A mysterious egg, encrusted with jewels...
If it's found, it'd be worth
over 1 billion... no, 1.5 billion!
Is that why the Kid went after it?
No...
Mori-san.
Could you accompany me to the
castle when we arrive at Tokyo?
But of course!
- Please allow me to come, as well.
- Me, too!
- Yeah! Lemme get it on film!
- I'd love to come, too!
Sure! We can all go together!
What the... Everyone's got
a new look in their eye!
Are they going after the second egg too?!
- There we go.
- Good bird.
Okay! I stopped the bleeding!
As long as we keep the wound
wrapped, it'll fly again!
Really?! That's great!
Luckily, Hattori-kun only
suffered some light sprains,
but do you suppose the Kid is dead?
He would never die like that.
Who knows, maybe he's already on this ship?!
Coming!
That's a great expression! Thanks for the shot!
What was that?
Hi, Ran! We came to visit!
Natsumi-san and Nishino-san, too! Come on in!
Sorry to disturb you!
Sorry to bother you!
I think I'll pass, after all!
Huh?
Oh, I get it! He's embarrassed
being around so many beautiful girls!
How cute!
I forgot the other beautiful girl!
I'll go get her!
Okay! Seiran-san, right?
- Let's go, Squirt!
- I'm coming too?
Yes! Thank you!
I'll be ready soon. Just a minute.
"Grigorii..."
Oh! Is that a photo of your boyfriend?
Eh? Oh, yes.
Everyone's got a man. They're so lucky...
I totally should've gotten my hands
on the Kid when I had the chance.
If you could get him, the police
wouldn't be having so much trouble.
So you lived in Paris since
you were 20, Natsumi-san?
That's right.
So sometimes I use strange Japanese.
Speaking of strange Japanese,
there's a phrase I heard
as a child and never forgot.
Oh? What is it?
"Barushe niku katta be ka?"
Eh?
I think it means, "Did Barougier buy meat?"
But I don't know whose name that could be.
Huh? Natsumi-san, your eyes are...
Yep! They're gray! The same
as my mother and grandmother!
I think we got it from my great-grandmother!
Now that you mention it,
your eyes are gray too, Seiran-san!
So they are! Do Chinese
people have gray eyes, too?
Say, "Seiran" is written
as "blue orchid," right?
My name means "orchid," too!
"Seiran" is the Japanese reading.
It's really "Chinran."
Chinran?
"Sei" is "Chin," "Ran" is "Ran."
"Hoshi" is "Pusu," so it's Pusu Chinran.
So "Ran" is pronounced "Ran" in Chinese, too?
That's right. "Mori" would be "Maori."
So my name would be Maori Ran!
I like how cute that sounds!
Oh, oh! How about me?!
Suzuki Sonoko would be "Lingmu Yuanzi."
L-Lingmu Yuanzi...
Say, I think we may be about
the same age, Seiran-san.
Yes. I'm 27.
I knew it! What month?!
May. May 5th.
Eh?! I'm May 3rd! We're only two days apart!
Oh, then you're both one day apart from me!
One day apart? That would mean May 4th...
That's the same as Shinichi!
That's a big coincidence... Could it be?
Could Conan-kun actually be...
That's so dumb. That couldn't possibly be true.
That's what I get for obsessing
about him. I really am dumb.
Oh!
Natsumi-san and Seiran-san!
Why don't you join us?
- You don't mind?
- No, be my guest!
Wow! You're so nice and sexy!
This old man's a lost cause...
There you are!
Thank you!
Sagawa-san! That pendant!
Oh? I'm impressed. You're definitely
a Romanov Dynasty researcher.
Wanna look?
Huh? Was he always wearing that?
"Maria"?
Is this the ring of Maria,
Nicholai II's third daughter?!
I suppose so, if that's what you say.
Where did you get it?!
Do you think it's real?
I don't know. I would need
to do a more detailed check.
Hey, Nishino-kun.
Your pen's about to fall out.
Oh. Thanks.
Mori-san! Are you there, Mori-san?!
Oh, dinner finally ready?
It's terrible! Sagawa-san is...
Sagawa-san is dead in his room!
What?!
Sagawa-san...
He was shot in the right eye.
The Kid was shot in the right eye, too!
Hey, you! Butt out, kid!
Are you okay?
His cheeks are just starting to stiffen.
It's been less than 30 minutes.
His ring pendant is gone!
Chairman Suzuki! This was a murder!
Contact the police!
R-Right!
Got it. I'll be right there.
Oh, Inspector Megure.
Shiratori-kun!
Weren't you going on vacation to Karuizawa?
I find cabin life boring.
- Did something happen?
- Perfect timing. Come with us, too.
Inspector! We've been expecting you!
Honestly! Why do incidents
always happen wherever you go?!
I suppose it's a message from God?
Are you sure you're not the god, Mori-san?
The god of death.
Assistant Inspector Shiratori is harsh!
Huh? What's with that bandage?
No, uhh, I had a bit of a scuffle
with a criminal yesterday...
The victim was Sagawa Ryu-san,
age 32. A freelance filmographer.
Inspector! This was a murder-robbery!
The killer stole a ring!
A ring?
Yes! It originally belonged to Maria,
third daughter of Nicholai II!
Sagawa-san had it on a pendant
he wore around his neck!
If it was about the ring, the person
could've just taken the pendant.
But it's weird...
...not only is the room in shambles,
but even the pillow's been cut open!
Are you scampering around again?!
Inspector Megure! This was on the floor!
A pen, huh?
"M. Nishino"?
This is definitely your pen,
correct, Nishino-san?
Y-Yes. But what was it
doing in Sagawa-san's room?
You're the one who found his body, yes?
That's right. Dinner was ready,
so I went to get him.
- Did you enter the room then?
- No.
Then why was your pen in his
room if you hadn't gone inside?
I don't know.
Then, what were you doing at around 7:30?
Let's see... I was in my room,
taking a shower at about 7:10,
and I took a short break after that.
Daddy, you don't think Nishino-san...
No. I don't think he would.
If Nishino-san did kill Sagawa-san,
then it's possible he's the
one who shot the Kid, too.
Inspector Megure!
We've found that all the victim's
videotapes are gone from his room.
- What?!
- I get it!
That's why the room was ransacked!
Hold it, Conan! Quit running around!
It's okay. I'll get him.
Ran-san, the killer could be
wandering around with a gun.
Please return to the others.
B-But, Conan-kun is...
I'll bring him back myself. Go on, now.
- Umm...
- Please let me handle it.
Oh, Doc? It's me. I need you
to look up something right away.
What? A sniper who shoots right eyes?
Got it. I'll look into it.
Call back in 10 minutes.
10 minutes...
Just my imagination?
I got it, Shinichi!
I checked the ICPO's criminal database
and a criminal with unknown
age and gender popped up!
He's known as the Scorpion!
Scorpion?
Inspector! I found it!
It was under Nishino-san's bed!
That's impossible!
It seems we have conclusive evidence now.
Please, wait! I didn't do it, Inspector!
If you're not the killer,
then why did you have the ring?!
I don't know, either!
It's almost for certain that
the Scorpion is the killer.
Which would mean
Nishino-san is the Scorpion...
Huh?
A rice hull pillow...
Conan!
Say! Are you allergic to feathers, Nishino-san?
Eh? Yes, that's right...
Then you can't be the killer!
What?!
Go ahead. Continue.
O-Okay...
After all, Sagawa-san's room
was filled with feathers!
The killer even cut up the feather pillow!
Someone allergic to feathers
wouldn't have done that!
Are you really allergic to feathers?
Yes. I can vouch for him.
Even just a feather or two will
make him sneeze uncontrollably.
Which is why he doesn't use a feather pillow!
Oh! So that's why he ran from
Ran's room! Because of the dove!
So who is the killer, then?
Inspector, have you heard of the Scorpion?
Scorpion?
A bad guy who goes to lots of
different countries and always shoots
people's right eyes and kills them
to get Romanov Dynasty treasures!
Oh! Now that you mention it,
there was someone like that on
the international wanted list.
Eh?! Does that mean our killer here...
I believe it's this Scorpion.
He probably shot the Kid, too.
Come again?!
The Kid's monocle was cracked, right?
The Scorpion shot the Kid down
trying to steal the egg from him.
And how do you know about the Scorpion?!
- No, I, uhh...
- Dr. Agasa told him.
Isn't that right, Conan-kun?
Y-Yeah.
Yikes!
So it was Detective Shiratori I
sensed watching me during that call!
"Your secret will come to light!"
Was that referring to Detective Shiratori?
But if the Scorpion is the killer,
why'd he steal Sagawa-san's ring
and hide it in Nishino-san's room?
Beats me...
Damn. I can't use the stun-gun
wristwatch in front of Det. Shiratori.
I have no choice.
Say, you and Sagawa-san
knew each other, right?
Huh?
Sagawa-san was shocked when
he saw you at the gallery yesterday!
Really?
You traveled all over the world, right?
You must've met him somewhere, then!
You knew Sagawa-san?!
Yes! It happened when I was
touring Asia three years ago!
He was filming a little girl whose
house burned down in a civil war.
He refused to stop when I told him to,
so I punched him unthinkingly!
So Sagawa-san must've
held a grudge against you, then!
I got it! Nishino-san! You're the Scorpion!
Oh, geez...
Mori-kun, the feather thing
already proved it wasn't him.
Oh. Right.
But you really lucked out, Nishino-san.
Eh?
After all, had the Scorpion
not killed Sagawa-san,
you would've been framed as the ring thief!
Huh? Hold on a sec.
That's it!
Just like the two eggs, there are
two overlapping incidents here!
Two incidents?
Now you got it.
In the first incident,
Sagawa-san tried to frame Nishino-san!
In order to frame
Nishino-san as the ring thief,
Sagawa-san showed the ring off to everyone.
Then, while Nishino-san was showering,
he snuck into his room and hid
his own ring under the bed.
And then he took the pen.
All to make Nishino-san look like the thief.
However, that's when the
second incident took place.
Sagawa-san was shot
to death by the Scorpion.
The Scorpion was most likely after the ring
and a tape that revealed his identity somehow.
But the ring hanging from his neck was gone,
so the Scorpion ransacked
the room in search of it.
Wow, old man! That's amazing logic!
For me, this is child's play!
Which means the Scorpion is still
lurking on this ship somewhere?!
About that...
an emergency life raft is missing.
What?!
So the Scorpion escaped in that?!
I put out an emergency APB, but I
believe finding him may be difficult.
Slipped right through our fingers...
Did the Scorpion really escape?
In any event, it's a relief to know
the murderer is no longer on board.
Right?
Yes. Very relieved.
But there's still a chance
the Scorpion will appear
at the Kosaka family castle for the other egg.
Eh?
No, he may be headed there already.
Inspector Megure, as soon as
we arrive in Tokyo tomorrow,
I'd like to go to the castle
with Natsumi-san and the others.
Understood. Do that.
Hey! You heard him!
You're absolutely not coming along this time!
No. Let's take Conan-kun, too.
What?!
His unique ideas could prove useful.
His?
Yes.
That dumb Conan makes me so mad!
Yeah! He doesn't contact us
even once after going to Osaka!
He doesn't realize he's a member
of the Junior Detective League!
Doctor, have you still not
found your driver's license?
I know I put it around here somewhere...
Edogawa-kun's going to
beat us there if we don't hurry.
You're so good at finding things, Ai-kun!
It would seem I've found
another bit of trouble.
- Eh?
- Tada!
Mori-san, do you think
Sagawa-san's ring really belonged to Maria?
I dunno. Inspector Megure
took it in to have it looked at, but...
Supposedly, Maria was the
kindest of the four sisters
and had large, gray eyes.
Gray eyes? That's just like
Natsumi-san and Seiran-san!
I believe you know that the entire
imperial family was shot to death
after the Russian Revolution,
but the bodies of Maria and the
crown prince were never identified.
Really?
It's such a pretty castle!
It's similar to the
Neuschwanstein Castle in Germany.
It's said that it was the model
for the Cinderella Castle.
Huh? Come to think of it,
why is it a German-style castle?
Natsumi-san's
great-grandmother was Russian...
Yo! Conan!
Conan-kun!
- How are you?
- Doc! Why are you here?
Oh, I got a call from Conan-kun.
So I dropped by while on a drive.
Here. I upgraded them just like you asked.
Thanks!
But why'd you hafta bring them?
They snuck into the car
while I wasn't watching.
This is almost like right out of a fairytale!
The treasure must be hidden inside!
I wonder how many boxed
eel lunches it could buy!
Listen, you!
You're absolutely not allowed inside!
- Yes!
- We know!
Oh, geez. They're being
a little too well-behaved.
Inui-san is late.
Yes. He said he had to drop
by somewhere along the way.
Sorry about that!
Took me a while to get ready!
What's with the bag?
Are you going exploring or something?
It's like they say,
"You can never be too prepared."
You'd best be careful. The Scorpion
could be closer than you think.
Yeah. I know.
- Please lock the door.
- Huh?
- To keep the kids out.
- Yes.
- Alright! Let's go, too!
- What are you planning to do?
We're gonna find the treasure first!
There must be another entrance! Let's find it!
Hey!
This is the Room of Knights.
It's decorated with Western
suits of armor and tapestries.
This is the Noble Women's Room.
The late mistress often
spent much time in here.
She said this was the most comfortable room.
This is the Emperor's Room.
Say. I need to use the restroom...
The restroom is in the hallway,
the furthest room on your right.
Just as I thought!
Doesn't look like the egg
is here, but that's okay!
What in the world?!
This is a security device
Kiichi-sama built 80 years ago.
There are many such traps
planted throughout the castle,
so please be careful.
In short, trying to beat
everyone to it is forbidden, Inui-san.
A flashlight should be the only tool you need.
Kiichi-san sure loved his
contraptions. Which means...
Say. Does this castle have a basement?
No.
Then where on the first floor
is the great-grandfather's room?
Oh, that would be his office.
Please, come in.
Photographs of Kiichi-sama
and daily scenes from the time
are on display in here.
Say, Natsumi-san. Where are the
pictures of your great-grandmother?
Actually, there aren't any.
So I don't know what she looked like.
That's odd. There are all these
pictures of Kiichi-san, though...
Hey! Isn't this man Rasputin?!
Yes. That's definitely him.
The signature even says "G. Rasputin."
G. Rasputin?
Hey, Dad. Who's Rasputin?
O-Oh, uhh, all I know is he was one
of the century's greatest villains...
He was known as Rasputin, the Mad Monk.
He won favor with the imperial family,
then caused the downfall
of the Romanov Dynasty.
He ruled as he saw fit for a short while,
but ultimately, Prince Yusupov,
a relative of the emperor, killed him.
When his body was found in
the river, his skull was caved in,
and one of his eyes had been...
crushed, or so they say.
One of his eyes?!
Inui-san, the other egg is more
important than Rasputin right now.
Even so, how are we supposed
to find it in this huge house?
Old man! Let me have that!
H-Hey, you!
There's wind coming from below!
There's a secret basement under here!
What?!
And, given that Kiichi-san
loved making contraptions,
there's gotta be a switch somewhere!
What is that?!
The Russian alphabet!
That opens the door to the secret basement?!
I think there's a password.
Sergei-san! Try typing in Russian words!
Right.
It's gotta be "memories"! "Vospominaniya!"
Vospominaniya...
Huh?
Then try "Kiichi Kosaka"!
Kiichi Kosaka...
Nothing's happening.
Natsumi-san, are there any words
that were passed down to you?
No. Nothing.
"Barushe niku katta be ka?"
Eh?
That phrase you mentioned
might actually be Russian!
- Hey. What's he talking about?
- Shh! Quiet!
Natsumi-san, "Barushe..." what?
"...niku katta be ka?"
"Barushe niku katta be ka?"
The spaces in the words might be different!
"Baru sheni kukatta bekka..."
"Barusheni..."
Could it be "Volshebnick Consta Veka"?
Yes! Volshebnik Consta Veka!
What does that mean?!
In English, "The Last Wizard
of the Century." In Japanese...
"...Seikimatsu no Majutsushi."
The Last Wizard of the Century?
Why does that sound familiar?
The Kid's warning letter!
That's right! Talk about a big coincidence!
Coincidence? Is it really?!
In any case, I'll try typing it in.
Volshebnik Consta Veka...
W-What's that sound?!
I didn't know about this!
Well done, boy!
No luck! This one's locked, too!
Darn it! They're gonna beat us
to the treasure if we don't hurry!
Hey! Ai-kun! Where are you going?!
Just going to check out that tower.
Haibara! Is there something there?!
- I bet there's treasure!
- That would be great!
It's open!
Huh?
What's the deal, Haibara? There's nothing here.
I never said there was anything.
Hey! We should just give up and leave now!
What?!
O-Oh no!
That hurt, you guys...
- You have a soft stomach!
- It saved us from getting hurt!
What's this?
Snake!
It's not a snake. It's a rope ladder.
It's rather old, too.
It looks like it originally
hung from up there, but snapped.
Stupid thing, scaring us like that...
What'll it be? Wait here
for the doc to rescue us?
Or keep going forward?
- That goes...
- ...without asking.
Let's go!
- Still, Natsumi-san...
- Yes?
Why was the password
"The Last Wizard of the Century"?
I think my great-grandfather
might have been called that.
When he was 16, he exhibited
wind-up dolls at the 1900 Paris Expo,
and then went to Russia after that.
I see. 1900 truly was the end of the century.
It still keeps going?
This place is really far down...
What is it?
- I heard a faint noise!
- The Scorpion?!
- I'll check it out!
- Conan-kun!
I'll go!
Mori-san, please stay here with the others.
Got it!
You?!
You guys?!
Conan-kun!
Geez...
? The thing that can attain
your love in this world!?
What are they doing?
Come now, Mori-san! The more, the merrier!
Still...
♪ The mystery begins to unravel! ♪
♪ You still don't suspect a thing... ♪
- Huh?
- A dead-end!
Did we take a wrong turn somewhere?
That can't be. There was only one passageway.
Which means there's some
kind of mechanism here, too...
Wow! Look at all the birds!
Huh? That's strange!
The big bird has two heads!
A double-headed eagle... An imperial crest.
Yeah.
Is that the sun behind the crown?
Sun... Light?
Could it be?!
Shiratori-san! Try putting a
narrow beam of light on that crown!
O-Okay.
It shined! What the...
Everyone get back!
An entrance! Now I see...
There's a photometer in this crown.
Whoa...
What a contraption...
It's like we're inside an egg...
What's this?
It appears to be a coffin.
It's Western in design, but made of paulownia.
That's a huge lock, though...
Natsumi-san! That key!
Oh, right!
So this is what it opens...
Which means inside the coffin is...
- May I open it?
- Y-Yes.
It's pretty heavy...
One corpse... and the egg.
It's as if the person's
holding the egg while asleep.
Natsumi-san, is this your great-grandfather?
No. I think it might be great-grandmother.
My great-grandfather has
a lone grave in Yokosuka,
which I always thought was strange.
It's possible that she couldn't
be buried in the ancestral plot
because she was Russian.
Natsumi-san, I know this is hardly
the time, but may I see the egg?
Yes.
Here you are.
There is a small hole in the bottom.
It's empty inside?!
That can't be!
What does this mean?!
Inside?
Is that a matryoshka?
- Eh?!
- A matryoshka?!
I have one at home!
My dad's friend bought us
one as a souvenir from Russia!
What's a matryo... shka?
A Russian doll in which smaller
and smaller dolls are placed inside.
Yes, it could be possible! Have a look!
It appears the notches inside are
meant to keep the inner egg in place.
Damn! If only we had
that egg, we could find out!
We do have the egg.
I thought this might happen,
so I borrowed it from Chairman Suzuki.
Hey, now. You didn't borrow it
without telling him, did you?!
O-Oh, come now.
You know I would never do that...
Let's test it out, then.
It fits perfectly!
In other words, Kiichi-san
didn't make two separate eggs,
he made the two eggs as one.
- You seem dissatisfied.
- Yeah.
I can't shake the feeling there's
more to the eggs than just that.
Something worthy of the name
"The Last Wizard of the Century..."
Those are some incredible diamonds!
No, I don't think they're diamonds.
Huh?
I think they might be ordinary glass.
Glass?!
Wait a minute! Come to think of it...
The glass on the inside of the egg's lid...
Kiichi-san's room...
The mechanism with the light...
And that pedestal!
It has to be! The pieces of glass
in the eggs are meant to be lenses!
Sergei-san! Let me see the egg!
Not more of your...
Hold on, Mori-san!
Can I help somehow?
Bring your light!
Narrow the beam, and put it in the pedestal!
Understood!
Sergei-san! Seiran-san! Put out the candles!
What's this all about?
Just watch.
I can see inside the eggs!
The imperial family figure is
rising without any winding-up!
There's a photometer inside the Egg.
W-What the...
T-These are...
...photographs of
Emperor Nicholai and his family!
I see! The figures inside the egg
weren't looking at an ordinary book!
It was an album!
So that's why it's the "Memories Egg..."
Had the imperial family
survived to receive this,
never would they have
been given a greater present!
Your great-grandfather truly
was the last wizard of the century!
I think my great-grandmother
would be delighted to hear that.
Say, Natsumi-san.
Isn't that your
great-grandfather in that photograph?
That one with two people sitting in a chair.
It is! That must be my
great-grandmother with him, then!
My great-grandmother... I finally
get to see what she looks like...
This must be the only
photograph taken in Japan.
Kiichi-sama must've added it in afterward.
Huh? She...
...looks just like Natsumi-san...
It seems this egg is Kiichi-san's...
no, Japan's... treasured legacy.
Russia hereby forfeits the
ownership rights of both eggs.
It appears they are worth
their most in your hands.
Thank you.
But the inner egg
belongs to Chairman Suzuki...
I'll speak with Chairman Suzuki myself!
I'm sure he'll understand!
Huh? Come to think of it,
where'd Inui-san go?
Rasputin.
He wasn't in any of the photographs,
even though he was close
to the imperial family.
Yeah. He was in a photo in Kiichi-san's room...
That Russian "G"! It couldn't be!
In any case, all has ended well!
That's...
Now, then!
Look out!
What's the big idea?!
Don't pick it up, Ran!
Ran!
Shinichi?!
Everyone get down!
The egg!
Dammit! You're not getting away!
Don't!
Mori-san! You take care of things here!
Yeah...
Shinichi?
Inui-san!
Dammit!
Crap!
There has to be a switch
to open it from the inside!
This one spot is a different shape!
Hold it right there!
You're expecting too much
if you think we'll just let you go!
We know who you really are.
You pretend to be Chinese,
but you're really actually Russian.
Isn't that right...
...descendant of "Mad Monk" Rasputin...
...Seiran-san?
W-What's this?! The path's sealed!
Does that mean we can't get out?!
Follow me, everyone!
Eh?!
What?!
Just do what I say!
O-Okay!
I didn't realize it at first.
That voice! Sagawa?!
When you rearrange your
Chinese name of "Pusu Chinran,"
you get "Rasputin"!
I-I killed you!
The Romanov Dynasty's treasures
were supposed to go to Rasputin,
who shared a deep connection
with the imperial family.
Convinced of that, you decided to
gather all those treasures yourself
for your ancestor's sake.
Your insistence on shooting
people in the right eye
is to avenge your
savagely-murdered ancestor, isn't it?
I-Inui?
- I'm alone.
- What?!
This is called a voice-changing bowtie.
It can produce all kinds of voices.
Who are you?!
Edogawa Conan. A detective.
You killed Sagawa-san because
your identity could've been revealed.
Because he went to people's
rooms and filmed them on tape.
It happened so quick that you forgot
to turn the photo upside-down.
It wasn't a photo of your lover.
It was of Grigorii Rasputin!
Grigorii starts with a G, and looks
like an upside-down L in Russian.
So his Russian signature on
the photo in Kiichi-san's room
didn't make the connection obvious.
Convinced that Sagawa-san
caught your Rasputin photo on video,
you went to kill him.
Isn't that right, Seiran-san?
Or should I say, Scorpion?!
I'm impressed, little boy.
I take it you killed Inui-san
because he saw you attaching
the silencer to that gun?
My, my. It's almost
as if you saw it yourself.
But you went after the old man
because he insulted Rasputin.
Hey, Dad. Who's Rasputin?
O-Oh, uhh, all I know is he was one
of the century's greatest villains...
And then you even tried to kill Ran...
That's enough talk now.
It's a real shame, but now
it's your time to die, too!
That gun's a Walther PPK/S, isn't it?
It holds eight bullets per magazine.
One each for Inui-san, the old man,
and Ran, and the five just now...
You're out of bullets.
Here's an interesting tidbit for you.
If a bullet's already loaded when
you insert an 8-bullet magazine,
you get 9 shots.
In other words, there's
one more bullet in this gun.
Shoot, then.
If there really is a bullet left.
Foolish little boy.
How?!
Too bad, Scorpion.
I asked the Doc to remodel these
glasses with especially hard glass.
Conan-kun! Are you okay?!
Y-Yeah! I guess!
Alright! Let's get out of here!
Conan-kun!
I'm saved...
O-Oh no! The castle is on fire!
Conan-kun!
Shinichi...
You dummy...
- Conan-kun!
- Conan!
What? Quit yelling.
Conan-kun!
Detective Shiratori took this
egg back from the Scorpion.
Shiratori did?!
What happened to the Scorpion, then?!
He arrested the Scorpion, Seiran-san,
and took her away in his car.
What?!
Seiran-san was the Scorpion?!
Here! He told me to give
it to you, Natsumi-san!
Thank you!
I can't believe Seiran-san was the Scorpion.
She had such beautiful legs...
Natsumi-san, I'm sorry
it turned out like this...
Not at all! The castle may've burned down,
but I still have this precious
egg my great-grandfather made!
Besides, I think the basement will be safe.
Yes. Once everything has calmed down,
we'll bury your great-grandmother
next to Kiichi-sama.
So the Kid never showed up at all...
Do you think maybe he really is dead?
No. He's alive.
The old guy's already asleep.
He seemed really exhausted.
Yeah. I can't blame him. A lot happened.
Ran-neechan?
Thanks for saving me at the castle.
You were really cool then, Conan-kun.
You were just like Shinichi!
You were really just like Shinichi...
Ran...
But you're different people, right?
You're different, right...
...Conan-kun?
I can't do it anymore.
L-Listen, Ran...
The truth is, I'm actually...
Shinichi?!
Eh?!
Is that really you, Shinichi?!
What kind of hello is that?
I came to check on you after I
heard you got caught in an incident...
This... can't be!
You dummy! What were you doing?
Why didn't you ever call?!
Sorry 'bout that.
It's just case after case, so...
I have to leave again tonight.
Wait here! I'll get you some dry clothes!
Not so fast, Kaito Kid.
You had me completely fooled.
I never suspected you were on the ship,
disguised as Det. Shiratori.
Oh! Shiratori-kun!
You did a great job this time!
Huh? What do you mean?
I just got back from Karuizawa...
Huh?!
You knew something
would happen on that ship.
I wasn't really sure of it, but I
bugged the ship's phone line anyway.
One other thing.
You tried to steal the egg so you
could return it to Natsumi-san,
its true owner.
You knew that Kosaka Kiichi-san made it,
and that he was known as
"The Last Wizard of the Century."
That's why you used it in that letter.
Oh? Anything else you've realized?
Do you mean how Natsumi-san's
great-grandmother was Maria,
the third daughter of Emperor Nicholai II?
Maria's body was never found.
That's because Kiichi-san
helped her flee to Japan
before she was shot and killed.
Love blossomed between them,
and they had a baby.
But immediately after, she passed away.
To protect Maria's body from
the Russian revolutionary army,
Kiichi-san sold her jewels and built a castle.
But he chose a German-style
castle rather than a Russian one
because her mother,
Empress Alexandra, was German.
So Maria and the egg were buried
in the secret underground room.
And in the other egg,
he left a clue about the castle.
In the hope that a descendant would find it.
In this way, all the mysteries are solved.
I have one piece of advice for you.
There are some mysteries
in the world best left alone.
Yeah, it might be best to leave
this particular mystery a mystery.
Then, can you solve
this mystery, great detective?
Why did I show up as Kudo Shinichi
and help you, a dangerous foe?
Shinichi!
Don't be stupid. That's no mystery at all.
You only helped me as thanks for
tending to this guy. Isn't that right?
Urgh! Why didn't you
stop him for me, Conan-kun?!
But Shinichi-niichan said he'd come back again!
Good! The next time I see him...
...I'm gonna do that to him!
I guess I can't turn back to
normal for a while, then...