Atlantic Ocean, before 15 years
Watru Kaido, 41 years old
Iceberg up ahead
turn to the left
Captian
Captian, are you alright?
sorry
Captian...
Captian
hang on captian
vice captian...
half month earlier west of Tama town
Yashiro's Residence
(Hideto Yashiro, 49 years old
Ship Engineer)
Beautiful view
Great sunset view wish
Shinichi with us to watch it
I'm watching it now...
what?
you can watch it better from here
ofcourse it's better
but it's so umberessing
we see that Conan
put me down Ran
we saw it
did you ask Ran to hold you?
I didn't, stupid
your face turned to red Conan
what are you saying it's because of the sunset
really, this kid very shy
not that, stupid
what are you saying it's because of the sunset
it's the same as that time
what?
nothing
what is it? tell me
I told you it's nothing
I know there is something
Detective CONAN
Strategy Above The Depth
I'm detective Kodu Shinichi
While I was with my fiance Ran Mori at fun city
I saw a man wearing a black suit
making an illegal deal
but then while I was busy watching
his friend knocked me from behind
then forced me to take a medicene
when I woke up
my body shrank
if the gang wearing black suits
discovers Kudo still alive
then everybody I know will be in danger
I did as Prof Agasa advised me
and hid my identity
so when Ran asked me about my name
I told her Edogawa Conan
in purpose to find any lead to them,
I decided to live in Ran's Father
investgation agency apartment
I'm Genta Kojima, school boy detective
first year class 2
I'm Metsu, the same class
I'm Aiumy Yushida
with my assistor Conan
and Ai, we form
the detective squad kids
this is the squad badge
contains wirless chip inside
we can use it also to track others movments
this watch can produce light
we can use it under water
because it's against water
this two devices invented by Prof. Agasa
Prof. Agasa invented many useful tools for me
since my body shrank
among these tools,
the trenqulizer watch and the voice changer tie
it is the reason which give birth
to the famous sleeping detective Muri
yeah, Hiybara Ai
she's acting cool all the time
also she looks mature
ofcourse she is
Hiybara Ai, her real name is Shohu Miano
she was a member of the black suits gang
but to escape from them...
she forced herself to eat the same medecine
I ate before, so her body shrank
that's why
I'm not a high school detective anymore
but elementry school detective instead
I solved a lot and tough cases
in addition to learn more about
black suits gang
when I think of my uncle...
you better ply more
to enhance yourself
even after my body shrank
my brain still the same
detectives never surrenders
because the truth is always there
wow very huge
ofcourse
Yashiro's companies group
is very huge
it's the first luxurious trip
for Yashiro's group
so expect to see more
sir
are you Mr. Muri
yes
one minute please,
I'll ready your table right now
Prof. Agasa, what is this?
this... it's a voice recorder
I want to record any idea come to my mind
yeah, by the way, speaking of new inventions
here, headphones in buttons shape
you can use it as mic also
beautiful
looks beautiful
buttons?
perfect timing, I'll take it
but..
hey brat, this only suits
a great man like me
too early for a brat like you to wear it
but father, it's...
don't worry Ran
I don't think I'll use it inside this ship
Mr. Muri
are you the famous detective Togo Muri
yeah it's me
great
what is it with that guy?
(Kasaka Hiranatori 26 years old Writer)
I'm Kasaka Hiranatori, I'm a writer
I'm a big fan Mr. Muri
Thanks
she is miss Minako Akayushi
she's the second engineer
who assist designing this ship
(Minako Akayushi 32 years old Ships Engineer)
also she's the one who named this ship aphrodite
I'm Akayushi, glad to meet you
I'm Muri
she's beautiful
yes
excuse me Mr. Muri
sorry for taking long, your table is ready
excuse me
can you add two more chairs
if you don't mind Mr.Muri
follow me please
uncle acting weird
why you think so?
you know the normal uncle will say:
"aphrodite godess of beauti"
"this name suits you more"
he would say this usually
I think because she looks like my mother
is that so
she looks like her indeed
so that's the type of women he afraids of
actually...
I write story takes a place
in a luxurious sea trip
that's why I made interview
with miss Minako. right?
yes
I see
by the way Mr. Muri,
did you receive invitation also?
or you came to explore something?
actually, about the invitation...
sorry, we didn't receive any?
didn't receive anything?
who received the invitation
are Sonoko's parents
her father is the president of Suzuki company
actually my parents have a lot of work
that's why I'm here
it's not fun coming alone
that's why I asked them to come along
we got 8 more tickets that way
I get it now
we are more like a kinder garden
I see...
ok then
which type of stories you write?
is it about a sea cruise around the world?
intresting
that's right
or is it like Titanic
which sank at first cruise
what are you saying Ai?
by the way
I heared one of Yashiru's ships sank
after crashing into iceberg
true, that was at winter 15 years ago
they say it was the captian mistake
one of the crew members died there
and the captian sank along with the ship
really?
what if this ship sink also? what will we do?
I only can swim for 7 meter
don't worry
Aphrodite's captian is very profitional
and there is no icebergs in this area
if the ship sink...
the first one to save is...
those people
isn't this constructing minister Neimi
and his wife too
also celebrities
the famous actresses, I'm very lucky
those two actress are the guest of honor
Yashiro's president invited them.
talking about them...
Mr. Yashiro and his daughter are here.
lady Takai,
she's the manager of Ships constructions factory
about that, Takai's husband died
lately in a car accident
really
yes, Hedito Yashiro
he was my mentour,
and the chief of the ship development
is that so...
I heard he got heart attack
while he was driving his car
and fell under the hill
it's the captain
wonderful
he's the captain, Watru Kaido
he was the vice captain of that ship
which sank 15 years ago
that we talk about earlier
a mistake?
you mean Hedito Yashiro's accident?
Yes, before the heart attack
while he driving under the hill
but...
it was an accident,
as the local police department said
but I still think...
Ok, no harm reviewing a case
if you feel there something wrong
I'll call the local police to inform them
about your arrival
thanks
Sato, do you need help?
but you didn't finish your report yet
Shiba... will you come with me?
yes
now before we drink...
leave it to me uncle
for this wonderful trip
and...
to congratulate Ran for winning
at eastern Japan championship
cheers
thank you... you Sonoko..
you know Ran?
winning the Karate championship
is really amazing
also it's the eastern region finale
your amazing, amazing, amazing
tell me, what did Kodu gave you as a present?
Shinichi?
when I told him he said..
"Really? cool"
what? is that all?
he's busy solving tough cases
that detective maniac
didn't I say a lot of "grats" as Conan
I'm full
that stakes was delicious
I wish if I could eat delicious food everyday
dessert supposed to be next
what is it?
I feel dizzy because the sea
I'm dizzy too
dad, you are drunk
you act like mothers
your father is cool
no, he's just crazy
excuse me I'll go to my room
to get some rest
are you really ok?
I have a medicine at my room, see ya
take care
dad, are you okay?
Muri is fine
don't worry Ran
all he need is some rest
sorry
so Conan, will you take care of him for me?
sure
Prof. Agasa, forgive me
don't worry
good night Ran
the door is open, Agasa
we'll come too
- so Conan, will you...
- take care of him for me
huh?
sorry for inconvenience
what are you all doing here?
we are deciding which present to give Ran
to congratulate her
what is this?
isn't it pretty?
we collected it from the beach this morning
we are planning to make a medal
and give it to Ran
it's so sad Shinichi didn't send her a present
good luck... i'll take a shower
you're taking a shower?
what? would you like to join me?
no
let me confirm your schedule for tomorrow
breakfast at 7 am
I'll order a western food to your room
lady Takai will play tennis with miss
Neimi at 9 am
I've already reserved it at the 7th floor
president Yashiro will play snooker
at 9 am
I've already reserved it at the 3rd floor
after playing tennis lady Takai will
return to her room at 9:30 am
how refreshing
drinking tea under the sea breeze like this
no doubt it's wonderful
yeah, it's wonderful
it's wonderful
did you see it? lady Takai's legs
doesn't look like a late 50 years old legs
Dad, what are you saying it's still morning?
Prof. Agasa, isn't it about time?
time for the quiz?
sooner or later you'll say it eventually,
just spit it now
this is really offending
ok, I'll give you an easy quiz...
it's about this sea cruise
let's presume Ginta went to the infirmary...
what is the reason for that?
1- His stomach injured because he ate a lot.
2- stumbled and injured his leg.
3- He got sun burns after
taking sun bath for a long time.
ok, which one is the right answer?
if we are talking about Ginta,
the correct choice will be the 1st one
no that's impossible
my stomacach will never be injured
even if I ate too much
I got it
me too
however,
isn't this quiz very hard for the children
the Eng...
Sonoko
English? will English help us to solve it?
Ship is another tip
Ship?
I know
the answer is 2-injured his leg
we are now on the ship
and Ginta will put bondage on his injured leg
that's right
the word "friendship" contains "Ship"
also "Gosship" contains "Ship"
it's "Gossip"
ok see you at 10 o'clock
then bondage in English is "Ship"
Mitso, it's dangrous to use bondages
while in sea cruise
why is that?
your brain is really slow
right, when to give Ran her present?
we can give it to her now
how about it?
Ran let's order another Juice
ok
- we sure gonna have fun
- don't overact about it
we'll go too
for the juice
which juice shall I order?
ok let's go
wait
what is this noise?
I know the secret behind
what happened 15 years ago
meet me at the depository 10:15
I see, it happened here,
in the street near the house
let's go to the house and take a look
ok, what to do now?
we can't swim, the weather still cold
ok, I'll go change my clothes
change your clothes?
actually.. the two actress invited me
they asked me to tell them about the stories
of the famous detective Mori
bye
uncle is great
when did he get the date?
forget about him
how about it, shall we play?
want to play hide and seek
it will be entertaining
let's play
hide and seek, it brings some memories
we played it a lot when we were kids
we were playing at car parks and gardens
we used to play it at elementry school too.
really?
sorry, pass.
come on Conan
you are so boring.
As I remembered Shinichi also said "I pass"
let's play hide and seek
ok, it maybe fun
Prof. Agasa?
I have massage appointment
liar old geezer
ok, let's say the rules
time limit 30 minutes
we can hide from the first floor
to the 7th floor
hiding in deposite, cabins and bathrooms
are not allowed
ok?
ok
then gather everyone
rock, paper, scissors
it decided
wait, I can't, I can't
how can I find 6 persons in 30 minutes
on a ship with this size
I'll definitly lose
ok, we'll put another rule, choose another person
there will be two.
why not, let's try this new rule
let's play
let's do our best
sure
what a couple they make!
oh yeah, give me your detective badge
why?
Since there is two of us
we wouldn't know who catch who
that's why we will use the badge
to communicate
don't drop it.
ok let's start at 9:50
if you find us all
before 10:20 you'll win
alright, I will win for sure
sorry but we will win...
because Conan with us
how can you say that?
ok let's go
let's start
I'll find you soon enough
do you think Ran will find it?
she will find it while playing
and she will be surprised
good
catch it
this is not a good place for hiding
when the movie show start?
10 o'clock
it's better to go now
I missed it
good
I can't believe the choice fell on me
sometimes it's not that bad
to search for other people.
5 minutes passed
I'll start from the 5th floor
you take the rest
ok
Kodu
Hi Ai
do you know that
you still playing hide and seek
ok, found one
how did you know I'm here
a person like you will only hide in a resturant
Ai
didn't you get this clothes from Agasa
this makes you more obvious
ok, come on out
I thought it's a nice place for hiding
not enough, you need 10 years to
defeat me in this game
yes, Akayoshi speaking
hi miss Minako, it's me Kasaka
let's start, first the cast members...
Nanami Okashi, 22 years old
a hostess works on a classy cruise
I'll read the story now...
Nanami Okashi, likes the ocean
maybe because she born and raised near the sea
more importantly
she likes the opening of the ocean
even though we found 4 of them very easily...
we still didn't find
the person who know how to hide
is Ran really that good?
she's like Ninja, Ninja
there is no normal person hang on ceiling
or hide under water
ceiling?
under water?
she was very vibrant since childhood
let's find her, we still have 12 minutes
she's not here also
10:11
means 9 minutes left
hi, I'm Muri
I'll avenge my father
countdown
5..4..3..2..1..0
we won
all that because of Ran
yeah
Ran
you see, we won
Ran, where did you hide?
Conan, didn't you play soccer all the time
I know everything
I think Ran didn't get it yet
strange
is she really that bad at finding stuff
she still searching?
what? the floor is cold? what's happened?
box? I'm inside a box?
no, anyone, anyone help me?
help, please help me
what?
what is it Sonoko?
help me... help me.
calm down Sonoko, where are you?
I'm locked inside a box, help
Wait Sonoko say that again I can't hear you
shit
batteries out
shit, that was then
cold Sonoko, is it cold there?
locked inside a box
inside a fridge
what are you doing here?
where is the fridge?
the fridge?
please, my friend she's in danger
downstairs at the second floor
there is a lot of boxes
where is she?
let's split and search
ok
Sonoko
Sonoko, are you there?
where are you Sonoko?
let's go seems she's not here.
very cold
Sonoko, Sonoko
damn, where is she?
maybe she don't answer
cause she's already dead
don't say things like that
but where is the other cold place?
dead!.... there
there is a Mortuary in this ship?
what a surprise
it's heavy
Sonoko
hurry take her to the infirmary
Thank god
don't worry
warm yourself and rest your body
you'll be alright
thank you very much
thank god your alive Sonoko
however...
what kind of joke is this?
joke? this is not a joke
someone tried to kill her
call the police right now
understand
tell me exactly what happened?
where did it happened?
I went to search for Ran inside the depository
then someone hit my back with a rod
then I fainted
how was he look like?
I think I saw him... but I forgot
how about the time?
I remember 10:11
10:11
I see, she's been attacked here
near the Mortuary
but why she's been attacked?
that's...
it's Yashiro's steel fan
why is it here?
nobody
Mr. Muri, the captain called the police
excuse me, it's Yashiro's room
yeah, the pretty actresses told me.
I remember, someone left this room lately
who was he?
didn't see his face
he was wearing a suit with hat
when?
almost about 10:15
are you sure Mr. Muri
strange, they don't like wearing the suits
this time only lady Takai should
be alone inside
walking in the hall wearing suit and hat
like he didn't want others to see him
could it be something happened to the lady?
lady, it's Sigimoto, lady
don't you have a master key
but...
lady, excuse us
lady
don't move, stay where you are
it couldn't be...
who did it?
she died before 30 minutes
I'll call the captain
I'll tell the president
she's been stabbed after taking a shower
the blood cleaned here
why? why it's only cleaned here?
what are you doing brat?
ahhhh...
really
Mr. Muri
miss Neimi said president Yashiro left
after playing a game and never came back
what?
maybe president Yashiro involved in this case
welcome
Mr. Muri
thanks for coming inspector
did you find president Yashiro?
we don't have any idea about his location
the crew members still searching for him
but by the way...
highr in mountin or deep in the sea
cases alwayes chasing you
is your next step up in the space?
do you need a rocket to launch?
how could it be?
what? Yashiro's fingers prints?
Yes, the location was near the blood marks
and the hatch
the blood marks there matches
his blood type
thanks, keep looking
also inspector...
as the crew members saying...
seems the hatch opened then closed
it happened in a short time
what?
Fingers prints blood marks and hatch opened.
inspector, it looks...
it looks like president Yashiro
been attacked there.
then thrown to the sea from that hatch
it's a possible presumption.
yes, you are right
Shiratory, call the the coast guards...
ask them to search the area
alright
Takagi
yes
I want to speak with miss Neimi
ask her to come here
sure
ok Conan
yes
go to your room, we'll take care of the rest
stay at your room and never leave it
under any reason
the killer still out somewhere
ok
it's cake
look delicious
stakes
small piece won't harm.
even small piece will harm you
right prof. Agasa
we will take some to Ran and Sonoko
they must be hungry now
No, leave it to the doctor
he knows what best for her
and Ran said she will eat later
and not to worry about her
really?
Mitsu
do you think she got the present?
I don't think she's in a good mood for that
yeah
where is Conan?
yeah he's not around
do you think he's listening
to the police investigations
maybe...
he know how to play
that kind of hide and seek game
thanks for the help
I hope you catch the killer very soon
yes
let's say lady Takai returned to
her room after a game of tennis
then murdered after taking a shower
this means that guy wearing the suit
which Mr. Muri saw at the hallway
then, let's presume
that guy went to the depository
and killed president Yashiro there.
it makes sense now
so, it's very possible these...
these two crimes done by one person
Mr. Muri, how the killer looks like?
170 cm tall I guess
his body almost skinny
we can't define the sex by the tall only
Yes, lady Takai was at the same tall
miss Sigimoto is this the suit?
yes
it's a present given to all passengers
but anyone can have...
even the crew can get it very easily
Shiratory,
what is the motive behind these crimes?
it must be revenge or hatred
the victims wallets
and jewelleries not touched
even the door knob not broken
that means the victim
invited the killer into her room
or the killer used
the master key to sneak in
Mr. Misaki, who's else have the master key?
a lot
security guards, hosts, and miss Natsu
have one cause she's on charge for this trip
I see
inspector, the killer was waiting
for the right time for the victim to be alone
If that's the truth maybe the killer
knew about their schedule
Miss Sigimoto , since you are
their secretary did you know their schedule
yes
who's else know the schedule?
I told security chief Misaki about it
but I didn't tell anyone else.
that means if you are taller by 10 cm
or Mr. Misaki was less 10 kg weight.
you would be the first suspects
and there's another case
- Sonoko's case
- I wonder if it's connected to these two
by the way, you walked near the killer
but didn't see his face
ok, I was...
however inspector...
it's a ship in a middle of ocean
I'm sure the killer still on board
if we add the crew members to the passengers,
we'll get 600 suspects
anyway Takagi
try to find any witnesses among the passengers
ok
miss Sigimoto
please tell me more about crew and passengers
sure
That's right
Shiratory is right
how did the killer know their schedule?
miss Natsu didn't tell anyone about it
she's...
that's right, if he used...
can I ask you something aunt
Conan?
you brat, from where...
did you read to Mr and lady yashiros the
schedule last night at their room?
Yes after dinner, I went to their room
and read it to them
was there a time the room
was empty last night?
ok, last night president Yashiro said he's tired
so after dinner he went to sleep
the only time there was no one inside
the room, was at dinner time
that's it
you...
didn't you hear what I just said?
it hurts
Mr. Misaki did someone
miss his dinner last night?
I think everybody was there
then the killer is one of the crew members
excuse me I'll go to my room
to get some rest
aunt, did Mr Kasaka make an interview with you?
Mr. Hiranatori Kasaka, ofcourse he did
is it possible that you lost one of
your master keys then
stop, how could something like this happen?
ok actually...
we lost a master key before 3 weeks
really?
as Conan said...
it happened right after the interview
with Kasaka
wait a minute, who's this Kasaka guy
you are talking about
he's ascenario writer,
made interview with us several times
I see
Conan, is there anything suspecious about him?
yes, Mr Kasaka went to his room at dinner time
he said he dizzy because of the sea
but I think he sneak to the Yashiros room
and listened to what they said
fool, he's not a kid like you.
how can he listen to them?
microphone
maybe he plant a microphone inside
that's it then
what do you think Muri
what Kasaka looks like?
ok, he's the same as the one I passed by
good, let's pay Mr. Kasaka a visit.
that's it, microphone
not bad from the famous detective Muri
no that was because Conan idea
which led us to this point
I see.
but you are wrong
because at 10:15
I was speaking to miss Minako by phone
do you mean miss Minako who designed this ship?
yes, we are in a middle of ocean,
mobiles doesn't works
that's why I used the phone
how long does the call take?
from ten, about 30 minutes
you can investigate the call data
that would be more accurate
what did you tell her at the phone
if you don't mind telling us, of course
we spoke about the story
and her opinion about it.
story?
yes
I'm writing a story
taking a place in a sea cruise
I learned how ships works from her
love story in a sea cruise?
I'm still single
I don't want her to feel inconvenience
why you didn't speak to her directly?
you are at the same ship
she still single like me
meeting at her room is a bad idea
we could meet at cafe
but maybe someone hear us and steal the story
in our business we always take precautious steps
I see
I feel Mr Kasaka is innocent
we are not sure yet, we need more proofs
I'm thirsty
let's go drink something
what is it Mr. Muri
did you like that chick?
she's really pretty
Mr. Misaki told me what happened
ofcourse, Mr. Kasaka called me at 10 o'clock
and we spoke for 30 minutes
I promised to give him my opinion about his story
he asked me during the tea time
he's about to finish it and he needs my opinion
he said he will call at 10 o'clock
and asked me to wait
that's it then, you confirm his side of story
sorry for inconvenience
at this case, Kasaka is not guilty
unless the two of them are guilty
the phone he used is not wireless
so he can't go to president
Yashiro while talking
what is it Mr. Muri
I'm sure he's thinking of miss Minako
he's right, she's hot.
- that means...
- yo experts
inspector Migury.
how was it?
we searched the room
but we didn't find any clue
really
except the floor near the body
there was a brown liquid trail
brown liquid
it wasn't blood, Mr. Tomi
nope, even though it looks like it
then thats...
inspector Migury
I asked everyone at 6th floor
but no one witnessed any crime
really?
the welcome party will begin at 5 o'clock
let's ask more people before that time
ok
yes inspector...
we'll take these evidences to HQ
thank you
aunt
I was searching for you,
can I ask you something?
sure little detective
what is it?
what did Mr. Kasaka say to you at the phone
we talked much...
he was reading his story
and I was just listening
just listening?
yes, he'll get angry if I intersect him
"Please shutup and listen".
it happened before
that's why I'd never intersect him
so, before Kasaka finish his story...
you were just listening?
that's right
then after 20 minutes
he asked me about my opinion
I told him it was interesting
finished
for you
thanks
how are you now Sonoko?
better
if I knew that will happen
I wouldn't play that game
no problem
by the way, when we start the game
sorry, but we will win...
what was you thinking about?
we used to play when we were kids
that day at the school
we were at the first year
we asked Shinichi to play with us
Shinichi did you hear me?
Shinichi
play hide and seek with us
it will be fun
sorry, pass
soccer mach will begin very soon
how rude?
he's rude even when he was kid
so Shinichi didn't play with us
do you remember the store room
under the rostrum
the place where they store the chairs in
there was only one door behind the ladder
you hid there?
Yes, I thought no one will finds me
if I hide there
but the teacher passed by
and returned the ladder
so I couldn't get out
and then?
no one finds me so I couldn't get out
I was afraid at that time
but Shinichi found me very easily
while we returning
I asked him how did he find me?
"School Monsters"
in that movie the kids who hid
inside the school got eaten by monsters
so the probability that
you could hide inside is zero
wait a minute,
how did you know I watched that movie?
you always look at the movie poster
every time we pass the movie store
and you always scares of monsters
that means you watched it for sure
so I figured that
you will hide outside the school
you will not hide in the pet farm
cause you like pets
the basketball team were cleaning...
so no way you could hide there.
swimming pool is at the entrance
that leaves only the rostrum
that's why it's obvious
and when we took a class there...
you looked behind the ladder once
what? surprised?
Shinichi are you watching me all the time?
stupid, why would I?
your face turned to red
what are you saying?
It's because of the sunset
now I know
yesterday when you said
"it's the same as that time" you meant that
and when you said before the game...
"sorry but we will win"
"the only one can find me is Shinichi"
right?
- no it's not
- your face turned to red
what are you saying?
it's because of the sunset
uncle, what were you doing in Kasaka's room?
coming
the little kid this time
came to play
I saw it before, this computer is magnificent
yeah, I use it for work
it's not a game for kids
yeah
this machine is like the one Agasa have.
why can't I hear anything
hey kid
get out
it's impossible
that he still hold the evidence
our vacation ruined this time
why you say that Ginta?
it's serious this time
indeed
why always people hurts each other?
it would be great if everyone
can live happier ever after
it's impossible
every single human have feelings
you can't feel what others feels
because it changes with time
pure relation will never change
but for some reasons, it may changes
into jealousy and hatred
that's when intention for killing appear
my parents always fight
but they still ok
that because they care for
each other, they love each other
Ai is right, sometimes...
people hurts each others
but to avoid all this...
we must think and care about others
to care for others?
prof. Agasa
I want you to lend me something
"Tama's westren side police department"
seat belt lock
come here Shiba
yes
have you found something?
take a look
this is the seat belt lock
See the marks here as if something
were tide in it
right, looks like a kite's thread
a kite's thread?
what are you doing here uncle?
where were you? the party about to begin
Mr. Muri, the inspector want to see you
the inspector
ok
I'll come now
stay here and wear your clothes
that's it then
there's some doubts about Hedito's accident
there is a mistake as miss Sato told us.
the marks in the seat belt lock
what do you think Mr. Muri?
ok, nothing else?
right
a juice can and other useless stuff.
but it is garbage, nothing much.
juice can and kite's thread...
if he use this
did I scare ya
you brat...
I wanted to use a cola can
to make a crack
but they don't sell cola here
you said cola?
I almost got a heart attack
if he uses a can to do it...
stun grenade...
maybe the killer used a stun grenade
ofcourse
what are you saying Shiratory?
Stun grenade...
stun grenade similer to flash bombs
it makes a huge voice and light
they always use it to part demonstrators
it's a grenade with a size of the cola can
if the killer used the thread
to tide the grenade key
then attached the thread
with the seat belt and tide it to it's lock.
when the victim pull the belt to tide it...
I see
even if didn't got a heart attack
he will panic and can't drive
that's how the car fell from the hill
but it's not easy to get a stun grenade
nothing impossible these days with money
unfortunatly everyone can buy some
since it's only used to scare others
they can use fireworks also
inspector, a message from the coasts guards
they found a body
which they think it's president Yshiro's
captain I want to speak with you
what is it?
about the party, I hope you cancel it
if the killer have more plans...
he may execute it and make chaos
but this...
please captain
no inspector
we will not cancel the party tonight
everything will clear up then
don't tell me Muri you...?
he started now
but he's not sleep yet
are you really ready for this uncle?
ok let's enjoy
I missed the fun for half day
it's better to begin now
Sonoko, how you...
let's tell Ran now
ask her about it
I think so
medal made from sea shells?
but the thread was too short
so we made a bracelet
that's mean you didn't find it
how disappointing
sorry, I promise to search for it later
thanks anyway, I'm really happy
welcome everyone onboard the Aprodite
I'm Natsu Sigimoto, the manager of this trip
I'll gladly start the party
thanks everyone
allow me to introduce the main staff
onboard this ship
first security chief Noya Misaki
second doctor Mizo Kubo
this is our chef Katsue Shiyumi
did you find the killer
yes but still don't have evidence
now everyone I'll introduce to you...
the captain Watru Kaido
before the begining I want to introduce
the woman who designed this ship
Minako Akayushi
I heared lady Yashiro murdered
is it true?
there is another rumor
says president Yashiro is dead
thats...
- you are police officers?
- did you catch the killer?
is it safe to make a party now?
silence please everyone, silence
what happened exactly...?
actually... Muri san?
Muri san?
please quiet everyone..
no need to worry now
I know the truth behind these serial crimes
I'm the famous detective Muri
I've waited for a long time, famous detective
first killed lady Takai
then killed president Yashiro
the killer is...
you, miss Minako Akayushi
the motive for your crimes is...
revenge for the death of Hedito
who died in car accident
the accident which done by
lady Takai and president Yashiro
but why would she revenge Hedito's death?
probably because they secretly married
wait Mr. Muri
it's true that I respected Hedito as a tutor
but there is no relationship.
add to this...
there is a proof that
I was speaking with Mr. Kasaka at that time
maybe that's right, but actually...
you let Mr. Kasaka read the story
but you didn't say anything
that's mean you don't have a proof
don't presists please
what if Kasaka stop and talk to me?
he would know I wasn't listening
I'm not stupid to give a weak proof like this
if you still think I'm the killer
then show me the proof please
that's right Muri, do you have proof?
ah.... no...
I can't believe my dad accused her
because she looks like mom
so Mr. Muri...
excuse me, it's bathroom time
time?
that's it
inspector, now while everybody loughing
do something
but...
don't worry inspector Miguri
because I know who did it
are you sure Prof. Agasa
great
now it's Prof. Agasa time
do everyone know the meaning of "Cruisder"?
it means The theft of the pirates
that because pirates way
of hunting and chasing their preys
there is a pirate on this ship
he doesn't hunt money or jewelry
but souls, yes it's a pirate doing
that pirate is the scenario writer
it's you, Kasaka Hiranatori
strange, didn't you hear
what miss Minako just said?
I have a proof I was reading the story
at that time
is this is the story your talking about
Nanami Okashi, likes the ocean
maybe because she born
and raised near the sea
more importantly she likes the opening
of the ocean
it's an easy trick
you played the tape which you recorded earlier
and murdered the two of them while that time
impossible I got rid of it
got rid of it?
you may think so, but not
you should clean your traces twice
it's a fake evidence, right?...the tape.
you recorded it using voice changer tie
that's right
but I have the perfect proof
this is not a proof that I killed someone
if you want a proof
look there
what's up uncle?
there is a black color on your red hair
could it be a blood?
blood?
wait Mr. Kasaka
yes
uncle, your hair color the same
as the blood color
that's why you didn't notice it
remember
blood get dry very soon
and color change
also, please remove the scarf you are wearing
if I was right, there should be...
some marks around your neck
caused by president Yashiro
excuse me
can you come with me Mr. Kasaka?
wait a minute, stop.
I still have one more thing
The winning card
don't move or I'll blow up this ship
bombs?
cooperate with me
if you don't want to sink this ship
it's him, it's the guy who attacked me.
at last you remembered
please calm down
why you did all this?
to avenge my father
revenge?
the man who died 15 years ago
aboard Yashiro's ship
was my father
yes, that...
I learned about it
when I met a friend of my father 2 years ago
there was a rumor about the accident
Takai Yashiro who was the manager
and president Yashiro
they drowned the ship,
to get benefit from the securing sum
also they wanted to get rid of captain Okita cause
he always wanted to improve the crew situations
they Have offered a bribe to the vice captain
and you accepted it
you forced the captain to sleep
after adding sleeping pills to his tea
and you hit the iceberg to sink the ship
at the same time you bombed the ship
doesn't Hedito Yashiro the one
who told you where to plant it
impossible? my teacher
how did you kill president Yashiro?
he sat on me and tried to choke me
but I threw him out using a Judo technique
now I wish I could do like you
and blow up this ship
then kill you inside the chaos
in your dreams
Wait
put the control down
shut up, don't come near
he disappeared
you'll not get away
- Conan
- after him
shit
wait Conan
wait for us
you...?
we will go too...
we will not let Conan get all the credits
Haiybra
ok. that's the reason
hold well now
everyone to the left
to the right now
we have passed him
I'm counting on you Ai
Conan
did you defeat him Conan?
great
the detective squad kids
hey kids
are you ok?
You are careless
this man is a murderer
what if something bad happened?
sorry
inspector Miguri
how many bombs did he plant?
what is the sitiuation there Ezawa
captain the bombs
made a several holes in the ship
how about safty locks
it's closed but the water already
inside third and fourth floors
what?
captain, issue the order
to evacuate the ship immediatly
captain
evacuate... the ship
to all passengers, I'm Eiyawa the navigator
please everyone wear the life jackets
and head directly to the lifeboats
this is not a training,
I repeat this is not a training
please take the emergency door
to all crew's guide the passengers
to the lifeboats
no, I couldn't find the medal
where is it?
Ran
Hurry up
Ran let's go
don't worry we still have enough time
walk in order
father, where is Conan and the others?
the kids are safe
inspector Miguri told me...
they chased Kasaka using a boat
and they've been picked by a near ship
thank god
Ran, you go on this boat
I'll take another one later
- but...
- later
dad...
don't panic, one after another
lower the lifeboats and don't
let the tide take you down with it
understand
it's very hot here darling
we don't have a choice at tough times like this
but I can't take it anymore
I remembered now
what?
I dropped it where I hide this morning
do you mean the medal
I will lower the lifeboat now, please hang on
I want to get out
but Ran...
go, I will catch you later
but...
even if it's made by sea shells...
for me it's a very important treasure
see you later
wait Ran
found it, so this is it
we are lucky this ship was near
is everyone there ok?
I'm worry
don't worry she'll be in the lifeboat
Kasaka said he wanted to scare us
so he could kill Kaidu
but these bombs is too much
seems like he wanted to sink the ship
and that proof
it was very easy
if miss Minako said anything...
the plan will fail
I think he tried it several times
to make sure she wouldn't intersect him
and to use it as a proof
right, she said that also
yes, he will get angry if I intersect him
inspector Miguri
the coasts guards just informed me now
that president Yashiro been stabbed
what?
what this is mean?
Kasaka didn't say he used a knife
it was 10:11
it was 10:15
wasn't Kasaka
who did it then?
she don't look like a 50 years old woman
Conan
where are you going Conan?
no wonder...
no wonder I felt there was something wrong
I have a feeling there's still something
might cost us a big loss
are you talking about a crime
yes.... maybe
maybe that
Conan
the case... are you really doing this
for the case Kudo kun?
if I'm not mistaken, the killer is...
captain
all evacuated safely
I'll take the last boat gather
everyone else and leave the ship
ok
don't you wanna sink
along with the ship captain
you? what are you still
doing here? leave now
do you remeber this?
my father loved it
a paper ship?
couldn't be...
yes me, the captain's daughter
whom you and Yashiro's killed 15 years ago
sorry all the remaining lifeboats destroyed
how could it be?
don't move
the place is tight here
let's go to a bigger place to speak
under the sea breeze
it was before half year
Kasaka told me
he want to make interview with me for his story
but he kept talkin about the Yashiros
which they don't have a relation in the story
it was very fishy
so I looked into his computer and found
the truth behind the ship accident
that was Kasaka real intentions
I felt something wrong
that's why I visited Hedito Yashiro next day
he confessed everything
after I put alchool into his drink.
ship drowning wasn't an accident
but they planned it
he didn't know I'm Okita's daughter
sorry, the president ordered me
I don't want to hear excuses
I'll let join the Yashiros
death is your destiny
the same destiny as my father
shit, I hope I could reach in time
please, forgive me
goodbye captain
stop
so you are the killer after all
uncle
stay there
sorry, I messed your gun, it will not work
during "bathroom time" I found it at your room
captain
we will talk later
miss Akayushi, as I presumed...
no need for that now, you will die here
presuming on this sinking ship
will not do you any good
I will not give up easily
To find the truth that's how detectives works
I think you knew about Kasaka plan
to kill Hedito Yashiro
but there was weak points in his plan
could result in failure
that's why you killed Hedito at
the car accident before him
using the stun grade
after Hedito's death,
Kasaka's targets decreased from 4 to 3
he used you to make a proof
but you knew all that...
so you used his plan to kill them
with your own hand
first, you and Kasaka planted
the bombs separately
you designed this ship
you knew the weak points
to make fatal holes
at that morning 10 o'clock
you received a call from Kasaka
when he started reading the story,
you went to Takai's room
you knocked her while she was taking shower
Then you wore her robe to disguise as her
that's when Kasaka sneaked from behind
thinking you are her
you let him stab the...
blood bag which you were hiding inside the robe
after Kasaka left thinking he succeeded
you killed her
then you cleaned the fake blood
you wore the suit after that
at that time I thought you don't want me
to see your face that's why you rolled your body
but I found the answer later
the reason because your a woman
your body rolled unvoluntary at that time
that's why
like the other time
then you went to the depository
and you saw the president chocking Kasaka
so you sneaked from behind
very fast and catch his legs..
legs?
yeah. you didn't touch his legs
you stabbed him from the back
yes, you stabbed him using a knife
then you hid yourself quickly
that's how Kasaka thought he did it all alone
everything went as you planned
you are really the famous detective Togo Muri
I planned to use him as a pawn
after knowing you are here
to fool the famous detective I need a pawn
and more importantly,
someone believe he did it
also on his computer he described my father
as the stubborn old geezer who died with the ship
I shall never forgive who insults my father
the one who shall never forgiven is you
you didn't murder 3 persons only...
but you endangered the life
of innocents people
and drowned the ship you desiged
with your own hand
I planned for everything
when I designed the ship
after bombs, water leaks, people escapes...
I found a solution
I'll force him to drown with the ship
to make him suffer like my father,
lonely and hopeless
Aphrodite was born from the ocean bubbles
and she will return to it someday as bubbles
however since you know all this,
I don't have a choice
but to surrender
I will not hit a woman
how romantic
uncle
so, do you want to change your mind?
I will not fight you
those three are dead, quit it
it is because you are an obstacle on my way
that kid...
Shinichi
huh?
no... nothing
it's time to end all this
Mr. Muri
it's very shameful to see
a famous detective in a bad shape
shut up
uncle
I did not expect that
I was your target from the begining
I think I look like someone you hate so much
not true...
that because you look like her
I hoped that you are not the killer
that's why I kept searching
for a proof your not guilty
but it ended like this
uncle
are you alright uncle?
that was a great conclusion uncle
how did you come here?
let's leave this place first
leave the place?
we can't all the lifeboats gone
and she's destroyed the rest
captain... captain
hey captain
we're saved
what is? this feeling?
the case closed
what? what this terrible feeling?
hurry up, the ship will sink
go inside now
what are you waiting for? hurry up
...Ran?
Ran leaved the ship earlier
uncle, isn't Ran with you?
what do you mean?
she went to where she hid before
to search for the medal
thats why I thought she was with you
this is the reason
wait
where is Ran?
anyone? anyone hears me?
Ran, so you are really here
Shinichi
you will find me
where is Ran?
Ran knew I was playing soccer at that time
that means...
she must be upstairs
I will find you
wait Ran, I will find you for sure
where are you Ran?
calm down and think
I easily found her that time
yes
how did you know where I am?
didn't you play soccer all the time?
Conan, didn't you play soccer all the time
I know everything
it's like the last time
uncle, search for a place under the ground
which can be used to hide
here
damn this stupid lock
uncle
we made a crack
Ran are you there?
father
we better hurry uncle
damn
this is bad, this is bad
hurry up and take the boat there
or everyone else will die
sorry, I can't do it
if we get near it now...
the tide will take us down
it can't be...
it's the rescue coasts guards helicopter
thank god
it's a helicopter
shit
let's go to the front
we are here
here
is everyone here
yes
hang well boy, we will leave this place
ok
hold on, ok?
going up now, hold your daughter
ok
what?
here
shit
hold well Conan
are you alright?
hey kid
give me your hand
we almost there
thanks
the ship where your mother is very near
you knew she's the killer
because Kasaka's proof was very easy
that trick will only used to prove
he is innocent
and also the other one can use it as
a provment for herself
and who's possibly can disguise
as lady Takai with her beautiful legs
must be someone with a beautiful legs
I see
thank god you find Ran's hiding place
that because...
my time to worry about you
actually I was playing soccer
with a volly ball
but Ran said I was playing football
that's why I thought she was hiding in place
where she can hears me but can't sees me
how disappointing
I thought the only one
who can find her is Kudo kun
no the reason we still alive is...
Ran
we fixed it for you
you can wear it around your neck
we changed it with a long thread
let put it around your neck
thank you
it suits you
I will treasure it
we made it...
because we care for each other.