Darn! Overtook again.
Rent a better car, man...
You can say that again.
-We should've come by train.
-Yep.
Really...
Shut up!
The client said to bring
all of you along too,
so I rented a car that all could ride,
didn't I?!
5 seconds more...
Huh?
Unless you turn the wheels right now,
we'll crash into the wall
in another 5 seconds.
What?!
Wow... look at that!
It's like a castle!
Then, a king used to live there?
No way...
I mean it's a hotel you know.
Well, it's right in front of Miracle Land...
so there may be a filthy rich person
that's staying here
for quite some time playing his time away
as if he were a king, though...
Come to think of it, they were saying that
the number of guests staying here
will be over 100,000 people.
Oh...
They're doing pretty good business
I guess so..
Oh, excuse me...
Are you Detective Mouri?
Oh, yes...
We've been waiting for you.
My name is Takada and
I'm working as secretary for your client.
Well, please come this way.
You, go and park their car...
Yes, sir.
(Hotel Red Castle)
Please follow me...
Wow...
Wow...!
I think we can see
the entire view of Miracle Land!
Oh, I'm sorry.
Please have a seat and wait.
Hey, just be quiet and sit down!
Okay...
Please wait a moment then.
This is so awesome!
What's the matter, Conan?
This chair doesn't seem
to match this room somehow.
Now that you mentioned it, I guess not...
Maybe they got tight on the budget?
No way,
after all it's such a gorgeous hotel!
Thank you for waiting.
I had you bring the children along with you
to give you this.
What on earth is this?
This is the free pass I.D of Miracle Land.
While you're working, Mr. Mouri,
we wanted to have
the children enjoy themselves
to their heart's content at Miracle Land...
Is the client the owner of this place
by any chance...?
No, he's not.
He rents this suite on an annual basis,
though...
Oh... what a character.
Okay, everyone,
please stick it onto your arms,
securely, so you don't drop it.
If you lose it, we can't re-issue it.
Here this is for you, Mr. Mouri.
No thank you,
because I'm not going to the amusement park.
Don't say that...
If you finish work early,
you can enjoy yourself with everyone else...
Oh...
This I.D is valid for a whole day
until 10:00 tonight,
the closing time for miracle land.
Meals and drinks are all free,
so please enjoy yourself
to your heart's content.
All right!
Thank you,
let's go, Conan.
Okay.
I'd like you to remain here.
I'm sorry.
Why?
Maybe you won the prize
for being the 100,000th person
to enter this hotel?!
Well, sort of...
No joke...
How lucky...
Let's go on ahead and stand in line then.
It seems that waiting you
normally have to
wait 2 hours to ride the Super Snake.
Okay...I guess so.
See you later then, Conan.
Uh, I wonder what the 100,000th person's
going to get?
All I know is that it's not
an eel lunchbox.
Well, well, how lucky of you!
Being the 100,000th person,
I'll bet you'll get super service.
I don't want anyone to get in our way so...
What do you mean, get in your way...?
I'm not the 100,000th person, am I?
The confetti from the decorative paper ball
was scattered in front of the hotel already.
Oh? Is he right?
Yes, the 100,000th person
already came about an hour ago...
Then, why did you make him stay back?
Your client asked me to...
Hey, what's this?
What's going on?!
Thank you for coming.
I'm the one who called you.
Please forgive me for not being able
to show my face
because of circumstances...
I asked you to come here today
because I want you
to solve a certain incident.
What incident is it?
That's your job to figure out.
Huh?
I will give you several hints from now
I want you to use those hints
to solve the case.
But why do you want me to do that...?
You're the 5th detective
I've asked to solve the incident...
And, how did the previous 4 do?
One of them is still investigating...
I had two quit,
and the one other detective is here
not being able to solve the case.
Ryu!
Do you know him?
He's a detective that I worked with before.
I gave you the investigation report,
didn't I?!
Just how long to you intend
to keep me confined in a place like this!
Hurry and let me out of here!
Detective Ryu...
you were unable to solve the case...
What?
Incapable detectives have no right to live.
What's this?!
It's the same I.D as the one we have...
Yeah...
Darn! What the hell is this?!
Don't worry, it won't hurt...
You'll be at ease in an instant...
Don't tell me that this is why...
Shigeki and Yarita disappeared.
Goodbye... Detective Ryu...
Hey, wait...
Please wait... Darn!
Composition 4...
In other words,
a plastic bomb was built in to it.
A bomb was built in to the I.D
that Detective Ryu
was wearing on his chest...
Hey, what about Shigeki and Yarita,
that Ryu mentioned?
Yes... They were two detectives
who were acclaimed by the public.
However, they were just dull-witted people
who wasted my precious time.
You are given till 10:00 tonight...
Please figure out the truth
of a certain case till then...
If you fail to solve the case in time...
Your I.Ds will also explode
and you will follow Detective Ryu's path...
What?!
No use trying...
That I.D won't come off that easily.
And, if it were to come off
before I undo it,
it will explode immediately.
Why darn you.....
Ran...
Right! Ran and the others...
What about their I.Ds...?
The I.Ds that the children
have on are almost the same.
What?!
Almost?...
Their I.Ds have one extra function
added on...
This is the blueprint of Miracle Land.
Several sensors are set up
as if to outline Miracle Land.
When their I.Ds enter Miracle Land,
the sensor detects it,
and the time bomb switches on.
Then, when they pass through the sensor again
in order to leave Miracle Land,
at that time the I.D explodes
It was too much trouble trying
to keep track of all of them...
so I set it up this way.
Ran...
Ai!
Can you hear me, Ai!
Darn!
Ai!...
Ai!
What?
Ai, don't go inside!
What's the matter?
Never mind, just stop everybody!
Don't go inside!
But how...
We're already inside...
You're V.I.Ps...
That I.D is only given to special people...
Oh, is that so...
Please enjoy yourselves
to your heart's content.
Thank you very much.
What's up?
I'll contact you again.
How's Ran?
Darn!
If you solve the case by 10:00 tonight
and find the real culprit,
I will pay you as much detective fee
as you want...
However, if you cannot solve
the case within that time,
I will explode that I.D!
Take me to where that man is!
Right this minute!
That's impossible...
because I don't know where he is either.
What?!
Mr. Mouri...
Your every move is monitored.
There is a built-in GPS in the I.D...
It won't do you much good to run
to the police for help.
You mean,
you're going to push the explode button!
Talking for a long time is
just going reduce the time you have left...
The first hint is...
I will say it only once,
so please listen well.
T, A, K, A, 3 minus 8.
What's it about?!
Please say it one more time.
I already told you,
I'm saying it just once...
You have 12 hours to go
before the time limit...
Go and solve the case
for me... as well as for the children...
Darn!
Mr. Mouri,
please use this...
It's a hotline connected to the client.
However, you are not able to
contact the client from your side.
You will be getting orders
from you client through it.
After you solve the case,
please call my number
that is in this cell phone,
and come back here...
I will listen carefully
to the truth you have figured out.
(Detective Conan Movie 10
The Private Eyes Requiem)
I'm Shinichi Kudo, a high school detective.
I went to the amusement park
with my childhood friend Ran Mouri
and happened to witness the suspicious deal
being made by dubious
looking men dressed in black.
Since I was so absorbed
in watching the transaction
that I didn't notice
the other culprit closing in on me.
I was forced to drink poison by that man
and when I woke up
My body had shrunk!
If those guys find out
that Shinichi Kudo is alive
they'll come after my life again,
and also endanger
the lives of those around me.
So, taking heed of Dr. Agasa's warning,
I decided to hide my true identity.
Ran cornered me to tell her
what my name was,
so I told her on the spur of the moment
that I'm Conan Edogawa.
In order to gather information on those guys
I decided to free-load at Ran's house
because her father ran a detective agency...
The people who know of my true identity are
Dr. Agasa,
my parents,
high school detective of the West
Heiji Hattori
and my classmate Ai...
Dr. Agasa has invented
all kinds of devices for me
since I've shrunk...
Ai had been a member
of the Black Organization,
but when fleeing the organization
she drank the same drug
that I was forced to drink
and also shrunk...
There is one other person
that also knows about me...
It's the Thief Kid!
When he comes into the picture
things start getting complicated...
A child in appearance
with the I.Q. of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan...
I see through the one and only truth!
Darn! What's with this traffic jam!
My daughter's life is in danger!
-Come on, move it! Darn!
-So,
no matter what,
don't let them out of Miracle Land!
If you go out of range of the area,
the I.D will explode!
Of course, the Super Snake's no good too!
Because the main feature that roller coaster
is that it goes way out
into the sea part way!
Hey, are you listening, Ai?
Yes, I got it.
Unless you solve the case by 10:00 tonight,
both you and I will turn
into particles of dust.
Fuh, very interesting.
In, Interesting,
how can you say such a thing.
Hey, Ai?!
Just what're you doing, hurry on over here!
Okay... our live are in your hands...
Mr. Detective...
I don't have the slightest idea...
What the hell is TAKA? 3 minus 8...?
This... can also be read 8 hyphen 3.
Then, T, A, K,A is the name of a town?!
And 3 – 8 = -5...
Remove the = symbol
and it can be read 3-8-5.
Here it is! Takashima-cho!
So it means, Takashima-cho 3-chome!
Hey... which way is 3-chome?...
There's no such place...
What?
There's no Takashima-cho 3-chome.
What?!
Give me that!
Darn...
We've got to think it over
from the start again...
No really.
Haven't the names of the towns in this area
been changed recently
because of redevelopment...?
Takashima-cho 3-8-5...
Yep.
Maybe the name changed
after development in this area...?
This area changed to Minato-Mirai.
There used to be a 3 chome...
Do you have a map?
Yes...
But...
does this place really
have to do with some incident?...
We have no choice
but to think that it does, don't we?
I can't figure out
why he would want me to do this
along with an elementary school kid
like you...
I think the client figured that
you wouldn't be reliable enough, Pops.
He's right...
Why would the client want me
alone to act along with Pops...?
Why on earth...?
What?
Who?! Who are you?!
You can't live here
because it's going to be demolished
next week...
You're look to be having it tough too,
with a kid and all...
No, no, that's not it...
Give me a break...
Have you been living here for long, sir?
Yeah... since two years
before the hotel went bankrupt.
Did anything out of
the ordinary happen lately?
Anything you can recall is fine.
Hmm... let me see...
Oh... a big white bird came flying here once.
Big bird?
It flew by right in front of the sun...
When was that?
On my birthday, April 4th.
That day from morning,
there was a strange car parked in front...
and the real estate agent
came to close off the basement.
A strange car?
Cars don't usually come in here...
When I went out in the morning,
a brand new car was parked in the yard
over there, but...
when I came back at sundown,
it had changed into an old beat up car...
By night time,
only the frame work of the car was left
after all the parts were stolen, though.
What do you mean
by they closed down the basement?
The basement is the place
where they keep devices...
I guess they wanted to sell
the devices and make money...
About what time was it?!
Sundown...
What is it?!
Hey, kid! What's up?!
Oh, there you are...
I tell you, don't scare me...
Yikes!
What's this?!
Huh? What...?
This was inside...
What's that...?
This is...?!
A cap and gloves...
Even a Colt Government...
A receipt...
April 4th... Yokohama Shindo...
Pops! Isn't April 4th the day that the man
said a strange car was parked?
Oh... the day the car was switched...?!
Switched...
I got it! This where the getaway car
was switched to another one!
After the culprit used
this cap and government
to carry out a crime!
The thing is to figure out
what cases there were on April the 4th...
As long as we figure this out
the rest is duck soup...
Who are they...?
A gun!
What we know for sure is that
they're not ordinary citizens...
Maybe they came to get this bag?!
Could be...
Okay, I got it!
You go out there and distract those guys.
In the meantime I'll get the car,
pick you up, and let's get out of here.
Don't worry!
They won't shoot right off the bat at a kid!
What's with you! Can't you trust me?!
I can't.
Never mind, just go!
Wait.
Freeze,
Get in...
Oh, brother.
Darn...why at a crucial time like this
This beat up lemon.
You're under arrest!
Arrest, you guys are...
Police detectives?
It's the big bird,
the same as the one I saw back then...
What?!
It's him...
He flies through the world of darkness
on white wings...
Thief Kid!
Thief Kid?!
Inspector!
We've visually confirmed Thief Kid!
He is currently
on the roof of Fukayama Building!
On top the statue of the devil.
Okay, I got you!
President Fukayama, Thief Kid has appeared.
All right, let's go.
Well, I don't think
that Thief Kid will be able to get
through the security system this time,
though.
Thief Kid!
Darn!
This is Yokomizo!
Thief Kid is fleeing
from the Fukayama Building,
heading towards
the direction of Landmark Tower!
I repeat!
Thief Kid is fleeing towards Landmark Tower!
Get going on the double!
It seems that the police on guard
was of no help.
Thank goodness for the security system...
Inspector Yokomizo!...
We've arrested a man who looks to be
in together with Thief Kid!
We'll take him to the station!
Okay! I'll return right away too.
Like I've been telling you,
I have nothing to do with Thief Kid!
I'm Kogoro Mouri!
Bummers... If things are left as is...
Your every move is being monitored.
The I.Ds have built-in GPS...
So, no use running to the police for help.
I.D number 1 and I.D number 2
are approaching
the Kanagawa Prefectural Police Department.
Hearing that voice somehow
makes me feel excited.
But... I'm tired of standing
in line already...
I wonder how much longer
it's going to take?
Hmm... let's see...
Let's say three people standing
makes a meter...
and this looks to be about 150 meters,
which comes up to 450 people...
22 people get to
ride the Super Snake at a time...
450 people make it approximately 20 times...
Since the time required for one round
including the time to get on
and get off is about 10 minutes,
which makes 200 minutes...
In other words we'd have to wait about
3 and a half hours.
Wow, fantastic, Mitsuhiko!
You mean we still have to wait that long...
I'm hungry...
If Dr. Agasa were here,
we could probably have killed time
with his play on words quiz!
True...
Okay, then would you like me
to give you quizzes today?
You, Ran?
I won't do?
Give the quiz, come on!
Okay, we'll answer your quizzes.
Okay, here goes, then...
Miracle Land Quiz!
The Super Snake that
you all want to ride at least once...
Well, out of all you little detectives,
who is the best suited to ride this?
I got it! It's Ai, isn't it?
Huh... why?
Because Ai looks like she likes snakes.
I don't like snakes.
Wrong...
Then, maybe it's me,
because just like the people standing
in line to ride Super Snake,
I'm always waiting for everybody.
What kind of a answer is that...?
When we go to school in the morning,
even if we go to pick you up,
we always end up waiting for you...
That's not right either...
What about you, Genta?
Hmm... me...
well, snake resembles eels...
and I love eels.
Really close!
How is Genta who likes
who loves eels over rice?
How is Genta...?
It seems he's hungry...
I see.
Super=cho(超)which means "very"
and Snake is pronounced hebi(ヘビ)
which resembles "heavy".
So, put together Super Snake
means "very heavy"
Therefore, the correct answer
is Genta who weighs the most...
Right.
I didn't think you'd give us
the same type of quiz as Dr. Agasa,
but... your quiz is a play on words
after all too.
(Kanagawa Prefectural Police Station)
Ooh, Conan, are you all right?
Inspector Megure.
What on earth happened... to Mr. Mouri...?
I heard you arrested Thief Kid's accomplice?
Oooh, Officer Nakamori.
Hey, Megure the badger,
what brings you here?
It seems that Mr. Mouri was
mistakenly arrested, that's why I'm here.
What... then you mean that
Thief Kid's accomplice
is that Sleeping Kogoro...?
Detectives must protect
the secret of their clients!
And I'm saying that if that client
is the Thief Kid then you're an accomplice.
Why was the Kanagawa Prefectural Police
staking out that building?
We got a warning note from Thief Kid.
That building happens to be the main office
of Fukayama Trading Company.
On the very top floor of that building,
the president Mr. Fukayama happens to have
an exhibition of jewelry that
he collects as a hobby.
However, unlike last time,
it seems that nothing was stolen this time.
You mean he was broken into before too?
Yeah, a huge diamond was stolen
on April 4th this year,
so it seems he upgraded
the security system of the building,
so President Fukayama must be elated
at the outcome this time.
April 4th.
Isn't Officer Yokomizo of
the 1st Division...?
The 2nd Division are the ones in charge
of the Thief Kid, aren't they?
There's a strange person after Thief Kid's life recently...
and because of that,
some people have been wounded,
that's why the 1st Division
is also helping out...
After Thief Kid's life?
I got a phone call.
Excuse me, a minute...
Detective Mouri...
Rather, Kudo?
So, it's you after all,
high school detective, Shinichi Kudo...
You being there
with Detective Mouri surprised me.
I actually wanted you
to investigate for me too, but...
but I didn't know how to contact you.
Phooey, so unable to solve the case you ran
to the police, eh...
No, we didn't come to the police.
Detective Mouri was mistakenly arrested
by police officers
who were staking out a dilapidated hotel.
Fuh... you're really honest, aren't you?
You mean this guy knew
that the officers were there...
Well, never mind...
And, what did you find at the hotel...?
We found a cap and a gun that
seems to have been used to commit a crime...
Good work, Kudo...
Then, here's the second hint...
Go to the Café Terrace at Night...
The Café Terrace at Night...
You should know where that is...
I'll solve the case no matter what it takes!
So, please remove
the I.Ds on Ran and the others!
Hey! Are you listening or what?!
Darn...
To lose a loved one...
How painful it is to lose a loved one...
Do your best so that
it doesn't turn out that way...
Kudo.
Why...
Why does ne know who I am...?
Who...
who on earth is he...?
The line's not moving at all and yet
I'm getting hungrier and hungrier...
True...
Come to think of it, it's already noon...
I'll stand in line,
so why don't you all go
get something to eat?
You mean you don't mind, Ai?!
But, I feel bad leaving Ai behind alone.
Oh...
Okay, I'll stay behind with Ai then.
I'll stay behind too!
Okay, me too, then...
How silly, if so, what's the point?
Then let's do this...
We'll stand in line every 30 minutes
taking turns...
And we'll start with Ai, how that?
Agreed!
Okay... so I'll see you all in 30 minutes...
-Okay...
-Here goes!
Okay, bye...
You can go first.
I wonder how long I can buy time here...
(Yokohama Ohashi Harbor Bridge)
I may be able to figure something out
if a take it apart but,
there's no guarantee that
it won't explode...
so, I can't do anything about it here...
I see...
Oh, that's right...
I powered this up.
Thank you!
Oh, right, did you figure out
where the "Café Terrace at Night" is?
Where on earth is it?
The Café Terrace at Night
is a painting drawn
by Vincent Van Gogh in 1888.
of a landscape of a café terrace lit
with the misty light of a street lamp,
where a carriage is coming from beyond.
Street lamp and a horse drawn carriage...
There's no other place
in Japan than the place
where the first street lamp was built,
which is Bashamichi!
Talk about really powering it up, Doc.
Ai,
here you go.
Thank you...
Thanks for waiting...
The line's moved only this much yet...
I guess my calculation wasn't correct...
Let me take your place.
Okay.
Oh come on, Ran.
You really like childish things like this,
don't you?
Sonoko?! What are you doing here...?
See, the Red Castle Hotel over there...
A party's going to be held there tonight,
celebrating the coming
or over 100,000 people today...
It's like dad built that hotel, you see...
That's I was killing time till then
at this amusement park.
Huh... Where did you pick that up
No!
Dad's client gave this to us.
A really VIP client,
I lost my I.D so I thought I dropped it.
Okay, I'll invite you
and the children to the party
so what do you say we go to the Red Castle,
just us girls, now?
Since the children also have I.Ds on them,
it'll be no problem leaving them
to themselves.
She looks especially capable too.
But...
They're having a cake buffet right now
at the restaurant of the hotel!
So long as you have this I.D
you're free
to go in and out of Miracle Land!
What on earth is going to happen here?...
Freeze!
Heiji...
Well, did I scare you?
Shut up!
What good timing.
I need your help, Shinichi.
What, you too, Shinichi...
You too, then...
He's taken Kazuha hostage...
Well, she doesn't know a thing
and is playing free of care
at that amusement park, though...
Phone voi The number you have reached
is not within service range
or is not switched on
so the line cannot be connected...
The number you have reached...
Oh come on! After telling me that
he'd finish right away
so to do what I want here and wait...
I really understand
how Ran feels having to wait for Shinichi...
Huh? Kazuha?
Oh, Ran...
Kazuha! It's been a long time
since I've seen you last!
I didn't know you were here...
Where's Heiji?
We're here on business, b-u-s-i-n-e-s-s...
I see, what a bummer...
Oh, Kazuha...
Sonoko!
We were just going to a cake buffet.
Would you like to come along too?
I love cake!
Okay, then let's go.
Come on, Ran, let's go.
Oh, I wait.
I see...
So, your girlfriend's being
held hostage too...
Yeah... not only Ran,
but the four children too... Besides...
the client seems to think that
I'm Shinichi Kudo.
You mean he knows your true identity?!
Well, I don't know about that, but.
Hey! I hope the secret about your body
having shrunk is not disclosed,
to the Black Organization, is it...?
Hey...
What's up?!
A cap, gun and getaway car...
I get it! A cash transporting car attack!
Yeah...
Is that it,
what the guy was talking about...?
Most likely...
Excuse me?
What is it, sonny?
Wasn't that cash transporting car
attacked before?
Yes... it was...
I think it was on April 4th...
Since you're doing business here,
I'm sure that the police
asked you questions, didn't they?...
Will you tell us
the details of what you know too?
Yes...
I think it was just about the same time...
Don't move, stay still!
It really seemed like just a split second...
It was hard to tell if it was happening
for real or just a dream...
You mean they worked really fast.
Thank you, Miss...
Wait!
Today is the worst day of your lives
for both you boys...
It's best to go home and sleep...
Okay, will do...
after we change it
into the best day of our lives.
Bye...
Stop roaming around on your own!
I looked for you, you know.
Ugh, stop...
Come, come, this is no time to be fighting.
How come the black boy from Osaka is here?
The reason you're here...
Mr. Mouri.
Give me the cell phone given to you
by your client.
Isn't it about time you tell us the truth.
The truth well...
There's only so much a detective can do...
I think it's best that you let us handle
this case as soon as possible.
This is Mouri.
So, this time it's you, Detective Mouri.
Oh well... You're on Bashamichi right now,
aren't you.
Yes.
You shouldn't be making friends
with the police.
Why you, are you watching me?!
Is that it?!
Are you going to break your promise,
Mr. Mouri?
No, I'm not.
What happened is beyond my control.
Mr. Mouri, who on earth are you talking to?!
Stupid... stupid...
Disappear incapable police!
What?!
Stupid... stupid...
Disappear incapable police!
Darn! What's with that doll!
Stupid... stupid...
Disappear incapable police!
Hey... This looks bad.
Look out! Get away from that doll!
It'll explode!
What?!
10 seconds before explosion!
-3
-Darn!
1...
Mama!
Officer Yokomizo.
We need an ambulance right away!
Why you!
Next the children that you brought with you
will turn out this way
Mr. Mouri.
What's the matter?
This I.D has begun flashing from
a while ago...
Mine too...
Sonoko, do you know anything?
Nope...this is the first time
I've seen anything like this before too...
Maybe the employee
at the exit would know something?
Ghads,
not being able to dodge
that scale of explosion,
I don't know about the police nowadays!
What?!
Isn't this all happening because of you?!
Come off it.
You have no such proof anywhere...
To be honest with you,
you're causing me a great inconvenience.
Stop hanging around me!
What...
I was right to have quit being
a police detective...
I want to live a long life after all...
Let's go, you guys.
Yeah...
Inspector...Is it okay?
It's okay.
Ran and the children are being held hostage
at Miracle Land.
They have an I.D on their wrists
that will explode if they leave the grounds.
Please save them under extreme secrecy.
Thank you, Mouri.
I asked the police
to take care of Ran and the others.
Well, whether it turns out to be good luck
for us or not is all up to our brains.
And? Did you get anything yet?
Yeah, it seems that a cash transporting car
was attacked on Bashamichi on April 4th.
The police officer was also saying
that it was the same day
that the Thief Kid stole the diamond
from Fukayama Museum.
I see...
Okay, I'll check things on my side too...
Don't you kids get too reckless now.
What the hell is he talking about.
This is probably the last hint
we'll bet at Bashamichi.
What the hell does he want us to solve
with just this much information!
But, there's still another hint
that hasn't been solved.
What?!
This is the hint he gave me!
Café Terrace at Night, and You cry...
You got a hint different from ours...
Right...
YOU CRY...
if written in capital letters...
YOU stands for,
Yeah..."Yokohama Oceanic University"
located in the suburbs of Yokohama...
So the only thing left is CRY...
That's what I can't figure out...
I guess we've got no choice
but to go to "YOU"...
Yeah...
Ran, quick!
Excuse me.
Yes? What can I do for you?
Why is this I.D flashing red?
I wonder...
this is the first time I saw anything like that...
-Ms. Ran Mouri, of Beika Town,
I see.
and Ms. Kazuha Toyama who is with her,
please come immediately to the medical room.
I wonder what it is...
Maybe something happened to the children.
Let's go right away...
I'm sorry, Sonoko... Will you go alone?
No problem, something may have happened
to the kids so hurry on over to them...
I'm sorry...
I guess I'll go eat my heart out...
What's the matter?
She passed out on the grounds of the park...
I think it's a light case of heat stroke.
I see...
I'm sorry...
It's okay, don't worry.
But, why did you also call Kazuha?
This is the first time
I ever talked to her...
That's... That's because...
That's easy.
She feels more secure
with two people than one.
Right.
Let's let her rest for a while...
Will you stay and watch her...?
Of course.
Please stay with me al the way...
I thought she was a sassy kid,
but she can be pretty cute...
All this acting...is tiring me out...
CRY, CRY, CRY...
Is it a name of a class,
an abbreviated name...
What about the name of a club
at the university
Could be...
Some other things it may stand
for would be...
Crime Research Yokohama...
I think that this club is more than close
to what it stands for...
Who are you?
I'm Saguru Shirauma.
I'm in the same shoes you are in many ways.
In our shoes?
You're the son of the Police Commissioner
and a high school detective, right?
Yeah. I could never beat you,
an elementary school detective, though.
I see...
so you're in the same boat as me
in that my dad's the head of
the Osaka Prefectural Police Headquarters...
That's not all...
Don't tell me that...
The one who is precious to me
is also in Miracle Land...
Well, let's talk about trivial things
while walking,
the more time we lose,
the more will end up CRYing.
True...
Hey, is anybody home?
Hey...!
We're coming in.
Get a load of the information
that got here...
Hey...take a look at this picture...
It seems to be snapshots of
the members of the club...
We better take pictures of this picture.
I guess so.
The client?
Yeah...
What is it?...
You've figure it out
as much as you did with the hint YOU CRY...
All of you have never stopped amazing me...
I don't know about you,
but you want us to solve the case,
don't you?
Why don't you give us simpler hints?
If you solve it too easily,
it's not interesting for me at all...
Besides...
I'm testing you all...
for your capabilities as a detective...
Whether you are qualified
to solve my case or not.
What?!
From here on now, there are no hints...
I'll be counting on you, young detective.
Hey, you! Wait up!
Darn... He hung up...
No hint...
Just what does he
expect us to do...?
(Mission completed at Yokohama Ocean University)
Huh? You guys are...
What do you want?
Oh, well, we're, you see...
We're planning to enter this university
next year,
so we came to check it out...
Okay, if you enroll,
make sure you join our club.
Yes, of course.
Uh, excuse me, miss!
What are those pictures lined up over there?
The pictures from the left are those of
the department heads of the past.
Then why is the picture of
the 3rd department head removed?
Look, next to the picture
beside the last picture
there is a hanger attachment on the wall,
and after the 3rd picture,
a small area of untarnished wall
can be seen next to each picture.
This means that for some reason the picture
of the 3rd department head
was removed for some reason,
and the other pictures
were moved accordingly
and put up again, right?
Am I wrong?
The 3rd department head,
Mr. Ito was dismissed.
Oh, Mr. Jiro Ito, was it?
No, it was Mr. Suehiko Ito, do you know him?
Yes, well, sort of...
It's him... isn't it?
No... it's him.
Oh, I see...
What an actor...
I'm sorry,
I guess he's not the Mr. Ito that I know...
(Osaka prefectural police station)
Suehiko Ito?!
Heiji, who's this man
you want me to look up supposed to be?
I don't know, that's why
I want you to check for me, Officer Ohtaki.
Does the Chief know about this...?
It's a secret.
A secret, Heiji...
I'll be waiting to hear from you, then.
Hey, Heiji?!
I guess, I'll go take a break, break time...
Well, shall we go eat at the cafeteria?
When the glucose count goes down,
my brain doesn't seem to work well...
Idiot, we don't have time to waste.
We're waiting for a call, you know.
Like they say, a samurai even
when starving acts as if his stomach is full.
But, they also say,
you can't work on an empty stomach, right?
Besides, I've already figured out the answer
for what you're about to investigate...
The Metropolitan Police Department
is closer to Yokohama
than the Osaka Prefectural Police Department
that's why.
He gets on my nerves...
Yes... Yeah...
This time for sure, when I get back there,
I promise I'll treat you... Yeah...
Okay, then thanks Ao-chan, right away, okay.
What's up, Ohtaki?
Boss...
Wasn't that your cousin Aoki that's at
the Kanagawa Prefectural Police Department?
It's nothing.
I just kind of missed talking to him...
You don't need to hide anything.
Heizo's son asked you to search for him,
right?
I got a call too.
Oh, so you got a call too...
I got you, Ohtaki...
What's up with my son?
Chief?!
Let's go to my office
and have you tell me the details, all right?
Spit it out and it'll be easier for you...
Well, uh...
Staying like this is not that easy...
Okay, then please take care of things...
Inspector Megure...
I'll go say hello to him.
I'll go too,
since he's always been nice to Heiji.
I'm going to go ride Super Snake
So take care of things here, okay!
Wait!
You've got to stay in bed yet!
Please stop him! Please!
Okay.
Inspector Megure...!?
Oh, Ran, Kazuha too...
What's up today?! Why are you both here...?
Are you working on a case or something?
Oh, well...it's our day off.
What a life, having to spend my day off
with Inspector Shiratori...
You mean you came to Miracle Land,
just the two of you...?
My god...
Huh? Ran.
Those children...
Inspector...
What? ! No joke...!
(Super Snake is currently down for maintenance,
we apologize for the inconvenience)
God punished you
from trying to beat us all to it.
Come on, let's go back to the medical room!
We're very sorry!
We ask for your cooperation
to maintain safety!
We'll be passing out
numbered tickets starting now!
Thief!
A thief!
Ayumi?
Ran!
I wonder why Inspector Megure is here...?
Hey, Officer Takagi?!
What're you doing?
Oh, well... you see....
Agh... I'll bet you were looking at
some cute girl while dating with me?!
You know
I wouldn't never do something like that!
What? Which is it? You're incomprehensible.
I,I guess so.
I won't tell her that
I saw Inspector Megure...
Wow, that curry sure looks good!
Here goes!
Go ahead and help yourself.
This is so good!
What curry is this?
Yuk! What's with this curry,
you can taste the flour!
And, what kind of person is Mr. Suehiko Ito?
It seems that Ito is wanted for the robbery
of the cash transporting vehicle
that occurred at Bashamichi
on April 4th this year.
I see,
that's why his picture
was removed from that room...
That's not the only thing that's interesting.
After he graduated from university
he managed an investment advisory company
but a person was also killed
at that company called Far East Office.
What?!
How about it? Interesting, isn't it?
Okay!
Let's head off
for that company called
Far East Office now then!
All that complaining
and you cleaned the entire dish...
I'm back...
Hi, Ms. Kisaki.
I'm sorry, Ms. Kuriyama,
but could you get me
something cold to drink?
Yes, ma'am.
Yes, this is Eri.
Oh, hi, it's you,
what's up?
I thought you were supposed to go with Ran
and the others to Miracle Land today?
Wait!
Documents for a case,
just what are you doing?
Uh, well, a lot of things...
and have nowhere else I can ask...
Okay,
the cash transporting car robbery
that happened on April the 4th, right...
I'll check on it right away
and get back to you.
Yeah, thanks a lot...
Dear?
Uh, Eri...
Do think I can solve... this case...
Footwork is important
to investigate a case...
Isn't that what you said?
Ex-police detective?
Right... That's right...
Get the papers for me, okay...
Yes, sure thing.
Come here...
Please come in.
Excuse me...
Huh? Didn't you just get a call?
Yes, I did.
From somebody that I really don't care for,
right, Goro??
It was from her husband , I see...
(Non-personnel are prohibited from entering)
When I'm told not to...
the more you want to go in...
That's the saga of a detective...
The one who was murdered
is Mr. Masaharu Nishio,
Chief Sales Manager of Far East Office...
It seems he was shot with a rifle.
He used to be a classmate of the President
in his University days.
Which means...
That maybe Nishio also belonged
to the Crime Research Yokohama Club?
You hit the bull's eye...
Come...
Come? Hey, that's my cell phone?!
When did he take it...
Look...at the front line of this picture.
The one in the middle is Suehiko Ito
who was then head of the club.
The one at the right beside him is Nishio,
the one who was killed...
Uh, who's the lady that
is sitting to the left of Mr. Ito?
Oh, she's Reiko Shimizu...
She seems to have been working
for this office too,
but committed suicide on May 15th.
Suicide?!
While she was being voluntarily questioned
by the police...
About Nishio being shot?
They seemed to have been really tough
with her...
This is the site of
where the shooting occurred...
It sure is dusty...
It seems to be left as it was
when the shooting took place.
Well, back then, the blinds and windows
seem to have been open, though.
The sniper shot Nishio
from the toilet of that building...
The rifle that was used was a
Charter Arms AR-7 with a scope and silencer.
They seem to have found 8 shell cases
on the floor of the toilet...
The sniper shot all 8 bullets
that were in the rifle.
One of the bullets that was fired seemed to
have struck Nishio in the back of his head,
and killed him instantly...
After that the plan for the attacking
and robbing the cash transporting vehicle
that Ito wrote out was found
in Nishio's desk,
so, Ito was listed as wanted by the police...
And, why was Reiko Shimizu called in
for questioning?
Beats me...
Take a look, Heiji.
If he was shot in the back of the head,
isn't the amount of blood a bit too small?
True...
But, on the other hand,
there's a large smear of blood
on this side...
What is the meaning of this...
The blood that smeared the chair
is dripped straight towards
the seat part of the chair...
Moreover, look.
One of the casters have been hit
and came off...
I get it, so that's the story...
Right...
This is Hattori.
It seems you've made it to the next step...
Heiji Hattori...
Yeah, somehow.
Did you figure out
which case I want you to solve?
The case of Masaharu Nisho's shooting,
isn't it?
Hey... Don't tell me that you're...
Darn!
What is it?!
Motorbikes?!
All I know is this doesn't look good.
Who're are they?!
Just some things to make
the game more interesting,
that the client mentioned.
This is just too interesting...
No good!
Let's split up!
-Right!
-Okay!
Okay! It's a one-to-one match...
I'm ready when you are!
What an ugly face...
Oh... did I offend you?
Darn...
You coward!
Fight bare-handed you! Bare-handed!
I wonder if Shinichi made it to safety...
Bummers...
Paint splattered on my shirt
and spoiled it...
Stop!
He was a man wearing a baseball cap
and a jacket, right...
Yes... but maybe he already took the off...
I guess so...
What's wrong?
Doesn't he look suspicious?
Oh.. the one with the ○○colored shirt...
See... the one with his hair flipped up
in two layers...
It goes to show that he was wearing a cap...
He probably got rid of it along
with his jacket and the bag he took...
Just as would be expected of the girlfriend
of the Shinichi Kudo,
high school detective of the East!
I'm not exactly his girlfriend!
Coke was spilled on the culprits shoe,
right?
Yeah, I did it deliberately
to leave evidence behind.
My bag!
Wow, Genta!
Wrong, Ayumi.
You shouldn't lie, Genta...
Thief!
I saw what happened!
Oh? You were...
There he is!
A middle-aged lady...
Hey, Ayumi?!
Is he the one, Ayumi?
Yep. He's got coke on his left sneaker.
He's looking around
and really looks suspicious...
No doubt about it!
Yeah.
Let's tail him!
No good...
I wonder where the children are going...?
Thief!
Hold it!
We won't let you get away!
Move! Get out of my way!
Move! Move!
Out of my way, move!
Please lend this to me for a while!
Hold it!
Darn...
Turn yourself in.
The police will be here soon...
Keep your nose out of
other people's business!
Oh no!
Oh, Ayumi!
Ayumi...
Don't move!
If you move there's no guarantee
what'll happen to this brat!
Number 5 is approaching the main gate.
Who is it?
Number 5... Ayumi Yoshida...
I see...
Stay away from me...
If you come close, this brat's going to die!
You! Let that girl go.
I'll be your hostage in her place!
You gotta be joking, old fart!
Then, I'll be your hostage...
Let me, because it's my fault
that she got caught...
Not you girls!
Oh, no, well...
We can't have lay people acting as hostage...
Quit babbling!
I'm not changing the hostage,
no matter what!
You guys stay put
until I go through the gate.
Don't forget the brat's life is at stake!
No! If she's carried outside...
Hey, this is the entrance, isn't it?!
The exit's beside it!
Never mind, and move out of the way!
No use shouting at me!
Follow the rules!
I tell you, adults nowadays
aren't able to even follow rules like this.
Get him!
Move!
Ha, ha, there are loads of hostages here!
Stay away...
If you don't I'm going to...
What're you going to do...?
What do you mean?
I wish you'd tell me...
What you plan to do?
Excuse me...
please let me through. Excuse me...
I got you a soft cream cone.
Officer... Sato?...
Inspector Megure...
Uh... what're you doing here...
I'd like to ask you the same question...
Oh, well... Uh...you see...
Shinichi...
Shinichi... Shinichi...
Hey, Shinichi! Shinichi!...
You've finally come out of it!
Where am I?
Inside gramps Agasa's car
Doc...
Don't push yourself!
I put splint on your leg
as a temporary measure,
but your bone may be broken
Heiji, you saved me?
No Shirauma did,
He called gramps asking him to come here,
and when he arrived,
he found Shirauma carrying you,
who with wounds all over...
After that,
gramps called me so I joined all of you.
Shirauma saved me...
Yeah, he left before I got here saying
that he had something he had to check on,
though...
What time is it now?
How much time went by since then?
It's been 2 hours and it's 8:30 right now...
An hour and a half to go...
We're headed for Red Castle...
Did you figure out who killed Mr. Nishio...?
No, we're just headed there, that's it.
I mean
it's no use staying in one place so...
While you were sleeping
we got a call from Mr. Ohtaki...
and found out many things...
We found out that
there was more to Nishio's murder case.
On the night that Nishio was murdered
a car turned over at a container yard
of a pier and was completely scrapped
The one driving was... Suehiko Ito...
He was wounded to the point
where many considered it a miracle
that he was still alive,
and it seems he had to stay in the I.C.U.
for a month...
When the police checked the car
that was involved in the accident,
they found that the oil pressure pipe
had been tampered with. Moreover,
they found a silencer equipped rifle
inside the trunk of the car...
The fingerprints were wiped off but,
the rifle was found
to be the one who killed Nishio...
And, was Ito arrested?
Several months after the accident,
the police were finally allowed
to see him at the hospital,
so they went...
We're coming in...
They say that Ito was gone...
After that,
Ito's whereabouts became unknown,
and had since been wanted by the police.
He was also suspected
for robbing the cash transporting car
while he was in the hospital...
Then, isn't the man called Ito
the culprit...?
Yeah...there's no doubt
that Ito shout Nishio to death...
Ito's footprints were found
at the site of the shooting,
as well as traces of gunpowder...
The number of bullets that were picked up
at the site matched
the maximum number of bullets
that could be loaded in the rifle.
The rifle mark also matched, but...
(Forensics Office)
Mascara?
Although very slight,
there was mascara found
on the scope of the rifle...
Here it is.
That is...
the killer looked through the scope...
and the mascara smeared off then
Exactly...
That mascara was of a rare brand...
So the woman
around Ito and Nishio were checked.
One woman who used mascara
of the same brand emerged...
It turned out to be Reiko Shimizu!
Oh, that lady that committed suicide
after the incident...
She was a Madonna-like symbol
of the Crime Research Yokohama club
at the Yokohama Oceanic University.
She seems to have been on very good terms
especially with Nishio who was killed,
as well as Ito...
After graduating,
she entered Ito's company along with Nishio
and served as secretary
and head of the laboratory...
The men who robbed the cash transporting car
are Ito and Nishio, right?
Ito may have a motive for killing Nishio,
but, does Reiko Shimizu have one?
According to one of her colleagues,
it seems she didn't like him
because he persistently made passes at her...
The police seemed
to have pressed her for answers
on the grounds of the mascara on the scope,
and her alibi not being clear
during the time of Nishio's murder,
but she never said anything about it...
And, on May 15th
She jumped in!
Although Reiko Shimizu's body
was not found...
the police concluded that
since the current was rapid,
there was no way she could've been saved...
Ito disappeared from the hospital 20 days
after the incident...
Consequently, two suspects of
the Nishio murder case disappeared,
so the case was virtually closed
with no known killer...
Of course, Ito's company,
having lost its president went bankrupt.
The one who bought the company
is Fukayama Trading Company.
Does it have anything to do
with Fukayama Museum
that Thief Kid... stole the jewelry from?
Of course it does...
The president, Soichiro Fukayama
is 4 years senior to Ito and Nishio
and was also a member of the same CRY club...
It seems Ito relied a lot on Fukayama...
Oh, talking about Kid, Officer Ohtaki,
while he was at it,
searched something interesting for us...
On April 4th when Thief Kid snuck
into the Fukayama Gallery,
and the getaway route of the men
who robbed the cash transporting car bumped
into each other
and there seems to
have been a shoot out there...
A shoot out?
Well, since Kid doesn't use guns,
I'm sure that
the robbers one-sidedly shot at him...
They probably fired at him because...
Thief Kid saw their faces... right...
Yeah... the shell cases of
the Colt Government and Charter Arms
were found at the site...
And ever since then,
every time Kid sneaks in to steal something
somebody comes after his life...
Interesting, isn't it?
But that's not enough to specify who
shot Mr. Nisho to death...
True...
We're lacking one more important something
to conclude the case...
Come to think of it,
Kogoro called a while ago
saying that he found an important witness...
There seems to have been a custodian
who witnessed Mr. Ito come bursting
out of the toilet with a golf bag,
after hearing some sort
of clanking noise several times,
on the day that Mr. Nishio was shot.
The clanking sound was probably
the sound of the shell case falling
on the floor of the toilet...
The contents of the golf bag
was the Charter Arms AR-7...
This is it, gramps.
Where's Pops?
He said he was going to report
his findings to the client
because he solved the case...
Don't tell me Pops...
If he makes a mistake, we're in big trouble!
Huh? Oh?
Gramps, step on the gas! Full speed!
Okay!
I was expecting you... Thief Kid.
I guess you tampered the ceiling
and rigged it
in the afternoon preparing to rob me,
but I won't let you have the jewelry...
I never steal
without sending out a warning...
What?
I came here tonight to bid you farewell...
Because I don't want to have people
keep coming after my life...
Just as expected of you, Thief Kid.
You knew all along.
Yes... in a way.
But, I just couldn't figure it out...
Why someone would so persistently come
after my life despite
my having returned the diamond that I stole,
back to you...
I've finally figured it out today...
I found that you really
treasure your subordinates...
It's your fault for having witnessed
the crime game of my dear subordinates...
A security guard was killed
and you dare call it a game...
Accidents are bound to accompany games...
The fact that you witnessed them
is also one of them.
If my precious subordinates come to me
with their problems,
I've got to do something about it, right...?
What kind of magic is that...
Did you really think
that I would come all the way out here
without making preparations?
Get rid of him! Shoot Thief Kid to death!
What's this...?
Please don't worry.
It's just plain sleeping gas.
Didn't you realize
that I've snuck in here several times
even after I snuck in here on April 4th...?
What?!
And today in the light of the afternoon
I came to rig the ceiling in order to
let you know that I would be here tonight
as well as to lure the two killers
that you hired, out here...
It can't be.
If you want to defend yourself,
do so to the police that I called.
You can do so,
along with the two dear subordinates of yours
that are asleep behind this curtain...
I guess your subordinates
were cooler than you...
Well, I'm sure the two over there
will talk their hearts out...
Including the truth of this gallery
that's full of stolen items...
It's the Thief Kid!
The Thief Kid's appeared!
Your game has reached goal...
I guess you've ended up making
the worst goal,
sending the ball into your own goal...
Open up! Police! Open up!
Hold on, Ran...
Good work, Detective Mouri...
Your client is waiting for you...
This way...
Detective Mouri is back.
I know you must be tired and I'm sorry,
but since there is not much time left,
please make your report...
The case you wanted me to check on
is the case that occurred
April 4th this year on Bashamichi,
where the cash transporting car was attacked,
and the case related to it,
that is, the shooting of Masaharu Nishio,
and the truth as to why he was shot.
I'm going to Miracle Land
where the children are!
Yeah! Take care of Kazuha for me too!
Got you!
The two men who attacked
the cash transporting car
are Suehiko Ito and Masaharu Nishio...
However, Nishio shot and killed
the security guard that fought back...
Four days later,
Nishio was shot to death by someone...
The police seem
to have suspected Reiko Shimizu
who worked for the same company,
for killing Nishio who
was making passes at her,
but I don't think so...
The motive of the killer was a grudge held
against Nishio for tainting the scheme
that he had thought out...
Yes, the one who killed Masaharu Nishio
is Ito...
Hold it!
Hey, you guys...
You people, Detective Mouri
is reporting right now...
Bummers...
Hey... What's the matter...?
Are you all right?
Detective Mouri... Hurry, continue.
That's why, to put it bluntly...
the man who killed Mr. Nishio is...
Sorry, Pops.
Bummers, the monitor switched off!
Darn!
Darn! Which button is it...?
What the...
Maybe the client is there...
What?!
When I called this man Takada a while ago,
I heard a sound in the background...
The same noise that
I heard from behind the client...
I see...
We don't have time, let's go!
Talk about dark...
We don't have time, let's go.
Welcome...Shinichi Kudo...
Heiji Hattori...
Yeah... so we finally get to see each other.
The president of Far East Office,
Mr. Suehiko Ito.
Wonderful... I was right to pair you
both together after all...
It's just as we thought, after all...
I'm sorry I have to greet you this way...
I'm quite disabled, you see...
It's because of the accident at the pier...
I found out that my body
would never be normal again...
so I came in here,
I was investing backroom assets
with the help of an acquaintance.
Miracle Land is one of them too...
Mr. Soichiro Fukayama?
Wonderful... you've figured out that far...
I'd like to give you the report since
we don't have time, okay?
Did you grasp the truth...
Yes...
I don't have much longer to live either.
That's why I needed a detective
to get to the truth of the case.
Not only one with brains,
but a tough, genuine detective.
Come, tell me...
the truth that you both grasped.
On April the 4th...
the killer who shot Mr. Masaharu Nishio,
who was at the Far East Office...
from the toilet of
the building opposite it was...
Reiko Shimizu!
She framed you up as being
the one who shot Masaru Nishio to death.
She tried to kill you also by making it
look like an accident.
That's a lie!
I shot Nishio from the toilet!
You guys are the same as the police,
as incapable as they are...
It's true that you fired the rifle
from the toilet.
But that is, after Reiko Shimizu shot him.
What?!
The 7 bullets that you fired all missed him.
7 bullets?
I can load 8 bullets
into that rifle you know...
Well, but having fled as you have,
all panicked,
not even picking the shell cases
from the floor,
it's not strange that you wouldn't be aware
of exactly how many shots you fired.
At that time,
Mr. Nishio had already been killed.
That can't be!
I saw with my own eyes
Nishio falling towards the floor
and collapse on the ground!
with the bullet I fired!
One of the bullets that you fired,
coincidentally hit the one of
the casters of the chair and blew it off.
Then, the bullet I fired
could've coincidentally hit Nishio too...
Don't be silly.
Do you think a person would sit
in place without fleeing
after so many shots are fired at him?!
Then maybe the first shot that
I fired coincidentally...
The blood on the back of the chair
that Mr. Nishio was sitting on
at the time of his death,
solidified after flowing straight down
the seat part of the chair.
That's how figured out
there were two shooters...
A sniper who had fired one shot right
through the back of Mr. Nishio's head
and after the blood that dripped solidified,
a novice at handling guns shot
at random towards him...
This did not help us conclude
which shots were the sniper's yet,
but after hearing the testimony
of the witness that Pops Mouri brought in,
everything came to light.
After hearing several metallic sounds
from the toilet,
the witness testified seeing you run out of
the toilet carrying a golf bag...
The metallic sound was the shell cases
falling on the tile floor of the toilet...
Since the witness heard
the sound several times,
the one who shot randomly was you...
That is, the sniper was Reiko Shimizu.
And you were the one who shot at random,
hit the leg of the chair, made him fall,
and thought you killed him.
The contents of the golf bag
was the Charter Arms AR7...
Before the killing,
Reiko gave you that bag...
Isn't that right?
That's true...
But, how does that connect with Reiko
having shot him...?
Something was found on
the scope of the rifle she used...
The rare brand of mascara that
Reiko Shimizu had been using.
That can't be!
After getting the bag from her,
you fired all the bullets that were
in the rifle from the toilet.
Then wanting to get rid of the car,
rifle and all you headed for the pier.
Reiko is probably also the one who tampered
with your car and caused the crash...
Her motive was probably to hog all the money
that was taken from the attack on
the cash transporting car for herself...
She was in the car when you guys attacked
and robbed the car, wasn't she?
You encountered Thief Kid when fleeing
in the getaway car.
Since he saw your faces,
you decided to shut him up.
However, since he lured you guys
into a crooked back road,
you panicked and fired at him.
They seem to have found the shell case of
the Colt Government on that back road...
No matter
how good your driving technique is,
driving along a crooked back road
with one hand,
and trying to fire at Thief Kid
who is flying over the sky
is an impossible feat
That means that two people
other than you were in the car,
one with a rifle and the other
with the Colt Government.
In other words, Mr. Masaharu Nishio
and Ms. Reiko Shimiuzu were with you.
Well, we got most of the evidence
that were used to back this deduction up
from the police,
and as for the witness Pops Mouri
came up with,
if it were the police
they could've got to him sooner.
Therefore, I think the police with allthis
in their hands,
went after Reiko Shimizu
Yes...
in this case,
it was not necessary to search for
a brilliant police officer
or capable detective to begin with...
So, the case has been solved.
Please remove the IDs of Ran and the others.
That's a lie...
Reiko would never do such a thing...
It's a lie... A lie... A lie!
It's not a lie.
So, you were alive after all...
Reiko... Is it you, Reiko!
You were not sufficient enough...
to be my partner...
Neither was Nishio.
He was merely violent...
Staying around to long
would put me in danger.
You're too timid, Ito...
And all you ever do
is brag about yourself...
You weren't fun to be around...
You gathered detectives
and it looked as if you were going
to protect me from the crimes I committed
so I let you go till now...
But, today, it all ends.
Your assets that Mr. Fukayama was managing
for you,
can now be used by me...
With Mr. Fukayama...
Mr. Fukayama is already gone...
He was gotten rid of by Thief Kid...
I'm the one who will make it
through after all!
Hey, hold it right there!
Shinichi! Don't move.
That's a Walther PPK.
There are 8 bullets!
After she fires all the shots,
I'll settle things once and for all.
6...
7...
8...!
Now!
Heiji!
I'm sorry... I'm ambidextrous.
Use this! Shinichi!
You don't need a balance point in mid air,
do you!
I get it!
Reiko...
Reiko, what's the matter?...
What's wrong, Reiko?
Reiko...!
Please undo the IDs.
I click release?...
Yeah, call an ambulance right now.
What?!
What's up?
Error?!
More complications.
Hey, Shinichi,
you know what you're doing, or what?
Not all of them are dead.
We've no choice
but to look for the live ones.
I think my time has come...
Kudo... Your voice sounds like a child's,
Heiji! Is the error still on display?
Yeah, it hasn't changed.
It's set so that
it'll explode when the time comes.
What time is that?
10:00 sharp.
Darn... Which one do I touch...?
I really wanted to ride Super Snake.
It was out of order right through.
My dessert sure is late.
Don' t complain because after all
the Inspector is treating us to all this.
Inspector Megure sure is generous.
Generously plump.
True...
Uh...Inspector Megure, did something happen?
Huh, what about...?
Because...
the police officers are gathered here...
Oh, well...
Inspector Megure...
Oh, Inspector Shiratori...
I'm sorry, Ran.
How about it...?
All the people here and
the restaurant employees have been evacuated,
so the ones left here are those children
and we, the police.
I see...
What's taking you so long, Shinichi...
Darn!
The relationship between
a man a woman deepens...
when a common secret... is held...
The deepest secret is
to be an accomplice in a crime...
with the woman one is in love with...
That's why... attacking the
cash transporting car with Reiko
was a display of my love for her.
But, because Nishio shot the security guard,
my perfect scheme was no more...
There is no such thing as perfect
in this world.
At one point things are going to
start falling out of place...
It's up to the person whether you move on
forcing your way through as is,
and lose everything
or you reset everything once,
returning things to normal,
and work hard to regain the time you lost...
You were just scared...
to reset yourself.
That could be...
Will it work...
What's this?
Unless the time is undone,
the ID cannot be removed.
Darn!...
Are you all right?
You still don't feel well?
No, I'm fine...
Oh... If you feel bad,
let me know right away, okay?
Yes... I'll do that...
Conan didn't after all, huh.
He went along with
Detective Mouri after all...
I mean, no fair, going all by himself!
Stealing a march
is one of Conan’s talents...
Did you get any word from Mr. Mouri?
No...
I see...
I'm going in at 1 minute to 10:00.
I can't just leave the children in there
by themselves...
True...
9:56...
there's not much time left, Shinichi.
-I get it! He's using wireless LAN.
-Y, Yeah...
If the wireless LAN isn't working,
if the cables are directly connected,
it may work!
A little more.
Okay,
it reached!
Okay, it worked!
All right!
Undo...time!
Enter password.
Hey! Pass...
Hey Shinichi! He's
Don't worry, he's just passed out.
It's probably an after effect
from the accident...
What is the name of the person
you love the most...?
10: 59...
You stay here.
Y, Yes sir...
Scary, right?
I wasn't scared at all!
How was it, did you enjoy the day?
Too bad we couldn't ride Super Snake.
But the one like a rocket was fun!
Yeah! I want to ride it again!
Ito's in love with Reiko Shimizu!
Wrong password.
What?!
Reiko Shimizu is no the one he loves?!
Wrong password.
If the next password is wrong
the system will shut down.
There isn't anymore time left, Shinichi!
Who is it?
The person that Ito loves...
Who...?
And all you ever do is brag about yourself...
But, because Nishio shot the security guard,
my perfect scheme was no more...
I got it!
W, What're you keying in, Shinichi?!
The timer has been undone.
Is it all over?
Yeah...this is it. It's over.
Good work, Shinichi.
I was able to undo the time bomb device,
but was unable to undo the area setting.
So, make sure you retrieve all the IDs,
every one of them, okay, Doc?
Yeah, I'll retrieve all of them right away.
Kudo... and Hattori...
you two are the best...
detectives that ever were...
You are...the worst of any human being.
Are you all okay?
Okay, take off your IDs and put it in here!
We have to take it off...?
It's closing time already, you see.
Too bad...
Handkerchief... Handkerchief...
Huh? I thought I lost it, but...Huh?
I wonder what this is...?
It looks like paint...
I wonder where I got it on...
Okay, your ID please.
Oh...that...
The Super Snake that had been
out of order today has been repaired.
Although it is already past closing time,
we will be running it one last time.
Those wanting to ride it,
please gather immediately.
Aaaaaa... All right...!
Are you okay, Heiji?
Don't worry, it's no more than a scratch!
I wonder why he thought
you were Shinichi Kudo?
This.
This... your fingerprint?
Do you remember the chair in that room?
I remember because it was so out of place
with the entire atmosphere of the room.
The armrest of the chair bothered me.
Most likely, on the armrest part...
a fingerprint recognition device was built-in
This fingerprint is of Shinichi Kudo.
If the client had a visual disability,
it's possible
that he thought I was Shinichi Kudo.
I see.
Oh... No... It's after 10:00!
It'll explode...!
Your ID belt will come off.
Huh, belt?
This, this,
Oh, yeah, really...
What a relief...
Retreived!
Hey, wait!
I tell you...
With him acting that way,
I guess the case is closed.
By the way, let me down already, will you.
Don't push yourself,
your leg hurts, doesn't it?
Right. Being piggy-backed by a girl
is the best cure for his leg so...
Why you! Darn it!
Brat...
Inspector, we've retrieved all the IDs.
The figures matched too.
Okay.
Give them to the bomb disassembling section.
Don't let anyone see what you're doing.
Yes sir!
Okay... Super Snake or what,
anything goes...!
Enjoy...
Lucky...
We have it all to ourselves...!
Heiji, I'm happy for you.
They say they sell underpants here too.
Idiot! I won't piss in my pants.
Okay everybody... raise your hands.
How exciting!
If you're scared you don't have to let go...
Who's scared?
I not only can let my hands go,
I don't even need this bar...
No! No! No!
Ha, ha, ha, ha,
Heiji, you're so funny.
Ooooh, you...
Genta, take it off...!
Genta...
What do you think you're doing?!
Hurry and take it off!
If you keep going like this
we're going out to sea
where it's out of range...!
Genta...
H, Hey, what do you think you're doing?...
You'll die if you move.
O, Okay.
Okay!
Shinichi!
Behind me!
Bummers...
Go for it!
No! Stop him!
Huh?!
No good! The safety bars all work together!
If you break one,
then all will stop functioning...
Everybody else's bar will...
This is super...
I didn't think we'd get to see fireworks too.
Special service, I guess?
I... somehow can't enjoy myself...
Hey... don't tell me that he...
Yeah... I think... that's most likely...
I tell you, that Ryu...
He pretended to be dead after they offered
to pay him a large amount of cash...
The names of the two detectives
he mentioned back then were just bluffs.
I can't figure how people would go that far
just for money... How wretched...
Yes, the Mouri Detective Agency...
Act in a commercial?
And? What kind of commercial is it...?
What? Commercial for sleeping pills?
It's easy because I always do it...?!
You gotta be joking!
Just who do you think I am?!
No matter how much guarantee
you say you'll give me...
T, That much?...
Well... Please by all means let me do it...
Yes... Yes...
Just as I thought...
As would be expected of
the Sleeping Kogoro...
I'd be more than happy to!