(Kyoto)
(Distrik Higashiyama)
(Kediaman Keluarga Yajima)
On the hills of Mimuro,
where the tempests blow.
Autumn leaves form a woven brocade flowing
(on the waters of Tatsuta River.)
The same trump card as Master...
It is all thanks to you...
Ooka Momiji.
After today's TV recording,
I must extend my gratitude to you.
What? So early?
You're here already?
Ah, it's you?!
What is it?
N-No way!
The flowers of Naniwa Bay now blossom...
after lying dormant all winter.
Now that spring has come,
these flowers bloom.
The flowers are blooming.
(The leaves of the maple trees...)
(of Mount Mimuro...)
I had no idea karuta cards could fly.
Oh, excuse me.
Excuse me.
So lovely!
Dad! Please be quiet!
Isn't she a beauty?
Just like an idol.
She looks so good in kimono!
So, why are we watching
this karuta competition?
Because Mikiko told us to!
She said to stay at the waiting room.
But Uncle followed that pretty girl
right into the studio!
Who's Mikiko?
Didn't I introduce her just now?
The girl in glasses who is competing
with that pretty girl!
She's the captain of my school's karuta club.
I'm from that club too.
Kazuha, you're part of the karuta club?
Yes! Didn't you know?
Haven't they been to the toilet
for rather long now?
Sorry.
The studio entrance was closed.
I didn't know if it was okay to open it.
Excuse me.
We are currently in the middle of rehearsal,
(Even this life, )
so could you quiet down a bit?
R-Right.
that I would not be sorry to forfeit...
Whoa! So cool!
Hey, Kudo.
Did the old man forget that our purpose
for coming to Osaka is for the interview?
Ah, give him a break.
The children were whining that
they wanted to visit Osaka,
but the professor was busy
so he had to take them.
Speaking of which, where is that rich girl?
Oh, Sonoko...
She's down with a cold.
I never knew.
So Kazuha joined the karuta club.
I'm in both the Aikido club
and the Karuta club!
The Karuta club has so few new members.
it might be disbanded soon.
Hence I'm a zombie member
who put my name down,
and occasionally serve
as Mikiko's practice opponent.
A zombie club member... how weird.
It's so fun and lively in here.
I wonder if I'm in a café.
S-Sorry!
DETECTIVE CONAN: THE CRIMSON LOVE LETTER
I am high school student detective,
Kudo Shinichi.
One day, at an amusement park
with my childhood friend
and classmate Mori Ran,
I witnessed
a suspicious-looking man in black...
...carrying out a deal.
Too engrossed in watching,
I failed to notice,
another of his accomplices...
approach me from behind.
That man forced a poison down my throat,
and when I woke up,
my body had shrunk!
If those men knew that
Kudo Shinichi was still alive,
they would target my life again
and endanger those around me.
Taking Professor Agasa's advice,
I hid my identity.
But when Ran asked for my name,
I spontaneously told her
it was 'Edogawa Conan'.
Because Ran's father is a detective,
I moved in with her family
to gather information on those men.
This is Hattori Heiji,
high school detective of the West.
Having inherited his father's
superior deductive reasoning
as chief of the Osaka Prefectural Police,
he has cracked many difficult cases.
He is one of the few
who know my true identity.
Toyama Kazuha is Hattori's childhood friend
and classmate.
What will become of them,
now that a love rival claiming
to be his future bride has appeared?!
Finally, the mysterious future queen.
Who exactly is she?
Even though my body has shrunk,
my brain is still unchanged.
I'm the one and only detective
who closes every case!
There is always only one truth!
(Nichiuri Television)
I'm here at the TV station
but am stuck in the waiting area!
I want to watch the live recording!
That's not possible.
Even Uncle Kogoro was making an angry fuss...
(Satsuki Association World of Karuta)
Sorry, everyone.
(Mr. Mouri Kogoro)
It's all my fault.
Oh, I know!
Shall we go souvenir shopping
when everyone gets back?
- Really?
- Do you mean that?
Yes. But only if you all be good
until the recording is over.
Of course!
Hurray!
Let's all go shopping together!
Hey, wait a minute.
Where's Conan?
Oh, speaking of Conan...
He's doing something on my behalf.
He's keeping an eye on my dad.
Hey, boy!
Didn't I tell you to stay
in the waiting area?
But Ran told me to keep an eye
on the recording situation.
Yeah, right!
Please make way!
Move aside, please!
Kurata cards coming through!
Wow, the Karuta cards
for the Satsuki Association!
Those Karuta cards are so famous!
Tell me about it, Kazuha!
Those are the very same cards
used by the Satsuki Association
for the Finals of the
National Karuta Compeititon?
It's your dream to compete with those cards.
Right, Mikiko?
I'm not the only one.
In the Satsuki Association's
20-year history,
there is no one
who does not long for those cards.
Ah, if I could only
just touch those legendary cards once,
in a finals round...
Say...
Why are those cards used
only in the final round?
After so many rounds of intense competition,
they must have suffered
quite a bit of damage.
No wonder they are encased,
only to be used in the final round.
The rest of the time,
they are on display at the museum.
Still, isn't the security
a bit too heavy for just cards?
Not at all.
After last year's Satsuki Cup,
it was chaos when the karuta cards
were found missing.
As a result, even though the cards
were recovered at once,
the champion Yajima wanted
reinforced security,
and seems to have successfully
persuaded President Achiha into doing so.
I see. By the way, who are those two?
Are you an idiot, old man?
Don't you recognise your interviewers?!
Oh, that's right.
- As expected of the old man.
- And speaking of Satsuki,
shouldn't it be a horse?
Here it is, a write-up
on President Achiha Kensuke.
A magnate who built Achiha Properties
in a single generation,
also known as Naniwa's king of property.
Why would such a person
be interested in karuta?
Apparently, it is his only hobby.
And he seems to be rather good at it too.
But it says here that Achiha personally
would rather be a reader than a player.
W-Whoa! Who is this beautiful lady?
That's Achiha's wife, Satsuki.
Darn it, she's married!
Satsuki Association was originally founded
by Queen Satsuki.
Achiha gradually took over
and became the president.
Another interview topic could be...
Oh, this looks interesting.
Achiha would always wash his car the day
before his wife, Satsuki,
had an important match.
Because as the saying goes,
the secret to winning is
to make your car look good.
So, I'll be attending the interview
with this husband and wife pair?
No.
Satsuki died of an illness three years ago.
Only President Achiha will be present
at today's interview.
I... I see.
Hey, who is this tough looking guy?
He's always within Achiha's reach.
Ah, that would be...
...Achiha's former secretary, Kaieda Togo.
He's a highly capable person
who single-handedly manages
Achiha Properties's clandestine activities.
Wonder where he went
after retiring as secretary...
Wait a minute, Hattori!
Don't say such things if you have no proof.
The president would never do that!
That's right, Heiji!
Calm down... Those were just rumours.
The president has entered!
It's President Achiha. We've to greet him.
Mr President.
We will be counting on you today.
Indeed, I'll be counting on you too.
Yes.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
but will today's schedule
be the demonstration match
between Yajima and Momiji,
followed by the interview?
Yes.
When airing, we have last week's recording
with Yajima's help.
The special feature
on the Satsuki Association's Karuta
will promote Karuta on a nationwide basis.
Ah, I see the karuta cards meant
for the Satsuki Cup are already on display.
I'll be counting on you then.
Yes!
What an overwhelming presence.
Indeed.
As expected of Naniwa's property king.
Sorry. Can someone get in touch with Yajima?
It's almost his turn.
But I can't seem to contact him at all.
That's strange.
He said he'd be here an hour
before the recording goes live.
Yajima is a stickler for time and he's late?
Please ask Sekine to standby just in case.
If anything happens,
he can stand-in for Yajima.
It... It can't be.
There's still time
before the recording starts.
Yes, there is!
Hey Heiji,
where are we going for okonomiyaki?
There's only one place
to go for okonomiyaki.
Indeed! Okonomiyaki is...
Sorry about that. Are you alright?
You were one of the karuta players
from just now!
This is fate...
I have waited to meet you...
My future husband.
Future...
Husband?!
I have some free time after the recording.
If you don't mind,
would you like to go for tea together?
She sure is huge!
W-Wait a second! What exactly are you...
No, wait...
Momiji!
Sorry, but please return to the waiting area.
Aww, but I was getting to the good part...
Actually, Yajima is late.
Yajima?
Well, he is after all
in-charge of this program
and must be held up by some matters.
Well then, see you around, Heiji!
Yeah, see you!
Who is she?!
That pretty lady!
She's beautiful, isn't she?
Unless I'm mistaken,
I heard her say she was... Momiji!
Like I said... I have no idea!
But she knew your name!
- Ran?
- I won't be angry, so tell me the truth!
- Let's go wait outside.
- You're angry already!
-Looks like something's going on.
Let's go!
- I'm not angry.
- What exactly is she mad about?
Well... maybe we did
meet each other somewhere.
See?! I was right! You knew each other!
I said I don't know her!
There's no way anyone could forget
meeting a babe like that.
A babe?!
Well, you're hard to forget too,
in a different way.
What?
What did you mean by that?!
Hey, hey.
Heiji, do you really not know that person?
Ooka... Momiji?
"High school champion
of the Satsuki Cup for two years running."
"Second-year student
of Kyoto Senshin High School."
"She is very likely
the future Karuta queen..."
Ooka Momiji?
The future queen?
(Osaka Prefectural Police)
Is this the warning?
Yes. It states "There will be an explosion
at Nichiuri Television."
What does this Karuta photograph mean?
It was sent as an email attachment.
I'm still not sure what it means.
And is Nichiuri Television aware of this?
I gave them a heads up.
What are your thoughts, Heizo?
It might be a prank, or an alert.
It's hard to tell
from the email alone, but...
...things could escalate
if it turns out not to be a prank.
We have received
an emergency evaculation alert
from the Osaka Prefectural Police.
- Kindly cease all activities and recordings,
- What's this announcement?
and evacuate the building using
the nearest emergency stairwells.
- I repeat.
- What?
An evacuation drill at this time?
Is something wrong?
It's from the police.
Any TV recording taking place?
Hey! Go check it out!
Y-Yes!
What's happening?
Kazuha!
Hurry up and get to the emergency exit!
You got that?!
Yup! What about you?
Not before I find out what's going on!
You just get out of here first!
Wait... Heiji!
That was close!
It's dangerous.
-Kid! Where do you think you're going?!
I left something in the studio...
Idiot!
Didn't you hear the announcement?
Sorry,
this is also my first time...
I've never done
an evacuation drill dressed in kimono...
This is bad. Let's evacuate quickly!
Calm down. What happened?
There was an explosion threat.
What?
President Achiha! It might be a hoax,
but let's get to safety
while confirming that.
Yes, you're right.
Everyone! Do as the announcement said
and get out of here!
Hurry!
Y-Yes!
What are you doing, Mikiko?
It's not safe here. Get out of here, quick!
Achiha, you too!
What are you doing? Get out of here, quick!
Everyone, please calm down and move along.
We are performing safety checks
within the building.
Everyone, stay where you are and wait.
What? Wait again?
-There's no connection...
We left dad alone and came out,
-I wonder if he's alright.
Ran!
Dad! Conan!
Hey, what exactly is going on here?
-Are they really
doing an evacuation drill
without prior notice?
-Well, I asked the TV crew just now...
- Looks like there really was a bomb threat at this building.
- What's the matter? Conan...
You can't be serious.
By the way, where are Kazuha and Hattori?
What?
Weren't they with you guys?
Yeah...
I'm worried. I'll go look for them.
No, I'll go!
None of you are to leave this spot.
Got that?!
Darn it, an evacuation drill now
of all times!
Heiji!
Mikiko!
What did I tell you? Get out of here!
I know, but I was worried about you two!
Sorry, Kazuha!
I just can't leave the karuta cards behind!
Judging from the GPS coordinates
on the smartphone...
Hattori still hasn't left the building?!
You!
What are you doing?
Leave that behind and evacuate at once!
Darn it!
Mikiko!
Kazuha! Hattori!
Guys, you have no idea how dangerous this is.
I'm sorry!
Seriously...
I have three persons here at Studio 3.
Mikiko!
- Gosh, why did you do that?
- They are the last three.
- Sorry...
- Evacuate them at once.
- If the bomb threat was real,
- Understood!
it would make no difference anyway.
I don't know when it will explode.
We will wait for instructions remotely.
I'll leave it to you.
The remaining three
from the studio have started evacuating.
Is that everyone?
Yes!
Alright!
The search for the dangerous object
will now commence!
All units, prepare to enter!
Understood!
- They went in.
- Is there really a bomb?
It's probably just a prank.
Over here, quick!
Over here!
It's for real?!
All units, back down!
All members, back down!
Get away from the building!
Mr President, hurry!
Danger!
Kazuha!
- Wow
- No! It's dangerous, stay down.
Darn it, where are they?!
Was Hattori still inside when it exploded?!
Kazuha!
You can't go!
It's not safe here.
Now, let's move.
It hurts.
Are you alright? Can you walk?
Y-Yes...
Good. Let's go, this way!
This way, you can go step-by-step...
Yes...
- More people are coming out!
- So there were people still inside!
They said there were two remaining...
What?!
Kazuha, over here!
Darn it!
Heiji!
That was close!
Run!
We can't go down...
Kazuha, over here!
- We've got to go higher!
- What's going on?! Aren't we going down?
If we can't find a way out,
we've got to go somewhere we can breathe!
No way. Hattori...
Did he climb up?
Darn... we didn't make it.
Let's go, Kazuha!
Kazuha!
Over here!
The roof top... Is it made of concrete?
Get nearer! We need to close in!
It's impossible!
Getting any nearer would be too dangerous!
Excuse me! Let me through!
Darn it!
The smoke is blocking my vision!
I can't do this alone... not by myself!
Kudo!!
We've got to take a chance.
It's do or die.
Come on!
What's that?
At last.
Hattori...
Wait, Heiji. Where are you doing?
Come on! This is the only way down!
Down... from here?
Stay right here, Kazuha. You got that?!
Wait, Heiji!!
Get down from here...
are you kidding me?
Hey, I'm ready whenever you are.
Ditto.
There's no time. I'll do this in one shot.
Right!
Kazuha!
You can't be serious.
Stop! I can't see...
Is this a joke?! Heiji!
Close your eyes and hold on!
What? Wh...?
Wait...
Thanks for this. See you at the bottom.
Yup.
Kudo!
Darn it!
Kudo!!
Don't tell me there's someone there. Quick!
I was right, there is!
Stretcher, get a stretcher over here!
Kazuha!
Heiji?
Darn it...
And that was the only way down from here.
Think! There has to be
another way out of this place.
A rescue helicopter!
No, it's impossible.
It can't even get close
with all the flames and smoke,
much less make a landing.
Hang on,
there's a river next to the TV station.
If I can somehow jump into that...
Alright!
No, I can't.
There's no more room
for the skateboard to accelerate...
This is bad.
My lungs feel like
they're on fire with even a tiny breath.
I need a plan... and fast!
Ran...
I can't simply give up...
There must be some room
for the skateboard to move... come on...
Over there!
What are you doing, Kudo? Come on!
That's...
No mistake, it's Kudo. But what is he...?
I see!
So that's it!
Come on...
More speed...
Darn it... it's getting harder to breathe...
Just a little more!
It's falling!
Is this the maximum?!
Darn!
There wasn't enough acceleration!
Oh no, I won't make it!
We were waiting!
Here!
Hey Kudo, are you alright?
I guess...
Here, you dropped this.
Thanks.
Come to think of it...
Why did you bring that thing today?
Did you know that Nichiuri Television
was going to get bombed?
Of course not.
It's in case of an emergency.
And that emergency just happened to be today.
Looks that way.
Kazuha!
Ran!
Are you alright?
Yes. Except for breathing lots of smoke,
I don't recall much.
It's a relief that you're fine.
In any case, it's good that you're alright
Yup...
Ran,
I might have dropped the car keys somewhere.
I'm going to look for them.
Okay.
Come to think of it, where's Conan?
Right.
I thought he was at the evacuation centre...
Oh, it's Conan!
It is!
Conan! Where have you been?
We were so worried!
Hi, Kazuha.
Hey, Heiji!
Where have you been all this while?
Ah, well you see...
You too, Conan.
I was so worried.
Sorry.
By the way, where's Mikiko?
Apparently she injured her arm
and was taken to the hospital.
Her arm?
Hopefully it's nothing serious.
I found out which hospital she was sent to.
Shall we all go later?
Okay. Let's go!
Heiji.
Ootaki.
Thank goodness you're alright.
Sorry, Kazuha. Please go on without me.
I'll catch up.
Oh... Let's go, Ran.
Okay. Come on, Conan.
R-Right.
Don't get separated again.
Okay.
See you around, Conan.
Is it true that
the police received a bomb alert?
This is the email that the police received.
An attachment of a Karuta card?
There might be some connection between this
and the Karuta program they were recording...
That's the state of Nichiuri Television...
Looks like the investigation
will take some time.
Looks like it.
What exactly is the perpetrator's motive?
(Naniwa Police Hospital)
Thank you for your care.
Sure. Please take care.
Mr President, are you alright?
Oh, it's nothing. Just a few scratches.
That's a relief.
But why did this have to happen
right before the tournament?
Indeed, who would have known?
What a pity that this year's Satsuki Cup
has to be cancelled because of this.
We mustn't give in!
It's times like these that
we need to push forward
to preserve the Satsuki Club's image!
But the Karuta cards for the Satsuki Cup
have been burnt.
Without those Karuta cards,
the tradition of the Satsuki Cup
cannot be continued.
There's no need to worry about that.
The karuta cards are safe.
What?
Whatever do you mean?
Hiramoto took them
during the evacuation process.
Mikiko did that?
The Karuta cards would have naturally
been destroyed in the fire,
but they are safe!
Is that the truth?!
Were the Karuta cards for the Satsuki Cup
really not destroyed in the fire?
T-The museum staff took the cards away
to check for damages and all...
Mr President,
the Karuta cards are safe,
so please calm down.
And I was sure that it was the end...
what great news!
And what about Mikiko who saved the cards?
How is she?
I heard that her life isn't in danger, but...
...it seems she's still under observation.
I see.
Mikiko sure is taking a long time.
The doctor said that
she just needed some first aid...
Thank you very much.
Mikiko! Your arm! Don't tell me...
Yeah. It's broken, most likely.
I guess it's karma.
No way...
I went back fort he karuta cards
and risked both Kazuha
and Hattori's lives in the process...
What do you mean?
Thank you, Mikiko.
You saved the Karuta cards
which are the pride
of the Satsuki Association.
As President, I cannot thank you enough.
But, Mr President!
I won't be able to participate in the event
with my arm like this...
It's a loss for the Satsuki cup that
someone with your capability can't take part,
but you really ought to focus
on getting better right now.
That's right.
There's always next year too, right?
That won't happen.
Unless I achieve good results
in this year's Satsuki Cup,
the Karuta club will surely be shut down.
I can't let the Karuta club
be shut down during my tenure...
Mr President.
The police are waiting.
It's about time.
Cheer up, Mikiko.
But...
Well it is true that
none of the other members
can play karuta except for us...
That's right, Kazuha!
You should compete!
Replace me as our school representative!
What? You can't just decide like that...
Kazuha, have you participated
in any tournament before?
No, never...
But you have been practising
with me all this while.
Y-Yeah.
You have the strength
and your reflexes are quick.
Also, your never say die attitude
makes you undefeatable!
And you're really thick-skinned
in a weird kind of way.
Somehow, that didn't sound like a compliment.
When does the competition start?
The day after tomorrow.
It will be fine!
If we start training now,
Kazuha will make it somehow!
A beginner competing in the event
with the aim of becoming champion?
Might as well just change Hyakkunin Isshu
to Iroha karuta.
Don't make fun of her.
I'm the one Kazuha's been practicing with,
so I know her strengths best!
Despite not having experience
in competitions,
her skills are top class, without a doubt!
Is she really that good?
Not to mention you
seem really close to Heiji.
What kind of relationship
do you two have exactly?
We've known each other
since we were kids! Heiji and I...
We're...
Sweethearts?
I could tell right away!
It's really obvious!
Stop interrupting!
Sounds like Poem 40 of the Hyakkunin Isshu
to me. (A poem about being in love).
Talk about childhood sweethearts.
Aww, how heartwarming.
I'll tell you what.
Whoever wins the event
the day after tomorrow,
will be the top candidate as Heiji's bride.
In other words,
she has priority over confessing to Heiji
and winning his heart.
How about that?
W-What are you trying to do?!
If you're serious about him,
you ought to be
motivated enough for this, right?
Kazuha,
you don't have to take her up on this.
I'll tell you one thing though.
I'm serious about him.
Wait!
I accept...
your challenge!
K-Kazuha!
I-Is she for real?
I hope your determination doesn't run out
before the competition date.
Likewise to you.
Don't burn out before our match!
I'll excuse myself then.
I need to go to the nail salon,
and think about what to say to Heiji
during my confessoin.
What a scary lady.
Yeah.
I can't believe I saw that.
You're unbelievable as always.
Fancy speaking to Momiji that way!
What should I do?
I made a terrible promise...
I'm so sorry.
Oh no, it was my fault too.
Dad. Did you find the keys?
No, I seached everywhere.
But I just couldn't find them.
Guess I'll just have to duplicate them.
What's wrong, Conan?
The lady from earlier must have dropped this.
Really? Let me see.
No mistake, this belongs to Momiji.
Dad, I'll go give this back.
Eh? Is it someone you know?
Gosh, this is depressing.
What do you think I should do?
What do you mean by that?
It was kind of scary.
She was really pretty!
If Heiji got a confession from that girl,
he'd be head over heels in love for sure.
B-But the one who really suits him...
is Kazuha!
Really?
Really, really!
No time for that kind of talk now.
Training starts tonight!
This is my first time at a hospital.
It's so huge, I feel like I could get lost.
Ran. She's there. Over there!
Momiji!
Wait up!
Momiji, wait!
Oh, she left.
What should we do about this?
We know her name and school,
but to get her contact number...
It'd be quicker to look inside for it?
That's true.
Ran, let me see.
Okay.
Let's see, this is...
- A photo.
- This person...
Who is it?
Wait, there's another one.
It looks like a childhood photo.
It's Momiji, and...
Hattori?
They're doing a pinky promise.
I wonder what kind of promise.
A promise to get married?
Even at that young age?
That can't be right, can it?
Actually,
that's the sort of thing he would do.
Knowing that guy...
That's Heiji's bike.
We must keep that photo a secret, okay?
Especially from Kazuha!
Yes.
Wow. Did you both come out to welcome us?
What's up with her?
Ran. Have you delivered the item?
Y-Yeah.
You're late.
Huh? Found anything?
No, the Osaka Prefectural Police
are still in a state of chaos.
Ootaki will contact us
once they've gathered all the information.
Mr President,
it seems like something important.
Would you take this call?
Oh. Sure.
Good grief.
What's gotten into Ran?
Ah... what,
from the Kyoto Prefectural Police?
Yes.
And what about Yajima?
What?
He was murdered?!
- Okay.
- I understand.
I'll cancel eveything and be right there.
Thanks for the hard work.
Just a minute kids,
this place is off limits.
We're with Mouri Kogorou.
What nonsense did you say?
Let those kids through.
Long time no see, the pair of you.
Detective Ayanokouji!
The victim was Yajima Toshiya.
He was the son
of a distinguished sake-making family.
It seems he lived alone in this mansion.
The time of death is estimated at 6 am.
His body was discovered at 2 pm,
8 hours after he died.
Oh, please watch your step.
It looks like they made quite a mess in here.
Was it a robbery?
Looking at the crime scene,
it is definitely a murder case.
Yeah, we think so too.
Someone broken in
with the intention of theft.
And Yajima happened to be at the scene.
On the spur of the moment,
the culprit killed Yajima...
...with the Japanese sword
he had planned to steal.
But why...?
From the looks of it, the victim seemed
to be practicing karuta when it happened.
That seems to be the case.
What...? Why are you all here?!
Hey, Inspector.
Let me check out the crime scene.
Well, the Criminal Identification Unit
is done here,
so be my guest.
Why is that allowed?!
However,
we will be taking the murder weapon with us.
Yes, no problem.
Please assist them as far as they need.
Right.
We'll wait outside,
so let us know if you find anything.
What do you think?
I can't really tell yet.
His right hand...
I see you noticed it too, Kudo.
It seems like
a bloodstained item was removed from it.
Speaking of bloodstained items in this room...
The karuta cards.
The culprit noticed the victim
left his dying message
and deliberately slipped that card
into the rest of the bloodstained cards.
Retrieving that card will be a problem.
Leave that to me.
I know someone good at this sort of thing.
What is that about?
That remote control,
judging from its blood stains,
should have been right beside the victim
when the murder happened...
Excuse me.
Is it alright if I turn on the television?
Yes, go ahead.
Thanks.
Could the victim have been
using the remote control
right before he was killed?
What could have been showing at the time?
It's Ooka Momiji.
Yajima was probably watching this...
...right before he was attacked!
What's the matter?
Looks like videos of old tournaments.
Yes.
The 15th to 20th Satsuki Cup.
Why was Yajima watching these videos?
In karuta,
the level of competition heightens quite a bit
by the time they reach the finals.
From different skill sets
to card sequence placed,
one can learn a lot just by watching.
This might have nothing to do
with the murder case.
But...
But, but, but...
You're nothing but a nuisance!
You too, get going!
- Wait, Uncle!
- Enough of your detective games!
- Sorry about this, guys.
- What are you doing?
-Put me down!
Alright, alright. I'll do it so let me go!
And now for the news.
Today, at Osaka Prefecture, Osaka City,
- Not this again... how worrying.
- a big explosion took place at Nichiuri Television around 1 pm.
Ai, why did you turn it off?
If you worry every single time
this news comes on,
you'd be ill in no time.
But...
You got in touch with the kids, right?
But I haven't heard from Shinichi.
Look.
(Edogawa Conan Incoming Call)
Speak of the devil.
Let me speak to him when you're done.
What have you been so busy
with that you didn't even contact us?
The Professor was really worried.
Sorry, sorry.
There's so much going on here right now.
So, what do you need?
I just sent some photos to your computer.
I need you to check on them,
they're photos of Karuta cards.
First the bombing incident,
now bloodstained Karuta cards?
I need you to identify the one card
from the pile the victim was holding
in his hand when he was murdered.
You're good at this sort of stuff,
aren't you?
Honestly, I ought to...
One of the photos is of a person.
Could you also find out
whatever you can about that person?
Is this person active in the Karuta scene?
Yes, I suspect so.
Alright,
I'll do my best so give me some time.
Great! I'm counting on you then.
Bye!
Oh, wait! The Professor wants to...
Given the situation,
it looks like the key members of
the Satsuki Association are being targetted.
We need to shadow two particular individuals.
I'll keep an eye on Achiha.
I think we're staying at the same hotel.
I'll keep watch on Ooka Momiji then.
Wait a minute. Who are you?
I'm from the Satsuki Association.
Let me through.
Wait a minute, I need to verify that.
Sekine!
Where have you been?
I tried to contact you again and again.
I'm sorry, Mr President.
I had too much to drink last night
and fell asleep without realising
that my phone was out of battery.
Honestly...
When I woke up,
I saw the news on a bomb explosion
at the TV station.
So I contacted the association
and they told me you were at Yajima's place.
They also said you were looking for me,
so I rushed over
and it looks like chaos here.
So many policemen too.
What happened to Yajima?
I'm sorry to say that
Yajima was murdered.
It appears to be the work of a robber
He was killed with a Japanese sword
from the corridor.
A Japanese sword?
No way.
Mr Achiha, who is this?
Pardon me.
I'm a member of the Satsuki Association.
I work as a photographer,
my name is Sekine Kouji.
Sekine is Yajima's biggest rival.
The final matches of the Satsuki Cup
over the last two years were
between them both.
Well, I lost two years running
and just as I thought
I'd finally beat him this year...
I'll never be able to spar with him again.
So, will the tournament proceed as planned?
About that,
I'm still at a loss what to do.
Mr President, you can't give up.
If the Satsuki Cup is called off
because of Yajima's death,
he would have been beaten in vain.
We'd all be ultimate losers!
Sekine, you ought not to say
such disrespectful words.
I see.
I'm sorry. I got carried away.
I'm from the Kyoto Prefectural Police.
Could you spare me some time
for two or three questions or so?
Of course. I'll do my best to co-operate.
This way please, then.
Right.
- Mouri, I need to return to Osaka soon.
- Hey Kudo,
- I think I know who did it.
- Really?
- Me too.
- I'll go with you.
Yajima's killer is probably
who we think it is.
But it doesn't seem like
the same person was responsible
for the television station bombing,
which was probably targetting
the Satsuki Association instead.
Exactly.
To be safe,
we'll have to keep tabs
on Achiha and Momiji like we agreed.
Yeah.
(Hotel New Otani)
Number One!
Number Two!
You're both cheating! Wait for me!
What a big room!
Sonoko booked this for us.
You see, she really wanted to join us.
That's why she booked a hotel
located near to the TV station.
One would expect no less
of the Suzuki Corporation.
Oh, right.
thought you'd be spending the night training,
so I gave instructions for supper
to be prepared for you.
Wow, thanks.
Gosh, why am I doing this?
It was the sight of you
supporting your friend with so much energy.
Well, it's no big deal!
Now, it's training time!
We'll help too!
Please let us know how we can help.
I'll do my best to support you!
You guys...
Thank you all so much.
Oh, someone's calling.
Who is it?
It's the Professor...
I want to speak to him!
We'll all speak to him!
Yes, let's.
Please go ahead with your training, ladies.
We'll be over there
so we don't get in your way!
Just when they promised us
their full support...
They meant this?
Oh, I can see each of you!
Has anything happened since?
We're all safe.
We're already at the hotel!
In that case, it's perfect timing.
-Don't tell me...
The moment you've all been waiting for!
The Professor's Quiz Corner!
Is that why you called?
Okay, let's start!
Competitive Karuta has been compared
to a certain Japanese tradition,
one that is labour intensive.
Which of the following is it?
1. Harvesting tea leaves.
2. Kite flying.
3. Making Japanese mochi.
4. Harvesting rice.
It must be the harvesting of tea
since it's similar to picking out
and stacking up the Karuta cards.
Kite Flying (Tako Age)?
I want some Takoyaki...
One can play foul in Karuta ("otetsuki")
so it has to be making Japanese mochi (mochi tsuki)?
Your final answer?
The answer is 4, harvesting rice.
Aww, Ai!
The action of cutting rice from the fields
is like card swiping in karuta.
It's exactly like Karuta!
Aww, I thought I had all of you.
Hey, kids.
You're travelling now,
so don't stay up too late.
Okay!
I'm hanging up then.
It's so late at night.
A lot happened today...
They're late, Dad and the others.
- I wonder if Heiji is with them.
- The sky turned dark so quickly!
If you're worried, why not give him a call?
You're right.
What's up, Kazuha?
What's up? indeed!
Where are you wandering around at this time?
What? Kyoto?
What's going on?
Sorry but something came up
so I can't take you back today.
You've got to go home by yourself.
What's that supposed to mean?
I thought you were practising with me
for Karuta training.
Training?
I'll be replacing Mikiko...
in the Karuta competition..
But you've never taken part
in a Karuta competition.
Precisely, that's why I've got to train.
Weren't you really good at Karuta
when we were kids?
Now that you mention it...
I once took part in a Karuta competition
during elementary school.
I was so surprised when you won, Heiji!
That was so long ago, I hardly remember it.
But I remember!
When Mikiko asked me
to help recruit new members,
you were the first one I thought of.
I remember all of that.
Right. Are you done talking about the past?
I've to hang up soon.
What's with that attitude?!
Do you have to hang up soon
because you dislike talking to me?
That's not what I said.
Right. I'll be just fine without you, Heiji.
Huh? What was that about?
I've had enough, and you're a jerk!
Darn it, what's his problem?
What's up with her?
No choice then.
Hi, it's me. I need your help.
(Ooka)
Yup, that's right. I owe you one then.
I'm so tired.
Welcome back, Uncle.
Good grief.
Who would have thought
we'd come all this way to Osaka
only to get caught up in that incident?
Dad? Where's Conan?
He said he wanted a ride back,
and we drove back together, but...
When we got to the hotel,
he said he had something
to tell President Achiha.
Gosh, that Conan.
If the culprit is who we think it is,
then his next target tonight
would be President Achiha.
What's up, Ran?
Are you done with your errand?
Y-Yeah!
Then please go back to your room, okay?
After what happened, I can't help worrying.
Yup, I got that. I'll be there soon.
Great.
Now, even if he steps outside,
I can trail him.
That person... unless I'm mistaken...
What is she doing here?
But we promised
That was amazing!
- Truly amazing!
- I knew I wasn't good enough
to be their practice partner!
- Hey, that was dangerous!
- It's as fast as Kamen Yaiba!
- Just a little closer, and...
- C'mon, just a bit more...
- I'm back!
- Oh, Conan!
I brought a worthy opponent.
Who is it?
Heiji's mum?
Heiji called me.
So I rushed over.
But why?
I've come to assist Kazuha.
You're about to start karuta training,
aren't you?
T-That's right, but...
I'll be your partner.
As a former Queen,
I might not be of much help, but...
Former Queen?
It was a request
from Heiji himself after all,
so I'll teach you everything I know.
But as time is limited,
practice will be intensive.
Are you up for it?
Yes! I am in your debt!
I knew you'd show up.
Inspector Ayanokouji.
It would appear that great minds think alike.
The little detective isn't with you?
He's keeping tabs on President Achiha.
I see.
You guys make a great team.
Indeed, although I'm regretting
making Momiji my choice.
To think she's living in such a big house...
Thanks for coming all this way.
I am in the service of Young Mistress Momiji.
My name is Iori.
How about a rest and some tea?
So you were worried about me
and came all this way...
My future husband.
That's why I said, you were doing it wrong.
Darn.
Looks like he hasn't left the hotel.
That was a great attempt from you.
To be honest,
I didn't think you could go this far.
Now then, shall we take a break?
Not yet... I don't need one!
Rest is also an important part of training.
I'll be having some porridge then.
Kazuha.
Are you alright?
Let her sleep.
She hasn't slept a wink. Amazing work.
How did Kazuha do?
Her potential way exceeded
what I expected of her.
While she can easily get into the top four,
entering the final championship
may prove difficult.
No way...
Hear me out. I'm not done.
I said it would be difficult,
but not impossible.
After all, the keys to competitive karuta...
are mental strength and focus.
The girl possesses these qualities.
With her indominable spirit
...and pure competitive streak,
she too, has a chance of winning.
Kazuha's spirits would be dampened
if she saw this.
I'll make this brief,
so bear with me.
Darn it, it's almost time
for the lottery results.
So, what is it?
It's regarding Yajima's murder.
Wasn't that the work of a burglar?
Was it really?
According to my speculation,
it was a planned murder commited
in cold blood.
Ridiculous! Yajima wasn't a likeable person,
no doubt.
But to suggest that someone hated him enough
to murder him, is just...
What about you?
Don't be stupid!
Why would I...
Sekine.
You lost the Satsuki Cup
for two years running.
And both times, you lost to Yajima.
Let's say Yajima were to disappear.
You would then...
Stop, stop. This is absurd.
I want to win, obviously.
But to kill my rival for that purpose?
It's ridiculous!
Anyway, the police have classified
this case as burglary, so what's this about?!
There are a few reasons.
First of all,
ransacking is almost a given in a burglary.
But in the case,
the culprit did not touch anything
related to karuta.
Could he have been in a hurry
to leave the murder scene?
Indeed,
but my speculation...
is the culprit's emotional attachment
to things related to karuta,
and an inherent inability to destroy them.
Detectives really do
think of the oddest things.
Well, speculate all you like.
It has nothing to do with me.
- Darn it.
- It has nothing to do with me.
Ah, wait.
What now?
The annex's corridor has creaky flooring.
It makes these creaky noises.
Do you remember that?
And what about it?
Given such a disturbance,
Yajima would have realised
at once if someone entered the annex.
But there were no signs
of dispute found on the body.
I see.
I guess you're implying that
the intruder was someone
Yajima was familiar with.
Well, you're wrong.
Even during practice,
karuta requires intense concentration.
The minute you start to focus,
you won't hear such noises.
And that's why Yajima was never
aware of the intruder,
and was killed.
That is not possible.
Yajima was dealt a fatal blow
to the centre of his head.
If he had continued playing karuta
unaware that someone had entered,
the wound would have been
to the back of his head, not the side.
In other words,
unless Yajima knew the culprit,
such a blow would not have been possible.
The culprit
is someone well-versed in karuta,
acquainted with Yajima and had no alibi
at the time of the crime.
Not to mention also,
this person would stand to gain
from Yajima's death.
Well, how curious.
Everything points to me.
Then again,
all that you have said
are mere speculations, no?
In order to make me the culprit,
you need evidence.
Sekine, time's up.
Please get ready.
Okay, I'll be right there.
What a shame, it's time.
Bye then.
Just one last question.
This is annoying. What?
I can't quite get
this conversation out of my head.
I'm not sure if you remember it, though.
If the Satsuki Cup is called off
because of Yajima's death,
he would have been beaten in vain.
We'd all be ultimate losers!
Indeed, I said that.
Normally, upon knowing that
the murder weapon is a katana,
one would think of slashing
and stabbing as the causes of death.
Even so, you mentioned the phrase "beaten".
Only the culprit would know
that the katana used for the murder was rusty
and therefore impossible to unsheath.
How did you know that
he was beaten to death?
T-That's because I saw
the body at crime scene.
Isn't it obvious?
Just before you arrived,
the body was fully covered up.
There was no way
you could have seen it up close.
W-Well, somehow I did.
Judging from the blood stains and stuff,
I concluded that he was beaten, okay?
Whatever it is,
I have nothing to do with the murder!
Seriously, how rude.
Now, let's see how far he can go.
All that's left...
...is the tournament venue.
Well,
judging from the interrogation just now,
it looks like this case will be a handful.
Gosh, this place is just huge.
And what's that structure
in the middle of the cliff?
That's Satsuki Hall.
Satsuki?
Yes.
President Achiha had it built
in honour of his wife,
hence the name.
I see.
This cliff can be accessed only once a year.
Moreover, the only ones allowed in the hall
are the karuta cards reader,
President Achiha and the two finalists.
The system is such that the match
will be broadcast live across the river
to a spectator's area
via cameras and microphone
within the competition venue.
It's elaborate, to say the least.
In the competition venue,
the air conditioning system
keeps the temperature
and humidity at a relative constant,
and the building itself is using
the latest sound proofing technologies
that completely blocks out
all external sounds.
Indeed a venue created solely for karuta,
a pinnacle of competition venues...
I'm hungry
Let's go for a buffet
I want cake
I'll go for some sightseeing then.
Yeah. Have fun!
Okay.
Ran
Let's go play
Ah, see you later then!
Yeah.
Take care
Sorry for the wait-
The souvenirs are going to get sold out soon
Let's resume practice
Wait a moment.
If you don't have some sleep,
you're not going to last
till the actual competition.
I'm fine!!
D-Don't tell me, Kazuha!
You are training with the former queen,
Shizuka san?
That's right.
Amazing! With this, maybe... maybe!
Then, let's return to the room
and resume practice,
If you really want to practice this much...
how about I be your opponent?
I don't think this girl will be able to last
till the finals, either way.
What did you say?!
Kazuha, rest.
Shizuka san...
I'll be your opponent.
You dissatisfied with me as your opponent?
Why would the former Queen,
Ikenami Shizuka san,
for such a girl...
With this, let's have a game
If you say so...
Please
Where's Achiha san and Sekine san?
It seems that after this,
they will be going to the competition
venue Achiha Association Hall
to have a rehearsal for tomorrow.
They will be travelling
with the escort of the police,
so there shouldn't be any worries there
but the problem's, as expected,
after they enter the Achiha Association Hall.
What about Ms. Momiji?
Don't worry.
That person lives in Kyoto too,
so everyone's travelling together.
Sorry, it's a call.
Regarding that man
in the photo you entrusted me with....
I've found out his identity.
What?! Really?
Yeah. The content may be rather shocking...
I've mailed you the details,
so do check it out later.
Thank you!!
And...
how is it going with the karuta cards?
I've just transferred it
to the analysing software.
As expected of the Professor.
We should have the answer
in about an hour or so.
Great. Inform me as soon as possible
when the analysing is complete on your side!
Seriously...
Nagoro Shikao...!!
I have had fun for the first time
in a long while.
Thank you.
Shall we return, Iori?
Yes.
Even so, you sure have guts...
Getting shocked by this level
and entering the competition regardless...
Remember this well. My name is Momiji!
Unlike you, a mere leaf, I'm different!
Huh?! Leaf?!
That's enough!
Even if my opponent is an amateur like you,
I will not hold back.
Afterall, I've let my guard down
beside another amateur in the past
and experienced humiliating defeat.
I don't want to experience
such regret ever again!
Which if why if I'm going to do it,
I'll do it with full force at my best!
T-That's exactly what I expect!
Well, let's put this karuta business aside.
Are you sure it's fine for you to be here?
The president would be worried, wouldn't he?
Thank you for the concern.
That's right but I will be fine.
Afterall, the famous detective of the West,
Hattori Heiji, is with me...
By that, what do you mean?
Oh, haven't you heard of anything?
Heiji kun is my bodyguard.
Yesterday too, without a wink of sleep,
he stood by the entrance of my house,
guarding me......
Well, I'll be off soon.
I'm looking forward
to the tournament tomorrow.
Oh dear,
it seems that there's more to Heiji
than it meets the eye, too...
Wait a minute, Kazuha...
Are you okay?
Heiji!!
I don't know what kind of relationship
you have with that girl
but I'll give you a thorough beating
through the karuta tournament!
Just you wait, Heiji!!
Yes! Nicely put!
What's up, Hattori?
No, I'm not really sure but just now,
I had the chills.
Caught a cold, maybe?
The cold? It's not anything as cute as that...
Something more dreadful, perhaps...
Hey! It's here!
President Achiha...
Ooka Momiji...
And also Sekine...
Seems like everyone's here.
Urgh, don't tell me?!
Sekine's car is...
So... how is Sekine's condition?
There was a call from the hospital.
It seems like his consciousness
is not returning.
Whether he'll survive is a 50-50 battle...
Was Ooka kun,
who was caught in the explosion, fine?
It seems that she did not suffer
from any injuries, but Just in case,
we had her go through an examination
at the hospital with Iori san,
who was driving.
As it has boiled down to this,
let's hear what you have to say
about the situation...
Achiha san!
The explosion at Nichiuri Televison...
that too,
was aimed at the Satsuki Association
which is what we think...
Hey, old man...
This... Nagoro Shikao san, who's that?
Little boy!!
Where did you get that photo from?!
From this wavering...
it seems that you have an idea?
If you know him,
mind telling us everything from the start?
Achiha san!
In Kyoto, there's a karuta association known
as the Nagoro Association...
Made up of a small number of elitists,
in an association with under 20 members,
they conducted tough trainings every month.
Nagoro Shikao san was its leader.
He had superb skills,
and it was said that
he was close to obtaining the rights
to challenge the current Master, yet...
His obsession with winning was so strong,
honestly, even just watching
from the sidelines
it is difficult to say that
he played beautiful karuta.
Hey! Darn it!
I was faster just now!
Give me that card!
How was that a foul?
Where are you looking at?
And Nagoro, 5 years ago,
challenged the then-president,
Satsuki to a game
with the condition that
the loser disband his association.
What's with that?
He's out to destroy the association.
But from Satsuki san's point of view,
there was no need
to accept the challenge, is there?
In order to prevent Satsuki
from rejecting his challenge,
Nagoro kun leaked the information
to the media beforehand.
Satsuki Association,
fearing the Nagoro Association,
avoided the challenge.
I see.
So they were forced into a situation
where they couldn't do anything
but to accept it.
So what happened to the match?
The match did not take place.
Nagoro did not appear
at the designated time.
In the end it was taken as a forfeit,
and Satsuki became the winner.
Despite pulling the media in
and creating much commotion,
he ran away on the day of the match itself
and disgraced the karuta community.
He then disappeared
from the stage of karuta.
So what happened to
Nagoro and the Nagoro Association?
Nagoro Association was dissolved
due to the lack of a president,
and Nagoro himself
remains missing till today.
Don't tell me?!
The case this time stems
from Nagoro Association's revenge
against the Satsuki Association...
I don't know...
Only, at that time,
the one who pushed the dissolvement
of the Nagoro Association the most was
Yajima kun, who was murdered.
What?! Really?
For us, the Satsuki Assocation,
we seeked to avoid conflicts,
carrying on smoothly but...
even that was unfufilled...
So, what happened to the members
of the dissolved Nagoro Association?
Of course,
we made it such that if they wanted to,
they could have joined
the Satsuki Association.
Eventually, two joined, though...
No way those two were...
Ah... It's Ooka kun and Sekine kun.
Two people who were caught
in the explosion just now?
Yes. Ooka kun, especially,
inherited lots of techniques
through Nagoro kun,
polishing her skills...
A few of her best cards
were exactly that of Nagoro's.
In fact, the six cards
which paint pictures of autumn leaves,
both of them never did let escape.
She is indeed someone
who can be said to be Nagoro's best disciple.
Why did Nagoro's strongest cards
included autumn leaves?
I heard it's due to his name being Shikao.
Deer meat, huh...
That's right,
we call deer meat "momiji" too, don't we?
The disciple he doted
on joining the Satsuki Association
and doing very well there
probably displeased him quite a bit
That may be right
but what's the point
of sending an explosion notice all the way
at this point of time?
We don't know the reason
why he kept silent for 5 years, too.
Perhaps that mail containing
the explosion notice
was to draw attention to his own return?
Which means that,
for this string of incidents,
we should investigate along the lines
of the revenge of Nagoro Shikao
against the Satsuki Association...
Pardon me.
What? Yes, yes.
It'd be easier to establish a common
investigation unit
with the Kyoto Prefectural Police, it seems.
What did you say?!
Chief!
After investigating Sekine san's phone,
it seems that a strange mail was received
just moments before the explosion!
Strange mail?!
The sender is unknown,
only an attachment file with a karuta card.
What does the karuta card say?!
"This time around, couldn't even bring
the sacred streamers, Offering Hill."
"But if this brocade of leaves,
is to the gods' liking."
That's Nagoro's forte card!!
What's the matter, Hei chan?
There's something
I have to confirm right away!
Momiji is in danger!!
Lori san?
That voice, Hattori sama I suppose?
Yeah. Quick,
check if Momiji's phone had received an email
from an unknown sender!
An email?
What's the matter, Iori?
Hattori sama is on the line.
From Heiji kun!?
Let me speak to him, Iori!!
Momiji? Check your email right away
Email... Why all of a sudden...
That aside,
I'm so happy to receive a call from you,
Heiji kun!!
Oh!? What's with this email...
There's only an attachment file...
Is it a picture of a karuta card?!
Wow! How did you know that?
Which poem is it! Read it out for me!!
Um, okay...
"It's the autumn leaves
of the hills of Mimuro,"
"where the tempests blow..."
Momiji!! Hey listen!!
Do not stay alone tonight!!
Don't go back home either!!
Come over to
Osaka Prefectural Police immediately!
Got it?!
I cannot listen to that
even if it is a request coming from you,
Heiji kun.
In order to prepare
for tomorrow's Satsuki Cup, I cannot.
This isn't the time to be saying that!
There's a chance that
you are being targeted!!
I'll be fine.
Because Heiji kun will be there for me.
You will keep me safe, won't you?
Because I haven't forgotten that promise...
Promise?!
See you
That idiot, she hung up...
It seems that she received the karuta email
as well huh...
Otaki!!
Strengthen Ooka Momiji's
police escort immediately
Yes sir!!
Which means Yajima san is the only one
who was murdered without prior warning...
There was message about a karuta card
at Yajima san's murder scene as well,
wasn't there?
So that means... the real culprit Nagoro,
after murdering Yajima san...
left behind his own forte card
before leaving the scene,
but Sekine came after
and disguised his work even further!
I see...
so through the message that
was left behind at the crime scene,
Sekine confirmed that
the murderer was Nagoro,
and in order to conceal
his former master's crime,
he ransacked the house to make
it look like it was robbed...
So you're saying that
Sekine kun got to the crime scene
before the police?
Yeah. That possibility is quite high...
Actually,
I got someone to analyze the crime scene
From the way the blood
got onto the karuta cards...
Alright!!
we should be able to figure out
how they were lined up during the murder...
Look at the Television
On the right hand side,
the cards that were stained
with Yajima san's blood
as they were left on the floor...
then... the clean cards
on the left hand side and,
the cards that became covered in blood
as they were mixed together afterwards...
And then, judging from the slight
distortion in the way
the blood was transferred,
the card that
Yajima san was made to hold is...
Number 32!!
Harumichi no Tsuraki...
"A wattle dam, laid seemingly by the wind,
across the mountain stream."
"Autumn leaves trapped in the current,
unable to work themselves free."
Just as I thought,
Nagoro's forte card was there
at Yajima san's place.
Look at this.
These are the cards that have been used
in the crimes at this point.
From the top left
there's Nichiuri Television,
Yajima san,
Sekine san,
followed by Momiji san
which was just identified earlier...
What these cards have in common is the
inclusion of the words
"momiji" (autumn leaves)...
I thought so,
these are all Nagoro's forte cards...
Yea
I guess this means that
there's no mistake in looking
at Nagoro Shikao as the true culprit.
I suspected as much but......
to think that
it really is Nagoro kun's doing...
What's worrying is that,
so far the cards all have portrayals
of scenes with autumn leaves,
and in total
there are six of such cards in karuta.
What are you getting at?
It means that there are still
two more cards left.
If he is trying to appeal his own crimes
by using karuta cards,
then he wouldn't leave things unfinished
by leaving out two cards now, would he?
Don't tell me,
there are others besides Ooka kun
The question is who are the targets
for the remaining 2 cards...
If we don't identify them quickly...
it will be difficult
to prevent Nagoro's crime...
As expected. If it's you guys,
it is likely that you'd be able
to stop Nagoro kun before the police can.
Yeah. But for that, we need more information.
Hey, what happened
between you and Nagoro san 5 years ago?
Well, that's...
There was something right?
I'm not letting you deny
that nothing's happened!!
You're right...
I couldn't say anything before,
but if it's you guys I guess it's fine...
Come over to my hotel room after this.
I'll talk in detail about
what happened that day.
Everyone, wait a moment okay.
I'm going to pass this to Momiji san.
- Okay!
- We'll be waiting!
Roger!
My lady.
There was a call from the police earlier.
It is regarding additional police protection
around the house.
Okay. Go ahead.
Excuse me...
You must be Momiji san, right?
My name is Mouri, I contacted you earlier.
Oh... it was you.
Thank you very much
for coming all the way here to return it.
Not at all. Here.
This belongs to you, right?
Oh my!! Thank you!
This is sort of like
a good luck charm of mine.
I was wondering how tomorrow's match
will go without this,
but now I'm sure I'll be alright somehow.
Perhaps to you
it would be like sending salt to the enemy,
wouldn't it?
Not at all.
That girl...
I hoped she practiced until her fingers hurt
What pretty nails.
Oh, these are for protecting my fingers.
One's fingers are one's life in karuta,
that's why I always have it
on outside of practice.
I see.
Oh... and...
I wanted to know who to contact
so I ended up looking inside...
And then... in the picture...
You mean this picture?
This person here in the picture is...
It's Heiji kun.
I thought so...
This was from a karuta competition
when we were kids,
when I lost to Heiji kun...
Heiji kun said to me as I was crying
after I had lost...
Don't cry...
The next time we meet,
I'll take you as my wife so just you wait!!
R Really?
Yeah...
It's a promise...
So he really proposed?!
And that's why,
Heiji kun is my future husband.
But, considering that
you were still kids at the time...
It doesn't matter
if you're a child or an adult!!
Once a man says something,
he shouldn't turn on it that easily.
Am I wrong?
To be able to read the thoughts
of the girl you love is really something
I guess so...
Because the current is swift,
even though the rapids,
blocked by a boulder are divided,
like them, in the end,
we will surely meet, I know.
Though we are apart,
as long as our hearts are connected...
Despite having believed in that I...
Please tell this to Happa chan...
H Happa chan?
I won't let anyone have the cards
that I am targeting.
I was taught as such by my teacher.
Momiji san...
Ran!!
What are you spacing out for?
You've been a little off
ever since you can back
from sightseeing in Osaka.
Sorry...
That aside, how's everything going?
Well...
I was given some homework by Shizuka san
to pick out my forte cards
in order to win but...
I can't seem to settle
on one card over another...
Is that troubling you so much?
Hyakunen Isshu are love poems, aren't they?
Instead of thinking about winning,
I think that if you stay true
to your own feelings
you will be able
to choose pretty quickly...
Love huh...
If it were me... I think I'd go with this...
As I was wondering,
whether or not I had seen it by chance.
Murasaki Shikibu
It's a poem about finally
being able to meet a friend,
but who is gone in a fleeting moment...
Yes. He goes off somewhere the moment
I thought I'd finally get to see him...
Even though there is so much
I want to talk about...
I see... In that case
I shall go with...
"Even though I hide it, it shows
all over my face, such is my longing."
"So that people ask me
“What are you thinking about?”"
A love poem about being unable
to completely conceal one's feelings,
this might be perfect for you...
Though,
it'll also be obvious to Momiji san as well.
Anyway, I wonder how she can be
so full of confidence.
As though she's already engaged to Heiji.
Don't you think so as well?
Y Yeah...
I can't tell her that
Hattori kun proposed to Momiji san
when they were kids...
What?
Nagoro came to challenge Satsuki san
the day before the match!?
Is that really true?
Yeah. It happened while I was away...
The article in that scrapbook,
Even though it was recorded that
Nagoro kun ran away from the match
against Satsuki because he was afraid...
the truth is that
he actually came by the day before.
But why the day before?
I don't know...
You wouldn't know why
unless you asked Nagoro himself,
but perhaps his intention was
to use Satsuki Association's karuta cards
to win,
at least that was what Satsuki had said...
Well did he use them?
But Satsuki Association's karuta cards
are normally kept in the museum, aren't they?
There wasn't any case of theft at the time.
They were indeed in our custody.
But without the reader
the match couldn't have happened, could it?
There're plenty of cassette tapes
on the shelf right?
A long time ago people used those
to practice karuta.
And so, how'd the match go?
The result was a complete victory
for Satsuki.
Apparently Nagoro couldn't even
move his hands or feet...
I returned home
just as he dashed out
of the doorstep pale faced,
I remember him leaving
as though he was running away.
That was the last I ever saw of him.
Why didn't you tell this to the police?
I was afraid that it would leak to the media
and Association members if I had done so.
Regardless of the significance
of the karuta that was used,
if it were known that
they had been used for some personal contest,
there would have been a revolt
amongst the Association members.
Well, I guess that excuse isn't
completely unrelatable but...
It wasn't that I didn't trust the police...
- It looks as if Nagoro kun had the upper hand...
- There's something out of place about this picture...
- You guys are the only ones I can count on.
- Achiha san's car is really something...
- In order to prevent any more casualties...
please stop Nagoro's crimes
as soon as possible.
Yeah, leave it to us!!
Ran chan, two isn't enough.
Can you put in another two for me?
My brain needs some sugar.
O Okay. Were you... able to hear that?
...This girl...
This is really bad...
I still can't use the kakoi te
and watari te well enough,
and I can't read the flow
of the game as well!
At this rate...
Heiji...
Heiji will be taken away by that her.
What's wrong Kazuha?
Making a scary face like that...
H Heiji!!
Did you have a fight with someone?
Oh shut up, you idiot!!
You're that person's bodyguard right?
Go back to her then!
Hey...
I just thought
I'd take a break from that old lady
and have a game with you...
You know,
I've never lost a game of karuta to you...
That was back in elementary school!
You wouldn't stand a chance against me now!
Hey Hattori kun.
Don't you remember anything
from that karuta competition you were in
back in elementary school?
Like say, a girl whom you beat at
during that competition...
Oh yeah! That's it! Kazuha!
It was back during that karuta competition!
The one which you joined on the spur
of the moment and won?
Yeah. At that time, there was a girl who lost
and was crying really badly right?
That was Ooka Momiji!
I see! That girl...!
And so... Hattori kun, don't you remember?
About?
Say, a promise you made
with Momiji san at the time...
I think I said something
like try harder next time...
Anyway Heiji, you better hurry back!
You have to keep her safe right?
Oh, the police are on that...
Oh just go already!
If she gets hurt before the competition...
we wouldn't be able to have our match...
I see...
In that case I'll be on my way then...
Mom!
I'll leave the rest to you!
"Even though I hide it,
it shows all over my face."
"Such is my longing,
so that people ask me..."
Nagoro sensei...
Please lend me your strength
this year as well...
Please watch over me.
Satsuki.
(Kyoto)
(Achiha Kaikan)
Naniwa Bay, now the flower blooms,
But for winter.
Here comes spring, now the flower blooms.
Here comes spring,
now the flower blooms
Kazuha oneesan She got it!!
She's really in a different league
from the others.
You could tell that right away.
Yea.
- That's... an Aikido uniform right?
- I wish Conan were here to see this...
It can't be helped.
It seems he had to go somewhere
with Heiji oniisan.
Ah! That's right.
I'll send Conan kun
that picture of Genta kun
we took over
at the souvenir shop a while ago
Yes, I knew that.
Looks like it has started...
Yeah.
Well if the security is this perfect,
I figure even Nagoro
wouldn't be able to get in
Yeah. Including Nagoro...
anyone who did not register
as a staff beforehand
- will not be allowed in.
- This way.
Background checks had been flawless as well.
Yeah. We're not going
to let Nagoro do as he pleases.
What's the matter Hattori?
Nah, it's nothing.
Who's this?
Oh, it's just Mitsuhiko...
Oh man, what is that Genta doing...
grabbing on to so much senmaizuke at once...
I see...
(MAP)
(Firing Alarm System)
As expected!
The first one to finish is Momiji!
Where is Kazuha?
I think she hasn't showed up yet.
Isn't that her?
Yes, it's Kazuha!
Yes!!
Way to go! Kazuha chan!
She's gotten through the first round,
what a good start...
Sekine san? Sekine san!!
Thank you very much.
Who would've thought that
she'd make it to the finals...
Yes. What a surprise
to find someone with such level of skill...
You think she can win?
Of course!!
Way to go, Kazuha!
At this rate you're gonna win!!
I wonder if Kazuha chan realizes that...
If Momiji san wins,
she's going to confess to Heiji kun.
She's trying hard...
Kazuha...
Looks like she's finally
going up against Momiji san.
Yeah...
What?!
Sekine san regained consciousness?
Ah, I see... that's the way it is huh...
Understood.
I'll leave things here
to Kyoto Prefectural Police
and head over right away.
Has Sekine san woken up?
Yeah.
Also it seems that Hei chan's deductions
were on the mark.
But why was Sekine san over
at Yajima san's place?
It seems that lately,
Yajima san has been looking up on Nagoro...
Realizing that Sekine san thought that
keeping watch on Yajima san
would lead him to his former master...
But later, having sensed something was amiss
he found Yajima's body...
I'm afraid so...
I'm heading back to Osaka
to question Sekine san directly
Understood. Please leave things here to us.
Sure.
Ah! Hold on, I'm going with...
This ends here...
Though, why is there dynamite here?
There wasn't any need to set up...
What?! No?!
- Hey, what is that smoke?
- A fire?
No, a fire would've
triggered the fire alarm system...
I couldn't have been an explosive,
could it...
Hey hey this isn't funny.
Something's causing a commotion.
Hey! Is there something
in the forest to the west?!
O Over there there's...
only an old storage pen.
The security cameras,
did they pick up anything?
That location is outside the facility
so there aren't any cameras.
What?!
Oi! Don't tell me that smoke is...
Ah, let's go!!
It's Satsuki Hall, that's where we're headed.
What is this smell?
Recently the elevator has been
under maintenance
so the smell is probably coming
from the lubricating oil that was used...
Does it bother you?
Oh no, no at all.
I must be a little on edge.
This is so exciting, how do you feel?
I didn't think
I'd really make it all the way here
so I'm excited
but it's a little different for you,
isn't it?
Not at all, I feel as though my heart
might spring out of my mouth.
I wonder
how my dear Heiji kun's reaction will be like
when I finally confess to him...
I won't lose.
I cannot lose, no matter what...
You cannot get any closer!
What in the world happened here?
Inspector!!
Was it really blown up?
Yes. There is one victim.
The body was badly disfigured...
It's not possible
to identify the victim right away.
I see...
The question is when, and how
Looks like bomb was set up here...
And, based on the circumstance
it is also possible that
the victim was carrying the bomb...
What?!
Could it be that
Nagoro had the wrong target?
Retrieve the body immediately
and start an autopsy.
Yes sir.
Inspector Ootaki, what happened?
What's the matter, Kudo?
Hattori, look at that.
What is this?
A ring?
Yeah, possibly the victim's...
Both of you, what's wrong?
Look at this ring.
It could be a lost article.
What a burly ring...
Yeah, judging from the size it may not...
A huge ring... Wait a second...
Kaieda Tougo!!
Kaieda? Isn't that
Achiha san's secretary (bodyguard)?
Yeah. There's no mistake.
This ring was worn by Kaieda on his thumb.
That means...
that Kaieda guy is the real culprit!!
No...
If we didn't find this ring,
that body over there might've been
mistakenly identified as Nagoro's...
Which means...
This explosion was set up
as a ploy to stage Nagoro's death...
Hold on.
Assuming that Nagoro is dead at this point,
doesn't that means that
the two remaining karuta cards
have already been sent?
Not two.
I got a call from Ootaki earlier,
we got President Achiha's secretary
to verify his email
and apparently he received
a karuta email this morning.
That means there's only one card left...
- One card remaining...
- No way!? All that's left are finals before everything's over.
- and the finals...
- Is something about to happen again?
I see!!
Since Achiha san's received the email,
that means there is one target left.
And the killer would made his move
after the card has been decided
at the finals.
Don't tell me?!
Inspector!!
Check Toyama Kazuha's phone right away!!
G Got it...
But why is this happening?
Why is the last card being left out?
That's because,
the person to receive it
wasn't decided until the finals!
Don't tell me,
the target is at the finals venue...
Satsuki Hall,
where the three of them are gathered!
Apologies to the both of you
Please do your best
and show us a splendid competition.
Let's have a good match.
Naniwa Bay
Ready go!
All the best!!
Kazuha chan, show us your true strength.
How was it?
Was there a karuta email?
Yes. About 15 minutes ago,
with Nagoro's forte card.
So it came after all huh.
- We have to stop the finals immediately!!
- Darn it!!
You hear?!
This way Kudo!!
Hey, where to?
It'll be faster on a bike!!
What!? Stop the finals?
Yes sir, understood.
Contact the venue immediately.
What?
A tremor...
There's no need to worry,
continue with the match.
What happened?
Is it broken?
- It was getting to the good part...
- Power Outage?
no, the visuals are still on
Not good!! It's already begun!!
Ah. Hold on tight!!
How are you gonna get to Satsuki Hall!
Trust me!! I have a plan!!
Hey, don't tell me?!
Even when the gods,
I see...
Happa chan didn't even move.
Is she giving up on her forte card...
Why is it burning so intensely?
There must be some kind of propellant.
Hasn't the fire department arrived?
Due to the narrow roads within the park
the fire trucks aren't able to get in...
And the firefighting equipments
are down as well huh
Looks like there's really nothing
that can be done huh...
Hattori! Do you still think that
Nagoro san is behind all of this?
No. There can only be one person
who could've set up Kaieda
as a registered staff
and handed him the bomb.
President Achiha Kensuke!
He wanted to end his own life
while bringing along the other two with him
I won't let such a thing happen!
There, hardest spot to reach...
Momiji san knows that as well.
That is where my forte card is...
You want to take this card right?
If so won't hand it over.
As long as I protect
this victory will be mine.
I'll take it. For sure I will.
I have to no matter what...
Argh it's so loud!
Get all these distracting noise
out of my head!
What's wrong Kazuha?
Making a scary face like that...
Did you have fight with someone?
Please excuse me.
Go ahead.
That's right,
I shouldn't be starting a fight... I can't!
The sound of the air conditioner,
the sound of the kimono,
the sound of touching the cards,
all these subtle noise and my heartbeat...
everything is harmony. Come within me...
Thank you.
I will catch the real sound!
If I hear you pine for me,
I shall return to you.
Even though I hide it,
The series of crimes
which have been staged to look like revenge
against the Satsuki Association
by Nagoro san,
was all part of the scenario planned
by Achiha san.
Five years ago, Nagoro,
who was going up
against Satsuki san in the competition,
somehow decided to show up the night
before to have a prelude match.
According to Achiha san,
the result was a victory for Satsuki,
except...
There is something inconsistent
on that point.
Because of the picture
in the article we saw at the hotel?!
Yeah. In Achiha san's introductory articles,
it said that
the car had always been spotless on the day
before Satsuki san's competition,
but that wasn't the case in that picture.
If the car hadn't been cleaned the day
before such an important competition,
that would mean he knew that
Nagoro wasn't going to show up.
It seems like I'm much faster than you.
No, I'm the one that was faster.
Whoever was faster,
I think you'd know that best yourself.
I never thought that the match
would last till the tiebreaker round...
That prelude match five years ago...
Assuming that Satsuki san had lost,
wouldn't that become a motive for the crime?
Yeah. In order to protect the honor
of the Satsuki Association,
Nagoro had to be silenced.
And, looking at the karuta images
left behind in the evidence...
Yajima san had found out
about Achiha san's crime!
But, what kind of evidence
would that karuta make...
If Nagoro san's bloodstained karuta
had been carelessly picked up...
I see! The fingerprints!!
I didn't realize it myself
until I saw a certain picture but,
I believe that Achiha san's fingerprints
would be on that karuta.
That's why Yajima proposed
the idea of the special feature
on Satsuki Association
to the television station
He was trying to preserve the image
of Satsuki Association's karuta as evidence!
Yeah.
That's why the bombing
at Nichiuri Television
and Yajima san's murder
were carried out at the same time.
So that was the case... but why?!
What did the Achiha Association
and even the finals have to be involved?
If Nagoro san's body were
to be found in Satsuki Hall,
the venue where the finals are being held...
Indeed...
that would be
the most suitable hiding place...
So all this had been planned out
right from the start huh...
Even if the plan to frame Nagoro san
as the culprit had been
carried out perfectly,
if Nagoro's body being found later...
it would all be... for nothing huh
I see it!!
Having seen the heartless morning moon.
With people, well...
A void card...
That's bad! The flames have spread
all the way over there...
We gotta get off quick!
But, what now...?!
Also, if we don't put that out...
There isn't time to hesitate!
Just think of a way to put out the fire!
Hey don't tell me...
No way!?
Let's go! Kudo!
Go!
What?!
Yeah, all the way!
Hurry! Please make it!
-What?! A fire...!?
Don't come over! Get inside!
- Heiji!
- Why are you here?
Oi! The rapids are changing direction!
It's a miracle!
-The flames are being extinguished!
W What is happening?
Whew, looks like we made it somehow...
As expected, Kudo...
Heiji kun, what is happening?
It's dangerous here,
didn't I tell you to go inside?
Conan kun too?
What in the world happened?
Whats with the both of you?
Well, I suppose it'll be faster
if you ask Achiha san.
What is the meaning of this?
The two of you, get behind me.
Eh?! Why is there a need to step back?
Hey, Achiha san. This karuta...
It's going to look bad on you
if we investigate it, wouldn't it?
Heiji,
what are the two of you saying
since a moment ago?
The answer to the recent string of crimes
lies with that old man.
The origin of the crimes...
Started about a year ago,
when Momiji won at this very location...
At that time,
the stack of cards that Momiji collected
during the match was extremely similar
to that of Nagoro's...
Indeed, my forte cards are
the same Nagoro sensei's
because I was taught
my attacking style of karuta by him... but...
Unless there's really such a coincidence...
you can't possibly...
But such a coincidence really happened..
has to do with the black marks on the side
this Satsuki Association's karuta.
The deceased Yajima san
had found out the truth behind the stain that
showed up all of a sudden five years ago...
What in the world are those black marks?
The fingerprint of the person
who held this karuta card
with his hand stained
with Nagoro san's blood.
A trace of blood
belonging to Nagoro sensei...
Nagoro san, who has been missing
since five years ago,
was actually murdered at the time.
N No way...
And the owner of that fingerprint is...
Nagoro san's killer.
I concede. I shall confess everything...
In exchange...
Satsuki Association's karuta...
Please don't turn it in as evidence...
To the Satsuki Association that karuta is...
So that's why...
There was something
I couldn't understand before but...
after seeing you like this now I get it.
The fingerprint on this karuta...
isn't yours, am I right?
No, it's mine! There's no mistake about it!
Indeed!
Kaieda and yourself were behind
the recent string of crimes but...
the Nagoro san's murder five years ago...
wasn't because of you!
It's Satsuki san, isn't it?
I understood everything
after I witnessed that scene...
Nagoro issued a challenge...
and Satsuki had lost...
They used the cassette
I kept of myself as the reader...
You understand what that means right?
Satsuki had used that tape
for practice countless of time.
Of course, aside from the reading patterns,
Satsuki would have to some extent memorized
the order of the cards being read out...
Regardless of the overwhelming advantage
that she had,
Satsuki lost...
Nagoro's ability was
beyond our wildest imagination...
I wonder how much fear Satsuki
must have felt...
She was sure to face a crushing defeat
in the match the following day...
That fear drove her to resort to crime...
Ever since then,
Satsuki began
to lose all emotion as a person...
And grew further away
from Satsuki Association's administration.
Two years later she died of an illness.
This is the truth. Please understand.
Stop!
Achiha! Don't!
It's all Nagoro's fault.
If that man didn't humiliate Satsuki...
Such a thing wouldn't have...
It's because he didn't want
to humiliate her!
That's why Nagoro sensei went
over a day before, right??
There was something that
I had asked Nagoro sensei previously
"Why do you despise
the Satsuki Association so much?"
Despise...? I see,
so that's how it looks like...
If I didn't
then I wouldn't be able to challenge her...
All I want is to win and be praised by her...
by my first love...
F-first love...?
That's right.
Nagoro sensei admired Satsuki
and started karuta...
However, because of a condition in his eyes
he was told by his doctor that
he could only continue karuta
for no more than a year...
I think that's
why he played karuta so aggressively...
because he didn't have much time left...
So... he challenged Satsuki the day before
in order to avoid defeating her
in front of everybody...
And also because he hoped
to request upon Satsuki Association
to take in his students including myself
when he could no longer continue
to be our mentor...
Without knowing that, Satsuki san...
ended up killing Nagoro san...
N No way...
W What have I done...
What now!
Kazuha!
Kazuha!!
Are you alright?
Yea.
But I can't stand up right...
Everyone quick, into the elevator!
Momiji! Hurry! Go!
Quick, get up and go!
I'm fine, just leave me and go...
Idiot!!
I can't possibly let you die now!!
Momiji san!
Hurry, get on!
Kazuha!!
Climb up over here!
O Okay...
Grab on!
Darn it... just a little more...
Gotcha!
W What?!
Please...
Don't fall yet!!
Darn it!
What?!
As if I'll let you!
Are you alright? We're going now!
That was close...
Hattori!
This is bad, it's going to collapse!
We have to move away!
Eh?! Wait... How come?
Why is it going away?
Heiji
Kazuha, get on!
-This girl here is fine.
Someone still in there.
Please. Make it out somehow!
Heiji! Over there!
Ok
What's the matter Heiji?
Hold on tight
Don't tell me,
you're planning to jump all the way
to the other side of the wall?
Good guess... Exactly...
No... No way!
What are you thinking! It's too far away!
Say, Heiji
Isn't it better to drop into the pond?
That's impossible!
If we fall from this height
the water surface would be
as hard as concrete
Hang on really tight!!
If you let go of that hand...
I won't forgive you
Got it!!
As if I'd die
in such a place!!
That's?!
Hattori?!
There's something that I...
have yet to say to Kazuha!!
That bike...
Reach!
Heiji...
Kazuha!
Are you okay? Kazuha...
Y... Yea...
...I think I've had enough of escaping acts...
...Those two...
For a moment I was worried
how it'd turn out...
By the way Heiji
What was that thing that you had to tell me?
What do you mean?
Didn't you say that you couldn't die
before you told me something?
You must have misheard.
Definitely not!
I've honed my hearing
through karuta training.
Hey if you have a problem with me tell me!
Hey wait up!
What?!
Thanks for visiting me!
I'm the one who should be thanking you...
By the way,
what happened to the karuta club?
The school recognised the efforts
of the club put in
when we got into the finals,
so they decided not to shut down the club
Even though
I ended up losing at the last moment...
Kazuha chan... Eh?
Ran chan! Come here for a sec...
I wonder what's up with them?
Hey what... a secret talk huh...
Really?
Yeah really. It's all good,
because I was able
to win the "shinoburedo" card
I see! So you ended up
targeting that card after all!
No no, it's not just the poem.
Look, the name of the person
who recited that poem!
Taira no Kanemori!
The only person in the Hyakunin Isshu
whose name is written
with the same initial kanji as Heiji's!
I can't see it any other way
except as Heiji's card now...
I'll send an image of that card
to Heiji later~
This is my feelings towards him.
Sending "shinoburedo"
to confess one's feelings?
That's against the rule!
Momiji san!?
Did you hear that?
I have good ears, unlike you...
Well if it isn't Momiji!
What are you doing in a place like this?
As promised, I came to confess my feelings...
In the first place,
I was the one
who was confessed to by Heiji kun...
Huh? What does that mean?
This is... the photo as proof!
They joined little fingers...
He definitely made a promise there...
If you break it
you have to swallow a thousand needles...
H Hey wait!
What kinda promise was that anyway?
The next time we meet,
(Kondo autara, )
I'll take you as my wife so just you wait!
(yome ni toru sakai, mattokeya!)
This guy... getting his
embarrassing moment caught again...
Or perhaps...
are you trying to take it
as an old story which never happened?
Ahh! I remember now!
This was what I said at that time!
Don't cry...
We can have another match next time!
But the next time we meet...
(...kondo autara)
I'll brush up my skill and wait!
(moto TSUYOME NI TORU SAKAI, ude migaite MATTOKEYA)
Meaning...
"YOME NI"
(I take you..)
"TORU SAKAI"
(...as my wife?)
Hey my opponent was a lady
so I had to take care not to hurt her,
that's why I played really nice
Iori... we're going!
Yes my lady.
Look, I'll leave it at that
and give it a break for today but...
I'll never let anyone take away
a single card that I target...
I'll have you remember that...
Kazuha chan...
What...
She just wants to play karuta
with Kazuha again, doesn't she?
I'm sorry, were you asleep?
Sonoko, you're pretty familiar
with Hyakunin Isshu right?
Yea. I play karuta with my family on
during the new year.
I sent Shinichi an image
of the "meguriaite" card and,
I got the "sewohayami" poem as reply...
what was the meaning again?
It slipped my mind...
"Even though now
I am separated from my beloved,
someday surely let's meet again"
It's an extremely romantic poem
recited by Emperor Sutoku.
There you go~
Ah!! Hey Sonoko~!!
Hey come on, don't you forget that.