(MARINA BAY SANDS)
Here you go.
Thank you.
Did I make you wait?
This is a strange place to meet.
Can we talk in Japanese?
So that people around us won't understand.
(SHERILYN TAN (40) LAWYER)
If there are people around,
you can't do anything strange, right?
(LEON LOWE (43) BUSINESS CONSULTANT)
Those are quite some words there.
It's like I'm after you or something.
You're not?
I thought I've been keeping
a great friendship with you.
Stop the small talk.
Just tell me your answer to my suggestion.
Yes? Or no?
Before I answer that,
let me guess what you ordered.
Iced Tea? No, not that.
Champagne... No, wine.
Not red. White.
A well-chilled Meursault.
Here is your Meursault.
H-How did you know that?
I read your mind.
I don't want it!
Oh, hold on.
What?
My answer is "no."
Thank for the help
Hey? Are you okay?
What?
Please be calm
follow our instructions...
Hey, wait!
What are you doing?
Protecting the scene of the crime
Otherwise,
This will be trample over, right?
Sir!
The one I called?
He is already inside.
Thanks
Sorry for make you wait, Rishi!
Inspector Aidan
Thank you for calling me!
(MARK AIDAN (38))
The incident happened in shopping mall I heard
(SINGAPORE POLICE ASSISTANT INSPECTOR)
This case could be little tricky
That Leon Lowe
First to discover the body
Mr. Lowe!
You were his favourite student, right?
Could you ask him not to interfere too much?
I can't ask that...
I'll go say hello
Mr. Lowe!
Rishi, It has been a while
Yes!!
Let's talk in Japanese.
Okay.
I heard you work
as a civilian reserve police officer now?
Looks like you've moved up.
(RISHI RAMANATHAN (29))
It's thanks to you for being
(RESERVE POLICE OFFICER)
my instructor and teaching me about
criminal behavioral psychology.
The "Mister" isn't necessary.
I'm a civilian now.
In any case,
the perpetrator
had a bomb prepared, too, huh?
The car that got blown up
belonged to the victim, Sherilyn Tan.
She was a brilliant lawyer,
so I'm sure she had her share of grudges.
She could also have dealt with dangerous...
Is inspector there?
Excuse me, make way!
What's going on?
There is something on the elevator wall
What!?
What is this?
Hah!?
It's blood.
No.
Can't you reconsider?
When I say no, I mean no!
Please!
What's wrong, both of you?
He wants to use that drug again
to go back to his original form.
And you just had a rough time with it
during your school field trip.
I managed to get by at that time, too.
So it'll be fine.
Please give me that drug!
No way!
Where in the world are you headed to?
Singapore.
Professor, it's this.
That person is going to be
in this tournament!
The "400 matches, undefeated"!
Oh, you mean Makoto Kyogoku.
Sonoko started talking about
going to watch the match.
She asked Pops Kogoro and Ran
to go with her.
She invited me, too,
but I can't leave the country
looking like this.
That's true.
The passport is still
in Shinichi's name, too.
So I'm begging you, Haibara.
You're persistent!
Maybe you should give up this one time.
I really wanted to go.
Don't hang your head down so much!
I know, I'll take your mind off of things!
What, we’re doing this already?
It's an Asian quiz!
What is the most popular event
in Singapore?
One, singing the national anthem.
Two, celebrating lunar new year.
Three, hoisting the national flag.
Four, Marina Bay fireworks festival?
What's with the outfit?
The answer is simple.
It's hoisting the national flag,
because the center is a pole.
Oh! Correct!
I wouldn't expect any less from you.
All right, one more question.
That's enough.
All in all, it's a bit lonely here
without the kids.
Sheesh. That Haibara...
Ran! Uh, hey Ran.
What are you doing
all the way out... here...
Ran?
I've been waiting for you this whole time.
Wh-What is this place?
- It's really huge...
- Ran's voice!
Where is this place?
I'm locked up inside something.
Crap.
All right, with this...
The... Merlion?
Wha...
I'm in Singapore?!
DETECTIVE CONAN
THE FIST OF BLUE SAPPHIRE
I'm a high school detective,
Shinichi Kudo.
While at a theme park with
my childhood friend and classmate, Ran Mori,
I witnessed a shady business deal
between two men dressed in all black.
Being distracted by watching the deal,
I didn't notice one of their partners
sneaking up behind me.
That man force-fed me poison,
and when I woke up...
...my body had shrunk!
But if they found out
that Shinichi Kudo was still alive,
my life and the lives of those around me
would be in jeopardy.
With Professor Agasa's advice,
I decided to hide my identity,
and when Ran asked me my name,
I spontaneously said "Conan Edogawa."
In order to get information on those thugs,
I arranged to live with Ran,
whose dad is a private detective.
One of my biggest rivals is this guy.
Kid the Phantom Thief.
He's a mysterious thief
and a master of disguise as well.
He also knows who I really am somehow,
so I can't let my guard down.
Someday, I'll capture him
with my own hands.
And Kid has a rival, too,
named Makoto Kyogoku.
Despite being a high school student,
he's a karate expert who is undefeated
in over 400 matches.
For some reason, he's head over heels
for Sonoko Suzuki, Ran's classmate
and the daughter of the Suzuki Group.
What are you looking at?
Hurry up and do your usual thing!
Although I've become smaller,
my intelligence is the same!
A great detective
who leaves no case unsolved!
There is always only one truth!
My hands...
Professor's tools are gone, too.
That's right, Ran should be here, too!
Wait, Ran!
Hey, Shinichi! Over here, over here!
Sorry, sorry.
I made you wait a bit, didn't I?
Where have you been?
We've been looking for you, you know!
Pops said he was hot,
so I took him to rest in some shade.
I see. Thanks.
Sheesh, your dad's the same as always.
Hey, Ran! Can you go buy me some water?
You're so hopeless.
Hey, let's go together!
- Come on, hurry!
- Uh, s-sure!
Oh, jeez. It's looking good!
Damn that guy!
Man, that brings me back to life.
Huh? Dad, what are you
wearing around your neck?
I got my passport in here
so that it doesn't get lost or stolen.
It's great, isn't it?
Dad, you really don't have to do that.
Singapore is a safe place.
Yo. Looks like you're up.
So it really was you...
Anyways, how'd you get out of the suitcase?
With this.
If I stick the tip of this thing in,
you can pretty easily
open stuff from the inside.
I thought a ball-point pen
wouldn't be a problem,
but I can't let my guard down, huh?
That's my line, Kid the Phantom Thief!
Oh, here it is!
Anyways, what are you up to with all this?
You already know what this is about.
That.
That's Sonoko's...
At the end of the 19th century,
a legendary treasure aboard a pirate ship
is said to have sunk
near the shores of Singapore.
One of the largest
blue sapphires in the world...
Also known as the Fist of Blue Sapphire.
(WORLD WATCH)
It's the big jewel Mr. Zhonhan Chen
(SALVAGING TREASURE)
successfully salvaged
(FROM A PIRATE SHIP ~ SINGAPORE)
last year.
Zhonhan Chen is a big figure
in Singapore, isn't he?
Right. And this old-timer
is a huge fan of martial arts.
He embedded the jewel
into a champion belt
and decided he was going to hold
a karate tournament.
The legendary jewel will be
in the hands of the winner.
So, a rich man's pastime.
That's what this is.
I thought I'd take just the jewel
while hidden
in the hubbub of the tournament,
but I can't enter this country as Kid,
you know?
If you were after just the jewel,
you didn't need to bring me here as well.
I have slightly special circumstances
this time around.
I'll give you the details in due time.
You...
Huh, Shinichi?
- Oops, she's calling for me.
- Have you run off again?
Hold it, Kid!
If you do something to Ran,
you're going to pay for it!
S-Sorry, but I can't guarantee that.
Then I'll disclose your true identity
right here right now!
You probably shouldn't.
You were able to enter this country
thanks to this suitcase.
A special one that blocks the X-rays
at the carry-on luggage check.
Inside is an oxygen generator
that lasts at least 12 hours
and it's lined with the best cushioning
to prevent body aches,
even after being in it for a long time.
You know what this means,
don't you, great detective?
Without my help,
you can't leave this country
because you don't have a passport.
That means you can't return to Japan.
There you are, Shinichi!
You're so quick to run off somewhere...
I-It's that kid!
Why is he here?
Conan?
Oh, he's running away.
See? What a surprise, huh?
This kid is apparently one of the locals.
What? Really?
- In any case, he really looks like...
- You guys are way too gullible.
Little boy, what's your name?
Wait, do you understand Japanese?
Um...
This boy...
Arthur! My name is Arthur Hirai!
Arthur Hirai?
My mother is Japanese, so...
I'm Sonoko Suzuki.
I'm Ran Mori.
And that's my dad Kogoro Mori over there.
Nice to meet you.
Y-Yeah, nice to meet you.
Ran, I'm sorry,
but I'm going to get going now.
Oh, yeah.
So, where's your father and mother?
Um... they're in Japan right now.
Arthur, you're staying home all alone?
Yeah, but I'm fine. I'm used to it.
Is that so...
If that's the case,
you want to come with us?
I can?
Yeah, of course!
Oh, that's right.
I'm going to go check up on Dad, too!
S-Sure.
In any case, he's late.
He could at least text me.
I thought we were meeting up right here.
You're in the way, move!
Outta the way!
What you lookin' at, huh?
What's up with them?
The guy in the middle is Reijiro Nakatomi.
Nakatomi...
Oh, the president of Nakatomi Shipping.
(REIJIRO NAKATOMI (39))
He's known to be a go-getter,
(NAKATOMI MARITIME TRANSPORTATION PRESIDENT)
but there are no ends to his shady rumors.
Hey girl,
are you alone
all the way out here in Singapore?
You want to hang out with...
I don't have time for that right now.
Go away.
Can you afford to say stuff like that?
If I really felt like it,
(ARE YOU HERE YET?)
it's easy to drag you into a car.
(I'M WAITING IN FRONT OF THE MERLION)
Sonoko!
Shinichi?
Don't go out of your way.
Hey!
She's with me. Is there a problem?
Y-You're...
Makoto! At least read your texts!
I'm sorry.
I'm really not good with machines.
O-Ouch!
Y-You'll pay for this!
I won't let you go easy next time!
Makoto! I was so scared!
I'm so sorry I'm late.
Mister, you're awesome!
I can do that, too!
Hey, karate boy!
How brave.
Hey, come on!
Sonoko, are you all right?
Yeah, because Makoto protected me.
It's been a while, Mr. Kyogoku.
Same here.
And you are?
Nice to meet you.
I'm Shinichi Kudo.
I'm Makoto Kyogoku.
Makoto, is something the matter?
Oh, it just doesn't feel like
it's my first time meeting Mr. Kudo.
N-No, I'm sure its just your imagination!
Well, now that we've seen the Merlion,
let's head over to the hotel.
About that...
You can't enter the tournament anymore?
We came all the way out here
to see your matches!
I'm sorry.
I had entered today's tournament
thanks to an invitation
from a certain individual.
You mean a sponsor?
Yes.
A lawyer named Sherilyn Tan
offered to cover all the expenses
and asked me if I would like to enter.
However, that person suddenly passed away.
One of her associates told me today
to forget about this whole deal.
That can't be!
I heard the strongest contender in Singapore
would be entering this tournament, too.
He was someone that I wanted
to fight a match against just once.
That's it! I'll become that sponsor!
Leave it all to me!
Just what I'd expect from the daughter
of the Suzuki Group.
(UNCLE JIROKICHI CALL ENDED)
Everything is all straightened out!
Makoto, you've been reentered
to the tournament as an invite!
Is that true, Sonoko?
Yup!
I made it so that Makoto will be
staying in the same hotel as us.
It's a double-date!
You're right.
If everything's all settled,
let's head back to the hotel.
I want to hurry up and throw back some beer.
Mr. Mori?
Is that you, Mr. Kogoro Mori?
Yeah.
I'm Rishi, a reserve police officer.
It's an honor to meet you.
Y-Yeah, that's quite...
So... a reserve police officer?
Yes! I am allowed to be special counsel
as a specialist
in criminal behavioral psychology!
Oh, I see.
Actually...
I received information
that you had entered this country
so I've been waiting for you.
Waiting for me?
Yes.
Many tourists stop by this location.
But why me?
Actually, there's been an incident where
I'd like to request
Detective Mori's assistance.
Oh, no, no!
I'm in the middle of vacation right now!
Oh, wait. I think we're better off
heading out with him.
Why?
Even if he's just a reserve police officer,
if you get along with him,
he may be able to recommend
cheap yet delicious places to eat.
Even a casino...
you know...
Well, you may be right!
All right! Great Detective Kogoro Mori
will lend you his strength!
- It's an honor!
- Come on, now.
Detective Mori, you're a hero in Japan,
my father's native country,
and I'm also a huge fan!
Actually, a certain businessman
received this in the mail.
(Advance Notice) (A legendary treasure guarded by
lions.) (Brilliantly glimmering a clear, deep blue.)
(That blue sphere will be mine.) (I will be there to
hold it within my fists.) (-Kid the Phantom Thief)
Kid the Phantom Thief!
(LEON'S MANSION)
I received the report that
Suzuki Group become the sponsor for Kyogoku.
Can you beat him?
(HEZLI JAMALUDDIN (25)LEON'S SECURITY CHIEF)
There is no need for concern
No matter who
I will put him down with only one blow
Good to know
Come in
Excuse me
(RECHEL CHUONG (28) LEON'S SECRETARY)
Mr. Ramanathan has arrived
with someone
he like to introduce
He's early
Please bring him into the lounge
Understood
So, how about Kid?
Apology, We're still investigating
Along with Sherilyn Tan
There is issue handling information.
I have a hunch who was behind it
You take care with that
Oh, man! This is amazing!
Dad, please calm down!
Wait, this suit of armor... it's so cool!
Are you all right?
Y-Yeah...
Dad... Now, behave.
I'm really sorry about my dad.
Anyway, who is this guy named Leon Lowe?
Mr. Lowe was a prolific
criminal behavioral psychologist
and has apprehended many
dangerous criminals together
with the police.
I see, so he's like
the great detective of Singapore.
He parted ways with the police force
two years ago
and is now the president
of a very successful security firm.
I was taught criminal behavioral psychology
by Mr. Lowe as well.
I see.
So, this Leon guy got the advance notice?
No, I will explain in due order.
First, please take a look at this.
Kid the Phantom Thief is targeting a jewel
called the Fist of Blue Sapphire,
and it's owned by a businessman
named Mr. Zhonhan Chen.
Kid's advance notice arrived at his place.
Then, wouldn't it be better
to go see this Zhonhan guy?
Actually, the jewel is being stored
in the basement of this mansion.
The jewel is here?
Yes.
It was the owner's wish.
This safe has been independently developed
with a state-of-the-art system
and compared to bank safes...
State-of-the-art, huh?
Looks like even Kid is going to have
a hard time with this one!
What a thing to say.
What are you talking about?
Even the most state-of-the-art safes
are a piece of cake for Mr. Kid!
Hey, Sonoko...
You know what I'm talking about, Ran.
Mr. Kid's graceful techniques in theft!
Any woman from anywhere on the globe
will have her heart stolen...
Stop, Sonoko.
W-Well, that's everyone
except for me and Ran!
Right, Ran?
Y-Yeah, of course!
If things get bad,
you won't get out of this safely.
Hey, hey, hey.
What a wonderful courtyard!
It's not bad.
It's a pleasure to meet everyone.
My name is Leon Lowe.
Please allow my bodyguard
and chief of security
Hezli Jamaluddin to stay with us as well.
Mr Kyogoku?
I was hoping to see you
Thank you,
I do karate too
I always want to have a match with you!
I have my own gym in this masion
Oh! So, you're the great detective
Mr. Kogoro Mori!
Well, now, nice to meet you.
I didn't realize my fame extended
all the way out to foreign countries.
It's weird!
I dont feel anything
What is it?
No way
And the high school detective,
Mr. Shinichi Kudo.
Nice to meet you.
It seems you're more
of a magician than a detective.
It's your fingers.
They're so thin yet refined.
Though I'm a detective, I fight up here
more than with physical strength.
I see.
Oh, that must be
Miss Sonoko Suzuki over there.
You can't let your guard down with this guy.
You can't come in, please wait!
That's ok, dont bother
(ZHONHAN CHEN (70))
Mr. Kogoro Mori!
(SINGAPORE FINANCIAL AUTHORITY)
My wife and I are big fans of yours!
Y-Yeah...
- Mind if I take a photo?
- Photo?
- Sorry, but he come in all sudden
- Ah, a picture! Okay okay, of course!
It's alright
I will like to show everyone our safe room
That's good, I love to come along.
I'd like everyone to see
the Fist of Blue Sapphire up close, too!
Beyond these doors is the pride
of our company, the safe room.
Only select individuals
can open the entrance.
The walls are made of a fireproof alloy
and are indestructible.
What!?
- All outside broadcast frequencies
- Sorry Sorry! Nothing!
-are completely blocked.
The location of the cargo
is set to relocate on a regular basis.
This safe is filled with my ideal,
so it's special and unique in this world.
Wh-What's this?
Everyone, please stand back a bit.
This is the jewel, the Fist of Blue Sapphire
said to be the proof of the king of pirates.
- This is one large blue sapphire.
- Can you see it, Arthur?
Yup! Thank you!
I see. As long as it's here,
not even Kid will be able
to get his hands on this.
But that's not quite how it goes.
During the tournament that starts tomorrow,
we must display the belt at the stadium
according to the rules.
In other words, during the tournament,
it will be stored in a room at the venue.
We will have tight security,
but it will be inferior to this room.
I see.
But there is also security
for stadium?
Yes, leave it to us!
If anything happen to the Fist
You will be paying a hefty compensation fee.
You mentioned that the security
will be inferior to this room.
In other words,
you're thinking that Kid is waiting
for the sapphire
to be relocated to the stadium?
That's right.
It's too risky to target this location.
I agree.
I may not be of much help,
but please let me assist
in guarding the jewel.
Thank you!
Piece of cake!
I've got your fingerprints!
This was too easy, maybe?
I've been waiting for you.
Kid the Phantom Thief.
For you to make it all the way here...
Brilliant, as I expected.
You sure are confident.
Sorry to say,
but I can't just hand the jewel over to you.
I don't want to pay a compensation fee
to Zhonhan Chen.
And it's my job
to steal treasure of that nature.
The more difficult it is to steal...
the more fired up I get!
It's over
(Lock)
I hope you like to taste the
Singaporian ward.
I didn't expect him to use a taser.
Kid!
Are you serious?
What happ-
What happened?
It's Kid!
Don't worry, I always...
A top-tier guy always acts
with the worst-case scenario in mind!
...one step ahead
I have to hurry up and get out of here!
There he is!
What a jab...
It would've been terrible
if I didn't leap backwards.
Unlawful entry into a home, isn't it?
But wait, why are you here?
I was invited for some training here.
I didn't think I'd come to blows with you.
Oh, no, I don't want to do that at all.
Don't waste your breath!
Hold it!
Brace yourself!
A soccer ball?
Where did it come from?
Thanks, great detective!
This one's amazing!
I can fly at will even without wind.
I have to give thanks to Gramps!
But to think... he's gone that far...
You saved me.
I knew it was the right call
to return your stuff just in case.
Though I didn't want to save you at all.
Anyways, isn't it about time you told me
the real reason why you brought me here?
Leon had been searching for
the Fist of Blue Sapphire for years now.
He was one step shy
of salvaging it for himself
when Zhonhan Chen beat him to it.
Apparently, the location of the sunken ship
was leaked out to Chen at some point.
The main suspect was Sherilyn Tan.
For a while, she was the legal adviser
for Leon's company,
but their relationship had turned sour.
Rumors say that
she became the sponsor for Kyogoku...
...to prevent Jamaluddin's championship.
In other words,
she wanted to stop Leon
from obtaining the jewel.
If that's true,
then the rumor that she leaked information
about the sunken ship
would gain more than just a grain of truth.
And then the same Sherilyn Tan was murdered.
If the rumors about the leaks are true,
Leon would have a motive
for Sherilyn's murder.
What do the police think about that?
Unfortunately,
Leon has been taken off
their list of suspects.
Why is that?
Because they have
an even more likely suspect.
A suspect?
The police haven't announced it yet,
but there was a card left behind
at the scene of Sherilyn Tan's murder.
My advance notice.
I get it.
But still, why do I have to see
such a breathtaking view
with this guy of all people?
If I had to see this with someone...
It's time to go back to being Arthur Hirai.
By the way, I know you got "Arthur"
from Arthur Conan Doyle,
but where is "Hirai" from?
That's...
taken from Ranpo Edogawa's real name,
Taro Hirai.
I see.
Anyways, this is definitely a trap!
I know that.
That's why I brought you with me,
great detective.
You excel at things like this, right?
I understand your reason,
but I don't like how you went about it.
I, the Kid,
can't stay quiet after what's been done,
can I?
You're late.
I've been waiting forever here.
Sorry about that.
Look.
It's a really beautiful nightscape.
It's so romantic.
Don't be so bashful.
We are dating, aren't we?
Y-Yeah.
Wait, you guys are?
Damn it, Ran,
can't you see that he's a fake?
Oh, but if she notices,
I won't be able to go back to Japan.
Nothing like a Singapore Sling
when in Singapore!
Give me another one!
Mr. Mori?
Oh, uh, you're...
Mind if I sit here?
P-P-Please, please do!
Let's drink together!
Actually, I...
Oh, my! What have I done?
I really am sorry.
Oh, no, please don't worry about it.
Mr. Mouri, a call for you.
Call？
It looks like you have a telephone call,
Mr. Mori.
For me? From who?
Mr. Mori?
There's something I must talk to you about.
Please come here tomorrow.
Jeez!
What? They hung up on me!
Time to booze up again!
(SINGAPORE INDOOR STADIUM)
Who do you think will win?
It'll be Mr. Kyogoku!
I mean, he's never lost!
Really? I've never heard of that before.
If you give enough effort in the right place
and in the right direction,
it will bear fruit.
Everyone got that?
Yup!
Who will get the Fist of Blue Sapphire?
That Jamaluddin guy
seems really crazy strong!
He's got the power of a heavyweight
along with speed and technique.
He looks like a tough opponent.
As expected from
the Teitan High Karate team captain!
You look at this
from a completely different angle!
Hey, if the jewel
falls into Kyogoku's hands,
wouldn't it be impossible for you to get it?
Yeah.
I don't want to get close to him
if I can help it.
Oh, here comes Makoto!
Come on everyone, cheer for him!
Wait, why is the local kid
tagging along with us?
Looks like he's taken a real liking to me.
Bow to each other
Begin
- Scary.
- He did it! Makoto, you're awesome!
I want to go see him right now.
(Calling: Dad)
Oh, it's from Dad.
I'm telling you, I'm nobody suspicious!
Dad!
What happened?
Ran, come on, explain to these guys!
I already took out
all the metal objects I have on me!
But still...
No entry
I've done enough already!
NO!
Damn it! I can't get in at this rate!
Mr. Mori, are you all right?
Mr. Rishi!
He is staff member, please let him in.
Yes sir!
Thank you Mr. Rishi!
I'm glad I could join up with everyone.
After the belt was presented
during the opening ceremonies,
it was taken to be stored
in the underground safe.
If you'd like,
I'll guide you there afterwards.
In any case, where have you been?
Well, um, I went on patrol for a bit.
I'm betting he overslept
because of a hangover.
The PIN code changes every 10 minutes.
It is maintained by a computer
that sends the code by email.
The only recipients of the email
are Inspector Aidan, myself,
and Mr. Lowe, who manages the safe.
This room really has nothing in it.
That's not quite true.
The floor has a weight sensor.
On the ceiling are surveillance cameras.
Police officers completely surround
the stadium as well.
Oh! If that's the case,
I'm sure that phantom thief
can't do anything!
Mr. Mori,
there's no smoking allowed here.
Oh, sorry about that.
(Rechel Cheong)
I completely forgot because I was drunk.
She gave this to me at the bar last night,
and said she had something to tell me.
This card belongs to Leon's secretary.
Is that so?
To be honest, I don't remember much of it
because I was drunk.
How do you know that?
It has the mark for Leon's company on it.
The mark, huh...
It says, "Tomorrow 3:00 p.m. Meet me
at the back of National Stadium gate 3."
It also says, "Tell no one."
I see, 3:00 p.m. means...
it's almost time!
Mr. Mori!
It's embarrassing
for a man to make a lady wait!
That was a truly marvelous match.
I'm already looking forward
to the semifinals and finals tomorrow.
Thank you very much.
Your strength is exceptional.
How about it?
Would you be interested in working for me
as a bodyguard?
If you'll excuse me...
Now, hold on a second.
That was just a joke, of course.
There's one thing
I wanted to ask you, though.
Tell me...
what purpose do your fists serve?
You seek greater strength,
but what lies beyond that?
What is the driving force behind you?
You can't answer that?
An imperfect fist with no goal
is a dangerous thing.
Not just for you.
It brings misfortune
to those around you as well.
Those around me? Misfortune?
Right.
For instance, someone you are in love with.
You have someone like that, don't you?
Your fist brings danger
and it may harm the one you love.
If something like that
were to happen to you,
what would you do?
I'm looking forward
to your matches tomorrow.
Is there something else?
Great job!
Sonoko.
Jeez, you didn't come out for a while,
so I came to see you instead!
I'm sorry to make you wait.
Now let's all go eat lunch together!
There's a restaurant I want to go to.
I'm sorry, Sonoko.
Can you two go eat by yourselves?
Why?
I'm really sorry!
I don't think
Shinichi can leave here anytime soon,
guarding the jewel and all.
I see.
Well, it can't be helped, huh?
I guess it's just the two of us, Makoto.
Okay.
See you later, Ran!
Please excuse us.
I really want you to eat a whole lot!
Thank you so much.
Now, be alert
and look everywhere
If you see anything unusual,
report it
And act immediately!
And-
Are you okay?
I am so sorry!
I'm sorry too
Inspector Aidan!
Sorry, couldn't help but notice
I.. I.., I'm sorry, what?
There you go
Keep up the good work
Yes ma'am!
Everything okay with the safe?
Yes, sir, everything's alright
Excuse me, I'm so sorry
What the matter?
Inspector Aidan is calling you to come quick
Who? but what...
I will look after this place
Ok
We will be back soon, thank you!
Now...
I'll be taking the treasure!
It's mine.
Am I stuck on something?
A corpse? And...
It's Rechel!
This is bad!
I have to get out of here now!
There are some letters here.
Crap!
Stop right there!
Drop the gun down now!
Kid, you were under arrest!!
What?!
(Gate 3)
Jeez, just how long
is Rechel going to make me wait?
Let's wait for 10 more minutes and...
Wh-What's that?
Maybe it's Kid!
Oh, hey, wait!
He's here
This really looks bad.
But once I'm outside, the game is all mine.
There were this many of them?
Hey, wait!
Damn!!
Go!! Arrest him
at any cost
Yes, sir!
Come on, now. Is everything okay?
There you are, Mr. Mori!
I've been looking for you!
Well, we sure have a big deal here.
To think Kid would show up
in broad daylight like this.
But rest assured!
The great detective Kogoro Mori is here,
and it won't be long...
We don't have time for that!
We have a huge situation on our hands!
Please come to the safe room right away!
Look!
There is giant bird in the sky
If I've come this far...
Th-This is...
The victim is Mr. Lowe's secretary, Rechel.
Rechel?
I see.
Did you check the surveillance cameras?
No good. It's been hacked,
and it was set to show footage
with nobody showing on loop.
So, you have any ideas on the culprit?
Of course we do.
We're doing everything we can
to go after him.
Go after him? That means...
There's no doubt that the perpetrator
is Kid the Phantom Thief!
In any case, you only have yourself to blame
for not disabling the security device, Kid.
You know, if that's true,
Rechel was at the stadium
to meet up with this man
at that time, right?
Why was she here in the safe room?
Oh, come to think of it, that's true.
According to the police officer
in front of the safe room,
she came here to relay a message
from Inspector Aidan.
Apparently it was urgent,
so that's probably
why they prioritized that.
And then there was
that ruckus right afterward.
But Kid committing murder is unheard of...
Oh, hey!
Don't go in there without permission!
This brat, again!
(she)
Hey, about this message written in blood...
You little...
Brats should stay out of this!
Look at this.
I see.
You've been completely framed, Kid.
Bring it on.
I-It's getting rather interesting now.
As I'd expect from your selection,
both the chicken rice
and watermelon juice were very delicious.
Weren't they?
Something wrong?
W-Well, now that our stomachs are full...
Makoto, there's somewhere I'd like to go.
I will follow you anywhere.
Aaahh.. This looks bad
Hey girl!
What are you gonna do about this?
Y-You're the one who ran into me!
Ha!? I don't know what you mean!?
Come here
There may be others hiding around here.
Sonoko,
please don't stray too far away from me.
O-Okay!
Your fist brings danger
and it may harm the one you love.
Sonoko!
There they are!
Please, help me!
Sonoko!
Sonoko.
Sonoko! Sonoko!
How are her wounds?
They said it wasn't life-threatening.
She's asleep for now,
so she'll stay here for tonight,
and they'll do tests in the morning.
I'm really glad.
In any case,
I can't forgive
malicious hit-and-run drivers!
It's my fault.
It's all my fault that Sonoko...
Sorry to make you wait.
I'm sorry I'm late!
Thanks for putting in hard work!
How's the investigation going?
Right. The scene was a back street
with little pedestrian traffic.
There weren't any witnesses.
No, to be precise, there were people,
but they were caught off guard
and knocked unconscious
when the police car was stolen.
Am I interrupting something?
Mr. Lowe! Why are you here?
I heard about the accident
and came right over.
Sonoko is still asleep.
Then, can you hand this to her for me?
Thank you so much.
It looks like
what I was worrying about came true.
The god of battle is giving you a trial.
He's saying you still don't have the heart,
technique,
and physique required to use your fist.
That's right. I'll give you a talisman.
It's something similar to a misanga.
When this snaps off,
it means that said god recognizes you now
possess heart, technique, and physique.
However, if you are to raise your fist
before it snaps off...
You know what will happen, right?
Ow!
They got you pretty bad.
This is nothing.
Jeez, they shot without hesitation.
This time, they had the upper hand on me.
Everyone is thinking that
you're the one who murdered Rechel.
Everything was a trap
to put the blame on you.
It's just like magic.
I wasn't present at that location...
but to the audience,
it looks like I was right there
in the role of the murderer.
So, if you flip the viewpoint,
you can see the trick they used for it.
Yeah. A magician is a guy who makes you
think something is inside a clenched fist
and a detective is a guy
who correctly guesses
what's inside before that fist is opened,
right?
So please give me the correct guess,
great detective...
about the contents
of this mysterious fist called murder?
Jeez.
Little boy, you still haven't gone home?
Hey, can I stay at your place tonight?
What? Over at my place?
Even if I go home, I'm all by myself.
After what just happened, I'm scared.
If I say I'm staying with you, Mr. Rishi,
I'm sure Dad and Mom will feel relieved.
There's also nothing worse than
sleeping in the same room
as him two nights in a row!
Wow, this is amazing!
Did your dad receive all of these?
That's right. Dad was an oceanographer,
though he passed away five years ago.
During his research process,
he found several ruins
that had sunk into the sea.
You must be proud of your dad.
Yup.
Well, I still have some work left to do,
so you can go to sleep before me, Arthur.
All right.
Hey, Rishi,
what is this red mark on this map?
Oh, this marks the location
where ships were attacked by pirates.
Do pirates still exist now, too?
They do.
In the past, there were many of them
around Singapore, too.
Well, the current headache isn't pirates,
but a murder case.
That and Kid the Phantom Thief.
I borrowed some reference materials
from inspector Aidan, but...
I'm going to be up all night.
I'm sorry I have to do this to you,
but I have to have you take a nap.
Hey, what's that?
Did you have something like that on?
Sonoko! You came to!
Actually, I did a while ago.
I'm so glad! I really am.
So, is that some kind of a magic charm?
Y-Yes, it's something along those lines.
You shouldn't.
You need to take it easy and rest up.
I'm not sleepy at all.
I came all the way out to Singapore,
but this is boring.
If you overexert yourself,
it's bad for your health.
Please stay put for tonight.
Hey, I've been meaning to ask you
for a while,
but why don't you take that
Band-Aid near your left eyebrow off?
W-Well, this is nothing at all, really.
I thought we were not
supposed to meet
after everything was done?
Your pray your plan was perfect
But are you totally sure?
You look tough
ut you actually
a coward
Now, watch your mouth...
I always keep promises.
I do!
An eye for an eye. That's how I roll.
We have an announcement to make
In the second semi-final match,
Makoto Kyogoku who has withdraw
And Tan Lee will proceed to the final
Damn it
I didn't ask for this
You withdrew from the tournament?
Why? Is it my fault?
It's possible that the group
that assaulted us may try again.
I can't possibly leave your side like that,
Sonoko.
So it really is my fault.
Please stay in the tournament!
There was someone you wanted to fight,
wasn't there?
Yes.
But, Sonoko, I couldn't even protect you.
I feel like I'm still lacking something.
Of course you're lacking something.
You keep hiding stuff from me.
Hiding things?
You didn't tell me anything
about that misanga,
nor about the Band-Aid.
Well, this really is, um...
Get out!
I don't want to be protected by a man
who is full of lies!
I really was worried about you yesterday,
okay?
I couldn't reach you at all for a while.
Sorry, my bad.
I got so engrossed in chasing after Kid.
Nothing less from that moonlight magician.
Even I, Shinichi Kudo,
find it impossible to capture...
Oh, it's you Arthur.
Hello.
Is your friend Sonoko all right?
Yup. I stopped by the hospital earlier,
but the test results showed no problems.
She'll be discharged this afternoon
and head back to the hotel.
I see. That's good.
Thank you for worrying about her.
Well, let's get back to the hotel soon.
I want to start packing for our trip home.
Is it okay to leave them as-is right now?
Yeah.
I felt I should leave them alone
for a while.
It sounded like
they were arguing about something.
Mr. Kyogoku forfeited his match, too.
Huh? Shinichi?
（FOUNTAIN OF WEALTH）
So, did you gather anything last night,
great detective?
This is what was in the reference material
at Rishi's place.
According to witness testimony,
Sherilyn wasn't stabbed
in the shopping mall where she collapsed.
Instead, it was likely
inside the elevator of Tower 3.
Why was it inside an elevator of all places?
If things go bad, there's no way out.
After getting stabbed with a plain knife,
she walked all the way to the shopping mall.
And right after she collapsed...
her car parked
in the underground parking lot exploded.
That caused the entire hotel
to have a blackout.
And thus, all security camera footage
within the hotel was wiped out.
What gets me is that Leon was at the scene.
Not only had he booked his own room,
but he booked Sherilyn's room as well.
However, when she was murdered,
many witnesses claim
he was riding a different elevator.
Because his alibi was confirmed,
he was removed from the investigation.
Exactly.
By the way,
why was Leon carrying a suitcase?
Oh, the police did go through
what was inside, of course.
But it was empty.
He had just picked up a suitcase
he had sent out for repair.
(delivery slip)
It's been confirmed that
a shop near the hotel
had received such a request from him, too.
So his alibi is perfect.
There's one more thing... this.
Why was something like this
left at the crime scene?
Why do I need to be dragged into this?
There was also some effort
taken to apply viscous blood to it.
Also...
the culprit is trying to frame you
for Rechel's murder as well.
The knife used as the murder weapon
was the same type
for Sherilyn's murder.
Rechel had been placed inside that pedestal
before I entered the safe room.
However, to enter the room,
you need to get past all the guards
as well as the numerous security systems.
Someone who gets past all of the security
and not even trip one of the sensors...
Oh, no, it's not me.
So, the suspicious guy is Leon Lowe
after all.
As the safe room's manager,
Leon has full knowledge of
the security system.
Furthermore, the belt was transported
to the stadium yesterday morning.
And Rechel was confirmed to be alive
until at least two nights ago.
That means the crime likely occurred between
that evening
and when the belt was transported.
But for what purpose?
Why was there a reason for him
to murder his own secretary?
Maybe the motive was that...
(Rechel Secretary)
Rechel was trying to tell Pops something.
The only clue we have
are those letters written in blood.
"She." Who does this "she" refer to?
No good.
I feel like something tremendous
will happen soon,
but I can't gather my thoughts.
Even the great detective
is throwing in the towel?
Then let's take a break for now.
So which hand has...
Your left hand has coconut water.
Correct.
How did you know?
You bought some earlier, didn't you?
So you were watching me.
Magic, huh...
A magician is a guy
who makes you think
something is inside a clenched fist,
and a detective is a guy
who correctly guesses
what's inside before that fist is opened,
right?
I get it!
By the way,
is Lady Sonoko having some fight
with that karate guy?
Apparently.
If there's a brawl and a traffic accident
while you're traveling,
it's no surprise
if you become emotionally unstable.
So that's what it was about.
Have Sonoko get injured
to sway Kyogoku emotionally.
The biggest obstacle for Jamaluddin
to win the tournament
was Kyogoku, after all.
I see.
So, that accident
was also something Leon had set up.
Just like he hoped,
Kyogoku withdrew from the tournament.
Now the champion's belt
will no doubt go to Jamaluddin.
In other words,
it will end up in the hands of his employer,
Leon.
Right along with the Fist of Blue Sapphire.
But why is Leon so fixated
on the Fist of Blue Sapphire?
I got hold of a clue that
might unravel that.
This is the guy
who Leon was meeting around dawn.
Can you figure out this guy's identity?
Well, it's not an impossibility, but...
You suddenly called the Professor
saying you're going to Hokkaido,
and we haven't heard since!
What are you doing right now?
Sorry, Haibara.
A lot has been happening here, too.
You guys, keep it quiet for a bit!
Okay.
Jeez. Knowing you,
I'm sure you're involved in some incident,
right?
Actually, that's exactly it.
I just sent you some pictures that Kid took.
Kid? Did you just say "Kid"?
You're kidding me!
Kid the Phantom Thief appeared?
You're on the phone with Conan, right?
Wasn't he in Hokkaido?
What is Kid stealing this time?
Maybe a wooden statue of a bear?
Maybe some ramen in Sapporo.
He'd never steal anything like that.
Ai!
Can I talk on the phone, too?
Me, too!
Sorry, the kids are over right now.
I-I see.
I'll tell you all about it when I get back.
For now, can you figure out
the identity of the guy in the picture?
Yeah, yeah. I hear you.
You're really all right, aren't you?
Yeah, somehow.
I'm sure this will fall on deaf ears,
but don't be too reckless.
Thank you.
That should do it.
So, what will we do from here,
great detective?
We'll see how things go.
How will Leon act
once he obtains the Fist of Blue Sapphire?
But before that is Pops.
Oh, hey! Wait!
The winner of Jun Han Karate
Jamaluddin!!!
So,
what do you think of
my city plan?
We cannot accept your proposal
Why?
You lose nothing with this plan
It also benefits the country
It's too hasty
If you proceed wih this much development
some maybe forced
ou of their home!
We can give them another place
My plan is perfect!
You are too young!
Learn some more and comeback
Old fool
Your era is now at the end
I will build a new city!
Hands in the air
Ok.. ok
We seem to cross paths a lot.
If this plan succeeds, we will be partners.
I'm counting on you.
You took good care of me quite a bit.
You saved me
when I was about to be taken away
by the cops with suspected theft,
and that was the first time.
And since then, you know, various things...
It was because I realized that
you were the famous Reijiro Nakatomi.
The son of Juzo Nakatomi,
dubbed the maritime transport king of Japan.
Don't speak my father's name.
My apologies.
In any case,
everything will change as of tonight.
How about we witness that moment up close?
Now, let's go together...
to be witnesses in a page that will be
engraved into Singapore's history.
Sorry, Pops!
What's this all of a sudden?
Oh, no, stop it! You perv!
This is it!
Nakatomi?
Nakatomi... You mean Nakatomi Shipping?
Probably.
Pops, I'm going to borrow this!
Did that brat just call me "Pops"?
Why are you suddenly leaving Japan?
It's a vacation. Vacation!
You also went to Singapore five years ago.
Yeah, this trip is the first time since.
What of it?
President Nakatomi is...
It's that guy who was at Merlion Square.
But he got taken down by that karate guy.
Hey, Haibara.
You figured out who that guy was?
Yes, barely.
His name is Eugene Lim.
What a surprise, he's a pirate.
A pirate?
He's been recently sighted near Singapore.
As expected of you, Haibara.
I can always count on you!
The fact that you're flattering me means...
you have something else
you want me to check up on?
Y-Yeah.
Have you ever heard of
the name Reijiro Nakatomi?
The guy from Nakatomi Shipping.
I know of him.
I want to know the status of the ships
that Nakatomi Shipping owns.
Just the ships around Singapore
would be good.
There are two freighter ships
and a tanker near Singapore.
What gets my attention
is that the tanker has strayed
from the planned route.
That's the one.
Send me data for that tanker!
Okay! I'll contact you again later.
Please do!
So, what's up with this tanker?
That word "she" that Rechel left behind.
They use "she" when referring to ships, too.
(NAKATOMI)
Was what you said over the phone true?
Everything that's been going on
was all planned by Mr. Lowe?
Can you explain in a way
that I can understand?
It all started
with the Fist of Blue Sapphire,
found by Zhonhan Chen.
He embedded it into the champion's belt
for a karate tournament
and said he'd give the belt to the winner.
Leon made Jamaluddin
participate in the tournament
in an effort to obtain the jewel.
However, he faced an unexpected obstacle.
Someone undefeated in 400 karate matches...
Makoto Kyogoku entered the tournament.
The one who invited him
was the murder victim, Sherilyn Tan.
E-Even if that was the motive,
Mr. Lowe has an alibi.
When she was stabbed,
he was riding a different elevator.
The truth goes like this.
After meeting up with Leon at the poolside,
she boarded an elevator
to return to her room.
However, she was staying
on the 16th floor of Tower 3.
Due to how the hotel was built,
she has to change elevators
on the 34th floor.
And when she was on her way
back to her room,
she was dragged into a different room...
by the secretary, Rechel.
Rechel is an accomplice?
It can't be...
The room Leon reserved to
enter the poolside restaurant
only for special hotel guests
is on the 34th floor.
Leon came down to stab Sherilyn,
and killed her in that room.
And placed the corpse in the suitcase.
(TOWER 3)
Later, Rechel and Leon
boarded separate elevators.
I'm betting they used
a type of magic knife for this trick.
However,
the blood was that of Sherilyn herself.
Pretending to be stabbed, Rechel collapses.
Moments later...
Everything took place unbeknownst
to everyone during the blackout
caused by the explosion.
Th-That's impossible.
Rechel, finding out about Leon's true plans,
was planning to tell everything
to Detective Mori
because it was so horrific.
But then Leon caught wind of that.
The Rechel that showed up at the safe room
was Kid in disguise.
Even Kid was used by Leon's plan.
The real Rechel had already been murdered
and shoved inside that pedestal.
He knew Kid would come disguised as Rechel,
so along with having an alibi,
he also made it look like
the whole incident was caused by Kid.
How can he know such a thing?
Then, Rishi,
who do you think
would be a safe bet to impersonate?
Let's see.
No matter how good the disguise is,
it's useless
if you bump into the real person.
So you'd want someone whose location
and time you'd know, wouldn't you?
I see! Rechel had scheduled to meet
with Mr. Mori at 3:00 p.m.
And that's why...
Right. Kid impersonated someone
who would never go to the safe room.
Kid completely fell for the trap because
Leon predicted that's what he would do.
Then tell me!
What in the world is Mr. Lowe trying to do?
It's all for a stupid little project of his.
Leon has been in contact with Eugene Lim,
the leader of a pirate group.
The word left behind on the pedestal
at Rechel's murder scene was "she".
And Rechel secretly entrusted a medal
made by Nakatomi Shipping to Detective Mori.
Everything involves ships.
How are all of those things related?
Rishi.
This is an analysis of
the Nakatomi Shipping vessel routes
in this area
that Mr. Detective received from Tokyo.
One tanker is greatly straying
from the intended path.
If it keeps going,
its destination will be Marina Bay.
Leon is planning to use pirates
to ram an entire tanker into the city!
In the first place,
why does Mr. Lowe have to do such a thing?
What's the reason?
I don't know
what Leon would say about this...
but if you were to destroy this city
and rebuild it,
a great deal of money would be used.
I think Leon was persistent
about the Fist of Blue Sapphire
because he needed it
in exchange for being able
to control the pirates.
B-But...
pirates evade the police's view
and are dispersed all over the place.
How did he contact them?
He used the Merlion.
You remember the incident
where the Merlion spewed red water, right?
I'm sure the pirates caught notice of it
because it was broadcasted
all over the world.
I'm sure that was the sign
for the plan to start.
But more than that, right now...
Yes. If we don't hurry, it'll be too late!
Even if you say that,
I can't do this at my own discretion.
We need more evidence
if we're going to mobilize the police.
We won't make it if we do that!
Isn't there any other way?
I know. We can consult
with Mr. Zhonhan Chen.
He has a lot of influence
with the military and the police.
I'm sure he will help us out with this!
Rishi, one more thing!
What is it?
If things go according to plan,
and the tanker rams into the city,
where do you think Leon will be?
Let's see.
He's a very cautious person,
so I'm sure he'd be watching from afar.
Perhaps he's already
left the country by now.
Well, then, I've got to hurry!
I see. Thank you.
Jeez, Dad, where are you?
The show is about to begin!
Shinichi has gone off somewhere as well.
Man, why did I get roped into this incident?
Was it really Leon that left my card
at Sherilyn's murder scene?
No.
The card posted on the elevator was found
quite a while
after the crime scene investigation started.
Why do you think that happened?
Whoa.
We got the newest path of the tanker.
Wh-What?
Oh no! If the tanker keeps going,
it'll hit the hotel!
Ran! Please answer the phone!
It's heading this way.
Hey, Ran! Are you having fun?
Dad, where are you right now?
Huh? I don't know what's up,
but I can see a huge boat!
Wait, hey, Dad!
Are you at the top of the hotel?
Hello? Hello?
Can we make it?
I think so
Sonoko! Sonoko!
What?
Something seems to be happening outside.
I think it would be better
if we left the hotel.
Hello?
Yes, I understand.
Who was that from?
Someone from the police.
They told me to stay in my room
because if I head out haphazardly,
people might come after me again.
Apparently someone's coming to guard me.
H-However...
It's fine. I'll stay here.
I understand.
Not good.
With this crowd,
we can't get close to the hotel!
Damn, it's all or nothing!
Oh, it's Kid
It's Kid! Kid is here!
I got this place all to myself.
Wh-What do you want?
I-It's the Sleeping Kogoro!
I really don't know... just about him.
Damn it, I can't get through!
Crap!
Jeez! Where in the world are you, Dad?
Look!
This city will be born again
with my hand!
Why are you ...?
W-Wait!
This is a surprise.
I didn't think you had the ability
to do this.
Even I couldn't see this coming.
Rishi.
Well, now, I'll be a man and admit it.
Yes, this was all part of my plan.
Let's have a little chat.
Please put away that dangerous thing.
Mr. Lowe, I think you're the one
with the misunderstanding.
Freeze!
There is no one here!
We stop the ship now
The tanker has stopped! Kid!
Let's leave this to the police!
Yeah!
The tanker!
What happened ...?
I-I'll stay quiet! Don't shoot!
Help me! Don't kill me!
Rishi... I didn't think you'd shoot.
Jamaluddin!
Wa-wait!
Jamaluddin! What are you thinking?
The only reason
I work for you-
was to fight against Kyogoku
I have no such reason anymore
What?!
Mr. Lowe!
With all due respect,
have you lost your touch a bit?
You were not the one controlling the world.
It was me.
It can't be... that you...
H-Hold on! Wait!
I-I'll give you this!
The jewel is inside.
It's a good deal, right, Rishi?
Kid the Phantom Thief?
Wh-What is Arthur doing here?
Let's see, I have to change elevators
on the 34th floor
to get to the roof.
Hey!
Wait
Are they?
Heading to Marina Bay Sands?
What are you doing?
I was just trying to capture
the two masterminds of the case!
You can stop your terrible acting now,
Rishi Ramanathan.
It's obvious to us that
you're the one behind it all.
What first sparked doubt
was Kid's advance notice
left at the crime scene.
The police noticed the note
right after you arrived at the scene,
wasn't it, Rishi?
And moments ago,
when I asked you where Leon would be,
my suspicions against you became definitive.
What?
Someone as conceited as Leon
wouldn't flee overseas right before
his project came to fruition.
He's sure to be watching it all
from a location with the best view.
There's no way
you wouldn't recognize that fact!
This is a surprise.
So you were testing me with that question.
Everything started five years ago,
after your father's accident.
The murder of an oceanographer,
and the suspect,
previously denying charges,
now plead guilty.
If I recall...
it was also five years ago
that you came to Singapore, Mr. Nakatomi.
N-No, I...
Leon captured the culprit.
And with Sherilyn as the defense counsel,
he pled guilty.
This can't be only a coincidence.
What do you mean by that?
It was all a trap
so they could obtain a tanker
that belonged to Nakatomi Shipping.
Everything was set up.
And then, there was one more trap...
You noticed it, didn't you?
I thought it was all an accident at first,
too.
But when I was going through
Dad's belongings,
I realized something.
In the middle of investigating a ruin
on the ocean floor,
he found a sunken ship by coincidence,
that had a high chance of containing
the king of pirates' proof,
the Fist of Blue Sapphire.
That's why you killed Dad first, didn't you?
So that
he wouldn't salvage the jewel before you!
Help!
Someone push me in the back
Help is on the way!
Hurry!
Save him!!
You figured that Dad,
who has a strong sense of justice,
would surely jump in to help.
Wh-What's the meaning of all this, Leon?
You...
Let go of me!
Rishi,
you have some kind of a misunderstanding.
The culprit who killed your father
has gone to jail...
Having doubts about Dad's death,
I became one of your students,
then a reserve police officer.
Then, I started to do my own research
about the incident.
I first approached Sherilyn Tan,
who was the legal counsel.
When I suggested we blackmail Leon
using incidents about Reijiro,
she was very quick to tell me.
And Rechel... That's right.
Through her,
I got every last bit of information
about you guys.
If so,
why did you post an advance notice from Kid?
Why don't you tell us?
The Fist of Blue Sapphire
and a murder case
that has nothing to do with him.
If I entice him with both,
I was sure the Phantom Thief would show up.
And by showing up,
he would surely get in the way of your plan.
I wasn't expecting that
high school detective to show up,
but he did quite a good job
of playing his role.
Mr. Nakatomi...
I heard Leon saved you back
when you were suspected of theft.
But was that really a coincidence?
Think really hard about it.
Perhaps everything has been...
Damn you!
You sure did your research well, Rishi.
Where is this? If I recall...
Dad!
Ran?
What?
Whoa, what's this?
Dad...
Ra...
Fall back
And regroup.. Tell the chopper too..
What's up with you guys?
Now, Rishi.
Unfortunately for you, the tide has turned.
Eugene, the plan seems to have failed
You can take this jewel
Take care of everyone here
What are you doing?
Dont move
H-Help me!
Now that I have the jewel,
I have no need for you
What?
I have no time for your nonsense
I am known to break promises
It just there was a more lucrative offer
You guys are after...
You're a very perceptive little boy.
That's right.
The young daughter of the Suzuki Group
is staying in this hotel.
If we kidnap her,
we'll get an unimaginable amount as ransom.
Hasn't the daughter evacuated already?
She should still be in her suite.
I already told her on the phone
to stay in her room no matter what.
H-Hold on, Makoto!
Excuse me.
All of the elevators have stopped.
We should get out of here.
There, come on
Don't shoot! You'll hit her!
M-Makoto, what is all of this about?
Look.
In the end, everything ends up
just how I imagined it to be.
This city will burn to the ground
and then be reborn!
You won't be around to see it though!
What?
They are going to shoot rocket
at us?
Damn
Take this!
Makoto!
What, what, what, what, what, what?
Go after her!
They're here!
What's going on here?
I don't know!
Most of the pirates are now in the hotel
Just what is going on inside?
Its dangerous..
Please get back
You okay?
Y-Yeah.
At this rate,
the city will really get destroyed!
Damn it. There has to be a way.
If we use that, we can do it!
Kid!
Are you serious?
Of course!
That's the Kid
shoot him down.
Boss, we can't hit em!
He's just little bird!
Hey, we have to do something
about those pirates
before we go through with our plan.
I only got one shot left in my card gun.
But we still have something left.
A trump card
that will turn the tables for us.
I see.
We're going in!
Wait!
Makoto?
Get them!
Stay back
He's
Mine!
Kid!
Take me towards the ship's bow!
I know that!
Ran, stay back.
Ran!
Go!
What the heck is going on?
I heard Shinichi's voice.
Are you okay, miss?
Arthur, why are you here?
Well, I got worried about you.
Thank you.
Jeez, where in the world is he?
I'm glad you're safe.
Thank you!
Makoto!
Kid have the jewel,
can you shoot him down?
Okay, boss
There.. Stay still
Take this!
Did it hit?
We're fine, Sonoko.
Oh no..
What?
Kid, you...
Hi
Wait
Help me mom!
Falling down!
Makoto, you're bleeding.
Sonoko, if you'll excuse me.
Wait, what in the world are you doing?
Makoto, what are you up to
in a place like this?
You can't!
This is a piggyback carrier knot.
Sonoko,
this time please do not stray away from me!
In this situation,
I can't stay away even if I wanted to.
Where is he!?
Mr. Kyogoku, grab onto something!
No!
Are you alright?
You can have it back.
Since that wasn't the jewel
I was looking for.
Sonoko, please sit over here for a minute.
I apologize.
I think I tied the knots a bit too tightly.
There, all untied now.
N-No, this is... well...
somewhat of a good luck charm for me.
You kept this on all this time?
Y-Yes.
I thought it would be disreputable as a man,
so I couldn't tell you.
So that's it.
I thought I was the one
being protected all this time,
but instead I was the one protecting Makoto.
I see, I see!
Please give me back that Band-Aid.
No way!
Please!
I'm going to treasure this forever!
So lovey-dovey.
Who in the world are you, exactly?
You're not just an ordinary kid, are you?
Conan Edogawa. I'm a detective.
But are you sure?
Letting that strong boyfriend
head to the United States again...
It's fine, it's fine.
After all,
Makoto should be fighting someone,
somewhere!
Oh, here they come.
Hey, what's that?
Hey, don't get so close to me like that.
It's hard for me to walk.
No way.
I'm not going to let you go ever again.
Really?
I've been waiting so long...
for this very moment.
Kid! I've been waiting for you!
Seriously?
I knew from the very beginning
that you weren't Shinichi!
Because Shinichi...
- What's up?
- ...never calls Dad "Pops," ever!
But he always...
Come to think of it,
I've never said "Pops" in front of Ran.
I can't forgive you
for disguising as Shinichi not only once,
but twice!
Miss,
please make sure to not let go of that arm!
Get him!
Kid! Arrest him!
I'm never letting go!
Don't let him get away!
Professor.
He's not here!
Jeez! He got away!
Damn it!
He should still be somewhere around here!
After him!
Conan!
Welcome back, Ran.
I'm back.
You weren't lonely, were you?
Idiot... I was with you the whole time.