Hey! Look at this! There's a dinosaur!
Huh?
Urgh. He always runs off suddenly.
Here! You must be thirsty!
Thanks...
Oh, no! It's three minutes 'til!
H-Hold on, Shinichi!
Alright! We made it in time!
What is this place?
It's just an ordinary plaza...
Just watch!
Ten. Nine. Eight.
Seven. Six. Five.
Four! Three! Two!
One!
What?!
These fountains go off every two hours.
You like stuff like this, right?
Shinichi!
It's your present for winning
the city karate championship!
Accept it gratefully!
Oh, you think you're such a big shot!
A rainbow!
Alright! Let's make a toast!
Okay!
Gah...
You're so funny!
I'm high school detective Kudo Shinichi!
I went with old friend and classmate,
Mori Ran, to an amusement park
where I witnessed a suspicious
deal with a man dressed in black!
I was so absorbed with watching the deal
that I didn't notice a second
man sneak up from behind me!
He forced me to take a poison,
and when I woke up...
...my body had shrunk!
If they learned Kudo Shinichi was alive,
they might go after me again,
putting all the people around me in danger!
Per Dr. Agasa's advice,
I decided to conceal my identity.
When Ran asked my name,
I quickly answered, "Edogawa Conan."
To get information on the men,
I wound up living with Ran
and her detective father.
Great Detective Mori! What was
the key to solving this latest case?!
No, uhh, I don't really remember...
That's only natural.
'Cause I always put the old guy to
sleep with my stun-gun wristwatch
and use my voice-changing bowtie
to solve cases with his voice.
Dr. Agasa invented these two gadgets!
Hi there!
He's always making unique gadgets,
like a Turbo-Engine Skateboard,
Tracking Glasses, and
Power-Assisted Kick Shoes!
However, neither Ran nor her dad
have realized who I really am.
The only ones who know are Dr. Agasa,
Hattori Heiji, the high
school detective of the west,
and my classmate, Haibara Ai.
She originally worked with the men in black,
but to escape from them, she took
the same poison I did and shrank!
The Black Organization
still remains a mystery!
And now, a large barrier is about
to stand between Ran and me!
Even when I'm small, my mind
remains that of a sharp detective!
There is always only one truth!
Fountains?
Yeah! It was so pretty with
the rainbow and everything!
Oh, yeah! It was!
Ugh. She remembers the stupidest things...
Say! Let's go to Tropical Land again!
Eh?!
We've never gone there
together since that day!
Of course we haven't!
I've been little ever since that day!
So, when do you wanna go?
No, uhh...
- Do you think Conan-kun's home?
- Good question!
We'll just have to find out!
Sorry, Ran! I'm involved in another case!
I'll call you again! Later!
Oh! Wait! Shinichi!
Urgh! It's always "case, case, case"!
You stupid case freak!
Not even Conan-kun'll figure this one out!
I can't wait to see his "I give up" look!
Conan-kun's "I give up," huh?
I give up! You beat me!
"Victory"
What're you smilin' about?
Conan-kun!
Perfect timing! We were just
headed to your place right now!
All three of us thought
up a super special riddle!
Riddle?
Ready?
When asked what she
thinks Conan-kun is like,
Haibara-san looked at the moon
and answered, "He's not summer."
Did Haibara-san 1. praise Conan-kun,
or 2. insult Conan-kun?
Which is it?!
Not summer... Moon...
Got it! The answer is #2!
- Eh?!
- W-Why is that?!
The months, or "moons," of summer
are June, July, and August.
Together, their numbers spell out,
"There's nothing good about him!"
You really are amazing, Conan-kun!
Bah! You're no fun.
Never mind that. Tell me
why you were smiling earlier.
Okay, then will you "I give up" for us?
Huh?
- Let's cross!
- Hold it! No crossing!
A blinking green light is
the same as a yellow light.
Wait until the next green light.
Okay...
We got in trouble...
Yeah, but he is right.
Now, I have a question for you!
What do you think that man's job is?
Eh?
A school teacher?
A businessman?
No, he doesn't have a briefcase...
An eel restaurant owner?
The answer is "police detective."
P-Police detective?!
Whenever police detectives
need to make note of something,
they rotate their police
notebooks and write horizontally.
- Really?
- You're so smart, Conan-kun!
You know everything!
Oh! It's green! Let's cross!
Yeah!
That man's been shot! That person did it!
Oh, no, you don't!
Conan-kun! Watch out!
- Call an ambulance!
- U-Understood!
Dammit! Got away!
Hang in there, Mister! Who shot you?!
What?!
At approximately 2:00 today,
at the Beika Park intersection,
Assistant Police Detective
Narasawa Osamu was shot and killed.
The shooter appears to have fled.
Assistance has been sent
from Police Headquarters,
and a task force has been
set up by the Beika Police.
I'm sorry to ask yet again, but
could you tell us about the murderer?
It was a young man!
No, it was a pretty lady!
No! It was a middle-aged man!
How about the person's umbrella?
It was a black umbrella!
It was green! Green!
I think it was blue...
Hey, now. Did you guys really see anything?
What about you, Conan-kun?
The raincoat and umbrella were gray-ish,
but I don't know if it was a man or woman.
But the umbrella was in their right hand!
Meaning they fired
the gun with their left hand.
So the killer is left-handed...
Incidentally, Inspector.
Why did Assistant Detective Narasawa
die holding the left side of his chest?
We believe it was meant to indicate
the police notebook in his pocket.
We're currently looking into
everything written in that notebook.
Inspector Megure.
The cartridges at the scene were
from a 9-mm caliber automatic.
A 9-mm caliber?
That's a common gun
even a woman could handle...
But it's a good thing none of you
got caught in the middle of it!
You too, Conan-kun!
Yeah!
Damn!
If only the light hadn't turned red,
they wouldn't have gotten away!
"Another Detective Murdered!"
"The Work of Extremists?"
"Gangs Enacting Revenge?"
"The Mystery Deepens"
"A Personal Grudge!?"
"Challenge for Police!"
This is Megure.
Oh, Mori-kun?
Inspector, I'd like to know
more about last night's incident...
I'm sorry. I'm busy.
Maybe some other time.
Hello?! Inspector?!
What happened?
Says he's busy.
Of course he is.
They've lost two of their detectives.
Still, he seemed
different from his normal self...
Alright, Shiratori-kun.
Only you and I can
know about the incident.
Do not tell anyone.
Understood.
As the ballistic fingerprints of
the bullets used in the murders match,
authorities now believe these
were acts of the same individual.
And now for the weather.
A high pressure system will...
Still, Shiratori-san's sister
sure knows how to pick a bad time
"15 F - Wedding Celebration" Still,
Shiratori-san's sister sure knows how to pick a bad time
"15 F - Wedding Celebration"
to hold a wedding reception...
It can't be helped. It was
planned a month in advance,
and it's not her fault
the incidents happened.
Besides, it's not a wedding reception,
it's a wedding celebration!
The bride and groom's friends
are the ones in charge of it!
Yeah, I know!
Hey! What's the groom, Haretsuki-san, like?
Apparently, he's a painter!
Add "struggling" to the beginning of that.
A struggling painter, huh?
I guess I can't expect very
much from his guy friends...
"Mori Kogoro"
I see your handwriting is as blunt as ever...
Mom!
You got invited, too?
Yes. Sara-san is an
up-and-coming attorney I work with.
"Kisaki Eri"
Wow! You have such great handwriting!
Geez. Don't sign in separately
if you're husband and wife.
Please store this for me!
Your number is 87!
Come on, Conan-kun!
Yeah!
Wow! Look at all these people!
Oh! The inspector's here!
It's so easy to spot members of the police.
They have menacing looks in their eyes,
and are all-around gloomy.
Can't blame 'em. This's no time
for a party, after what's happened.
Detective Sato is always cheerful, though!
Well? Fine feathers make
fine birds, wouldn't you agree?
N-Not at all! It suits you very well!
Oh! It's Odagiri-san!
I'm gonna go say hello.
- Who?
- Police Superintendent Odagiri.
He was Chief Detective when that
bonehead private eye worked there.
I believe he's head of
criminal investigations now.
Thank you all for your patience!
Here are the bride and groom!
Please greet them with
tremendous applause!
Wow! How wonderful!
Kotaro! Sara-san! Congratulations!
Mori-san.
Oh! Congrats!
Thank you.
Oh, let me introduce you.
This is my doctor, Dr. Kazato.
He's a psychiatrist at
Beika Yakushino Hospital.
I'm Kazato. It's nice to meet you.
I'm Mori.
This is my wife Eri, my daughter
Ran, and my moocher Conan.
Quit callin' me a moocher.
But Shiratori-san... A psychiatrist?
Yes, worries and concerns are always
a part of management positions.
Which is why...
...I think you should have him
take a look at you, Mori-san.
Yeah... Lately, my memory's been a bit...
Hey, you! What's that supposed to mean?!
That's enough laughing out of you!
Ouch!
Excuse me!
Inspector!
Oh, Mori-kun.
Have you found anything out since then?
I'm sorry, but I can't talk about that.
Why won't he talk to me?
There must be something he can't tell you.
Hey! Is that true, Takagi?!
N-No, not really!
Say, Takagi-san. You like
Detective Sato, don't you?
How interesting!
I'll go tell her how you feel!
H-Hold on! Wait!
Okay!
We're keeping it from the press,
but Detective Shiba also died
holding his police notebook...
What?!
Which means...
There is no use in prying
any further, Mori-san.
"Need not to know."
That should be clear enough.
"Need not to know..."
This can't be!
"Need not to know."
A special phrase used
among police detectives...
Does this mean the killer is someone
inside the police department?!
And not just anyone...
it's someone high-ranking...
Or it could be the entire
police organization itself!
So he didn't say anything special to propose?
No, he's not good at that sort of thing.
It's better when men are like that.
Anyone who lays the flattery
on so thick is no good.
Say! I've been meaning to ask,
but how did Dad propose to you?
It was just a bunch of
over-flattery, like I said.
Sensei! Please tell us!
But I've forgotten.
Oh, you're always playing dumb!
- Please tell us, for future reference!
- C'mon! Quit teasing us, Mom!
Let me think...
"I love you. More than anyone on this Earth."
Or something like that!
No way...
That's so nice!
"Oh, if Shinichi were to say that to me..."
Get that look off your face!
L-I don't have a look, Sonoko!
What's wrong, Ran-neechan?
Your face is red!
No, it's nothing!
Toshiya! What are you doing here?!
This is no place for the likes of you!
You weren't invited to this party!
Shut it! I just happened to come
to this hotel 'cause of work!
That's his son, Toshiya-san!
I heard he's in a rock band...
Now, now! It's all right, Superintendent!
- Toshiya-kun, enjoy yourself.
- Get out!
Quit prowling around like
a stray dog looking for food!
- Say what?!
- Toshiya-san!
Sorry to bother you!
Toshiya-kun!
Huh? Where have I seen her before?
Sato-kun.
About you-know-what...
- No, I'm fine!
- But...
- There's no need to worry!
- Hey, now!
- #38, please.
- Right!
- Oh! Ran-chan!
- Detective Sato!
Such a weird party, isn't it?
With all those police...
Not really. But please be careful, okay?
Eh?
Police detectives are being
shot one after the other...
I'll be fine! I'm tough!
Huh?
A blackout?
- What do you suppose happened?
- That's strange.
I'll go look around. Stay here.
Detective Sato! There's a flashlight here!
See?
No, Ran-san!
Detective Sato!
Detective Sato...
Detective Sato! Say something!
It's... It's because
I picked up the flashlight...
- Ran!
- Sato-san!
Hey! Ran! Are you alright?!
Ran-neechan is only unconscious!
The injured one is...
Sato-san! Sato-san! Please say something!
W-What on earth?!
Megure! Call an ambulance! Shiratori!
Seal all of the hotel's exits!
Yes, sir!
Hello?! I'm on the 15th floor
of the Beika Sun Plaza Hotel!
A woman has been shot!
Please send an ambulance immediately!
It's out of bullets...
A 9-mm caliber automatic!
It's the same person!
But... why is there a flashlight?
Hurry!
Seal off all exits!
Test everyone but the children
for traces of gunpowder!
No exceptions! That includes
me and every officer here!
And this fool too, of course!
That guy's still here?
But I don't see those two...
"In Surgery"
Inspector Megure.
What is Sato-san's condition?
One of the bullets stopped
right next to her heart.
They say she only has a 50-50
chance of pulling through...
Inspector, what about Ran?
Luckily, she suffered no external injuries,
but she's still unconscious.
She's in the room at the far end.
Ran is probably all right.
But I'm curious about that flashlight...
Could it have been...
Shiratori-kun, how is the investigation going?
We checked everyone for traces
of gunpowder, but we found nothing.
Nothing?!
We believe the shooter fled the
building before the exits were sealed.
- Any fingerprints on the gun?!
- Nothing there, either.
Chiba-kun, did you figure out
how the switchboard was rigged?
Yes. It appears it was set to
explode via a cell phone call.
There's something that has me curious.
The flashlight on the bathroom floor...
Did it belong to Sato-san?
I don't think so!
The cabinet doors under the vanity were open.
It was probably left in there...
with its light on.
What?! Then the shooter...
I see! Nobody would've noticed
it when the lights were on!
There's almost no question this is
related to "the" incident, then.
What's "the" incident?!
No, uhh...
Why won't you tell me?!
One misstep and Ran could've been shot!
Inspector!
- I have terrible news! It's Ran!
- What about her?!
She's conscious again,
but she's acting strange!
What?!
Ran-neechan!
Are you all right, Ran-neechan?
Who are you... little boy?
W-Whoa, now...
She can't even remember
her own name, much less us...
That can't be!
I'm Mori Kogoro, your father!
She's Kisaki Eri, your mother!
I don't know. I can't remember anything.
Ran...
Dr. Kazato, I'm sorry to bother you like this,
but there weren't any
psychiatrists on duty, so...
Do you know who you are?
Then, do you remember
what happened today?
No.
What's the capital of the United States?
Washington, D.C.
What's 5 times 8?
40.
Please click this ballpoint pen.
"Conference Room 4"
Retrograde amnesia?
Yes. It's a type of memory disorder
in which sudden illness or injury
leaves the sufferer unable to remember
anything prior to the infliction.
In your daughter's case, I believe
she received a strong mental shock
after witnessing Detective Sato
being shot before her very eyes.
So, will my daughter's memory return?!
I can't say anything at this point in time.
But I found no problems with her
knowledge about everyday life.
So she can live a normal life, then?!
Yes. But let's keep her here for
observation for a few more days.
It's only natural that
Ran would be shocked
if a detective she knew was
shot right in front of her...
But there had to be more to it than
that for her to lose her memory!
Something that would
pierce her mind even more!
They've finished operating on Sato-san.
They managed to remove the bullet,
but it's hard to say
if she'll survive or not...
I see...
Inspector! You still won't say
anything, even after all this?!
Shiratori! You know, too! Tell me!
We will arrest the person
responsible ourselves.
Damn it!
Say, Detective Chiba.
Did you check for fingerprints
on the flashlight in the bathroom?
Yeah. But we only found Ran-san's fingerprints.
We all assumed it was Sato-san
who had the flashlight,
but it appears it was actually Ran-san.
In which case, Ran would've felt
it was her fault Sato-san was shot.
And it's because of that shock
that she lost her memory?!
Ran...
Even if your memory
never comes back, I'll always...
...be your friend...
I'll tell you everything.
But, Inspector Megure! That's...
It's okay. If I get fired, I'll just
open a detective agency like Mori-kun.
Inspector...
Takagi-kun, watch Sato-kun.
Chiba-kun, you watch Ran-kun.
If anything happens, report immediately.
Yes, sir!
Last summer, the body of Jinno Tamotsu,
a doctor at Toto University
Hospital's 1st Dept. Of Surgery,
was found in his apartment.
The investigation was headed
by Inspector Tomonari,
my superior in Investigation Section 1.
Under him were Narasawa and Shiba,
who've been shot and killed.
Sato-kun was also working with them.
Mr. Jinno drank a lot of alcohol
and then cut his right jugular vein
with his own scalpel.
He died of blood loss.
The first person to find him
was his sister Tamaki-san,
an investigative reporter
who lives in a neighboring town.
Old man! She's...
She was at the hotel party!
Now I remember!
She came to see me once before!
Eh? She went to your office?
What did she tell you then?
Actually, I was quite intoxicated at the time,
so I can't remember what
she talked to me about at all...
I remember the incident
with this Jinno person!
Didn't the family of a patient
sue him for botching an operation
a few days before he died?
That's right.
He left a final message on his
word processor, apologizing for it,
so Inspector Tomonari concluded
it was most likely a suicide.
But his sister, Tamaki-san, disagreed.
She said he was a terrible doctor
who never cared about his patients,
and that he'd never kill himself
to apologize for a botched operation.
And a week before,
she apparently saw him arguing
with a purple-haired young
man in front of a warehouse.
Purple hair?!
Just to be sure, Inspector Tomonari
took Sato, Narasawa, and Shiba
to the warehouse.
It was a particularly hot day,
with temperatures topping 35°C [95°F].
It's locked!
Alright! Let's stake it out!
- You're over there, Shiba-kun!
- Yes, sir!
I can't believe this heat...
What's wrong, Inspector?!
He's having a heart attack! Call an ambulance!
Right!
- Don't!
- Eh?!
- We're in the middle of a stakeout!
- But...
I'll be fine!
I'll take a cab to the hospital!
Keep... watching the place!
But before long, Sato-kun
grew worried and went to look...
Inspector Tomonari!
Sato-kun took Inspector Tomonari
straight to Toto University Hospital.
However, he died during surgery...
- Sato-san's been gone a long time...
- Yeah...
Here he comes!
Damn, it's hot today!
- Let's go!
- Wait!
Do you know who that man is?!
Huh?
He's Superintendent Odagiri's son, Toshiya-san!
In the end, with Inspector
Tomonari's sudden death,
Jinno Tamotsu's death was deemed
a suicide, and the case closed.
His sister Tamaki-san
checked the guy out,
but Detective Shiba told her
he was unrelated to the case.
So that's what happened?
Incidentally, Inspector Tomonari
had a son named Makoto...
Oh! He was at the party!
He disappeared soon after, though...
Does he have something to do with this?
Yeah. It happened at the wake.
Why didn't you call an ambulance?
My father might still be alive if you had!
No, we only did what he said...
You're the ones who killed my father!
I'll never forgive you for this!
- Here you go, Conan-kun.
- Thanks.
Shortly after, both Detective
Narasawa and Detective Shiba
were transferred to
the district police station.
But Shiratori-kun noticed that
Sato-kun had started investigating
something on her own just recently.
She, Detective Narasawa, and Detective Shiba
started to re-investigate
that case from one year ago.
But it seems Sato-san wasn't
informed about the relationship
between Toshiya-kun and Jinno.
Detective Narasawa was
shot and killed shortly after.
Then, after Detective Shiba was killed too,
we realized they were targeted
because of the case one year ago.
From the police notebooks,
we deduced the killer was
connected to the police somehow.
Detective Takagi investigated the
inspector's son, Tomonari Makoto,
and I investigated the
superintendent's son, Toshiya-kun.
I felt there was a good chance
Sato-kun would be targeted next,
so I told her to have someone guard her...
...but she declined.
So that's why you talked
to her at the party, too?
Yes.
I've figured it out, Inspector!
The killer is Odagiri Toshiya!
Detectives Narasawa, Shiba, and
Sato had started to re-investigate
Jinno's case from last year,
so he decided to strike first!
But he wasn't the one who shot Sato-kun.
We found no traces of gunpowder on him.
Oh. I see.
More important is Tomonari Makoto.
We're unable to locate him.
Plus, he was seen nearby when
Narasawa and Shiba were shot.
And, given that he was at today's party...
We do know the killer
is left-handed, though...
C-Come to think of it,
Tomonari Makoto is left-handed, too!
Alright! Put Tomonari Makoto
on the wanted list!
Yes, sir!
Say, Inspector. How was this
Jinno person's jugular vein cut?
How? He was cut on the right side,
straight from top to bottom.
Then, if it was a murder,
his killer might've been left-handed.
- Eh?
- And how do you know that?!
- After all...
- To avoid being covered in blood.
To do that...
...you'd have to cut the right
jugular vein with your left hand.
Right, Conan-kun?
Y-Yeah.
I see!
No, but there's no connection
between Tomonari Makoto and Jinno.
If Jinno was murdered, it must've
been a different left-handed killer.
Toshiya-san is left-handed, too.
He lit a match with his left hand.
There's another. His father,
Superintendent Odagiri.
He's left-handed, too.
Don't be stupid! He couldn't
possibly be the killer!
L-Inspector?
"Beika Yakushino Hospital"
I'm Yoshida Ayumi!
Kojima Genta-kun, Tsuburaya
Mitsuhiko-kun, and Haibara Ai-san!
We're all Conan-kun's friends,
and we came because we're worried about you.
Thank you. But, I'm sorry.
I don't remember any of you.
No! I can't believe this!
You always played with us!
Do you not remember me, either?
I'm Agasa Hiroshi.
You know, the brilliant
scientist who lives next door
to your childhood friend
and classmate, Kudo Shinichi-kun!
Kudo... Shinichi?
You remember Shinichi-niichan?!
No... I don't.
Oh.
What is it, Haibara?
It felt like someone was
staring at us just now...
Must be my imagination.
I'm sorry. I'm a little tired.
That's okay. Get some rest.
Who's there?!
Damn!
What is it, Conan?
Old man! Do you think Ran-neechan
could've seen the killer's face
when Detective Sato was shot?!
What?!
If so, then the killer
might try to go after her!
I've been waiting for you.
Rest easy. Takagi-kun and Chiba-kun
will take turns guarding her.
Where is she now?
- My husband's with her.
- Alright. Let's go.
- Um, Kisaki-san?
- Yes?
Dr. Kazato says he'd like to
talk to you about your daughter.
Her MRI scan shows
no damage to the brain.
It appears your
daughter's amnesia occurred
as a way to save herself
from mental trauma.
Meaning if we take her to that
hotel and recreate the incident,
she'll regain her memory?
What are you talking about?!
There's no need to make her recall
something she doesn't want to!
Are you saying you don't care if
she never gets her memory back?!
I'm against anything
that makes her suffer!
Now, now. Forcing her to remember
something could harm her brain.
See?
Pardon me.
This is Kazato.
Okay. Understood. I'll give him a call.
If Ran did see the killer's face,
she's in danger
unless we restore her memory
and catch the person ASAP!
But just like the doctor says,
we can't force her to remember...
I'll just have to protect Ran myself!
Huh? He won't answer.
Sorry about that.
Doctor, is there any way to
restore her memory naturally?
It's common for people to suddenly
remember things while relaxed.
Understood.
Once Ran checks out,
I'm living in your office too.
What?!
I can take care of her that way,
and help her relax.
This isn't a joke!
You'll only stress me out more!
I don't care what happens to you!
This is all for Ran's sake!
Got that?!
This won't be good...
Ran-san, please don't push yourself
too hard to remember anything.
Okay?
Yes.
Please contact me if any
of her memory returns.
Understood.
You've lived in this town 17 years,
since you were born.
Recognize it?
This is your home.
"Mori Detective Agency..."
You'll get wet.
What's wrong, Ran?
She must not like puddles.
There was a lot of water when
Detective Sato was shot, too, so...
Pull up a little.
Right.
The second floor is the office.
I'm always solving difficult
cases at that desk there!
All you do there is drink beer and watch TV.
Here on the third floor is
the living room and the kitchen.
And over here is your room.
His name's Kudo Shinichi.
He's a real jerk who's trying to seduce you!
I'm not tryin' to seduce anyone!
Oh! You practice karate, Ran-neechan!
I know karate?
You won the city high school
championship! You don't remember?
No.
Oh.
But don't worry! I'll remember
everything sooner or later!
Yeah! Let's have something
good to eat tonight
to celebrate Ran getting out of the hospital!
In that case, maybe I'll cook
something up for old times' sake!
Oh? What's with you two?
W-W-What do you mean?
Y-Y-Your cooking...
I don't need any, then! I'm not hungry...
You don't need to hold back
to be polite, Conan-kun.
I'll work hard to make some scrumptious,
yummy beef stew for you!
That's the worst of all...
Huh? Where are you going, dear?
No, uhh, I completely forgot
that I promised to play Mahjong
with the neighbors tonight!
This is no time for Mahjong,
when your daughter is like this!
Or, what? Are you saying
you can't eat my cooking?
Whew! Ran's more cheerful than I thought!
She'll definitely be okay!
Ran...
Bodyguards? Mine?
We heard from Detective Takagi
that the killer might come after you!
We, the Junior Detective League,
have decided to protect you!
We call ourselves...
...the Ran-neechan Protection Squad!
Oh, geez...
I brought a squirt gun filled with hot sauce!
I brought a boomerang!
And I got handcuffs!
C'mon, now. Those kids' toys won't help...
Thanks, guys! I feel much safer!
As thanks, I'll treat you to
something nice and cold! Come on up!
Okay!
Hurray!
She still can't remember anything?
Nope.
Wouldn't it be better for you
if her memory never comes back?
Eh?
There'd be no need to worry about
her learning who you really are.
W-What did you say?!
If I could, I'd want
to lose my memory, too!
My sister's murder,
me joining the organization
and creating the poison...
How nice it would be to forget
everything and become Haibara Ai,
just an ordinary grade-schooler...
And then...
you and I...
...could always stay together...
Haibara... Are you...
Gotcha! Feeling any better?
Hi, Squirt!
Your new girlfriend?
And another annoying one shows up...
See! These are from when you
won the city karate championship!
Do you remember?
No.
He's...
Oh, Kudo-kun! He's your beau!
I'm not her beau!
She seems to recognize him.
Really, Ran-neechan?!
No.
- But...
- But?!
...I feel very nostalgic for some reason.
I don't know why, though.
Hey! Won't she remember
if she sees Shinichi-san?
Yeah! Bring him here!
I would if I could!
Say, he's the high school
detective who solves tough cases
all around the country, right?
I can't believe him! Where in the
world is he, while Ran's like this?!
Yes?
Ran-neechan, the bath's empty now.
Thanks.
Tell me, Conan-kun.
What's Kudo Shinichi like?
What's he like?
I think he probably thinks about you the most,
but can't just come out and say how he feels.
I think I'd like to meet him...
Hey, Ran. Want to go Ginza tomorrow?
Eh?
I get so annoyed when I'm around that man!
So let's go on a shopping spree to feel better!
You too, Conan-kun!
Yeah!
Are you all right?
Sato-san! Sato-san! Please say something!
Thank you!
Uhh...
Damn it!
Here it comes.
Ran!
"Beika Yakushino Hospital"
- Ran!
- Shh! He just gave her a sedative.
Is Ran alright?!
Only a few scratches, thankfully.
But I'm concerned this may make
her afraid of regaining her memory.
Takagi! What were you watching?!
I'm sorry!
But now we know for sure.
When Sato-kun was shot,
Ran-kun did see the shooter's face.
Listen! No matter what happens,
we must keep Ran-kun safe!
Yes, sir!
Keeping her safe isn't enough.
We have to go on the offensive!
After it happened, no one tested
positive for traces of gunpowder.
Is it really impossible to fire
a gun and leave no gunpowder traces?
Wait a minute!
If I remember right...
...that umbrella was buttoned up!
And after the incident...
...it was not only unbuttoned,
but in a different location, too!
And then, after Ran left the hospital...
Could it be?!
Eh? That was your umbrella, little boy?
Do you know where it is now?
I'm sorry. There was a hole
in it, so I threw it away.
Eh?!
I should've figured, after all this time...
No, I'm just kidding! I saved it!
Oh, geez...
Thanks!
Just as I thought!
I found the way to fire a gun
without leaving gunpowder traces!
It's not just Tomonari Makoto-san
and Jinno Tamaki-san now!
This makes even Toshiya-san,
and everyone at the party, a suspect!
This is it!
Now I see!
Tamaki-san was at the party
because she was tailing Toshiya!
Dammit! Why're you following
me around day after day?!
Does it bother you?
What?!
I'm going to find the proof
that you murdered him
in place of the two
police detectives you killed!
Trying to entrap him?
You're Jinno Tamotsu-san's sister,
Tamaki-san, right?
You found out he was the guy
arguing with your brother a year ago,
and that he didn't get interrogated
because his father's the
police superintendent, right?
Who are you, little boy?
Edogawa Conan. A detective.
Detective?
If you really did love your brother,
you might've held a grudge
against the three police detectives
who called your brother's
death a suicide and moved on.
I hated my brother!
I'm only investigating what
happened to know the truth!
Then let's take a risk and
raid the enemy's home base!
Eh?
He's trying out his sword
with an iai technique!
Whoa!
Jinno Tamaki-san, yes?
I have something for you.
For me?
I found it a month ago,
in my son Toshiya's room.
T. Jinno...
This is my brother's?
Yes.
I remembered the name, as it was
from Inspector Tomonari's last case
before he suddenly died
of a heart attack a year ago.
When I pressed Toshiya about it,
he confessed he learned Tamotsu-san
was selling drugs on the side,
and blackmailed him for it and money.
However, Toshiya wasn't in any
of the investigation documents.
So I ordered Detective Narasawa
to re-investigate the case.
Eh?! You, yourself,
ordered the re-investigation?!
After Detective Narasawa was killed,
Inspector Megure took over.
But if Detective Narasawa had
started re-investigating on his own,
you might've tried to keep
your son out of the picture, right?
Indeed, I also have a motive
for murdering all three.
Say, if you're serious
about uncovering the truth,
let me see the investigation documents!
I can't do that!
Uncovering the truth is
the job of us, the police!
But it's a real relief
that you weren't hurt!
Thank you. The doctor says I can leave now.
Say, Sonoko-san.
Quit that! Just "Sonoko" is fine!
What kind of boy is Conan-kun?
Eh?
He risked his life to save mine...
Yeah. He's strange.
He's real quick-witted for a kid.
Though if you ask me,
he's just an ordinary little brat!
I see.
Tropical Land's newly added
"Island of Wild and Ancient Times"
will undoubtedly thrill patrons!
I know that place...
Tropical Land?
Yeah! You and Shinichi-kun
went there together!
"Psychiatric Examination Room"
I see.
Your memory's very close to returning.
Doctor, if she actually visits
Tropical Land, will her memory return?
Yes, it is possible.
- I'll go there tomorrow.
- Eh?
Wait! I'm against this!
The killer might go after you again,
and it'll hurt you if
you remember the incident!
To be honest, I'm afraid of
remembering the incident myself.
But I can't stay like this.
I need to take that first step forward.
Ran...
You certainly are courageous, Ran-san!
With your outlook, you should
be fine if you visit Tropical Land!
Then could you at least wait
until the day after tomorrow?
I have work tomorrow. I can't...
Quit worrying! I'll go with her!
I'll put my life on the line to protect Ran!
Dear...
Ran! I'm coming, too!
Thanks!
But keep it a secret from Conan-kun.
Eh?
I think he'll come for sure if we tell him.
And I don't want to put
him in any more danger.
Alright.
- It got late so fast!
- Yeah.
Conan-kun.
If you wanna see the investigation
documents, I have copies.
Really?!
I am an investigative reporter!
They're in my apartment,
so I'll show 'em to you tomorrow.
Okay!
I'll be back later!
There he goes! Little does he know!
Okay! Let's head out, too!
Yes! Ran-oneesan is leaving!
Keeping watch all morning was worth it!
Do you suppose Edogawa-kun wasn't informed?
That's fine by me!
He's always beating us to the punch!
Listen, now! Nothing dangerous!
Follow the car in front of us!
Well? Figure anything out, Detective?
This notebook Detective Shiba is holding...
What about it?
If he pulled it from his breast pocket,
wouldn't his notebook
be turned the other way?
It's like so, and when you pull it
out of the pocket... You're right!
It's possible the killer pulled
the notebook out, not Detective Shiba!
Eh?! L-I see. That is possible.
Huh?
I'll find it!
I thought you were right-handed, Tamaki-san?
Eh? Oh, I was originally left-handed,
but switched to right-handed.
So when I'm thinking or smoking or whatever,
I sometimes use my left
hand without realizing it!
Without realizing it?
Come to think of it, back then...
Wait a minute! Does that mean...
Could it be?!
Is that what it meant?!
Say! Your brother worked at
Toto University Hospital, right?
Yeah, but I'm sorry, Conan-kun.
I have somewhere I have to go.
- That's all for today.
- Eh?
Bye, Conan-kun!
Tropical Land.
You got it!
I remember this place...
As I recall, when Shinichi
came here with you,
he solved a murder that
happened on a roller coaster.
Then let's ride it!
You might remember some more stuff!
Let's see...
The Mystery Coaster is on the
Island of Mystery and Fantasy.
You two take the front seat.
So you see? Conan Doyle
must've wanted to say this!
Huh?
No, nothing!
Oh! There's Ran-oneesan and the others!
Bah! I wanna ride it...
What are you talking about?!
We need to use this time to look
around for anyone suspicious!
- Let's go!
- Alright!
Say, wasn't Mori-kun afraid of heights?
Oh, no! T-Time out!
Um, are you all right?
- Ran! Want a cola?
- Sure!
Yay! Troppy balloons!
Urgh! Who made that stupid thing, anyway?!
Here! You must be thirsty!
Here's your cola!
T-Thanks!
You're Kudo Shinichi?
But... I still can't remember who you are.
Um, Mori-san...
- I need to use the restroom.
- Yeah.
Yay! Thank you!
The balloons are flying away!
Ran-san! Look out!
Stop!
Wait, children! Stop!
I won't let you escape!
Oops!
Eat this! Hot Sauce Squirt Gun!
You're Tomonari Makoto!
What is that?!
A knife!
That's...
Tomonari Makoto! You're under
arrest for attempted murder!
We did it!
- "The Ran-neechan Protection Squad..."
...is victorious!
M-Mori-san! I'm going to take
him directly to headquarters now!
Wait. I'm coming with you.
- Hurray!
- We did it!
There's no need to worry
about being attacked now,
and it'll be easier for you to
remember Shinichi without me here.
D-Da...
It's alright. You can call me that
once you remember everything.
Your detective league saved her!
That was excellent work!
He said we did excellent work...
- A great detective...
...praised us!
Alright! Now we can
have all the fun we want!
I wanna see the parade!
We can stay until nighttime, right, Doc?!
Yes. After all, Shinichi and Ran-kun
stayed until nighttime, too.
Hurray!
Is it really over now?
Hey, Ran! Let's go to the
Devil's Laboratory! It'll be fun!
Eh?! You're the famous Mori
Kogoro-san's assistant, little boy?!
Yeah!
If I help you, do you think
I could get Mori-san's autograph?!
Oh, me too!
Sure!
I can give you as many of that
old guy's autographs as you want!
Dr. Jinno, right?
I know it's not nice to say this,
but he was a creepy doctor.
That's for sure! He was a
tight-wad and had no skill at all!
He caused lots of problems
because of botched surgeries!
Hey, remember that heart attack
patient that got brought in?
Dr. Jinno cut the other surgeon's
hand during that operation!
Yeah! Yeah! And that's the reason
that patient couldn't be saved!
Tell me more about that!
It's just as I thought!
I gotta tell the old man right away!
Hello, this is the Mori Detective Agency.
The great Mori Kogoro is
currently busy, solving...
Damn!
Kisaki Law Office.
- This is Conan!
- Oh, Conan-kun?
Is Kisaki-sensei there?!
Her trial just ended,
and she left for Tropical Land.
Tropical Land?
Apparently, Ran-san is there, so...
Oh, no!
"Metro Police"
Well? Able to talk now?
I got a phone call from a man.
Said he'd tell me the truth
behind my father's death.
So I went to the intersection in Beika.
But the man never showed,
and Detective Narasawa was shot nearby!
When I returned home,
the man called again.
This time, he said to come to the
Midoridai Maison Park Apartments.
But again, he never showed up,
and Detective Shiba was found in the
basement parking lot, shot to death.
It was then I realized
I was set up by the killer!
That night, I stayed at a business hotel.
The next day, when
I checked my phone messages,
a woman calling herself Detective Sato
had left a message telling me to
come to the Beika Sun Plaza Hotel.
She said she'd arrest me
for murder if I didn't come.
But, when I went,
the place was filled with police.
So I left, as if escaping.
But then Detective Sato was...
Why didn't you tell the police right away?
Because I couldn't trust them,
after what happened to my father!
I decided to ask the great Mori-san
for help, so I hung around him.
Are you saying you didn't
approach Ran-kun at Tropical Land?!
That's right...
I was going to talk to Mori-san...
Hold on, now! You had a knife!
For protection.
The killer might try to kill me...
W-Whoa, now...
Then... the killer is someone else?!
And he has a female conspirator!
Ran... is in danger!
"Labyrinth of Ice and Fog"
Yeah! This should take me there!
Um, is the observatory empty?!
Yeah! Everyone's busy watching the parade!
Thanks!
Welcome to the Labyrinth of Ice and Fog!
Ran! Where?! Where are you?!
Genta and the others?!
I didn't know they came too!
Which means Ran is nearby!
That's him!
Ran!
Oh, yeah! The detective badges!
Genta! Mitsuhiko! Ayumi!
Hey! Do you read me?! Respond!
Conan-kun? I read you!
Guess where we are!
Don't be too shocked, now! Tropical Land!
Hey! Calm down and listen closely!
The killer is there with a gun, to kill Ran!
Eh?!
Tell Ran to go through crowded
areas and get out of Tropical Land!
Hey! Are you listening?!
- Ran-oneesan! Run!
- There's a gun pointed at you!
Watch out!
Doc!
People around me are
in danger, because of me...
D-Don't leave, Ran-kun!
The killer wants to get you all alone!
Ran-kun?! Ran-kun?!
Damn!
Ran's on the Island of Dreams
and Fairytales, the next place over!
The only way to get there is...
Next group, please!
H-Hey! Little boy!
There it is!
Conan-kun!
You're safe now, Ran-neechan!
Let's blend in with the crowd
and get out of here!
This way!
Dammit!
So it doesn't matter what happens
to anyone, as long as Ran dies?!
Help! There's a crazy person!
- Jump into the boat!
- Eh?!
Hey, you!
Conan-kun! Where did
you learn to drive a boat?!
My old man taught me in Hawaii!
Eh?
Hey! We're safe now, wouldn't you say?
No!
My cola!
Cola?!
20 minutes to 9:00!
Conan-kun! Waterfall!
Hold on!
Let's hurry!
Just a little more! Hang in there!
Y-Yeah...
Damn! He already caught up!
Climb up and hide behind the rocks! Hurry!
C-Conan-kun?!
No one's here; this place is closed
at night. You can show yourself.
You're quite cautious.
But there's no point in hiding...
...because I figured out what Detective
Narasawa's message really meant.
He didn't grab the left side of his
chest to indicate the police notebook!
He was indicating his heart!
One of the letters in the Japanese
word for "psychiatry" is heart!
Isn't that right, Dr. Kazato Kyosuke?
When did you figure out it was me?
The first time I thought, "Oh?"
Was when I remembered the phone.
First, right-handed people
don't dial with their left hand.
Yes. You were left-handed.
I see. That was careless of me.
7 years ago, you were the best young
surgeon at Toto University Hospital.
But one day, during an operation
handled by you and Jinno-san,
he accidentally cut your
left wrist with a scalpel.
Because of that accident, your
so-called "Golden Hand" was ruined.
Because of your pride,
you abandoned the scalpel
and switched from surgery to psychiatry.
Ever since, perhaps out of pride,
you lived as a right-handed person.
Exactly.
Never imagined just dialing
a phone would get me found out.
You transferred to Beika Yakushino
Hospital as a psychiatrist,
and something happened between
you and Jinno-san one year ago.
I ran into him again, just by coincidence!
He invited me over for
a drink at his apartment.
Drunk, I unleashed the suspicion
I had held in my heart for six years.
I asked if that accident
had been on purpose.
You're such a pushover.
It had been on purpose after all!
That's when the bloodlust arose!
He was being sued for
a botched operation at the time,
so he had plenty of reason to kill himself.
As expected, the investigation
deemed it a suicide.
But you knew the case
was going to be re-opened.
Yes, I heard from Detective Narasawa,
who transferred to the Beika Police.
The death of his partner, Detective
Tomonari, was a shock for him,
so he came to me for counseling.
I also learned from him that
Tomonari Makoto blamed the police!
So, before the re-opening of the
case brought the police to you,
you shot the three detectives
and lured Tomonari Makoto-san
to the scenes to pin the blame on him?
That's right. For Detective Narasawa
and Detective Shiba, I called him myself.
For Detective Sato...
...you edited a tape you recorded
of a female patient. Right?
Precisely.
You heard that Detective Narasawa
died holding his notebook
from Inspector Shiratori, didn't you?
I am his doctor, after all.
And then, to suggest it was the
detective's son, Narasawa Makoto,
you purposely put the police
notebook in Detective Shiba's hand!
Impressive work, Conan-kun!
But there's no proof that I did it.
When Detective Sato was shot, no
gunpowder traces were found on me.
If you'd like, I can
explain that trick for you!
What?!
After the police arrest you, that is.
- This way!
- Eh?!
"Authorized Personnel Only"
He'll be waiting for us at that exit!
Where is this?
The main isle of the Island
of Adventure and Frontier!
We passed under the ocean
from that small island!
Really?
Let's go!
We still haven't finished our discussion!
Damn! He followed us in a boat!
I can't have you revealing that trick, now.
It'd make me one of the possible
people who shot Detective Sato.
Even if Ran gives her eyewitness testimony,
you can still play innocent due to
the lack of gunpowder traces, huh?
That's right. Because Ran-kun
only saw me for a second.
But I'd rather nip these
dangerous buds early on!
So let's hear if your theory is right or not.
My pleasure!
First, after you blacked
out the hotel's 15th floor,
you put on surgical gloves
and took an umbrella you prepared
in advance to the ladies' room.
You made a hole near the tip
of the umbrella ahead of time.
You stuck your gun through that hole and fired.
In short, the umbrella protected
you from the gunpowder and smoke.
That's why you didn't test
positive for traces of gunpowder!
I assume you flushed the gloves
down one of the men's toilets?
Correct, Conan-kun!
It seems you will have to die.
C-Conan-kun...
- Tell me! Why?!
- Eh?!
Why are you going so far to protect me?
Tell me... Why?
- Because I love you!
- Eh?!
Because I love you! More than anyone...
...on this Earth!
Jump!
- Take a deep breath!
- Eh?!
Hurry!
Thanks!
Mr. Grownup!
Yeah.
Damn it!
46 seconds!
He's here!
What do you say we end it here, Conan-kun?
Besides, you have no place left to run...
C-Conan-kun!
L-I'm fine! It only grazed my arm!
I just told you. There's no place left to run!
If you kill Ran now, won't Tomonari
Makoto-san be proven innocent?
That's right. I planned to eliminate
Tomonari before he got arrested...
...but that can't be helped now.
Now, then. I guess this
should be "ladies first"?
Ten. Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
- Five.
- Some kind of magic charm?
Three!
Two!
One!
No, Ran-san!
Detective Sato!
Here! You must be thirsty!
One!
Distance yourself from me!
You're through once the
fountains stop! Give it up!
A childish trick!
There you are!
Die!
Take this!
♪ I sadly watched the rain
pound on you as you bent over ♪
Conan-kun...
Ran! Could it be?!
♪ I sadly watched the rain
pound on you as you bent over ♪
♪ If there was only one umbrella
in this world, I'd find it for you ♪
Damn it! I'll take care of you first!
♪ If there was only one umbrella
in this world, I'd find it for you ♪
No... way...
I remember everything now!
I remember that you shot Detective Sato,
and that I was champion of
the city karate tournament!
Karate... champion?!
♪ I can't do anything but I can't
get drenched in your place, either ♪
♪ I beg of you, please confess your worries to me ♪
W-Wow!
- Ran!
Mom! Dad!
Y-You...
Your memory's back?!
Do you remember me too, then?!
Of course, Suzuki Sonoko, my friend for life!
Ran...
Ran! Thank goodness!
So he was the killer after all?
Superintendent Odagiri re-opened
the case himself, and filled us in.
That's no fair, Conan!
Catching him yourself!
Don't be silly! Conan-kun wanted
to keep you out of harm's way!
- That's exactly it!
- We're in the same detective league!
Sorry, sorry!
Huh? You're bleeding, Conan-kun...
- Eh?
- Here.
Thanks.
Things are well, for now.
Yeah...
Well done, Mr. Great Detective!
Tamaki-san! What are you doing here?!
I came to keep an eye on Toshiya.
He played here today.
Turned out to be pointless, though!
Still, what was that about putting
your life on the line to protect Ran?
It was Conan-kun and Dr. Agasa
who risked their lives for her!
N-No, uhh...
In any case, what a relief that she's alright!
- Seriously?!
- Yes!
Everyone! Sato-san is conscious again!
There's no need to worry anymore!
Oh! Really?!
Sato-san!
This is wonderful, Takagi-san!
That's great!
That wraps everything up!
Don't be stupid!
There's still Toshiya's extortion case!
His victim is dead now,
but give him a good
wringing and get all the facts!
Understood, sir!
It would seem you were
the first to uncover the truth.
Just who are you?
Need not to know.
I'm just a regular grade-schooler!
If there was no impurity in this world,
we could've loved each other
without changing form
Why does time divide people?
Please, stay by my side, just for now
I grow stronger because I have you
The vowed ring is so sparkly and pretty
You will realize little dreams too
You are the one, my heart is filled
I grow stronger because I have you
The vowed ring is so sparkly and pretty
You will realize little dreams too
You are the one,
someday they will come true
Thanks, Conan-kun!
You said those things earlier to
help me get my memory back, right?
Eh?
You heard it at the hotel, right?
How my dad proposed to my mom!
"I love you. More than anyone on this Earth."
So you said the same thing on purpose!
- The old guy said that?!
- Huh? It wasn't on purpose?
N-No, uhh, it was.
I thought so!
After all, the two of us have
too much of an age difference!
But it made me happy! Good night!
Good night...
Ah, well.
Wait a minute! That means...
...I thought up the same thing he did?!
Ugh...