Mom?!
Stay away, Ran!
Just a dream...
Eh? You dreamed I was shot?
Is that why you called me
so early in the morning?
Oh, come on, I was worried!
Sometimes even lawyers get people
who have grudges against them...
You're just being paranoid, Ran.
It's because of all
those crimes you've seen
that you have dreams like that.
But I'm glad you're all right!
Oh, yeah! You were a little younger
in my dream, you know!
My! How rude! I'll have
you know I'm still young!
Oh, I'm sorry! Please forgive my rudeness!
Very well, then!
Okay, so 7:00 tonight, right?
Dad and Conan-kun can't wait, either!
I wonder... Does she remember?
Conan-kun...
What's goin' on? Why're you up so early?
Oh, no reason. Sorry for waking you up.
Oh, it's tonight! Our dinner date
with Ran's mom...
Man, I can't stand that lady...
I'm high school detective Kudo Shinichi.
I went with old friend and classmate,
Mori Ran, to an amusement park
where I witnessed a suspicious deal
with a man dressed in black!
I was so absorbed with watching the deal
that I didn't notice a second man
sneak up from behind me!
He forced me to take a poison,
and when I woke up...
...my body had shrunk!
If they learned Kudo Shinichi was alive,
they might go after me again,
putting all the people around me in danger!
Per Dr. Agasa's advice,
I decided to conceal my identity.
When Ran asked my name,
I quickly answered, "Edogawa Conan."
To get information on the men,
I wound up living with Ran
and her detective father.
Yes. This guy is Ran's father...
...and the now-incredibly
famous detective, Mori Kogoro.
But he's really a bonehead detective...
...and you all know who's really
solving the crimes, right?
The secret behind that is in
the two gadgets Dr. Agasa made for me!
The first... is this!
The Stun-Gun Wrist-Watch!
Pressing the button while using
the aiming device on the cover
will launch a tranquilizer needle
that can knock a person out instantly!
Next is the Voice-Changing Bow-Tie!
By adjusting the dials on the back,
I can produce all types of voices,
from children to adult!
For offensive items, I have
the Power Assisted Kick Shoes!
They use electricity and magnetic fields
to stimulate my feet muscles
and maximize my kick power!
To chase down criminals, I have
the Turbo-Engine Skateboard!
And an unexpectedly sweet item
are these Elasticity Suspenders!
One press of a button, and the rubber
will expand or contract!
It's a really unique gadget!
I can't ID the men in black yet,
but other cases won't wait for me!
Even when I'm small, my mind
remains that of a sharp detective!
There is always only one truth!
"Mori Kogoro-Beika Street, Beika City"
Genta-kun! You're gonna eat that one, too?!
Who cares how many I eat?!
This one's a Black Choco Bar!
It's got a grownup taste!
Oh?! Really?!
Yeah, right.
Geez, what's taking him so long?
Look! Look!
"You two are a perfect match!"
Conan-kun and I are a perfect match!
A-are you sure that game's not broken?!
B-but more importantly, Genta-kun!
Card fortune-telling is
obviously a pack of lies!
Now let's check Conan-kun's!
His birthday is...
Hey, now.
Don't be tellin' people's fortunes
without their permission.
"You and the girl of your heart
are rapidly approaching!"
It must be talking
about me and Conan-kun!
"An 'A' is in your future"
- An "A" is in your future?
"A"?!
Oh, geez. How old of a game is that thing?
Hey. What does "A" mean?
The letter A, you see,
is the one before the letter B...
So it means fried shrimp!
("AB" sounds like "ebi" which is shrimp)
Oh. So it doesn't mean "kiss".
(It actually does mean "kiss")
Sorry! Sorry! I overslept! ...Huh?
...Geez! What took you so long, Doc?!
Sorry...
Awesome!
Look at all the planes!
I hear you can even play a
helicopter flight simulator here!
- That sounds like fun!
- Yeah!
Too bad!
Why's that, Conan?
It says here only fifth graders
and up can do the flight simulator!
Aww, that's no fun.
Sorry. I played it to death
when I got into 5th grade.
In that case, how about I tell
you all an interesting story?
Hey. We're in for a long story
if we don't stop him now.
Leave it to me.
The "Pegasus" from Greek mythology is-
Tadah! And now for a quiz!
Huh? What're you doing?
Three people who were born
on New Year's Day, April Fool's Day,
and Children's Day all
got together and formed a club!
So, what was their club's name?
Here's a hint: it's a flying animal,
much like the Pegasus!
A flying animal?
Oh? You figured it out, Conan-kun?
Of course! You just need to
add their birthdays, right?
- Eh?
- Birthdays?
January 1st, April 1st,
May 5th... October 7th?
Yep! October 7th!
It's the Tonakai (Reindeer)!
(to = 10, na =7, kai = club)
And they fly while pulling
a sled on Christmas, right?
Correct! You're so smart, Conan-kun!
Hey! Isn't that Shishido Eimei?!
- So cool!
"Mori Detective Agency"
- Thank you!
- Next, please!
"To Mori Ran"
Alright! Here you go!
Thank you so much! I'm a
big fan of yours, Nishina-san!
Please continue to write
lots of delicious books!
That's a unique comment. Thank you.
He's even hotter than he is in pictures!
His type is my favorite!
You're so silly, Sonoko...
- What a reckless driver!
- Isn't that...
It is Osanai Nana, the model!
I have no interest in women.
Let's get some tea!
What time do you have
dinner with your mom?
7:00.
Did you set it up again this time too?
Yeah.
You sure have it rough, too.
What was it, ten years ago
when your mom left?
Yeah. When I was seven...
...I remember them having a big argument.
Apparently they split
because of personality conflicts.
And then in no time flat...
...your mom began to flourish
as a lawyer, right?
In contrast, your dad quit his job
as a police detective,
and became a lousy private eye instead.
Wha?
Yeah! Your dad's suddenly
all famous and stuff now,
but I bet he would've ruined himself
by now had you not been there.
I don't think so, but my mom
was really with-it in that regard.
I'm back!
Welcome back!
Huh? He's still not ready?
He went to play mahjong
during lunch and just got back now!
Geez! Why do I hafta eat dinner with Eri?!
Please quit complaining
and get ready already.
I'm here at the house
of Asahi Katsuyoshi-san,
owner of Aqua Crystal,
the aquatic recreation center opening
today by the Toto Bay!
Conan-kun.
I'll change too!
Sorry, Mom! We ran a little late!
That's all right. I'm sure "someone"
was busy playing mahjong.
She's as sharp as ever.
I gotta watch what I say around this lady...
Hello, Conan-kun!
H-hello!
You're so scatterbrained, Tsuji-san!
Oh! Long time, no see, Mori-san!
Oh! Tsuji-san!
Who's Mori?
You know, the detective.
- The famous detective?!
- Mori Kogoro?!
Yes. I am detective Mori Kogoro.
Oh, Tsuji-san! Let me introduce my family!
This is my wife Eri,
and my daughter Ran.
And that's Conan, the mooch.
Isn't there any other way to say that?!
I'm Tsuji. I played with Mori-san
in a pro-amateur golf tournament.
That reminds me, Tsuji-san.
Doesn't the All-American Open
begin next Thursday?
Yes! I basically practiced an
entire year for this one tournament!
This year, I will make it
to the top ten for sure!
I look forward to it!
But sometimes it's important
to take a breather,
so I thought I might take the girls
out for a flight tomorrow.
Tsuji-san here also owns and
pilots his own helicopter, you see.
Say! I'm planning to fly
the following Thursday, too!
Why don't you come along?
Wow! Really?!
Sounds wonderful!
Yay!
No, uhh, flying isn't really my thing,
so maybe some other time.
Oh? That's too bad.
He's no fun.
That man's name is Sawaki-san,
and he's known my mom and dad
since they were young.
What's that grape badge for?
That's the symbol of a sommelier.
Oh, a sommelier is someone like
Sawaki-san who specializes in wine.
What's that around his neck?
That's a "tastevin".
It's for taste-testing wine!
Whoa, you really know your stuff.
I read about it in Nishida-san's books!
For example, red wine is
best at room temperature,
and white wine and rosé are best chilled!
It's true that many people say that,
but a wine's best temperature is
really up to personal preference.
Excellent.
Light red wine is actually
quite delicious when chilled.
The key is that a wine's astringency
is diminished when cooled.
Really?
Still, I can't believe you're old enough
to be interested in that sort of thing now.
That just means that
we've gotten that much older.
That's for sure.
They seem to be getting along well now!
Oh, Conan-kun! Your mouth's all messy!
N-no, that's okay...
Come on, now! Don't move!
"An 'A' is in your future"
An "A" is in your future?
Sheesh! Kids are such a pain!
Urgh!
That was delicious.
The wine and food here tastes
just like it did back then!
Say. Do you remember?
When we first came to
this restaurant 15 years ago,
you gave me a present.
Yeah. Your favorite Zigoba chocolates.
And then we ate them all on a bench
at Beika Park on our way home.
Oh, that's right.
Towako-san!
Who's he?!
Isn't that Peter Ford?
You know. He often
hosts TV shows and stuff.
Dammit! What's she doing with him?!
Who's Towako-san?
She runs a hostess club in Ginza.
She's been extra generous whenever I've-
I should be going now.
Already? I thought we might
have some coffee back-
I'm sorry. I still have work to finish.
Thank you for the meal.
Mom!
Dad!
Towako-san disappeared somewhere!
The old guy never learns...
Come on in.
"Megure Juzo"
"Megure Jusan"?
It's read "Juzo".
Oh!
Oh, Genta-kun!
So Inspector Megure's name is Juzo, huh?
Oh, Mori-kun! You came all this way?
And everyone else, too?
We were all just about to go hiking.
Inspector. How is your injury?
Luckily, it missed a vital spot,
so there's no danger to his life,
but they say he'll need to
stay here for a few days.
Hey, Inspector.
Why do you always have a hat on?
Oh, uh, does it really matter?
- I bet he's barely got hair!
- He could have huge bumps!
We believe a handgun-type
crossbow was used.
We're investigating this
from two directions:
whether he was attacked specifically,
or just for fun as he passed by.
Hey, old inspector guy!
Didn't you have a gun?!
And you still let him get away?
Of course he wouldn't have
a gun on him while jogging!
Plus, even if I had had one, I'm a
horrible shot, unlike Mori-kun here.
Eh?! My dad is good with guns?!
Enough to have been one of
the best shots on the entire force!
I guess everyone's good at something...
However, something odd was found
where the crossbow was fired.
Here it is.
- What is it?
- It looks like a Western sword.
Huh?! I've seen this somewhere before!
But where?
- Good morning!
That's a pretty broach.
Here is your schedule for today, Sensei.
And I found this in the mailbox downstairs.
Oh, Zigoba!
Those are your favorite
Swiss chocolates, aren't they?
Ah! So he...
But I don't see the sender's name...
It's all right. I know
who's responsible for it.
Wow!
Water! Water...
Sensei!
How's my mother?!
Rest easy!
We flushed her stomach immediately,
so there's no danger to her life!
Thank goodness...
Was it poison, then?
Yes. We believe it was
agrochemical in type.
Mom!
Mom...
Ran...
Eri...
You're here too, dear?
Are you okay, lady?
Even you, Conan-kun?
Thank you. I'm okay now.
Just to be safe, she should
probably stay here for today.
Sounds good to me.
Still, first the inspector, and now Eri...
Is this just coincidence?
Incidentally, I hear she collapsed
the moment she ate some chocolate?
Yes. It was apparently
in the agency's mailbox.
Zigoba!
A-and... this paper flower!
You don't mean...
the same person did this?!
Huh? That flower...
Where?! Where have I seen it?!
But why would someone so cautious
eat poisoned chocolate?
Yeah. The old man got Ran's mom
mad at dinner the other night.
Apparently she mistook it as his apology.
Ah.
Here you are! Repairs complete!
Who pulled this prank?!
Doc! Don't open it!
Doc!
I'm fine! Go after him, Shinichi!
But!
Go, Shinichi! Go after him!
Got it!
Which way did he go?!
Ayumi and Genta live
down this left street...
Alright!
Oh, Conan-kun!
A black off-road motorcycle?
What's a black pot-holed motorcycle?
That's it! That's the
off-road motorcycle, Genta-kun!
C- Conan!
Roger that!
So he did turn left!
Conan-kun! He just turned right,
toward Beika Station!
Roger that!
Alright! I gotta beat him there!
Yes! Found ya!
Oh, no, you don't! I'm not
letting you get away!
Are you okay, lady?!
Thank you!
What's this?
That's it! I figured it out!
Playing cards?
Yeah.
The culprit is doing these crimes
to match the pictures on the cards.
Inspector Megure was attacked first,
and his name is Juzo, right?
It's written as "thirteen",
thus the King of Spades!
Doesn't this king's sword look
like the one found at the scene?
Next, Ran's mother's name, Kisaki,
means "Queen" in English.
Hence the Queen of Spades.
This queen's flower is the same one
that was on the chocolate box!
He's right! They're the same!
But how are Dr. Agasa
and "eleven" related?
The doc's name is Agasa Hiroshi,
and the "shi" in his name
is a combination of 10 and 1!
Hence the Jack of Spades.
"Jack" originally refers to soldiers,
thus this sword-like object...
They're the same! No doubt about it!
But why playing cards? And why spades?
Spades refer to death.
Similarly, hearts refer to love,
diamonds refer to money,
and clubs refer to happiness.
Then is the culprit planning to
follow the playing cards in order
and kill people with the
numbers 13 to 1 in their names?
More specifically, people connected to you.
But who would do this?
Our only clue was the
motorcycle's license plate number,
but it turned out to be stolen.
Inspector!
What are you doing here?
I heard that first Eri-san was attacked,
then Dr. Agasa too...
But what about your wound?
It's been sewed up! I'm fine!
I heard everything. The culprit
is most likely Murakami Joe.
Murakami Joe?!
Who is he?
A maverick gambling dealer.
He committed a murder ten years ago,
and was just released
one week ago on parole.
A gambling dealer?
A person who deals out cards
to gambling patrons.
This is Murakami Joe, 10 years ago.
Murakami, huh...
It's true that I wouldn't be surprised
if he held a grudge against me.
Why's that?
Because I arrested him.
Hold on! It's only natural
that policemen arrest criminals!
That's true, but...
Actually, I have heard
about that incident.
If I'm not mistaken, after he was
taken to the police station...
Shiratori-kun! We don't
need to hear the story!
But why wouldn't Murakami Joe
come straight after me?
He could deal with me directly...
Probably to make you suffer.
So as to ruin you slowly but surely.
Say, is there anyone you know
with a "ten" in their name?!
They might be the next person
to be attacked!
Ten... “Juu”... “To”...
Towako-san!
- Welcome.
Oh! Mori-sensei!
Towako-san!
You're all right!
"All right?" Did something happen?
Umm, Shiratori-san. What were you
going to say back at the hospital?
You know, about that Murakami guy!
Oh. Well, I guess I'll tell you
since you could find out easily enough.
I heard this from a superior officer.
Ten years ago, when Mori-san
was a police detective,
he and Inspector Megure-
Or was he still an
assistant inspector back then?
In any case, the two of them
arrested Murakami Joe for murder.
While they were interrogating him
at the police station,
Murakami said he wanted
to use the restroom.
Mori-san and the inspector
ordered an officer to take him there,
then took a smoke break
in front of the interrogation room.
Just then, you and your mother
arrived to bring a change of clothes.
That's when it happened.
Murakami managed to steal
the officer's gun in the restroom.
I remember.
Just then, I...
Get a car ready!
This woman and I have a
rendezvous at the ends of Hell!
Mom!
Ran! Stay away!
Mori-kun.
What's on your mind?
Oh, nothing!
You're saying he shot her?!
I had forgotten until just now!
It must've been something
you didn't want to remember.
But... But why would Dad shoot her?!
He must've been really
confident about his skill.
Confident he could miss the hostage
and hit only the criminal...
But the bullet missed
and hit your mother instead.
Apparently, the fact he shot
without concern for the hostage
caused quite some trouble for him
at the police station, too...
I believe it was soon afterward
that your father left the force.
Hello?
Hey, Ran! Been a while!
Shinichi?!
Dr. Agasa filled me in on everything.
Sounds like some bad stuff is going down.
It's much more than "bad"!
Where are you?! Come back right away!
Sorry, I'm in the middle of a case here.
I won't be back for a while.
Oh...
Don't get all glum on me!
But the doc and the inspector
gave me a summary of what's up,
so if I figure anything out,
I'll call right away!
Tell me. Would you shoot, Shinichi?
I found out why my mom really left my dad.
The Kogoro-san shot your mom, huh...
I don't care how confident he was...
I can't believe what he did.
You would never do anything
like that, right, Shinichi?!
Good question... I dunno.
But even if it's a fact
that your dad shot your mom,
are you sure that equals
the truth behind it?
What do you mean?!
That doesn't make sense!
Anyways, that's all I can say.
Cheer up, Ran!
Later!
Strongly...
Wait!
Shinichi?! Shinichi?!
Strongly...
Gently...
The truth...
Inspector! I'll watch the emergency exit!
Wait! Mori-kun!
He gets really fired up when
there's a pretty woman involved...
The old guy never came home...
Still, why would Murakami Joe leave
clues that point straight to him?
Is he trying to challenge
the old guy and the police?
But how did Murakami research
his acquaintances from behind bars?
He even knew Ran's mother's
favorite brand of chocolate...
"Tsuji Hiroki"
Tsuji Hiroki...
Tsuji...
"Ten"
Tsuji Hiroki? The pro golfer?
Yes! Conan-kun noticed it,
but Tsuji's name has a "ten" in it!
Tsuji...
She's right! There is one!
I called his home, but he left
for the heliport 30 minutes ago!
Got it!
Contact the station and have them
send someone to keep watch here.
Yes, sir!
Conan-kun! Let's go, too!
Let's go, Mori-kun!
Go? To get breakfast?
Dad!
Hey, you! What're you doing here?!
Don't give us that!
We're involved in this too, you know!
I'm your daughter!
So, people connected to Mori-san
are being attacked one by one?
Yes. Counting down from 13.
And since you're #10,
you're in danger now!
Anyways, it'd be wise to
cancel your flight for today.
I'll be fine!
If you're that worried, why don't
you and Mori-san come with me?
No, flying isn't really-
Incidentally, where is
your flight to today?
Toto Airport. With other places
along the way, though.
When did you submit your flight plan?
Hmm... The day before yesterday,
at the Aviation Bureau.
Inspector.
There's a chance Murakami
is lying in wait at Toto Airport.
Alright! You head for
Toto Airport in the car!
Yes, sir!
Mori-kun! Just to be safe,
we're going to ride the helicopter, too!
Ran-kun! I know how you feel,
but this is as far as you go.
But!
Fine.
Inspector! I'd prefer to go
with Detective Shiratori in the car!
Are you trying to run away on your own?!
I, uhh, need to use the restroom!
I- Inspector! I don't want to die too!
Get in! If you die, we'll die together!
So we are gonna die!
Well, I'm off.
Conan-kun. We should get going-
Huh? Where are you?!
He couldn't be!
One sheep! Two sheep!
Is that an anti-crashing spell?
- Conan-kun!
- When did you get in here?!
I always wanted to try sitting
next to a pilot's seat!
Welcome to my cockpit!
We're scheduled to fly over your place
on Beika Street, you know!
Yay! That's great!
We have no choice.
We can't exactly go back now.
But if you cause any trouble,
I'm tossin' you out!
Nothing seems out of the ordinary...
Whatcha lookin' at?
You're in a helicopter here!
Take a look outside!
Is something the matter?
Not at all.
Say, you applied some eyedrops earlier.
Do you always use them?
Yeah, when I'm driving, or when
I'm piloting my helicopter.
Beika Street's coming up now!
So it is!
Mori-kun! There's your place, too!
I don't wanna look!
What's wrong?!
It's too bright! I can't open my eyes!
Say what?!
Wait! Were those eyedrops-!
- Does that mean...
Mister! We're drifting to the left!
M- Mori-kun! Do you know how to fly?!
Of course I don't!
We can't stay in the air like this!
I gotta find a place we can land!
Teitan Elementary! Alright!
Huh?!
I'm gonna land us in the schoolyard!
You handle the pedals
and corrective measures!
Wha?! You idiot! No! Stop!
Are you trying to kill us?!
Don't worry! I did lots of flight simulator
practice when I was a kid!
B-but you still are a kid...
Tsuji-san! We're gonna crash
if we don't do something now!
Help me out!
Alright! Let's do it!
A-are you serious?!
Elevation, 300 feet!
Speed, 40 knots! Go ahead!
H-here goes!
Elevation, 200 feet! Speed, 30 knots!
Press the right pedal 10 degrees!
The schoolyard is dead-ahead!
Distance, 500 feet!
Hey, Genta! Do you read me?! Genta!
Conan?!
I'm about to emergency land a helicopter!
Get everyone out of there!
Helicopter?
Everyone! Run! A helicopter's
about to crash!
Like hell it's gonna crash!
We're spinning left!
Hit the right pedal hard!
Oh no! We're in a downwash!
It really did crash!
Is Conan-kun in there?!
I'm alive!
Conan-kun!
Are you all right, Tsuji-san?!
The fuel is leaking!
- What?!
It exploded!
Aren't helicopters expensive?!
Don't just the rotors alone
cost 10 million yen?
How many boxed eel lunches is that?
I'm glad everyone is all right.
"Agasa Hiroshi"
But, Doc! Conan's unfair!
He got to pilot a real helicopter
all by himself...
That's not the issue here!
We just about died, you know!
About that...
Tsuji-san's vitamin eyedrops had
been switched with dilation drops.
Dilation drops?
Medicine used to open up the pupils
to treat pseudomyopia and such.
Ah. So that's why the sunlight
overwhelmed his eyes...
Except the ones Tsuji-san used are
to treat something called "iritis".
Iritis?
How are they different?
Pseudomyopia drops take effect
in 5 minutes, and don't last long.
Conversely, iritis drops take a
half hour to work, and last a long time.
A long time?
It varies per person, but they usually
dilate the eyes for 10 to 14 days.
That long?!
Then what about Thursday's
All-American Open?!
He probably has no choice but to cancel...
Say, when did the culprit
switch the eyedrops?
About that...
This morning, after Tsuji-san
took his car out of the garage,
he apparently applied
his eyedrops in the car.
Immediately after, he heard glass break,
so he left the eyedrops on the
center console and went back inside.
Apparently, a rock had been
thrown through a window.
A rock?
That's what happened to Dr. Agasa!
However, Tsuji-san figured
it was just some kid's prank,
so he had the maids
take care of it and left.
There's no question that
the culprit threw the rock!
And Tsuji-san's eyedrops were switched
while he was in the house!
Yes. Most likely.
Inspector.
There is no doubt that
Murakami Joe is responsible.
We found this.
The 10 of Spades...
Mori-kun! "Nine" is the
next one to be attacked!
Do you know anyone with
a "nine" in their name?!
- I can't think of anyone. I do know an "eight" though.
- Eight?
Sawaki-san, a sommelier.
"Sawaki Kohei"
"Sawaki Kohei" His name is Kohei-san, and the
upper part of his "ko" is "eight"!
"Ko" His name is Kohei-san, and the
Alright! Let's meet this Sawaki fellow!
So this Murakami person is attacking
your acquaintances one by one
to get revenge on you, Mori-san?
Yes.
Still, you certainly do
seem calm, Mori-san...
Oh, I'm "five", so I still have
lots of time until I get attacked!
Wine...
That's called a "wine cooler".
It keeps wine at the proper temperature.
There sure is a lot in it!
Sawaki-san's family has
an orchard in Yamanashi,
and he has hundreds of
bottles of wine stored there!
Isn't that right?
Yes. I thought I'd keep some for
whenever I open my own restaurant.
I'm quite fond of wine-
may I take a quick look?
Certainly.
Oww!
The wood flooring is scratched up!
Oh, are you all right? I dropped
a bottle there the other day.
Conan-kun. You're not
wearing slippers, so be careful.
Margaux, Lafite, Haut-Brion...
Such an impressive
collection of top-quality wine!
That reminds me, what was it called again?
Your treasured... Petr-?
You have Chateau Petrus, too?!
Chateau Petrus? That's what
Poirot drank in "Death on the Nile"!
I did, but I drank it the other day.
Huh?! But I thought it takes years
until it's ready to drink?
I just couldn't help myself.
Sawaki-san. We can talk wine another day.
Can you tell us your plans for today?
Do you know Asahi Katsuyoshi-san?
He's a businessman who operates
dozens of restaurants in the city.
Oh, I've done a job for
Asahi-san in the past!
I hear he's opening Aqua Crystal,
that aquatic park in Tokyo Bay.
"Asahi Katsuyoshi" I hear he's opening Aqua Crystal,
I hear he's opening Aqua Crystal,
that aquatic park in Tokyo Bay.
Yes. He's offered to let me
run a restaurant there,
so I have a 3:00 appointment with him.
Asahi Katsuyoshi?
- Asahi?
- Hold on, now!
Nine! There's a "nine" in "Asahi"!
"Asahi"
"Nine"
Nine! There's a "nine" in "Asahi"!
Which means he's the next to be attacked.
But he only hired me to find his pet cat.
We're not really acquaintances...
Murakami might not think so.
In any event, let's protect Sawaki-san
and meet with Asahi-san!
Is that all right, Sawaki-san?
Yes. I don't mind.
Then you and Conan-kun-
Are coming.
Conan-kun and I are coming, too!
I've had enough of this, Ran!
This isn't a game!
That's right! Lots of people are
being attacked because of you!
I can't just wait for my turn to come!
Ran...
That's Aqua Crystal?
- My...
- What a flashy building...
Reckless driver!
A little bit off. But not too bad.
Hey, you! That's dangerous, girly!
- What is?
- Listen, you...
Oh, Nana-chan! You too?
Oh, Asahi-san invited
you too, Shishido-sensei?!
Pardon me, ma'am, but who are you?
You don't know who I am, mister?!
She's Osanai Nana-san, Inspector.
A popular model.
Those three are-from left to right-
the essayist Nishina-san,
the photographer
Shishido Eimei-san, and...
Peter Ford.
I take it you two are policemen?
And the famous Mori Kogoro-san?
You're that famous detective?!
I've never seen the real one before!
Shishido-sensei!
- Take a picture!
- Peace!
Oh, geez. Where'd that anger just now go?
This is Sawaki Kohei-san, a sommelier,
Mori-san's daughter, Ran-san,
and Edogawa Conan-kun.
Oh, you're the "delicious book" girl.
Wow! You remember me?!
Beautiful wine and women
always remain in people's hearts.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Have you all been
asked here by Asahi-san?
- Yes, for 3:00.
- I'm at 3:00, too!
Same here.
Inspector. Has there been
some sort of incident?
Yes, as a matter of fact...
Hey, it's almost 3:00! Let's go already!
Oh, right! Let's head to
the restaurant for now!
Huh? Come to think of it,
all four people called here are-
Is the monorail the only way
to get to Aqua Crystal?
Huh? There's no driver!
It looks like you just
need to press this button.
"Start" It looks like you just
"Start"
This is quite something!
A-are you not good with hanging
in the air either, Nishina-san?
No... It's water I'm afraid of.
I can't swim at all...
Y-yeah, everyone has their little quirks.
Even if it's a fact that
your dad shot your mom,
are you sure that equals
the truth behind it?
It's like an aquarium! This totally
is an underwater restaurant!
A Ferrari F40! How did they
get it in here, I wonder!
I don't seem to see Asahi-san...
That's odd, after he invited guests here...
Don't tell me Murakami already got to him?
What does that mean?!
"Murakami already got to him?"
Oh, right! I need to tell you about that...
Inspector. I'll go look around the place.
- I'll come too.
- Alright.
Okay, everyone! Just to be safe,
please sit with your backs to the wall!
So this is where the emergency exit is...
"Wine Cellar"
This is the only room that's locked...
I see. So that's what's going on...
Nothing out of the ordinary.
Which means I could be "six".
Why's that?
The "shishi" in "Shishido"
has a "six" in it.
So it does!
The other three have numbers
in their names, too.
What?
Nana means "seven",
"Nishina" has "two",
and Ford has the English "four".
Yeah...
Now we just need a "three"
and "one" to have all the numbers...
I know of a "three".
He's right in front of you.
Wait, you don't mean-
"Shiratori Ninzaburo" (Zabu = three)
My name is Shiratori Ninzaburo.
Ninzaburo?
But there's definitely no "one" here...
Shinichi.
(Ichi = one)
Do you think Shinichi could be "one"?
Is Kudo-kun coming here?!
No. But I just got that feeling...
It's true;
had I not shrunk, I would've been
intrigued enough to come too!
Does that mean “one” does refer to me?
Tell me, are any of you connected
with Murakami Joe in any way?
Of course I'm not!
Me neither!
I am.
Before I became an essayist, I was
a criminal investigative reporter,
and I had done a report
on the Murakami incident.
I'm connected, too.
I photographed him for a photo album
called "Portraits of Criminals".
Did any trouble occur at the time?
Nothing at all.
What is it, Nana-san?
He got out of prison eight days ago, right?
Yes.
Then it's unrelated.
Oh, you guys! Getting all serious!
Let's quit talking about this!
More importantly, aren't you the one
who wrote that lame book,
"Restaurants in Paris"?!
All the restaurants
you recommended in it sucked!
- Do you even understand tastes?!
- How rude!
Of course I do!
Then let's see some proof.
Proof?
I brought this as a gift for Asahi-san,
but let's see you guess what wine this is!
Blind tasting, huh? All right, then.
This elegant, violet fragrance...
This velvety texture going down...
Chambertin, the beloved drink
of Napoleon, Emperor of the French.
I got you!
As if I'd ever buy something
that cheap as a gift for someone!
Then what is this?!
- You're a sommelier.
- Yes.
Tell this fraud of an essayist the answer.
Moulin-à-Vent, Beaujolais, yes?
Correct!
No way! This is a Beaujolais?!
High-quality Beaujolais,
when left to age for a long time,
can produce top-quality
Bourgogne-like flavors and fragrances.
Now do you get it? I suggest you
call it quits as a "gourmet essayist"!
Now I feel like having some wine, too!
Let's all have some, then!
I'll get the stuff!
I'll have some beer. Where's the kitchen?
That way.
Alright! Lead the way, brat!
Okay!
Who're you callin' a brat?!
Ah! Here we go!
Good news, brat! There's juice here, too!
Really?! I'm so happy!
Enough with the brat stuff!
Here, Ran-neechan!
Thanks!
Oops!
It really is as delicious
as you say, Sawaki-san!
Sawaki-san! How about another glass?
Oh, no, thank you.
I'll have some mineral water.
Thanks!
You're not having beer?
Of course not! There's no telling
when Murakami could strike!
Here you are, Inspector!
Here, Conan-kun. You can have mine.
T-that's okay! I'll get another one!
Hey! Don't be scampering around, now!
The mineral water is in the
bottom drawer of the fridge!
Oh, thanks.
I saw a rare seasoning here,
so I gave it a taste.
- Is your juice up here, Conan-kun?
- Yeah!
What's taking Asahi-san so long?
What could he be up to?!
W-what's going on?! What's wrong?!
Just joking!
Ugh...
Ford-san! Please don't
joke around at a time like this!
Incidentally, why are
you all here today, anyway?
I got a call from his secretary.
Said Asahi-san was a fan of mine
and wanted to meet with me.
Maybe he wants me to help
promote this place or something?
I also received a call from his secretary.
I got the same invitation.
I even got a present from him!
Here! This nail polish!
It's made in France and super expensive!
- You too, Nishina-san?
- Yeah, me too!
What're you doing there, Nana-chan?
I drew on the wine cork
with nail polish! Isn't it cute?
What is it? A raccoon dog?!
Oh, you're such a meanie! It's a cat!
Sawaki-san. This is addressed to you.
I found it on the ground.
“Sawaki Kohei-san...”
"I may be late, so please treat everyone
to any bottle of wine you want
from Rack M-18 in the wine cellar."
"The key is in an envelope
on the checkout counter."
"Thanks. -Asahi Katsuyoshi"
Was that paper there when
I picked up the juice earlier?
Hey! I wanna see the wine cellar!
Me too!
I'd like to see what wine there is, too!
Then let's all go together!
- My word!
- What a sight!
- It's cool in here...
- No, it's almost too warm!
A temperature between 10º to 14º C
is ideal for preserving wine,
but it's up to 17º C in here.
Just look at these, Inspector!
They're all rare wines!
Romanée-Conti, La Tache, Le Pin,
Cote-Rotie, Clos du Mesnil...
Just amazing!
Shelf M-18...
There it is!
Look out!
A booby-trap!
Mister! Inspector!
This is just like the one
that hit me in the side!
Inspector!
The crossbow is set up here!
An 8 of Spades...
So it was Murakami who set this up,
and wrote that letter!
If so, why would he skip nine
and go after Sawaki-san, who's eight?
It couldn't be!
Inspector! Let's evacuate from
this building for the time being!
Huh? It's closed.
Was the entrance not here?
No, this is the place.
If we're leaving, can I get my coat first?
Go ahead.
Asahi-san!
The 9 of Spades! It was Murakami!
Inspector! I can't open this door,
it has an electronic lock!
What?! Alright, I'll call for help!
"No Service"
No good! We're out of service range!
It's been cut! Damn it!
Inspector! I'm gonna
check the emergency exit!
What?!
It's blocked with cement!
This is your fault! We have
nothing to do with this!
Yeah! What do you have
to say for yourself?!
The fact Murakami didn't
go out of numerical order
means you're next, Nana-chan!
Q-quit it!
Why do I have to be targeted by
some man I've never even heard of?!
But something bugs you, right?
Earlier, you...
He got out of prison eight days ago, right?
Yes.
I already told you, it was unrelated!
We will determine if it's unrelated
or not. Please talk to us.
Three months ago...
Apparently!
We didn't collide,
but I got scared and drove off!
Did the person have
an off-road motorcycle?!
No, it was a regular motorcycle.
Inspector. Nana-san is right.
It's unrelated to what's happening now.
More importantly, we need
to figure a way out of here!
Yeah. We might find an exit
if we search the entire building.
Then let's split up and look, too.
Guess there's no other choice.
Listen! Ran and Conan, you stay here!
You remain here too, Nana-san!
Okay...
What's taking everyone so long?
Can't they find an exit?
Don't worry! I'm sure they'll
find one and be right back!
I'll just do some searching, too!
You were told to stay here!
Honestly! You're so
curious about everything...
But!
A power outage?!
What?! What's going on?!
Why are the lights out?!
Luminescent paint!
- Help!
- Stay there, Nana-san!
Don't tell me this blackout-
What?! What happened?!
- What was that scream?!
- Inspector!
- Mori-kun! The electrical room!
- Right!
Nana-san?!
Is this it?
Nana-san!
What the-?!
- Nana-san!
- Move aside!
She's dead!
The 7 of Spades, and a Joker...
It's Murakami! Murakami's here,
inside this building!
Damn it!
I'll go check around!
Mori-san! It's dangerous to
go alone! I'll come with you!
Shishido-san.
Please cease your photography.
Why's that?
Since help can't come right away,
you'll have to do the autopsy,
but won't you need to photograph
the scene of the crime first?
Y-you have a point...
Then I expect you to hand them over
to the police later on.
Yes, but of course!
But how did Murakami manage
to do this in pitch darkness?
Luminescent paint.
Nana-san's fingernails were glowing.
What?!
I see! Luminescent paint was added
to the nail polish she was given!
Her middle nail...
Hey, Inspector!
Nana-san's left fingernail is weird!
The nail polish came off!
Or, wait... did her nail break off?
I think that's a press-on nail
that came off.
Press-on?
They're not real fingernails.
They come in various designs,
and you glue them to your nails.
Oh? So it came off by chance, then?
Here we are!
It doesn't seem related to her murder...
Oh...
She was grabbed with a left hand!
And pretty forcefully, at that!
Which means... the killer is right-handed!
If I remember right,
Murakami... is left-handed!
It wasn't Murakami who killed Nana-san!
Wait a minute! A while back, the killer...
Think back! Remember!
He's right-handed!
What the hell?! I've been making
a huge mistake this whole time!
Inspector! No luck!
Murakami's nowhere to be found!
Could he have already escaped?
That can't be! There's no way out!
He must be hiding somewhere still!
No... Murakami isn't the killer.
It's someone in here!
Who?! Who killed Nana-san?!
Come to think of it, the killer...
...kicked the can of juice
I left on the floor!
The contents have spilled onto the floor.
I'm certain there was about half
left in it when I set it down.
So if the killer kicked the can...
...the juice must've flown out
and stained the killer's pants!
Nana-san's killer is one of these four men!
Him?! But why?!
I'm sorry, Sawaki-san.
Because of me, Asahi-san was murdered,
and you never got to discuss
running his restaurant...
Not at all. I was going
to turn him down, anyway.
Actually, I've decided to quit my
current job and return to the country.
I'm an only son, so I need
to take care of my parents.
In any case, we'd be wise
not to act rashly now.
Especially you, Shishido-san.
Yeah, I know. I'm next, right?
I'll be extra careful not to get killed.
Inspector! I refuse to die!
I will get out of here alive!
Wait a minute! Could it be that he...
What're you up to now?!
I thought everyone might be thirsty...
You idiot! Don't be
running around on your own!
There's no telling where
Murakami might be hiding!
But there's no number in my name, so...
Yeesh!
Here you go!
Here you go, Sawaki-san!
Thank you.
Hey, brat! Gimme some too!
Sure!
Japanese water really is delicious!
That's great!
I was right! No doubt about it!
But there's no proof.
Come to think of it, where is it?!
I found the proof!
What was that?!
There appears to have been
an explosion somewhere!
Shiratori-kun! Shishido-san
is next! Protect Shishido-san!
Yes, sir!
Shishido-san!
Where are you, Shishido-san?!
- Right here.
- Put that out!
Do you want to die?!
I'm "two", so I won't get
attacked for a long time!
Sawaki-san! Are you hurt?!
N-no. Do you suppose
I'll be targeted again?
I- I'm not sure...
Thank you! Emergency lights!
W-what the?!
H-h-help! I can't swi-!
Here, grab on!
Heya, brat! Glad to see you're alive!
Huh?! Ran! Where are you?! Ran!
Don't tell me she's...
Wait, Conan! Where are you going?!
Ran! Where are you?!
Ran!
Ran! Everything's okay now! Calm down!
S- Shinichi?
Conan-kun!
It's no good!
Oh, yeah! My Elasticity Suspenders!
Crap! My leg's stuck!
Dammit! Oh no! Can't breathe!
R- Ran!
Hey! Ran! Ran!
Damn it!
I'm free! I gotta hurry!
Hey! Ran! Ran! Say something!
D- Dad...
Thank Conan.
Thank you, Conan-kun...
No, uhh...
What's wrong?!
I seem to have reopened my wound!
What?!
Look! Over there!
The 6 to 2 of Spades!
Damn it! Is he planning to kill us
all at once here?! Screw that!
But, at this rate, it is going to happen.
Because there's no way out!
- I know a way out!
- What?!
You know, the exploded windows!
Yeah! We can go
into the sea through them!
N-no! I can't!
Quit bein' a sissy! I'll take you with me!
Then I'll take you, little boy!
I'll be fine by myself!
And I'll take you. Think you
got a little bit left in you?!
- I'll help you, Inspector.
- Thanks...
Then I'll lead the way! Let's go!
Here we go! Deep breath!
Hold on tight and don't let go now!
R-right!
Here! Grab my hand!
- Take Ran!
- Right!
We're saved, aren't we?
Yes. We're safe now!
Nishina! Nishina!
Hey! Say something!
I'll give him CPR!
I'm a certified lifeguard!
Hold it! Detective Shiratori!
You give him CPR!
Huh? No, I didn't say anything-
Do it now, Shiratori!
Understood!
Huh?
Mori-kun?
Inspector!
The person behind this string
of incidents is not Murakami Joe!
Say what?!
Because the person who shot
Dr. Agasa and killed Nana-san
was right-handed!
Right-handed?!
Y-you're all right!
The real culprit most likely
met Murakami after he was released,
learned things from him,
like how I shot him 10 years ago
and that he was once a gambling
dealer nicknamed "Joker",
and decided to use him.
Use?
Yes. The killer realized that he
and the people he wanted to kill
all had numbers in their names.
So he came up with the idea
of combining these "name numbers"
with playing cards to
pin his crimes on Murakami.
Then the reason Eri-san,
Dr. Agasa, and I were attacked
was to act as camouflage to make us think
Murakami was getting
revenge against you?!
That's right.
Then who did the culprit
really want to kill?!
Asahi-san and Nana-san.
And Tsuji-san.
Given that the method used against him-
switching his eyedrops-
had a very high probability of being fatal,
there's likely no doubt.
Mori-kun! Who is the killer, then?!
The killer is among us.
What?!
Come to think of it,
didn't Nana-san humiliate you?
N-no! I didn't kill her!
That's right. You were to be killed.
As you can't swim, the killer
attempted to drown you
by blowing up the underwater restaurant.
Say, Detective Shiratori.
When you gave CPR to Nishina-san,
what was the first thing you did?
What did I do?
You're supposed to tilt
the head back, lift the throat up,
and keep the airway open!
Then, what would happen if you
hadn't kept the airway open,
and only pretended to give CPR,
while shutting the nose and mouth?
That'd kill him, obviously!
Y-you're not saying...
Yes. The person who murdered
Asahi-san and Nana-san
and tried to kill
Tsuji-san and Nishina-san...
It was you, Sawaki Kohei-san!
Mori-san! I was attacked
with a crossbow too, you know!
You had set that up beforehand.
After you murdered Asahi-san
here last night, that is!
Then the letter that was
under the table...
And the secretary that called us all...
Sawaki-san was behind it all.
Including Nana-san's
luminescent nail polish, of course!
Motive! What was his motive?!
Something to do with ageusia, most likely.
Ageusia?
That's when you can't taste
food and drinks anymore, right?
Yes. He suffers from this ageusia.
Apparently, ageusia is caused
by stress or external head injuries.
External head injuries?
Then Sawaki-san was the person
Nana-san got in an accident with?!
H-h-hold on now!
You claim he lost his sense of taste,
but he named Nana-san's
wine brand correctly!
He could tell the brand by the
wine's color and scent alone.
That's possible?
After it happened,
Sawaki-san continued as a sommelier,
relying on vision and smell alone.
But it was an affront to his aesthetic
desire to be a perfect sommelier.
That's why he decided to leave
his position and return to the country.
But not before getting revenge
on Nana-san and everyone else
who had caused him to
lose his sense of taste!
It must have been quite hard to accept.
Enough to make him break the
bottle of wine he treasured and saved
for the day he would finally
open his own restaurant.
Then that mark on his floor was-
But how did you manage
to figure all this out?
Yes. It was because he tried
to taste some seasoning.
What he tried was chili powder.
People like sommeliers who
use their tongues for a living
don't put irritants or stimulants
in their mouths, you see.
I was able to confirm that he
had lost his sense of taste
when I had Conan give him
some mineral water.
Mineral water?
The glass that Conan
gave you had salt in it.
And I drank it without realizing it?
It's true that I suffer from ageusia.
But that hardly proves
that I murdered Nana-san.
But there is proof. In either
your left or right jacket pocket.
That's the cork Nana-san drew on!
Nana-san had that cork on her
until just before she was murdered.
So what was it doing in your pocket?
It's because when you
stabbed her from behind,
Nana-san spun around and grabbed at you,
at which time the cork
slipped inside your pocket!
The press-on nail on the floor
likely came off at this time.
How ironic that a wine cork
should prove a sommelier's crime.
But there's one more thing!
And it's most likely still
asleep in one of your pockets!
The final Ace of Spades
that matches those there.
The card for Kudo Shinichi!
The Ace of Spades!
Mori-san. It's all as you say.
Three months ago, on my way
home from the restaurant,
I nearly collided with her car,
and fell off my motorcycle.
A while after, I suddenly
lost all sense of taste.
The doctor said stress
might also be the cause.
Having lost all hope, I decided
to give up being a sommelier
and enact revenge on the cause
of the accident, Osanai Nana,
and the causes of my stress,
Asahi, Tsuji, and Nishina.
But what did Asahi-san
and the others do to you?!
Asahi caught wind of a "wine boom"
and used his vast fortune
to buy up all the
rare foreign wine available!
And he couldn't even take care of it right!
Nishina! You pretended to be a gourmet,
wrote know-it-all books,
and planted incorrect information
about wine in readers' minds!
And Tsuji Hiroki!
He sullied my dignity as a sommelier!
Four months ago, I attended
a party he held at his home.
Oh! You're here!
Here's a good sommelier badge for you!
And for your tastevin!
Oh! Lookin' sharp!
You tried to kill Tsuji-san for that?!
"For that"?! You can't possibly
understand how I felt then!
I sought dignity, honor, and pride
as a sommelier in my work!
And he stomped on all of it
with his grimy feet!
Did you kill Murakami Joe?
Yeah.
The day he was released from prison,
I just happened to meet him
in front of the Mori Detective Agency.
That's the day he went to play mahjong!
I thought I might be able to use Murakami,
so I invited him over
as an acquaintance of Mori-san.
Way back when, he did hold
a grudge against Mori-san,
but now he wanted to apologize
for everything, so he went to see him.
That's when I came up with the idea
of using playing card numbers
to camouflage my crimes.
Killing Murakami while
he was wasted was easy.
So you had no grudge against Mori-san
or Inspector Megure, then?!
Exactly.
So you brought me and Shishido-san here...
...because you needed
a "four" and a "six"?!
That's right.
I figured three and five-
Mori-san and Detective Shiratori-
would naturally come if I mentioned
Asahi-san invited me here.
I had actually hoped "one" -
Kudo Shinichi-would come too...
...but unfortunately,
my wish didn't come true.
Did you ever stop to consider
if innocent people were killed?!
I blew up the underwater restaurant
simply to kill Nishina.
I didn't give a damn whether
any of the others lived or died.
This place would collapse afterward,
Murakami would go missing,
and it'd all remain an unsolved mystery.
This place would collapse?!
Sawaki-san. There's nowhere
to run now. Give yourself up.
Detective Shiratori! Seize Sawaki-san!
What?!
W-what the?!
Oh no!
Come on!
Crap!
Huh? Why does Sawaki-san have Ran?
What are you talking about?!
You just exposed his crimes!
Huh? I did?
Stay where you are! Move and she's dead!
Damn it! Ran's too out of it
to use her karate-
That last explosion has caused
the building to lose its balance!
Ran! Where are you?!
Up there!
Where is he going?!
He plans to escape in a helicopter!
What?!
He called one here using the
secretary's name so he could escape!
That's what he thinks!
Wait! Mori-kun! Leave the rest to us-
Conan-kun!
- You guys evacuate immediately!
- I-I can't swim!
Don't worry! We'll find a plank
or something and get you to shore!
- Let's go, Shiratori-kun!
- Yes, sir!
- Which way?!
- Up the stairs!
The elevator, huh?!
Mori-kun! This way!
Hurry! Hurry!
Inspector. How good is
Detective Shiratori with a gun?
He's as bad as I am.
W-what in the world's going on?!
What are you doing?! Land!
W-who is this guy?!
Why does he have a knife?!
Dammit! Why doesn't that
elevator go to the roof?!
Get down here now!
I'm the one who ordered the chopper!
Emergency! Emergency!
A man with a knife has a girl hostage
on the Aqua Crystal heliport!
And the building is in danger
of collapsing! Send help at once!
Ran!
Stay back!
Any closer and she's dead!
Stop this, Sawaki-san!
Let Ran-san go! Let her go or I'll shoot!
Amusing!
Go ahead and shoot, if you dare!
His hands are shaking!
He'll hit Ran if he shoots!
Shiratori-kun! Don't!
Inspector! Are you all right?!
Escaping in a helicopter
won't help you! Let Ran-kun go!
Shut up! I'm gonna take
this girl and go kill Tsuji!
Tsuji-san?!
He can't be in the
All-American Open now!
Isn't that enough?!
Nope! I'm going to kill him,
and then I'm going to die!
And she's coming with me!
S- Sawaki-san...
Shinichi... Help me...
Shinichi...
If he runs off with Ran, he'll kill her!
This is bad! If this keeps up,
we'll all be goners, not just Ran!
Hand over the gun.
What?!
I'll stab her!
Hey, Shiratori. Gimme the gun.
I said give it to me.
Yeah, right! I can't give it to you!
What're you doing?! Hurry it up!
A-all right!
Boy! You bring it here!
Do you want this girl to die?!
N-no! Don't make a kid do
something that dangerous!
Hey!
C'mon! Bring it here!
N-no!
Conan-kun... D-don't give-
Don't give it to him!
'Atta boy! Now bring it here!
Hurry up!
I said bring it here now!
Ah! Now I see! That's why the old guy...
Shi-
Shinichi?
Damn it! Hey! Get up! Hey!
Hey! Hey!
♪ I sadly watched the rain
pound on you as you bent over ♪
pound on you as you bent over ♪ Ran!
♪ I sadly watched the rain
pound on you as you bent over ♪
♪ If there was only one umbrella in
this world, I'd find it for you ♪
That was a close one, Ran...
N-now I see! So that's why Mori-san
shot her back then!
It wasn't to stop the killer,
but to save the hostage!
Yes. A hostage shot in the leg
is just a burden to a fleeing criminal.
It was to save Mom...
So that was the truth, then?
Dad!
♪ I beg of you,
please confess your worries to me ♪
Sawaki Kohei!
You're under arrest for murder,
bodily harm, kidnapping, and more!
♪ I beg of you,
please confess your worries to me ♪
Let go! Let me die!
I'm not letting you die!
I'm gonna make you understand
the weight of what you've done!
Talk about a close call!
It looks like you're over your
fear of helicopters now, huh?!
Let me off this thing!
Here you go!
He suddenly jumped at me,
so I got surprised!
Honestly! It's just a good thing
you only grazed Ran-san's leg.
Anywhere else and things
could've ended badly.
I'm sorry!
Can't really tell him that my old man
often taught me how to shoot
at the shooting range when
we visited the lodge in Hawaii!
But... I did cause Ran pain...
Inspector! This is the perfect opportunity
to take some time off!
Yeah, I think I will!
The hat can stay on, if you don't mind.
Say, do you think even Shinichi
would've shot like you did?
Who knows. He might've,
if he was as good a shot as me.
I think so, too. Right, Shinichi?
What's that?
Shinichi's card. The Ace of Spades.
I was holding onto it the whole time.
Who knows, maybe Shinichi
helped protect me!
You dummy! The person saved by the ace...
"An 'A' is in your future"
...was me...
...you know!
Whenever I wake up from the dream
I regularly have
I realize my heart is beating fast
Love does not beat to a regular rhythm
I wound up falling asleep again
on the comfy sofa
As if I had returned to the nostalgic time
of when I was a little girl,
you gently caress my hair
How long I had waited
for those warm hands
You alone softly wrap me up
I love you so much, I love you so much
I love you so much, with a red heart
Lovin' you
With you
Eh? You knew why Dad shot you?!
Of course I did! We are married, after all.
Plus it's only natural for a
husband to protect his wife.
Then why did you leave him?
That very night, he said my cooking
was horrible and didn't eat it.
Huh?
My leg hurt so much, and I worked
so hard to thank him with food...
Yet, he...
You idiot! If this is the best
you can make, get the hell to bed!
And that's why I moved out.
Just remembering it makes me mad!
That insensitive old clod!
O-oh, I see...
Looks like they won't be
making up for a while now...
Come to think of it, Mom's cooking...
...was horrible...