Damn it. Where'd he go?
Gotchya!
The game is over, Mr. Thief
Definitely
It's too dark to play Hide and Seek
Detective brother
I am Senior Detective Shinichi Kudo
When I was visiting the amusement park
with my best mate Ran Mouri
Witnessed the deal scene of the man in black
At the time I was only concentrating
on peeking the deal
But I neglected the other guy coming from my back
I was poisoned by that man
When I came to
My body's already turned small
If they know Shinichi Kudo is still alive
My life will be in danger
And also my relatives around will be jeopardized
Under Dr. Agasa's suggestion, I hid my identity
When Ran asked about my name
In an emergency, I used the alias Edogawa Conan
In order to collect those guy's information
I moved to Ran's place, her father's a detective
The criminal is you
This man is called Mouri Kogoro
He is Ran's father
Now he is a very tough well-known detective
People call him slumbering Kogoro
About its reason
Needless to say, I guess you all know it
Watch narcotic gun Cravat toner
These two props were invented by Dr. Agasa
In order to help the smalled me,
Dr. Agasa had invented a few handy props
Especially this football ejecting belt
Just press the button on the belt
Then the football will be expanded
and ejected, superb prop
Oh, yea
Besides the Doctor there are still
a few know who I am
My parents
Kansai Senior Detective Hattori Heiji
And Ai Haibara who was
in the same elementary school with me
She and her sister Miyano Akemi
were the complices of the man in black
But Miyano Akemi was killed by the organization
Haibara was very unhappy about this.
When she fled from the organization
She was forced to drink the same poison as me,
and therefore also got shrinked
There's another one
Kaitou Kiddo
We haven't gotten even yet
Bet the reputation of a well-known detective
I am sure to try him this time
The body is smaller
but the brain is still the same good
A famous detective without maze
There's always only one truth
Aha, I see
Is this the warning letter sent by Kiddo?
Yes
This morning on the balcony of my home
(Maki Jyuri (37) Actress)
Put together with a big bunch of rose
Hemhem
That guy still likes bumbling
Romeo Juliet
Victor Bravo
In the 26 scattered flying letters
(Yaguchi Masayo (32) Manager)
I will come and take the Sapphire of Fate
Kaitou Kiddo
And a torn poker card
Here you are
Thank you
What do you think, Mr. Mouri?
Not quite clear
"The Sapphire of Fate" refers to...
It refers to this
Wow, so beautiful
This is a sapphire, right?
Yes
The three interleaving lines on the surface
stand for "belief", "hope" and "fate" respectively
It's called The Sapphire of Fate
Aha
So beautiful
Because Josephine loves this sapphire very much
She used the sapphire in the show this time too
The show?
I know
Your living drama in the new
Universal Theater in Shiodome, Josephine
Josephine?
That's Napoleon's first queen
She's also known to be a rose-lover
I see, so roses are sent
Exactly kid, you know very well
Not actually.
He only knows a little useless knowledge
Romeo Juliet
Victor Bravo
In the tree?
Yes?
Now in your show theater
Romeo and Juliet?
Yes
Although I didn't take part of the show
That happened to be first performance
in public of the theater
Any problems?
I know the answer now
Really?
The foretell letter sent here by Kiddo
has 3 W's and 1 H
That is to say
Who
When
Where
How
These words are to imply us
I see
Hey, any problems?
Above all, who
This is Kiddo for sure
Then where
The performance of Romeo and Juliet
takes place in the Universal Theater
Then when
The foretell letter mentioned about Bravo
So it is when the spectators bravo
Finally how
The letter mentioned about Victor
It refers to Napoleon
The role Kiddo will play
Then it's poker card in the foretell letter
The card's torn into two meaning Victory V
So after your drama of Josephine
when the spectators bravo
Kaitou Kiddo will show up disguised
as Napoleon and steal the ring
Bravo
Bravo, Mr. Mouri, creditably well-known detective
Just so so
Uncle
What are the 26 scattered flying letters?
You fool, count the letters on it
Romeo Juliet Victor Bravo
Aren't they totally 26 letters?
It's like this
Ah yeah, in the tree
When will the play of Josephine end?
Today is the last play
Then Kiddo will...
Weird
Dumb kid, what is it now?
But it's so weird
Look, here are only 22 letters
How come?
It's true, I've also counted it
Lack of 3 even if I count the excalmatory mark
Then Kiddo must have been wrong
Hey...
Anyway Kiddo will surely come
and steal the Sapphire tonight
OK, I know
I have something to discuss with you
Of course the police will then be here too
Can I invite you to the theater tonight
to stop Kiddo from stealing the sapphire?
No problem
I, Mouri Kogoro
never rejected beauty's entrust
Thank you very much
Masayo, take it out
Yes
Here're the tickets for tonight
Welcome you to come with your friends
Thank you
In the 26 scattered flying letters?
The 26 letters must refer to the alphabet
And this poker card
Impossible that it stands for V
Shiodome Tower
Universal Theater
I am so excited
Me too
Actually I've wanted to watch the drama for long
Hey, Conan
Why do you have that bag on your back?
It's troublesome
It's ok
What's inside?
You brought cracks along?
I'm not like you
Hey, you guys
I've broken the rules to take you here
Show some politeness
OK
I'm sorry. I come here too
Don't mention
Mouri
Sorry, kept you waiting for long
Hello, Yaguchi
I'm Yaguchi, Mr. Mouri has come
Come in please
Thanks
Welcome Mr. Mouri
Hello
Sorry that I am not very tidy now
Natuki, This is the famous Mouri Kogoro
You must have heard of him
(Sakai Natuki (26) Hair Maker)
My name's Sakai Natuki
Hello
It's so spacious here
So many flowers
Great!
I'm sorry
That I've brought the children along
Don't worry, it's OK
Jyuri, Do you dive?
Yes, I've just started to learn
Shall we call it a day to go together?
Great, I will go for sure
You obviously haven't dived
What did you say, Ran?
Nothing
Wow
So much cosmetic
Yeah
This is called foundation make-up
Exactly
Barely foundation make-up...
5 kinds
So many? 5 kinds?
Hey!
Little sisters!
You are too young to learn make-up
Behave as the kids you are
Understood?
Yes
I'm coming
Masayo
ć
I've heard that Mouri has come
Ah
Mouri
You are the well-known detective Mouri Kogoro?
(Narusawa Bunjirou (34) Actor)
My name's Narusawa, I adore you very much
Thank you
You will play as Napolean, right?
Yes
I'm very sorry that
I'm still in theatrical costume
Ah, let me introduce to you
(Tajima Tenko (36) Actress)
This's Tajima Tenko as Josephine's good friend
as Josephine's good friend - Teresa Terrian
How do you do?
(Shinjyou Isao (28) Actor)
This is ShinJyou Isao as Josephine's inamorato
as Josephine's inamorato - Hippolyte Shallore
Hello
And then the director
and the the sponsor of Josephine
as Barras De Boer...
(Ban Tohru (45) Director and Actor)
My name is Ban Tohru, how do you do?
How do you do?
Is everyone here?
Officer Nakamori
Hello, Mouri
How've you been?
Thank you for the last time
Don't mention, I should thank you
Are they themselves?
Definitely
Kiddo always disguises
as related personnel in advance
Maybe he's already among these people
I nearly forgot
This time I specially took someone
to assist the investigation
I said no, but damned Megure...
No
It's because Officer Megure
strongly recommend him
Come on in
Hi everyone, I am Kuto Shinichi
Shinich?
Kuto?
Weird... weird...
This brat
Kuto Shinich is...
That well-known Senior Detective?
Weird... weird...
Who is he?
What are you talking about?
He is sis Ran's boyfriend
He is not!
Her husband
Sonoko!
He is Kaitou Kiddo
This guy is not brother Shinich
He's Kiddo disguised
Kiddo disguised?
How do you know that?
Because I am the real...
Real what?
Nothing...
I see. That's possible as well
It hurts!
Officer Nakamori, stop!
What's going on?
I don't know either
Maybe Kiddo does look like me
Or...
You are the fake one
Hey...
OK. Now we can be sure he's real
I think we pull everyone's face by the way
No, it's not necessary
I feel that Kiddo is not among us
Obviously he is
And I already have a good idea to catch Kiddo
Haha
Then please speak out
Ms. Maki,
I'd like to have the others to go out first
Never mind, Officer
Anyway I am ready
Ah
Excuse me
I want to catch the criminal in my way
What did you say?
That's right. Little detective, don't make trouble.
Then we are going out first
Looking forward to your brilliant performance
Wait
Now that you've come,
you should have informed me in advance
Sorry
Because I wanted to give you a surprise
Cute
You guys are talking so sweet
I'm going to the roof
Do you want to come, Ran?
The garret seems to be an observatory
Come on go, Ran
I want to go too
You can't go there
I do, I want to go too
Stop it
I want to go too
All right, everyone go together
Great
Don't you feel Conan...
looks like another in front of sis Ran?
I suppose he's at a peevish age
Aha, I see
He's really like a brat
You are brats too
How could I let Kiddo and Ran be together alone
OK, here's locked also
Yea
How's it?
The doors to the roof are all locked
Aha
If my consequence is correct
Kiddo will come from the roof
Probably
Obviously already here
Ran
I'll take care of Conan
You two can take a walk around
No
Besides...
I feel Shinichi's weird
He never talked like that before
Like what?
Like say that I... I'm cute
That means he's more frank now
You should be more frank too
You should tell him if you really like him
Fool, I don't mean that
Great great
Gentai, why do you keep saying great?
I can't help
It's really great
It's so beautiful here
Certainly can be described only by great
Look
Yeah, so great
How dare he disguised as Shinichi
Yea
Maybe it's easier to handle if disguised as me
But at least we save time looking for him
Yea
Do you know who Napoleon is?
Yes, I do
He's the French hero used to conquer the Europe
OK...
Take it like a preview before the drama
I am telling a riddle related to Napoleon
Brother Shinich's going to tell a riddle
Looks like Dr. Agasa
Don't be a bad joke again
My riddle is related to history,
you can learn something from it
Think it together kid
Nonsense
Listen up
On Napoleon's soil
It's said that two Japanese built up houses
Do you know which two in the following?
1. Huyuno
2. Huruno
3. Hukano
Huyuno Huruno Hukano
Everyone has FU and NO
I got it!
Sh...
Don't tell
The difference between the three is YU,
RU and KA in the middle
I know it, it's Huyuno and Huruno
Only Hukano has KA in the middle
KA in the middle means China
So Hukano was Chinese
What? Am I wrong?
The answer is right,
but it's not the right reason
Do you know the famous saying by Napoleon?
"In my dictionary
there's no such word impossible"
Ah
I've heard it
This riddle is from that saying
Tochi(soil) is also called Jishyo(dictionary)
"Word" refers to the name on the doorpalte
In other word is "In my soil(Tochi)
there's no such word Hukano(impossible)".
It's like this
Actually Napoleon should have said
"Hukano(impossible) can only be
in the fools' dictionaries"
This is the right way to say it
Haibara is so awesome
But still a bad joke
Besides...
Is this something to learn from?
Isn't it?
Josephine, Teresa
Barras, Do you have anything?
General, let's me introduce to you
These are Teresa and Josephine
I know who you are
You are General Napoleon Bonaparte
I've heard that you are very brave
Overpraised
General, Would you like to have a dance with me?
My pleasure
I've kept in my mind till now
Those splendid memories
Bonaparte
Elba Island
Roman King
Ran
Is the man beside the pontificate your father?
This is your good idea to catch Kiddo?
Haibara, you stay here
Bye
I in the name of the holy father,
holy son and the holy ghost
Present this crown
which stands for the French King
I am the French King, Napoleon the first
Kid, are you all right?
It's very dangerous like this
Yep
I'm fine
Oh, yea
What?
Nothing
This kid ran out from the corner
rammed with me and fell down
Kid, are you all right?
I'm fine
But brother's baton looks so cool
much longer than this uncle's
Yea, pretty long
There are all types of batons
Shorter than 60 cm in length
Slenderer than 3 cm in diameter
Lighter than 320 grams in weight
Thare are strict rules
to the batons by PSCs everywhere
Your baton seems to be too long
Why?
Why too long?
That's is because
This is not a baton
You can't get away
Wait
Damn
Everything in this world
Glory
Victory
And future all belong to me
Everything belongs to us
Wait untill the purdah fully set then action
I know
Now, everyone catch Kiddo
He disguised as Napoleon
What do they want to do?
Kiddo, didn't you anticipate this?
Your stupid secret sign
has been seen through by me Mouri Kogoro
No, I am not Kiddo
Cut the crap
Show yourself you Kaitou Kiddo
It hurts!
He's not Kiddo
Then where is Kiddo?
The game is over, Mr. Thief
Definitely
It's too dark to play Hide and Seek
Detective brother
You can only lie now
Let's get it even
All right
Because your girl has made dinner waiting for you
Conan
Dinner's ready
Damn
It'll be eaten up if you don't come fast
It seems we can get it even today,
detective brother
Yeah
I thinking so too
No
Hey hey
Aha
Glider vs. Flying parachute
It's really something
The flying parachute you used just now
Another invention by Dr. Agasa?
You are already cornered
If can't fly
Kaitou Kiddo is just a normal thief
Then I turn back to the Kaitou before
What's that noise?
Oh no
Good-bye!
Damn
Haneda Airport
Now the weather information around the airport
Firstly
Hokkaidou
Hakodate is raining tonight
And thunder storm in some regions
Thunder storm in Kakodate
Terrible weather
What if the plane catches a lightning strike?
Don't worry, planes flies over the clouds
But under the clouds when landing
Today I put make-up so specially, but it rains
My grandma told me wearing this kind of clothes
bellybutton will get stolen
by the god of thunder when it's lightening
Hem, really?
Come on and steal
I'm very sorry
We're invited to the celebration party as well
Because of everyone, the sapphire is safe now
This is natural
Yes, it is
Please come with us to Hakodate and have fun
But Jyuri hasn't come yet
Yeah
Excuse me
Ms. Natuki is helping her with her make-up
They are in the car in the parking lot
Making up
It's hard to be a super star
Natuki is hard working
Yeah, Jyuri regards her highly
Have her do the sundries also as an assistant
Ah
I see
Hi~
I kept you waiting for long
You are very beautiful today
Thank you, Mouri
It seems everyone's here
Not yet, Shinjyou's not here
Shinjyou's not feeling very well
He called this morning saying that
he can't be here
Aha, I see
What a pity, Jyuri
What?
Nothing
Will other stagers come?
Of course not
Those minor roles don't mean anything here
I just felt...
Hakodate, Oonuma lakeside
Jyuri's cottage
If I felt it right, that guy will be here
Officer Nakamori, everyone's here
Very good
Team A guard the front door
Team B guard the back door
Team C patrol around
Yes, sir
Officer Nakamori
What?
There's light in the cottage
What
That is...
Sky Japan Airline, flight to Hakodate
Flight Number 865 leaves at 18:15
Now start to check in
Passengers who take flight #865
So great, the chair is so soft
Not bad
Like big boss
On the second floor there are first-classes
on the demostic flight
Only in this Sky Japan Airline
Hey, Ran
Ah
What is it with you?
Why keep looking back?
Nothing
Welcome on board
Hello
coming
Who?
Sh, don't talk
Excuse me, is the seat beside you free?
Please sit down
Eiri
It's you?
Auntie?
Strange, Mama wants to go to Hakodate too?
What a coincident
What a coincident for you two
What are you talking about?
You said Jyuri invited you to Hakodate
But your father's occupied,
wanted me to go with you
Ran, was it you again?
Don't mind, you two sit down first
Joke, I won't sit beside her(him)
Hem
Don't be like this you two
Father
Jyuri, May I sit beside you?
Ah
OK, please
Sigh
Wait, mother
Excuse me, Are you Ms. Maki Jyuri?
Yes
My name's Kisaki Eiri
Thank you very much for the treat this time
Ah
You are welcome
Go go go
Ah
Oh yeah
If the ungraceful man beside you harasses you
I can help any time
Aha, you are a lawyer
Talk to you later
OK
Hem
How could it be like this?
Naturally
No wonder
Hello everyone, kept you waiting for long
Shinjyou
Aren't you feel bad and can't come?
Yeah, I feel better again
I have nothing to do alone
So I decided to go with everyone still
Queen Josephine, sorry that I am late
Why didn't you follow my words?
Don't worry
No hurry if we prepare when we get there
We are setting out
Have a pleasant journey
All staff attention please
Please close all hatches
What are you thinking about?
Ah
Probably thinking about Kiddo
Yea
Did he really want to steal the sapphire
last night?
It's too dark to play Hide and Seek
Detective brother
And with a overlength baton
Kiddo wouldn't have made this kind of mistake
Mitsuhiko
My seat is 4K
Is the K from Kiddo
My seat is 4J
Is the J from Giant
My seat is 4B
That is
I understand now
The four words in Kiddo's foretell letter
It refers to these letters
These letters?
Exactly
To prevent hearing errors
in the radio communication
Romeo - R
Juliet - J
Victor - V
Bravo - B
And also used in radio communication on planes
SKJ865
Runway 16L
Permit to take off
Please go on JULIET10 ECHO10 CHARLIE10
SKJ865
JULIET10 ECHO10 CHARLIE10
In the 26 sattered flying letters
Meaning to foretell there'll be crime
on the plane using these letters
And has to be the plane from Tokyo to Hakodate
Why?
It could also be on the return trip
Because of the figure of the poker card?
Exactly
Spade 2 was torn into two parts
This means odd numbers
which can not be divided by 2
The flights from Tokyo are all odd
like this one 865
While flights return to Tokyo are all even
This makes sense
for the things happened last night
He drew our attention on purpose
Pretends that the plan's failed,
then everyone'll become careless
Then...
Kiddo is on this plane
Still wants to steal that ring now
Thank you for travelling with Sky Japan Airline
What's wrong with you?
I don't feel very good
You must be very tired
Jyuri, give me your hand
Take some Vitamin
The capitain of this plane is Ohkoshi
I'm the Cabin Chief, Jinto
SKJ865 permit to take off, wind direction
160 degrees, wind speed 10 nodes
SKJ865 ready to take off
runway 16L
Take off!
Confirm
V1
VR
V2
Confirm
Wheel up
My ears are feeling weird
Me too
That's because the air pressure changed
Try to swallow some slaver
Still the same weird
It's still the same
Then pinch your nose swallow some air
But don't do it hard
Or you will feel faint
OK
Look, snot is out
Conan, look ahead
It's ok now
Really, it's OK again
Girls are like this
Pinching nose and swallowing air
don't look so nice
So in front of opposite sexes...
They especially don't want others to see it
Hm
The lady Jyuri, please do me a favor
Please sign as for commemoration
Ah
All right
Damn, I forgot my signature pen
Maki
Please use this pen
Thanks!
So I can't be without her
What is father doing?
Don't care about that light-minded man
Now let me introduce to you
yeah
sorry
Are you all right?
Yeah
Ok, done
Thanks!
Western or Japanese style dessert,
which one would you prefer?
No, thanks!
Western and Japanese dessert...
Neither
Nor drinks
I'd like to have beer
and some dishes to go with it
Just a moment please
It's great to have beer in the first class
I dislike rain
Me too
Hope everything will be fine
SKJ865 This is Tokyo Control
118 Navigation point 90
SKJ865
Tokyo Control SKJ865
Altitude 390
SKJ865 Tokyo control roger
Captain, are you all right?
Yeah
My kid had a fever last night, I had little sleep
Do you need coffee?
Then please make an order for me
Is the ring still there?
Yes, but we can't get careless
Why so fast out?
Wait, Masayo
Chocolate
Send stuff to cockpit?
Demostic airlines seldom
encountered this kind of occasions
I'm Nisawa, coffee is here
Come in please
Excuse me
Hi
Miss, you're not supposed to be here
Never mind, Nisawa
She's your senior sis
Ah
Captain, long time no see
Yeah
It's been five years since
I last met you when you resigned
7 years
Can't imagine already so long time
I haven't seen Nakaya for long time too
Hello, I've gone to see Josephine
Oh really?
Wonderful performance
Really? Thanks!
We'll keep supporting you
Captain, meet again some day
Maki
Please have some chocolate
Thanks
Do you want one, Mr. Mouri?
Oh, yes please
Delicious
Why like this?
Uncle it smells like almond
Should be cyanide
It must be the chocolate
The chocolate is poisonus
Chocolate
Don't worry, If the one uncle ate was poisonous,
symptom would show up already
But why Ms. Jyuri would get poisoned
The Captain wants to tell everyone
In order to prevent chaos, hope we can
cover up the things happend untill landing
I understand
But how did the criminal put the poison?
Must be on the chocolate
Because she died just after she ate the chocolate
I think so too
Can't be...
Really it's not me
I bought the chocolate from the usual shop
in Ginza in the afternoon
And it's opened just now
Natsuki, you saw it, didn't you?
Ah
Sorry, I didn't see it clearly
Natuski!
But you are fine after eating it
meaning only part of the chocolate is poisoned
But how to make Jyuri choose the poisonous one?
The broker should know which one she eat first
Really, it's not me
And she follows different orders each time
Jyuri hesitated when she chose the chocolate
Shut up! Don't talk kid!
Anyway I'll keep this box of chocolate first
OK
The rest can only be handed over
to the police after landing
Yeah
In order to protect the crime scene,
please sit back
And the front toilet is also forbidden to use
After boarding, except chocolate, Jyuri also ate
vitamin
But think twice
Couldn't make sure that she would eat it
I know it now
I know who the criminal is
Father?
Who, Who is the criminal?
Listen up
Ms. Jyuri ate two things on the plane
But which two?
One is the chocolate just now
The other is the vitamin
Ms. Tenko gave to Ms. Jyuri
Ah
It's you...
I guess everybody knows the answer now
The criminal who killed Maki Jyuri
on this plane is
Ms. Tenko, it's you!
You're kidding, I'm innocent
Besides I don't have incentive at all
Really?
Everyone has the incentive to kill Jyuri
What are you talking about?
You are the cosmetician Sakai Natuski, right?
What did you mean?
Please listen on
I had been with Jyuri longer than any one else
I know very well about her human relations
First Mr. Ban
Although he's the nominal director if the drama
Actually Jyuri was in charge in the group
He brought up Jyuri all along at first
But now he should obey her
I've seen several times her wife
Tenko blame Mr. Ban for this thing
Narusawa was divorcing with Jyuri three years ago
But he still has attaching to Jyuri
He used to request remarry but got rejected
Jyuri was tired of her young boyfriend Shinjyou
And asked me to introduce her a cute guy
Then the broker Masayo
Jyuri dislikes her of her dumbness and slowness
Always blame her in front of everyone
I myself was played by capricious Jyuri
Wanted to change job,
but she kept being in my way
It's very pleasant to be in an important position,
also hate her at the same time
Isn't it so?
So everyone could be the criminal
You still have appetite even now, Gentai?
What a waste if I don't eat
Delicious
If the poison was on her fingers
Shinjou was the first one
had contact with Jyuri's hand
He put the poison at that time?
No
There are other chances
If the pen has poison on it
Put the poison when turn on the spot lamp
No, there's another possibility
Put poison in the toilet on the place
where possible to contact
If so, Jyuri came out very soon
after got into the toilet
Wait, before that...
Ah
I know it now
I see, so I was...
I don't feel very well
I solved the puzzle
And I know who the criminal is as well
It's weird uncle
Look, what's that?
What?
There's nothing
Ah
What
Huh?
OK, now
Oh no
Hey, what is it on earth?
It seems I made a mistake, I go to toilet
What's wrong with the kid?
No other choice, although this is the first time
Husband, you don't talk like that
What
Damn, wrong voice
Sonoko
Me?
don't keep me guessing, do tell the truth
What
This case doesn't need Kogoro
OK, let me tell the truth
Really
Great, today auntie will give us
a consequence show
Firstly how the criminal poisoned Jyuri
I'll start from this surprising way
Exactly
That is ventilating ears
Ventilating ears
The criminal knew Jyuri
would ventilate her ear on the plane
Using the thumb and forefinger to pinch the nose
This is done normally using the right hand
I guess everyone knows this
When learning diving,
ventilating ears is the first thing to learn
Masters can do that even without pinching nose
But Jyuri has just started to learn
Still needs to do that quite often
Right, husband?
Yes
Wait, how did you know about this?
Ah
When ventilating ears, Ayumi is all the same
Women are too shy to do that in front of men
Moreover Jyuri is a super star
and you were aside
A loser but does count a man
Me?!
So Jyuri went to the toilet to do it
Then back to her seat and took the chocolate
with thumb and forefinger of her right hand
Customarily lick off the cocoa
remained on the hand
She didn't know this habit
let her take the poison completely
What does it mean? Where's the poison?
Don't you feel fuggy?
Yeah
Strange
Actually Jyuri was infracted
by the poison already at first
Exactly. She felt uncomfortable
was because her skin absorbed poison
Skin?
That is...
Exactly
In the car in the parking lot of Haneda airport
Fixed the poison with foundation make-up,
daubed on Jyuri's nose
The criminal who killed Mr. Jyuri
Sakai Natuski, It's you!
How could it be possible?
but your consequence sounds very interesting
Conan has told me
You have blamed the kids
for playing with your foundation make-up
The day when you put the poison
The kids were playing with the make-up,
just in case
You shouted at them telling them
not to touch it, right?
Do you have concrete evidence?
Well...
Ms. Jyuri's right hand thumb and forefinger
If there's make-up and poison by testing
Considerably it could be the evidence
But Jyuri has licked off all the evidence,
there's nothing left to test
But there's still something else
The rest of the poisonous make-up
You are so smart that it's impossible for you
to bring it onto the plane
But it's also too risky to throw it
into the dustbin in the airport
Yes, I'd send it if I were you
Send it back to my home
Contact the post office of the airport,
ask them to check the post, it should work
Can you tell me your home address?
That woman ruined my dreams
Dreams?
I hoped to be a cosmetician in Hollywood
In order to realize my dreams,
I went to cosmetic school in LA
I've learned to speak fluent English
When I got back I was
doing make-up for that woman
while I kept sending job
applications to Hollywood
One month ago, A Hollywood actress came to Japan
The broker company regarded highly about
my skills and hoped that I could go to Hollywood
It's a unique chance for my entire life
But
But that woman...
That woman ruined the chance behind me
It seemed that she didn't want you to leave
It would be OK if she only wanted me
to do make-up for her
But this was not the case
She regarded me as a servitor easy to use
When I got to know this, I decided to kill her
She destroyed my dignity as a cosmetician
Dignity as a cosmetician?
Don't tell jokes
Then why did you choose cosmetics
as your lethal weapon?
You're not competent to talk about dignity
I...
You are still young,
start over after you repay your sin
Why do I have bad premonition?
My head hurts
Oh no
Tell the captain not to eat the snack
sent in just now
Captain will be in danger if not in time
Dumb kid
The snack is not poisonus
The point is not the snack
The captain's hand could have touched the poison
What?
What's going on? tell me
OK, I'm going
Excuse me
As expected
Captain?
What's wrong, captain?
Are you all right?
What's going on?
Nakaya, are you all right?
Captain...
Damn, the auto-pilot system's been cancelled
Cheer up, captain
Captain
Pull him up now, pull the seat back
OK, press the auto-pilot button
Shinjyou
Good job, little brother
It's ok now, send the doctor in fast
OK
There's a passenger suddenly passed out right now
If anyone in the passenger is a doctor,
please tell the waitress around
As expected it's acute chemical toxicosis
I'll do first aid for them
Please move them to the cabin
Yes
Narusawa, Ban, come and help
Bring the first aid kit
OK
Conan, why is the captain also poisoned?
Jyuri has been in the cockpit just now
Captain and copilot kissed her hand
Aha I see, so they touched the poison on her hand
Very unlucky
If only shaking hands, the poison would only
on their palms, wouldn't be in the mouths at all
Doctor, how is it?
Fortunately only tittle poison,
their lives are not in danger
But they are unconscious now,
can't fly the plane at all
What? Captain and copilot are unconscious?
Excuse me, May I have your name?
I'm Shinjyou, a passenger
Shinjyou, what is the status of the fly?
Altitude 12000 feet
Speed 280 nodes
Fortunately the auto-steering system
has also the landing code ready set
I have little experience
on operating flap and undercarriage
Only have to give me timing instructions
I understand
Take off and landing of other planes
are completely stopped
And other captains are called
in to the control tower
Because the weather of Hakodate is not steady
All flights can't take off or land temporarily
Please be patient and wait
Ladies and gentlemen...
So the captain seat is for me
Then the copilot seat
you are in charge of it
Great pilot skills just now
Awesome
Because I have
played in the amusement park a few times
Hey...
Conan, you are rascally
I want to sit too
And me too
This is not playing!
And now it doesn't need steering
But auto-pilot needs some steering when landing??
So I need his assistance
Anyways you don't need a kid
Anyway I will take care of it here
It's going to land in 15 minutes
Please go back to your cabin and have your seats
Shinjyou said he's got pilot experience
Does he have small aeroplane license?
Strange
Father, mother seems asleep
What?
Please go back to your seats
and put on your life belts
Father, sit beside mother
Sigh, can't do anything about her
Hey, wake up
Hey
Sigh
You are Kiddo, right?
I don't know what you're talking about
Don't play dummy
Who will let a schoolboy pilot the plane
Hehe, finally you noticed
About the real Shinjyou...
He disguised as you
and now he's in Hakodate cottage
Isn't it?
Seeing you boarding, Jyuri was very angery
Probably for this carabet,
Jyuri asked Shinjyou to disguise as you
Creditably well-known detective, but...
Someone thinks that Kiddo won't stop
like this and he's already in Hakodate
Maybe now he's still chasing the fake Kiddo
When do you plan to steal the sapphire of fate?
I don't need it any more
Ah
You should have known it also
The real Sapphire tastes freezing
That one was fake
So you did that to know if it's fake
It was for drawing the spectators attention
to the drama
So fake gem was used to imitate the real one
So
Do you still want to prison me?
Detective brother
Of course,
as soon as this big bird goes back to nest
Flight SKJ865
Hand over to Hakodate control in a second
Please change the frequency to 118.35
118.35 roger that
This is Hakodate control
This is Control Chief Uesugi
Now please let captain Shimaoka on the radio
This is Shimaoka
Can you see MCP - Module Control Panel?
Yes, I see
Please press the APP button on it
Thus the plane will automatically
land on the runway
Roger
APP...
It's there
Ah
It's pressed
Who are you?
This is Edogawa Conan
I am Shinjyou's assistant
Assistant?
There's a kid around?
Little boy
Don't touch the joy stick and other buttons
Do you understand?
Yeah
His heart is at rest for now
You know how to steer the flaps
and the undercarriage?
I do
My father taught me how to do it
on the small plane in Hawaii
Reall, I certainly didn't pick the wrong guy
But that's about the theory
I've never piloted a real plane
Terrible weather,
but it should be possible to land
Yeah
Heavy rain
The wind is hard too
The plane won't crash, right?
There's the airport
It's coming
Flight 865, please set the flaps to 1
Set the flaps to 5
Set the flaps to 10
Wheel down, set the flaps to 20
It's going to land
What's going on?
It's lightening,
the plane's been hit by lightening
This is flight 865
After the lightening just now
everything's disappeared
Calm down,
turn the white button beside the dash board
The lights are on
Not all of them
The auto-pilot light is not on
What did you say?
Stop landing,
pull up the steer stick as much as you can
Good, wheel up
It's done
Good, keep climbing
Damn, the wind blew it away
Turn right, turn right now
It'll crash onto the airport lounge
Pull up now
Oh no
No, oh no
What a view
Any problems with the fire in the airport?
Flight 865, do you read?
Loud and clear
How about the damage status?
Zero casualty in the control tower
But I'm afraid the runway
can't be in use right away
How about you there?
Engine 2 detached
It's OK, it's possible to land
with only 4 engines
But you have to take care of the balance
The plane's currently in balance
I've set the rudder to the 3rd throttle
Very good,
how about the current altitude and speed?
3000 feet, 200 nodes
Flaps set to 5, fly horizontally
Head to 180 degrees, climb to 4500 feet
Roger
Then hover waiting to land?
Maybe
If the auto-pilot machine
can be recovered and runway cleared
we can do the auto-landing again
Didn't I say the fire engines were not enough?
Put out the fire on the runway, fast!
Conan, it's too bad
It's too bad
One engine detached
I knew, don't worry
It will do with 3 engines
And the fuel is quite enough...
What?
Almost empty
Fuel out?
What's going on?
Because the engine detached?
The fuel to each engine is provided individually
The fuel valve is on?
Hey, what valve?
It's the fuel valve
Press that button,
the valve for saparating the fuel tanks will open
And turning into a whole fuel tank
Damn, why like this?
Ah
It's all because of that damned old fellow
It seems not much time left
Yeah
There's a map,
Can anyone help me bring it here?
This is flight 865, there's an emmergency
Do you read, control tower? Please respond
Flight 865, This is control,
I don't hear it clearly, please speak louder
hey, too much statics, I can't hear it clearly
What's going on?
Doctor...
One engine detached, the fuel's almost out
What did you say?
Map map...
Should be the red one
Found it
Damn
Auto-pilot system, runway, fuel
Now even the radio is not working
Even the auto-piloting is broken?
So now it's manual piloting?
Conan, map's here
Thank you
The fuel left is about 3000 pounds
300 pounds per minute, so only 10 minutes left
We have to find a place to land within 10 minutes
Find a place to land?
The runway is not going to be in use
within 10 minutes
What if go to Shinchidose airport?
It's too risky, we'll run out of fuel on the way
How about other airports?
Is there any other airport near by?
No
Or maybe the airport in farms or militia base?
The runways are not long enough
Ah
What if we occasionally land on the road?
There are many straight roads in Hakodate, right?
No
The width between the wheels
of the plane is 11 meters
Roads wider than 12 should have saparating
lsland and nameplate in the middle
And there're civilian buildings
and lamp posts around
Then how about farms?
No
The ground is too soft
Then land on the sea surface near by
No, the tide will overturn the plane
Where? where?
There must be a place we can land on
Long and straight, and nothing around
What if we can't land?
Then the plane will crash
I don't want to die
Conan, I know where
Long and straight, and nothing around
Ah
It was in the dolphin TV program last time
Can't help thinking about Muroran
when talking about dolphins
The pier
Shinnittetsu Pier
Nakauhe Pier
West Motowa Pier
Muroran Pier
Nisseki Pier...
Found it!
Sakimori Pier
About 1400 meters in length, 30 meters in width
How about the width of this plane?
Ah
60 meters
Let the other wing stretch to the sea?...
Impossible, not long enough
This kind of plane slides
over 2000 meters when landing
And there's some problem
with the strength of the ground
Don't know if it's fortunate or unfortunate
The fuel is almost out,
and not so many passengers
The lighter, the shorter the plane slides
If the wind blows in the right direction,
it can be even shortened
Ah
I saw the weather forecast in the airport
It'll be west wind all night
Mitsuhiko, is it so?
Yes
This pier is transmeridional(east-west)
If we face the west wind, land from the east end,
maybe we can land successfully
No
I injured my left hand
when crashed onto the control tower
I'm now piloting only by my right hand
If I manually land
I have to use both hand to hold the steer stick
How is your eyesight?
1.5 both
Any disease?
No
how about BWH?
My breast is...
Why?
Good, you are qualified
You sit here instead of me
What are you saying?
Want me to pilot the plane?
Don't worry, I will guide you behind you
You only have to hold the steer stick firmly
No, I can't do it
The plane... the plane's going down
It's going down
Ms. Ran, sit down now
Then pull up the steer stick slowly
Calm down
Good, very good
It's easy, isn't it?
Sounds so easy
What is the direction of Muroran?
I am looking
I found it
Airline Hakodate-Sapporo
It's via around Muroran
The direction is 023 degrees
023, right?
Go over the mountain,
altitude must be greater than 5000 feet
Got it
Please
Please tell the passengers
we are heading to Titose
OK
By the way please tell the 2nd floor
passenger to go to 1st floor
If they knew it's a senior high school
school piloting, it would be a big chaos
You guys go back to your seats as well
You can't help at here
And I need you to conciliate other kids
This is very important, I'll ask
someone else if you don't want to do it
OK, can you do it?
I got it
We'll do our best
We'll take care of it
OK, then it's all up to you
Yes
I want to stay here
If there's an emmergency, only I can help Ran
All right then
I'll explain the rest devices later on
There's not much time
Go
Flight SKJ865
This is Hakodate Control
Do you read? please respond
Sigh, even the spare communication
is not responding
Look
Flight 865 is flying away
Where is it heading to?
There's the Bridge Shiratori
Right, Shiratori
Officer, it should be Bridge Hakutyou
You seggusted me to visit Muroran
on the way back from Sapporo, it's really nice
The bridge Shiratori is really beautiful
I wish one day I can come with Minako
Hehe, I won't choose to come here for sure
Huh?
Why so many police wagons?
Probably chasing a vicious criminal
OK, we go there and take a look
Dear passengers
I am so scared, mom
The plane has encountered a little accident
Is it serious?
We are currently heading
to spare airport - Titose airport
Actually we are going to Muroran, right?
Sh~
We are almost in Muroran
Set the altitude down to 2000 feet
Got it
I see it, lamplight
That is Muroran port,
Sakimori pier is on the near left
At the other end of the bridge Hakutyou
Damn
Look
It's too dark ahead to see anything
We are going to land on this kind of place?
So? We can't turn back any more
Conan, will it work?
What're you gonna do?
It seems bad, I take my leave first
Good luck
Wait
Hey, wait
Ran, drop the prow a bit
Wait, what do you wanna do?
Hold on
What? What happened?
It's ok, don't worry
Keep the plane steady
Kai~ Kaitou Kiddo
Lady, we'll meet again
Hope we can meet again
under the beautiful moonlight
OK
Excuse me
Ah
He jumped?
Yea, Shinjyou is Kiddo
That's why he pushed the botton
to reduce the air pressure in the cabin
He's afraid to crash, so fled first
What a shame, I had respected him so much
Sonoko, it's not bound to crash
But Conan...
What should we do next?
Now we can only rely on ourselves to land, Ran
Don't worry, Ran
The three musketeers are equal to a Napolean
We will be OK
For christ's sake, it's no Napolean
It should be Napoleon
Was I wrong?
Anyway we hover over the pier
and see how it will be
Help
Help me
I am not Kiddo,
you must've mistaken me as someone else
Then why did you run away?
Because I stole the clock
I knew it, you are Kiddo
Officer Nakamori
What?
What is that?
Hm
It's obviously Kiddo
Kiddo?
Then who are you?
I've said you recognized the wrong guy
Sonoko, how is it?
No way
Only some places have lamplight
But almost completely dark,
I can't see it clearly at all
Damn
Ran, are you all right?
Ran, what's wrong with you?
I don't now, my body starts to shiver
Conan, I still can't do it
No, you'll make it
Damn, it's too dangerous if it's still like this
Sonoko, let's make a change
I go to the toilet
Toilet?
I'll be right back
The radio's going to be back online soon,
you'd better put on the earphones
Wait...
Ah
Give me a break,
go to the toilet when it's so urgent
That's why I don't like little boys
Hello hello
Ran
Ran, can you hear it?
Shinichi?
I am calling from Sapporo control tower
It seems that you are in a dangerous situation
But everything will be ok
Calm down and do as I tell,
then you'll land safely
I will protect you, don't worry
Ran, do you hear me?
Ran, answer him
Nonsense
Only tell me this kind of good words
Do you know?
All passenger's lives are in my hand
Don't talk so easy for christ's sake
You are never around when it's urgent,
only give me a call
Sometimes you were back,
you disappeared right away
Every time...
I've had enough, I don't want to listen on
Shinichi brother said this
Ran, wait for me
Don't ever think about escape
I will be right back
Always leave me alone
He said he hoped you can wait for him
Who do you think I am?
I...
I love you, Shinichi
Ran...
There's lamplight, I see lamplight!
Red lamplight flowing like a belt
What?
Aha, I see
Damn, damned Kidd, don't ever think about escape
Hey, Kiddo is heading to the pier
I got it
Kiddo is heading to the pier
Team A and B go around
to the other side to surround him
Occupy the sides of the pier with police cars
Team C follow me
I'll catch Kiddo
Grandpa, there're so many police cars
What happened?
It seems they are heading this way
Ran, prepare for landing
Those lamplight should be
the police cars allured by Kiddo
So Kiddo jumped off to...
Use the light from the police cars to be a runway
Creditably my saint Kiddo
I knew it that he is a good guy
Ran, turn left again
Got it
Find out Kiddo now!
He must be around, find him!
Hey, have you find him?
No
How about there?
It's up to you, well-known detective
Dear passengers,
our plane will make a emmergency landing
Please put on your safety belts
and follow the staff's instructions
Please put aside your pens and glasses and put your
high heeled shoes in the bag under the seats
Bow yourselves
and put your heads between your legs
Ran, listen up, we are going to land
How about the current altitude and speed?
Altitude 700 feet, speed 140 nodes
Very good, keep the decline rate at 3
Sonoko
Release the undercarriage and flaps
undercarriage? flaps?
Undercarriage lever is that one
Flap lever is this one
Got it
Pull down the undercarriage lever
Pull up the flap lever
Ah, What happened?
What's wrong?
Shinichi, the fuel's running out
Got it
There isn't a second chance, we have to make it
Officer Megure
Hm?
That plane...
Seems it's coming this way
Why?
Pull up prow, pull the power lever to the end
Everybody take cover!
Prow down
Eject in converse direction
Stop stop stop
Shinichi, there's a crane in the front
We are crashing
Damn
Take the rudder, right foot step onto the pedal
Stopped
The plane's stopped
Great
Kuto, it seems there's no such word
as impossible in your dictionary
Awesome, Ran
Ran?
Ran, cheer up
Sonoko?
Aha, just passed out
no wonder
It was really hard for you this time
Good job, Ran
Blood pressure and pulse are very normal
It should be no problem
But anyway we send you to the hospital
and have further examination
Thank you
Is Sonoko all right?
She's not injured at all
It must be that she's over scared and passed out
That's good
Please write down your name and address here
OK
And your BWH
Great landing just now
Ki...
Then we shall meet again
Tell me your BWH next time
Ki... Ki...
Hey
Ran, it's me
Shinichi?
Listen to me...
It wasn't you who called a while ago, was it?
I knew it, it was Kiddo
What?
I felt strange, it seemed that you could see me
And I heard Conan shouting in the middle
Damn
But Sonoko told me that Kiddo had jumped
Actually I was sneakingly...
I got it, the guy jumped off
was Kiddo's understrapper
What?
Kiddo disguised as someone
and stayed on the plane
It was good that it wasn't you
Not a bit
Very good, good that it's not blabed
What blabed?
The secret between Kiddo and me
Tell me
No, take a guess, aren't you a detective?
How could I know?
Then ask Kiddo after you've caught him
You!