Marutakeebisuni Oshioike
Rokakku Bride..Takonishiki
Shiayabttakamatu
Wan five units
The snow shoes..
ding-ding-dong-dong
Passing through the 6th
and the 7th..and the 8th
You'll get to the Tonsi Avenue
And the final one
is the ninth avenue
Detective Conan
Crossroad in the Ancient Capital
I am a high school student
Kudo Shinichi
When I went to the amusement park
with my childhood friend
Mouri Ran
I witnessed an illegal deal
I just paid attention
to the deal
but ignored an accomplice
coming from my back
I was forced to drink the poison
After I woke up
My body shrank
If they know Kudo Shinichi
is still alive
I will be in danger
and moreover..
my loved ones will be affected
Under Dr. Agasa's suggestion
I have to disguise myself
When Ran asked my name
Without a second thought
I told her I am Edogawa Conan
In order to gather information
about those guys
I moved into Ran's place
Her father is a detective
I am Hattori Heiji
a high school detective in Kansai
My reasoning
and skill of martial arts
were passed on to me
from my father
And I inherited my boldness
from my mom
My dark skin complexion
came from my grandfather
There's saying..
Hattori in the west, Kudo in the east
We are equally popular
But Kudo is really outstanding
Using the strange machines
invented by Dr. Agasa
He has broken many cases
Besides the doctor and me..
there're other people
knowing his real identity
Kudo's father and mother
And Kudo's classmate
Haibara Ai
This kid..
He used to be the partner
of the man in black
But after he got out
of the organization
She was forced to drink
the poison
so her body shrank too
I have a childhood partner
She's Tooyama Kazuha
a nagging woman
Who's nagging?
Hey
Don't show up without any notice
Pighead
You are the pighead
Who are you talking to?
Come on
I'm explaining to the audience
Right?
Are you crazy?
You are crazy!
Your body shrank
but your brain did not
There's only one truth
Here we're at Beika Station
The exit is..
So you can't come back
temporarily
See..
I'm working on a case
Got it
It's pretty cold lately..
You have to take care
Same to you..
Don't forget to cover the belly
That has never happened to me
idiot
Yoshinoyama
Stepping on the white snow
in the mountains
in order to look for
any living signs
You are not Yoshitune
and Shizuka Gozen
What's wrong?
You are worried about
your childhood friend?
My father is being nagging now
I gotta go
Ah..hey
Come on
I have to call
when he's not there next time
Yoshitune and Shizuka Gozen
Haven't they met each other
after the departure?
Hey..hey
(Tokyo Nishikunitati)
(Kamei no Rokurou)
(Kataoka no Hatirou)
(Washinoo no Shitirou)
Benkei is so slow
Right..he claims that
he has solved the problem
Because that guy is very interested
in this
Kataoka
(Osaka, during the night)
(Neyagawa City, Takohei)
(Bizen no Heishirou)
(Kyoto, during the dawn)
(Tosan District, Zirou Bar)
(Suruga no Zirou)
According to the investigation
The five victims murdered
in Tokyo, Osaka, and Kyoto
used to be the members
of the robbery ring, Genzihotaru
As to this incident..
Satou
They say Captain Aynokouzi
in Kyoto Police Precinct
used to be the Shiratori's classmate
Yes
As the descendant of an imperial
minister he is nicknamed Captain Royalty
Look at his left pocket
What is that?
That is his pet, a squirrel
He always carries it
no matter where he goes
He's weirder than Shiratori
Starting from the year of 1991
Genzihotaru has been stealing
famous Buddhist statues or artifacts
around Tokyo, Kyoto,
and Osaka areas
They call each other by the name
of the servants in the Yoshitune's
Every one of them
has a Yoshitune Book
Yoshitune is the leader
There are totally 8 members
including Benkei and Ise no Saburou
Five of them have been killed
and their Yoshitune Books
have been taken away
Do you have any clues?
We only know the murder
is good at sword craft and using arrows
As to Yoshitune, Benkei,
and Ise no Saburou
We don't know their age or gender..
However
In order to round up
the other accomplices
We'll do our best
in the investigation
(Hattori's Residence)
Yoshitune is the leader
of the robbery ring
Heiji, are you there?
Come on
Isn't this very important?
Yes..
I have to keep it
Heiji..are you going out?
Yes..I need to check out something
How can I help you?
I'd like to invite you to appreciate
cherry blossoms in Tomorogi
But..forget about it
Really?
I gotta go
Take care then
Oh
Why do I have to
see him off with smiles?
Kyoto is really a good place
Listen
I brought you here
with a good will..
Don't interfere with my work
Alright
No problem
Conan has left for Kyoto
There is a temple
called Sannouzi
So Mouri is asked to
probe into the case
We'd like to go to Kyoto soon
I can take you there
Really?
So I can see Conan there
Kyoto..Kyoto..
We'll go to..
But you have to answer
these questions..
Here we go
You aren't planning to
take us there
That has nothing to do
with this
Let him do it
Perhaps we can kill some time
What can we do?
Let's give it a try
That's right
You know who Benkei is
Right?
Yes..he's Yoshitune's servant
Hey..who's Yoshitune?
His nickname is Usiwakamaru
On the 5 big bridges in Kyoto
He defeated Benkei who wanted to
get the 1 000th sword
At that time, the Genzi
and the Hira were in a war
And Yoshitune won
However, his brother, Razou
hated him
At last he killed himself
in Hiraizumi no Koromogawa
I know a lot about him
I'll ask you some questions now
Benkei has a lover
called Uzune
That girl is gonna marry
someone else
After Benkei knows about this
He will be..1.angry
2.happy
3.sad
Which one is true?
First lover?
Of course he will be angry
He can't be happy
So you think the answer is 1?
It's "sad"..
The answer is 3
You get the idea from
"Benkei's weakness"
Ai is so cool
What is "Benkei's weakness"
Benkei is outstanding..
but he cries when he's hurt too
That's here
The fore part of the leg
is called "Benkai's weakness"
But does this have anything
to do with the question?
Uhh..
I see
So the groom and Uzune
will get married
The groom and Uzune
Groom Uzune (In Japanese,
it sounds like the fore part of the leg)
It's not funny at all
But..since we've got
the right answer
We can go to Kyoto now
Ah..no
Because Ai got the right answer
And he's a member
of the Youth Detectives
Don't estrange Haibara
My mom told me
to keep my promises
Thanks for your patronage
Thanks..
That's right
But you can't tell others
about this
(Ryuen, a monk in Sannouzi)
Oh..Mr. Mouri
Thanks for coming
I am Ryuen..
I talked to you on the phone
Please allow me to introduce to you
This is the master, Enkai
These three are the faithful
of this temple
This is Mr. Sakura Syouzou
He's running an antique shop
on Teramati Road
Are you the famous detective
Mouri Kogorou
Ah..really?
Am I famous?
And this one is a young master
Mizou Syuntarou
This is Mr. Saizyou Taiga
the owner of a 2-hand book store
Nice to know you
Actually the faithfuls and us
are friends in swordcraft
Everyone is learning swordcraft?
No wonder you look so healthy
Friends in swordcraft?
By the way..
they say in this temple
there's a Buddhist statue
presented to the public every 12 years
Yes
That is the main statue of this temple
Medicine Buddha
And it will be presented for worships
the day after tomorrow
We are looking forwards to it
Thanks to you
I bet the Buddha will be delighted
What are you saying?
The Buddha is gone?
Yes..it happened 8 years ago
On the left side is
Sun Buddha
and the right..
Moon Buddha
But in the center, Medicine Buddha
was stolen
I meant to report to the police
but the master stopped me
He said..
let the fate be
He's really optimistic
So it's been 8 years now
But 5 days ago..
a letter was tossed in the mailbox
without any stamps on it
There's no sender
and it says we can find the statue
if we solve the puzzle
What map is it?
Thanks..sir
It's really hard to look for
eye-witnesses to this kind of cases
There's a thief
Get away
It hurts
You'd better watch out
If I hit your Benkei's weakness
You'll suffer
This is yours..madam
Thank you..
You were so great
Really..thanks
I am running a tea house
in Miyagawatyou
My name is Yamakura Tae
Say hello to them
Yes
I am Tika Suzu..
Nice to meet you
How should I repay you?
It's not necessary..
Please drop by my shop
next time
Take care then
Thank you
What is this map about?
On the 5th layer..
you see cricket, dog, and gold fish
And the 4th layer..
chicken and..loach?
The yellow loach looks disgusting
What is it?
It should be just stains
And in between the 2nd and the 3rd
There are violet, dogs,
and Fuji mountain
And next to them are nuts
Father
Can we find it
before the day after tomorrow?
Don't worry
I can handle it..
A piece of cake
Hey..is that true
Let the experts handle it
Let's go visit Kyoto now
Go ahead
You will only make troubles
Actually I talked to Kazuha
She will take us to Kyoto
tomorrow
But she said Hattori will be busy
It doesn't matter
since he's not available now
That guy is not coming
Conan..come with us
Ah..I'm not going with you
I'm going fishing with the kids
living nearby
Wow..you have made local friends
so quickly
But you have to be careful
I bet Genzihotaru
must be the thief
But
Why is there a map?
And is there any connection
with the 5 murder cases?
Genzihotaru..
Speaking of Yoshitune and Benkei
I think that's the only place
we should check out
(The 5 Big Bridges)
I don't see anything related to
this mysterious map
On the 5 big bridges in Kyoto
The strong man, Benkei
held his long sword
and waved it towards Usiwakamaru
Hattori
I can't believe
I will meet you here
It's really interesting
for us to meet here
Sir..can I have the knife back?
Oh..I'm sorry
Thanks
Let's go
You have to practice more
Why did you borrow the knife?
Let's not talk about this
What are you doing here?
I wanna ask you this question
The owner of an octopus ball shop
in Osaka was killed
We were very familiar
Although he was rumored to be
a member of the gang
I often visited that shop
when I was a student
He was nice to me
So I wanna find out the murder
and take revenge for him
That's why you come here
to look for the clues
If so..I wanna show you something
I see
Just solve this puzzle
You can not only
find the statue
but also get the clues
critical to the murder case
That's why you..
Right
If Genzihotaru was the one
who stole the statue
Maybe we can find clues
to the puzzle
at the places involved with
Yoshitune and Benkei
But I'm not familiar with Kyoto
So..count on me
I'll lead you
This is the 5 Gods
According to Yoshitune Book
They didn't first meet on the bridge
but at this place
So..is there any connection?
No..I don't think so
So let's go to the next place
But I can't accept it
Why doesn't the monk
ask me for the help?
I should be the first one
he comes up with in Kansai area
They don't want to
expose the incident
Because your father
is a high-ranking police official
Forget it
Wait..it's really weird
We're here..
It's right here
Benkei Stone?
Benkei often sat on it
Someone said he threw it down
from Hiezan Mountain
There are numerous legends
But there's no connection
with one another
Really..
let's check out the next place
Where are we going then?
Keage Slope
I am a police detective in Kyoto
Ayanokouzi
You're probing into
Genzihotaru's case?
This is not Osaka
You'd better not get involved
It's a squirrel
You see?
There are strange detectives
everywhere
(Kiyomizudera Temple)
Let's take pictures now
I want the cheery blossoms
to be the background
It's so beautiful
It's really beautiful
It would be great
if Makoto was here too
Ran..you are embarrassing me
You often do that to me too
Kazuha..
You had a quarrel with Hattori?
Heiji often comes to Kyoto
for a certain case
And his first lover
also lives in Kyoto
(Keage Slope Park)
(Yoshitune Sun Buddha)
This is not right
Let's go have lunch
Alright
Cheery blossoms
It's nothing
It reminds me of
what happened 8 years ago
I had an adventurous trip
to temples in Kyoto
My head hit the window frame
of a temple
and the frames were broken
and I fell to the ground
I fainted
and I don't know
how long I slept..
When I came to myself
I just remembered
Passing through 8 avenues
I'll get to Tonsi Avenue
And the last one is
the 9th Avenue
Maarutakeebisuni
Oshioike
Rokakku Bride
Takonishiki
Shiayabttakamatu
Wan 5 units
Snow shoes..ding-ding-dong-dong
6 units..
It was like a dream
but I'm sure it happened to me
I felt someday we'll meet again
Hey..what's so funny about it?
I'm sorry
Please go on
I'll take this with me
whenever I come to Kyoto
Crystal ball?
I have seen it somewhere before
Really?
Does anyone have the same thing?
Nope
So..does she know about this?
She?
You mean Kazuha?
I have never mentioned to her
but she seems to know about it
It's because..
The magazine report?
Right..a very popular magazine
in Kansai area..
The reporter interviewed Heiji
about his first love
He met a girl a little bit older
than him when he was in the 3rd year
And he showed something
very important to that girl
and we shot pictures too
What is this?
An ordinary crystal ball
I think the girl gave him this
So you and that girl..
I don't know her
And Heiji seems to have met her
only once
He visits her
whenever he comes to Kyoto
Ah..that's why he holds
the ball in the picture
He wants to show to that girl
through the report
He's pretty wicked
And there's a picture of him
in his childhood
Wow..so cute
Right..Heiji at this time.
Ran..this is not important
Don't care too much about it
Even if he has a first lover
That's the past
I think your relationship
is very stable
But for men..
first love is very special
Sonako
Don't talk about this anymore
By the way..Would you like to
drink some adzuki bean soup?
Madam..3 bowls
Please serve them quickly
This is the west gate
of Kuramadera
Usually we have to go from
Renwan Gate
But it's faster to go from here
(Kuramadera Temple)
( Altitude: 588 meters)
This is Sango Fudoudone
Uniwakamaru met sky-dog
and learned swordcraft from him
This is a good place
for practicing swordcraft
But this tree is really tall
Heiji..this is..
Get down
Don't run
Hey..Kudo
This guy is like Uniwakamaru
Damn
Kudo..catch it
Gotta go
He's coming right after us
How can he make it?
(Kuramadera Temple)
(Kuramadera Station)
Please get on the train now
The train will leave right away
No..you don't have to rush
Hey..this is the rail
I will be distracted
Don't talk to me
Violation of traffic law
You'll get your license suspended
What does he want?
Damn
We can almost make it
That should be the one
who killed Genzihotaru's members
I think so
But I don't know
why he wants to kill you
It's so strange..Heiji
Why are you here?
I bumped into Ku..
No..this kid
We wanted to solve the puzzle
And how about it now?
Not yet
It's pretty hard
By the way..
has the uncle solved it?
Eh..
I really miss her
The dangling ribbon..
Good job..Ms. Tika Suzu
The first in Japan
Thanks..for your compliment
Come..pour wine for Master Mouri
Yes
Please..
Kogorou is so delighted
So don't come back anymore
Why are you here?
The master told us
The master told you to come?
So do you wanna come along?
I'm sorry for the bother
It's strange..
You are from Miyagawatyou..
Yes..I am Tika Suzu
Thanks for the help
Do you know each other, Heiji?
Ah..I think so
Come on..
You get out of the line again
Ran..don't blame him
We invited him to come
Right
Let's ask the famous detective
to analyze Genzihotaru's case
They say all of their members
have a Yoshitune Book
I have one
That is a good book
Right..2-hand book dealer
Yes
But I don't like it very much
Its name is Yoshitune Book..
But in fact..it's a biography
of Benkei's admirable deeds
I like it very much
Especially the "Secure Residence"
What does that mean?
It's the name of a Noh play
In order to escape
the pursuit
Yoshitune and his servants
disguised themselves as monks
and planned to pass the checkpoint
at the secure residence
When Yoshitune
was almost discovered
Benkei used his King-kong stick
to hit Yoshitune
Why?
In order to deceive the guards
No one will ever believe
a servant will hit his master
And then Yoshitune passed
the checkpoint
When Benkei asked for pardon
with tears
Yoshitune complimented him
for his quick wits
You can see the strong tie
in their relationship
It has become a famous story
I'm sorry..
I don't have enough sleep here
Can I take a rest here?
There's no other guest tonight
You can go to the next room
No..I prefer the rooms downstairs
So..please wake me up
at 9 o'clock
Please enjoy now
Wow..I can see the river
That is Kamogawa River
The cherry blossoms
are so beautiful
Yeah..
Ran..come over
It's not bad for valentines
to sit by the river
But it's even better
to appreciate the blossoms
across from Misogigawa
Yeah..so beautiful
Ayah..I can't believe it
It's like white fish
I wanna eat it
Are you wounded?
Yes..a little bit
Let Kogorou heal you
Don't go overboard
You just don't get it
Hey..look over there
Captain Ayanokouzi
What is he doing over there?
You can appreciate blossoms
on that platform
After the clouds go away
we can see the moon
Let's check it out
Mmm..alright
I'll stay here
So will I
Why?
Are you interested
in that dancer?
Idiot..don't say that
I lost
That guy is crazy
He's always like that
Tika Suzu..
One more time..one more time
I wanna go to the toilet
That's alright
I'm not drunk
You stay with Master Mouri
Yes
Alright..it's my turn
Oh..the moon is coming out
Moon?
What's wrong?
Nothing
It reminds me of
my appointment with Ran
It was 2 hours later
when I remembered it
That's incredible
I thought she's left
But I still went to that place
Who is it?
I'm sorry..Ran
I forgot about the appointment
Great
I've been worrying about you
It was that time..
You found she wasn't
just your childhood friend
Idiot
That's not true
I have been..
Now she's still waiting for me
Ran..what's wrong with you?
Nothing
Heiji that guy..
I'm really pissed
But..Kazuha
I envy you
Because you can see each other
anytime you want
Ran
That's right
It's not easy for me
to see Makoto
There are too many troubles
for girls
Come on now
Compared with us
Your father is really energetic
Ayah
Mr. Sakura
It's 9 o'clock now
I'm sorry for the bother
It's so strange..
Where is he?
Is he..
Mr. Sakura
Strange?
What's going on with the scream?
Help
What's wrong?
Mr. Sakura..
Mr. Sakura
Don't let anyone come in
Ran..call the police
Alright
The neck artery is cut
with a sharp knife
It's like done by a pro
Maybe along with a series of cases
they are done by the same person
Classmate?
No wonder you look familiar
You are the student detective
Hattori Heiji
Right
Before the police comes
Please stay in your room
and don't come outside
I now
I think Mr. Sakura was killed
while he was looking for something
What was he looking for?
The button on this shirt
was torn down
The criminal couldn't wait to
take the clothes off
But the wallet full of cash
wasn't stolen
So it wasn't about money
Don't touch the corpse
How many times should I repeat?
It hurts
Coming
I am a police detective in Kyoto
Ayanokouzi
Thank you for coming
Please come in
Stay outside
Yes
Isn't this the detective?
You are so fast
You don't bring your squirrel?
I don't bring it out
everyday
What do you think
about this case?
It's not impossible
for outsiders to do it
But the door makes noise
when it's opened
And the madam
should've heard it
So it's more likely..
the murder knew
Mr. Sakura would be in the warehouse
That's to say..
Mr. Sakura's friends..
Saizyou, Ryuen, and Mizuo
are more likely to be the suspects
They went to the toilet respectively
after Mr. Sakura and Ran
went out
And the stair to the basement
is next to the toilet
So they could pretend
going to the toilet
and kill Mr. Sakura
in the basement
But I'm confused with one thing
Ms. Tika Suzu going with
Mr. Mizuo to the toilet
It's common for dancers
to do that
But she didn't go with
Mr. Ryuen and Saizyou
That's because she was playing
with the uncle
So we can say..
The murder went to the toilet
at this time
We can presume the murder
is either Mr. Ryuen or Saizyou
And Mr. Mizuo is innocent
If Ms. Tika Suzu isn't
the accomplice
That's right..
so..let's go now
You can't pretend
You took that away
for the investigation
You mean this?
I remember his shop
is located on Shitin Road
(Sakura Antique Shop)
Yoshitune Book
Ise no Saburou
Hattori
What?
Mr. Sakura is Ise no Saburou
What is this?
This..
The copy of this map
What's going on?
Mr. Sakura's map shows..
He mailed the letter
to the temple
But for what?
What?
Sakura is Ise no Saburou?
Yes..he's the member
of Genzihatoru
Wait..so the victims are..
Am I the next one
for I have "5" in my name
That happened long ago
Since Sakura's map
is just a duplicate
That means Sakura
has the original with him
And the murderer took it away
I see
The killer didn't know
Sakura has a copy
Who will he be?
I think Mr. Ryuen, Saizyou
and Mr. Mizuo are the suspects
One of them..
But they are not armed
Because we've checked their bodies
after you left
No one will be so stupid
that he brings the weapon with him
He should've dumped it
or hid it
We haven't found anything
in the shop
What about Misogigawa River
Is it thrown out of the window
in the basement?
Right..I think so
Sonako heard some noise
from the river
Really?
That's right
But the police found nothing
in the search
It's really strange
So there are accomplices
I think someone has picked
up the weapon
I don't think so
Why no?
Conan
It's full moon tonight
It's very bright tonight
If there's any fissures..
we can see under
If there are accomplices
Ran should have discovered that
Right
I know the truth
The murder is from the outside
Before Ran came to the platform
He sneaked into
from the basement window
and hid himself
in the toilet
He killed Mr. Sakura
when he looked for something
And then escaped
from the window
We didn't see anyone suspicious
There are no eye-witnesses
This is just a coincidence
This is just a co-incidence
And the murderer
is just lucky
I think it's not true
We met that guy
on Kuramadera Mountain
Kazuha..hold tight
What?
Stay here..you see
Heiji
Wanna challenge me?
Fine
What?
There are weaknesses everywhere
Does he wear
any wrist protection pad?
Are you the one
who killed Mr. Sakura?
If so..
I'll treat you
like how you treat him
This is not what you want
The sight gets blurry
Mr. police
Here..
Heiji..are you okay?
Kazuha..how about the police?
That's not real
Where did you learn this?
What a terrible woman
Heiji
(Mayshirou Hospital)
Heiji..are you awake?
Heiji..
Great
I'm so worried about you
Heiji
Mr. Ootaki
And..who is this?
I am Shiratori
from the Police Department
I heard Sakura used to be
a member of Genzihotaru
So I came immediately
Is it painful?
It is..
We have found the stolen artifacts
in Sakura's shop
Are you awake?
Mr. Police
How about that knife?
I'll ask someone to test it
Please inform me
when the result comes out
If there's no enough evidence
You can take samples
from my wound on the shoulder
Eh? What evidence?
The knife was used
to kill Mr. Sakura
It's better if we can find
anything the murder touched
What about the motorcycle?
Isn't there a motorcycle?
That is a stolen one
Can you find the evidence?
By the way..
Do you have any ideas?
This was found in Yoshitune Book
in Sakura's place
You have no ideas?
Forget about it
After this incident
you'd better be careful next time
So..I gotta go
Take care..
I'll call my father
I'll ask the doctor for you
Conan is with me
Ran..I gotta go out
Please take care of Heiji
Are you not gonna
stay in the hospital?
I'll be alright
But that guy is really weird
I have never seen
the swordcraft style
Maybe he has added iron bars
to the protection pad
I meant to match the weapon
with the wound
That's why I made him
hurt me with the knife
But he didn't take away
the knife
Why not?
Not only that..
When we fought..that guy
wanted to pick the bag I dropped
I don't get it
Is that masked guy
your first lover?
Bingo
How is this possible?
(Mizuo's Residence)
You were attacked afterwards?
That's why I wanna know
if Mr. Mizuo has an alibi?
Because the murderer
wore a Noh-play mask
A Noh-play mask
Can I ask Mr. Saizyou and Ryuen?
if they have the alibi?
We too?
Come on
We meant to discuss on the case
with Ms. Tika Suzu
Right?
That's alright
After I left the tea house
I headed home directly
But I'm single
So there's a distance
between my mom's room and mine
I can't prove
if I were at home at that time
Neither can I
Because I live on the 2nd floor
of the shop at Shiting Road
I chanted at the hall
and went back to my room
No one can prove for me
I see..
I have another question
Do you practice shooting arrows?
Arrows?
Nope
I used to do it
on the Noh-play stage
I tried to imitate
shooting the devil with arrows
So no one in the tea house
was able to use arrows
I remember ..Yamakura
Mrs. Yamakura practices
shooting arrows?
But she wasn't there
Ah..sorry
Sorry for the bother
Ah..she's coming
Strange
What?
Come in..
Sister..
You must be Ms. Tika Suzu
Yes..I am
You must be surprised
at my look
Yes..please come in
Thanks
Thanks for your help
Please come again
You are welcome
Thanks..goodbye
Sannouzi Temple
is on Rokakku Road
This is Ichan Road
Marutakeebisuni
Oshioike
Sister Rokakku
So it's the 6th road
Marutakeebisuni
Oshioike
What was that?
Eh..we call it a ball song
It's made up with
all the avenues in Kyoto
Marutakeebisuni
Oshioike
Sister Rokakku
Takonishiki
Shiayabttakamatu
Wan five units
Snow shoes
Ding-ding-dong-dong
Passing through the 6th
and the 7th..and the 8th
You'll get to Township Avenue
And then you'll see
the 9th avenue
All the kids in Kyoto
remembers road names this way
So you are from Kyoto too?
I am..
How old are you?
19?
This is Oshioike Road
I gotta go
Goodbye
You think she is..
I can't make any mistake
She's from Kyoto
and she's 2 years older than me
But all the kids in Kyoto
are familiar with the song
Finally I can see her
Finally
Hey
Heiji..what are you doing?
How can you get out
of the hospital without permission?
Ah..Mr. Ootaki
Forget it..
Let's not talk about this
The test result is out
Sakura's blood is detected
on the knife
And the wound cut
matches the knife's blade
Really?
You'd better listen to me
Don't do anything stupid
If anything happens to you
how am I gonna..
I see
Thank you..
Mr. Ootaki
So we can say..the man
with the mask attacked me
and also killed Mr. Sakura
And those 4 guys
unable to get rid of the weapons
are not the suspects anymore?
Conan..what are you doing here?
Why are you here?
Because we've answered
Dr. Agasa's question..
But Genta..
He's lost
If we call him
he is not able..
We have contacted him
But he can't read Chinese words
So he can't tell us
where he is now
We want to look for him
with your glasses
Ok..count on me
Hey
This is interesting..
It's over there
Come on..
There's a murder case here
Yes..
I'll explain to you later
Come on
Ai..give me the drug
What is that?
The drug controlling
the growling of the stomach
The doctor invented it
for wedding banquets
And those who can't
drink wine at all
Also..there are drugs
giving you symptoms of colds
Ai assisted in the invention
None is useful
Oh..here
He's in Rokakku Hall
Great
Mom
I found Genta
I'm saved
Great..Genta
I thought I can't see you anymore
I did too
But this is very convenient
A badge communicator
Yes..
The signal is sent from that device
This and the glasses
use the same frequency
Heiji
Now I see
What's going on?
Kudo..is it possible..
It can't be wrong
Ah..what that sister heard
was the noise
of dumping the weapon
Now we can say..
the killer is among the 4
No..among the 3
My first lover
can't be the killer
Hey
It's strange
There's something different
from what I heard before
My first lover sang "Bride Rokakku"
instead of "Sister Rokakku"
How come?
How do I know that?
I have found the broken pieces
of the glasses
Captain
Why do you sigh?
What is this?
These were worn
on those victims
One, wearing a hat
one, scarf
and the other, gloves
All the color, pattern, and clothes
are the same
You don't feel anything strange
It's strange
Eh..why?
If reasonable for one person
to wear the 3 at the same time
If Mekurashi wears this hat
And I wear this scarf
and you wear the gloves
Don't you think it's strange?
Indeed
It feels like Shiratori is dead
and we share his belongings
That's it
Eh..what's going on?
I'm hungry
Be patient
Ms. Taki Suzu's mom
was an actress Miyagawatyou
She died
when she was five
She wasn't married
So Yamakura Tae
brought her up
She wasn't married
Eh..
She bore the baby
without getting married
She didn't know
who the father was..
but every month
someone mailed her some money
But 3 months ago
the support was interrupted
It sounds strange
The money wasn't sent
3 months ago
But how do you know this?
Captain Royal told you?
Nope
Don't look down on me
I'm quiet famous here
This is nothing at all
Everyone says
he's my rival
But I'm not the kind of person
who carries a squirrel everyday
Squirrel?
Yes..he put it in the pocket
But he doesn't take it
to the murder scene
Squirrel..
Yes..I am Shiratori
I am Mekurashi
As to Yoshitune and Benkei
we've come up with one idea
Sharing the leftovers?
If we put it that way
we can solve the puzzle?
That's to say..
one of them may have died
I see
Mr. Mouri
You know
who the murder is now?
Yes
Let me tell you
The murder is..
Ms. Taki Suzu..
You are the one
How is this possible?
This is nonsense
He's alright
Anyway..
let him finish his analysis
You want to take revenge
for your father
And your father was Yoshitune
the leader of the gang
But his men betrayed him
and killed him 3 months ago
That's why he stopped
mailing the money
I see
and you have an accomplice
That is Benkei
Benkei?
As to that person..
Captain Royal..it's you
Ms. Taki Suzu
You brought something
to the tea house
That is the knife
and the captain's squirrel
Wow..so cute
This is the key to the trap
Ms. Taki Suzu
You pretended to go to
the toilet during the banquet
And killed Mr. Sakura
in the warehouse
And tied the knife
to that man
You left it go
through the basement window
The squirrel jumped into
Seage River
And then was picked up
by the captain down the stream
After that..the knife
was used to hurt Heiji
So the noise
was caused by the squirrel
You are also involved
in the other murder cases
Mr. Captain..
Can you use arrows?
How can I use it?
Are you sure?
But Ms. Taki Suzu
The arrow shooters
usually have a wound here
Indeed
My "yanomakura"
is wounded too
But I just learned
and I couldn't hurt anyone
I think so
My friends told me
only the beginners hurt that part
And if you get killed
how can you share the leftovers
Mr. Mouri
You think she's the killer?
No..I mean
You must be kidding
The dancers have to
perform shows and greet guests
I don't have time to do it
Uncle
What's up?
As to that squirrel
It's so small
I think it can't move the knife
You are very nagging
Then I'll prove to you
Do it now..Squirrel
I can't stand it
You intend to ignore me
so as to get out of the guilt
Stop
It's pitiful..sir
You are teasing the animal
You'd better shut up
Genta..go save the squirrel
Oh
Kudo
Ah..thanks to the uncle
I know who the murderer is
So do I
Only the arrow shooters
will say that
We just have to find out
the proof and..
the Buddha statue
You are so poor..squirrel
Let's feed them
I have nuts
It's like the song
"Nuts, rolling and rolling"
Nuts, rolling and rolling?
Maybe..
Hey..what's wrong with you
Kudo?
Maybe the duplicated map
refers to the roads in Tokyo
What are you talking about?
Firstly..it's an east-west road
And on the 5th layer
there are 5 roads
The 4th layer
there are 4 roads
And in between the 2nd the 3rd layer
There is Oshioike road
The proof is..
Nuts, rolling and rolling?
And then the south-north roads..
There's a song
referring to violets
So this means Shichuan Road
The sky-dog
comes form Kara-sky-god
So it means Karasuma Road
And there's "fu"
on "Fuji Mountain"
So it means Fu-shao Road
What about the chicken?
Loach has something to do
with Laochan Pot
So this means
Laoma Road
And the chicken
Does that mean..
Shitonyan Road
Because it means west
It's so hard
What does this mean?
There's a kind of cricket
called Yo-cricket
And the sky-god
refers to Karasuma Road
The gold fish has something
to do with wheat powder
So it means
Fuwutin Road
And then the violet
and Fuji have the same color
Connect the chicken, cricket,
gold fish, and sky-god
Wang (Chinese character)
How come?
This is the point
I think so..
Tama can be read as "Gyoku"
It means diamonds
This place is..
Bukkouzi Temple
We've found the treasure
What's wrong with you?
Nothing..
I feel dizzy
I'm sorry
How do you feel now?
Ah..better
Hatori..you broke into
Sannouzi Temple 8 years ago
How do you know that?
Idiot
I discovered that from your look
of appreciating the blossoms
And there was a window frame
next to it
Right
I found the crystal ball
under that tree
I don't mean to
hurt your feelings
But wasn't it dropped
by your first lover?
What are you saying?
It should be the hair
on the stolen statue?
Hair?
You mean the splendid hair
on the statue?
Right
Sometimes they use crystal balls
to replace the hair
It's used in Noh play too
This is my analysis
Genzihatoru sneaked into Sannouzi
8 years ago
and stole the statue
But during the delivery
the hair dropped
And the leader, Yoshitune
found this..
and sent someone to look for it
At that time..
I wanna drink adzuki soup
I'd like mixed ice
The leader had no choice
but to put the statue is Sakura's shop
8 years later..
the criminal found
you were the one
he knew 8 years ago
That magazine?
At this time..
someone happened inside the gang
I think their leader
is seriously ill or something
Knowing he's not able to make it
He hid the statue
in a different place
And drew the map
like a puzzle
letting the successor
solve the puzzle
And then he died?
His men tried to solve the puzzle
but they couldn't get the right answer
At this time..
One of the members
came to work with the killer
I think Sakura
saw the killer's swordcraft skills
So he asked someone
to kill all his men
And then they found out
the statue and the hair
They sold it and split the money
I think the antique shop owner
Mr. Sakura
has found the way
to sell the stolen antiques
That's why he said
it was safe
The criminal pretended to
cooperate with Sakura
In fact..
he planned to kill them all
and posses the whole antique
But he still had to solve
the puzzle
So he came up with an idea
of asking the famous detective
Mouri Kogorou to help him
Bukkouzi Temple..
It's right here
But is the statue here?
Yes..
I don't think so
Hey
What's wrong with you?
Hey..Kudo
What have you come up with?
This is..
Yuryu Temple
Is this the point on the map?
Right
Kazuha?
It's me
I have the girl
In one hour
come to Yuryu temple alone
If you dare call the police
I'll kill her
Heiji..you can't come
They will kill you
Kazuha
Hattori
Kazuha is kidnapped
What?
He wants me to meet him
at Yuryu temple in one hour
Yuryu temple?
Great
We'll go together now
Heiji
Ray Bridge
(Learning the father's death
the son came back to Kyoto)
(When the funeral team came to
the bridge)
(His father woke up)
(and talked to his son)
Hey..
(Kuramadera Mountain)
(Yuryu Temple)
This is an instruction
of the master
The knife will be put
in Benkei's drawer
And the arrows
in Rokaku's
Benkei's drawer is..
From the top
one, two, three
Which are Benkei and Rokaku's?
Bukkouzi Temple?
I heard them say so
Where are they?
Kazuha doesn't pick up the phone
Yurye Temple
I am hungry
Really?
I'll cook you something later
Excuse me
Where is Yuryu Temple?
Deep in Kuramadera Mountain
But it was abandoned
long long ago
Thanks
Kuramadera Mountain
Why is he not here yet?
Who will be so stupid?
really?
Maybe he has no guts
Heiji
You didn't hurt Kazuha?
I..I'm fine..
You want this
In order to get the crystal ball
You attacked me yesterday
You failed..
and then you killed Mr. Sakura
at the tea house
in order to possess the treasure
And I know why you
began with Sandotin
not with Miyagawatyou
Because there was a river
behind the tea house
River
After you killed Mr. Sakura
You tossed the detector
of the security company
and the weapon
into the bottle
And then used mobile phones
to check in the security company's
webpage
You checked the position
of the detector
and when I was about to
go back to Osaka, you attacked me
You tried to kill me
with a short knife
Although your plan failed
because of Kazuha's intervention
You intended to drop the weapon
in order to avoid suspicision
You wanted to let us believe
the murderer was someone else
Am I right..
Mr. Saizyou Taiga
No..I should call you..
Misashi pretending Benkei
Hattori Heiji is really outstanding
How do you know
it's me..
Because you tried to lie to us
you can't shoot arrows
When you kneel down
you always pull back your left leg first
That's called "pull half leg"
The arrow shooters
all have such a habit
When you were asked
who practices shooting arrows
You mentioned "yanomakura"
unintentionally
I remember "yamakura"..
You are not talking about
Mrs. Yamakura
You mean..
"Yanomakura"
The second section of the left thumb
used to hold the arrows
I think you wanted to say that..
I remember..
Ms. Tika Suzu
hurt her yanomakura
Only the professionals
use this term
By the way..
Mr. Ryuen is an outsiders
He can't even pronounce accurately
Ryuen and I
practice swordcraft at the same place
Because of that..
Someday
I learned an ancient school
called "Yoshitune School"
and I started to study it
I quit the practice
2 years ago
and claimed to be the heir
of Yoshitune School
Benkei is the founder
Compared with Benkei..
I think I like it more
I wanna be a part of it
But the title was always taken away
The leader of the robbery ring
was given the name of Benkei
Were you in need of money?
Right..
I didn't do it for personal desire
I wanted to build a school
in Kyoto
And the leader was the master
of the temple
and he administered the temple
after it was abandoned
That's why I use this place
as a practice place
3 months ago..the leader died
And the temple
has to be dismantled
I can't use it anymore
I have a question
You are just using Mr. Ryuen
Right
I heard him talk about the statue
After I mailed the letter
As I have expected
he came to talk to me
So I advised him to
ask Mouri for help
Even if I don't count on him
I can find a buyer
Because it's very easy to do it
on the Internet
Alright..the chat is over
Please hand me the crystal
No problem
but you have to let Kazuha go
If you tell me
where the statue is
What?
Where is the statue?
It's in the temple
What are you saying?
It's called..
people always forget the nearest
Don't lie to me
I have searched the whole temple
I just can't find you
I am not lying to you
Kazuha..run now
Heiji
They are my favorite disciples
Don't get involved
Heiji
Stop..this is not Heiji
You..who are you?
Who are you?
I am Kudo Shinichi
I am a detective
What?
What are you talking about?
You made him swallow the pill?
Because Kudo called
and asked if
there's any way to restore him
even just for a short moment
But the anti-poison of APTX 4869
is out
The Bakanya that restored him
has lost its effects
because of the generation of antibodies
It occurs to me..
If you take some medicine
that gives you symptoms of colds
and drink Bakanya
Maybe you can restore
your body again
So..he..
As I have expected
the experiment worked
Kudo is restored
But he's like having a terrible cold
He's very weak
I can't guarantee
he will be safe..
How about Heiji now?
I don't know
Before the future check-up
he has to take a rest
I'm assigned to
take care of him
Kudo..
Damn..
How can he lie to me
I wanted to let her
escape here first
But now I can't make any move
Damn.. Bakanya has lost its effect
I'll be dead
Maybe you can be the best detective
but if you'd like to be a warrior
You're way to far..
Hattori
Heiji
Sorry for the waiting..Kazuha
You..
You are such a big idiot
Why are you here now?
Hey, Kudo
How dare you steal my clothes
And..
I don't know
what you apply to your face
But I don't have such a dark skin
Really?
Forget it
Let me handle it
Go now
Hide yourself first
And come back again
after you're restored
Stop right there
I am your rival
Kazuha
Don't tell anyone
about seeing Kudo
Even that girl
Eh? Even Ran?
Why?
There's no reason
They won't meet
It's better not to tell her
You can't go back alive
What the hell is it?
Chase him
Hey..you find him?
Not yet
Carry on
Eh..what's going on?
Hush..don't make any noise
Don't move
Shinichi
You look like before
What's wrong with you?
Why do you sweat so much?
Who are they?
Where have they been?
I have no choice..
Let's go back first
I'm sorry..Ran
I can't..
It's locked..
I can't open it
Do something
This smells like "Tata-mi"
This is the room
where I was imprisoned
Get me the axe..quick
Damn..they will break in
Is there any weapon?
What?
Why are there so many drawers
The knife was put
in Benkei's drawer
And the arrows
in Rokaku's
Heiji..
the knife is in Benkei's drawer
What?
In this drawer?
But there are so many
I don't know which is his
I have seen it before
The alignment of the drawers
is like the roads in Kyoto
I see
These are Karasuma Road
and Sanyashi Road
Wait
Do they give each drawer a name?
Name?
Right
Like Rokakku..
is Rokaku's Hall
Benkei's drawer..
means Benkei's stone
Going east from Santo Fuwutin
This is the ball song
Marutakeebisuni..
and then..
Damn..I can't remember
Marutakeebisuni
Oshioike
Bride Rokakku..
Takonishiki
Heiji..Santo is 2 layers
above the Takonishiki
Alright
2 layers above Takonishiki
And the west-east road is..
Temple..Yushin..
Fuwu..Fu..
Fuwutin is the 3rd
Right here
Die now
The unique pattern
on both sides
This is the evil knife
Using it to deal with
the devil on Yoshitune
is the best idea
What are you talking about?
Go away
What are you doing?
Chase him
Yes
Listen..
I'll delay them
You'd better run now
NO..I wanna be with you
Be good
Heiji
We have found it
Run now
Go get that girl
Yes
Conan
Kazuha..how about Heiji?
He's over there
Heiji
Damn
I wanna call the police
but there's no reception
You can use this
Hey..go put out the fire
Yes
Alright..
I hope someone has spotted the fire
Hey..Ran
Are you awake?
Father
Where is Shinichi?
You fainted?
Why is that guy here?
Why are you sleeping here?
Why are you here then?
I informed him
Kazuha was kidnapped
by Genzihatoru
Mr. Mouri
It's time for a fight
As I wish
I won't be trapped again
How about this?
Knife?
This is not an ordinary one
There's poison on it
What are you saying?
If you're cut
you'll die immediately
What a wicked guy
Damn..
Heiji is in danger
You have nowhere to run
The arrows are aimed at you
You have to figure it out
Conan
Don't run
Hey..I am here
Look
Go..Heiji
Heiji
You want to be Benkei?
If you were Benkei
Yoshitune would've been killed
at the checkpoint
The master is defeated
Arrest them
Yes
Great..Conan
Yes..
Didn't you call Heiji
by "Hattori"?
I'm sorry..I was too excited
It's Heiji
Heiji
This temple..
Now all the puzzles are solved
And the medical effect
is only temporary
Thanks for letting me
gather so much information
Are you okay, Heiji?
I am fine
But where is the statue?
Heiji..Shinichi is..
What..
Nothing
It was just a dream
(Sannouzi Temple)
It's really embarrassing
I can't find where the statue is
Don't blame yourself
it's up to the fate
Never mind
Please be careful
Goodbye
It's really troublesome now
It's only one hour left
Don't worry
We'll inform the faithfuls
The Medicine Buddha
The Buddha is back
(Yuryu Temple, During the Dawn)
We found it..Kudo
Am I right?
The shape of the temple
is like the Chinese character ""
And the point refers to
this clock tower
I didn't perceive that either
With a "" on top of it
it becomes ""
which implies the "roof"
I see
So now it's returned
to the original owner
Yes
They are the best partners
Just like Yoshitune and Benkei
You mean Heiji and Mouri?
You are not mature enough
What do you mean?
Alright..Ayumi will be the next
Alright
So cute
I'll take it back
No
Because it's my best friend
Mr. Captain
You don't have many friends
Sorry for suspecting you
to be the criminals
That's alright
I knew my father
I asked him
to stop mailing me money
Your father?
Who is he?
This is a secret
That nasty monk
Marutakeebisuni
Oshioike
Bride Rokakku
Not bride..but sister
Idiot
Where did you learn this song?
I learned it from my relative
in Kyoto
I remember
when I was in the 3rd year
We learned it together
With me?
What?
You don't remember?
I remember now..
You were so impatient
You wanted to go to Sannouzi
and then you went out
At that time
my relative helped me wear Kimono
and hair dressings..makeup
I went to Sannouzi
to look for you
Because I couldn't see you
I left soon
I'd like to show you
the scene I saw at that time
The blossoms were scattered
everywhere
Marutakeebisuni
Oshioike
Bride Rokaku..Takonishiki
That means..
Finally I can see you
See me?
Heiji you saw your first lover?
Who is she?
The dancer?
I won't tell you..idiot
It doesn't matter..stingy guy
Tell me please
Eh..
I'll tell you
in another 1 500 years
Come on
Conan..what are you doing?
Why do you sweat so much?
Shin..Shinichi
By the way..
I called Shinichi
I wanted him to disguise himself
as Heiji and save Kazuha
Right?
Yes..
but that guy is really vulnerable
He escaped half way
Didn't you tell me
not to tell anyone?
I see
So that was Shinichi?
Finally I see you
I'd like ice cream
Alright..it's 300 yens
I am the only one
who hasn't met the special someone
Sonako..
you will see Kyogoku someday
I'm not good at waiting
So is Ran
Come on..
I don't dislike it
Because the longer I wait
when we meet..
You look like before..
we will feel more delighted
Ah..damn
I hope Kudo could hear about what she just said.