Tonight, we're at the Tohto Tower
in the Minato ward...
The Tanabata Festival is being held here
at the Tohto Tower now,
there is a large crowd of people...
Yeah, I know!
Be at Doc's house by 4:00 p.m. right?
I mean, Genta,
don't you be late either! See you.
All I need now is a flashlight...
Uh I'm sure that...
it was in this drawer...
H, here it is...
Huh?
Who is it?... Ran?
Pop's out playing Mahjong...
Ha,
ha... I guess it's just my imagination.
Long time no see, Shinichi Kudo...
No... you're Conan Edogawa now...
Phooey... I had no idea that
you'd be alive with the body of a brat...
You can say that again, boss...
Really a surprise...
How?! How did they figure out my identity...?
Conan?
Conan, is anything wrong?
I heard a loud sound just now...
Conan?
Watch closely...
the kind of fate the people who have
become involved with you have to tread...
Conan, are you all right...
Conan...
Are you inside?
I'm coming in...
Conan?
Ran...
Darn... What a crummy dream...
(The Raven Chaser)
I'm a High School Detective Shinichi Kudo.
I went to an amusement park
with my classmate and childhood friend,
Ran Mouri,
and happened to witness the
dangerous dealing of men dressed in black...
Since I was so absorbed in watching the deal
I didn't notice the other man dressed in
black who was approaching me from behind...
That man shoved a poison drug down my throat
and when I got up...
my body was shrunk!!
If they find out that Shinichi Kudo is alive
they'd come after me again
and endanger the lives
of all the people around me...
I decided to hide my true identity
thanks to Doc's advice.
So, when Ran asked me my name,
I introduced myself as Conan Edogawa.
In order to gather information
on those guys in black
I decided to freeload at Ran's house
being that her father was a private eye...
The Black Organization
that is obscured in mystery...
Gin...
Vodka...
Belmot...
Chianti... Korn...
And, Sherry...
Her real name is Shiho Miyano...
Since her parents who had passed away
when she was still young
used to be scientists
working for the Black Organization,
she was called by the code name Sherry
and worked for them as well.
She was the one who had developed
the drug called Apotoxin 4869...
However, after her only older sister,
Akemi Miyano is killed by the Organization,
she rebels against the Organization
and decides to take her own life
by drinking the poisoned drug,
only to find that her body had shrunk...
Therefore, she changes her name
to AI Haibara at present,
successfully fleeing
being pursued by the Organization.
She leads a life of a first grader just like
me at the elementary school I attend.
Amidst all this, I confronted Belmot
and got hold of a clue...
You better not,
If you pull that out,
my comrades will receive...
notice of your boss's mail address...
S, Seven crow chicks?!
Yeah,
when the boss's mail address is keyed in
that's what it sounds like...
The song "Seven Baby Crows"
Don't tell me
you sent mail to that address...
Don't be silly...
I wouldn't do something like that...
Well, I'll send mail to this address
after Officer Takagi
tracks down who owns it...
They'll kill him...
as soon as Officer Takagi
tries to track down who owns it...
And if that should ever happen,
they'll come after you
who provided the mail address...
Now that you know,
don't pry further and just forget about it...
Because... that mail address is
a Pandora's box
that should never be opened...
A child with the brains of an adult
No case is left unsolved
with Detective Conan.
There is always only one truth!!
(Beika Forest)
Oh! There it is...
I've found a stag beetle!
All right
Stag beetles are at the top after all!
Okay, I'm going up too!!
No, Genta, don't!
I think it's better you don't
I guess not.
Only Conan or a monkey
is capable of climbing up
to a high place like that.
Sorry I'm a monkey...
That's right, use your suspenders!
Suspenders...
Oh... You mean this, that you gave me
back at your house a while ago?
Right... I revised it so that
it extends up to 100 meters
with a push of the button...
It keeps on extending
while you're pushing the button,
then, when you push the button
the next time, it shrinks rapidly!
S, Sorry...
Come on, be careful, will you...
I found a stag beetle!!
Aren't you lucky, Genta...
It's a beetle!!
It stopped!
Wow, there're two of them!
It's a male and female...
Huh?...
This female beetle has a tape
stuck on to its front wing...
See...
True, how cruel!!
Huh? There's something written on it...
Uh...
Oh, it says OPEN.
You can find it on lunches
sold in convenience stores...
The same tape was on the fried chicken lunch
about yesterday...
Fried chicken...?
You secretly went out and ate something
that would make you fat again...
Uh...
L, Let's see, I'll peel it off.
Oh, okay...
Who could've done something like this...
If they're male and female
they could be lovers, right?
Okay, then, I'll name them!!
Uh...
the male is Altair
and the female is Vega!
That's nice
Come to think of it,
it's almost Tanabata. (Star Festival)
Speaking of Tanabata...
Okay... it's peeled off...
Now, for the long awaited quiz time.
Nobody's waiting...
On Tanabata evening of a certain year,
it rained so hard that
Altair and Vega couldn't see each other...
The two who were troubled,
thought very hard created a day
called "Koi Tomo No Hi"
which meant a day to spend with your lover,
and decided to see each other anyway...
Now, which day did they choose?
Number 1: January 1st, New Year's Day...
Number 2: February 2nd, (Setsubun)
Seasonal Division Day...
Number 3, March 3rd, (Momo no Sekku)
Girls' Day...
Number 4, May 5th, (Tango no Sekku)
Boys' Day...
I got it!
Number 3, Girls' Day, right?!
Because The Emperor and Empress are lovers!
No, it's Boys' Day, May 5th, (Tango no Sekku)
because the passionate dance
you dance with a lover is the tango!
I say, it's number 1!!
Because I'll eat rice cake in soup
with my lover on New Year's Day!
Oh!
You can sure think up a lot of things...
What's the correct answer, Doc?
Number 4, May 5th.
I did it!
But, my way of thinking is different...
May 5th is Children's Day...
When you take Children's Day apart
Ko, i, to, mo, no, hi...
In other words,
A day to spend with your lover, right?
I see...
You deliberately used the
short cut way of saying it, right?
"Koi tomo no hi" Day
to spend with you lover...
I hope that Altair and Vega
get to stay together forever...
But,
Altair and Vega,
what a mismatching name to give beetles.
Oh? I don't think so.
In fact, it's an unlikely but perfect match,
I'd say. Weaver's star is called Vega...
The tape stuck onto the female beetle
sort of looks like
the initial "V" doesn't it?
True!
Absolutely!
Yep.
And, how do I get down?
Darn, what the hell's going on?
Stop! Stop!
Darn!!
Hey, you, are you okay?!
-Hey, call an ambulance!
-Yes, sir!
To... day...
is the Star Festival... (Tanabata)
Hey, get a hold of yourself!!
The ambulance will be here soon!!
Hey! Hey! You!!
Get a hold of yourself!!
Listen...
I brought you along as a special favor
so stay put and wait, understand!
Okay.
Oh, dad, your necktie's crooked...
Oh, Mr. Mouri...
Thank you for coming all this way
from so early in the morning...
Good morning, Ran, Conan.
Good morning.
I hear it's a serial murder
committed throughout a wide area.
Yes, sir...
At the site of the murder that was committed
the day before yesterday
at the toll street in Odawara City,
a Mahjong tile was found...
Likewise, cases where
a Mahjong tile was found occurred
in Tokyo, Kanagawa, Shizuoka, and Nagano.
We've found that 5 cases in all
have occurred in each prefecture.
I see...
Well, we can go over the details
at the conference...
Yeah...
After you...
Oooh! It's you, Mr. Mouri!
Long time no see!!
You always talk so loud,
Yokomizo...
I'm Sango...
This is my younger brother, Jyugo.
I know... I've seen him many times.
S, Sango, Jyugo...
(Sango-Jyugo means 3 X 5=15 in Japanese)
And... who is that woman?
Pardon me.
She's from the Saitama Prefectural
Police Department, Inspector Hagino...
(Ayami Hagino Saitama Police)
I'm Ayami Hagino,
I've heard a lot about you...
Well, what a surprise
that there's such a beauty
at the Saitama Prefectural Police...
She's was my subordinate
when I working in Saitama.
Saitama Prefectural Police?...
Since the home of the victim
that was killed was located in Tokorozawa,
I was called to attend the conference...
What brings you here, Mr. Mouri?
He came here by request of
Superintendent Matsumoto
as a special advisor.
How wretched to have to ask help
from a private eye...
You can say that again...
If I'm not mistaken you're...
Inspector Kansuke Yamato of
the Nagano Prefectural Police Station...
And...
the klutz police detective
from the Gunma Prefectural Police Station...
Oh, please Mr. Mouri,
(Misao Yamamura Gunma Police)
I've got a decent name,
Misao Yamamura, you know.
See...
Didn't the case
occur in Nagano Prefecture, though...?
Why is the police
of the Gunma Prefecture here...
The site of the murder was right on
the border of Nagano and Gunma...
that's why...
The body of the murder victim from knee down
was inside the border of
the Gunma Prefecture... You see.
Rather, now that I know what your name is...
In, Inspector?!
You mean, you've become an inspector...
Oh, so you noticed?
Thanks to everyone,
I've successfully been promoted to Inspector.
You've become an Inspector,
Is the Gunma Prefectural Police Station
all right, or what...
By the way,
isn't that boy wearing glasses here today?
Boy wearing glasses?...
You mean Conan?
Yes, yes, Conan Edogawa
For some reason cases are solved
when he's around...
Come to think of it,
it was the same for me too...
Same here!
Oh,
so all of you experienced the same thing!
The same goes for us too.
I seem to lose consciousness part
way through,
and when I come to, the case is solved.
Shoots!
You lose consciousness...?
Really?
Not me...
Never happened...
Huh? You mean I'm the only one?...
You're the only police detective
that I can shoot the needle
of my tranquilizer gun into...
That's strange...
Yes, yes, we would like to
start the conference soon...
I, I'm sorry...
Mr. Mouri...
Hey, Mr. Mouri...
Who's that?
That evil looking person...
You idiot!
(Kiyonaga Matsumoto TMPD Police)
He's Superintendent Kiyonaga Matsumoto!
What?! With a face like that?!
If you don't hold your tongue,
he's going to punch you out...
Ha, ha, ha, ha...
First of all, in order to solve the 6th case,
the common points
all the previous 5 cases have are...
A large knife was used in all the cases.
Moreover,
judging from the shape of the wounds,
we think that the knife
was flung down with the right hand.
On top of that, all 5 victims
were kidnapped using a stun gun,
and killed at the scene of the crime,
then left behind.
One question arises though.
In spite of the fact that the victims were
rendered immobile,
why did the murderer go out of the way
to move the victims
all the way to another place then kill them?
Moreover,
Mahjong tiles
with a round red emblem in front,
with alphabets and black vertical lines
in the back
were found by the corpse of all six cases...
I'm sure that this is a message
left behind by the suspect.
The round red emblem is the 7 of circles.
Of the four circles located below,
the painted circle on the top right
and to the bottom left are missing.
The alphabets are two As, then E, H and Z.
You turn it inside out
and get an upside down L...
On top of that, of all the things
that the six victims usually have on them,
one thing that has been taken away
from each of them.
A pendant, a pouch, a lucky charm bag...
A motorbike key holder, a compact,
and mascot doll...
Maybe the victims lost it
when they were kidnapped?
No,
since one thing was taken from all 6 victims,
it's only natural to think that the suspect
took them away.
Hmm...
so it all boils down
to the meaning of the message.
There's one more message.
It's a dying message left behind
by the sixth victim Ryuzaki,
"It's Tanabata... today... "
It could be that Ryuzaki saw the suspect
at the rest house at the Hakone-Turn Pike
where the brake oil of his car
was supposedly drained...
Uh... Everyone,
I think you're thinking too hard, maybe?
The Mahjong tile indicates
just what it is, Mahjong!
The motive of the murder is just what it is,
trouble over a game of Mahjong!
There was the 1 of circles and 7 of circles,
which indicates that 8 people
were playing Mahjong.
And of the 7 of circles,
there are two with no red painting on it...
One of the two indicates the suspect
and the other tile
indicates the final victim!
Which means that
there will be more murders?!
Yes... most probably...
But if it's indicating 8 members,
would the 8 of circles be better?
The 1 of circles and the 7 of circles
hold another meaning...
That is, the suspect
just needed either of the tiles...
the 1 or the 7of circles to win the game!!
Moreover, his hand was a big one
that would make him the top winner!!
I see!!
However, somebody else won with
a small and cheap hand!
That's why the suspect got angry?!
Exactly...
I'm sure that the other members were also
playing a similar sly game too.
I'm sure the suspect couldn't stand it...
This, was the motive for the murder!!
Then, what do the alphabets mean?
Why were the victims taken deliberately
to a different place and then killed?
And...
What is the meaning of
Mr. Ryuzaki's dying message...
W, Well... you see...
That's...
I'll get to that... later on... you see...
Superintendent...
Could the six places
have a special meaning to the suspect?
If there is,
chances are high
that it would lead us to a clue
of who the suspect is.
And, the six victims.
I'm sure that the six are in some way
connected to the suspect...
The fastest way to track down the suspect
would be to find what the six have in common.
It's true that as Mouri had mentioned,
it most likely has
something to do with Mahjong.
Moreover, we've got to figure out
the meaning of the alphabets
and vertical lines that
were written on the back of the tiles,
as well as the meaning
of the dying message, "Tanabata today."
Listen, all of you!
Chances are high that the suspect
will commit more murders in the future!
We've got to avoid that from happening
at all cost
over the dignity of the police!!
Forget all petty things
such as whose jurisdiction is where,
or personal ambitions,
and make public all the information you get.
We'll all share whatever findings there are
and nab the serial killer
by all means as soon as we possibly can!!
Aye!!
The john, the john... I'm going to leak!
I guess the conference is over...
I guess so.
Oh... Superintendent Matsumoto...
Long time no see.
How is Sayuri?
O, Oh... You're Mouri's...
Well, my daughter's the same as ever...
See you, Mouri... I'm counting on you.
Yes, sir!! I, Kogoro Mouri
will with all my heart
and soul meet up to your expectation!!
Hmm...
Have a nice day!
Huh?
Officer Chiba, did you lose weight a bit?
Oh, you noticed?
I'm dieting recently.
You know, the morning program
aired on TV now?
Talking of slimming down...
Shiratori,
it seems that you on the other hand
gained weight?
Ugh... Y, You've gotta be joking, Mr. Mouri!
I may not look it,
but I go to the gym twice a week.
How unusual,
for you to drink black coffee, Sango.
Yeah, I've been told by my doctor recently
to cut out on sweets...
I thought you didn't like... yourself?
There're been three murders in a row,
that I need some sugar to keep me going!
Uh, Inspector Yokomizo?
Oh, no, I mean the older one...
Uh...
Is that the boy, Conan Edogawa
that you happened to mention
just a while ago?
Yeah...
I don't know if it's because he's always
listening to Mr. Mouri's deductions,
but he sometimes
comes up with amazing hints!
Besides, he's really observant
and notices things
that we professionals tend to overlook.
Is that so...
Little baby crows... why are you crying...
The crows are in the mountains
Whaaa!!
"Officer" Yamamura! That song!
Hey I guess you're not aware
because you weren't listening but...
Why were you singing that song just now?
"Inspector" Yamamura!
Why...?
because I heard it outside the men's room
just a while ago...
Like the buttons of a cell phone
were being pushed...
When I came out of the men's room,
An officer wearing glasses was
making a call on his cell phone.
H, Huh?
Hey, Conan?!
It can't be?!...
Don't tell me that they...
It can't be?!
There he is!
H, Hey, Conan? What's the matter?
Darn!
I've got to go pee!!
C, Conan?!
The men's room's right here...
That car was a Porsche 356A...
Gin's car...
Why...? What brings them here
to the investigation conference...?
What're they after...
What?! They snuck into
the investigation conference?!
Shh! Keep your voice down!
I hope Ai's okay.
Yeah... she should be in the basement lab.
I'm sure that the one who was disguised
as a police detective was Belmot.
I'll bet she was mailing the results
of the conference to her boss
while waiting for the elevator.
I see,
so that's what Officer Yamamura heard...
The buttons that sound like the song,
"Seven Baby Crows"
when pushed to send mail...
But, why...
I tell you...
The two of you
keeping secrets from me again...
Ai...
And? Why do you think it's Belmot?
You can't tell just by
the sound of the buttons being pushed...
Gin's Porsche was there...
It would be too risky for them
to sneak into the police bare faced.
If someone were to be in disguise,
then chances are high that it was Belmot...
At any rate,
there's no doubt
that the cases are in some way
connected with the guys in black...
So, I'd like to check the cases myself.
Will you help me?
I don't mind...
You wouldn't quit even if I told you to,
would you...
But, be very careful...
I'm sure you already know but,
if they find out
what your true identity is...
Yeah... I know.
(Metropolitan Police Department)
(Conan Edogawa)
(Karuizawa, Nagano Observatory)
(Odawara Atsugi)
(Nerima District, Nishidaizumi Forest)
(Isogo District, Yokohama)
(Shizuoka District, Mountain range)
(Hayakawa Toll Gate)
Huh? They don't play Mahjong?
No...
As a result of our questioning,
we've found that
all six of the victims didn't play Mahjong.
It's too bad,
but I guess your deduction
wasn't correct, Mouri...
Oh...
We've hit a dead end...
I wish that Shinichi Kudo were around...
Kudo, you mean,
the high school detective Shinichi Kudo
that you frequently ask for help
with investigation?
Yes, I guess...
Come to think of it,
there's not much talk about him recently.
Maybe he just got tired
of playing detective?
Oh, no, that's not it.
Just the other day, he solved a case
at Teitan High School's school festival...
Officer Takagi!
Huh?...
Oh, I'm sorry, I sort of got carried away...
Just what do you mean?
He wants us to keep it a secret
that he's involved in solving the cases.
I see...
Oh! he sure is a modest person.
He's recently become that way
for some reason...
In the past he really used to like being
in the spotlight and getting attention...
I guess being absent from school
for two days, was not worth much.
N, No... I guess not...
Did you figure out the meaning of
the mahjong tiles and the alphabets?
I still haven't figured that out yet...
I don't know what "Tanabata today"
means either...
Wow! Mitsuko,
you're good
That's a beetle, isn't it?
Yes, I'm pretty good with things like this.
But, what a crummy thing to do,
sticking tape onto the wings...
Oh, you mean Vega...
I wonder who did that...
Really...
By the way, Genta,
Is that a snake that you're making?
Can't you tell just looking at it...
It's an eel. E-E-L!
E, El again...
You really like eels, don't you, Genta...
Even the other day you wrote eels
on the piece of paper decorating
the Tanabata tree too, right?
(I want to eat eel)
Come to think of it, Tanabata is tomorrow...
Tanabata... today...
What does it mean...
Bad... you should have it turned off
during the conference...
Excuse me...
It's me...
Oh... Yeah...
And?...
What?!
Yeah, I got it!
Good news...
A man
that could possibly be the serial killer
may show up in Beika City.
What?!
Minoru Fukase, age 27...
is on the wanted list
for stabbing and badly wounding Shuhei Jinno,
who was murdered at Usui Pass...
I had one of my men keep an eye on his lover,
and just got word that
she headed from Nagano to Tokyo
and got off at Beika Station...
Her name's Lisa Yoshii, age 21...
I hear she's working at
a snack in Nagano city...
And? What was Fukase's motive
for stabbing Mr. Jinno?
When they were in a line at Tropical Land,
Jinno seems to have
told him to stop smoking...
Tropical Land...
Officer Takagi?
Did you figure something out?
Maybe...
Maybe all the other victims
were standing in the same line?
What? Explain in detail.
Yes, sir...
Two types of Mahjong tiles
were left near the victims.
Mr. Jinno's 1 of circles and,
the 7 of circles that were by the others...
If you set the position of the red circle
of each Mahjong tile like this...
maybe the victims were
lined up in this order.
I see...
Then, Fukase's the one who...
Okay, Megure,
take your men
and accompany Inspector Yamato!
I tell you...
why do you have to tag along too...?
I've always wanted to
speed along on the Shuto Expressway!
How about you, Inspector Yamato? Huh? Hu?
Over here!
Okay!
Okay, let's stake out just as planned!
Is it the suspect?
Or, could he be...
Minoru!!
Fukase's shown up...
All of you, stay in place and wait...
Don't let him see you!
Hurry! Hurry!
The game house is on the 7th floor, right?
Yep, let's eat ice cream on the way home!
I want a double with vanilla and chocolate!
Inspector, there are children near Fukase...
Stay cool.
We're nabbing him
after the children distance away from Fukase.
Roger!
Which floor is this?
We have one more floor to go
They passed the 5th floor.
Next is the 7th floor.
Okay, nab him!
Roger...
-Ro...
-Roger!!
H, Hey.
That idiot!
Fukase! Freeze!!
Police!!
You can't get away!
Darn!
Don't, Fukase!!
Stay away!!
If you don't I'm going to kill this broad!!
Darn!
Don't move!
If you don't want me
to drive this through you!
No! You can't get away
even if you do something like that!
Shut up! Stay away!!
Stay away!! Ow...
You guys stand back too!!
O, Okay, cool it, will you...
How dare he make us waste our time...
It seems he's passed out...
But, why...
Pull away...
Pull away from Minoru...
Get away from Minoru...
Calm down, Lisa,
put the knife down...
No.
Doing something like that
isn't going to help you at all.
Put the knife down.
No...
Let go of Minoru!!
Okay... that's enough, Lisa...
No need to commit further crime...
I, I'm sorry...
Are you all right, Inspector?!
No need to worry.
I've got especially lots of fat on my belly.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry...
I'm to blame for being off guard...
Well,
we can't have any police detectives
that aren't in this jurisdiction
getting hurt here, so it's okay...
Huh?
What's up?
Well, the woman who was being held hostage...
Huh?
Are you sure...?
Do you really want to leave as is...?
Didn't you have
something to say to that man?
Belmot.
Fuh...
What can I do about it?
You're the one
who made it turn out this way, right?
Besides, I don't think that he's the culprit.
Yeah, you're right...
Take it easy on me, will you...
I hurt my right shoulder...
You hurt your right shoulder...
Come to think of it, just a while ago you.
Stay away!! Ow...
It's impossible for a man
who cannot raise his right arm
to fling down a knife...
Unless he hurt himself
after committing the crime.
It's amazing how you figured out it was me.
Your leg.
Leg?!
Your right ankle's swollen...
You've got a gun stashed in there, right?
Besides, despite being slashed on the cheek
with his knife,
not even one drop of blood is dripping.
Darn...
I've got to think up a mask
that will bleed next time then...
It's most likely that you deliberately
set yourself up as hostage from your side,
then after pulling him away from the police,
you were going to turn around and kill him
with that gun of yours.
Well, you probably didn't even have to
use a gun to get at him though...
I didn't think
that you would be complimenting me...
Why are you and your organization
pursuing this murder case?
You sure are straightforward...
Tell me!
NOC.
NOC...
Non Official Cover...
A member of the Organization
that's disguised
as a lay person is among the victims?
Right... We found out that the NOC...
be it for insurance measures or what,
is carrying around the memory card
with the data of the NOC list
of the Organization around.
That person was to be killed
by the Organization soon...
However...
That person
was killed by someone else instead...
Right...
and that killer
made away with the memory card,
most probably unaware of what it is.
I see...
If the killer is nabbed by the police
and that data is seen,
that's a lot of trouble...
That's why...
You coming here means
that there's a NOC among the investigators...
No, rather,
you set up one of your men to disguise
himself as one of the investigators!
That's why you snuck into
the investigation conference, right?
You wanted to make sure that the member
was doing all right under disguise...
Otherwise, you would've still
been undercover at the conference...
Who is?! Who's the guy disguised as?!
Is the real investigator safe?!
This is as much as I can tell you...
The rest is up to you to find out...
His code name is Irish...
Irish...
Yes...
It's a mild tasting whiskey...
security guard!
He seems to be lost...
What? Lost?
Oh, no...
Good luck...
I hope you the best...
Darn...
Yes, this is Megure. Oh,
Superintendent.
I just got a call from an artist
named Sumire Shindo
saying that she has an idea
who the serial killer may be.
Her address is Hachioji...
Yes! Yes! Understood.
Sato, Takagi,
Go to Hachioji on the double!
Yes, sir!
Okay, Sumire Shindo, got you...
No good boss, from here
even if we were to beat the cops there,
we'll end up confronting them
before we get rid of her...
We're not going to face the police...
Yeah, it's me...
We did it!
We made it just in the nick of time!
I get the right...
Okay, I get the left.
Cute boy.
Foxy chick...
W, What was that?!...
Cool it!
Go slowly to the shoulder of the road.
My god...
It's a flat after all...
This side too...
Officer Takagi, call Inspector Shiratori!
Yes, ma'am
Darn! I guess we were a bit late.
We shouldn't hang around too long.
Let's get going.
What?! She's not there?!
It's not that she left home, is it?
No, there are signs of struggle in the room,
and it seems that the culprit
took her away in a car
Search for her right away!
And please also get the forensic officers.
Okay
Bye...
Officer Takagi...
What is it?
Ms. Sato?
An investigator?
Yeah, his code name is Irish...
Do you know him?
No... I never heard of him.
I see...
If we at least can tell
what kind of guy he is,
we may be able to figure out
who he's disguised as...
I don't think you should get involved.
If that guy called Irish is disguised
as one of the investigators,
he would've gotten suspicious about you
after you noticed Belmot
in the conference room
and ran out after her...
Yeah... But...
Don't you understand?!
The more you solve the case,
the more you're proving
that you're Shinichi Kudo!!
Ai...
I understand you worrying...
But, I can't afford not solving the case.
The life of the investigator that Irish
is disguised as is in danger.
At any rate,
there's no doubt that Irish was among
the investigators
that attended the conference.
I've got to figure out who he is,
while at the same time
catch the culprit before those guys do
and get a hold of the memory card
that he took away from NOC!
With just that one card
I could maybe crush them all!
But, are you sure
you can trust what Belmot said?
She knows that Ai is Sherry...
She probably knows who I am too...
However, for some reason
she hasn't told the Organization about us...
I've got no choice but to believe her now.
You're still cautious enough
to meet at a shrine.
Irish is the one who's cautious...
Well, until everything is cleared,
I don't think we should see each other
anywhere except for at school...
This is just to be safe...
(Teitan High School)
(Black Knight's Clothing and Accessories)
(Teitan elementary)
(Conan Edogawa)
What do you want... Gin...
Where were you the past 2 hours...
You seem to have been in a place where
you had to switch off your cell phone...
Does it bother you...
Phooey... no big deal.
All you need to concentrate on is to
carry out the mission that was given you...
Come to think of it,
you're the one who got rid of that
high school detective with that drug,
aren't you?
What're you talking about?
Shinichi Kudo...
Have you forgotten?...
What's the matter?
I'm sorry. I cracked your rice bowl, Conan.
It's okay...
How unusual of you to crack a dish, Ran.
You can say that again.
I wonder what got into me.
(Kouryou Sports Park)
No doubt about it,
the victim is Sumire Shindo.
(Kogoro Mori detective agency)
Okay, I got it,
at three then.
See you...
Was that Officer Takagi?
Yeah. There's going to be
an investigation conference again from 3:00
Was there any progress?
The corpse of the lady Sumire Shindo
seems to have been found...
Where?
I heard it was at Ayase City
in Kanagawa Prefecture...
Was the Mahjong tile found there
the 7 of circles?
Yeah...
The red circle was at the upper right
of the 4 circles below.
On the back there were no alphabets,
but rather a triangle...
Hey!! Hurry and go to school!!
Alright!
What the...
So strange...
Good morning...
Oh, Conan!
Bad news! Your dolphin's fin is gone.
The fin?
Really...
This is the remains of a leather glove!
A mysterious case has occurred.
It's not such a big deal.
Somebody was probably cleaning or something,
bumped into it and it fell off.
We looked for it,but couldn't find it.
It's okay,
I'll make another one and stick it on.
Don't tell me that... that fin...
No... don't worry...
No doubt about it,
it's them...
Come to think of it,
I still cold sweat thinking that
this could've turned out
to be a tragic accident...
Don't you think it's strange?
Getting two flat tires at the same time
is something that could never happen.
Then, did someone
scatter nails or something?
Snipers...
I'm sure someone shot at the tires...
Somewhere from this overpass...
I'm sure that a car was parked here...
No kidding...
You know what Officer Takagi,
this may be a freaked out idea
but I have a feeling...
that aside from the culprit,
there are other non-identifiable people
moving around in this case.
Unidentifiable people...
The paint at Ms. Shindo's atelier
was stepped on twice...
The paint was squeezed out of the tube
after being stepped on
and yet the paint that was
already pushed out was stepped on again...
Wouldn't this mean that after the culprit
kidnapped Ms. Shindo by car,
someone else came...
I wonder.
Maybe the person stuck around
till the paint dried?
I mean the culprit.
Another thing
that bugs me is the woman who disappeared
from the mall in Beika-cho.
Maybe she was one of them too.
Maybe she deliberately set herself
up as the hostage...
Huh, for what?
Officer Sato,
I think you're just getting carried away.
I guess so, maybe I am.
But, if this is a fact,
it would mean that a spy
who is sending them information
is among the police.
Furthermore, it's someone
who has attended the conference...
Huh? The helmet of the Black Knight?
It broke.
The members of the drama club were
making a fuss over it a while ago.
The rice bowl...
Huh?
I cracked Conan's rice bowl last night.
And now it's the helmet
that Shinichi used to wear...
It feels like a bad omen.
I think you taking it too far.
That brat and Shinichi
are two different people.
I know,
but... I'll let him know about it anyway.
Helmet of the Black Knight?...
Bad...
My fingerprints are on that helmet...
Darn...
If the dolphin's fin and the helmet
are their doings.
What shall I do...
I've got to think up something fast...
or I'll endanger
the lives of Ran and Pops too...
The memory card!
If only I get hold of that memory card,
I'll have the upper hand.
I've got to find
the culprit as soon as possible...
Oh, maybe it's Shinich.
Yep...
"I'm involved in a dangerous case right now
so don't mail or call me..." So, he says...
I wonder what kind of dangerous case it is?
The least
you could do is let me hear your voice,
Shinichi...
That should do it...
The thing that bothers me is, the message,
(Crickets like the rain)
(Kyoto)
"Tanabata, today"...
Kyoto?
Oh, Kudo, it's been a long time!
(Kaihou High School)
What is it you want to ask me?...
- That might be on the test...
-Yeah... Yeah...
I see...
Who're you talking to?
Don't scare me like that, stupid...
Sorry, sorry...
I tell you, you scared me out of my wits...
You're talking to someone that
you have to be so surprised about,
Don't be silly, it's Kudo! Kudo!
He asking if "Tanabata Kyoto" rings a bell.
It's about the investigation
of the serial killing case...
I'm sorry, Kudo.
Silly Kazuha is bugging me...
saying that "Tanabata Kyoto" could mean...
The Mitarashi festival?
The one held at Kitano Tenmangu...
The Tanabata Festival at
Shujin Shrine is also famous...
Right!!
Why don't we go there together tonight?
If you want to go, go on ahead alone.
Can you hear me, Kudo?
Yeah... but somehow it doesn't sound right...
I guess so...
There may be other clues...
Come on let's go.
If it's in Kyoto,
we don't even have to reserve a hotel.
Stupid!
It wouldn't even cross my mind
to stay at hotel in the first place!
Did you forget that big fire
that broke out the year before last?!
Miser.
Hey, Hattori.
What big fire?
Oh, there was a big fire in Kyoto
the year before last...
Come to think of it,
it was on the night of Tanabata...
Tell me more about it in detail!
The name of the hotel
if I remember correctly was "Vega"...
Two guests were killed in the fire...
Hattori!!
Check that fire in more detail for me,
will you!
ASAP!!
Okay!
H, Hey, what're you doing, Heiji?
Class is going to start soon, you know.
Oh, tell the teacher for me, will you...
That Heiji went to see Weaver, Vega
because it's Tanabata.
-Alright!
-Huh?
Hey, who's Weaver?
Fire...
Do the red seal and alphabet on the
Mahjong tiles symbolize the fire...
The cause of the fire
(Beikachou public library)
was a cigarette that a guest
on the 5th floor was smoking,
and the stairs of the emergency exit
couldn't be used either.
A guest on the 6th floor was also trapped
in the smoke and died...
Nanako Honjo... Mitaka City Jindai...
(Mizutani)
Mr. Mizutani
Mr. Mizutani?
Mr. Mizutani isn't in right now...
Would you have any idea where he is?
Oh, so you're Detective Mouri's assistant.
I'm Shun Sawamura.
I'm a post graduate at
Jonan University's Law Department.
Nice to meet you.
Thank you.
But, don't tell anybody about this, okay?
It seems this investigation is top secret.
Oh,
so that's why he's using a child like you...
And,
Mr. Kosuke Mizutani and Nanako Honjo are...
They're lovers...
It seems that
they went against their parent's wishes
and eloped all the way here from Chiba.
Eloped...
On Tanabata the year before last...
they took a trip to Kyoto
and stayed over at the business hotel.
However, he alone went to see his friend
who lives in Kyoto.
It was then that the hotel caught fire...
He blamed himself saying that
if he hadn't gone to see his friend,
Nanako wouldn't have had to die...
He was crying when he said that...
What does Mr. Mizutani do?
He was a free-lancer,
but ever since she died,
he doesn't seem to have been working much.
It seems he hasn't come back to his room
for some time either...
I wonder where Mr. Mizutani is now?
I have no idea...
Oh,
maybe in Chiba,
because today is
the third memorial day since her death.
You mean at the temple?
Maybe.
I'm sure we can find out
from her older brother.
Wait here.
Her older brother came to see her
at this apartment several times
before she died
you asked me to contact him
if his little sister
seemed to be in trouble...
Here, here it is!
See... Her older brother's name card.
And this is Mr. Mizutani.
May I take this phone number down?
Sure.
Can you also give me
your cell phone number too, Mr. Sawamura?
Sure.
Hello, Hattori?
Hey, Kudo, you're right on... Bull's eye!!
The name list of the seven victims
you sent me,
matched the name of the guest
who was staying at a room
on the 6th floor at the time of the fire!
There are two more people
who were guests on the 6th floor...
Nanako Honjo and Kosuke Mizutani...
What? You already knew...
Then, how about this?
That man called Mizutani a year ago,
seems to have been investigating
the same thing I am now!
There seems to be no mistake
that the murder case
that you're after now has something to do
with the fire that occurred two years ago...
But, what the hell's going on?
Let's say that Mizutani were the culprit,
what's his motive?
Ms. Honjo died of an accident, didn't she?
Hattori...
How many elevators does that hotel have?
Elevator? One, I think...
What's the maximum capacity of that elevator?
Hold on.
The maximum capacity is 7 people.
So what, Kudo?
Oh! I'll get off. I'm getting off.
I see! I got it, Kudo!
Yeah, it's most likely that
on the day of the fire,
Ms. Nanako Honjo...
Was forced off the elevator she boarded
because the 8th guest got on
and she was forced to get off.
That 8th person
was Mr. Jinno symbolized by the 1 of circles!
The other six people
were all riding in the position
indicated by the position of the red circle
of the 7 of circles Mahajong tile.
The last circle is Nanako's position.
Most probably.
The Mahjong tile itself
resembles the box shape of the elevator,
and the black line in the middle
on the reverse side of the tile
symbolizes the door.
No doubt about it.
Jinno got onto the elevator last
and the buzzer sounded.
He forced somebody to get off
so he could get on.
Nanako happened to be the one
who was forced off.
The other six,
maybe pretended not to see and did nothing.
Or, maybe they even helped Jinno
because they themselves
didn't want to be forced off.
Nanako who couldn't get on the elevator
couldn't make it out in time...
What, is my deduction wrong?
No... what bothers me is
the meaning of the alphabets on the tiles...
Yeah,
it's strange that
the 7th tile was not an alphabet
but rather a triangle...
Well, if the remaining red circle
were to be Nanako,
there will be no more murders...
I sure hope so...
At any rate,
I'll try and find Mr. Mizutani...
Thanks... Hattori...
Seriously...
Kudo...
Oh!
I found this
really delicious Okonomiyaki shop!
I'll take you there,
so why don't you come over here
Y, Yeah...
Promise...
I'll be waiting, okay...
Yeah, okay...
See you...
Kudo...
Promise...
What?! July 7th 2 years ago?
Were all the victims in Kyoto that day?
Yes, we got this information
through questioning people.
Which means...
The remark, "Tanabata today..."
that the eye witness heard...
Meant Tanabata Kyoto, eh... (Kyo=today)
That day...
I'm having the men check
what happened that day in Kyoto but,
the problem is...
the message that the culprit left behind
on the Mahjong tile...
The red circle on the lower left
of the 7 of circles is still blank,
so there's a great possibility
that there will be one more victim...
Moreover.
It's probably no coincidence
that today is July 7th...
W, which means, that the last person
will be killed today...
Where and who on earth is he after...
Maybe that person is among us...
I got it!!
These 7 sites
were indicating
the shape of a certain animal.
Animal?
Listen
You see, you join all the sites...
like this... by drawing a line.
I'm sure you can tell by now...
This long line is its neck.
This is its chest,
front paws,
its back,
and these its hind legs.
In other words!!
This is not Nessie of Lochness but
Asshee of Lake Ashino
Asshee?!
Ouch,
You mean such a thing exists?
No... I've never heard of it...
I don't understand it much either...
Then, what if I turn it this way...
Hmm...
now that you mentioned it...
It does look like an Asshee...
But, what makes you say it's an Asshee?
It could be the Yasshee of Lake Yamanaka...
Look at the shape of the lake.
Lake Yamanaka is shaped like whale...
Lake Ahino is...
I get it, Mr. Mouri.
The next murder site
is going to be
the tip of the nose of the Asshee!
not too fast, Inspector Yokomizo.
You're lead to think so,
but it's actually here!
I see! Where the eye is!!...
Annaka City in Gunma Prefecture.
I know Annaka very well.
I'll go to the site to. Take me there!!
Yes, sir!!
I'll go too...
Wha?
W, What do you think you're doing!!
Don't go...
But, only two people
to face a vicious killer isn't...
Two's enough...
It sure was fun.
Yes, Conan should've come too.
Hey, don't you think that
Conan's not quite himself recently?
He went home all be himself today too
I'm sure he hasn't
recovered fully from his cold yet...
Remember, he was absent for two days.
Here comes the bus!
It's a beetle!
This bus came from Beika Forest.
I see...
It got on grandpa's shoulder
when he was walking through the forest
and came on the bus together...
Oh...
It's the tape of the convenience store.
Not again...
There were other beetles
that were tampered with too...
Poor thing.
No good. It's stuck on good and hard...
Let's have Dr. Agasa peel it off again.
And let's have him give us something
to eat too while we're at it.
Kazuki,
there was only one bunch of flowers
sent by an anonymous person... today...
That's right.
Hello...
You're Detective Mouri's assistant...
Is it true?
So, I'm looking for Mr. Mizutani because of
a certain case I'm investigating...
but it seems he didn't come
to the memorial service.
No... he did come early this morning
and left after leaving
just some flowers behind.
Only some flowers behind?...
My parents still haven't forgiven him for
eloping with my younger sister, you see...
That's why...
So, the flowers that were sent here
by an anonymous sender was...
from Mr. Mizutani?...
She was saying there was only one today,
does that mean that you got
several other such flowers?...
Yes... from people other than him...
Do you know when and where
they were delivered from?
Yes, I do...
Uh...
we got four during the funeral
the year before last...
from the cities of Matsumoto, Kawasaki
Numazu and Kamakura.
Three during
the first year memorial last year...
The flowers came from Tokorozawa, Odawara
and Hachioji...
All seven are addresses of the victims...
In fact, when I saw Kosuke this morning...
he said something strange...
Something strange?
"There're 8 people I can't forgive... "
"There's still one more person left."
Hmm... This is...
It's the doings of the same culprit...
The tape is stuck on in the same V-shape...
I see... this could be somebody's message!
Message?!
Now, can you tell what the message is?
Hmm
The answer is "help", "SOS".
Huh?
How come?
Because of the beetle...
My car, the Volkswagen, because of its shape
that resembles the beetle
is also called Beetle...
Another thing is,
the word "beetle" was combined
with the word "beat" used in music,
and a famous pop group
was named after the word.
You mean... "the Beatles"?
Their 1st album was titled
"Please, Please Me."
Their 2nd "With the Beatles."
The 3rd, "A Hard Days Night",
the 4th "Beatles for Sale",
and their 5th "Help".
How about it? Now do you understand?
What's the Beatles?
I think it's a foreign music band.
You mean, you don't know the Beatles?...
Nope... I don't either... Don't know them
Come to think of it, big sis
used to listen to them sometimes...
Because she used to like oldies...
O... Oldies...
I would rather have you dish out food for us
than give out a quiz...
"Help"...
that means someone's seeking help...
I see...
It's show time
for the Youth Detective Squad!
Yep!
I've figured it out,
the meaning of "Tanabata Kyoto"
The seven victims stayed at the hotel?!
The victim of the fire was
a young lady called Nanako Honjo.
Her lover, a man called Kosuke Mizutani,
seems to have come a year ago
asking about the fire...
And 2 hours ago,
Heiji Hattori seems to have come asking
about the same case.
Yeah, that's right...
I got sort of interested in the case...
Oh, right, Inspector.
I'll tell you something good...
The Mahjong tiles symbolize the elevator...
Elevator?
Ouch, ow...
There were 9 guests spending the night
on the 6th floor of the hotel
Aside from Nanako who died in the fire
and Mizutani himself,
7 people have already been killed...
Who's the last one left...
I know...
This is water to wash your hands with,
right?
Right! Wow, so you know.
But, I don't know how to actually use it.
Oh... I'll show you then...
Ready?
What?! Position of the stars?
Yeah... The seven murder sites
indicated the position of the six stars
of the Polar Star and the Big Dipper
Wait a minute.
True... this more than resembles it...
When you match it over
the actual picture of the stars,
it's almost a perfect match...
What a diligent person.
Likewise,
all the Mahjong tiles and the alphabets
indicated the Polar Star and Big Dipper.
The 1 and 7 of circles
formed the shape of
the Polar Star and Big Dipper.
The alphabets were
the Greek names given to each star,
that is, Alpha, Beta, Gamma,
Delta, Epsilon, Zeta, Eta...
And? Ai...
The last of the Big Dipper,
the position of Merak, right?
I'll get it right away...
Do that, will you.
Here it is...
Around Shiba Park, in the Minato ward.
I'm sure
(Beikachou Forest)
there's a person who's calling for help
near the trees where
we found the beetles the other day!
We've got to go help!
Yes.
Youth Detective Squad,
Let's go!!
If it's about Nanako and Mr. Mizutani,
about 2 hours ago
a boy wearing glasses came
to ask questions about them.
A boy wearing glasses?
Yes... he said he was
Detective Mouri's assistant...
Then this is what Mr. Mizutain said?
"There are 8 people I can't forgive...
There's still one more person left."...
Yes...
What happened...
Did Mr. Mizutani do something...
No, it's not that...
What?!
Which means the killer
intends to murder another person?!...
Yes, most probably...
And, Conan seems to have come here too...
Conan did?!
No...
I would never ask a brat like him
to do something like that...
Then, who on earth...
It could be Kudo...
Superintendent...
isn't Kosuke Mizutani the killer...
Yeah... there's probably no doubt about it...
But, who's the remaining person...
and where's the next murder site
going to be...
Nana...
Kosuke
Once more...
Uh, can I try once more?
This is so much fun
After all, it's the first time
I'm taking a trip with you,
Kosuke.
Nana!! Nana!!
Let me go! Nana's inside!!
Nana...
Okay.
I'll go look around where they may be...
Goodbye...
Mitsuhiko isn't home yet?
Hmm... It's already 7:00 pm
and where did those three go...
They're not answering
their detective badges either...
Doc, maybe the children...
Yes...
Oh, Mr. Sawamura?
Huh? The thing that Mr. Mizutani and Nanako
were interested in?
Yep... maybe something like star gazing?
Right...
They did say that they decided to live here
because it's near an observatory...
Just as I thought...
Among all the stars
they liked the Polar Star
and the Big Dipper most of all...
They liked the beautiful shape
of the Big Dipper
and the Polar Star for it is always
shining brightly facing the northeast...
I think they were reconfirming their love
for each other by watching those stars...
What am I doing talking about something
like this to a child like you
who's not ready to understand yet...
Thank you...
The place that's closest to the stars
in this area is...
Good evening
I am at the Tohto Tower
where a Tanabata Fair
is being held right now.
The weather unfortunately is not the best,
but tonight is the last night
of the Tanabata Fair.
People dressed in Yukatas
are coming in one after the other.
Now, here's the weather forecast
for tonight and tomorrow.
-it will begin raining
-In the Tokyo area,
from a little after 10:00
There may be thunder and lightning
in some areas...
Excuse me!
What is it, sonny?...
Could you keep this for me?
Huh?...
Sure... But, are you alone...?
Well, while I was in the bathroom,
my father and younger brother
went on ahead without me...
How dare they.
Your Yukata is pretty.
Yours is cute too.
Hey, why don't all four of us
take a picture together!
Let's take a lot of pictures, a lot!
Okay! here goes!
Cheese!
Did we go by this road before?
The road... maybe we took the wrong road?...
I'm hungry... let's go home...
No... we've got to find the person ourselves.
Right...
don't you want to try and solve a case
without Conan at least once...
I do.
But... there aren't any
sawtooth oak trees around...
Oh, that's right!
Let's have this beetle guide the way...
Beetles usually fly to the tree
that gives out the same sap...
That way...
Do we have to run?
As a result of investigation,
we've found out who the suspect is,
and that he may go on
to kill another person...
But, we don't know where the suspect is,
neither do we know
where the crime is going to be committed...
Does anyone have any ideas?
Darn...
while we're here doing this,
I'm sure that...
Maybe someone is being killed...
All right, it's an oak tree.
Huh?... There's another one...
Maybe there'll be tape on it again...
J... Just a bit more...
There!...
There's tape on it too... after all...
I'm sure it's over there!
The person who's asking for help
has got to be there!!
Yeah! But there's something eerie about it...
Yep, it looks haunted...
D, Don't say things like that please.
It sure is nice and the stars are beautiful
all the way up here...
That's the Polar Star...
And, that's the Big Dipper...
Yeah...
Huh?... That shape...
sure looks familiar...
What? What?
The Polar Star and the Big Dipper?!
Ouch, ow...
So, you're saying that the next murder site
is indicated by
the Polar Star and Big Dipper!!
There's no doubt about it, Inspector!
Oh, you're the officer
I talked to you a while ago...
Yes...
Then, Mr. Mizutaini and Ms. Honjo
used to like star gazing...
Thank you...
Superintendent!
The place that matches the position
of the remaining stars
of the Big Dipper is Shiba Park!
Okay!
Megure, put out an emergency search
for Kosuke Mizutain right now
and wait here!
All the others head for Shiba Park!
On the double!!
Yes, sir!!
Ah, gee...
Don't scare us like that...
What do you mean, "Ah, gee"...
You shouldn't be out playing around
like this at this time of day.
We weren't playing around!
We came to help someone!
The person that used the beetles
to ask for help!
At any rate, it's time to go home.
Your parents are worried about you.
It's still early...
We can all go home after they answer
the plea that message indicates,
don't you think?
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much...
Oh...
I'll get it.
Thanks... I'd appreciate it.
Yes, this is officer Takagi's cell phone.
Oh, Dr. Agasa.
His hands are tied right now...
I'm sorry to interrupt you when you're busy,
but could you please
tell him this please...?
Well, this is a weird story you see...
Beatles?...
It can't be...
I got you. We'll be right over!
You and the others hide somewhere safe, Doc!
Officer Takagi,
head for Beika Forest, will you.
No, but...
Don't worry...
I'll take full responsibility!
All right, I'll take full responsibility!
H, Hey, which way?
Huh? Oh... I don't get it!!
To the left.
Okay.
(Kogoro Mori detective agency)
What?! Conan was on TV?!...
Yeah... I saw him
walk into the Tohto Tower alone.
I think it was around 20:00...
I see...
Well, I'm sure you don't have to worry
and he'll be back soon...
But... his cell phone is switched off too...
No good... Superintendent...
Neither Takagi nor Sato is answering.
Never mind them!
Okay!
I'm sure Mizutani
is hiding in this vicinity!
Split up and nab him
as soon as you find him!!
Yes, sir!!
It's not visible because it's cloudy...
The star that Nanako and you liked...
The Polar Star and Big Dipper...
Sonny...
Oh, this customer...
Did you see him?
Yes, he kept asking me
what time we close over
and over so I remember him.
If I'm not mistaken
he went up to the observatory alone
at around 19:00.
Oh!
You're Detective Mouri's assistant...
Sort of...
But, it's too bad
that despite coming to a place
so near the stars,
there are no stars to see.
No... They're visible in my eyes.
No matter where and when
those stars are always visible to me...
What?! The observatory?!
Yes, this woman says she saw him.
Did you see him leave?
No, I didn't...
Okay! There's no doubt that the suspect
is in the Grand Observatory!
I'm sure he's summoned someone there
and is getting ready
to commit his final murder!
We're going in now
and taking custody of the suspect
as well as shelter the hostage!
The suspect is most probably armed
so take great care!
Please leave the lights inside as is.
Yes, sir!
-Let's go!
-Yes, sir!
Uh, Mr. Mizutani...
After you finish drinking that wine,
you're planning to die, right?
"There are 8 people I cannot forgive... "
"there is one more person left... "
The remaining one person
is you yourself, right... Mr. Mizutani.
W, What the?!
I think I can understand
how surprised and angry
you were to the point of trembling
when you heard of how Nanako passed away...
That's why you went to the hotel in Kyoto
to check things out, right?
You're absolutely right...
On that day, 2 years ago,
if I didn't go to see my friend,
Nanako wouldn't have had to die...
When I think about it,
I just can't forgive myself...
But killing yourself's not right!
Suicide is killing yourself,
you know...
I know... I know,
but... I can't bear to live in world
where Nana is no more...
Besides...
I'm going to be sentenced to death anyway...
No you won't...
Because you didn't kill anybody
Mr. Mizutani...
There was a person who came to you
and asked you to kill yourself
since you yourself being as kind as you are,
couldn't make yourself kill those 7 people,
right?
Since you felt responsible
for Nanako's death,
you didn't think of disagreeing...
But,
the person that,
that man really hated and wanted to kill
was actually you, Mr. Mizutani!
Because you, Mr. Mizutani,
were the one who took his
beloved younger sister away from him...
Isn't that right...
Nanako's older brother
Mr. Kazuki Honjo!
B, Big brother, what bring you here...
Don't lecture me!
Brat... How'd you figure out I did it...
I just couldn't understand...
No matter how much I thought about it...
If Mr. Mizutani were the killer,
I just couldn't understand the psyche behind
why he chose the position of the Polar Star
and Big Dipper to indicate the murder site...
Because it would be like throwing dirt
onto the stars that he liked, right?
So, I deduced that maybe someone else
schemed the entire murder taking advantage
of the fact that Mr. Mizutani liked stars,
and to frame him as the murderer...
Once I realized this, I was convinced...
Besides, the killer accurately
set the coordinates of the Polar Star
and Big Dipper on the map,
and was a person meticulous enough
to set that place up as the murder site...
On the contrary, the name plate at
Mr. Mizutani's apartment was slightly crooked
and his handwriting
wasn't all that nice either...
The telephone number
written on Mr. Honjo's name card
was beautifully written
and a light line was drawn
so that the handwriting
wouldn't go crooked...
Even in your notebook, Mr. Honjo,
you had the names and addresses
of the people that had sent flowers
neatly written out in a small space.
This means that you're
a very meticulous person, doesn't it?
Who the hell are you anyway...
Conan Edogawa...
a detective...
It's been a hard day...
Dr. Agasa... where are the other children?
I took them home to their parents...
Let me take you there.
Please do.
You wait in the car, Ai.
You're the one who called Mr. Mizutani
about Nanako's death, right?
Yeah...
I heard from him
that Sumire Shindo the artist
was staying at the same hotel
on the same floor that day...
(Art Exhibition)
I went to Sumire's exhibition
wanting to talk to her...
Back then, I coincidentally heard and
eavesdropped Sumire and Ryuzaki
talking to each other...
So, you went ahead
and told Mr. Mizutani about it...
Including a bit of your lies too...
He told you that the flowers that
arrived on Nanako's first memorial service
were sent by the seven people who were
staying on the sixth floor that day.
If it were just one or two people
they could've sent it of goodwill,
but all seven of them doing so,
can be taken as nothing more than
their feeling of appreciation.
In appreciation for Nanako
getting off the elevator
and making way for all of them...
Then, don't tell me that Nanako wasn't
forced off the elevator,
but rather, got off of her own initiative...
Yeah, right,
because Nanako was a kind person...
But!
Even if she got off on her own,
it makes no difference that
she died because they got on!
Mr. Mizutani...
It's true that Nanako's died as a result
of saving the 7 people...
But... She sacrificing her life
compared to you taking on Mr. Honjo's crime
and killing yourself
sacrificing your own life
is as different as heaven and hell.
It so different
as a star glittering in the sky
to a stone rolling on the ground!
Nana...
-I'm not going to do it...
-What?!
I'm sorry, but I've decided not to die...
This boy woke me up.
Mizutani...
I'm sure that Nana who's in heaven
doesn't want me to commit suicide either...
I'll give this back to you.
I don't need it anymore.
Please turn yourself in... big brother...
Damn...
Mr. Honjo...
Those are things that you stole
from the 7 victims, right...?
You gave it to Mr. Mizutani saying that
if he died with that on him
it would be proof
that he's the killer, right.
I'm glad I came after all...
I heard that Detective Mouri
was investigating the case,
so I was worried that things
would be exposed and came...
I lied to you expecting
that you would avenge
my younger sister's death,
but you didn't have the courage to do it...
That's why I took it upon myself
to kill them.
That's not courage!
It's nothing more than
gratifying your own needs!
Shut up!!!
I guess you came here alone
because I don't see Detective Mouri around!
How dare you make light of me!!
We made it in time...
I'm Matsumoto from
the Metropolitan Police Department...
M, Metropolitan Police Department...?
Are you hurt?
Oh, no...
You're coming with me to the station...
Shoots!!
Damn...
I'm not getting caught...
Just as I thought...
you were Irish after all!!
-Police!!
-Freeze!
Just as I thought!!
Superintendent!!
S, Superintendent?!
Please get a hold of yourself!!
Superintendent?!
Why is he in a place like this?
That Superintendent Matsumoto's
an imposter...
He switched...
Superintendent lived in the age
when the Beatles were popular...
I couldn't believe it but...
Contact Inspector Megure...
Okay.
It's me. What's up?...
They've found out... that he's an imposter...
Okay...
Belmot...
Huh? He did come here?
Yes,
he left his skateboard here
but didn't come to get it
so I was wondering about him.
Don't tell me he's still in there.
No way.
If he still is, that's bad news.
He'll come face to face with the killer.
K, Killer?!
The police are inside investigating now.
Sonoko, wait here!
H, Hey, Ran?!
You!! Wait up!!
What did you do
with Superintendent Matsumoto?
Don't tell me that you...
No, he's still alive...
I've got to have him take my place
as the killer you see...
Is that the memory card
with the NOC list of the Organization...
Yeah, sort of...
When did you figure out I was an imposter?
I sort of had an idea...
that you weren't
the master of disguise Belmot
and that someone else had snuck in
because your physique
is too different from hers,
and it was impossible for her
to disguise herself as the Superintendent...
As a result,
you become the number one candidate...
I see...
Just as would be expected of you...
Shinichi Kudo...
I wasn't really all for it
until I saw the fingerprints match though.
Did you report this to your boss?
No, not yet...
I haven't told anybody yet.
Not even to Gin?
No...
Shinichi Kudo...
Have you forgotten...
I don't remember the name of each
and every person I killed...
What about him?
No... it's nothing.
Phooey... just concentrate on your mission,
will you.
Why...
Some time ago that guy...
on top of shooting a member
of the Organization who goofed
left the corpse of that man to burn to ashes
in the burning inferno of Haido City Hotel...
That member was a man that I respected
and depended on like a father.
Haido City Hotel...
Pisco?!
You've checked everything out on us too,
I see...
His greatest mistake
was failing to kill Shinichi Kudo,
on top of not being able
to expose his identity...
I'm taking you to that person myself...
as witness
to put that
snobbish cold blooded bastard away.
Only this man's knows my identity...
All I have to do is knock him down...
But,
I can't use my tranquilizer gun already...
The only thing I can do is...
Don't worry, I won't kill you...
I'm just going to knock you out
for a while...
I've got to take you to that person alive
or he won't believe
that you're Shinichi Kudo...
T, This is...
Officer Chiba?!
Officer Chiba, are you all right?!
I think he's just passed out...
I think the same goes
for the rest of the people too...
Conan?!
Hey, you?!
You! Wait up.
Conan...
Conan! Are you all right?!
Ran... big sis...
Conan!
Are you both okay?
Superintendent Matsumoto!
Superintendent!
The other officers downstairs are...
Yeah... they were attacked by the culprit...
No...
Get out of...
What? What's the matter?
Run for it... That guy's...
Huh?
You're not... Superintendent Matsumoto...
Phooey...
No...
I'll be fine...
I can't take on rifles
like Kyogyoku,
but if a shotgun...
Hey, Ran do you know?
The speed of a bullet from a rifle
goes at 1000 meters per second.
On the contrary,
a bullet from a shotgun
goes at only one-third of that,
at 350 meters per second!
What's so funny...
Don't tell me you think
you can dodge my bullet?
Exactly.
Very interesting...
Try it...
Wow...
You're pretty good, sweetie.
It slipped my mind...
that you, sweetie... are a master of Karate!!
Ran!
How dare you waste my time...
Ran, stay down!
Leave the rest to me and you stay still!
Damn!
Run! Run!
Let me enjoy this even more...
Damn!
Too bad! You almost made it!!
Kugh! What's the matter? Is that it?
Okay, keep that up. Hang in there!
It's about time we end this game of chase...
I guess the situation's reversed...
Damn...
Okay, give me the memory card.
Here they come...
The situation's reversed...
It's me...
How're things...
Did you get a hold of the memory card...
Yeah...
I can't see it too clearly...
Stick it out more in front.
Right... More in front.
Fire.
Bingo.
I wanted to shoot him...
Boss...
Look below.
Huh?
That's... He can't flee already...
Good work... Irish...
There's one more...
Hey! Get a hold of yourself! Hey!!
You'll be fine.
They've missed the vital point.
So long as we can get you treated as soon as
they're taken care of...
I get the picture...
No wonder Belmot fell for you...
Don't talk!
Once I get your wound treated,
you better be ready
cause you're spitting out
the identity of your boss!
Irish!!
Shinichi Kudo...
keep pursuing them... forever...
Irish!!
He used Irish as a shield!!
We can't afford to let him get down.
Use the you know what.
Roger.
Damn!!
No good, Ran's below...
There he is, keep it up!
Boss... what shall we do?
Chianti, smoke him out.
Okay
Darn... What now...
Tear gas?!
Here he comes... Corner him all the way up!
Phooey... we've cornered the mouse...
From above... Aim at him from above!
There'll be no blind spot.
Roger.
Damn!
What now...
If I keep this up, I'm a rat in a trap...
Darn... What now...
Now, let's see what he looks like...
H, He jumped off!
He gave up thinking he couldn't flee.
Go for it!!
We've been hit...
Hey, what the hell's going on?!
It, It's out of control!!
We've got no choice... retreat...
Roger.
What the...
Who the hell is he...
Just as expected of Silver Bullet.
He's pretty good...
And suddenly there was a loud bang...
Well...I'm embarassed...
We're lucky no one was injured.
I'm sorry!
Okay, Ran,
I think we'll be asking you
for the details at a later date,
so when the time comes,
please help us, all right?
Okay.
They'll be dispatching a car
to take you home so wait a while longer,
okay?
Thank you very much.
Are you really okay?
Yep.
Right, I'll go get us some drinks.
Oh, don't worry about it...
No problem at all...
Thanks...
Ran.
Everything's okay now.
Shinichi said that...
Oh, now that you mentioned it, Shinichi...
Oh, well you see,
He said
he had to go attend to another case...
What! He left on his own again
Yep... And...
I'll bet he left saying,
"Don't tell anybody about me"
or something like that, right?
Oh, right,
he says you can call him...
I "can" call him?
Oh, rather...
he was saying to please call him,
I think it was...
Well, I guess it's forgivable that
I got to at least hear his voice...
Besides...
Talking of voices...
after all, there are people...
who only get to see each other once a year...
It seems that no dead bodies were found
in the helicopter that crashed.
Yeah...
I'll bet they all escaped
just before the explosion...
AI... So, Irish's identity remains unknown...
I'll bet the police have nothing on him, too
I can't tell them anything
about him either...
But,
it's horrifying to think that
he was being confined for 10 days
in a place like this...
It seems that Superintendent Matsumoto
didn't see the face
of the one who abducted him either...
Either way, thanks to the children,
he was safely rescued.
Yeah...
After all, Irish died before he could tell
where the place of confinement was...
Irish...
Shinichi Kudo...
Keep pursuing them... forever...
I sure will keep pursuing them...
Until I crush those guys to a pulp!!