Uh... Today at around a little after 21:50...
the National Tokyo Microorganism
Research Center in Nishi Tama City
was attacked by
a group of seven armed men...
The armed group captured two security guards
and took the researcher
who is on duty hostage,
(Tadayoshi Uno Chief Commission Councilor)
and made it into the high security lab.
(Toshiro Odagiri Chief Commission Detective)
A few minutes later,
after exploding the plastic bomb
that they set up,
they fled the site.
Counselor! Excuse us!
In the lab that was bombed
it is assumed that
some very dangerous bacteria was stored,
and that it was taken away by the culprits.
Dangerous bacteria?!
It is said that if infected by this bacteria,
there's an 80% chance of death,
and moreover,
no antidote for it has been found yet.
Could the bacteria have leaked out
to nearby areas due to the explosion?
No.
The chief of the research center
has testified that
since the scope of the explosion was large,
even if there were to have been
any bacteria remaining,
they would have perished to ashes.
What is the purpose of the group?
We don't know yet...
But, we are also taking into consideration
the possibility of bio-terrorism.
I would like to make a request to all of you.
In order to avoid needless panic,
we would like you to limit your report
to this being a case of a bomb explosion
and refrain from mentioning anything
about the bacteria,
or the possibility of this
being an act of bio-terrorism.
You mean you're censoring the press?
Hello...
Hello.
Chief!
It seems that the culprit group
declared their action on the internet!
Moreover, they are calling themselves by
the name of the terrorist group
Red Siamese Cat...
We, the Red Siamese Cat
have attacked the
National Tokyo Microorganism Research Center,
and have gotten hold of a killer bacteria.
We will be doing the following things
in the next 7 days.
Prepare yourselves for it...
So, the bacteria was taken away after all...
But, didn't the Red Siamese Cat
perish 10 years ago...
Chief!
So, we're not going to be censored anymore,
are we?!
It can't be helped...
All right!
So, today we have with us here,
scholar of bacteriology, Ms. Chiaki Ota.
(Chiaki Fujimoto, bacteria specialist)
If infected by this bacteria,
a rash accompanied by itching will appear.
What a terrible thing they've done...
(Bacteria invasion)
This is the only news that has been aired
since this morning...
The body will become weak
and eventually death is inevitable.
It spreads mainly from being
sprayed with the bacteria.
Little children are especially susceptible
and will catch it easily.
Characteristically,
symptoms will appear almost immediately.
So they say. What now?
Since you've turned into a little child,
Conan?
Leave me alone.
More than that Heiji.
What bothers me is...
Why the culprit group
exploded the lab, right?
If their purpose was
to get away with the bacteria,
they didn't have to explode the place.
True...
By the way,
did you know about the organization
called Red Siamese Cat?
No...
only that 10 years ago,
they used to target rich people
and repeat terrorist activities...
Well, we were both still kids then too...
Oh, I'm sorry, so sorry.
It slipped my mind
that you're still a kid, Conan.
How rude.
By the way, Kudo,
you told me that you were going to
board a blimp, didn't you?
Yeah... on the one that will fly
from Tokyo to Osaka... ,
(Largest Zeppelin built)
because that old man slammed a letter
of challenge at Thief Kid again...
(Attention the Kaito Kid thief!)
A letter of acceptance seems to have arrived
from him a while ago too...
So, I'm sure that the old man is...
How dare those Red Stray cats!!
To take my news of the world's best blimp
that I had completed with me being
the center of the project,
off the first page headlines!!
Thanks to them, the letter of challenge
that I received from my arch rival Thief Kid
has also lost its grandeur!!
Then, Kudo.
why don't sleep over
at my house at that time.
I'll take you to the okonomiyaki shop
that I promised to take you to.
Okay, I got it, See you.
Beep.
(The Lost Ship in the Sky)
I'm high school detective Shinichi Kudo.
I went to the amusement park
with my childhood friend and classmate Ran.
When I witnessed suspicious looking men
in black making a deal.
I was so absorbed in watching the deal
that I didn't notice one of the men
approaching me from behind at all.
I was forced to drink poison by that man
and when I woke up...
my body was shrunk!!
If those guys find out
that Shinichi Kudo is alive
they would come after me again,
and moreover, endanger the lives
of the people around me too
Through advice from Dr. Agasa,
I decided to hide my true identity.
So, when Ran asked me for my name
I answered Conan Edogawa,
and made up my mind to free load at her house
where her father runs a detective agency
in order to gather information on the guys.
One, two, three, four, two, three, four!
Jirokichi Suzuki, 72 years old...
I'm sorry.
Thank you very much!
He is Ran's best friend Sonoko's Dad's cousin
as well as the advisor
for the Suzuki Financial Group.
He received all the awards he desired,
and realized all the dreams
he had wished for,
is what this proud old man always says...
He is currently
putting his entire heart and soul
into his confrontation with Thief Kid...
But, my concern is those guys...
The terrorists who bombed the laboratory
and fled with dangerous bacteria...
What is their purpose...?
I may have shrunk
but my brains remain the same.
No case remains unsolved
with Detective Conan.
There is just one and only truth!!
Wow, it's Tropical Land.
The castle looks small!
It looks like a toy amusement park!
Fantastic scenery, fantastic...
Dad, the scenery is great!
Uh, why don't you come over here and look?
Shut up!
I'm thinking of something right now!!
-Oh boy...
-Come to think of it,
you're not at home with high places,
are you, Mr. Mouri?
That's not it!!
Uh, I wonder if Thief Kid
is always looking at scenery like this?
I envy him.
I wonder though, is Thief Kid really coming?
He will!
Because Uncle Jirokichi received a letter
of reply from him...
See!
HE NO GO N DE 0 KESHIMASU?
What's with you reading
just the words you can read!
I tell you...
Here goes, okay?
Thank you for inviting me
on board your blimp.
I happily accept it.
However, considering that
you are already 72 years old,
it hurts me to think that
I'll be keeping you tense for 6 hours, so...
I'll go to get it after sundown
just when the blimp passes over
the skies of Osaka City.
Until then, please enjoy your pleasure flight
to your heart's content.
Thief Kid...
Oh~ how I wish he would come to get me too,
Thief Kid
I used to think so from before,
but she sure has a unique personality...
W, Well. I guess so...
By the way,
are we the only passengers on this flight?
I'm sure that a writer of reports
called Mr. Fujioka is on board...
O, Oh, that's him...
(Takamichi Fujioka, freelance writer)
He said he wanted to write a report
on the confrontation of
Thief Kid and Uncle Jirokichi..
He came from his side and sold himself...
-The others are...
-Uh, excuse me...
You're Mr. Kogoro Mouri, aren't you?
How do you do?
(Masaki Mizukawa, producer of Nisai TV)
I'm Mizukawa, director of Nichiuri TV.
And they are reporter Kasumi Nishitani
and cameraman Junpei Ishimoto.
Hello, nice to meet you.
Oh, same here...
We've been exclusively chosen
to broadcast live the confrontation
between Mr. Suzuki and Thief Kid this time...
Oh... you're going to be airing a special
from sundown today...
Yes...
We wanted to put our all
into airing the program
like we did some time back
when we broadcast the mid air walk,
but, unfortunately, the timing was bad...
Timing?...
On the Red Siamese Cat...
Yes...
ever since they warned of the things
they'll be doing within the next 7 days,
our station is prepared
for any type of emergency...
If they go according as planned,
today's the deadline...
Phooey! Thanks to them
the flight permit
that I needed to fly the helicopter
for my autobiography wasn't granted...
I tell you
I hate those good-for-nothing cats,
right, Lupin.
Uncle Jirokichi...
Hello, hello, advisor Suzuki.
I'm looking forward to today.
My, what a fantastic blimp.
Phooey!
You're broadcasting that fantastic blimp
and all you have is a staff of three...
Oh, well...
Thanks to that incident,
you already know about,
the station's hands are tied...
But,
I wonder what those culprits
are planning to do with the bacteria...
Right, right,
if anyone catches it
there's almost no chance of staying alive...
I hear that you can catch it
if the bacteria is sprayed in the air
or something...
It sure is frightening
The bacteria's going to be sprayed in air?
No sprayed.
It means that it's contagious
and can be caught
if someone infected
with it sneezes or coughs.
Children seem to be especially
susceptible to it,
so you should be careful.
What...
No sweat.
I don't know
if it's some killer bacteria or what but,
I came from a place that's filled with germs,
but see, I'm alive and kicking.
Humans are way stronger than bacteria.
Right.
But then,
kids like you may go just like that, though.
Please stop it!
Please stop saying things
that will scare the children!!
Right! Talk about insensitive!!
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha. no sweat, no sweat.
No problem.
No matter
where in Japan the bacteria is scattered,
as long as we're on board the blimp,
we'll be fine,
don't worry!
That's only if you keep on flying...
Isn't it about time
we prepare for tea service?
Yep, but let me take a quick puff
before that.
I'll be right back.
So, you can't figure out
who the culprits are after all...
Yes, the higher ups of the Red Siamese Cat
that are serving sentence now
insist that they have no idea
what's going on...
For now,
the only clue that we have is that ampule,
but it's not one that's been made by
any manufacturer domestically
or outside of Japan.
It's probably an original
that was made by the Red Siamse Cat.
The fact that the ampule was found
in the parking lot of the research center
means that...
there is a high probability that
the culprits brought several empty ampules
into the research center.
Then, they put the bacteria
that was stored in the lab
into the ampules and took them outside.
And they mistakenly dropped
one of the empty ampules...
Yes,
inserting the bacteria into another container
is extremely difficult
and dangerous.
It is presumed that the culprit possesses
much scientific knowledge.
But, why didn't they
take the bacteria out as is,
rather than do something as dangerous as
to insert it into another container.
In the first place,
why did they suddenly appear like ghosts
after a period of 10 long years...
What on earth is their purpose...
Hey! There's a window over here too!!
They really seem to be having fun,
those children.
Hmm...
How lucky that they get to ride
a blimp despite being so young.
They should be grateful to Sonoko.
Because for them
it's just like riding a large cloud
that is afloat in the sky...
Oh, it's nothing...
I just sort of remembered some things back
when I was a child...
When Ran saw a blimp go through the sky
for the first time...
Shinichi!! Oh, no! Oh, no!!
It's a UFO! UFO's flying!!
UFO?
Well,
since a balloon monster like thing
was flying gracefully through the sky,
she was probably surprised
and thought so but...
Oh,
are you bragging about
your dear little princess?
I, I'm not bragging.
But,
you've appealed her feminine side
more than enough...
Even I'd like to ride a magic ship
that flies through the skie
and go to a dream land
that's above the clouds too...
... I'm just joking.
I, I thought so...
Everybody!!
Uncle Jirokichi says
he'll show us to the sky deck!
You'll get to see the Big Jewel!
All right!!
Treasure, treasure!!
Okay! Do you want to see the treasure?!
Aye!!
Let's go, then!!
Conan and Ai, let's go.
Well, all I can say is to keep
a firm grip on her
so that some Peter Pan
doesn't snatch her away from you
and take her off to dreamland.
Just what's she trying to say...
Doc...
That story about the UFO just a while ago,
don't tell Ran about it, okay.
I know.
Is everybody gathered?
Yes!
All right, I, Chief Stewart Sano
(Asano Mitsuhiro, Cockpit Captain)
will now show you to the sky deck.
Wow!
It's glass all around!
We get to see the inside of the blimp!
Okay, here we go!
It's so exciting.
-Yep.
-Everyone, don't be surprised.
This Bell Tree #1
is 246 meters in length
and its maximum diameter is 42.2 meters.
In both length and diameter this blimp
is 1 meter larger than the famed Hindenburg.
It is literally the world's largest blimp.
Darn,
why does it have to be glass all around...?
and is equipped
with a computer controlled operation device
in the cockpit.
Huh?
Something that looks like a balloon
is wriggling
That's an air sac and
it's filled with helium gas.
It's just like the lungs of whales.
Really, it looks like it's alive.
It indeed feels like
we're moving up a whale's stomach...
Wow! It's so bright!
You can see the sky!!
It's the jewel!!
This is Advisor Suzuki's pride and joy...
the sky deck.
One part of the roof
can be opened and closed...
So, it's good for sunbathing,
or star viewing.
There are many ways to enjoy it,
but today I've rigged it a little bit
in order to capture him...
I wanna see the jewel!
It's not something for kids to look at!
What?! What's the problem?!
No!
Hey, you!!
You...
Inspector Nakamori...
Oh, Mr. Mouri, you too...
Let me introduce you...
Oh, wait...
That's the Lapis Lazuli
that's going to be used
to lure that guy over here today...
It's the big jewel, Lady Sky!
How beautiful.
This blue color is indescribable!
The gold particles are glittering!
They look like stars!
Out of all the golden particles
don't you think that the biggest one...
look like something?
Hmm... The biggest particle?
Oh, it looks like the face of a lady!!
Exactly,
that's how it got the name "Lady Sky!"
The natural philosopher
of the ancient Rome called Plinius
called this stone
"a piece from heaven
that shines as the stars... "
It is indeed a jewel that is worthy of
being display in this sky deck.
Phooey! Why do you have such a valuable piece
exhibited behind a mere plain glass case?
Oh... Inspector,
the bullet proof glass
that repels the bullets of a machine gun
and the iron wall device that won't open
unless my fingerprint
and the pass code matches
is beyond your comprehension?
Phooey... they're all of no use.
After all, even at the research center
where the bacteria was stolen
a similar kind of device was set up...
What happens if this is pushed?
Why don't you push it?
Like this.
Dad?!
That device wasn't rigged like this, was it?
Well, no...
W, What a thing to do you darn brat!!
Dad?!
I see... That sensor...
But, talk about full of problems...
It's true that
such a device wasn't attached but
what if he does this, then what?
If a gun is stuck out at you like this,
you've got no choice
but to open it using your finger, right?
Well, I don't believe
he'll do something like that,
but if he does...
In, Inspector Nakamori?!
Ha, ha, ha... in that event, I'll do this.
Don't tell me it fell into the sea?
No way.
Darn! What a device!!
Do you still call this a plain glass case?
I'm sure it was, 4, 7...
I see... That's what it is...
At any rate,
he's going to appear at sundown.
There's no need to keep guard over here
till then, is there?
Phooey!
We're going to re-think
the strategy downstairs!
-Let's go!!
-Yes, sir.
Well, what an interesting thing to watch.
Thanks to you
I'll be able to write a good report.
Excuse me,
please smoke in the smoking room on B-Deck.
Mr. Mouri, how about joining us?
No, I'll go rest in my room...
I don't have the slightest idea
what's going on...
Ha, ha, ha... that comes as no surprise...
Oh, what a relief...
Uncle sure had a hard time, didn't he?
Yep...
Oh, by the way,
that band-aid was good, wasn't it?
The band aid, band aid!
Haven't you used it yet?
Don't tell me...
you did something to the band aid?
Hey, just what is this?!
(Shinichi Love)
Heh, heh, heh... You like it?
I tell you, what's with you...
Oh no!
I gave some bandaids to the crew
when I boarded the ship!
Hurry, everybody!
Oops...
Take it easy little lady,
or it's dangerous.
Thank you...
Thank you very much.
No problem...
Oh, blood...
By your elbow...
Oh, maybe I scraped myself just now...
Wait.
Please use this.
Thank you.
What shall I do
if he thinks that I wrote it...
He won't notice it,
because the writing was so tiny anyway...
Oh, boy...
I guess I'll go take a look at
that jewel once more...
I didn't get a good look at it a while ago
because since there were
so many people there.
Oh...
I'll go to my room then,
because I promised to mail Makoto.
The thing about Thief Kid is a secret, okay
-See you later, then
-Yep.
I wonder who it is...?
Hello...
Hello... Uh...
Oh, I'm a waiter on the blimp...
I slipped away from my job
to go take look at the rumored jewel.
Oh... Oops.
Oh no, I gotta go back to work...
Enjoy yourself, bye...
Oh, thank you...
Please wait!
W, what is it?
That band-aid...
Oh, I burned myself a bit just a while ago.
No joke!!
It, It's no joke.
Then take a better look at the band-aid!
Shoots!
How come you have the band-aid
that I gave someone else?
You're Thief Kid, aren't you!!
Ugh, she saw through me...
-Ow, ow, ow...
-Spit it out!!
Oh boy...
It'd be kind of hard to keep on insisting
that I'm the waiter too...
But, I don't think forcing my way away
from her will either...
What's so funny?
Hurry up and confess.
So, what do you intend to do if I confess?
Will you take me to Inspector Nakamori?
Phooey, that's not a bad idea...
But, you're the one
who's going to get yourself in trouble
if you do that...
Huh... You still can figure out
Who I am...?
Right...
the true identity of Thief Kid
was... me!
Sorry, sorry.
Are you all right, Conan...
Did you catch a cold again?
It's not a cold.
What's the matter?
Did you forget my face
because we've been apart too long?
Thief Kid's identity is Shinichi you say?
Come off it!
It's probably just one of your disguises
that you pride yourself in...
Ow, ow, ow...
It's not a disguise?!
Course!
I've got nothing on.
No...
Back when I crash landed a plane,
and the Inspector pulled at his face,
the disguise didn't come off...
Maybe you both just look alike to begin with?
Damn, how careless of me.
That guy always comes to check out the place
before committing a crime...
- If we leave the diamond...
- Oh! Inspector Nakamori!
You've run out of luck now
that you've boarded this blimp
where there's no escape route...
Give yourself in!!
Not a blimp...
But a UFO... right?
If I remember correctly,
that what you said
when we were kids, right...
I must look like an unidentified alien
who suddenly appeared in a UFO to you,
but I'm playing the role of Thief Kid
because I have no other choice than to do so
in order to solve a certain case...
As proof of that
I return the things a steal
to the owners later, don't I?
B, But... but... What?!
Well... there's no way
that the renown detective Shinichi Kudo
would overlook a flashy thief like this,
so I thought
that you would figure it out, Ran...
If you want to catch me go ahead,
I'll give myself up...
Shin... ichi?
What's up?
Is something wrong?
Oh, no...
If you notice anything...
It's nothing...
I seem to have made a mistake. I'm sorry.
See you...
What's going on...
Shinichi is Thief Kid...
Which means that he was saying he was busy
because of cases he had to solve,
but was stealing all the while...
Hey, can you give me
the glass cup over there?
Huh? What's wrong with your arm?
Yep... it seems that
I've been bitten by a mosquito or something
and it's so itchy...
To think that there're mosquitoes
in a place like this too...
- Here.
-Thank you!
See you.
Hey.
I... don't believe you...
If you will excuse me, then.
Time, time!
Mr. Fujioka...
Well, excuse me, really.
Just as would be expected of the champion
of the Kanto Karate Tournament...
You've got great muscles.
Look! A blimp!!
Wow!
It looks like a whale!
It's a whale flying through the sky!
Thank you for waiting
Just great!!
Lady, another serving please!!
Hey
You've completely come back to life...
Moreover, lady, he says...
Thank you for waiting,
here's your cake dessert.
T, Thank you...
Wow! It was worth waiting for.
It looks delicious
Hmm?
What is added in this cream?
Isn't this blackberry?
Hey, Ran...
Ran, I said!
I didn't know you liked
that type of person, Ran?
What are you staring at so seriously for?
It, It's nothing like that...
Maybe I should tell your hubby about it...
I told you it's nothing like that!
Like I'm saying, if you open this door
you can go out to the corridor in the middle.
And if we go out from the door in front...
We can go there, right?!
Right!
Are you children...
going somewhere?
Oh, no... well...
We were talking over whether
we should play cards in our room from now...
They're up to something again...
I can't wait
I want to get to Osaka as soon as possible
and meet Thief Kid
And if all possible...
If I can I'd like to place my lips
on his dauntless lips...
No, no, no darn way!!
T, Thief Kid is a criminal,
you know! It's just not right.
What are you getting all worked up for...
I, I'm not!
What...?
Nothing...
You guys, hurry up and eat!
Yes, sir!
Inspector Nakamori,
why don't you take your time and eat,
since my men
are keeping watch over the jewel...
But, Thief Kid is probably on the move
as we're eating too.
We're finished eating!
We're going back to our room
to play cards, then.
See you later
What's with them, hurrying on like that.
Thank you...
Oh, sorry.
Boy, be careful, will you...
Didn't your mother teach you
to cover your mouth
like this when you sneeze?
-I'm sorry.
-No problem.
-Okay, let's go.
-Okay!
(Anonymous caller)
Who on earth is it?
Hello...
I scattered the killer bacteria
in the smoking room of the blimp.
What?!
Just what do you think you're talking about?!
Try looking under the sofa to the left.
Hey, wait!...
Is something wrong, Uncle?
No, it's nothing. It's a crank call.
Inspector...
What's this...?!
No doubt about it...
It's the same ampule as the one the guys
who attacked the research center dropped...
We haven't publicized this ampule.
Which means...
What the man said on the phone
is probably true.
The ampule that was found in the parking lot
was something that
the guys probably deliberately dropped there,
so that we could verify
whether the ampule in the smoking room
-is authentic or not...
-Darn!
At any rate, I'll inform the higher ups.
Thanks.
It seems that what the man said is true.
MY God.
I guess arresting Thief Kid
is not the problem right now.
Close off the smoking room right away!
Just to be safe,
we should close off this bar too.
Yes, sir!
What?! O, Oh no...
Are you sure?
Maybe it's just a prank or something...
No, unfortunately, not...
I just confirmed it with headquarters...
At any rate, just like I said before,
we're closing off
the smoking room on B-deck...
He... Help me...
R, Rash?!
Don't tell me he caught the germs?
Come to think of it,
he went to the smoking room a while ago...
Help me, please...
I sort of feel bad.
Cool it... calm down.
I don't want to die.
I, I'm sorry...
Don't be...
Ran, you should sterilize your hands
right away.
This way!
We've got sterilizing alcohol
in the service room!
Okay.
To think that we got people
who caught the germs in this blimp...
Is there anyone else who
went into the smoking room?
Hey! Are you all right?
R, Rash
on her right hand and left arm...
Darn, her too...
Where can we isolate them?
There's a hospital room
beyond the examination room.
There aren't any doctors on board today,
but we can lock the door from the outside.
Okay, let's move them over there.
I'll take them there...
Hey.
Okay!
Just to be safe,
we should close off this dining room too.
Then, all of you move over to the lounge.
Dad, get up!
I'm sure glad
that the children weren't here, though.
Yeah...
Yeah, we've better inform them
about this too...
True...
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh no!!
It sure was fun, wasn't it!
Let's go to the tail of the whale next then!
Genta...
Whales have no tail...
they have rear fins...
-Is that so...
-Genta!!
Conan!
Oh, uh, we didn't know
that this place was off limits...
Genta,
do you feel all right?
He's got no rash...
Maybe he didn't catch it,
or is it still incubation period...
Hey, Conan?
What's the matter?
Yeah,
let's go explore the blimp together.
This is no time for that.
There's something really bad going on now.
What bad thing?
At any rate, let's go back to the cabin.
Pull away!
Stay still over here!
Who's that...
and what's that person in a place
like this anyway...
He removed the lock right now...?
Don't tell me that
he's the one scattering the germs...
Who is he?
Is he Thief Kid's accomplice?
Oh boy...
No...
I don't think he's with Thief Kid...
I'm sure he's with the Red Saimese Cat...
No good...
This is really bad...
Shoots!!
That's? Is that a bomb?
Go on beyond!
Climb the ladder by the gas shaft pole!
Hurry, quick.
Freeze!!
Who're you?
Did you find the ampule?
Red Siamese Cat...
We set a bomb up in the blimp...
If you do exactly as I say
we won't explode the bomb...
Lupin! Quiet!
I'm telling you be quiet...
How about the front and back?
Cat F... we seized the cockpit...
Cat D... we seized the kitchen...
Cat C... we seized the sky deck.
There's nobody in the passengers' cabine.
Okay...
Use the on board announcement device
and gather
the entire crew in the dining room!
Conan... what shall we do...?
To the entire crew on board!
Gather in the dining room
on the double.
We the Red Siamese Cats
have hijacked this blimp...
All of you, take out your cell phones.
Dad, wake up!
I don't have one.
It's me.
The blimp's been hijacked.
Just as I thought.
And what're they demanding?
What do you want?
Is it money?
Or do you want the members of your team
who are locked up released?
We have a grudge
against the Suzuki Financial Group.
And, especially against this old man here!
It's true that 10 years ago,
I helped the police crush their organization!
So, I'll be your hostage,
let the others go.
No darn way.
Why not!
This blimp is going to head for Osaka as is.
Contact the police.
Only,
"if you make any funny moves,
we're going to bomb the blimp!"
Tell them that!
And...
This is the much rumored
about killer bacteria!
Don't you even think of arresting us...
Because if you do,
not only the smoking room,
but these killer bacteria will be scattered
throughout the entire cabin...
What shall we do, Conan?
We've got to go save Ai and the others!
Before that I've got to take the bomb apart.
Ai,
the accomplices of the culprits
maybe among the hostages
-so be careful.
-Roger...
I hope you guys didn't go
inside the smoking room.
You went in?!
Yeah... but all I did was look inside
just a little...
But it smelled so much of smoke,
that I closed the door right away.
Brother...!
Not only was he sneezed on,
he went to the smoking room too!
Don't worry,
because we didn't go inside.
We've got no rash either!
More than that, what about the bomb!
Y, Yeah... There are a total of 4 bombs.
Out of the four,
two are in the rear of the corridor below.
Near the fuel tank
is most probably the place.
You guys
do you think you can find the bombs?
Of course!
Only, don't dare touch it
even if you find it.
Let me know right away.
Yep, okay!
And,
if you start feeling even a little sick,
let me know too.
Understand!
Aye!
I'm sure that Ayumi and Mitsuhiko are okay.
But, Genta...
Darn!
I guess I've got no choice but to pray that
he hasn't caught the germs
Uh, where are the children...?
No need to worry, Conan is with them.
Just as I thought,
one of them is in back of the smoking room...
If they explode the bomb hidden there,
the bacteria scattered here
will spread through the entire blimp...
Moreover, if they open a hole in the blimp
the bacteria spread outside...
But, why are the culprits
using both the bomb and bacteria?
Because it's true that they can hijack
the blimp using just one of them...
Why?
Why are the culprits
using both the bacteria and the bomb...?
Maybe they just want to be extra sure?
Either way,
so long as they haven't made any demands yet,
we've got no choice
but to watch how things go for now...
Go after the blimp making sure
that they don't realize
you're following them.
I'll contact all the police departments
where the blimp will be passing through
as well as the Osaka Prefectural Police.
Yes, sir!
Conan, I found the bomb!
I've found one here too!
Okay,
we've only got one more left to go!
Get down!
I'll go look for the remaining one,
so you guys stay here and wait!
Open it.
Don't do anything funny
if you don't want any of the hostages
to be killed.
Just what are you doing Mr. Mizukawa?
Mr. Mizukawa, don't tell me that...!
It, It's nothing.
Mr. Mizuakwa...
It's nothing...
Rash?!
No!!
T, This is just rash from allergy!
Come to think of it,
he smelled of cigarettes just a while ago!
He went to the smoking
and caught the germs there...
No!!
I did go, but I didn't catch it!
As you know, the other places aren't...
If now, I can take on these two...
I can pin them now...
Go shove them in the smoking room!
Don't tell me that I caught it too...
Here it is...
Uh, come to think of it the children
are nowhere in sight.
Children?
Oh, yes...
I'm sure that they were about
the same age as the three.
I'm sure there was one girl among them too...
Look for them.
She should mind her own business...
Conan,
they've noticed that all of you aren't here.
Conan, Conan...
Two men went off to look for you guys...
You're pretty cool, aren't you?
You?!
Just what do you think you're doing?!
Are you all right, Ai?
You're the pits, hitting a child!
Next time you do something funny,
I'm going to kill you.
Okay, that's it.
Did you guys do this?
I'm the one who did it.
They have nothing to do with this.
Phooey... you've got guts.
-Conan!!
-Don't move!
Shinichi.
Damn it!
All right!
Thief Kid?!
Nice catch!
Just as would be expected of Thief Kid!
Although he's an enemy, good for him!
Shinichi...!
So, Thief Kid's appeared after all.
Now, we can get rid of all the nuisance.
Go and set up two bombs!
I didn't think
he would throw you out the window.
What now, famed detective?
Do you want to give up?
Course not.
Go back to the blimp right this minute!
Don't be ridiculous.
My hand glider's not equipped
with an engine you know.
You're lucky we're even alive!
(Aichi city, Sakushima island)
They're headed straight west.
I guess they're headed for Osaka,
after all...
(Osaka police headquarters)
The blimp if flying over Tsuu city
of the Mie prefecture at present...
If they go on as is,
they'll probably reach Osaka
in about an hour from now...
At Nanko (harbor) the symbol
of the Suzuki Financial Group,
the Bell Tree Tower is there...
That's the destination of
the test flight of the blimp,,,
Are they planning to crash right
into that tower
and blow themselves up blimp and all...?
Is that the scenario that
the culprits who have a grudge
against the Suzuki Financial Group have
in store for them?
We can tell for sure
whether it is nor not...
But, if that's it,
the bacteria will spread all over Osaka.
The lives of over 700 million
will be endangered...
We've got to keep that from happening
at all costs...
But, what can we do...
Heiji!
Hey, what took you so long?
Sorry, sorry.
Who's this boy?
Hello.
Oh, he's Satoshi Kawaguchi...
He's relative of mine and
he moved to Nara from Yokohama in spring.
He was over at my house and playing,
so I brought him along.
Satoshi said he wanted to see you too, Heiji.
And, since you stick around with Conan a lot,
you like children, don't you Heiji?
Y, Yeah... sort of...
How do you do, nice to see you.
Yeah, nice meeting you too.
I hate to be intrusive,
but are you going with each other?
I, Idiot!
Why do I have to go
with somebody like her.
Heiji's just a childhood friend
and like a kid brother to me.
-She no darn way at all my type!
-We're not on a date today, either!
What a thing to say.
Which means that you don't mind me
taking Kazuha for my wife?
I don't mind, I don't mind at all.
If you don't mind wedding somebody like her
I'll wrap a ribbon around her
and give her to you.
Thank you, uncle Heiji!
Just who do you think you're calling uncle!
Oh come on, he's just a kid...
Satoshi,
I'm happy of how you feel about me,
but that's something
you have to give great thought to...
Besides, you're still too young
to get married anyway...
I know.
Boys can't get married
until they turn 18 right?
Okay, so if your feelings for me don't change
when you turn 18,
let's think about it then.
Okay, so much for this subject!
Oh, I hope the blimp would hurry up
and get here...
I've got to confront Thief Kid before that!
The stage will be over the skies
of Osaka City.
I'm sure
that we'll be able to see it from here...
If it's the ring side,
we've got super special seats!
I love Thief Kid so much.
I'll get a picture of him for sure!
Really, I can't wait!
Kudo...
Yeah, where are you now?
Sakushima in Mikawa Bay.
What, you'll still in some place like that?
I mean, not really,
I was thrown off, you see.
Thrown off?
The fact is, Hattori...
What the...?!
Are you serious?!
Yeah,
a blimp carrying bombs, the killer bacteria
and hijackers are headed that way!
W, What a gorgeous menu
Pork, squid, octopus,
with fried noodles mix patty...
Two people have already been infected...
Make that three.
The director called Mizukawa
came down with rash
on the palm of his right hand.
You heard him...
I just thought I'd let you know about this.
Are you all right?
Yeah, at least for now...
Oh, it's the police chopper...
I wonder if they're going after the blimp...
Police department...
Sorry, I'll call you back again!
Hey, hold it, you!
Darn! going off on his own again...
It can't be helped.
I want to go to the place
that sells good food
and eat right away...
Weren't you talking with somebody
about a good Okonomiyaki shop?
Well,
did you find anything on their identity?
Well, we tried investigating all the way
to an acquaintance
who was close to the former executive but...
No likely person emerged.
No good after, eh...
Yes, Megure here...
Inspector Megure, this is Kudo.
Oh, Mr. Kudo!
I'm in Sakushima of Aichi Prefecture
right now but,
a police chopper is going after the blimp...
Yeah, Officer Sato and Takagi are on board.
The thing is Kudo...
I already know about the hijacking.
I have a favor to ask of you, inspector...
Huh, what could it be?
I want to get on board that chopper too...
I, Shinichi Kudo...
Hey, where is Shinichi Kudo?
You're him, aren't you?
So, I'm telling you
to disguise yourself as me.
Oh, boy...
So, I'm going to disguise myself
as you again.
Oh, well...
I don't mind helping you,
but, don't you get in the way of my job.
I can't give you my word, though
I'll try to cooperate with you
as much as possible...
Alright.
Cat E, start preparing.
Roger!
What is it?
What're they planning to do?
It's been a long time, Mr. Kudo!
Hi...
But, what a surprise
that Conan is also with you.
Did you have something to do in Sakushima?
We'll talk about that later.
Please continue following the airship.
Please follow the airship.
There it is! The blimp.
Please go up close
and stay at a high enough altitude
so the hijackers don't notice you.
Roger.
What is the direction of the wind
and speed of the chopper right now?
East southeast,
going at a velocity of 200 kilos!
Please keep going as is,
and after you overtake the blimp,
match the speed to the blimp.
Mr. Kudo?
Mr. Kudo, just what do you intend to do...
See you, we'll be leaving you now.
Thief Kid?!
W, Wings! Wings!
Put your wings away!!
Hurry up and put away your wings!!
I can't push the switch
because you're in the way!!
Darn!
Oh, hey,
just where do you think you're touching.
S, Stop it.
Stay still, I'll push the switch right now.
Boy, but it's ticklish...
Endure!
Hey, that's...
Look out!
L, Let's get out of here!
By the way, Mr. Kudo is...
Was he Thief Kid?
Oh, well, good luck then...
Aren't you going?
I'm staying here
and checking things out for a while.
The diamond has fallen into those
robbers' hands anyways.
That's right...
Here
H, Hey. What's this?
It's Jirokichi's fingerprint seal.
Thank you!
My deduction that he'd be using
a fingerprint recognition glass case
this time hit the bull's eye but...
I won't use it anymore, so you can have it.
More than that,
you'd better take care of
your precious girlfriend...
That guy called Fujioka
grabbed both her arms.
She jumped away right away, though.
He didn't sneeze or cough so
I don't think she was infected
or anything but...
I thought... I'd let you know.
Not here...
I was sure that they rigged it here but...
Not here either...
Maybe they rigged it in a different place
than they did before...
I only found two, after all...
Moreover, the bombs that were found were
where Genta and Mitsuhiko were...
Why...
why didn't they reset the bomb
in the most important place,
where the bacteria is...
I guess, I'd better start
by taking this apart...
Hey, Kudo!
You said you were going to call me back,
but you never did!
Kudo?
Oh... I mean... C, Conan
Sorry, sorry, I completely forgot.
Oh boy...
where are you now?
Inside the blimp.
You went back there already?
You're really fast, aren't you?
By the way, what do you want?
I'm busy right now, you see.
The hijackers publicized the thing
about the blimp on the internet,
so Osaka is entirely panicked out.
What?!
The trains are jam packed with people
traveling from Osaka to the west.
Like I said, there are no more seats.
If in the direction of Tokyo...
Idiot!!
Why should I go where the bacteria is!!
Trains are coming in succession
Don't push!
Come on,
there's still space for people to get it!
Please board the next train.
(OSAKA STATION)
The expressways and regular streets heading
from Osaka to the west are filled with cars.
And there is a terrible traffic jam.
It seems that the tellers of the bank
as well as the security guards
are all being told to evacuate,
so the best time to steal is now.
I don't think that's a good idea,
because security is tight everywhere now.
I'm only joking. Only joke.
Keep out of the conversation of the adults!
Security...
What it is... Don't scare me!
You can see something interesting.
Sorry, I'll call you back.
H, hey?!...
Darn, he hung up again...
What's going on, what's going on?...
Uh, Kazuha?
What?
Who was Uncle Heiji talking to just now?
Oh... to Conan.
Conan?
He's about the same age as you Satoshi,
and a super smart elementary school boy.
It seems
he gets along really well with Heiji.
Then it's not a conversation
between adults, is it...?
Hey!!
Stop talking about things
you don't need to talk about!!
Yes, yes, I'm so sorry,
Uncle Heiji
What's the interesting thing?!
A flare?
What do you mean...
If we go over these mountains, it's Nara.
The people of Nara are sure
going to be surprised
seeing a blimp smoking
while flying over their city.
They're not only going to be surprised,
they're going to panic.
Panic?
They made public on the internet
about the bacteria and bomb.
I'm sure that the people
are being evacuated just about now...
Well, if that's what's happening in Nara,
it's super for a thief.
Idiot,
even if people are gone,
in modern days
they have security... you know...
Security?
Don't tell me...
That's why they're headed for Nara!
It could be...
But... if so,
why did those guys...
use the bacteria for something like this...
I see... I got it.
Leave it to me!
Where are you going, Heiji?
Nara! To Nara!
Nara?!
Nara,
you mean it has to do with that blimp?
Yeah,
it's dangerous so don't come with me!
Please take me there too!
Idiot!
I just told you not to come with me!
I know the streets of Nara,
so I'm sure that I can be of use to you!
I'm going too!
You too?
Besides, three people riding one motorbike
is against the law...
No problem, no problem...
I came upon a good idea!
Hang on tight!
I know!
Satoshi, are you all right?
Y, Yep... I'm fine.
We'll be there soon, so hold on for a while.
I wonder if this is what I should be doing...
Oh no... why?
Ran?
Ran!
Ran! Ran!!
Sit down!!
Ran...?
Rash...?
Please help me Please!!
Let go!!
Come! You go inside and stay there too!!
Don't touch me!!
Darn!
What's going on...
Just as Thief Kid said,
she couldn't have gotten infected
just because he grabbed her arm.
Besides, Ran leaped away,
and Mr. Fujioka had no rash
and didn't sneeze either...
In comparison...
Genta was not only sneezed on,
he most likely inhaled
the air of the smoking room
and yet wasn't infected...
Why?
That director called Mizukawa
had rash here.
Maybe...
The blimp's going to come falling!
M Bacteria!
Bacteria's going to come falling!!
They're loaded with bombs!
(Hofu Temple)
Everyone here?
Hurry, hurry! Evacuate
But, the Buddha.
The Buddha
will not be infected by the bacteria!
Please ride, quickly!
I hope we don't get punished for this
Think about it, if you're punished.
Just get in, please...
Ran...
Go look.
Yes, sir!
Hey.
You're?
Cat A...
Cat A, what's wrong? Answer me!
Shoots! Go check things out!
Yes, sir!
Hey, what's the matter?
Hey!!
A, Are you... sleeping?!
Cat B!!
What's up?! What's wrong?
Cat B is passed out on the roof.
Strange...
Cats usually don't fall on their backs.
It's Conan!
He's back!
Thief Kid's with him too
Thief Kid's not here.
Darn!
Cats C, D, E,
catch that brat!!
Rather...
shoot him as soon as you find him!
-Roger!
You go and keep guard over the dining room
Cat F!
Roger!
I'll switch over to automatic pilot
and head over that side!
Darn!
The brat's in the sky deck!
1...
The thing rigged
for Thief Kid came in handy...
And, this too...
Wait a sec...
Maybe he gave this deliberately to me
so that I would use it.
Freeze!!
Throw that down!
Raise your hands in the air.
I saw you.
You sure do a lot of stuff, don't you?
Come on, get down on your hands over there!
D, Do I have to?
Listen to me...!
Y, Yes, sir.
I'm not like the others so far, you know
Oh goodness! I told you so. Why you
Darn!!
Hey, hey, are you serious...
What's this?...
The third trap
that Jirokichi got ready for you.
I get it.
If I try to escape from that window
after snatching the jewel
and fire my wire gun...
Close call close call!
That old man is really something.
You mean you were up there all this time?
Take this!
Amazing!
Talk about an... award-winning warrior.
The rest of you, are you listening?
I beat your leader up.
The same with the other three too.
W, What?
You gotta be joking.
Go get him, Lupin!
All right!!
Come on
Don't go swinging stuff like this around!
Conan?
The two over here are beat up too.
Roger!
Talk about a lot of call history... Moreover,
all in the last 2 to 3 hours...
Uh, who were you talking to
on the cell phone?
I mean, this are so many calls here...
If you don't want to talk about it...
What're you going to do with it...
If you don't tell me from your side
I'll call all the people in here...
suit yourself...
Okay... Put it down once...
Slowly...
I see...
A really great idea...
Bio terror strategy using the blimp...
The real motive behind the crime
was to steal all the national treasures
at one time
after everyone evacuates from the temple
and it is emptied out...
They tried to take advantage of the fact
that the security of the temple
is not too tight!
Because people usually wouldn't think
that statues would be stolen.
Heaven'll punish them for sure!
Just what're you talking about?
We were trying to protect the statues...
Then, I don't care who...
just give me one of the names
of the officers that work
at the Nara Prefectural Police Station.
W, Well...
What, you don't even know one person?
That's strange, and you're a police officer?!
Come on, there's an Inspector
with just the right name for Na
All we have to take on is a brat.
Get him!
Hello? Did you just say something?
He said that all he has to take on are brats.
what?
Maybe those guys are stupid?
Really...
What makes you think that we'd come here,
just we three,
when we've come to nab thieves!
What?!
Darn!!
Oh, I'm Inspector Tsuyoshi Shikantsuno
from the third inspection division
of the Nara prefectural police.
(Tsuyoshi Shinkantsuno, Nara city police)
Don't forget!
Don't you ever make light of
the Nara Prefectural Police!!
Hey, Kudo...
The guys who were after the statue...
have all been arrested.
Of course, the monks and everybody else
are all safe!
I got it!
Thanks big brother, Heiji!
What's this?
So that Osaka detective boy
was pulling the strings after all, eh?
...Pulling the strings...
Right...
Here, this.
Oh, thanks little sonny.
We've got to hurry
and take Ran to the hospital.
Oh, right, and about that...
I don't want to die...
Ran...
Conan?!
No!!
Don't come, Conan!!
Don't worry, Ran,
because no one is infected by bacteria.
Huh?...
But, I've got rash...
That's just simple itchy rash.
You must've touched lacquer or something.
Lacquer?
The person who brought you here, Ran,
wasn't he the same man who
Mr. Mizukawa here too?
Y, Yes...
Just as I thought...
I think he was the only one among them
was immune to lacquer...
Because his nails were black.
He was probably a lacquer craftsman
or something in the past.
In other words,
the hijackers never stole the bacteria
to begin with.
All they did was bomb the research center
and made it look like they were
really committing a bio terror attack.
As proof of this is this ampule...
...I tried to open the lid of this ampule
in front of the leader,
but he seemed completely calm...
If bacteria was inside,
he would've desperately tried to stop me,
right?
Like you shouted at me a while ago, Ran.
Conan...
That's right, isn't it, Pops?
Huh? Yeah...
Are you okay, Ran...?
Beside, look...
Aside from the rash you had at the start
you have rash on the palm of your hands,
in the back of your arms...
and in the back of your thighs, right?
Huh, no joke?
I think that the hijackers
sprayed lacquer
in every corner of this room...
On the walls, sofa, and the door knob...
That's why when Mr. Fujioka
who smoked in this room
and came down with rash
from lacquer grabbed you on your arm,
your arm broke out in rash.
But, as to the other parts,
rash broke out only in places
where you touched...
something in this room...
Wait a sec...
then, why did that person...!!
Don't tell me that!
H, Hey,
what's the matter?!
Conan...
Shoots...
We got word from the Nara Prefectural Police
that they found out
the identity of the hijack group.
They're a group that
have experience being guards abroad.
Guards, eh...
Then, the name Red Siamese Cat was...
They have nothing to do with that group.
They disguised themselves
as a terrorist organization
to camouflage their true intent
as Buddha statue thieves...
And the one
who hired those guys with money was...
Wait a sec...
Don't you think it's much too cowardly
to leave your men behind and flee alone?
Boss of the hijack group,
Mr. Takamichi Fukioka?
Brat, good work disclosing my identity...
No...
I was completely thrown off
because you pretended to be the first one
who was infected...
It's most likely that your woman accomplice
soon after takeoff,
sprayed liquefied lacquer
in the smoking room,
and placed the ampule there...
Of course she did it
under your instructions...
After that, you deliberately
went into the smoking room
to come down with rash from lacquer...
In order to make us believe
that you were infected by the bacteria...
You invited Pops to come to the smoking room
on the sky deck too, because...
Mr. Mouri,
would you like to join me for a smoke?
You grabbed Ran's arm because,
you wanted to get people who
would get in your way
to look like they got infected
to render them immobile...
Since Pops didn't work out like you planned,
you probably put a sleeping drug
in his beer or something.
Thanks to you,
he was fast asleep until a while ago...
Mr. Mizukawa and the waitress
broke out in rash on the palm of their hands
and in back of their arms...
They probably touched something
in the smoking room.
Genta only looked inside the smoking room,
but didn't touch anything,
so he didn't broke out in rash...
In other words, you're the only one...
who broke out in rash in places
that could not be touched easily,
like your face and throat,
and even on your chest!
Besides, the leader seemed to
have constantly been in touch with someone...
That's how I figured it out...
That fact that you,
covered your entire body with the lacquer
that was sprayed all over the smoking room,
to break out in rash in order to
breed terror of bacterial infection.
You isolated yourself deliberately
and gave orders out to the hijackers
from a place where nobody would see you.
You're the big boss
who was pulling the strings behind the scene!
Pretty good deduction there, brat...
But, you've overlooked an important point...
What?
First of all, I'm not planning to flee alone.
I'm sorry to say that all your men are...
Not them...
Not the men I paid to hire...
The men that worked under me from before.
Don't tell me that there're more...
Freeze!!
Sonoko!!
I told you don't move.
Conan, there are still two more!
The cameraman and reporter
are his accomplices too!
Darn!
Secondly,
I didn't come here to flee.
I came to lure you out.
What?!
Do you know why we planned the hijack
to steal Buddha statues
instead of take money?
In the IT world of today,
the flow of money is sure
to be tracked down right away.
Therefore,
we figured that
stealing priceless Buddha statues
were safer to deal with...
Japanese Buddha statues
are popular abroad too,
and we already had buyers waiting
for them too...
I'll make you pay for
washing our profit down the drain.
We still have a lot of time...
Let's enjoy to the fullest...
Mr. Hattori, you've done a great job!
The one who did a great job
is that boy over there!
By the way,
will you please go after that blimp?
I can't get a hold of the boy
from a while ago.
I have this bad feeling, you see...
Okay!
Listen Satoshi...
you go on home from here.
Huh?... But...
I know...
we were able to save the Buddha statues
thanks to you.
Uh, Uncle Heiji.
I think the thieves are after Gofuku Temple.
They have a lot of national treasure there.
Okay! I got it!
Then, take me with you...
No.
It's too dangerous.
Go home with Kazuha!
Satoshi, let's do that, okay?
I'm sure your mother's worried too
Okay...
but then,
introduce me to the boy
called Conan next time!
You're going to save him, aren't you,
Uncle Heiji?
Okay, I promise!
Kazuha, take care of things from here, okay?
You can count on me.
You be careful too, Heiji.
I will.
Okay! Here goes.
Y, Yes...
To think that
you were their accomplices too...
The other side's okay.
Hey!
Hurry and let me go!
Oh, sorry, sorry...
I forgot to tell you guys but,
we've had a slight change in plans...
Change in plans?
After all,
this is all the loot with ended up with...
You're going to have to die
along with them!!
What?!
Let me tell you something good
before your final moment.
We'll be bidding you farewell
by that bridge over there
where our cruiser is anchored...
Soon after we leave,
the blimp will explode...
along with the cabin
where the passengers are...
I see... that's why.
You may have removed the bomb
that was placed near the fuel tank but,
there were two others left in the cabin.
Darn!!
But, before that...
As for you, I'll have you drown at sea here
and disappear.
Darn, what now...
What can I do...
to turn things around at once
and get out of this situation?
There it is! The blimp!!
It's flying pretty low, isn't it...?
Uh... if they go as is...
they'll crash into Ohashi of Akashi Strait!!
Port Tower is in view!
The squid mark of Rokko too!!
Wow!!
You're trying to distract me
so that I bump my head on the pillar
or the bridge or something, eh?
I'm not falling for such a childish trick.
W, What the?!
What's the matter?!
Damn!
Wow...
The whale took a leap...
Hello.
Hey, Kudo, are you okay?
Oh, Hattori, great timing.
Contact the coastguard, will you?
The coastguard?
The head of the hijackers,
Fujioka fell into the sea.
The hijacker fell into the sea?!
Yeah...
and near the bridge,
their cruiser is supposed
to be anchored with other members on it.
Nab those guys too, will you.
Got you!
See you later, then...
We're having okonomiyaki tomorrow,
so look forward to it.
Hey, Hattori?
Was that call from Shinichi?
Huh? Uh...
I'd like to ask you something...
Is Shinichi... Thief Kid?
What?
Hey, everybody, are you all okay?
Yes, somehow...
We were just a little surprised.
Where're those guys?!
If you're talking about the two culprits,
they're passed out over there.
They crashed into the wall
when the blimp sharply ascended
a while ago...
Serves them right...
I guess we were saved because we were tied...
Well, I was surprised.
I went to the hall to check things out.
Then, suddenly the floor tilted...
Why you, Thief Kid!!
Dear Thief Kid.
Where's Conan?
That boy's fine.
I'm sure he'll be here in a little while...
Please untie everyone's rope then.
Oh, dear Thief Kid, me too...
Stop!
Thief Kid you prick!
Oh, of course untie the inspector last,
please.
Then, everyone,
I shall take the jewel with me as I promised.
Wait up!
Hold it, Thief Kid!!
How dare you petty thief!
It's Thief Kid.
Hmm... Oh...
and the hijackers?
I see, okay...
Good work.
All the hostages are safe.
The group of criminals
have all been arrested.
and... the case is closed... now...
Yeah...
Oh, I'm starved!
It's finally the long awaited dinner time.
I wonder if they have eels over rice.
I can't help feeling we forgot something...
Now that you mentioned it...
Okay, so it's quiz time
that you've all waited for!
We haven't been waiting for it...
Ayumi, Genta and Mitsuhiko
are really good children but,
who out of the three
have nothing to do with the flight?
What? Is that... all?
If you don't know the answer,
I'll give you a hint...
All three have something to do with it,
right?
If all three are good children,
none of them will get into a fight, right?
Flight... no fight...
Oh, I see.
I see.
Oh,
if only he was a simpleton like this riddle,
I could've nabbed him easily
and made the front pages...
Uh, Sonoko.
Where's Ran?
Come to think of it, they sure are late.
She said to go on ahead
So I thought she had to go
to the restroom or something...
She went up the elevator...
I wonder if she went to meet Thief Kid?
What?!
It obviously isn't transparent...
Shinichi...
Uh, Shinichi...
Oh no! Come to think of it,
she did say something to that effect...
Hi there, Ran...
Today was a pretty stimulating day,
wasn't it...
Shinichi!!
Admit it, Shinichi!!
A thief is a thief,
and not good!
Please, Shinichi!!
Okay...!!
Then...
If you give me the treasure that I want most,
I'll turn myself into the police.
Huh?... But, I have nothing.
Shh
That is, of course...
Huh?
Oh, wait, wait,
Hey...
You're not Shinichi!?!
Conan.
Thief Kid, why you!!
Yes...
I'm not a detective, but a thief...
The job of a thief is to steal...
Be it the heart of a person.
Dear Thief Kid, you're fantastic.
Being told that after what he's done,
blows everything...
Huh? What did he do?
Oh, Thief Kid returned the Lady Sky,
right...?
Uh, what did Thief Kid do to you?
Something that Shinichi would never do.
What?
Why...?
Why wouldn't Shinichi ever do it?
What made you think so?
So, that's...
It, It's not because I like him, you know!
Don't get me wrong!!
What?...
H, Hey, Ran!!
Hey, hey...
what the hell does a thing like that
mean anyway...